MAN: Just before my father died,
he said the worst thing about growing old
was that it gets harder
to protect the things that matter.
Honour, freedom, justice and family.
Those things are sacred.
You live your life by a code, an ethos.
Every man does.
It's your shoreline.
It's what guides you home...
and trust me, you're always trying to get home.
NEWSCASTER: Authorities say the ring
is centred in Costa Rica with the primary export being...
widely unknown if the war on drugs
is connecting them with...
Teams in the region have been known to retaliate using a...
25,000 troops be...
flying from the U.S. to control that region.
Can we get some ice cream?
- No, we got to go. - You always say no.
Well, are you gonna buy? No, you buy.
Okay, what are we getting today? Passion fruit.
Okay, passion fruit.
AMBASSADOR: How about macadamia nut?
NEWSCASTER: ..claimed responsibility
for the attack at the International School in Manila.
MAN: Your father was a reader.
He loved Churchill, Faulkner,
and books about other wise men.
He loved artists who painted people
with bodies that looked like boxes.
I'd give him hell about that.
He'd just say, "You got to look harder."
Ambassador Margulies had long been a strong supporter
of joint counter-terrorism operations
conducted within this region.
Not one group has yet claimed responsibility
for the attacks on the International School.
- Here's your coffee, Rorke. - Thank you, ma'am.
- How's it going? - Hey.
- You want the usual? - Sounds good, thank you.
You're late again, Dave. I didn't say anything.
What do you got going on over here?
Are you serious, man?
We're not telling anyone yet.
You a little nervous, though, huh?
Last time I checked, they don't come with directions.
Yeah, tell me about it.
- Hey- - Hey- My man here is having a baby.
Hey, congratulations.
Hey, everybody, Rorke's having a baby.
What did I just say?
Ah, don't worry about it, man. You're gonna be awesome.
I'm so excited for you, man. You'll be a good dad.
Hey, tomorrow Jackie and I are heading to the beach.
Bring Sandy and the kids. I'll bring an board for you.
- You know I don't surf. - I know you don't surf,
but it'll be good to get the families together.
- All right. - Now you've told everyone here,
try and contain yourself tomorrow.
L will try.
: "Look harder," your father would say.
I always knew he wasn't just talking
about those strange boxy paintings.
Order and chaos throughout the world.
One often disguises the other.
Hey, I'll be right down, all right?
Whatever you say, boss.
WOMAN: How was the ride?
MAN: I left Colombia this morning.
Colombia to here in one day?
Piece of cake.
Anyway, estimates say that Christo is worth
- close to a billion. - That's with a "B"?
Yeah, and he gives back a lot to this community here
with medical clinics, schools, political donations,
you name it, so this is the deal:
They are extremely loyal to him over here.
When did the DEA hand him over to us?
When they intercepted a 707 of his
filled with Soviet weapons.
Listen, Langley says that the boys over at NSA...
they found some interesting intercepts connecting Christo
to a jihadist network out of Southeast Asia.
Apparently, Christo and one of the guys running the network...
they're childhood friends.
DAVE: Your father's grandfather
gave up his life flying a B-24 in World War II.
He kept the liberator aloft
just long enough for everyone to jump,
and then he went down with the plane.
That's the blood that courses in your veins.
Daddy, can I come with you?
Want to come with me? Did you feel how cold it is out there?
I tell you what.
Go hang out with Mommy for a little while, help out
with the baby. When I come back in,
if you still want to go out, I'll take you out with me.
- Promise? - I promise. Hurry up, go.
What's going on, sir?
What's up, brother? Nothing much, man.
Now, I know you got the New York heritage,
but this isn't exactly like sitting back in Staten Island.
You got to actually work hard to get through the surf.
12-plus years on the teams and you don't know how to do this?
Hey, wait till you have five kids, man.
You'll see how much time you got to play in the surf.
You ready to get in the drink or what?
Okay, man, lead the way.
- All right, don't embarrass us. - All right.
: Your father was my boss, and I was his chief.
We'd saved each other's lives more than once.
There was a brotherhood between us, and we depended
on each other more than family.
A wise man once said,
"Although a single twig will break,
a bundle of twigs is strong."
Okay, okay, gracias. Wow, this is unbelievable.
I still can't believe you ordered Chinese in this place.
It's really good.
Double word score, 18 points.
Dumb?
Read it and weep, sugar.
Hmm.
I'll try not to.
Look at this, look at this.
38 points for me.
Adumbrating... that's not even a word.
Okay, first of all, it's pronounced "adumbrating,"
and it means pretending, foreshadowing.
Hmm, guess who's buying dinner tonight, sugar.
Fine.
In most cases, officers get tactical partners.
Langley sets me up with some sort of Scrabble hustler.
Scrabble Yoda, okay? Get it right.
- How much do I owe you? - Nada. - Shit.
DAVE: Our platoon was headed downrange.
Weimy... he was our sniper.
Ten years ago he worked nights
stocking shelves at a grocery store.
Now he's another watchman
standing guard while the world sleeps.
He was a husband and a father.
Ray... our comms guy, our radioman.
He grew up in East L.A. gangland.
He had a Silver Star for pulling a wounded teammate
out of the fray.
Sonny... he was made of granite.
This guy didn't even do push-ups
'cause he was afraid his chest was gonna get too big.
Ajay joined the teams late in his 30s.
He'd been a Muay Thai fighter early in life.
Before that, he grew up dirt poor in Trinidad.
Mikey had 20 years in the teams.
But as humble as he was, you'd never even know it.
He kept a picture of his wife in his helmet
and a lock of her hair in his pocket.
Quiet as the breeze.
And finally, Senior Chief.
I couldn't really tell you much about him,
other than I'd rather take a knife into a gunfight
than have to be interrogated by him.
That last night at home,
you'd think about how you could have been a better dad,
a better husband.
That bedtime story you should have read
or that anniversary you forgot.
You don't expect your family
to understand what you're doing.
You just hope they'll understand
you're doing it for them.
When you get home, you hope you can pick up
right where you left off.
- Yo, what's up, Chief? - That boy is so, so awesome.
What, you putting the wild bunch down?
Hey, uh, Senior,
you mind giving us a couple minutes, man?
- Nah, you got 'em, jefe. - Thanks.
RORKE: Fellas, you know I only got so many speeches
in a given work-up or deployment, but, uh...
it's like Chief and I said
right at the beginning of this platoon.
Once we step off on campaign,
once this bird's ready and we're downrange,
everything back home needs to be in balance.
We're not gonna be worth a damn
to each other or ourselves if we get
over there and something's out of whack.
I mean, if things aren't right with the family,
things aren't right with the finances, or something's off,
it's gonna put us all out of balance,
so we need to have that tight before we launch.
If somebody/s got an issue, bring it up.
Chief can take care of it, I can take care of it.
Everybody's got each other's back. Let's make sure
we lock that down so when we're ready to roll,
all our focus is on the mission.
For all those who have been downrange...
to us and those like us... damn few.
- ALL: Cheers. - Hear, hear.
I still like the name James.
I'll think about it, if it's a boy. Come here.
I'm proud of you.
Thanks, baby.
Hey, little one,
you make sure you keep Mama away from Aunt Carol.
I don't like that chain-smoking at all.
I got it, Lieutenant.
- Okay. - It's gonna be okay.
- All right. - It's gonna be fine.
Try to keep this as long as you can
- for a while, yeah? - Anything else, Commander?
Yeah, I'd like to be able to look into your eyes
when our first child is born.
You know I'll do my best.
I love you, baby.
Love you.
DAVE: War is a country of will.
There is no room for sympathy.
If you're not willing to give up everything,
you've already lost.
CHRISTO: What is it about you Americans that makes
you feel entitled to fuck with how I make my living?
I know who you are, Miss Morales, and who you work for.
: So why don't you save us both some time
and tell me exactly what you think you know?
: How did that feel, Miss Morales?
Have a great day at the spa.
HENCHMAN: Si, jefe.
- Hey, fellas, what's up? - Hey.
It's hotter than two rats
screwing in a wool sock out there, yeah?
Africa-hot... Tarzan couldn't take this heat.
Anyway, here's the deal. Time to get your frogman on.
Lights. Three days ago,
two CIA agents... a Walter Ross and a Miss Lisa Morales...
were ambushed inside their hotel room
here in Costa Rica by a unknown amount
of heavily-armed assholes.
Unfortunately, Mr. Ross was murdered
and Miss Morales has been abducted.
We believe that this has been the work
of a guy named Mikail Troikowicz, aka Christo.
LT's going to give you the skinny on him.
Thanks, Senior.
Mikail Troikowicz, aka Christo.
This guy is believed to have been working
cocaine-for-weapons deals between the Russian Mafia,
the FARC guerrillas, and the Mexican drug cartels
ever since the late 1990s.
Now, before she was captured,
Morales was working a possible link
between our boy Christo and this guy Abu Shabal.
Glory to Allah, Lord of the world
who has created us as Muslims
and delivered us with the jihad on his direct path.
Peace be upon those who follow his direct path
to the Day of Judgment.
Let me explain this to you Americans.
We are not separatists.
We Chechens are not a legal part of anyone,
but you Americans are willingly
or unwillingly assisting
in the genocide of our people
by demanding that we obey certain rules
and by your continued occupation
of all Muslim countries.
With the grace of Allah,
glorious and exulted is he,
America will never be safe until safety becomes
a reality for us.
Allahu Akbar.
LT: Abu Shabal is a Chechen terrorist
who is associated with
the Beslan School Massacre. He's been jumping
between training camps in Indonesia
and the Philippines.
Now, the connection between Christo and Abu Shabal
is still a little bit fuzzy,
but if this was the lead that Morales was working on,
it could be why she was abducted.
- Senior? - This is a personnel recovery
of Miss Morales.
All right, who's got questions?
Senior Chief, you got any, uh, updated source intel
on numbers inside the camp, and what about roving patrols?
Maybe eight to ten, bro, but we don't know anything
about roving patrols. You just have to assume
they're out there walking around or squared away.
They do this for a living, too.
Senior, what kind of weapons- on-target are we looking at?
Heavy weapons.
These guys are narco-traffickers,
so they can have anything from Soviet-bloc DShKs.
They could have M2HP, .50-cals out there, we don't know,
so if there is a weapon supplacement up there,
I suggest you guys bring rockets.
Of course, rockets and foliage don't match,
so make sure you got a clear shot.
All right, what else?
Any idea whether she's ambulatory or not?
There was a ton of blood on the scene
and a lot of it was Mr. Ross'... we confirmed that.
Miss Morales may have blood there, too,
but these guys are savages,
so you have to assume she is non-ambulatory,
so you have to bring stuff to carry her out.
MAN: Two minutes to drop.
Hey, LT.
You got to let us know who that guy is,
so when we get back, we can kick his ass.
What guy?
The guy that gave you that fucked-up haircut.
Fuck.
RAY: Damn, Sonny, you should be the last guy to talk.
You look like the Dominican Mr. Clean.
SONNY: That means my head shines
like your gold teeth, huh?
RAY: Don't be like that...
Ramp!
RORKE: Mask up.
Man, I tell you what.
The only thing better than this right here
is being a dad,
except for that whole changing diaper thing,
but Sandy does that for me anyways, so...
I'm actually looking forward to it.
MAN: Blackbeard green light in ten.
Five.
Blackbeard Main, Blackbeard Main,
this is Blackbeard Actual. Radio check. Over.
this is Blackbeard Actual. Over.
: Roger, Actual. This is Main.
We have you Lima Charlie.
Roger, Main.
All boots are on the ground. I pass T-bird.
Any traffic for my station at this time?
Actual, imagery picked up an increase in traffic
at secondary location, known to be enemy QRF,
eight clicks from primary target.
The swift boats will insert
at 0600 for your extract. Out. Copy.
Roger, Main.
You ready?
Roger that, sir.
We got about 4.7 clicks at 355.
Take it out.
BLACKBEARD MAIN: Whiplash, one minute out.
BLACKBEARD MAIN: 3O seconds.
Ten by ten.
BLACKBEARD MAIN: Whiplash, go.
WHIPLASH: All boots on deck.
WHIPLASH: Line secure.
BLACKBEARD MAIN: Whiplash,
Bucket One and Two are out.
Whiplash, this is Blackbeard. Radio check. Over.
Blackbeard, Whiplash. Have you loud and clear.
Standing by on the set.
Roger, Whiplash.
What is your ETA to my pos?
WHIPLASH: ETA 20 mikes.
Be advised, Raven is in flight and pushing
to your location.
No mas, pot favor.
No!
Hey, sir, we got to go.
Roger. Take it out.
I feel like we're pretty thin.
I'd like to take you guys with us.
Chief, I got a SBT coming up on-step.
I got a Raven pushing my pause.
Weimy and I are in good watch position, and I got
to keep reporting back to Blackbeard Main.
- We're staying here. - Roger that.
Keep it tight.
Got it.
Whiplash, this is Blackbeard.
Assault force is moving to the target early.
Request immediate fire support.
Blackbeard, this is Whiplash. Good copy.
Request fire support.
Pushing to your location in 15 mikes.
Whiplash, this is Blackbeard.
I have positive control of the Raven.
Chief, are you set?
RORKE: Chief, Chief, hold. MAN: Juan!
Get back in there.
1:00, base of the tower. - Got him.
RORKE: You're clear to the door.
I've got two squirters coming out the back door.
Going in!
- Clear! - All clear!
Weimy, 11:00, driver's side, truck.
- Got him.
- Fuck.
- Come on. - DAVE: Go in! Go in!
Clear!
All clear!
Target's secure.
Chief, I'm going to get Mikey.
LT, this is Chief. Target is secure.
Stand by for confirmation of the package.
Be advised Mikey is down. Mikey is down.
Status to follow.
Roger. You have the package.
Chief, I got his cell phone.
LT? LT?
Chief, looks like you have two aggressor vehicles
approaching from the north, about one mike out.
You can take the truck outside the west door.
Meet us at extract.
Miss Morales, I'm bringing you home.
I just need to ask you a few questions.
What's your mother's maiden name?
Rosales.
What street you were born on? Hot Springs.
All right.
Just hang on.
RORKE: Whiplash, we have enemy QRF
approaching from the north.
Roger. You have enemy QRF
coming in from the north.
Chief, you need to start your exfil now.
- Meet at secondary extract. - Roger that.
Hey, boys, we got to roll!
Shit. Sir, there's trucks about 1,000 yards.
Yep.
Ma'am, I'm taking you out right now.
RAY: Took a round to the eye - an exit wound behind the ear.
He's alive, but we got to get moving now!
Weimy, coming out.
RORKE: We'll meet you at the rally point.
Let's go! Let's go! Move it!
- Fast moving trucks! - Right turn! Right turn!
We're not going to make it to secondary extract.
I got to find us a route, find this road.
Left, left, left, left, left.
Left turn! Left turn! Mikey, come on, buddy.
Hey, Chief!
We're not going to make secondary extract!
You're going to have to figure it out, man!
Hold on!
SONNY: Come on. Stay with me. Stay with me.
Stay with us.
Come on, Mike. Wake up. Wake up. Come on, man.
- We're on track! - I got him. I got him.
LT! We can make it to rally point!
Sounds good! Pass it to LT!
Come on, man.
LT, LT, this is assault team.
We just lost secondary extract.
I say it again, we just lost secondary extract.
Moving to rally point. Hard copy. Over.
- We're about a click out. - Mikey, wake up.
Drive like hell!
SONNY: Let's go, Mike. Wake up. Come on, buddy.
Come on, Mikey! Wake up!
- Got it? - Backstage clear.
- Rocket out!
He's not breathing. He's not breathing!
- Breathe, Mikey! - We're up! We're up!
Chief, let me get your M-4!
Sir, what's the status on those boats?
I lost Whiplash on the run.
Told him you hit the target early.
They're coming in hot.
Roger that.
SONNY: Fuck, take this, man.
Breathe, Mikey. Come on, Mikey.
- I got no pulse. - Car attack rear!
Car attack rear!
- Car! - Holy shit! Taking rounds in...
Pick it up. Pick it up.
DAVE: Ajay!
QRS coming up the rear!
Whiplash! Whiplash! Secondary extract is burnt.
Moving to tertiary extract.
I have eight packs, seven Sierras, one package.
: Package with multiple wounds.
The Sierra has a gunshot wound to the head.
This will be a hot extract.
What the fuck?!
- Shit! Mikey, stay down!
- Keep him down, man! - Where the fuck am I?!
Calm down, brother.
Mikey's up, man. Mikey's up.
Stay down, brother. Calm.
Be easy. We're almost out of here.
We're almost out of here.
"- Mikey!
- Hang on, buddy. - Where are we?
- On our way to extract. - What happened?
You're good to go. You took one to the face. You're a hard motherfucker.
- Did we get her? - Yes.
- Oh, my God. - We're on our way to extract.
Ajay, splash it. Splash it.
Water! Water! Water!
Going in! Going in!
I got her! I got her!
Out!
Get the fuck out!
It wasn't for nothing.
You know, from time to time,
I get to see my old friends from my old life.
And it's always, always disappointing.
Some become assholes, or they're boring,
and I can't believe I tried to get them in bed
all those years ago.
Hey.
It is nice not to be disappointed, Yuri.
That's not my name.
I know.
Mohammed Abu Shabal, the son of Shabal.
Come on.
Your father's name is Yevgeny. Things change.
Yeah, things have changed.
That's why this is the last time
we might see each other for quite some time.
For I might have to find a hole to hide in.
I don't understand.
I'm being watched by the CIA,
and I'm not taking any chances.
As soon as the opportunity presents itself,
I'm taking my family south.
I don't have the energy to fight the Americans.
What about our deal, Mikhail?
My men have been training for almost a year now.
I have devoted much of my resources...
The deal stands, Yuri.
Just because I've taken early retirement doesn't mean
I'm not holding up my end of the bargain.
There is so much to be done.
And it will be, just without me.
You'll have to use my trusted associates.
That's not so good for me.
- Hey... - Hey! Shut up! Shut up!
Stop your fucking bullshit!
It's not good. Doesn't work.
You can't change it like that.
Nothing changes. Nothing.
You just told me everything's changed.
What-what is that? What is that?
Do you know what I do to get here?!
Do you know the men I had to sacrifice to get here?!
Do you have any idea?!
No, you shit! You live up here in this ivory tower!
You have no... you don't care!
Hey, Chief, what's the status on Mikey?
He's definitely gonna lose the eye,
but he's-he's hanging tough.
Hey, I'm gonna get right into this.
Great job smoke-checking those assholes
and getting Morales back.
It's a bum deal for Mikey, but that was solid work.
So, Chief, you get that down to the boys right away.
- You hear me? - Check.
All right. Now, Morales,
Morales was one tough chick, but she should've
gotten this stuff up the chain a lot faster
because this thing is way bigger than we thought.
How is that?
I thought this was a cut-and-dry AMSED recovery.
Yeah, it was until we got into that phone
that you guys picked up in that shit-hole.
It turned me on to something
that just does not look right at all.
And what's not right about it?
Christo and Shabal are a lot closer
than I thought they were,
and Shabal is a wild card, man.
He is an old-school Jihadi
that couldn't give a rat's ass about money or drugs.
And his childhood friend, Christo, the dope dealer?
He is not a dealer, man.
He's a smuggler.
You have got to be kidding me.
That is exactly what I'm thinking.
Shabal wants to kill Americans.
Christo knows how to get fuckers inside America.
This could be big trouble in little China, fellas.
They're gonna hit us at home.
I just got done talking to the boss
and the Spec OP's Task Force,
and this is what's gonna go down.
I need Ajay and Ray standing by
to launch for an SR in two hours.
They're gonna get some frequent flyer miles on the way to Africa.
Why Africa?
We pinned an airfield there with that phone that you got,
and I think that Shabal is gonna be there
doing a weapons transfer on his way west.
When you say "west," what are we talking about?
- Mexico west? - Yeah, Mexico west.
That's worst-case scenario.
You two and the of the platoon are gonna stay here on standby.
You'll be the primary assault force
in case something goes down anywhere near America.
- Check. - Check.
You gonna be around for questions as they come up?
No, man.
Christa" he pulled a Roman Polanski
on my ass and disappeared.
So I'm gonna link up with Seal Team Four,
and we're gonna hunt his ass down in the South Pacific.
So it's straight up Mai Tais and palm trees for me, baby.
Yeah, brother. Go get him.
- You be cool. - Take it easy.
Good luck with that baby, Lieutenant.
Does everybody know?
Only the important people.
The important people to who? You?
I guess so.
I'm gonna go brief the boys.
Hey, hold on one second.
Hey, brother, I've never written one of these before.
Hey, I'm tracking with you, sir. I am.
But to be honest with you,
I was thinking of calling the command
and trying to get you home.
But now that work's picked up so much,
I feel like we really need you here.
You remember our last cruise to Al Ambar? Yeah.
When you had that final turnover op
and you said I didn't need to be there?
I was laying in bed and I realised
the only thing I needed to do now was go home.
But if something went south on your op,
I would always regret not being there with you.
I appreciate you taking care of me big-time, Dave,
but I'm working some things with the brass.
If I can, and things slow down,
I'm gonna get two weeks off.
Well, I hope it works out either way.
I really do.
But if it doesn't,
I'm gonna take this piece of paper,
and I'm gonna make it into a nice paper airplane.
Beat it.
We're good, we're good!
Chief to Watch, submerge to one-six-zero feet.
Dive. Dive.
Scope down.
All doors are green.
- Oh, good. Hey, guys. - Sir.
Thank you for getting here so fast.
- Grab a seat, please. - Thank you.
You'll have Bulldog overhead.
We need you to get in, grab the intel
and bounce it back to us.
Do you have any questions?
Sir, I have a question.
We have the rally point and time.
What if the meeting doesn't take place as scheduled?
How long do you want us to stay on target?
Now, this one counts,
so I'd plan on being out there for a while.
- Check. - Are we good?
- Think so, sir. - Yes, sir.
MAN: Ray and Ajay are rigged up
and ready to check each other out.
Garage door clear.
- You got a visual? - Yeah.
Got three trucks moving in...
a fuel truck, two jeeps,
some skinnies in the back.
One of them has a 50-cal.
You hear that?
Yeah, I think that's our plane.
Yeah, we got some inbound.
'Bout time these guys showed up.
Jesus. Let me get my camera.
Ray, we got two birds at the end of the field
southeast our pos,
no tail I.D.'s.
You got that? Check, no tail I.D.'s.
MAN: Allah akbar!
Ray, last time I checked, we were in Africa, right?
Yeah. Why, what's up?
Dude, there's, like, 16 Filipinos down there,
all praying to Mecca right now.
- Filipinos? - Filipinos.
Definitely not skinnies.
I'm picking up the praying.
I'm also picking up some Russian.
RAY: Bulldog, Bulldog,
Redrum, radio check, oven MAN: Good check, copy.
Roger, good check. Be advised, we got two sterile aircraft
departing to the east for the following location:
Ten, Papa, Lima Sierra.
Please advise when tally target, over. Roget
Copy, two aircraft,
location Ten, Papa...
RORKE: Hey, Chief, you are not gonna believe this.
One of the planes Ray and Ajay tagged
just landed on Cedros Island
off the Mexican coast.
It has Shabal on it with an unknown number of Jihadis.
Are you kidding me?
No, looks like we're gonna get to hit that target.
Well, Senior and the swift boats are punching out.
They should pull more intel for us, so we'll see.
All right.
I don't know how long we're staying.
Hold on, baby.
- Be safe. - You know I will.
I got to go, honey. Love you.
I love you.
BLACKBEARD MAIN: Bravo Alpha, we're 200m out.
Bravo, you have a tango on your starboard side.
BRAVO ALPHA: Tango on the starboard side.
BLACKBEARD MAIN: Whiskey Charlie, we have
a visual on tango.
BLACKBEARD MAIN: Bravo, you have a viper at 12:00.
Get down! Get down!
Clear!
Bridge secure.
MAN: Senior, you're clear.
- English okay? - English is fine.
Can you cut him loose, please?
If you get cut loose,
you're not going to do anything crazy, are you?
Crazy Ivan? So to speak.
So you're Russian, yeah? Yes, I am.
You all right?
Yes, I'm good. Thank you. You're welcome.
I'm sorry. I don't know your name.
- I'm Otto. - Otto.
- Yes. And you are? - Nice to meet you.
Christo.
- Crisco? - Christo.
Troskawicz?
Hey, brother, we need to make this hit count
because the lieutenant commander
will be working at the White House.
Oh, man. Did you carry his football?
He better let me carry that thing.
No kidding, man. You know what?
Either way, that's gonna be
quality time with your new family, bro.
Yeah, I know it's gonna be a good career move,
but I'll be a PowerPoint commando from here on out
as opposed to shooting bad guys with you.
Yeah, well, you were never that good an operator anyway.
Come on, man, you know you suck. - Yeah.
Come on. Hey.
Come on, come on, man.
You're sitting on a wonderful boat.
- It's fabulous. - Thank you. Yes.
I believe it's called Starship.
"Starship." I love the way you say Starship.
It's like Russian. That guy, uh... "Star Trek."
What's his name, Scotty? Oh, he was... sorry... Scot.
- I wouldn't know. - You've never seen "Star Trek"?
- No. - Oh, that's insane.
- So here's the problem, pal. - Mm-hmm?
You're worth a lot of money.
Or you were worth a lot of money.
I believe I still am. - You do? - Yes.
All right.
Let me tell you how the world works there, Crisco.
- It's Christo. - Sorry?
- Christo. - Oh, of course. Sorry.
Let me tell you how the world really works.
- Please. - This is no longer your boat.
Since I walked through that door,
you're not the same guy you used to be.
You're just not.
There's nothing I can do to stop that,
nothing I can do to help you right now,
unless you let me help you.
We need to do this together, pal... you and me.
So how is it that you're working
with these, uh, Jihadi folks, then?
You're Jewish, right?
Shabal is what?
You got a friend, like, you grew up with?
- Sorry? - Have you ever had
a friend that you grew up with?
- Yes. - Had interests like soccer,
or... what would you play? Baseball, probably, right?
- Probably. Yeah. - Yeah.
And then you went on your separate ways,
and then some years later, you meet up,
and you totally didn't recognise the person.
And that's what happened with Shabal.
We share a common interest.
So he came up with this incredible idea
because of his beliefs.
I don't necessarily share his beliefs,
but he's a smart guy.
You know, it's almost like...
you know, it's almost like... like this is me.
And that's Shabal.
Is it?
And America is in between. - Is it? - Yeah.
Cool concept, no?
- Right here? - Yes.
You think this is some kind of game?
Do you? Do you find this amusing?
No. No. I'm not finding...
Do you realise what you're doing here?
Blackbeard Actual,
this is Blackbeard Main.
Post nation counterpart. Secured target Bravo.
Report to Tri Hole.
You're clear to move on target Alpha.
Roger, Main. Clear to target.
The only people I answer to is my family.
To my wife and to my child.
And nobody else.
Running late somewhere? Shit filter's full.
- Really? - Yeah.
So here's the problem, pal.
You do love your family, don't you? Yes, I do.
And what about your daughter?
What about my daughter?
Are you looking forward to seeing her again?
Every minute of my life.
I wanted you to see that
so you'd think about some things very seriously,
because you're gonna be sitting in a box somewhere.
You'll be treated properly
and humanely.
That girl is gonna grow up,
and she's gonna get married,
and your wife is gonna find someone else,
and you're gonna miss everything.
If I had done something
that would endanger my family,
I would feel just like you do right now.
You promise not to touch my family?
I would never touch your family.
I would not.
Are you familiar with...
ceramic ball bearings?
No.
Just imagine 16 suicide vests
filled with those ceramic ball bearings,
slipping by every metal detector
and every checkpoint in your country.
You think your economy is fucked now?
Just think what the media is gonna do with this.
Hmm? It's gonna make 9/11 look like
a fucking walk in the park.
The Grand Central Park.
So you're telling me...
there's 16 Jihadis
wearing suicide vests.
They're gonna walk right across the border.
So where are they going?
San Diego, San Francisco, Houston...
you pick a city, they'll be there.
And this is happening now?
It's happening as we speak.
Sorry, what?
How can you stop this?
I can't.
Blackbeard Lead,
containment element is set. Roget
Gun! Gun! Gun!
- Clear! - Go.
- Coming out!
Rat Pack, this is Blackbeard.
We're in contact, midtown south of the church.
AJAY: Walker!
DAVE: Ajay!
Blackbeard Lead, what's your pos?
RORKE: Over watch. Clear to engage.
Going hot.
Frag out!
Weimy, I've got two squirters
heading south in a pickup truck.
I see 'em.
Get those two guys in the truck.
Rocket!
Frag out!
Sir? Sir?
LT? You all right?
Damn.
You checked that box, huh? Yeah.
Good thing that was a dud.
I might've gotten hurt. Yeah.
Whoa.
Jesus.
This is not some bush-league vest
from an Iraqi hut.
This is some high-speed shit.
Maybe we should put this somewhere else, huh?
Hey, Sonny, find somewhere to put this, would you?
Target secure.
Set security.
One's to the north, three south.
Hey, Chief, target's buttoned up.
- Everything's secure. - Thanks, man.
LYONS: Actual, mission not complete.
Stand by for follow on.
You only got half that Jihadist cell.
- The target's secure, sir. - This fight isn't over yet.
LYONS: Now, listen,
the other half of that cell will be crossing the border
using a tunnel network from Mexicali at 0700.
We're coordinating with State,
but for now the birds will drop you off
outside the city where your POC is a Commander Pedros.
I'll give you more details en route.
Actual, how do you copy? Roger, Main.
Okay, we've got a helo landing on the deck.
We're gonna meet a Mexican SOF commander and his team.
They're gonna help infill us into the target
and join us on the assault.
What the hell are you talking about?
We haven't got all of 'em yet, Chief.
- Where's the rest of 'em? - In Mexicali on the border.
All right. And the rest of the boys,
how are they getting back to the ship?
Bon Homme Richard stayed on station.
They're gonna send in the Marine element
to help exploit the target.
When they're done, the boys will pull off with them.
Okay. I'm thinking Squad One and myself roll out.
Perfect. Squad Two stays here, buttons it up.
- Pulls out with the Marines. - Okay.
We're moving north up here through town.
We're crossing at sunrise.
Your other group will get to Texas the following day.
No bodies.
Comprendes?
Hey, sir!
Who the hell cleared us hot
to go to Mexicali anyway?
This one's going all the way up the flagpole.
State Department's on it.
Hey, sir.
Channel two.
Hey, this tempo keeps up like this,
Jackie's gonna be squeezing that kid out on her own.
However, we hit this target quick enough,
you jump on a burro and ride that shit home.
Hey, I ain't gonna need no burro.
Did you get your two weeks?
All that time I was spending on the SAT phone,
it wasn't to convince them to let me go home.
It was to convince them to leave your ass in charge.
- Sir. - Lieutenant.
Seems our governments have been very busy
to make this possible, huh?
All the way to the top, from what I've heard.
There is something that you have to understand.
My superiors, they're very fearful
of a Mexican Mogadishu.
No Black Hawk Down is what they're saying,
so we do need to stay under the radar.
- I understand completely, sir. - Good.
Your team's presence here is greatly appreciated.
But we are out of time.
- We need to move. - Tell me where, we go.
Help piece this together for me.
- Go ahead. - Our intel says
they're using a tunnel network
that is under a milk factory.
This mean anything to you?
I know exactly where that is.
It's not far from here.
Then that's where we're going.
Of all of the places in Mexicali
you could have picked, this is probably the worst.
The cartels control that area from all angles.
They have us heavily outgunned.
Simply reaching your target will be very difficult.
Sir, we have eight foreign nationals
heading to our country.
Needless to say, they are no big fan of ours.
If they're at that factory, that's where we're going.
Lieutenant, I'll take you anywhere you need to go,
but prepare your men for a bigger fight than you imagined.
You're not fighting eight men.
You're also fighting the cartel protecting them.
If your targets make it into those tunnels,
they'll disappear like ghosts.
You enter the tunnels right here.
You will walk seven miles to this fork.
My men will tell you what tunnel to take.
Once you get to this point,
my job is done.
You're on your own.
Lieutenant, we're going now! Roger that.
Chief, we're not stopping.
We're rolling up on target hard.
Roger that, sir.
We're about 30 seconds out.
RORKE: One mike out from the south entrance.
Jefe! On the roof!
We got to go. Now.
Sir!
- Leave two men here!
Weimy!
I need you to lock this shit down!
Frag out!
On me.
You guys got the gate!
Call! You're going to the front door!
Go!
Call!
Ajay!
Bomb...!
Damn it, sir.
How you gonna explain that one to my family?
Get back there so I don't have to, huh?
Clear!
Grenade...!
LT!
Chief, I got him.
Keep going. I'll cover you.
Chief.
DAVE: Who are you?
Chief!
Assault Two, this is Assault One.
Be advised, tunnel is secure
and all threats are neutralised.
LT and Chief are down.
I say again,
DAVE: Your father was a good man.
Growing up without him is gonna be hard.
It's gonna hurt.
You'll feel alone, out to sea,
with no shore in sight.
Remember, you have your father's blood
in your veins.
The code that made your father
who he was is the same code
that'll make you a man.
Your father's will, his values, live on in you.
Like those people in the paintings your father liked,
we are men made up of boxes,
chambers of loss and triumph,
of hurt and hope and love.
Ready! Aim!
Aim!
DAVE: No one's stronger than a man
who can harness his emotions and his past.
Use it as motivation to write
the most important letter of your life.
Lieutenant Engel!
ALL: Boo-yah, Lieutenant Engel!
DAVE: Before he died, your father
asked me to give you this poem by Tecumseh,
a man he greatly admired.
I told him I'd fold it into a paper airplane.
And I guess that's what I'm doing,
sailing it from him to you.
"Live your life that the fear of death
"can never enter your heart.
"Trouble no one about his religion...
DAVE AND RORKE: "Respect others and their views,
"and demand they respect yours.
"Love your life.
"Perfect your life...
RORKE: "Beautify all things in your life.
"Seek to make your life long
"and of service to your people.
"When your time comes to die, "be not like those
whose hearts are filled with fear of death,
"so that when their time comes they weep and pray
"for a little more time to live their lives
"over again in a different way.
"Sing your death song.
"And die like a hero going home."