Peanuts! Roasted!
Freshly roasted!
Get your peanuts!
Roasted! Red hot!
Hot peanuts!
Red hots! How about
some red hot peanuts?
Peanuts!
Get your peanuts here!
Go, go, go, go!
Safe!
Now batting
for the Cardinals,
number 14, Stanley Boyer.
Come on!
We missed four innings.
Well, like I said,
I had to stop
and do some business.
Here, sit down.
Hey, you, usher, come here.
Can I talk to you a second?
Yes, sir.
Can you watch him?
Sure, no problem.
I'll be back.
Gil, this is Stan.
He's gonna watch you
for a while.
I have some friends
I'm meeting.
I'll meet you right here, huh?
For the ninth inning.
Have fun, kid.
Programs here!
Get your programs! Programs!
So, Gilly,
big baseball fan?
Kind of.
Yeah?
Dad bring you here a lot?
Once a year on my birthday.
Then he pays an usher
to watch me.
Oh, I see.
Look, you have
to understand.
My father,
in his own childhood,
was without
a positive male influence.
Huh?
His own father
kicked him out
when he was 15,
so my Dad was taught
to see child-raising
as a job, a burden,
a prison,
rather than a playground.
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
You don't talk like a kid.
Yeah, well,
I'm not really a kid.
You're not a duck.
This is a memory
of when I was a kid.
I'm 35 now.
I have kids of my own.
You don't really
even exist.
You're an amalgam.
A what?
A combination
of several ushers my dad
left me with over the years.
I've combined them
into one memory.
Why?
This was a great
symbolic moment
of my life,
my father dumping me
with you.
It's why I swore
things would be
different with my kids.
That's my dream.
Strong, happy,
confident kids.
That's great. That's great.
You know,
you got a lovely family,
and I'm a goddamn amalgam.
Gil?
Who's that?
That's my wife.
Nice.
Gil.
Yeah?
The game's over, honey.
The St. Louis
Cardinals wish to thank you
for attending today's game.
Please drive home
safely and soberly.
Let's go!
Come on, Justin.
You want to walk?
Come on, let's walk.
It's fun.
You sure
you don't want to walk?
There we go.
I'll get it. I'll get it.
There's your pennant.
There you go.
I got him.
All right?
Yes.
Come on, watch it,
watch it, watch it.
There you go.
Watch the car.
Watch it.
There's so many cars.
Here you go.
Here you go. Down?
Where is that kid?
Where is she?
Daddy!
Oh, there she is.
There she is.
All right, come on,
go inside. Grab a seat.
Buckle up.
Honey. Taylor!
You're a rat.
You're a rat!
When you're sliding into first
And you're feeling
something burst
Diarrhea
When you're sliding into third
And you lay a juicy turd
Diarrhea
When you're sliding
into home
And your shorts
are full of foam
Diarrhea
When you're sitting
in your Chevy
And your shorts
are feeling heavy
Diarrhea
Kevin, honey,
where'd you learn that song?
Last summer
at camp, Mom.
Ah! That was money
well spent.
When you're sliding into first
And you're feeling
something burst
Diarrhea
That's what you're
gonna sleep in?
You'll get cold.
Perfect.
Gil, Taylor isn't
feeling well.
She wants you.
It's those hot dogs.
I'll deal
with Kevin and Justin.
Hey, what do you say later,
when the kids are asleep,
I wear this outfit?
She's in our bed.
Hi, Daddy.
What's the matter, honey?
You don't feel so good?
Mmm-mmm.
You feel like
you wanna throw up?
Okay.
Gil.
Oh, my God.
Oh, Taylor, baby.
Oh, sweetie.
Gil, why are you
just standing there?
Oh, sweetie!
I'm waiting for her head
to spin around.
You'll be all right.
You'll be okay.
Oh, can you
come with me
to see Kevin's principal
on Monday morning?
Oh, boy. I love it
when you talk to me
about school and meetings.
Now talk to me
about shopping.
No, I know. I know.
Go on, go on.
I'm sorry. I just
remembered now. I've been
meaning to ask you, okay?
Fine. I'll be there.
Okay.
What's the matter?
Nothing. I was
a little tense before
but now...
No, no. I mean with Kevin.
Why are we going
to see his principal?
Oh, because his teacher said
he's been making
that face again.
What? This?
Yes. The tense face.
He makes that same face
at Little League.
You know what
his teacher asked me?
What?
If we'd ever taken him
for a psychiatric evaluation.
What?
She was just asking.
Why, because
he makes a face?
Has she ever
looked in the mirror?
You know, the face,
the crying, the nervousness.
They mentioned
the crying?
Yeah. You know,
he doesn't really
finish his work.
Hey, we'll talk to them
on Monday. Don't worry,
I'm sure it'll be fine.
Come here.
Where was I?
Here? Was I here?
Yeah, yeah.
I was there already?
Mmm-hmm.
You know,
that really pisses me off.
Kid's a little different,
a little special,
needs a little more attention,
teacher's gonna put
a label on him.
"Problem kid."
When we go see
Kevin's principal,
let's find out
who his teacher is
gonna be next year
and make sure it's not
one of these hysterics!
You're right, Gil. You know,
Kevin's great. He can't be
that much of a problem.
Right. Now, if it was
my sister's kid...
Garry.
Now, there's a kid
with problems.
Hi, Garry!
You're up so early!
Yeah.
Where are you going?
Out.
What's in the bag?
Nothing.
Garry, you know,
the whole family's
coming over tonight.
There's a big surprise.
Grandma and Grandpa
are gonna be here,
and Uncle Gil and Aunt Karen,
they're bringing their kids.
Aunt Susie's gonna be here,
and Uncle Nathan,
their kids and... It was
nice talking to you.
Julie!
Hey, Julie!
Yeah?
Julie, can I come in
for a minute?
Yeah.
Julie, I really need
your help. The whole
family's coming over tonight.
I don't know why,
but the place is a mess.
Could you just
give me a hand?
Yeah, okay,
in just a few minutes.
Are you all right?
I thought I heard you
moaning last night.
Well, I kind of had
a little bit of a
stomachache,
but it's fine now.
It's gone.
You hate me?
What?
You know, for making you
study so much
and giving up all your dates.
No, you were right.
Honey, I'm telling you,
those SAT scores
are your ticket.
And, sweetie, you know,
once you get to school,
you're gonna meet a lot
of guys that you like
just as well as that Tod.
Why do you always say
"that Tod"?
It just sounds so...
You're right. I'm sorry.
It's been pleasant
for a moment.
Okay, I guess I'm just gonna
give everybody
spaghetti and salad,
and I better cook
a steak for my dad.
See you later, honey.
Are you okay?
Man, your mother can talk!
Gosh, she hates my ass.
And it's such
a cute ass.
Last night, she heard
the moaning.
She thought it was me.
Yeah?
Mmm-hmm.
So you're gonna have to try
and control yourself, Tod.
With you? It's impossible.
Wait.
What?
I brought something.
Ooh! Good.
We can record our love.
Susan. Hi, Sis, it's Helen.
Yeah, did I loan you
my big platter?
Oh, great, great.
Yeah, I thought so.
Would you
bring it over tonight?
I just need it to serve.
Oh, listen,
Julie got 1,291 on her SATs.
I know. I know.
I feel so proud of her.
It's great.
Yeah. How's Patty?
We're a little disappointed
with the effort
she's been giving lately
towards her work.
Math, French,
everything's gone down.
Nathan's talking to her
right now. He's trying
to figure out what's wrong.
Look, Patty,
all I'm saying is,
if you wanna have
just an ordinary
academic career
and attend
an ordinary university,
that's your prerogative,
but I must tell you
I think you're
selling yourself way short.
How's it going?
I don't know. Sometimes I feel
as though we want it
more than she does.
Patty, you know
we love you.
Could you just give
your father that little
extra effort he's looking for?
Okay, Mama.
That's all I ask.
Come on, Kevin.
I got you.
I want that, Kevin.
I want that!
No.
Kevin! Taylor!
No!
Time to come in
now, children.
Okay.
Okay, Grandma.
Hey, hey, you wanna...
Come on, I don't believe it.
Gil, you have a good memory.
Was it yours or Helen
or Susan's wedding
I got drunk at?
It was all three, Dad.
Congratulations.
Well, which one did I
punch the bandleader?
That was mine.
We have photos.
I'm having them blown up
for the commitment hearings.
You think he's funny, huh?
When he was a kid,
he wasn't this funny.
Stayed in his room all day.
Boy, you were a moody
little son of a bitch.
Gee, I wonder why?
Do you remember
that little guy
who wouldn't leave my side?
I know.
Well, now, you know,
if I take a step towards him,
he just takes a step away.
I don't know
what's happening to him,
you know.
He's just so unhappy
and he won't talk to me,
and I don't know
how to help him.
Did you ever consider
having Ed talk to him?
Are you kidding?
He won't even acknowledge
he's got these kids,
now that he's got his new wife
and his new kids!
He won't even fix
my kids' teeth anymore.
He says it makes him
uncomfortable.
Please.
Yeah, I wish
he'd drop his drill
down his pants.
Are you seeing anybody?
Well, Garry's biology teacher
asked me out.
Biology? That's promising.
No, no, no, no.
He's not the type
I usually go for.
"The Penal Colony
by Franz Kafka."
Hey, Nathan,
Patty a doctor yet?
Mock if you will.
All right.
Our children are more capable
of retaining and absorbing
information than we are,
and yet we insist
on treating them
like adorable little morons.
What are you saying,
Patty can learn things
I can't learn?
Patty, which one of these
is the square root of 8,649?
Ninety-three.
They're like sponges, Gil,
just waiting to absorb.
I want this.
You see?
Take my advice. Forget about
Kevin and Taylor.
It's too late. Work on Justin.
Actually, Justin is quite
bright. In his preschool
class, he was the only...
Slow down, Justin.
I'll get you some dip.
Oh, you remember that guy
you went out with in college?
Jeffrey Sanders?
You know, you always chased me
out of the room
whenever he came over.
Oh, yeah.
I saw him today.
God, what a loser, huh?
In a Rolls.
I meant me.
What is that?
Oh, Nathan and Patty and I
are power-eating.
We bring our own
food everywhere.
He turned me onto it,
and I never felt better.
Where do you
get that stuff?
This is it.
Everybody in the living room.
This is the big surprise.
Okay, Frank.
Oh, Larry. My baby.
You look great.
Dad!
How are you, son?
Oh, boy.
Great to see you!
Shit.
Well put.
Who's that?
Wait a second,
I've got something for you.
That's my kid brother
Larry. Your uncle.
Don't give him
any money.
I won't.
Just a little something
for being the best dad
in the world.
I found it
a couple of months ago.
It's for your collection.
A toy car!
Oh, this is great.
A Stutz!
Yeah, you got it.
Spend it on
the people you love,
right?
Is this Grandma?
Yeah, she's still alive.
Jesus, Grandma,
you got short.
I'm shrinking.
Bummer.
Gilbo.
Larry.
How long has it been?
Three years?
About that.
You stopped
wearing your turban.
Yeah.
My God, Susan, you look great.
If you weren't my sister...
Helen, I know
it's been hard.
Dad?
You were supposed
to wait outside
so I could introduce you.
Well, why don't you
do it now, Larry?
Everybody,
this is my son Cool.
Did he say, "Cool"?
Cool.
Your son?
It's a long story.
- Let's eat.
- Yeah, well, good idea.
Keep Patty
away from my brother.
He'll suck the intelligence
right out of her.
Cool is adorable. Adorable.
Why didn't you ever
write us you had a son?
I didn't know myself
until a couple of months ago.
You see, a few years ago,
I was living in Vegas
with this girl.
Showgirl. She was
in that show Elvis on Ice.
Anyhow, we drifted apart
as people do
in these complicated times,
and then
a couple of months ago,
she shows up with Cool,
tells me, "You watch him.
I shot someone.
I have to leave the country."
That's a parent?
Anyway,
we're back in town because
I've got something
really huge cooking.
Enormo. Monster.
Dad, this is it!
From now on,
I'm going to be
taking care of all of you.
This isn't another
get-rich-quick scheme,
is it, Larry?
What's wrong
with getting rich quick?
Quick is the best way
to get rich.
Look who I'm talking to.
Did you ever see
her family?
They find a nickel,
they huddle together
and bury it like squirrels.
What's the deal, son?
What do you have going?
Has anyone heard
of hydroponics?
Well, that's great, Larry.
Hydroponics is the growing
of plants without soil.
It's very exciting.
What are you using?
Coarse sand
or suspension hydroponics?
I don't...
There's a guy with glasses
and a lab coat
that makes that decision.
I make the deal.
And I got to thinking.
Cool's had no kind of life,
no family,
so while I'm locking
this thing down,
I thought it'd be nice
if we stayed with you.
With us?
Couple of weeks.
The thing is, Larry, we don't
have the big house anymore,
you know?
We didn't need it.
We just have
the one bedroom for us
and one for Grandma.
Well, Grandma's welcome
to stay with us for a while.
I think it'd be valuable
for Patty to have
a multigenerational influence.
Fine with me.
Well, I'll have to give you
a list of the medications,
and when and how much,
and you'll have to
pick up her shower chair.
There's the batteries for
her hearing aid, magnifying
glass for reading...
Oh, jeez.
What happened?
Your mouth used up
all the power.
Don't worry, Dad,
we can still find the bar.
- I'll get a flashlight.
- - I'll get it, Sis.
Mom, Dad,
what happened?
Where is it?
In the bedroom?
It's in the nightstand.
Mom, Dad,
what happened?
I'm getting a flashlight.
Kevin. Kevin!
You know I don't
like it in the dark.
Honey,
this is a blackout.
It's a temporary interruption
in the electrical supply
of the home.
It's okay, honey.
Something's busted.
Relax.
Where's the switch?
Does this look
like my house?
Here. Bring it here.
Oh, here it is.
What is this?
Mommy, what was that?
That was
an electric ear cleaner.
It was kind of big.
It sure was.
I mean, I don't think
you really
have to worry about it.
The point is that once
they see us, then they'll
realize that we're fine,
and the kid is fine,
and it's not something...
Gil.
Karen.
I think we're going to
have to be very careful
about Kevin's
educational environment.
Absolutely.
With that in mind,
I don't think Kevin should
come back here next fall.
I'm going to recommend
that he be transferred
to a school
that offers special
education classes.
You mean because
he's so smart?
Actually, I mean a class
for children
with emotional problems.
Hi. I'm sorry I'm late.
You must be the Buckmans.
I'm Dr. Jeffrey Lucas.
Dr. Lucas is
a child psychologist.
He's been observing Kevin
for the last couple of months.
Why?
Mr. Buckman,
this is a public school.
Thirty-eight kids
to a class.
We estimate
that Kevin's teacher
spends at least
20%. of her time
dealing with Kevin.
That class is going to
finish the year behind.
It isn't fair.
Kevin is
a very sweet, very sensitive,
extremely tense little boy.
He needs
some special attention.
It's 'cause
he was first.
Mmm?
It's because
he was our first.
I mean, I think
we were very tense
when Kevin was little.
If he got a scratch,
we were hysterical.
By the third kid, you know,
you let them juggle knives.
On the other hand,
Kevin may have been like this
in the womb.
Recent studies indicate
that these things
are all chemical.
She smoked grass.
Gil! I never smoked
when I was pregnant.
Yeah, but in college,
you were like a chimney.
I thought
you were gonna join
a reggae band.
Fifteen years ago.
I'm just saying
there could've been
some chromosome distortions.
Well, you let them do
anything. You let them
watch TV just like that.
So we'll throw the TVs out.
We'll put the TVs
in the garbage, then,
and you and I,
we'll perform works
from Shakespeare or some...
I'm sorry.
I'm just a little
thrown off by this.
Gil. Karen.
You should not look upon
the fact that Kevin will be
going to a special school
as any kind of failure
on your part.
No, I'll blame the dog.
In an educational environment
that's more sensitive
to his needs...
All right, look. First of all,
Kevin is not going
to a special school.
Whether it's right or not,
there's a stigma.
People are cruel,
especially children,
and I won't subject Kevin
to that kind of cruelty.
If we have to,
we'll send him
to a private school.
I don't care what it costs.
I'll get a second job.
Mr. and Mrs. Buckman,
this is a problem
that won't just go away.
Well, if we need to,
we'll send Kevin
to a private therapist.
That's right.
Look, it's a problem.
We're aware of it,
but we're his parents.
We can handle it.
Well,
the next school year is
four months off, so
let's see
what can be accomplished.
Thank you.
No! Tod. Tod!
I need to see.
No, not in the street.
Please. Please.
What is this?
It's the party celebrating
my mother's promotion
at the bank.
Give me that.
Excuse me.
This is the wrong batch.
This is my mother's.
There should be
another envelope for Buckman.
Okay.
That was picked up already.
By who?
Huh.
Hmm.
I think this one
is my favorite.
This is just...
It was just for fun, Mom.
Well, I'm glad
to know it's not a job.
That's that Tod, isn't it?
There's one where
you can see his face.
Is that what bothers you?
That I did those things
or that I did them with Tod?
Gee whiz, Julie,
there's so many things
that bother me about this.
I don't know
how to separate them.
Oh!
Ooh! Here's something
for my wallet.
Tod is very important to me.
And we've got
the pictures to prove it.
Mom!
This is your room.
You did these things
right here in my house?
Well, I thought
someone in this house
ought to be having sex.
I mean, with something
that doesn't
require batteries.
What did you say to me?
God damn it,
you get back here!
Open this door,
God damn it to hell!
I would just like
a little respect!
Not a lot! Just a little!
Do you know why I'm having sex
with machinery?
Because your father left
to have a party, and I
stayed to raise two kids.
I have no life! God damn it!
What are you doing?
I'm leaving
before we say things
we'll regret.
You're gonna say
something worse
than the battery remark?
Tod and I are in love.
It's not "going steady"
love, it's love.
I need him.
He's my life.
He touches me, and I quiver.
Oh, would you give me
just a small break?
See? You can't handle it.
Tod's working now.
We'll find a place
to live somewhere.
Hi, Garry.
Hi.
I'm moving out, Garry.
Bye.
See? You've upset
your brother!
Julie,
I'm telling you,
if you walk out of this house
against my wishes,
don't ever think
about coming back here.
Fine.
Julie!
Honey.
Honey, I'm always here
if you need me.
Sweetheart!
Honey, be careful.
If you want anything,
just call me!
Julie!
Bye.
Oh, man.
lncredible.
Just incredible.
I knew you'd be the one
who'd appreciate this.
Three years, every night,
every weekend.
I had dinner out here!
You know,
it was a piece of junk
when I found it.
First time I got laid
was in a car like this.
Frank!
What?
Cool just finished lunch.
I'll call the newspaper.
I thought you and Larry
could take him somewhere.
I am showing Larry my car.
Just plop him down
in front of the TV.
That's what he
always does.
Wasn't that Super Bowl
incredible right down
to the last minute?
Amazing.
They're usually
not that close, huh?
Oh, no.
No, that's right,
and usually
the winning team
covers the point spread.
Usually
you can count on it.
Take a beating?
No, thanks.
I already took one.
Anyway, I had to pay off,
and it's left me a little...
What do you need?
Come on, don't insult me.
I didn't come here
to be insulted.
Come on. Come on.
Putting together a deal,
you got to look like you can
piss with the big boys.
You see? You know.
How much?
Couple of thousand.
Three, tops.
Three?
Tops.
Good.
You see, Grandma,
Patty studies
Eastern philosophy.
Our future leaders are gonna
have to be much more in tune
with the Oriental mind.
Okay, sweetie,
one more time.
Nathan, guess what?
Oh, you're home early.
Yeah, I have good news.
What?
What's up?
I'm going to teach
summer school classes.
That means we'll have
vacation money.
Oh, that's great.
Mexico.
Sí, sí.
Gil and Karen
are gonna take Patty.
I just wanna call them.
Gee, honey, I'm really
not too pro on Patty
spending a week with Gil.
Why not? They offered.
I'm a little concerned
about his jocularity.
I mean, he's a wonderful guy.
It's just he's a little,
you know, light-hearted
about things that I...
That, you know,
that we consider important.
She has fun over there.
You know, she scampers.
She cavorts.
Try this.
We take Patty with us.
To Mexico?
It's a perfect opportunity
to start her on Spanish.
It'll be fun.
Nathan.
I thought it would be nice
if you and I could be alone.
We will be.
We'll get two rooms.
Which one will I be in?
Patty.
That means
"come here" in Spanish!
Por favor. Please.
I want you
to listen to something.
I got a tape
of a mariachi band.
An authentic, indigenous,
native Mexican form of music.
Gil, good morning.
Hello, Cindy.
When were you
gonna tell me?
Tell you what?
Lenny called this morning
and he said
they were wondering
where I thought we should
take Phil Richards
to celebrate his partnership.
That Lenny is an asshole.
Do you believe that guy?
Nobody was supposed to have
that information
until next month.
That partnership is mine.
You said it was just held up
by Ted's surgery,
and then when he got back
you'd make it official.
Look, I never said
you didn't do great work.
You do terrific work.
Every firm does good work.
Look, I know you're
a lot smarter than Phil,
but the guy works
like a Trojan.
He schmoozes clients.
He brings in business.
He's here nights,
weekends. I own the guy.
And that's what puts your name
on the door.
This is really
coming out of left field.
I've been here eight years.
I'm the backbone
of the operation.
I know that.
If I don't
get this partnership,
I got to think about
going somewhere else.
I got to tell you, Gil.
I don't consider that
a realistic idea.
Why?
You go somewhere else,
you're gonna have to
get in line behind guys
who are younger than you,
who have been there longer,
who are more committed
and who are willing
to work for less money.
Look, this thing with Phil
is not etched in stone.
I can jerk him along
for the next month.
Why don't you use that time
to give us your best shot?
Put in the hours,
dazzle me.
Dazzle you?
Listen, Dave,
I'm having
a problem at home.
I really need to spend
a lot of extra time
with my son right now.
Then I don't know
what we can do.
Get this guy! Get this guy!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh!
Well, they're bad dudes.
That's why they call the game
Bad Dudes.
Okay, I should go
stay with the girls.
You got enough quarters?
Yeah.
Okay.
Dad?
Yeah?
How come I'm seeing
a psychiatrist?
Yeah, we were gonna have
a big talk about that.
What's wrong with me?
Nothing. Nothing.
You're great.
Then how come...
Look.
You're a kid like I was.
You have a lot of worries,
that's all.
And these doctors,
they're experts at helping
people with their worries.
It's nothing
to feel bad about.
Look, you're a great kid,
and I love you
very much, okay?
Okay.
You know what I think?
I think this is gonna be
a great summer for you.
And don't forget
you got a birthday
coming up.
Let's have a great party.
That'll be fun, huh?
Can we have Cowboy Dan?
Who?
Cowboy Dan.
The gun-fighting balloon man.
He was at Billy's party.
He's cool.
Absolutely. It's a done deal.
This is your dad talking now.
Now, you've got me excited.
Okay, now, what do we say
when we see a cute
eight-year-old girl walk by?
Hubba-hubba.
Hubba-hubba. Okay.
Oh, don't tell your mom
I taught you that.
It could be bad. Let's go.
Wow!
You like it?
Yeah, it's good. It's shiny.
Yeah! You know,
it was junk
when I found it.
The first time
I got laid was in...
That's a story
for another time.
Hi, Dad. Dinner ready?
What was that?
Huh?
Oh, some friends
were just dropping me off.
Friends? Friends slow down.
They even stop.
Dad...
Oh, Mommy.
Sweetie,
you're gonna be okay.
Honey, why would you
be panhandling?
I needed money
for a place to stay.
Julie, you have
a place to stay.
I'd have to tell you
what happened.
What did happen?
I just said I didn't
want to tell you.
Did you leave that Tod?
Yes.
He promised me
he was gonna start
a house-painting business,
then he said
he'd changed his mind.
He's gonna race dragsters
with his brothers.
He can't even drive
a regular car.
So his brothers came over
and we got in a fight.
He said,
"No bitch is gonna tell me
what to do for a living."
He told me he loved me.
Sweetie.
They say that,
and then they come.
Honey, what can you expect
from a kid like that?
Mom, back off.
The last guy you dated
stole our furniture.
Men are scum.
I know.
I know, sweetie.
Men are scum.
Hi, Garry.
Honey, Julie's home.
Great.
Come on, let's go
eat lots of ice cream.
Do you want
an ice-cream soda?
No.
How about...
Do you want, like,
a hot-fudge sundae?
Do you want
a banana split?
Mmm-mmm.
Do you want something
like French fries?
Yeah.
You do?
Julie!
Tod!
I thought I'd
find you here.
What does that make you,
Sherlock Holmes? I live here.
You live with me.
I wouldn't live with you
if the world were
flooded with piss
and you lived in a tree.
Excuse me,
I'm going
to the movies.
You're not leaving here
until you hear
what I have to say.
I'm not...
Julie!
Let go of me!
Let her go!
Julie, just listen to me!
Julie, please!
Let her go!
God damn it! Let her go!
Julie... Please!
Please, Miss Buckman,
I love her.
Let her go! God damn it!
Julie, you can't
run out on me.
You're my wife.
If you don't let her go,
I'm gonna call the...
You're his what?
His wife. We got married
a couple of days ago.
Are you out of your mind?
Mom!
No, please, Miss Buckman!
Are you out of your mind?
Julie, I didn't mean it.
What?
I'm sorry.
My brothers were ragging on me
and I couldn't back down,
but last night, I told them.
They mean nothing.
You mean everything.
Oh, Tod.
Christ.
Okay, look lively,
look lively.
You're doing great.
Shortstop, here it goes.
All right, pick it up!
Easy, now over to first.
That's right. That's the way
to play. That's good.
All right, you're beautiful.
You're a bunch of wild,
young bohemians. Okay.
Let's go again.
Okay, second base.
Here we go.
Now get down on it.
Don't be afraid.
It can't hurt you, Ben.
Here we go. Get down on that.
Get down on it, get down!
Wayne, get Ben some ice.
All right,
we're gonna need
a new second baseman.
Now, which one of you
outfielders wants to try
second base, huh?
Huh?
How about you, Kevin?
You wanna try second base?
Okay.
All right.
Oh, Matt, come on.
None of that. We're a team.
Let's be a team.
Now, come on.
Get out there and hustle.
Let's go.
Hey, Kevin, remember,
the word is "fun."
So just go on
out there
and what you catch,
you catch,
and what you miss,
you miss.
Okay?
Okay, Dad.
Okay. Come on.
Way to go, Kevin.
And now it is
my great pleasure to
introduce our valedictorian,
Kevin Buckman.
Thank you.
You know, when I was
nine years old,
I had kind of a rough time.
A lot of people thought
I was pretty mixed up.
But there was one person
who got me through it.
He did everything right.
And thanks to him, today,
well, I'm the happiest,
most confident,
and most well-adjusted person
in this world.
Dad, I love you.
You're the greatest.
All right!
Okay!
One more out, guys!
Let's go! Let's go!
How's your arm, son?
Not too tired?
Hey, Gil, our boys
finally gonna win one game?
Way to be supportive, Lou.
That's right.
That's right, Kevin!
Way to go. Way to go, Tommy!
All right! All right!
All right, Adam.
We got bases loaded.
We're only one run down.
Now, you can do it.
Get up there.
Come on, now.
Please, God,
let them win one game.
Got it!
No!
You stink, Buckman!
He had no business
being out there!
What's the matter with you?
No business!
No!
He had no business
being out there! Terrible!
Why'd you make me
play second base?
Someone's climbed to the roof
of the bell tower
with a rifle!
It's Kevin Buckman.
His father totally
screwed him up.
What's he yelling?
You made me play
second base!
Kevin, I'm sorry.
I did the best I could.
Nice shot, son.
It's important
to be supportive.
Come on, let's sing
one of the old tunes.
When you're sliding
into home
And your pants
are full of foam
Diarrhea
Well?
Why are you pouring water
through my diaphragm?
To check.
To see if it's okay.
You didn't know I did that,
did you?
No.
Obviously not, or you
wouldn't have tried this.
Are you accusing me
of making that hole?
No, a woodpecker came in here,
went into the bathroom,
opened the drawer
with his little wing,
and pecked a couple of holes
in your diaphragm.
I can't believe you would
jeopardize our plans, Susan.
Remember what we read?
"A vast majority
of truly exceptional people
"are either only children
or first-born
"with at least a five-year
separation between sibs."
We agreed to...
No, you agreed.
And they're not sibs.
They're babies.
And I wanna have another one.
So, this is how you
go about it, by vandalizing
a contraceptive device?
Because you won't
discuss it with me!
I did discuss it with you,
years ago!
Well, I think we were wrong.
Well, I think we were right.
And I'm not
discussing it again.
Tod!
Yeah.
Do you want me
to cook you breakfast?
No, thanks, Helen.
Julie's gonna do it.
Great. I'll get
the fire extinguisher.
All right.
I'll see you guys at dinner.
Sweet Jesus!
What are you doing?
Are you joining the Marines?
I knew you'd make
a thing out of this, Mom.
Just clean up the hair.
Wait.
Do it like that.
Cool! No, I love it.
Thanks so much.
You ready, Garry?
You want anything to eat?
How long are they
gonna be living here?
Not much longer, I think.
Well, I was
just thinking.
It's getting
pretty crowded here.
Oh, it's not so crowded.
There's a lot more room
since they shaved
their heads.
Well, I was just thinking
maybe I could stay
with Dad for a while.
What?
Well, I've been here
a long time. Maybe I should
live with him for a while.
You wanna live
with your father?
Kind of.
Have you talked
to your father about that?
No, not yet.
I thought I'd call him.
Honey,
you know,
you don't know
your father like I do.
I don't know him at all.
What's his number?
Well,
he'd be at work now.
So that's
206-5790.
Yeah, yeah..
Is Dr. Lampkin there?
His son.
No, Dad, it's not Joey.
It's Garry, your other son.
Well, I need
to ask you something.
It'll just take a second.
Well, would it be okay
if I stay with you
for a while?
A few months.
Okay.
Oh, Ed. You shit.
He, um...
He didn't think it was
such a good idea.
Oh, sweetie.
I gotta go.
Oh, honey.
Gil? Hey, Gil?
Yes, Miles?
When's Cowboy Dan
the gun-fighting balloon
man gonna be here?
Isn't that him?
No, that's the schmuck
who brought the horse.
I don't think
he's coming.
Yes, of course he is.
The man's a professional.
Do you think he wants to
put a blot on the entire
balloon-bending profession?
Go on and have fun.
And we'll have some burgers
and dogs in a second.
Let's go watch
the horse shit!
Yeah!
Patty, why don't you
play with Justin?
I don't understand
what he's doing.
Well, he's spinning.
What for?
No reason.
Just for fun.
It doesn't look
like fun.
It isn't.
You tried it?
So does Julie
have a nice place?
Oh, yeah, yeah,
she has a lovely place.
Yeah, she has my place.
She and that Tod
are both living in my house.
Really?
Well, actually
it was my idea.
You know, otherwise,
she was gonna quit school
and get a job and...
I don't know.
Maybe this way,
she'll still go to college.
All right. All right.
Here we go.
The thumb trick. Ready?
Thumb trick.
Do the thumb trick.
Look at my thumb. Ready?
Here we go.
Watch it. Watch it.
What are you doing?
Thumb trick.
Show her, Dad.
Okay, but this is
the last time.
Here we go. Ready?
I mean,
Justin's gonna go
full-time next year,
so everybody's asking
when I'm gonna
go back to work,
like I'm supposed to.
And I'm thinking about it.
I mean, I used to work.
It was okay, but...
You know, I think
I'm better at this.
I mean, I think
I'm sort of
good at it, so...
But then, people make me
feel embarrassed,
like I don't have
goals or something.
Like I sit around here
eating bonbons
all day, right?
Oh, I don't know.
Well, what does Gil say?
He says I should do
whatever I want.
I could've
killed him for that.
What are you
so upset about?
Nathan, she's weird.
She's a weird child.
I think a few days
a week of preschool
could be very helpful.
This is not the right age
for Patty to be
socially activated.
We went through it.
She's not a bomb.
She's a little kid
who has no ability to relate
to other little kids.
Do you want her
to relate to him?
Help! Help! Help!
See, when I met him,
I was a little wild.
I was a little
out of control
and he kind of
took me in hand.
I liked that.
He's very commanding.
He got me into teaching.
He got my shit together.
Boy, he really
turned me on.
Really? I mean,
of course, really.
Oh, Nathan and I
used to be hot.
I know he doesn't
look it, but...
I mean,
we were like rabbits.
I used to give him,
you know,
oral,
on the highway.
What?
You know, he was always
trying to get
a research grant.
And you thought
that would help?
No, but... I mean,
he kept getting turned down
and he'd get real,
real tense.
So if I saw him getting,
you know, really tense,
I'd just lean over
while he was driving
and I'd...
Susan.
What?
I just spoke
to your mother.
Grandma wants to stay over
at Helen's for a while.
Can you drive her there
tomorrow?
Sure.
Great.
He likes to butt things
with his head.
How proud you must be.
Here it is.
Now it's right there
in front of you.
Okay. Careful now.
Careful.
Yeah!
Here,
take this off.
Now really try
and hit it.
Yeah. Really give it
a good shot.
Yeah. Give it
a good whack!
Whack!
Put your shoulder into it
and whack it.
Now just kill it!
Kill it!
When I was born,
Grover Cleveland
was president.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Where should I do it?
Who are you and
what are you going to do?
I'm from Party Time
Entertainment.
I'm your stripper.
What's the birthday boy's
name? Because I paint it
across my breasts.
Okay, it was a mix-up.
I got Cowboy Dan's card
and he got mine.
I'm sorry. Goodbye.
Wait a minute.
What about Cowboy Dan?
He is coming.
He showed up
at the Lodge Hall,
and they were expecting me.
They beat him severely,
so Cowboy Dan
ain't coming.
Cowboy Dan's
not coming?
Come on, Kevin,
hold it together.
I knew it.
I told you.
All the kids are gonna
hate me. It's gonna be
just like Little League.
Cowboy Dan is coming.
Gil!
He's coming.
Cowboy Dan is coming!
Howdy, partner.
You're Kevin's father!
You're not Cowboy Dan.
Yeah!
That's right.
They call me Cowboy Gil,
as in guilty.
I saw Cowboy Dan.
I didn't like
the look on his face.
It was like this,
so I killed him.
I blew a hole in him
this big.
That's too small.
Actually,
it was about this big.
You know,
when I think about it,
that hole was about this big.
Yeah, and his guts
were spilled out
all over the floor.
As I was walking away,
I slipped around on his guts.
And a couple of other people
came by and they started
slipping on his guts, too.
After I blow
a hole in somebody
and slip around on their guts,
afterwards,
I always like to
make balloon animals.
That's mighty
courteous of you.
Here we go.
What's he doing?
I don't know.
Your lower intestines.
Watch out,
you little varmints!
Why, you! You darned kids!
Why, you little
lily-livered lumps
of cat meat!
Where's Cowboy Gil?
Where'd he go?
Ambush, you little
four-footers.
And here it is. It's made
with a quart of milk,
two cups of sugar
and three cow pies.
Come on and get it.
Will you get down
off the horse
before you hurt yourself?
Honey, I got to make
a big exit.
That's Cowboy Gil's woman.
Take a bow, little lady.
Hi. Hi.
I sure hope
that when I mosey back
this way one day,
you don't mind
if I stop in and say hello.
Well, I got to be moseying
on back to Abilene.
Keep your powder
and your pants dry.
Kevin, I hope this is
the best danged birthday
you ever had.
Adiós, buckaroos.
Giddy-up, Thunder Thighs!
Don't try and follow me
to Abilene.
Good night, sweetheart.
Good night, Mom.
Did you have
a nice birthday?
Dad was funny.
He sure was.
Well, good night,
nine-year-old boy.
Happy birthday, kiddo.
Dad?
Yeah?
When I grow up,
can I work where you work?
Why?
That way we can still
see each other every day.
Good night.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Mom?
Hubba-hubba.
Garry?
Let me out of here,
mango face!
Hello, Helen?
Oh, the door was unlocked.
Oh, my God!
What channel
is this?
No, Gran, this is a tape.
She needs a man.
Now.
Gran, this isn't mine.
I don't watch this.
What's everybody
doing in here?
Did you break
my lock?
Susie, Gran,
would you please
go to my room?
Sure.
One of those men
reminded me of your grandpa.
God bless him.
Garry, listen to me.
How could you break my lock?
I came in here because
I was afraid
you were on drugs.
Why would you think that?
Because of what you did
to your father's office.
What do you mean?
He found your hammer.
You know,
those were your initials
burned into the handle.
Someone must have taken it.
Oh, Garry, just...
Honey, you know,
all these feelings...
You're right to have
all these feelings.
You're a great kid.
You're a great kid, honey.
You just got a lousy dad.
And you've just got
to learn to say,
"The hell with him!"
Actually,
that's good advice
for both of us.
The hell with him!
I don't know what to say
about the tapes.
You know,
I assume that,
you know,
you're watching these
because you're curious
about sex,
you know,
or filmmaking.
Is there anything
you'd like to ask?
Who?
Me.
No, I don't blame you.
What about Uncle Gil?
He's busy
with his own kids.
Hi.
Where's my wife?
She's still at school.
She's got
cheerleading practice.
Bitchin'.
So what's up?
Would you like
to speak to Tod?
Can I speak frankly,
no holds barred?
Please.
That is one messed-up
little dude.
You sure
we can talk straight?
All right.
A few months ago,
Garry got his first boner.
You know what that is?
If memory serves.
Great! Anyway,
since then he's been
uh,
slapping the salami.
No offense.
No.
Apparently, he's going
for a world record.
Chicken's burning.
Oh!
Oh.
Damn! That looked
good, too.
Anyway,
he was afraid
there was something
wrong with him, you know?
Like he was a pervert
or something.
I told him that's what
little dudes do.
We've all done it.
That made him happy.
Garry was happy?
Yeah,
he even smiled.
I never even knew
he had teeth.
I guess a boy Garry's age
really needs a man around.
Yeah, well,
it depends on the man.
I had a man around.
He used to wake me up
in the morning by flicking
lit cigarettes at my head.
"Hey, asshole, get up
and make me breakfast."
You know, Miss Buckman,
you need a license to buy
a dog or drive a car.
Hell, you need a license
to catch a fish,
but they'll let
any butt-reaming asshole
be a father.
Well, I'm gonna
pick up Julie.
They're hassling her
about her hair.
She does look
kind of stupid.
I don't know what
we were thinking about.
Tod?
Thanks.
Kevin wants to go.
How did you go
through those quarters
so fast?
Another kid
took Kevin's money.
Shut up!
What kid?
Never mind. Never mind.
Can we just go?
It was that kid.
Never mind!
That kid? That kid's
not bigger than you.
Go back and get your money!
Dad, let me
handle it, okay?
Kevin, do you want me
to help you get
your money back?
No, can we just go?
I wanna go!
Okay.
"Okay"?
Now, that's a little kid.
Justin can beat up that kid!
Shut up, Dad.
Will you just shut up?
(CRYING) Oh, no!
What's the matter?
I lost my retainer!
Where?
Shh. Honey.
It's okay.
I put my retainer
on the table.
Just relax.
Kevin, it's
okay, honey.
It's his retainer.
He lost his retainer.
It's all right, sweetheart.
Come on, sweetie.
We'll find it.
Oh, God!
Here, let me.
Where are the kids?
Your folks are
driving them home.
They'll wait with them
at our house.
Oh, that's just
what Kevin needs,
time alone with my dad.
Yuck!
Let's just go.
Gil, they're $200.
If you dropped $200 in here,
you'd look, right?
Yeah.
Let's face it.
He's getting worse.
He has his good days,
and he has his bad days.
Why is he so high-strung?
He's like a poodle.
Everything's blown
out of proportion.
Where does he get
this obsessive behavior?
I wish I knew.
They're gonna put him
in special ed.
Gil, what did you think?
That you'd dress up
like a cowboy
and coach Little League,
and Kevin would be fine?
No.
I mean, no, I didn't.
Yeah. Yeah, okay, I did.
Well, honey,
you were really
kidding yourself.
You know,
when your kid is born,
it can still be perfect.
You haven't made
any mistakes yet.
And then they grow up
to be like...
Like me.
Oh, I'm gonna be home
late tomorrow.
How come?
I'm attempting
to dazzle Dave.
I'm trying to put together
a major income-property thing
for one of our
bigger clients.
Has Dave said anything?
Thursday when I left
for Little League,
he said,
"Let's all thank Gil
for stopping by."
I didn't take it
as a good sign.
Well, let's just wait and see.
You know, worrying
isn't gonna help.
God, I'm so tense.
You're tense
right now, honey?
My back is tense.
My neck is tense.
My ears are tense.
It's like they're hot
or something.
Maybe I can do something
to help you relax.
I doubt it, honey.
I'd like to try.
I am so sorry.
It's all right, honey. It was
my fault. You just kind of
took me by surprise.
So how did this happen?
Show him, honey.
It's awfully late,
Frank. We need to get Cool
right to bed.
He'll be all right.
Hi, Dad.
Take the boy inside.
I couldn't resist. I had to
take it out for a spin.
It purrs like a kitten.
You're probably wondering
why I took it out
without telling you.
I wanted to have it appraised
so that you'd know how much
it was worth.
Only they can't appraise it
unless they have
all the paperwork,
the registration, the proof
of purchase. You've got
those things around?
I'm not a schmuck!
You were going to
sell my car.
Sell... Dad...
Look, don't bullshit me
anymore!
It belittles us both!
I want you
out of the house.
Dad, they're gonna
kill me.
Bookies?
Frigging basketball!
I had a lock.
This miserable son-of-a-bitch
rookie throws in
a goddamn 50-footer
at the buzzer.
It was a nightmare.
It was like he reached
into my chest
and ripped out...
Oh, shut up!
How much do you owe?
The truth now!
$26,000.
Jesus!
Dad, I'm never
gambling again,
I swear to God,
but these guys
mean business.
What about that 3,000
I gave you?
I took it to the track.
I wanted to run it up
so that I wouldn't have to
hit you for the whole amount.
What the hell
is the matter with you?
You're not a kid anymore!
You're not stupid!
Dad, I can't get a break.
I have been so close
so many times,
I could touch it.
Did you ever think
about getting a job?
Oh... Great.
Oh. That is just great.
Now, what did you
always tell me, huh?
"Make your mark!
Make your mark!
"Don't be one
of the numbers.
Make your mark!"
You misunderstood me!
You weren't listening!
Oh, come on,
if I called you up
to tell you,
"Hey Dad, I'm the new
assistant sub-vice president
of pencil sharpening
"at some crappy
little company,"
you're telling me
you'd think that was great?
I am better than that!
I am not Gil!
Look, I've made some mistakes.
I have to learn from them.
They're going to
kill me, Dad,
with pain.
I'm your son.
Hydrogen.
Helium.
Carbon.
Excuse me, honey.
I don't mean to interrupt,
but I've made up
some new cards.
Really?
That's great, Mommy.
I'm so glad you're back
with the program.
Let's do your cards.
Why don't I show them
to you first and make sure
they're appropriate?
Okay.
Sweetheart, Mommy and Daddy
will be back in two minutes.
How many seconds is that?
One-twenty.
Excelente.
"This is
"the only way
"I can get
"your attention."
Honey, this is really
basic stuff.
She's way beyond this.
"I'm leaving you."
You're leaving me?
"Yes."
Well, thank you.
I really had
a great time.
It's been years
since anybody's
taken me to a carnival.
You thought that was
a carnival?
That was my parents' house.
You know,
you're pretty funny
for a biology teacher.
Thank you.
Would you like
to come in?
Sure.
Okay.
Hi, guys.
Hey, Miss B!
Hi, Mom.
Hi, Mr. Bowman.
Knee drop!
It's a nice
knee drop, honey.
Would you like
some coffee?
I'd love some.
The kitchen's
right through here.
Can I ask you
something?
Sure.
How come
you finally decided
to go out with me?
Well, my grandmother
told me to.
No, really.
She's been staying with us.
Only, it's a little crowded,
so tomorrow.
I'm taking her over
to my brother Gil's.
Hi, Julie. Julie,
I would like to introduce you
to Mr. Bowman!
Tod??
Julie?
What's up?
Did you get the Twinkies?
I found
this
in the trunk of your car.
You're racing again,
aren't you?
Yeah, so what?
So you promised.
That's what!
I changed my mind.
You changed your mind?
Yeah, I changed my mind!
What about
house painting?
I gave it up.
You gave it up?
That was your future!
Well,
Dave and Rod kind of took
all the equipment and split,
and I don't know
where they are.
I told you not
to trust those guys.
Didn't I tell you?
I'm not as smart
as you are, okay?
I didn't get 1 3,000
on my SATs, okay?
I'm stupid, okay?
Okay!
Julie...
Butt out!
Maybe
I should leave.
No,
maybe I should leave.
What do you mean
"maybe"?
Tod?
What is it
with the women
in this family?
They make all the men
in this family want to leave.
Well, if he thinks
I'm having his baby now,
he's crazy!
Baby?
Your daughter's
having a baby?
A baby?
You're gonna be
a grandma?
No, no, no, no, no, no.
I'm too young. You know,
grandmothers are old.
They bake, and they sew,
and they tell you stories
about the Depression.
I was at Woodstock,
for Christ's sake!
I peed in a field!
I've hung onto
the Who's helicopter
as it flew away!
I was at Woodstock.
Oh, yeah? I thought
you looked familiar!
Gil, I've spoken
with Ted and Dan,
and we have decided
to make Phil Richards
a partner.
Holy shit!
Now, I know you're upset.
Upset?
Haven't you seen the deals
I've been putting together?
I have been killing myself.
I mean, aren't you dazzled?
You still don't
get it, do you?
Phil has just brought in
three brand-new
multimillion-dollar clients.
He has spent the last month
wining and dining these guys,
getting them laid.
He doesn't tell me
about problems with his kids.
I'm not even sure
if he has kids.
If this man's dick fell off,
he would still
show up to work.
He is an animal.
That's what dazzles,
not the work.
You can't do what he does.
You hate that shit.
Now, Phil Richards...
I quit!
Oh, Gil...
Forget it.
Phil brought you
some big clients.
You're happy.
Oh, Gil...
I'm just going to
call my clients, give them
the news, and I'm out of here.
Friday's my last day.
Don't make me a party.
Gil!
Dave!
Hey, this is not
a playground, okay?
Dad!
Daddy...
Not now!
Okay...
Knock it off!
God, I can't believe
they did this.
All right, the other kids
got picked up,
ours are watching a tape,
and Helen just dropped
your Grandma off. Let's talk.
I quit my job.
Why?
They gave the partnership
to Phil Richards.
Phil Richards,
this is a guy who
leaves his wife and kids
and then puts all his money
in his girlfriend's name
so they can't touch him
for child support.
I mean, the guy is...
Anyway, I couldn't
stand it. I snapped.
Can you still
change your mind?
What do you mean,
change my mind? I quit.
I know,
but did you say anything
that would make it
difficult for them
to take you back?
Jesus, honey, I was hoping
you'd be a little more
supportive. It's not like I...
I'm pregnant.
Since when?
Since I am.
I'm due in February.
I didn't want to say
anything till I was sure.
How did this happen?
It was an accident.
Anyhow, this is why
I'm saying
maybe now this isn't
the best time
for you to be out of work
or starting a new job.
You know, if you'd told me
there was a chance
of this happening,
I might not have quit
in the first place.
Well, you never told me
there was a chance
you might quit.
It was a spur-of-the-moment
decision.
Pretty big one.
So what are you saying
I should do?
Crawl back to work
and kiss Dave's feet
and get my crappy job back?
I quit! If I go back now,
they got me. I'm a eunuch!
You know,
this puts a minor crimp
in my life, too.
I was thinking about
starting back to work
in the fall. Now I can't.
Well, that's the difference
between men and women.
Women have choices.
Men have responsibilities.
Oh, really?
Oh, okay, well,
then I choose for you
to have the baby, okay?
That's my choice.
You have the baby.
You get fat.
You breastfeed
till your nipples are sore.
I'll go back to work!
All right, let's return
from la-la land because
that ain't gonna happen.
And whether
I crawl back to Dave
or I get another job,
it's obvious now
I'm going to have to
spend less time at home.
I'm gonna have to have
business dinners,
and I'm gonna have to
play racquetball,
get guys laid,
so I hope you don't mind
if I bring a few
prostitutes home, honey,
because that's
what it takes
to get anywhere,
and I'm not
getting anywhere,
so whatever happens,
you have to count on
less help from me.
Why don't you just say
what you're really thinking?
What am I thinking?
That I should have
an abortion?
I didn't say that.
That's a decision
every woman has to
make on her own.
What, are you running
for Congress?
Don't give me that.
I want your opinion
about what we should do.
Let's pretend
it's your decision, okay?
Pretend you're a caveman
or your father.
What do you want me to do?
I want...
I want
whatever you want.
Well, I wanna have the baby.
Well, great! Let's have it,
then. Let's see how I can
screw the fourth one up.
Hey, let's have five.
Let's have six!
Let's have a dozen
and pretend they're donuts!
I'm really happy
about the way things
are turning out, aren't you?
You know,
with the frame of mind
you're in,
not only am I not sure
we should have another baby,
I'm not sure we should
keep the three we've got.
Well, I'm ready
to discuss it.
However, I can't right now
because I gotta go
to the goddamn Little League.
Ten little boys
are waiting for me
to guide them
into last place.
You really have to go?
My whole life is "have to."
Come on, Kevin,
get your glove.
You said I didn't
have to play anymore.
I know what I said,
but now I'm changing
my mind.
If I have to go,
you have to go.
Move it!
Kevin,
this one's for you.
Get behind the ball.
It's easier to come in.
Hi, Dad. What are you
doing here?
Karen said
you were here.
Can I speak to you
a second?
Yeah.
Hey, Wayne,
can you take over
a second?
What's up?
I need your advice.
Wait a second.
My head is spinning.
Come on.
Look,
Larry needs $26,000
or gamblers
are gonna kill him.
Jesus!
I'm supposed to decide
whether to give it to him.
And you want my advice?
Why me? Why now?
Because I know you think
I was a shitty father.
Thank you
for not arguing.
And I know
you're a good father,
so, tell me,
what would you do?
You got
that kind of money?
I got it,
but it's gonna hurt.
I wanted to retire next year.
This'll put that off
for a while,
a long while.
I never
should've had four.
You know, when you were
two years old,
we thought
you had polio.
You know about that?
Yeah, Mom
once said something.
Yeah, well,
for a week,
we didn't know.
I hated you for that.
What?
I did.
I did. I hated
having to go through that.
The caring, the worrying,
the pain,
that's not for me.
You know, it's not
like that all ends
when you're 18
or 21 or 41 or 61.
It never, never ends.
It's like
your Aunt Edna's ass.
It goes on forever,
and it's just as frightening.
It's true.
There is no
end zone.
You never cross the goal line,
spike the ball
and do your touchdown dance.
Never.
I'm 64,
Larry, 27,
and he's still my son,
like Kevin is your son.
Do you think
I want him to get hurt?
He's my son.
Come on.
Oh, I'm all right.
I'll figure it out.
Hey.
Who's to say
who's a shitty father?
Kevin's in therapy.
We got called to school
last year because Taylor
was kissing all the boys.
Justin keeps ramming things
with his head.
My career is
in the shithouse.
You worry too much.
You always did.
Okay, let's go.
Let's get them.
Let's get this one.
Come on, you can do it!
We only need one more out!
Can't you even field
a ground ball?
Matt, I'm not gonna warn you
again. One more comment,
and you're out of there.
I don't care what happens.
What are you
yelling at him for?
He's the only player
you've got.
Hey, Matt, we need
one more out, son.
Wherever it's hit,
you go for it!
It's the only chance
you have to win!
All right, come on, now,
don't blow it!
All right, no big deal.
No big deal.
One more out.
Come on, just relax.
Play ball!
Relax and concentrate.
Let's go!
One more. Let's go.
Oh, shit!
Get it, Matt!
He's out of there!
I'm gonna
help you.
Oh, Dad.
Now, we see
these gangsters.
We agree to pay them
$1,000 a month.
They're businessmen.
They'll see that something
is better than nothing.
Then, Monday morning,
8:00 a.m.,
you come to work with me
at my place.
I'm going to teach you
the business.
Plumbing supplies.
And in a few years,
I'll retire,
and you'll take over.
Meanwhile, as long
as you're working,
and if you agree to go
to Gamblers Anonymous,
I'll keep paying
your debt.
That's it.
Okay.
Let me just add a wrinkle.
About an hour ago,
I got a phone call
from an associate in Chile.
Big opportunity.
Platinum.
Now, why don't I just
toddle off down there
for a couple of months,
see if it pans out?
If it does, great.
If not,
we put the Frank-Buckman
plan into effect.
Sound good?
Sure.
Great.
Oh, I could use
a little...
2,000 enough?
Ample. Ample.
Well, better pack.
What about Cool?
Huh?
Oh, Jesus,
that's a tough one.
This is not really
the kind of trip that...
Listen,
how about if...
Don't worry about it.
My dad's going away?
Yes.
He's leaving right away?
Is he ever coming back?
No.
Would you like
to stay here with us?
Yeah.
Good.
Good morning,
Mrs. Huffner.
Hi, Michelle.
Susan, I need
to talk to you.
Not now, Nathan,
I have a class.
I want you to come home.
This is very bad for Patty.
She can't
concentrate.
I gotta go.
No, wait.
No, let me go.
Listen to me.
It's bad for me, too.
I love you, Susan.
Those are words.
They don't solve anything.
I can compromise.
I can change.
Nathan, I don't think
you're capable of change.
Okay, come on, we're
way behind because of
yesterday's bomb threat,
so let's get going.
Why do birds suddenly appear
Every time you are near?
Just like me
They long to be
Close to you
Nathan, please,
I'll lose my job.
Why do stars
twinkle in the sky
Every time you walk by?
Just like me
They long to be
Close to you
Nathan, we're trying so hard
to keep these kids off drugs.
On the day that you were born
The angels got together
And decided to create
a dream come true
This was the song
from our wedding.
So they sprinkled
moon dust in your hair
And golden sunlight
in your eyes so blue
It's a wedding kind of a song.
That is why
all the guys in town
Guys in town
Follow you
All around
Just like me
They long to be
Close to you
Nathan, you're crazy.
Susan, I love you.
Please come home.
We have
a great start.
The Plymouth missile,
Rick Carsmith,
right in the far lane.
Five-fourteen, left car...
How's it look?
...let's hear it
for Popper Jay.
Looking hot.
Looking damn hot!
Mom? Mom, hurry!
He's over there.
He's gonna kill himself.
Julie, I'm not
his mother.
Please, Mommy.
Please, I'm so scared.
Now, I'm "Mommy."
He's trying
to prove something.
I don't know.
Competing in the first round
of the competition,
the Eliminator,
and on the grandstand lane,
we have Theresa Vega.
The last few feet
of the course
is going to be very crowded.
Oh, God,
he's already going.
In eight seconds,
he's going to be
a legend.
And challenging her
on the power lane,
newcomer Tod Higgins.
Great start!
Vega with the home shot.
Higgins pulls ahead!
He hit the guardrail!
He's out of control!
Oh, my God!
Come on!
Tod? Tod?
Tod?
Bring it around
to the back of the track!
Come on.
One, two, three!
Let's get him out of here!
Back up. Back up.
Give him some room.
Give him some room. Back up.
Easy. Easy. Easy.
Did I win?
Oh, my God.
You okay?
I'm all right.
Well, we'll get you
to first aid to make sure,
all right?
My brother's car.
I killed the car.
We'll take care of it.
Julie, come on, let's go.
Just get in.
I can't.
What?
I can't. This is
too intense. This is...
This is marriage!
Now, let's get
in the truck!
Come on,
let's go.
Can you do that again
next week?
The crowd loved it.
Yeah, sure,
that's a good job for me,
crash dummy.
Stop that!
You're very important.
Yeah, why?
Why? Because you're gonna be
the father of my grandchild.
That's why.
I love you.
I love you, too.
I was so scared.
You, like,
saved their marriage.
That was really cool.
Yeah, well,
I give them six months,
four if she cooks.
You don't think
they're gonna make it?
Well, you know, honey,
the odds aren't good.
Then why did you
say all that?
Why did you try
to keep them together?
Well, because
Julie wants Tod.
Whatever you guys want,
I want to get for you.
That's the best
I can do.
I'm glad
you're going out
with Mr. Bowman.
Yeah, why?
Well, he's funny,
and he's the kind of guy
that'd be nice to you.
Somebody should be
nice to you.
I tell you, kid,
I could stand that.
Yeah.
Can we tape
over Susan's wedding?
No.
What are we
supposed to tape over?
Mom, my ears are loose.
Oh, give me. I'll fix them.
Oh, your pants
are on backwards.
Go upstairs and turn
them around, and tell
Grandma we're leaving.
She's still playing
Nintendo.
Do you know your lines?
Daddy, I don't have
any lines. I'm Dopey.
I'll say. Hey!
Kevin? Kevin,
take Justin outside,
and put him in his car seat.
I have to do everything.
Come on, shrimp.
Hey.
And I'm the one
in therapy.
I'm not a shrimp.
I love you.
I love you, too.
No, I mean
I really love you.
I love you, too.
Dave called. He was crying.
He actually cried.
He said if I'd come back,
they'd give me a corner office
with new furniture
and a raise,
like that's supposed
to make up for everything.
Anyway, I took the job.
I couldn't think.
I was still high
from the Little League game.
Isn't that demented,
that a grown man's
happiness depends
on whether a nine-year-old
catches a pop-up?
I mean,
what if he missed?
But he didn't.
But he could have.
But he didn't, Gil!
You threw him
1 2 million pop-ups
in the backyard.
You cut the odds
considerably.
If he hadn't...
But there's three of them,
and you wanna have four,
and the fourth one
could be Larry,
and they're gonna do
a lot of things.
I mean, baseball's
the least of it.
And in all those things,
sometimes they're
going to miss.
Sometimes they won't.
Sometimes they will.
What do you want me
to give you, guarantees?
These are kids,
not appliances.
Life is messy.
I hate messy.
It's so messy.
You know, when I was 1 9,
Grandpa took me
on a roller coaster.
Oh?
Up, down, up, down.
Oh, what a ride.
What a great story.
I always wanted
to go again.
You know, it was just
interesting to me that a ride
could make me so frightened,
so scared, so sick,
so excited
and so thrilled,
all together.
Some didn't like it.
They went
on the merry-go-round.
That just goes
around. Nothing.
I like the roller coaster.
You get more out of it.
Well, I'll be seeing you
in the car.
She's a very smart lady.
Come on, Taylor,
your ears are ready.
Yeah, a minute ago,
I was really confused
about life,
and then Grandma came in
with her wonderful
and affecting
roller-coaster story,
and now everything's
great again.
I happen to like
the roller coaster, okay?
As far as I'm concerned,
your grandmother's brilliant.
Come on, Taylor.
Come on, hurry up.
Yeah, if she's so brilliant,
how come she's sitting
in our neighbor's car?
It's good to be home.
It sure is.
Somebody stole our dishes.
"They're not stolen.
They're put away."
They're not stolen.
"They're not stolen.
They're put away."
They're not stolen.
They're put away.
What was that?
It came from the bedroom.
It sounds like a monster.
Someone should see what it is.
Not me!
Let Dopey do it.
Yeah!
No!
Come on, Dopey!
Yeah!
They're hurting my sister!
Hey, look, he's going.
Get him! Get him!
Get him!
Hang on, Taylor.
Justin! Justin!
Taylor, I'm gonna save you!
Get away from my sister!
Hey, stop!
Justin!
No.
No, Justin.
Justin, no! Justin!
Oh, Justin.
Come back here.
Please come back here,
little one.
He's ruining the play!
He's ruining the whole play!
I think that's
the Buckmans' kid.
That's great!
You're doing great.
One more push, and the baby
will be here. Bear down.
- Bear down.
- - Push.
We're almost there, Mom.
Come on, push.
Push.
That's it. Great.
You're doing great.
Push. Push. Come on,
you're doing fine.
Push! Push!
Good.
Okay, here we go
now. Push.
I can see the head.
Here comes the baby. Good.
Here you go.
Here it is. It's a girl!
Good. Congratulations, Mom.
She's beautiful.
You better get out
in the lobby, Dad.
I think you've got about
1 00 relatives out there.
Dr. Ciccolini,
Dr. Anthony Ciccolini,
please call three-six.
Well?
It's a girl.
Helen's fine.
Yay, Mom!
Thank goodness!
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer™)
That's great!
Congratulations!
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer™)