- Wait!
- Have you looked thru' them?
- Are you sure you are up for this?
- Can't Mrs MacLeod be nervous?
- Anna....
- Methos, try and listen to what I'm saying.
- Reggie, calm down, tell me what's going on.
- Over the past week, the planets of our solar system
have moved outside their orbital paths
- and are coming into alignment.
-  I mean, do you know how unusual that is?
- There's no simple way to explain this.
- But that could just be orbital wobble.
- How can that be possible?
- Orbital wobble is one thing, but this...
- This is outside the laws of celestial mechanics.
- And that's not all.
- Literally millions of celestial bodies from here to the
central Sun of our galaxy are lining up.
- When that alignment is complete....
- In exactly 4 days, 3 hours, 47 minutes,
- The Earth is going to be bombarded with cosmic radiation.
- The moment of The Source.
- The Light of the cosmos is literally reaching out to us.
- Aye...
- What about Zai? Did we hear from him?
- No... Nah, he's overdue.
- Isn’t your friend MacLeod there? Can't he help?
- MacLeod is...
- Not the man he once was...
- Well, just try...
- I can't stay with you Duncan.
- Why?
- Duncan.....
- Hey, Hey you.
- Please something to eat...
- Oh God thank you. Thank you...
Thank you.
- Hey! Stop!
- No! No.... No!
- Food..... Food.....
- Thank you.
- Ugh.... Hi.
- Hi.
- Is it good?
- Uhuh.
- Oh, God... I hate that....
- Yes..
- There can be only one.
- Voice match accepted.
- Login confirmed.
- Connecting
- Yes!
- Signal acquired
- Are you sure when the alignment will be complete...
- Guys!
- Come on... - Four days at most....
- Dammit!!
- They are going crazy out there.
- I suspect some big messy thing
are all going down the toilet
- Reg!
- Z... where the hell have you been, man?
- Reg, there's no time... It’s coming down...
I think I found it.
- Where is Giovanni?
- What do you find Zai?
- I found ancient writings in Gaza.... I followed them...
they took me to central Europe....
- And I found the location of the source.
- Z, I'm losing you mate...
Try and stabilize your signal.
- Zai... easy okay. From the beginning.
- I can't hear you. I can't hear you.
- Zai.... you do God's work.
- Don't be afraid.
- Your Eminence.
- Tell us what you found.
- The ancient writings I found In Gaza....
I followed them...
- They took me to central Europe....
then I knew I was getting close....
- I found a monastery where the monks
studied an ancient text....
- That spoke of The Source.
- One of the monks took me to a place where
it last happened over 10,000 years ago.
- I feel the power of this place...
-And then.... he appeared...
- So I ran.... And I ran....
- He has risen...
- The Guardian....
- Signal failure...
- Reacquiring signal... Signal reacquired...
- I always thought the Guardian was bullshit.
- He's the immortal antichrist.
- The false prophet created in evil....
- Well if he's such a bad boy...
why did't he take Zai's head?
- To get to us...
He knows Zai's not alone.
- You think he knows we are looking for the source?
- He must...
- Signal acquired.
- He's more than an immortal...
- Zai... where is the Location of the Source?
- He's like...like death.
- Zai, you're in danger.
- Zai.... The location.
- He's coming.
- Zai! Get outta there.
- What have you learnt? Give us something...
- I've written the co-ordinates down on
this map.... the co-ordinates are...
- The co-ordinates are on...
- Okay, you have to get to the monastery.
you have to find the monks that bear the symbol
- Of the Brothers of Doleo.
- They will help you find The Source.
- Zai.... you have to get out of there....
- Zai... we have enough... Save youself..
- Pray for me..... Father.
- Reg...
- Did you get the signal back? Did you get the signal back?
- Requiem aeternam Dona eis Domine--
- Zai!- Zai!
- Arghh!
- What he mean by Delio Brothers?
- Brothers of pain.
- Sounds like a foul bunch.
- They're an ancient religious order in estern Europe...
- They are not a religious order...
- They are an heretical cult..
- But their Elder might be able to help us.
- Their elder corrupted his monks.... turned them from
the true faith during the fall of Rome...
- Rome is a long time ago my friend.
- Not for me, it wasn't...
- Giovanni, this could be it!
- Guys!!
- If this Elder could help us, who gives a toss?
- Let's go and find him..
- Zai’s no Jack-the-Lad.
- He can handle himself...
He's got a shot... right?
- Joe...
- Methos... What do you got?
- The Guardian is awake....
Find MacLeod...
- There can be only me...
- Hello....
- This is the end of time....!!!
- You think I'm mad?
Maybe a little bit crazy...
- What are you?
- I’m The Guardian...
- Question is.... who are you?
- I'm Duncan MacLeod...
- I'm Duncan MacLeod.... I'm Duncan MacLeod...
I'm Duncan MacLeod....
- You have squandered your precious gift!
- You could have ruled the world...
...and you pissed it away...
- Have a nice day...
- The female, Anna...
- She's not for you...
- What's Anna got to do with this?
- Nothing..Everything...Nothing..Everything...
..Nothing..Everything...
- It's time for me and you to dance.
- In that outfit?
- Foreplay....
- Let's go...
- Okay...
- Are you the One, MacLeod... MacLeod?
Would you kill to be the One?
- Would you kill her, MacLeod?
- Hello... Joe!
- Joe...
- Get In the car...
- Get out of here, Joe.
- I don't have time for this bullshit.
- Get In the car!!
- What are you doing?
- Seek The Source...
- What...?
- The Source....
- Joe....
- Before you get all whacked out, just listen...
- Joe, stop the car...
- Stop the damn car...
- You're a Watcher... you can't interfere...
- I just said fuck it..
- You took an oath...
- There is no Watcher organization anymore...
- Most of my people are dead....
- You shouldn’t have interfered...
- If I hadn't... you'd be dead.
- Sure, fine.. Go ahead...Go back and let that thing kill you...
What do you have to live for anyway?
- He mentioned Anna...
- Have you even talked to her?
- No, not in months...
and don't give me the ends of day bullshit.
- Methos and others don't think it's bullshit...
They're looking for the source...
- Oh, the Source...
- You can join them and find out what that’s about..
- And see what it has to do with Anna..
- Or you can go back and play with that freak...
It’s your call...
- Can't believe I’m letting you drag me into this...
- I know this is going to be hard to explain, but...
I’m Immortal....
- It's just a dream..
- I was born In the Highland’s
of Scotland in 1592.
- It's more than a dream Duncan.
- Anna...
- Nothing will hurt you...
- So you're not gonna grow old?
- This is how I am.
- I’m going to grow old, though...
- Will you still love me when I’m old?
- I’ll always love you...
- I’m leaving.... I can't stay with you, Duncan..
- Why?
- You mean everything to me...
- But it’s not enough...
- What do you mean I mean everything to you ...
...but it's not enough?
- That doesn't make sense Anna...
- I can't!
- What do you want from me?
- The Impossible...
- I want a child...
- A child...
- It’s good to see you, G...
- Who are you?
- I'm Duncan MacLeod...
- MacLeod... MacLeod...
May I ask you what you're doing here?
- Reggie Weller...
- My astronomer...
- And part time cultural stereo type...
- Sure,you are...
- Funny... Who's that?
- It's Joe Dawson, a friend of mine.
- Hey...
- Methos.......
Been a long time...
- This is different...
-Times are different... MacLeod...
- Yeah...
- Leather’s a really good look for you...
Methos...
- Giovanni...
- I hear you're on a quest for the Source...
- You make it sound so grand...
- We are here to get information...
- Brave men died to get us this far...
- Brothers of Doleo.. Rumours have it they've been
governed by the same Elder for thousands of years...
- One of us?
- I'm thinking so...
- Well let's find out...
- What's a man of the cloth doing on
the quest for the source...
- I am here for the greater glory of God...
- But if you don't like what you find?
- You assume there will be an inherent contradiction
between what we will encounter and the Gospel..
- I know that will not be the case...
- You seem very certain of that...
- Doesn't it? The Lord guides our
hands on this holy quest...
- We are all in His service...
- Question is, Duncan MacLeod...
Are you?
- I had a sneaky suspicion you'd know where to find him...
- Yeah, well...
- You know I did it for him and not for you...
- Sure...
- What do you want?
- We have come to see your Elder...
- We have no Elder...
- That went well...
- Oi! You! Open this door!
- Right!
- Aaah!!!
- Wait a minute...
- Who's that?
- That's my wife...
- Hello...
- I can explain...
- Stop!
- The Elder will see you.....
Now that she is here...
- Hello Anna Teshemka...
- Hello Duncan MacLeod...
- You look like shit...
- What are you doing here?
- Look, I have so much to tell you...
- You won't even believe what’s been happening to me?
- Lead us...
- Duncan, I have visions...
- Seriously, I saw this... I saw you... I saw all of you...
- Come, girl... I’m near...
- Look... well....
- There are worse things than death...
- Apparently...
- What do you want?
- We seek the Source...
- Are you willing to pay the price?
- That's fixed...
- Thank you.
- Hoo! Hello.
- Yeah. That's a sweet piece... But a..
- This is my beat, okay, Reggie?
- Sorry...
- What is it?
- I don't know...
- So you have encountered the Guardian...
a riddle that cannot be solved...
- A force that cannot be defeated...
- Man... that's one fast bird...
- You stay here...
- I can take care of this...
- I was once like you...
long ago, before recorded time...
- Like now, the world had fallen into chaos...
- The people cried out for a redeemer...
- Do any of you have redeeming quality?
- Greetings, brother...
- This is holy ground!
- We were a group much like yours...
- All of us immortals from different tribes...
All seeking the truth....
- We all thought we would find the answer,
In the Source...
- But there were darker...
Secret desires in our hearts...
- The journey was long...
- Our tempers flared... and being immortals...
...heads were taken...
- Finally, there were only three of us left...
the strongest of our kind...
- But the ancient one gaurding the source...
...was stronger still...
- My friend fought valiantly...
...but I wanted my immortality...
- The source wasn't mine to take...
Something went terribly wrong...
- It left us both cursed...
- Both, for ever...
...decaying...
- Me like this...
- And he doomed to take his place
as the Guardian...
- You like graveyards?
I love 'em...
- I mean, who wants to live forever?
- Who wants to live forever?
- Can you tell us the way to the Source?
- You should ask her....
She's already seen the way...
- Come....
- Anna..
- It's alright...
- A child....
- It calls to you, does it not?
- This is blasphemy!
- It is truth!
- Don't touch her...
- It's okay...
- Follow the signs...
As for you lot...
- Follow the woman...
- The women...
- Anna...
- What did you see?
- Stars, worlds...
- A warning... as you get closer to the Source...
you will grow weaker...
- What's in it for you?
- Release....
- Release!
- There can be only one...
- Maybe... but they weren't talking about you...
- Joe!
- Man, come on! Have a shot!
- To the right...
- Come on!!
- Ouch....
- MacLeod!
- No!!!!
- Joe!!!
- Thank you... you've been a wonderful audience
good night!
- Joe! Get me a bandage...
- Just get anything...
- Joe...
- Methos, you're a doctor... do something...
- Oh, Joseph...
- You shouldn’t have interfered...
- Most fun I’ve had in years...
- MacLeod... Knowing you...
Watching you...
- Was an honour... It’s been my greatest--
- MacLeod, you...are...My...best friend...
- You're my best friend, Joe...
- You are the father that never kick me out...
- If there can be only one...
- It was never good for me..
- You can't cheat me now, Mac...
- It’s...your destiny...
- No...
- Joe...
- Holy Mary, Mother of God... Pray for us...
- Joe..
- Amen....
- Amen...
- I’m done...
- Didn't go quite as planned, huh?
- Don't be glimp... Not now...
- Why are you upset, MacLeod?
- Is it because Joe died? Or because you,
the great Highlander couldn’t save him?
- Go to hell...
- Is this the new MacLeod?
- Someone who's going to betray the memory
of his friend? Betray his history and his Clan?
- You quitter...
- Move it, MacLeod...
- Oh, no...
- This is holy ground!
- I don't care!
- No!
- Get up!
- This is what we do...
- Do you know why he interfered?
- Why?
- It wasn't for me.. It was for you...
- So that you might be the One... And now
you're going to piss on his grave? Well, come on!
- You can hide behind that bullshit, Methos..
But if you're looking For someone to blame..
- Blame yourself!
- We're leaving...
- No... I’m not...
- I have to go with them...
- What?
- It’s not your choice, Duncan, it’s mine.
- Anna...
- I need to find the source...
- What do you want?
- You want me to bury you next to Joe?
- Then stay with me...
- You said nothing would hurt me.
- I was chosen for this.. and so were you...
- Anna, this doesn't make sense.
- Yes, it does...
- Look...
- It calls to us...
- I saw it before..
- But it was over me like a cathedral...
- Reggie...
- Yeah, yeah, I’m on it.
- Where?
- Water... We need to go by water...
- The alignment is centred over an island...
- Like the Lady said...
- We need a boat...
- I thought you would have found someone else
to have those kids with...
- I don't want just someone's kids..
- Duncan... I made a choice...
- It went against everything I felt for you...
- You think it’s a coincidence..
We ran into each other?
- Something, some power, is guiding us...
- Can that power bring Joe back?
- We need to dock...
- Impossible...
- Why?
- Look.. Over there...There are maniacs
On that island, cannibals...
- They must have seized the port...
- That was Carl Louis, the port captain...
- I have no wish to join him...
- I have no choice... the Lady has a date...
- There is nothing there but death...
- There's death everywhere...
- May God take his soul...
- Light.... Ha..ha...ha
- We're not gonna let them do that, are we?
- No, we're not...
- Reggie.... Reggie...
- Reggie... Stop...
- I fucking Love this!
- Duck!
- What are you doing?
- God is mercyfull... Even in death...
- Duncan!!
- Everyone get down!
- So here we are... Born to be kings..
- We are princes of the universe..
- Here we belong...
Fighting to survive..
- In a world with the darkest hour..
- And here we are at the princess of the Universe...
- Here we belong....
Fighting for survival...
- We're here to be the ruler
of your world....
- It’s turning into a surprisingly good day...
- Blue house..
- Where are we going?
- Okay...
- It looks as if we're meant
to keep going to...
- We keep going east, right?
- Right...
- Listen MacLeod,thanks for saving my neck
at the dock earlier, yeah?
- You didn’t really give me much choice,
now did you, Reggie?
- Did all right...
- Find anything?
- More bodies.
- Did you find any food? - No...
- Christ al-fucking-mighty, I’m starving...
- Do not blaspheme...
- Or what? Is your good Lord gonna come
down here and slap me, is he?
- Wake up, G!
Look around you...
- I’m afraid, my old friend...
that He has not turned His back on us.
- Rather, we have turned away from Him.
- Still, a roast chicken would be nice...
- What do you think, MacLeod?
Have we come to this because of who we are?
- We live, we learn...
- Except we don't Learn, do we?
- We were given the ultimate responsibility...
free will...
- And what have we done with it? We watch generation
after generation making the same mistakes, Methos...
- The Source is His gift to us... Through it,
one us may be reborn into something more..
- More than Immortal?
- Perhaps...
- Spare us the sanctimonious bullshit, Giovanni...
- You don't know what the Source is...
No one does, if it even exists...
- How can we know we're gonna
get to the source anyways?
- Maybe the Guardian will kill us before we reach it...
- That's if we don't all kill each other first...
- That could happen...
- No... it’s not about death...
- It’s about life...
- Life...
- Okay, who wants first watch?
- Sergeant Reginald Weller reporting for duty, ma'am...
- You look cold... you want some?
It warms the blood...
- Please...
- Thanks...
- So how old are you?
- I'll be 314 years old 3 weeks from next Tuesday...
- I’m just a wee lad compared to
old Giovanni and Methos...
- You're a smart guy, Reggie...
How come you make believe you're not?
- Now, what makes you say that, love?
- When people think you’re a bit of a cabbage,
they tend to underestimate you...
- That's good for keeping a head on
one's shoulder’s when you're Immortal..
- If you know what I mean...
- Yeah...
- Why are you here?
- For the truth...
- I saw you...
- You're supposed to get some sleep...
- I know what Joe meant to you...
- I spent my entire life watching the people I love die..
- The women I love die... Tessa, Kate, all of them...
- I kept telling myself... I’m an Immortal...
it was the price I paid....
- But deep down Inside,
I always believed that one day..
- The light bulb would come on, and
I would know why I spent the Last 400 years..
- Cutting people’s' heads off to survive...
- I would know why I am what I am...
- Look, I haven't lived like you...
- I haven't seen what you've seen...
- I don't...
But we've come this far for a reason...
- I won't lose you...
- You won't...
- Hello... Reggie....
- How did you do that?
- How did you do that? How did you do that?
- I'm supposed to feel you coming...
- Fresh... flesh....
So delicate....
- Young...blue eyes...
- Fuck you...
- Reggie!
- Reggie...
- I fucking hate this bit...
- See you soon....
- Why didn’t he take his head?
- Why didn’t we know he was here?
- Help me get him in the car...
- He should be alive by now, right?
- Why isn't he coming back?
- As you get closer to the Source...
you will grow weaker...
- Reggie..... Reggie....
- Oh, my God... He's dead...
- It’s happening....
- He didn’t heal because his faith wasn't pure...
- Let's see how well you heal, brother...
- Methos!
- Giovanni!
- Stop it!
- We should go...
- In a hurry, Methos?
- Where are we going?
- What for?
- That’s all bullshit anyway... There can be only one....
the Source.... it’s all been a lie...
- Yeah, maybe it is... maybe it was just a story
we made up to make ourselves feel better at night...
- Maybe this is the way the dream ends...
- You don't believe that...
- Yeah? Why not?
We're mortal now...
- Everything has changed...
- Now what?
- I don't like it...
- He's alive...
- This is a trap...
- Be careful...
- Get out! Get out! Go!
Everyone out! Anna!
- Get out now! Go! Go!
- We are they?
- They are above us.... They are using the tree..
- Don't let them go!
- Behind us!
- Say your prayers..
- The heroes! Take them! For meat!
- I'm thirsty...
- I hope the bastards choke on me...
- This can't be the end... God wouldn’t let this
happen to a true Christian...
- You know Giovanni... I saw Christ...
- I saw Him teach... I saw Him heal...
- You! you self-centred son of a bitch..
you are no Christian!
- Anna...
- I never saw this...
- It'll be okay?
- I don't know..
- It's okay...
- There he is, Duncan...
- I saw him before...
- Hello...
- MacLeod...
- How do you like being mortal?
- It could be worse... I could be you...
- Gallows you more... That's funny...
That's very funny...
I like you MacLeod.... MacLeod...
- Enough of the bullshit... bullshit...
- I have very high hopes for you...
- Either kill me or piss off....
- No, no!
- Leave her alone...
- Anna!
- Woman, come...
- The Source calls you...
- Follow me now, or I'll kill them all...
- Anna, don't listen to him...
- Come for me...
- Anna!
- Anna no!
- We never should have
turned to be mortals...
- He's burning the rope...
- The fires burning me free...
- Giovanni .. please..
- He's releasing me...
- Giovanni.... Come on Giovanni...
- He has chosen me..
- Giovanni... Cut the ropes!
Giovanni... Cut the ropes!
- No... There can be only one...
- Giovanni...!!
- Giovanni, you bastard!
- I will leave you...
- I need someone to watch my back...
- You trust me?
- You’ll do...
- The Source calls to me...
- Time to hunt!
- They have escaped!
- Hey...
- It’s really happening...
- Go!
- Hello little priest!
- You gonna be shit, ha! ha! ha!
- God save me!
- Forgive me father for I have sinned...
- Leave him...
- I can't...
- Kill him! Die!!!
- Ready to die, priest?
- Giovanni...
- Giovanni!
- Methos.. No!!
- Go.. find Anna...
- What?
- It’s you, MacLeod... I wanted it to be me,
but...You are the best of us...
- You're both totally human and totally incorruptible,
and Joe knew that, and... I know it, too...
- You're such an asshole...
- I never said I was deep...
- Go!
- Methos...
- Come on, you greasy mongrels!
fresh meat!
- The Source...
- I'm almost there...
- I await your blessings....
- Rise... Giovanni...
- The end?
- Yes...
- I'm the One...
- No...
- Anna...
- Duncan....
I knew you would come....
- Come on...
- Get out of my way....
- Doesn't work that way, MacLeod...
- You can't just run away with the women...
- So why don't you just tell me
how it works...
- In your world...
- One of us has to die...
- I’ve heard that before....
- Duncan...
- Anna...
- Supprise!!!
- What is this?
- It's not time... Face the Guardian...
- Yeah face tthe Guardian...
- Atta boy...
- Feel that speed.... Feel that power....
- It's the Source..
- And it can be yours...
- Forever!!!
- The Source.... Intoxicating, isn't it?
- Pick up the pace or die, Highlanders!
- It’s happening...
- The moment is close...
- Yeah! The moment is close...
- It's happening...
- Anna...
- Go ahead...
- Joe Dawson screamed like a child when he died..
- Are you willing to pay the price?
- And Reggie Weller. He cried like a little girl...
You will fight McLeod....
- Yes, I killed your friends... Take whats yours...
Take your revenge....
- Be who you are!!!
- I am Duncan MacLeod
of the Clan MacLeod...
- Who I am is who I was...
- Do it, you Immortal fuck!
- Make your choice Duncan...
- Take my head!!!!
- No...
- I'm done with this...
- Aaaah! I'm cursed..
Forever! Forever!
- I feel life....
- I feel our child...
- He.... Is the One...