Wait!
Here, let me do that.
You sure you are up for this?
Can't Mrs. MacLeod be nervous?
Anna...
- Methos, try and listen to what I'm saying.
- Reggie, calm down, tell me what's going on.
Over the past week,
the planets of our solar system
have moved outside their orbital paths
and are coming into alignment.
I mean, do you know how unusual that is?
There's no simple way to explain this.
But that could just be orbital wobble.
Fucking hell, Methos!
Orbital wobble is one thing, but this...
This is outside the laws
of celestial mechanics!
And that's not all.
Literally millions of celestial bodies
from here to the central sun
of our galaxy are lining up.
When that alignment is complete...
in exactly 4 days, 3 hours, 47 minutes,
the Earth is going to be bombarded
with cosmic radiation.
The moment of the Source?
The Light of the cosmos
is literally reaching out to us.
Aye.
What about Zai? Did we hear from him?
No. Nah, he's overdue.
Isn't your friend MacLeod there?
Can't he help?
MacLeod is...
not the man he once was.
Well, just try.
- I can't stay with you Duncan.
- Why?
Duncan.
Hey. Hey you.
Please, something to eat.
You're kind, lady. Thank you. Thank you.
- Hey! Stop!
- No! No, no, no! No!
Food. Food.
Thank you.
- Hi.
- Is it good?
- Uh-huh.
Oh, God, I hate that.
Yes.
- There can be only one.
- Voice match accepted.
Login confirmed.
- Connecting.
- Yes!
Signal acquired.
- Are you sure it's only a few days
until the alignment is complete? - Guys!
- Come on, come on!
- Yes.
- Four days at most.
- Damn it!
They are going crazy out there.
Source better be some big medicine,
or else we're all going down the toilet.
- Reg!
- Z! Where the hell have you been, man?
Reg, there's no time. It's coming down.
I think I found it!
- Where is Giovanni?
- What have you found Zai?
I found ancient writings in Gaza.
I followed them,
they took me to central Europe.
And I found the location of the Source.
Z! I'm losing you mate.
Try and stabilize your signal.
- Zai, easy, okay? From the beginning.
- I can't hear you. I can't hear you.
Zai, you do God's work.
- Don't be afraid.
- Your Eminence.
Tell us what you found.
The ancient writings I found in Gaza,
I followed them.
They took me to central Europe.
Then I knew I was getting close.
I found a monastery where
the monks studied an ancient text
that spoke of the Source.
One of the monks took me to a place where
it last happened over 10,000 years ago.
I could feel the power of this place.
And then, he appeared.
So I ran. And I ran.
He has risen.
The Guardian.
Signal failure.
Reacquiring signal.
Signal reacquired.
- I always thought the Guardian was bullshit.
- He's the immortal antichrist.
The false prophet created in evil.
Well if he's such a bad boy,
then why didn't he take Zai's head?
To get to us. He knows Zai's not alone.
Do you think he knows
we are looking for the Source?
- He must.
- Signal acquired.
- He's more than Immortal.
- Zai, where is the location of the Source?
- He's like... like death.
- Zai, are you in danger?
- Zai! The location.
- He's coming.
- Zai! Get out of there!
- What have you learnt? Give us something.
I've written the co-ordinates down
on this map. The co-ordinates are...
The co-ordinates are on...
Okay. You have to get to the monastery.
You have to find
the monks that bear the symbol
of the Brothers of Doleo.
They will help you find the Source.
- Zai, save yourself. Get out of there! Zai!
- Zai, we have enough. Save yourself!
Pray for me, Father.
Reg.
Can you get the signal back?
Did you get the signal back?
- Zai!
What are the Delio Brothers?
Brotherhood of pain.
Sounds like a fun bunch.
They're an ancient religious order
in estern Europe.
They are not a religious order!
They are an heretical cult.
But their Elder might be able to help us.
The Elder corrupted his monks.
Turned them from the true faith
during the fall of Rome.
Rome's a long time ago my friend.
Not for me, it wasn't.
- Giovanni, this could be it!
- Guys!
If this Elder could help us, who gives a toss?
Let's go and find him.
Zai's no Jack-the-Lad.
He can handle himself.
I mean, he's got a shot, right?
- Joe.
- Methos! What do you got?
The Guardian is awake. Find MacLeod.
There can be only me.
Hello.
This is the end of time!
You think I'm mad?
Maybe a little bit crazy.
What are you?
I'm the Guardian.
Question is who are you?
- I'm Duncan MacLeod.
I'm Duncan MacLeod.
You have squandered your precious gift!
You could have ruled the world...
and you pissed it away.
- Have a nice day.
- The female, Anna.
- She's not for you.
- What's Anna got to do with this?
Nothing. Everything.
- It's time for me and you to dance.
- In that outfit?
Foreplay.
Let's go.
Come on, over here!
Are you the One, MacLeod, MacLeod?
Would you kill to be the One?
Would you kill her, MacLeod?
Hello, Joe!
- Joe.
- Get in the car.
- Get out of here, Joe.
- I don't have time for this bullshit!
- Get in the car!
- What are you doing?
Seek the Source.
What?
The Source.
- Joe!
- Before you get all whacked out, just listen to me.
Joe, stop the car!
Stop the damn car!
- You're a Watcher, you can't interfere.
- I just said fuck it..
- You took an oath.
- There is no Watcher organization anymore.
Most of my people are dead.
You shouldn't have interfered.
If I hadn't, you'd be dead.
Sure, fine. Go ahead.
Go back and let that thing kill you.
What do you have to live for anyway?
- He mentioned Anna.
- Have you even talked to her?
No, not in months. And don't give me
any of that end-of-days bullshit.
Methos and others don't think it's bullshit.
They're looking for the Source.
- Oh, the Source.
- You can join them and find out what its about.
And see what it has to do with Anna.
Or you can go back and play with that freak.
It's your call.
I can't believe I'm letting you drag me into this.
I know this is going to be hard to explain,
but... I'm immortal.
It's just a dream.
I was born in the Highlands
of Scotland in 1592.
It's more than a dream, Duncan.
Anna.
Nothing will hurt you.
- So you're not going to grow old?
- This is how I am.
I'm going to grow old, though.
Will you still love me when I'm old?
I'll always love you.
I'm leaving. I can't stay with you, Duncan.
- Why?
- You mean everything to me.
But it's not enough.
What do you mean I mean everything
to you and I'm not enough?
- Make sense, Anna.
- I can't!
What do you want from me?
The impossible.
I want a child.
A child...
It's good to see you, G.
- Who are you?
- I'm Duncan MacLeod.
MacLeod, MacLeod.
May I ask you what you're doing here?
- Reggie Weller.
- My astronomer.
And part time cultural stereotype.
- Sure, you are.
- Funny! Who's that?
It's Joe Dawson, a friend of mine.
Hey!
Methos! Been a long time.
This is different.
-Times are different, MacLeod.
- Yeah.
Leather's a really good look for you, Methos.
Giovanni.
- I hear you're on a quest for the Source.
- You make it sound so grand.
We are here to get information.
Brave men died to get us this far.
Brothers of Doleo.
Rumour has it they've been governed
by the same Elder for thousands of years.
- One of us?
- I'm thinking so.
Well let's find out.
What's a man of the cloth doing
on the quest for the Source?
- I am here for the greater glory of God.
- What if you don't like what you find?
You assume there will be an inherent contradiction
between what we will encounter and the Gospel.
- I know that will not be the case.
- You seem very certain of that.
Doesn't it? The Lord guides
our hands on this holy quest.
We are all in His service.
Question is, Duncan MacLeod, are you?
I had a sneaky suspicion
you'd know where to find him.
Yeah, well...
- You know I did it for him and not for you.
- Sure.
- What do you want?
- We have come to see your Elder.
We have no Elder.
That went well.
Oy! You! Open this door!
Right!
Wait a minute!
Who's that?
That's my wife!
Hello.
I can explain.
Stop!
The Elder will see you...
now that she is here.
Hello Anna Teshemka.
Hello Duncan MacLeod.
You look like shit.
- What are you doing here?
- Look, I have so much to tell you.
- You won't even believe what's been
happening to me. - Lead us.
- Duncan, I have visions.
- Uh-huh.
- Seriously! I saw this, I saw you, I saw all of you.
- Come, girl. I'm near.
Look... well.
There are worse things than death.
Apparently.
- What do you want?
- We seek the Source.
Are you willing to pay the price?
- That's fixed.
- Thank you.
- Hoo! Hello!
- Yeah. It's a sweet piece, but...
- This is my beat, okay, Reggie?
- Sorry.
What is it?
I don't know.
So you have encountered the Guardian.
A riddle that cannot be solved.
A force that cannot be defeated.
Man, that's one fast bird!
You stay here.
I can take care of this.
I was once like you,
long ago, before recorded time.
Like now, the world had fallen into chaos.
The people cried out for a redeemer.
Do any of you have redeeming quality?
- Greetings, brother.
- This is holy ground!
We were a group much like yours.
All of us Immortals from different tribes.
All seeking the truth.
We all thought we would find
the answer in the Source.
But there were darker,
secret desires in our hearts.
The journey was long.
Our tempers flared, and being Immortals,
heads were taken.
Finally, there were only three of us left,
the strongest of our kind.
But the ancient one guarding the Source
was stronger still.
My friend fought valiantly,
but I wanted my immortality.
The source wasn't mine to take.
Something went terribly wrong.
It left us both cursed.
Both, for ever decaying.
Me like this...
and he doomed to take his place
as the Guardian.
You like graveyards? I love them.
I mean, who wants to live forever?
# Who wants to live forever? #
Can you tell us the way to the Source?
You should ask her.
She's already seen the way.
Come.
Anna.
It's all right.
A child!
It calls to you, does it not?
- This is blasphemy!
- It is truth!
- Don't touch her!
- It's okay!
Follow the signs. As for you lot...
Follow the woman.
- The woman.
- Anna.
- What did you see?
- Stars, worlds.
A warning. As you get closer to the Source,
you will grow weaker.
- What's in it for you?
- Release!
Release!
There can be only one.
Maybe, but they weren't talking about you.
Joe!
Hey, come on! Have a shot!
To the right!
Come on!
Ouch!
MacLeod!
No!
Joe!
Thank you, you've been a wonderful
audience. Good night!
Joe! Get me a bandage!
Just get anything!
Joe!
Methos, you're a doctor. Do something.
Oh, Joseph.
- You shouldn't have interfered.
- Most fun I've had in years.
MacLeod, knowing you, watching you...
was an honour. It's been my greatest...
MacLeod, you... are... my... best friend.
You're my best friend, Joe.
You are the father that never kick me out.
- If there can be only one.
- It was never good for me.
You can't cheat me now, Mac.
- It's... your destiny.
- Joe.
- Holy Mary, Mother of God, pray for us.
Joe.
Amen.
I'm done.
Didn't go quite as planned, huh?
Don't be glimp. Not now!
Why are you upset, MacLeod?
Is it because Joe died, or because you,
the great Highlander, couldn't save him?
- Go to hell!
- Is this the new MacLeod?
Someone who's going to betray the memory
of his friend? Betray his history and his Clan?
Quitter!
- Move it, MacLeod.
- Oh, no.
- This is holy ground!
- I don't care!
- No!
- Get up!
This is what we do.
- Do you know why he interfered?
- Why?
It wasn't for me. It was for you!
So that you might be the One.
And now  you're going to piss
on his grave? Well, come on!
You can hide behind that bullshit, Methos.
But if you're looking for someone to blame,
blame yourself!
- We're leaving.
- No, I'm not.
- I have to go with them.
- What?
- It's not your choice, Duncan, it's mine.
- Anna.
- I need to find the Source.
- What do you want?
You want me to bury you next to Joe?
Then stay with me.
You said nothing would hurt me.
I was chosen for this. And so were you.
- Anna, this doesn't make sense.
- Yes, it does.
Look.
It calls to us.
I saw it before.
But it was over me like a cathedral.
Reggie?
- Yeah, yeah, I'm on it.
- Where?
Water. We need to go by water.
The alignment is centred over an island!
Like the lady said.
We need a boat.
I thought you would have found
someone else to have those kids with.
I don't want just someone's kids.
Duncan, I made a choice.
It went against everything I felt for you.
You think it's a coincidence?
We ran into each other?
Something, some power, is guiding us.
Can that power bring Joe back?
We need to dock.
- Impossible.
- Why?
Look. Over there. There are maniacs
on that island. Cannibals.
They must have seized the port.
That was Carl Louis, the port captain.
I have no wish to join him.
I have no choice. The lady has a date.
- There is nothing there but death.
- There's death everywhere.
May God take his soul.
Light!
We're not going to let them do that, are we?
No, we're not.
Reggie! Reggie!
- Reggie, stop!
- Now?
- I fucking love this!
- Duck!
- What are you doing?
- God is mercifull, even in death.
Duncan!
Everyone get down!
♪ So here we are
Born to be kings ♪
♪ We are princes of the universe ♪
♪ Here we belong
Fighting to survive ♪
♪ In a world with the darkest hour ♪
♪ And here we are
We're the princess of the Universe ♪
♪ Here we belong
Fighting for survival ♪
♪ We've come to be the rulers of your world ♪
It's turning into a surprisingly good day.
Blue house.
- Where are we going?
- Okay.
It looks as if we're meant to keep going to...
- We keep going east, right?
- Right.
Listen, MacLeod. Thanks for saving
my neck at the dock earlier, yeah?
You didn't really give me much choice,
now did you, Reggie?
- Did all right.
- Find anything?
More bodies.
- Did you find any food?
- No.
- Christ all-fucking-mighty, I'm starving!
- Do not blaspheme!
Or what? Is your good Lord going to
come  down here and slap me, is he?
Wake up, G! Look around you.
I'm afraid, my old friend,
that He has not turned His back on us.
Rather, we have turned away from Him.
Still, a roast chicken would be nice.
What do you think, MacLeod?
Have we come to this because of who we are?
- We live, we learn.
- Except we don't learn, do we?
We were given the ultimate
responsibility, free will.
And what have we done with it?
We watch generation after generation
making the same mistakes, Methos.
The Source is His gift to us.
Through it, one of us may be reborn
into something more.
- More than Immortal?
- Perhaps.
Spare us the sanctimonious bullshit, Giovanni!
You don't know what the Source is.
No one does. If it even exists!
How can we know we're going
to get to the source anyway?
Maybe the Guardian will kill us
before we reach it.
That's if we don't all kill each other first.
- That could happen.
- No, it's not about death.
- It's about life.
- Life.
Okay, who wants first watch?
Sergeant Reginald Weller
reporting for duty, ma'am.
You look cold. You want some?
It warms the blood.
- Please.
- Thanks.
- So how old are you?
- I'll be 314 years old 3 weeks from next Tuesday.
I'm just a wee lad compared
to  old Giovanni and Methos.
You're a smart guy, Reggie.
How come you make believe you're not?
Now, what makes you say that, love?
When people think you're a bit of a cabbage,
they tend to underestimate you.
That's good for keeping a head on
one's shoulder's when you're immortal.
If you know what I mean.
Yeah.
- Why are you here?
- For the truth.
I saw you.
You're supposed to get some sleep.
I know what Joe meant to you.
I spent my entire life
watching the people I love die.
The women I love die,
Tessa, Kate, all of them.
I kept telling myself... I'm an Immortal.
It was the price I paid.
But deep down inside,
I always believed that one day
the light bulb would come on, and
I would know why I spent the last 400 years
cutting people's heads off to survive.
I would know why I am what I am.
Look, I haven't lived like you.
I haven't seen what you've seen.
I don't. But we've come this far for a reason.
I won't lose you.
You won't.
Hello... Reggie.
- How did you do that?
I'm supposed to feel you coming.
Fresh... flesh. So delicate.
- Young... blue eyes.
- Fuck you!
Reggie!
I fucking hate this bit.
See you soon.
- Why didn't he take his head?
- Why didn't we know he was here?
Help me get him in the car.
He should be alive by now, right?
Why isn't he coming back?
As you get closer to the Source,
you will grow weaker.
Reggie.
Oh, my God. He's dead.
- It's happening.
- He didn't heal because his faith wasn't pure.
- Let's see how well you heal, brother.
- Methos!
- Giovanni!
- Stop it!
- We should go.
- In a hurry, Methos?
Where are we going? What for?
It's all bullshit anyway. There can be
only one, the Source. It's all been a lie.
Yeah, maybe it is.
Maybe it was just a story we made up
to make ourselves feel better at night.
- Maybe this is the way the dream ends.
- You don't believe that.
Yeah? Why not? We're mortal now.
Everything has changed.
Now what?
I don't like it.
He's alive!
This is a trap.
Be careful.
- Get out! Get out! Let's go! Get out! Anna!
- I told you it was a trap!
Get out now! Go! Go!
- Where are they?
- They are above us. They are using the trees.
Behind us!
Say your prayers.
They're heroes! Take them! For meat!
I'm thirsty!
I hope the bastards choke on me!
This can't be the end. God wouldn't
let this happen to a true Christian.
You know Giovanni... I saw Christ.
I saw Him teach, I saw Him heal.
You, you self-centred son of a bitch.
You are no Christian!
- Anna.
- I never saw this.
- It'll be okay.
- I don't know.
It's okay.
There he is, Duncan.
I saw him before.
Hello...
MacLeod.
- How do you like being mortal?
- It could be worse. I could be you.
Gallows you more.
That's funny. That's very funny.
I like you MacLeod, MacLeod.
- Enough of the bullshit, bullshit.
- I had very high hopes for you.
Either kill me or piss off.
Leave her alone.
Anna!
Woman, come.
The Source calls you.
Follow me now, or I'll kill them all.
Anna, don't listen to him.
Come for me.
Anna!
Anna, no!
We never should have trusted the mortal.
Shut up, Giovanni! Stop moaning!
He's burning the rope.
The fire's burning me free.
Giovanni.
He's releasing me.
- Giovanni. Come on, Giovanni. Giovanni.
- He has chosen me.
Giovanni, cut the ropes.
Giovanni, cut the ropes!
No. There can be only one.
Giovanni!
Giovanni, you bastard!
- I'd leave you.
- I need someone to watch my back.
- You trust me?
- You'll do.
The Source calls to me.
Time to hunt!
They have escaped!
Hey.
It's really happening.
Go!
- Forgive me, Father, for I have sinned!
- God save me!
- Leave him.
- I can't.
- Kill him!
Ready to die, priest?
Giovanni...
Giovanni!
Methos, no!
- Go, find Anna.
- What?
It's you, MacLeod. I wanted it to be me,
but... you are the best of us.
You're both totally human and totally incorruptible,
and Joe knew that, and... I know it, too.
You're such an asshole.
I never said I was deep.
- Let's go!
- Methos...
Come on, you greasy mongrels! Fresh meat!
The Source!
I'm almost there.
- I await your blessings.
- Rise, Giovanni.
- Is this... the end?
- Yes.
I am the One.
No.
Anna.
Duncan, I knew you would come.
Come on.
- Get out of my way.
- Doesn't work that way, MacLeod.
You can't just run away with the woman.
So why don't you just tell me how it works...
- ...in your world.
- One of us has to die.
I've heard that before.
Duncan.
Duncan!
Anna!
- Surprise!
- What is this?
- It's not time. Face the Guardian.
- Yeah, face the Guardian.
Atta boy.
Feel that speed. Feel that power.
It's the Source.
And it can be yours.
Forever!
The Source, intoxicating, isn't it?
Pick up the pace or die, Highlander!
The moment is close.
Yeah! The moment is close.
It's happening.
No, Anna!
Go ahead.
Joe Dawson screamed
like a child when he died.
Are you willing to pay the price?
And Reggie Weller. He cried
like a little girl as I cut him in pieces.
You will fight, MacLeod. You will fight!
Yes, I killed your friends.
Take what's yours. Take your revenge.
Be who you are!
I am Duncan MacLeod
of the Clan MacLeod.
Who I am is who I was.
Do it, you immortal fuck!
Make your choice Duncan.
- Take my head!
- No.
I'm done with this.
I'm cursed forever!
I feel life.
I feel our child.
He is the One.