This is the Persian Empire
known today as Iran.
For 2,500 years, this land
was ruled by a series of kings
known as "Shahs".
In 1950, the people of Iran
elected Mohammad Mosaddegh
a secular democrat, as prime minister.
He nationalized British and US
petroleum holdings,
returning Iran's oil to its people.
But in 1953,
the US and Great Britain
engineered a coup d'etat
that deposed Mosaddegh,
and installed Reza Pahlavi as Shah.
The young child was known
for opulence and excess.
His wife was rumored to bathe in milk,
while the Shah had his lunches
flown in by concord from Paris.
The people starved.
The Shah kept power through
his ruthless internal police,
the Savak.
An era of torture and fear began.
He then began a campaign
to westernize Iran,
enraging the the mostly
traditional Shia population.
In 1979,
the people of Iran overthrew the Shah.
The exiled cleric, Ayatollah Khomeini,
returned to rule Iran.
It descended into score settling,
death squads and chaos.
Dying of cancer, the Shah
was given asylum in the US.
The Iranian people took
to the streets outside the US embassy,
demanding that the Shah
be returned, tried…
and hanged.
The carnival is a
little bigger today, huh?
The windows are supposed
to be bulletproof, right?
They have never been tested.
Okay, you just need to finish filling out
this section here.
We need some security.
Yes, it is your responsibility-
They drew over the walls.
We should all split.
I'm gonna close up my office.
My God!
Marins to Number 1.
Full back.
– Look, I need police,
– Can anyone hear me?
– I need police right now.
– We're on the second floor.
– You understand me?
– We need help.
Right now, goddamn it!
Can anybody hear me?
There is a breach.
Burn everything! Burn it, now!
Alright burn everything,
all the files, file cabinets, safe.
Lets get a cart over here.
Burn it all, come on!
Burn everything, including
the classified. Everything!
Don't fucking shoot anybody.
You don't want to be
the son of a bitch who started the war.
They need an hour to burn the classified.
I need you to hold.
If you shoot one person,
they're gonna kill every
single one of us in here.
I'm telling you if we're going to go,
we need to go now!
– And we need to make a decision, and-
– Joe can we- Joe can we wait,
can we wait until
the Iranian police come?
– No!
– They're not coming.
How do you know they're not coming?
They may well be coming.
The police have abandoned their post-
If the police are not coming, okay,
then the army's gonna come.
The Prime Minister is not gonna let
the embassy be taken over.
I understand. The Prime Minister
may come tomorrow,
but the Komiteh are here today.
Alright, is there- is there any value
that we're waiting 15-
Look at me!
No one is coming.
Burn it!
We have forty minutes.
Get it down to the incinerator,
in the vault. Now!
Tear gas is a last resort only.
I repeat: only if you're under threat.
In here, we are in America right now,
outside of these doors, we are in Iran!
I'm not going out there!
– They're not safe here.
-Alright, first let's get these-
If they get caught
applying for visas to the US…
You know what, lets-
lets wait five minutes.
We're in the only building
with direct access to the street,
if we're going to go,
then we need to go now!
– Yeah, I'm in.
– Yeah.
Yeah, lets go.
I'm going outside.
Why?
To reason them.
Open the door!
Open this goddamn door!
You said you wanna see the world, Elton?
Let me in! Let me in!
– Burn it all, come on!
– Right come on, guys!
The safe and the filing cabinets get long.
All four drawers,
I want them shredded, right now!
But the shred not fast enough.
Guys, get the visa plates.
All four, and anything
else you see out there.
If in doubt, you shred it.
We've got ten minutes,
lets go, go, go, everything!
Get the shredder.
There are no police.
– Okay.
– Come on.
– Where do we go?
– We gotta get off the streets.
This way, up here to the left.
These fucks hit us,
we can't hit 'em back?
Mossaddegh, we did it to them first.
The Soviets would put up with this shit,
they would fucking invade them.
Shaffer!
Sir, what d'you expect? We helped the guy
torture and deball an entire population.
How many were there?
At least fifty. We're not sure.
Shaffer!
You still haven't found Shaffer?
No I was screaming his name
'cos I was fucking 'em.
It's confirmed, sir, six escaped.
I was told five.
Now sir, apparently it's six.
So what happened?
Not clear. We know they
escaped the embassy.
Where are they?
The Canadian Ambassador's house.
Do they stay put?
Are we attempting a rescue?
I put through the Secretary of State.
Yes.
Is White House joining?
They're claiming the Embassy
was a den of espionage.
We wish it was a fucking den of espionage.
CIA's got three people over there,
they don't see a revolution coming?
Call it something other then intelligence.
Hold for the Chief of Staff.
Harding?
I'll call him back.
They're sticking to it, no release
till we expel the Shah.
Well, put him on a plane then, fuck him!
He's half dead and he's in chemo.
Well, we took him in, he's ours now.
Great, so we'll take any prick
as long as he's got cancer?
Just the pricks on our side.
So all of our other pricks
on their prick thrones
will know that when they
get thrown out on a rail,
they won't get their
fucking spleens taken out
by some camel vet in Sinai.
What about the six who are
with the Canadians?
We've got sixty in the Embassy
with guns to their heads right now.
The whole world is
watching the Embassy.
That makes them safer
than the six on the street.
Bonnie Sauder's saying
it will be over in twenty-four hours.
We leave the six where they are.
I'll go brief the President.
Right, I'll through it.
Iran's Revolutionary Guard, has
rounded up a gang of terrorist blamed
for one murder of a half-dozen
followers of Ayatollah Khomeini.
It says security at Khomeini's home
now has been raised.
This by the way, is the 69th day that the
American hostages have been held in Tehran,
there is no change reported
in the hostage situation.
In this country, George Mitty died last
night, he was eighty five years old.
Yeah.
Yes.
What?
To begin with, of course,
we wanted to learn
about the hostages held in
the American Embassy compound.
They may not understand what their
ordeal means to their countrymen.
That this nation,
their nation, is outraged.
And we cannot really
know what it is like
inside the prison
that was once our embassy.
Actions of Iran have shocked
the civilized world.
Our embassy has been seized, and
more than sixty American citizens
continue to be held as hostages,-
As the situation in Iran this morning
is unchanged for the hostages,-
the NBC situation in Iran
has changed however-
What happened?
Six of them went out a back exit.
Brits turned them away,
Kiwis turned them away,
Canadians took 'em in.
Traffic calls them 'House Guests'.
They haven't left the Canadian
Ambassador's house since it happened.
Why didn't we get them ten weeks ago?
Too dangerous.
We got revolutionary guards going
door to door, like Jehovah's Witnesses.
Half of them think that Khomeini's been
too lenient on the ones in the Embassy.
What about the White House?
Carter's shitting enough bricks
to build the pyramids.
The Canadians are done,
they say they're baring too much risk.
Their Foreign Secretary
corners Vance in Brussels,
and told him she wants
the six of them out.
Who else knows?
Just the families.
Meanwhile, some genius in our Embassy
was keeping a mug book on
everybody who worked there.
Jesus Christ!
We think it got shredded
before they got in.
But now the bastards are using
sweatshop kids
to reassemble the shreds.
Once they reassemble that book,
they'll know six Americans got out
and they'll know what they look like.
Standing room only for
beheadings in the square.
Who's handling?
State is coordinating in-house.
State?
They don't do exfil's.
They do now.
They wanna run it by us,
strictly as consultants.
Engell says, it's a lose-lose.
These people die,
they die badly, publicly.
State wants the blame,
we'll give it to 'em.
What does he want me here for?
So he can tell State
he ran it by his best exfil guy.
Okay.
This is Bob Pender from State OS,
he's been talking
to Morgan, an ex-staff.
Thank you.
Alright.
Mark and Cora Lijek,
twenty-nine and twenty-five,
he's a Consular Officer, she's
an assistant, newly weds,
They uh… only just got
there a couple months ago,
No language skills
or in-country knowledge.
Henry Lee Schatz,
Agricultural attaché from Idaho,
a bit of an oddball apparently,
he was there to sell U.S.
tractors to Iranian agro.
Joe Stafford, late twenties
he's smart
and a climber, speaks Farsi,
he arranged the hire of his wife,
Kathy.
The Embassy was understaffed,
so the faculty wives
were the typing pool.
And Bob Anders,
senior consular officer,
oldest of the group,
and most likely to be group leader.
They've been hiding at the
Canadian Ambassador's residence.
Fortunately, we do not believe the
Iranians are aware the six have escaped.
So…
What we'd like for this are bicycles.
We've identified back roads
from the Chamran district,
couple of rat lines
through the mountains
to the crossing near Tabriz.
Cars are off the table,
because of the road blocks.
We wait until the weather clears up,
then deliver the six bikes,
provide them with maps
to the Turkish border.
We have intelligence,
they can ride bicycles
or we're prepared to send in
somebody to teach 'em.
Or you could just send in training wheels
and meet them at the border with Gatorade.
Tony…
It's three hundred miles
to the Turkish border.
They'd need a support team
following them with a tire pump.
We were just asked to sharp shoot this,
State is handling the ops.
I'm sorry, who is this?
Tony is an exfil spesh,
he's got a lot of Shah's
people out after the fall.
Sir, if these people can read or add,
pretty soon they're gonna figure out
they're six short of a full deck.
It's winter. You can't afford
to wait around until spring,
so it's nice enough
to take a bike ride.
They only way out
of that city is the airport.
You build new cover identities for 'em,
you send in a Moses, he takes
them out on a commercial flight.
We've explored those options.
You're never gonna get them through
airport control, Komiteh own the place.
They could pose as reporters, if the
government issued seventy something…
– Seventy four.
– Visas,
– for American journalists…
– And the Revolutionary Guards
keep them on seventy four leashes.
If they're caught with
fake journalist creds,
it's Peter and Jane's head
in a noose in an hour.
Look, North America accents
gives us limited options,
so we get the Canadians
to issue them passports.
What about English teachers
at the international school?
It's a good idea, but that school's
been closed for eight months.
Okay, so how about
'the do-gooders'?
Six Canadians have been over there
inspecting crops, ensuring the kids
are getting enough to eat,
we give them creds, makes
them look like ag' NGOs.
It's a 'feed the kids' thing.
Okay.
Those kids are black.
Those are African kids.
We can get ethnically appropriate kids.
Are there starving kids in Iran?
I'm sure there's some
skinny kids in Iran.
What about missionary?
– Or… seeds…
called… "seeds of hope".
Hold on… Sir, do you have
this newspaper in front of you?
Would you mind taking a look at it?
What's in this picture?
Tehran.
Right.
What's on the ground?
– Snow.
– Right.
So what crops are the 'do-gooders'
inspecting under frosting?
Sir…
Exfils are like abortions.
You don't wanna need one.
But when you do,
you don't do it yourself.
You have a better plan?
No Sir.
What ever the conflicting
signals from Iran today,
for that matter everyday,
about whether the hostages will
or will not be tried as spies,
the government of the United States
has not deviated from its basic demands:
the hostages must be freed.
.. to defend human rights,
it not only does not defend them,
it violates them for all nations.
We demand extradition of a man
who for more than 37 years,
with the United States support,
has killed months old babies
in the arms of their mothers.
He said that if the Americans try
military force to rescue the hostages,
the students will kill them all
and blow up the Embassy.
Americans were outraged
at Iran and anyone Iranian.
Before this decision was taken,
there was a demonstration in Houston.
An Iranian flag was burned,
while Anti-Iranians demonstrators
gathered near the Iranian
Consulate. The demonstrators-
.. also it's what led to a decision
to scrutinize the bases of the Iranian-
They knew exactly what
was going on, they knew it.
But I don't understand wha-
what they should do now,
send them back, just to-
to be tortured and killed?
I don't think that justice
is the worst thing.
When did people first tell you
that torture was going on in Iran?
They would never come to me and say:
"Well Sir, we have tortured this fellow".
.. Sadat of Egypt he calls you Imam,
forgive me, his words not mine: A lunatic.
Why didn't he have a choice,
why do you think he didn't have a choice?
Because he would have been
referred to as a barbarian.
– Please!
– That's why they're stating
he liked the current regime!
The Shah did more for women's right-
I think we've better if…
Please everyone, get into the coal.
.. Get out of here!
At one point the mob
cornered one of Iranians.
When he tried to protect
himself, this is what happened.
Hit him again!
Hit him until he can't take it anymore!
We're sick of them!
– Yeah!
America!
.. even in our little community here,
I mean people are drawn
uptight, they're tense.
They shouldn't even let those
students in that Embassy there.
Just shoot a couple of 'em.
Show 'em we mean business.
Men who served in Vietnam for what
they believed was right are angry.
I'm mad as hell.
I'm- I'm like the guy screaming on that
movie program in 'network' you know,
I've had it! And if huh…
if need be I'll bear arms again!
That's the way it is,
Wednesday, January 16th, 1980.
74th day of captivity
for 50 Americans in Iran.
Hello?
My man!
I'll get mom.
I'm calling for you.
Did you do your homework tonight?
Yeah it was easy.
Excellent.
What are we watching?
Battle for the Planet of the Apes.
Tell me, what channel is it on?
Five.
Alright.
What did you do at school today?
Nothing, I don't know.
Nothing.
It can't be nothing.
Something must've happened.
After school I've traded baseball cards,-
Hmm-Hmm…
Ok you know those science
fiction, Star Trek, Star Wars,
they need an exotic location to shoot,
Moonscape, Mars, desert, you know…
Now image this.
They're a Canadian film crew on a location
scout for a science fiction movie.
We put it out there,
the Canadian producers
put it out there.
They were looking at Egypt, Istanbul.
Then we go to the Consulate and say:
'Hey, we want to look in Iran too'.
I fly into Tehran, we all fly
out together as a film crew.
Done.
Flamboyant cover identity
should be avoided
as it increases operational visibility.
This is a lot more
plausible than foreigners
who wanna become teachers in Iran.
You want to blend in with the population
you don't look like a rodeo clown.
Just gonna wake up tomorrow morning
and be in the movie business?
We already have credentials
for the teachers.
No Sir, we have a contact in-
– Chambers.
– John Chambers,
he's a Hollywood prosthetics guy, he's got
an Oscar, he did Planet of the Apes
he's done a bunch of contract
work for us in the past.
I go see him, he sets this up.
One, two days, make it look real.
I went outside for thirty seconds.
Alright?
Could you give me a break?
I can't breath in this house.
I need some fresh air,
I can't- I can't breath!
Stay inside the fucking house!
Who saw me go outside, I'm just curious?
– That's not the point.
– That's not the point Bob.
Doesn't matter if I saw you
go out or you see me.
– Did you see me go out?
– No! You did go outside…
I did. Okay, I saw you.
Bob, it only takes one
second for them to spot you.
Some Americans are missing.
Look at the repaired list
of embassy employees.
The numbers don't match.
Finish assembling the
pictures from the Embassy.
All I need is their faces
and I will find them.
Yes Sir, it'll be done.
We want you to go to LA.
If you can make the movie thing
credible, we'll take it to the director.
Don't fuck up.
The whole country is watching you.
They just don't know it.
My creation…
My creation!
What the fuck, Bryan?
– Cut!
– We are cutting!
Chambers!
John Chambers make up!
He says the minotaur prosthetic
is too tight so he can't act.
If he could act, he wouldn't
be playing a minotaur.
Mr. Chambers…
Kevin Arkins.
Hey Tony.
What are you shooting?
Monster movie.
Yeah? Any good?
Target audience will hate it.
Who's the target audience?
People with eyes.
Talk to me.
It's an exfil.
From where?
Worst place you can think of.
Universal Studio.
How are you gonna get in the Embassy?
They're not in the Embassy.
During the takeover six people escaped.
They're hiding out in Tehran…
and that's who I'm gonna go get.
What am I making?
I need you to help me
make a fake movie.
Well, you're in the right place.
I wanna setup a production company
and build a cover around making a movie.
– That we're not gonna make.
– No.
So you wanna come to
Hollywood and act like a big shot,
Yeah.
– without actually doing anything.
– No.
You'll fit right in.
Let's see.
Well this one has got an M.A. in English,
she should be your screenwriter.
Sometimes they go along on scouts
because they want their free meals.
Here's your director.
Can you teach somebody
to be a director in a day?
You teach a recess monkey
to be a director in a day.
Look if you're gonna do this,
you gotta do it.
The Kominiacs are fruit loops,
but they got cousins
who sell prayer rugs
and A-tracks on Le Brea.
You can't build cover stories
around a movie that doesn't exist.
You need a script, you need a producer.
Make me a producer.
No. You're… an
associate producer at best.
You're gonna do a 20 million
dollars Star Wars rip-off.
You need somebody who's a somebody,
to put their name on it.
Somebody respectable…
with credits…
who you can trust
with classified information…
who'd produce a fake movie…
for free.
Hi, I only got a couple of minutes.
I'm getting a lifetime
achievement award.
Mazel tov, Lester.
I'd rather stay home and count
the wrinkles on my dog's balls.
Okay.
You got six people hiding out
in a town of what… 4 million people,
all of whom chant death to
America' all the live long day.
You want to set up a movie in a week,
you want to lie to Hollywood,
a town where everybody lies for a living,
then you're gonna sneak 007 over here,
into a country that wants CIA
blood on their breakfast cereal,
and you're gonna walk the Brady Bunch
out of the most watched city in the world.
That's about a hundred militia
at the airport. That's right.
Right.
Look I… I got to tell ya,
we- we did suicide missions in the
Army that had better odds than this.
Sir, the car is here.
You ever think, Lester,
this is all for the cameras?
Well, they're getting the ratings,
I'll say that for them.
We're going to need a script.
I love you.
Sahar, how are you doing?
Fine, thank you.
Your friends from Canada, ma'am,
all this time, they never go out.
Sahar knows.
How about 'The Horses of Achilles'?
Νо gооd. Νоbоdy dоеѕ wеѕtеrnѕ аnymоrе.
It's ancient Troy.
If it's got horses in it,
it's a western.
Hey, Kenny please?
Yeah it's John Chambers,
about the office space.
It doesn't matter.
It's a fake movie.
If I'm doing a fake movie,
it's going to be a fake hit.
Cardinal wants all cover options
on his desk Friday morning.
Engell's prepping the bikes option,
teachers option,
you have 72 hours to make yours better.
Fine.
Hey is 8006 still on the open list?
Yeah I'll hold.
Fade in on a starship landing.
An exotic Middle Eastern vibe.
Women gather offering ecstatic
libations to the sky gods.
Argo.
"A Science-Fantasy Adventure."
It's a turnaround, it's dog shit.
It's a space movie in the Middle East.
Does it matter if-
Could we get the option?
Why do we need the option?
You're worried about the Ayatollah?
Try the WGA.
Just let me do the talking.
I've known this guy for 25 years,
he's full of shit, and he comes on hard,
but uh… I can handle it.
You want to go into production
with this in one month?
Up like a carny ride.
One month, yeah.
– Who are you again?
– Kevin Arkins, Studio 6 Films.
He's the money.
Look, what d'you say uh…
fifteen thou'and, let's close on this?
You want me to be honest with you, Les?
No. I would like you to bullshit me, Max.
Alright.
I enjoyed your films, the early ones.
I took this meeting out of respect,
because I wanted to say no to your face.
Thank you. Very respectful.
You're finished, Lester.
Get your cataracts fixed,
read the trades.
MGM just capitalized for six new films.
They're screaming for Sci-Fi.
They're offering me four times
what you guys are offering me.
Well… what can I say?
Congratulations.
But see,
it kind of worries me what you
said, let me tell you why.
Couple of weeks ago I was sitting
at Trader Vic's, I was enjoying a Mai Tai,
when my pal, Warren Beatty comes in,
he wishes me well,
we have a little chat.
Seems he was attached
to star in 'Zulu Empire',
which was just gonna anchor
that MGM slate.
But Warren confided in me that
the picture's gone over budget
because the Zulu extras
want to unionize.
They may be cannibals, but they want
health and dental so the movie's kaput!
Which means that the MGM
deal ain't gonna happen,
and your script ain't worth
a buffalo shit on a nickel!
So, the way it looks to me through
the cataracts I grant you,
is that you can either sign here,
and take 10,000 dollars
for your toilet-paper script,
or you can go fuck yourself!
With all due respect.
You really know Warren Beatty?
Yes I do.
I took a leak next to him
once at the Golder Globes.
Taco?
Got any kids, Lester?
Yeah, I have two daughters.
See 'em much?
I talk to 'em once a year…
maybe.
Why is that?
I was a terrible father.
The bullshit business…
it's like coal mining, you- you
come home to your wife and kids,
you can't… you can't wash it off.
You?
Yeah I got a son.
He lives in Virgina with his mother.
You're divorced?
Taking time off.
He needs to be, you know…
where he is.
Kids need the mother.
They caught the Shah's chief of security
trying to get on a plane to Paris.
Listen,
"since the incident, the number
of guards at the airport has doubled,
a thorough background examination
should be expected".
The movie cover isn't strong enough yet,
I need another week, Jack.
You don't have it.
We got an office,
we got business cards,
we got a poster.
If I'm the Revolutionary Guard, there's
nothing we couldn't have made at home.
Six people's lives depend on this.
It's not enough.
If we're gonna fool these people,
it has to be big,
and it has to have something
that says it's authentic.
I did a movie with Rock Hudson one time.
If you want to sell a lie…
get the press to sell it for you.
No no no, press event, then they're-
they're gonna read through the script.
I got a bunch of actors who are gonna read
from beginning to end, all the way through.
They have costumes and everything.
No, no, no, I can't, I got, uh,
Variety has the exclusive on that.
Any way to make this more uh…
Middle Eastern?
Mesopotamia?
Egypt?
Iran.
Look, I can get you in, but you
gotta promise me at least half a page.
No, no, this thing's an event,
it's going to be a spectacle.
Lester.
Nina, you look fabulous!
You doing the reading?
I'm playing Serksi, the Galactic Witch.
Great, I'll call ya.
Keep that fucking space
witch away from me.
You know her?
I was married to her.
Oh my God, Iraq is amazing!
Well, we're shooting in Iran.
Iran with an N?
Yeah.
We're very excited.
You ever watch the news?
What does the title refer to?
The Argo!
The thing…
Like Jason and the
Golden Fleece, or what?
No, no, it's the ship, it's the-
the spaceship, it goes…
it goes everywhere, it goes all…
…all throughout space.
So it's the Argonaut?
No.
What- what does Argo mean?
I don't know.
You don't know?
It means "Argo, fuck yourself"!
Will you pay me every attention,
ladies and gentlemen?
If our artists could settle in,
we'll just be ready to begin the reading.
Argo. From Mary Ann Boyd.
Begin on starship…
The people working here are not diplomats.
In fact, as the Iman Khomeini said,
they have found no evidence that proves
that these people are diplomats.
All evidence proves that
these people are spies.
In the name of God,
the beneficent, the merciful,
our message to the waking
peoples of the world,
at this time we want to expose
the hateful acts of United States…
Our world has changed,
Fires of hope stopped burning
in this galaxy long ago.
The ship is turning around.
Fire the thrusters!
He says a gravitational field
that strong will kill any…
.. completely unjustified.
They and all others must know
that the United States
of America will not yield
to International Terrorism
or to blackmail.
Sir, we'll be crashed.
There's no enough time to…
– .. are controlled by capitalists,
and large oil companies.
The United States government considers
revolutionists as terrorists,
but itself and its CIA are the most
terrorizing organization of all time.
We'll find her ship,
we will find our chance.
For the Argo lies my hope,
my hero, my husband.
.. We will begin the trials and
carry out the sentences.
.. We wonder where and how this apparently
endless parade of hatred will end.
What do they want?
They say the question should
be not 'what', but 'who'.
The answer to this question is clear,
they want the former Shah,
.. They should be ashamed
to talk about human rights.
Carter and his government
have given asylum
to the worst criminal.
– .. in this compound,
for what, for life?
They will remain until
the Shah is returned.
But if the exiled Shah,
now in the New York City hospital,
leaves the United States
for any place other than Iran,
harsher decisions will be taken
against the hostages.
.. We go outside of the ship now,
holding on a single red flower
as it goes to the ruins
of the starship in the desert,
fade to Back. The end.
Here it is. What did I tell you!
First shot of the picture.
"Argo, fuck yourself."
Argo, fuck yourself.
Brace yourself.
It's like talking to those two
old fucks from The Muppets.
Aliens and robots?
Yes, sir.
You're telling me that there is a movie
company in Hollywood right now,
that is funded by the CIA?
– Yes, sir.
What's wrong with the bikes again?
We tried to get the message upstairs, sir.
You think… you think this is
more plausible than teachers?
Yes, we do. One, there are no more
foreign teachers in Iran…
And we think everybody
knows Hollywood people,
and everybody knows they
ain't shootin' Stalingrad,
with Bob Hope directing
if it would sell tickets.
There are only bad options,
it's about finding the best one.
You don't have a better
bad idea than this?
This is the best bad idea we have, sir.
By far.
The United States Government has just
sanctioned your Science Fiction movie.
Thank you, sir.
I'm required to remind you that if you are
detained, the agency will not claim you.
Barely claim me as it is.
Is there any in case of obstacle?
Just Christine.
I should have brought some
books to read in prison.
No.
They'll kill you long before prison.
– Thanks for the ride.
– Yeah.
– Studio 6.
– We got a green light.
Keep the office running
until you hear otherwise.
– Argo fuck yourself.
Your attention please,
this is the final calling for
British Airways flight 87.
We are a nation of 35 millions,
and many of these people
are looking for to murder them.
Hey.
Come to bed.
Another 5 minutes.
She pleaded with me.
When it started in the streets
nine months ago, she…
she begged for us to leave.
She packed our bags.
I said, "just- just a little bit longer".
And all I was thinking was…
"stay…
this is good for me.
Stay.
Show Newsom you got the balls".
I can't believe I put Kathy
in this position.
I think we're gonna die here.
"Iran is a hundred percent not
in a pre-revolutionary state".
CIA brief, November, 1st, 1979.
Can't be right all the time.
Kevin?
When did you get back?
The Shah escaped on the 747
so laden with gold bars,
that they didn't make it off the runway.
But you kept busy.
Fairing out the torture apparatus
of our friends fallen dictation.
It's getting worse.
Anyone that lands at Mehrabad
now fills in one of these.
This strip makes a copy
to the one underneath,
passenger keeps yellow,
airport keeps white,
when you leave the country,
they match them up
to verify you came into the country
when you say you did.
So if they look,
they'll see I didn't come into
the country with six people.
If they look.
When you land, you should go straight
to the Ministry of Culture and…
Islamic Guidance, kiss the ring.
Get on record as having
applied for film permit.
If they catch you later, at least they'll
be confused while they're torturing you.
IRANIAN CONSULATE - TURKEY
What will be the purpose
of your visit to Iran?
Uh… film production. Business.
Why didn't you get your visa in Canada?
Well, I would have loved to, except my
boss didn't send a telex until I got here.
If the guy had an intelligent thought
in his head, it would die of loneliness.
The Times and AP found out six escaped.
They know who they are, and they know
they're hiding out with the Canadians.
Somebody withdrew on the family's talk.
Mother of God.
Yeah I just put Vance on a plane to
take the head of eds to a circus,
he thinks he can get him
to sit on it for now.
You guy'd better get them.
And get the hell out.
The Captain has informed us
that we're entering Iranian airspace.
We'll be coming through to collect
any remaining alcoholic beverages.
This film crew is just yourself?
No, we have six more from
Canada meeting us today.
You'd like to film at the bazaar?
The bazaar, maybe the palace.
Landmark sites.
I see.
The exotic orients.
Snake charmers, flying carpets.
You came to us at a complicated time.
Before the revolution forty percent
of the movie theaters in Tehran
were showing pornograph.
I understand.
The function of this
office is purification,
as well as promotion for the arts.
I'll review this for the Ministry.
Thank you.
– Salam.
Lester, you're working late.
Until the dawns early light.
You got stamina, Lester. I wanna be you.
Well, I'm a hundred and fifty years
old, so you wouldn't be me for long.
– Ambassador.
– Ken Taylor.
Thank you for what you're doing.
I was expecting more of a G-Man look.
I think you're thinking of the FBI, sir.
Ah. This way.
These are blank- you know, stamps…
Yeah, I'll take care of this.
How long?
A day to prep their covers…
two if they need it.
And- and you'll fly out with them?
Yeah.
There's something you should know.
We think our housekeeper's
figured out who they are.
We don't know if we can trust her.
So, sooner is better.
Hi.
Hi. My name's Kevin Harkins…
and I'm gonna get you home.
These are the screenplays
for your cover identities.
It's- it's theater of the absurd.
What are our chances?
Chances are good.
Good? Well, what's the uh…
what's the number value of good?
A thirty percent chance of
being publicly executed?
Can you- can you tell me what the
objection was to normal cover identities?
There are no Canadians in
the country for no reason.
They'll sniff us out regardless.
The Swedish Consul, they- they accused him
of being an American at the airport,
they held him for an hour.
We can't hold upon that, we don't know
what the hell movie people do.
That's why I'm here.
I'm gonna help you, I'm gonna be
with you the whole way. This is what I do.
Have you gotten people
out this way before?
This would be a first.
Do you know that everyday they catch
another friend of the Shah at the airport?
– Joe…
– Kangaroo trials, and-
And then firing squads just for having
American names in their phone books.
You've been here and hour,
and- and you're asking us to trust
you with our lives, Mr…
Harkins.
That's your real name?
No.
I know there are risks involved.
Serious risks.
But it is time to go.
We've got orders to close
the embassy and go back.
There's nowhere for them to stay.
We will never make it through
immigration at the airport.
I'm serious.
I mean no, this is what? The part we say,
this is so crazy it might actually work?
– Come on!
– I saw in Burma, they get people out.
Snitches and Banana Republic, they get
them over the border after the coup,
pay the guards at the crossing a
hundred bucks to look the other way.
You know, his opinion got us out
in the first place.
If we go out there with fake passports,
we are spies, period, that's execution.
You got a problem lying, Joe?
But the point is, we can't stay here!
If we get caught, you and Pat go on trial
for harboring the enemy, you know that.
Pat and I have discussed this,
it's the risk we took.
That man out there has got bad
cards and he is going to lose,
and if he loses… it's our lives.
And his life too.
Look, we don't have any alternatives.
We gotta go.
These cover identities were created
specifically for each one of you.
What you need to do is memorize
everything that's inside.
Who you are, what you are, where you've
been, complete bio. And then add to that:
where do you vacation, what are you
allergies, who'd you have an affair with.
The only way this works,
is if you believe that you're these people
so much that you're dream like them.
Get started tonight.
I'll be back tomorrow. We'll get going.
Good luck.
Wow, my guy kind of sucks.
What's your name?
Mike McEwan A.
Sounds convincing.
Kathy, what's your name?
The Loveboat will be seeing
fifteen minutes from now.
.. insisted that the crisis in Afghanistan
will not divert the attention of the United
States from the plight of the hostages.
.. he seems to be if not impotent,
but at least reluctant…
The United States finds itself
in such bitter confrontation
with the Soviet Union over that
country's invasion of Afghanistan…
The United States is now
moving towards the decision
to boycott the summer
Olympics in Moscow.
Bad new, bad news. Even when
it's good news, it's bad news.
John Wayne's in the ground six months,
this is what's left of America.
The Minister of Culture and Guidance
has approved your location scout.
He will send his representative
to meet you and your crew at the
Grand Bazaar tomorrow at 3 P.M.
They called your bluff.
– Maybe they're cooperating.
– Absolutely not.
Seven Americans walking the bazaar
is asking for a riot, it's the hive.
Seven Canadians, Jack.
Never give them opening shots at a cover.
– Are they even ready?
– They're getting there.
There's no prize for most improvements.
I don't have a choice.
We say no, they show up at their residence
and drag everyone out at gun point.
How well do you think their
covers are gonna hold up
when they're getting their
fingernails pulled out?
You want us to go the Grand Bazaar
at three o'clock in the afternoon?
You said a day learning our cover
then straight to the airport.
– Do they suspect something?
What I know is we need to
pretend to be a movie crew.
We go to the bazaar today, we
fly from the airport tomorrow.
We won't do it.
He told them that there are six of
us, so then they're expecting six,
it would be suspicious not
to show up at this point.
Goddammit, guys! What else
do we have to do?!
Alright? What el- what-
what's the alternative?!
We don't have to show them
the only cards we're holding,
which is that they
don't know we're here!
I get it! That's the ball game,
okay, we- you know,
Look, we don't have any other…
other choice! What are we gonna do?!
Who says that we'll know
our covers well enough?
We're no in the CIA!
It's suicide.
I'm asking you to trust me.
I don't trust you.
This is the game, Joe.
What world are you living in?
What world am I…?
The one where they're hanging people
from construction cranes, Bob!
It's too dangerous,
– I don't want to bring my wife into this.
– Joe, can you stop?
Joe?
So, we'll see you at two.
So, don't be recognizable, but look
exactly like your passport photo.
I haven't been this nervous
since our wedding.
Only this isn't a huge mistake, hopefully.
Like this… Okay.
Hello?
Who was that?
– Mark?
– Yeah?
I'm scared.
It's okay.
Where are they?
In the kitchen.
This is what I do…
I get people out…
and I've never left anyone behind.
I wish I could believe you, Mr. Harkins.
My name is Tony Mendez.
I'm from New York, my worked construction,
my mother teaches elementary school,
I have a wife and a ten year old son.
You play along with me today, I promise
you I will get you out tomorrow.
Fuck.
Hang on.
You alright?
Okay, tell me who you are?
Mike McEwan, cameraman.
Robert Baker, director.
Timothy Harris, location manager.
Mary Ann Boyd, screenwriter.
Rachel Dewart, production designer.
Sean Bissett, associate producer.
Alright, let's go make the movie.
Welcome, welcome,
my name is Reza Borhani.
Kevin Harkins, I'm the producer.
– Nice to meet you.
– This is Mike McEwan, our cameraman,
this is Tim, this is Mary,
our screenwriter,
and this is our director, Bob Baker.
– You are the director?
– Yes.
Is this film a foreign brides film?
I'm sorry?
A film where a foreign bride
comes to Iran, but uh…
she doesn't understand the
language or the customs,
and there is misunderstandings and laughs?
Oh, no.
The bazaar in Tehran is one
of the largest in the world.
[Farsi] Izar, salam, choukran.
This Bazaar has been on this spot
for over 8000 years.
You can find many items such as
paper, spices, precious metals,
All, right here.
Uh, right this way.
[Farsi]
This way.
– Uh, Mike?
– Yeah.
If I was to say that you're looking
through the wrong end
of that view finder, would I be right?
Yeah.
Just a little bit now.
[Farsi]
Please wait here, let's uh, stay together.
He wants to know the
photograph you took…
It's okay, it's her job to take
photographs. Production design.
He says, he did not give you permission
to take photograph of his store.
Well that's okay, you can
tell him he can have it.
Please, please take that photograph.
He's saying that the Shah killed
his son with an American gun.
No! Canada! Cana- Canada!
Ι'd lіkе tо ѕuggеѕt thаt
wе аrе еndіng thіѕ vіѕіt!
Let's go off this now!
How did it go?
What about tomorrow?
Tomorrow they'll be ready.
A man in Scranton is placing a flag
in his lawn for every day of captivity.
He runs out of lawn,
Kennedy wins the primary.
The six with the Canadians are coming out.
Who signed off on this?
You! Where was your passport issued?
– Vancouver.
– Where were you born?
– Toronto
– "Torono".
Canadians don't pronounce the T.
Some Komiteh guard is
actually gonna know that?
If you're detained for questioning they
will bring out someone who knows that, yes.
Mary, who were the last three
Prime Ministers to Canada?
Uh… Trudeau, Pearson and Diefenbaker.
– What's your father's name?
– Howard.
– What's his occupation?
– Fisherman.
– Where were you born?
– Halifax, Nova Scotia.
What's your date of birth?
February 21st, 1952.
Good. What's your job on the movie?
– Producer.
Associate producer. What was
the last movie you produced?
– "High and Dry".
– Who paid for that?
– CFDC.
– What's your middle name?
What's your middle name?
– Leon…-
– Shoot him! He's an American spy.
Look, they're gonna try
and break you. Okay?
By trying to get you agitated.
You have to know your
resume back to front.
Do you really believe your little
story's gonna make a difference
when there's a gun to our heads?
I think my story is the only thing
between you and a gun to your head.
That's right.
Hey. They made it through
the location scout.
You have a call.
– What is it?
– Go to black on green.
Go.
– It all just changed.
– What?
They're calling it again,
you gotta come back.
– What?
– Flight Chiefs are planning
a military rescue of the hostages,
Delta Force started training
to storm the grounds. So,
if the six of them are brought down there,
they won't be held for long.
Goddammit! I never would have exposed them
if I wasn't authorized to get them out!
– It's over, Tony.
– If they stay here, they will be taken.
– Probably not alive.
– Listen to me!
The thinking has changed.
Six Americans get pulled out of
the Canadian diplomat's house
and executed, it's a world outrage.
Six Americans get caught
playing movie make-believe
with the CIA at the airport and executed,
it's a national embarrassment.
They are calling the operation.
We're responsible for these people.
What we are is required to follow orders.
I'm sorry.
Come in.
We're ready to try again.
You're ready.
You worked hard.
Probably the best thing to do
for you right now would be…
just to relax.
Okay.
You did good.
Thanks.
So you know.
Exfil wants you to burn the
passports before you leave.
If you tell them now, they'll panic.
I think it's best if you just don't show.
It was always a fucked mission.
You came closer than anybody else.
It's off…
they want us to pack up the office.
This can wait. Let's go get a drink.
He's late.
O'Donnell.
Somebody's responsible
when things happen, Jack.
I'm responsible.
I'm taking them through.
Tony?
Alan! Alan,
we need to confirm those seven
tickets out of Tehran on Swissair.
Engell shut that down.
I say it's back on!
– I can't do it, it's back stopped!
– Wait wait, wait a minute!
What the hell are you talking
about, back stopped,
what the hell does that mean?
Carter's gotta say yes
for us to get the tickets.
Time to go.
Alright.
– Where's Engell?
– Uh, he's in a meeting.
Pull him out.
Pull him out!
Thank you. See you soon.
Sahar's on the bus.
– Great.
– Sahar will be fine.
– Thank you.
– Thank you!
You two leave right now.
We'll leave on the train in half an hour.
Good.
And he said no.
This is not a long leisure
and it never has been,
and you don't decide if it goes!
It is going!
Jack. You are this close.
Am I? Am I really that close?
You are this Goddamn close to-
I am not gonna leave him at the airport
with six people and his dick in his hand.
You tell the director
to call the White House!
Do your fucking job!
– Get to your plane, Claude
– Oui monsieur.
First time anyone's gonna ask you
a question is at the first check point.
The first check point is just to
get a look at your passports.
Passports came straight from
Ottawa last week. They're clean.
You're gonna find White
House Chief of Staff!
How would I find him?
We're a fucking spy agency! Find him!
The second check point is immigration.
You're each gonna hand them one of these.
It says that you landed in
the country two days ago.
They'll look for the matching
white one, which doesn't exist.
You'll say you don't know what happened…
and if you believe they
lost they white set,
they'll believe it too.
Jordan's in the West Wing,
he's not taking calls.
Where are his kids?
What?
Where do his kids go to school?
Thank you, thank you.
Pace Academy, Buckhead, Georgia.
White House.
Yes, this is Mr. Murphy from Pace
Academy calling for Mr. Jordan.
Yeah, I'm afraid it is an emergency.
Hold for the Chief of Staff's Office.
The third check point is the trap.
It's manned by the Revolutionary Guard,
most of them were educated
in the U.S and Europe…
and all of them are looking for Americans.
– Hello?
– Jack O'Donnell from CI-
– Wait, wait! Who?
Iran Guesthouse operation is ready now,
if we don't have the President's go ahead,
they are going to be captured.
David, pick up!
Zurich, it's under Harkins.
I'm sorry sir, I don't see
you'd have these reservations.
Telex for Flash!
Would you mind checking again, please?
Copy D.S., confirm the tickets, go!
My apologies, they just came through.
Swisair says they picked up the tickets.
Get the L.A. office, tell them
to be ready, in case they call.
We told them to shut that down.
There you go.
Not here.
When did you come through Iran?
Two days ago.
What was the purpose of your visit?
We are looking for locations for a film.
– We have a….
– Oh, yeah,
I've got a letter from
the Ministry of Culture.
If you want to look at that.
You can go.
Come on, come on.
Passports.
No passports, no plane.
[Farsi]
We're together yes, uh-
Pierson's telling Swissair
they're not on the plane.
They should have boarded already.
Still no answer in L.A.
Sir.
N-No, I'm… I'm now a writer, and uh…
Kevin, give me the storyboards.
You don't go until we verify.
– I understand.
– Sir…
Call our office.
They'll verify.
.. It goes all the way
throughout the thirties.
Hold on pal, we're shooting.
We're just going to the
producer's building.
Yeah I understand, I understand
but we're shooting.
Swissair announces final boarding
to flight 3-6-3 to Zurich.
Recess, back to one!
– Alright, recess.
– We going again!
Again, everyone!
And… we're rolling!
– We're going to the producer's building.
– Sorry, we're rolling
Sorry pal, we're gonna be in the movie.
Call my agency.
Sir!
Studio 6 Productions.
May I speak to a Mr. Kevin Harkins?
I'm sorry, Mr. Harkins is out of
country on a location scout.
May I take a message?
Doors are closing for
flight 3-6-3 to Zurich.
– We can go.
– Excellent.
You can these. It's a gift.
[Farsi] Wait a moment.
Others are coming.
Swissair 3-6-3, clearance for taxi.
Swissair 3-6-3, you are
number two for departure.
cleared for take off.
Swissair 3-6-3,
clear for take off.
– We got wheels up!
– Wait.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it is our pleasure to announce
that alcoholic beverages
are now available
as we have cleared Iranian airspace.
They're clear.
Yes! Yes!
They're out!
They're out. They're out!
Yes! We got them out!
They're out!
Great work, boys.
We've managed!
You are admitted to the republic of Iraq.
We made history today.
" History starts out as farce
and ends up as tragedy".
Or it's the other way around.
And who said it?
Marx.
Groucho said that?
Called 'The Times' to nail
it to the Goddamn door.
CIA are the good guys.
The Canadians are the good guys
And if we're not agreeing, them too.
Only. Canada takes the credit, or
they'll retaliate against the hostages.
Great Satan wasn't involved.
No CIA.
Is that right, Jack?
Involved in what?
We were surprised as anybody.
Thank you, Canada.
We knew that each day
that they stayed there,
the danger was becoming greater.
We had been looking for a solution to have
them to leave the country during the past-
.. Day 87, and finally a sliver
of really good news…
.. American department of State
hereby honors
Joe Stafford…
Kathy Stafford…
Mark Lijek…
The Americans will be forever grateful
to our great and ally to the North,
for the protection and safe passage,
provided to our diplomats.
– Bob Anders…
Here or anywhere in the world…
Canada will pay…
for this violation of the
sovereignty of Iran.
.. ambassador Ken Taylor
and the great nation of Canada.
So I'm sitting in Jerry's this morning,
I'm having breakfast.
Waitress comes over to me,
she's waving a newspaper, she says:
'You see what those Canadians pulled off?
Why can't we do something like that?"
I said to her, do you know what I said?
No, what?
"Argo, fuck yourself!"
All set.
Thanks a lot.
And I left my autograph book at home.
His eminence called me.
He wants to see you.
Probably wants to fire me himself.
He wants to give you
the Intelligence Star.
You're getting the highest award of merit
of the clandestine services
of these United States.
Ceremony's on the fourteenth.
If they push it a week I can bring
Ian, that's his winter break.
The op was classified. So…
the ceremony's classified.
He can't know about it,
nobody can know about it.
So they're just gonna give me an award,
then they're gonna take it back.
That's right.
If we wanted applause we would
would have joined the circus.
– I thought we did.
– Yeah.
Carter said you were a great American.
Great American what?
He didn't say.
What happened to your picture?
It's in turn around.
Can I come in?