Hello.
Mr. Blake, please.
Blake?
I don't think there's
mister ...there's Tony?
Here.
Mr. Blake, we booked in 103.
Who?
I've got to go.
It's about six.
No way.
No more than four.
Jesus Christ, don't bother
me with this kind of crap,
okay.
No bye-byes?
No, no bye-byes.
Can I call you sometime?
Any time.
What's your name?
Felicity.
Back to your boyfriend,
Felicity darling.
What's his name,
what's his name?
The stud
He's the stud,
stud
What's his game,
what's his game?
Stud
Hello my pretty.
And I have to start, boy,
who plays the brake down.
But I'm moving, even
if I have to push it.
But I nearly started to
write that ticket for you.
Oh, just try and
see if it works.
It works.
He is the stud...
Stud...
What's his game,
what's his game?
Stud...
Oh Charlie.
And I'd tell you wildly.
Come on, come on,
let's have it.
The little punters
are on their way.
A very good set.
This is it.
Mr. Blake is very early.
What's the time again?
That little guy,
what's his name?
Lukeno.
Yeah, give him a jacket
tonight, all right?
Okay.
Mr. Blake, this came
for you yesterday.
Hey Claus, how is it going?
Top of the tree, man.
I'm going to whoop
their ass tonight.
Mr. Blake, there's a phone
call for you, Mrs. Khaled.
Yes, Mrs. Khaled?
You're never late
are you, lover.
The car is waiting for you.
So am I.
Put your coat on.
I don't want you
catching a cold.
Franco, reservations.
Yeah.
Miss Carla Casini,
she is coming tonight?
You put the wolves on a second
to best table last night,
my baby.
Never mind the backhanders
you put them back in oblivion
where they belong, all right?
Yes, Mr. Blake.
Yes, who is it?
Your mother, Mr. Blake.
All right, put her through.
Franco,
you've got Mike Rovani on the bad
side there explain that to me.
Yes, you put them in with the silk shirt
and the colors around
it may dye it pink a bit, my
handkerchiefs are a bit red.
Mr. Blake, he bounced
three checks last week.
He's not exactly
a good costumer.
Look, you know
who his old man is?
If he likes a client,
a couple of checks,
you let him, all right?
So put him on the
good side, all right?
Well Tony, all right.
Yes mom.
Christmas, what about it?
All right.
I'll try and make it.
I'll let you know.
All right.
Ta-ta.
Franco.
Si.
I've just got to
pop out for an hour.
Keep the mafia
more busy, will you?
Don't drop it,
will you, lover?
It's 5th Century.
You're wondering how
much it was worth,
weren't you?
It's not hard to
imagine what your thinking,
most of the time.
Well, I was thinking about
the weather now and again,
and I think about you
and what you're thinking.
Let's go and
discuss the weather then.
What's going on?
It's an emergency.
What's that?
That's your cue.
That's enough.
Oh, that's enough, Tony.
That's enough darling.
Come on.
Where's your husband then?
In Geneva.
What's he doing there?
Meeting his daughter.
Well I'm supposed to
be working in his club.
It's my club and I can
take a loss for an hour.
You're supposed to
be looking at me.
That's right.
Was nice.
Let's go,
let's go
let's go disco
Let's go disco,
Let's go disco
everybody getting down
And having a good time you all
Will get to the funky south
Well, well, well. Well
And make it with the right you
all
The night is still young
Let the DJ play
your favorite song He-hey,
let's go disco,
let's go disco
Let's go disco,
Let's go,
let's go disco
Let's go disco,
move your body To the beat
See that foxy lady go
Sure no tire to use
that feet
Drive them people crazy ya'll
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
The night is still young
People dancing till
the morning comes
Let's go disco,
let's go disco
Let's go, disco time
Let's go,
let's go
The night is still young
People dancing till
the morning comes
Let's go disco,
let's go disco
The night is still young
Let the DJ play
your favorite song
Let's go disco,
let's go disco, Let's go,
let's go disco
Let's go disco, let's go
Let's go disco
Easy go I did love the
cars
I build my love
I missed you darling.
Tony, So nice to
see you, darling.
How are you?
I want you meet a
friend of mine? Carl...
Tony.
Nice to meet you.
Take care.
Okay.
Blake,
Mrs. Weinstein.
That's all right.
Franco, please tell Mr.
Blake Lord Newton is here.
Tony, it's a
privilege to see you.
I haven't got a reservation
but one doesn't go in the
afternoon but one's
going to go in the evening.
Molly darling, you
look like a dynamite.
I take it your unescorted.
What? No, no... I've got two
charming twins with me,
Nigel and Jeremy.
I suppose you know the rules
single gentlemen pull
the ladies in.
How are you?
Fine, fine.
Got a table for
me and the lad?
Absolutely.
Franco, table for Mr. Flynne.
Thanks, Tony.
Single gentlemen
pull the ladies,
it makes the other
gentlemen uptight.
Well, I never
pulled a lady in my life.
That's a bloody silly rule.
I don't make the rules.
Oh, nice to see you surely.
You can always
make an exception for a very
special pal, don't you?
Look, everyone
here is special.
Well, what if I
should jolly well decide to
cancel my membership then?
Well if that's how you feel.
No, no, no, no it's
only a joke, Tony.
Anytime, let me know.
Yes.
You'll know where we are
going when you're not so busy.
We'll go somewhere else.
Come along child,
we'll go down the road.
You love it, don't you?
Well, I deal
perks with like that.
I used to run my ass up for
them and they leave me for
money for a tip.
Waiter never forgets, eh.
How are you going?
Uh sneaking by.
Hello darling.
Good morning?
Hello, sweetheart.
Hi darling.
Hello sweetheart.
Jesus, you'd be sneaking by
the child offenses act
if they get me...
How are you doing?
Where did you find them?
There's nothing to it.
I just follow the school bus,
ran in a roll and wait till
they climb in, and they do.
You rob the cradle,
Hal robs the graveyard,
what a pair.
You don't have to twist
their arm these days,
you know?
Can't hop down on the old
foggy before he complains.
I'll blame the lad on the
moral standards on the TV
and so do you?
Well, I'll blame it on
gray head women like you.
They ask for comics, not a bag
of sweet and you give them a
penthouse to have on my trade.
You're only young
once, you know.
That's what their
dad's keep tellin them.
Franco, get Mr. Marc's a
scotch and a milk shake for
his daughter.
I left my wallet in
my other suit, right?
Boy, doesn't matter honey.
A buddy of mine runs the club.
Hey Tony, meet Maxine.
She runs Springs.
Oh, this is a nice place.
She is loaded.
What?
Nothing.
Listen I want to talk
about the menu, right?
Now she's... oh yeah,
hail to the chick.
Good evening, Mrs. Khaled.
Ah, Good evening, Franco.
Umm that's good.
Darling, you look fantastic.
You look divine.
We must have lunch someday.
Yes, darling. Call me.
He's good, there's nothing
else that I would rather be
The greatest pleasures
teach us soon
He's in the top with you
Mrs. Khaled.
Do I smell mouthwash?
Just a little.
I didn't want to
spoil the flavor.
Why?
You reek of sex anyway,
it's your main attribute.
You're too kind.
Yes.
It's my main failing.
Franco, the music is much too loud.
Of course.
Tony.
Vanessa, darling.
Hello sweetheart,
you look terrific.
You look terrific.
Tony.
This is Marc.
How'd you do Marc?
Welcome to the club.
Thank you.
Is Jeremy here?
Later.
Why don't you come through?
Life is very light.
Merry Christmas
and... we do our best.
How are you?
Hey, Leonard.
Okay.
How was LA?
Sinking slowly into the sea
as far as I could tell,
too slowly.
That's Maxine behind me.
Thank you my darling.
Have you heard from
Benjamin, darling?
Yes, he called me
from Switzerland twice.
How's the novel coming on?
Page by page.
I see you brought your bit of
crimpy jail bait with you then dear.
Well, Denise... nah
she's an old age pensioner,
well preserved
like her highness.
Oh bitchy.
You better mind your tongue
dear she might bite it off.
Lucky her.
What did he say?
Faggot.
And how's little...
Alexandra?
Alexandra.
Is Alexandra liking Switzerland?
Well how the hell should I know?
She's his little
brat, not mine.
Go stay with
somebody your own age.
Because I saved him from...
You're a nice old geezer,
but you don't own me honey.
But then I judge other writers
by what they write...
myself, by my best intention.
What, the first Mrs. Khaled?
Is she in London then?
No darling.
She's in Bark.
She is breeding pit ponies
and I understand they all
look exactly like her.
Oh beastly.
I think she's got
a stud there too.
This is a dance floor
not a geriatric pool.
All right.
That's enough, leave it out.
Hey, where the hell
are you taking him?
Please sit down.
Franco, get me and
my lady champagne.
She's dry from yelling.
Yes.
I'm right in.
Okay.
You can't leave him alone
for a moment, can you?
That's my job.
Well, come do a job with me.
I never could believe the
things you do to me
Never could believe
the way you are
Who is that?
That?
That's Molly.
Molly?
What a divine name.
Everyone's a winner,
baby, that's the truth
Making love to you is
such a thrill
Everyone's a winner,
baby, that's no lie
You never fail
Amazing creature.
Is she part of your job too?
Look at her.
Never could explain just what
was happening to me
Just one touch of you
and I'm in flames
Doesn't that give you a hard on?
My, my, my... I do believe
the boy is embarrassed.
Your very friendly
this evening madam.
Everyone's a winner, baby,
that's the truth
Was my good
enough for the lip?
Oh yes, it's about the one place
you are good enough, Tony?
Just bear that in
mind, won't you lover.
I'm leaving now tiger.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Oh and Tony turn
the music down.
It's much too loud.
Franco, get her bag.
Fontaine.
Oh dear.
How are you?
Well looking good was it.
Be good...
I will.
It could give me some of the
figures on this place
in the meantime.
Yeah, sure.
Moonlighting
They're leaving
everything
Moonlighting
They're losing
all their friends
Moonlighting
It's the only way
It's frightening
But it means they'll stay
Together They're gonna
make it together
I'm not in love,
so don't forget it
It's just a silly phase
I'm going through
And just because
Sam... Nico.
Right.
I call you up
Don't get me wrong
Don't think you've got it made
Where you from honey?
Center Page, of Playboy honey.
Oh, can't see
any staple marks.
Oh don't you know, they
touch us up afterwards.
That's the kind of job I like.
Looks like you've got it.
Not so hard Sandro.
Sorry madam but
there's so much tension.
I take Valium for
tension Sandro,
not punishment.
Why do you keep him?
Who?
Tony.
Darling, he's my masterpiece.
I own him.
I have turned a common waiter
into one of the most fancied
young men in London, more
or less with my bare hands.
I totally redid
him, clothes, hair,
even sex, especially sex.
Do you know when
I first met him,
Tony thought that 69
was a bottle of scotch?
You're priceless.
Well, frightfully
expensive though.
Then when do I have him?
Whenever you wish my darling,
unless it's not during club hours.
But wouldn't you be jealous?
Good God, it would be like
being jealous of a turnstile
at Regent's Park zoo.
I might even
arrange it for you.
Oh I've got
something to show you,
I think you'll be fascinated.
Will I?
Do I hurt you madam?
I realized Sandro that
this is not your intention,
but you're getting me excited.
It's all right Sandro,
just bring me the phone.
Hello.
Good morning lover.
Oh, it's you.
Are you up?
Yeah I'm awake but...
What do you mean 'but?
You're an early
riser, aren't you?
Good, then I'll
have all of it then,
I'm coming over.
Coming over,
coming over where?
Oh, I don't really
mind wherever... wherever,
besides I miss you.
I've been lying here
thinking about you,
and I'm ready, I'll be
around in 10 minutes.
God.
Hey, you do this
for a living huh?
Oh shut up.
Oh, well, I got one for
free from a real professional.
Do I have to fill in
a form or something,
for your income tax?
Cut it out.
No, I mean if it's any
easier I don't mind paying.
Do you take Access?
Several times last
night, didn't I?
Okay, suppose we put the
little extras down to Diners
Club then.
It's not often I get the
chance to eat that much,
who does this
one charge it to.
Come on, it's not like that.
Sure I know?
You good looking
tarts are all the same.
Well, don't let me
keep you from your work.
I won't be long Sanders.
Very good, ma'am.
I've got 15 minutes Tony.
I'm late for the
hair dressers.
Christ, I'm not a
machine you know.
In the meantime
lover, you will do.
What are you wearing tonight?
Oh I don't know, anything.
Oh Fontaine you're
positively wicked,
you know that?
Yes, I am, aren't I?
I knew I should have
gone into the movies,
instead of wasting my
best years modeling,
they wanted me too.
How on earth did
you manage that?
I can take a loss for an hour.
Practice darling, endless
practice a bit like ballet
lessons.
What's he doing?
He's looking at his watch...
cocky little bastard.
Oh this isn't fair.
When are you going to
arrange him for me?
Yeah.
Maybe I'll give him
to you for Christmas.
You know I'm in Paris.
Oh yes I know.
Oh I love Paris.
Oh, ah.
Oh shit.
You look like shit.
Yeah, I've had a busy day.
Still going
across the boss' wife.
You're playing a
mugs game, Tony.
She's got you both ways.
You can't even
blow the whistle,
right?
Anytime I want, I can go.
What happens then?
All of sudden you're an
ex-manager of a night club.
She probably won't even
let you keep a jacket.
Might fit the next guy.
You got to use your head
first and your cock second.
Basic law of physics, that is.
Christ.
Creeps up on you, doesn't it?
What?
Age, darling, the
invisible enemy.
Don't be silly,
you look incredible.
Hmm, I'm my own work of art.
Maybe if I could've had kids,
I'd be all nice and mummsy by
now.
I didn't know you
couldn't have kids.
Rather unfortunate
abortion, took care of that.
'Don't want them' sounds much
better than 'can't have them'.
Anyway at least I'm not
risking thrombosis from the
pill.
You always said
you hated kids.
Anyway, Leonard thinks you're
the most beautiful woman he's
ever seen.
Does he now?
You must remind me to
thank him properly.
Oh darling, you must
bring Tony to Paris,
then we can all have him.
All?
Maybe you should
take up the banjo,
Tony baby.
Always good to
have a second trade.
Nah... he's going to be a tap
dancer when the old trouser
snake lets him
down, ain't you tone.
Listen, you two toe rags.
In the not too distant future,
I'm going to make the pair of
you look like twin arseholes.
I've done the waiter bit,
I've done the manager a bit.
The next one is going
to have my name on it,
Tony's very own.
I've got a certain person to
put his limbs up and I'm going
to be making bread.
I'll blow the whistle on the
performing bit when I feel
like it right now I
don't feel like it.
I enjoy it, right?
End of story.
What's Glen like in bed?
Well, inventive.
Inventive?
Hmm.
I always thought he
was a trifle gay.
I must say invention isn't
one of Tony's strong suits.
With him it's more of a matter
of... enthusiasm and staying
hard.
You know, I think
Paris is a fantastic idea.
We could do some
Christmas shopping.
I need a new coat.
What would you do about Ben?
Oh Ben... he'll be far too busy
fawning over his daughter to
worry about what I am doing.
He'll probably be grateful to
me for getting out his way.
Very considerate
of you, darling.
Do you mind if I
watch it again?
Now I know what I'm
getting for Christmas.
Be my guest.
About Fontaine
Khaled, she's using you.
Listen, Fontaine
Khaled is a beautiful,
intelligent woman.
She's a ball breaker.
She gave me a chance.
She wanted you to screw.
Eh, you're unhappy because I
pull beautiful ladies and you
have to pay for your cufflinks
by dicking over old age
pensions.
Don't tell me I'm schmuck.
It's only my hobby.
What are you doing
in your spare time,
make model airplanes?
All right, Warren Beatty,
you stick to your hobby.
You can nail it to the wall
when it doesn't work anymore.
That is unless
someone nails it for you.
Well, it won't be you.
You're too busy wheeling
bath chairs round now.
Let me tell you something
about those old dragons.
Their husbands
are usually dead.
How's Mr. Khaled?
So, which bright young things
do we have the pleasure of
this evening?
Mario's is with Gordon
and Alex is with Peter,
of course.
Christ.
Another one of those
upper class itentikits.
Peter's a very nice boy.
Alex likes him.
She always has done.
I think they are
very well suited.
Maybe they can all live
happily ever after then.
Is that so wrong?
It's all so boring.
He is boring.
She's boring.
They all bore the arse of me.
I hope you won't be using
language like that in front of
her.
It's that puritanical attitude
of yours that makes me talk
like that around her.
You know she can't bare me to
be more attractive than her
own mother.
So you'll make it up to her
by treating me like a servant
whenever she's around.
Do I really treat
you like a servant?
Well, no.
No, not really.
But she doesn't like me and
you know I just can't help the
way that makes me behave.
She won't be here for long.
But she is my daughter and I
can't refuse her to stay in my
house.
Must you absolutely be
here until the New Years,
darling?
Yes, I'm afraid so, why?
Oh, Vanessa and Leonard
have asked us to Paris for
Christmas.
It would have been
divine if we could have gone.
Why don't you go?
Oh, it wouldn't be the same
without you after all it is
Christmas.
Don't be silly.
Do some shopping,
have a marvelous time,
you'll be back
by Christmas Eve.
Well, I shall have to
bring you something very,
very special then.
You get too much You get too
much And I know I'll get you
back And
gentleman in England...
Where is Mr. Blake?
He's in the store.
Go and get him.
We're not here in this piss
hole for you boring farts and
hold their manhood, see while
any speak of those who fart
and fight upon the
same Christians.
Oh Tony, get your bum
chums off and get Bowsy a
drinkington.
Thank God for Harry,
England and Tony Blake.
Ladies and gentlemen...
Mr. Tony...
Take it easy Bowsy, please.
Hey Tony... why don't you and
I drop our trousers and see
whose got the
biggest willy in the room,
eh?
Come on, off we go.
You disappoint me, Blake.
I thought you had more style.
He used to kiss my arse
when he was a waiter.
You're nothing but a working
class bum in Gucci shoes.
Listen Franco, I don't want to
see his fat little face again.
Yeah, maybe it's best that...
If he wants to
shoot his mouth of,
he can go do it in the
House of Lords not in my club.
Right.
Don't let the ruling
classes ruffle your feathers,
right.
Ah, Fontaine.
Good evening, Tony.
We are going out for a party
so we shan't be here very
long, but let me
introduce you.
Hello.
And his sister,
Madeline, Gordon Brown,
and this is my
daughter Alexandra.
This is Tony Blake
who runs the club.
Alex is a bit young for night
clubs but I don't think she'll
come to any harm here, do you?
Of course not.
Which one is Alex?
She is the one in
the fairy frock,
talking to Tony.
Who is that man
being thrown out?
Oh, that was one of
our titled customers.
We get all the Lords and
Ladies and layabouts down
here.
Do you?
I don't seem to
recognize anybody.
Well, they often look
different in real life.
Is this real life?
Peter was just telling
us about an expedition
he went on to.
Where was it Peter?
They Hindu Kush, actually.
I think the younger generation
is very adventurous these
days.
We took the train from Bombay.
Of course they are
still using steam trains.
Do I get enamored
with a noble lord,
Shakespeare in
flights, Henry five,
one of the better moments.
I hate to hear one
of his worst moments.
You saw Mt Everest
too, didn't you?
I suppose it would
be hard to miss.
Well, it certainly
is quite a sight.
You can see the main
peak for about 200 miles.
Goodness knows how anyone's
brave enough to climb the top.
I think they're all stoned
out of their minds before they
start.
I think it's terrific.
I see it closing in the
morning before breakfast.
She's awful.
She was always giving me
those funny looks during P.E.
She was probably
a raving dyke,
and I'm sure you'd
be very attracted to
that sort of person.
Shall we go and dance, Gordon?
Well, actually I
don't dance very well,
I'm afraid.
Well go and dance, so that
they don't have to sit here
and watch you pick your teeth.
Is that alright?
Yes of course, go
on enjoy yourself.
Come on Gordon.
Well, what do you
think of the club?
Why did you make
fun of him like that?
Tony, beware of the
cock in the tail.
God, Jesus.
Who is the princess then?
Oh hold on, Benjamin
Khaled's daughter,
now would you believe that.
Don't know if you
believe it yourself.
Now Alex darling however
Fontaine behaves to you
whatever she
does... she can never...
Excuse me.
Have you seen, Madeline?
I've seemed to have
lost her in the crush.
Why don't you sit down.
She can never affect our
relationship you know that?
Daddy, I know that, but she's
so impossible and so rude to
my friends.
It's part of growing up.
How is the family
outing getting along?
Huh, wonderful.
Little Miss Muffet and Winnie
the Pooh are making googoo
eyes at each other.
The other moron is taking
his horrific girlfriend for
dancing lessons and I'm
behaving like a bitch.
When Ben gives me his Arab
glares even Tony seems to have
turned to stone this evening.
Have you said
anything to Ben about Paris?
That's the one thing that's
kept me from screaming in his
face.
And he said yes?
He said yes.
I'm flying over
with you tomorrow.
Marvelous.
What did you tell him?
Oh, he thinks he's
doing it for Alexandra.
So that I'm not around to
criticize the yodeling and she
can't bore me to death
with her sixth form brain.
And what about my Tony?
Your Tony... hmm.
Well, I think that we should
keep Tony in the dark until we
share him up.
You know, he's only used to
having one woman at a time.
We wouldn't want to
frighten him off,
would we?
I love the TV special.
Has anyone else taped him?
No.
I think I'm the only one
who starred opposite him.
And you haven't
got Ben as well?
God forbid.
Ben gets his cock
sucked once a month,
always in the dark and
never ever in the lift.
When he drop you off and
he said to you girl oh...
So this is Tony, eh?
Nice to meet you, Tony.
Nice to meet you.
Well, I'm just happy about it.
Oh thank you very much.
Mr. Blake.
How is it going my dear?
There's too many
people in the restaurant.
Have you seen my wife?
No, I didn't.
She's always
fucking on somebody.
Hello Tony.
Hello over here.
There she's...
Ah, Vanessa, I should
like to go home now.
No, we'll go and dance.
"Don't be such a drag.
You're going to dance.
Oh go and dance.
Come on, I'll practice here.
Making me rooms and why don't
you allow that These brand new
ones Out in the shadow
searching for someone For
someone To set you free
From New York City...
Hi, Tony.
You're running
the club very good.
Is everything all right?
It's just be... it's just that
we have had another engagement
I can't keep them
waiting too long of course.
Ah superman.
What have you done with
your little girlfriend?
Well, I've sort of
lost her actually.
Oh and I'm sure you'll find
her when they sweep up in the
morning.
I'll take out with some
service, all right.
I'm going to Paris.
Oh thank you.
"Can I catch a lift, sir?
I think I should be
getting along as well.
Would be delighted to, yes.
Your car's
waiting, sir
Hello stranger you are an
angel to the love I knew
Hello darling.
Hello.
You want to dance?
Oh, no really I couldn't.
Of course you could.
No really.
How old are you?
I'm 16.
Awful, isn't it?
Hmm, that's lovely.
You're a virgin?
Well, fortunately
you're talking to a man who
specializes in
such diseases. Oh.
Sorry, I'm a lady Sorry,
I'm a lady I would rather be
Rather be Just
a little shady
Just a little shady
Naughty dynamite
Who is he?
Oh, he wants me
to dance I think.
Bloody boots,
forget about dancing,
probably walking too.
I should have worn my flats.
I'm so fed up with looking
like a cute little dumpling.
I want to be groove bit.
Can we go soon?
Yes, I suppose so.
Alex...
Franco, now she's gone.
Turn the music up for me.
Yes, sure.
Well...
Funny place, wasn't it?
What was funny?
Well, you know the...
Oh, all those old
men and young girls.
Sure.
Funny really.
Peter.
Hmm.
Kiss me.
Yes, of course.
What's the matter?
Nothing, nothing.
Crikey.
What's wrong?
It's just that I don't want
Maddy to come out and find us
in the throws of fore play
before we're even engaged.
Oh my God.
The door.
Yes of course.
What are you doing?
Oh it's you.
What is that?
And you're supposed
to be looking after...
I was going to
tell right away,
really I was.
But you weren't here.
What you're doing?
I heard it all in the loo
and then we left with Peter,
but I couldn't tell
you in front of him,
could I?
Heard what?
They were talking, she and
that rinsed out blond friend
of hers.
They're going to Paris
with him for an orgy.
But I don't think
he knows it yet.
I don't know if
Daddy would know.
Never let them
get away with it.
He doesn't know.
They said so.
She said he thinks she's going
to Paris to get out of your
way really it's to...
what you're doing?
It looks like he's
pretty good at it.
"Which is more than
your brother can say.
Oh Alex you're not
going to ...not with him.
Fontaine would hate
it, wouldn't she?
She said she doesn't
care who he does it with.
She says that's
what he is for.
We'll have to take
her word for it,
wouldn't we?
Lying in my bed on the 40th
floor suddenly crunched
in through the window.
He flies covered in blood and
glass and I just can't believe
what's happening.
I mean it's just the
most ridiculous thing.
Is Miss Khaled upstairs.
She wants to speak to you.
Who?
Daughter of Mr. Khaled.
Is she... alone?
Yeah.
Champagne.
Hello.
Hi.
I hope I haven't dragged
you away from anybody.
My pleasure.
What can I do for you?
Well you could let
me in if you would.
Well, in the club.
Yes.
It is not against the rules?
I make the rules.
Welcome back.
Thank you.
You do like it here.
Yes I did.
Am I allowed to sit here?
I wouldn't want to
upset your hierarchy.
I don't think you
would upset anything.
Oh I might.
Take it from me you're the
least upsetting person I've
met in my life.
I suppose that
is a compliment.
It is.
You are actually old
enough to drink, huh?
Everything is quite legal.
Don't worry.
Well, where do we begin?
What do you suggest?
Like to dance.
No.
Eat?
Well then, what
would you like to do?
Perhaps you
could take me home.
What now, you just got here.
Well, if that's what you want.
Almost...
What's the rush?
You don't turn into
a pumpkin, do you?
Not if you take
me to your house,
otherwise I might.
Mind these steps I don't
think they've been cleaned for
months.
Bloody cleaner, I don't
know why the door is open.
All right.
Damn.
Someone must have
cut the lights off.
I'm only ever here in the day.
Be careful.
I'll make some coffee.
What?
Electric kettle.
Never mind.
Do you want to go to bed?
Well, just like that?
We reach the
stars Beyond the star,
almost To Jupiter,
yes To Venus and mars,
yeah, almost I've won and lost
me a bet or two Making each
lover routine Now do I
have a regret or two,
almost Almost
Hey, sugar,
it's almost morning.
Do you think
Fontaine is attractive?
Put it this way, if I had two
choices you'd be both of them.
It's going to be
Christmas soon,
what are you doing?
I'm seeing mommy this weekend,
I'll probably stay there.
Are you?
Where's that?
A cottage in the country.
Would you like
to come with me?
Mm-hmm.
How's that?
I tell you how that
is, I think I love you.
I hope you would.
Will you call me later?
What, in Paris?
What are you thinking?
Dye your eyes green, it might
suit you and I tell you what,
dye your hair green
and change your shirt.
What are you so
bleeding cheerful about?
Its life man, its life.
Oh knickers.
The lady goes away for
a couple of days you're
ecstatic.
If she comes back you're
bleeding suicidal again.
I can handle it.
Anyway this one is different.
What's different about it?
Hey, mind the pins will you.
It's like fucking acupuncture.
Which side do you dress sir?
On the right,
I'm a south pole.
Thank you.
It's not like that
with this one Sammy.
If I didn't know you better
I'd say cupid was up your
arse, Antonio.
I'd say love was
rearing it's ugly head,
my son, which for a bright
young lad your position is a
bleeding disaster.
Bullshit.
Yeah, but delightfully served.
What's wrong with me
being in love with her anyway?
It does happen.
Not with you and then
diamond studded hippos,
I know, but it does happen.
Personally, I'm tired of
putting it in everything that
winks at me.
I don't care if I'm
in love with her.
I want to be in love with her.
Wrong.
What you think, then?
Jacket looks fine,
you, you look fucked.
Yeah, I was last night.
Top it all, she nicked 15
quid of me while I was still
kipping.
You can't trust them, can you?
I've been telling
you that for years.
Look at me and learn, babes.
Yeah, look at you.
The tie matches your eyes.
That Khaled had been
coming a little bit
stronger last night with you?
Mind your own business.
What are you doing now
mother daughter act?
What are you talking about?
You haven't forgotten
who your boss is, have you?
Fontaine.
What she got to do with it?
Oh, nothing sweetheart.
She's only the wife of
this fair damsel's father,
who you're screwing twice a week.
You are going to need a pair
of dark glasses and a white
stick pretty soon.
If you really want a broad?
How about Mamie?
At least she could
bank roll you, right?
Yeah, another Fontaine deal,
only this one's old and ugly.
"Hark at these
two, rent a pricks.
Thanks for the offer Hal,
I've got other avenues.
You got dead ends
baby, dead ends.
New York girl, ooh,
ooh, ooh Runnin pretty,
New York City
girl Twenty-five,
thirty-five Hello, baby, New
York City girl You grew up
ridin' the subways, running
with people Up in Harlem,
down on Broadway
You're no tramp,
But you're no lady, talkin'
that street talk You're the
heart and soul of New
York City And love,
love is just a passing word
It's the thought you had in a
taxi cab that got left on the
curb When he dropped you off
and he stated
firm Oh, oh, oh (oh,
oh, oh) You're a native New
Yorker. You should know the
score by now You're a native New
Yorker New York
girl, ooh, ooh,
ooh Music plays, everyone's
dancin' closer and closer
Makin' friends and findin'
lovers There you are lost in
the shadows, searchin'
for someone (Searchin' for
someone) To set you free
from New York City And,
whoa, where did all those
yesterdays go When you still
believed love could really be
like a Broadway show You are
the star, win the
applause Oh, oh,
oh You're a native New Yorker
No one opens
the door For a
native New Yorker
You're confirmed on the
10 o'clock flight to Orly.
You'll be met, something
about opening a club in Paris.
Oh shit.
A bit early isn't it?
How're you keeping?
Well, very well.
Listen, I'm getting those
figures for you tomorrow.
Figures?
Oh, yeah.
It should be most revealing.
So... make it a
gold mine this place.
Well, we'll call our
place the gold mine,
shall we?
All in good time
sweetheart, all in good time.
I can start looking for
premises before Christmas.
All I need is your okay and
we'll start emptying this
place into our own pockets.
That's a very good idea
Tony, very good idea.
Well, when?
"Soon as I've had
a piss, partner.
Listen, I'm serious.
Yeah, it's a very
serious business.
Give me a call over Christmas.
We'll sort
something out, okay?
Okay.
Tell me, where does Fontaine
Khaled come into all this?
Nowhere, it's just you and me.
Oh, it's a shame,
lovely lady, right?
Paris?
Yeah, well what
else could I say?
I'd be basking in Shit Street
for the New Year if I had say
no, wouldn't I?
If it had been the New Year, I
would've totally get run out,
wouldn't I?
Why?
Santa Claus
bringing you a new job,
is he?
Well, don't screw his
reindeer when he does,
will you?
One of them might turn
out to be your boss.
Listen, you 40 year old teenager,
I got Thane backing me in a
new club in a couple of weeks'
time and then I can
tell her it can run out.
Give this to Thane and let
Franco have the books back,
all right.
Yeah, sure.
You comfy back there.
It'll do.
Here, take a couple of these.
Keep your eyeballs open
even if your brain falls out.
What are they?
Uppers, you know, keep
you on top of it all.
Paris.
Welcome to Paris, Cheri.
Bon Jour.
So, what have you been doing?
Anyone I should know about?
Look, are you serious
about opening a club here?
Of course not.
That was just an
excuse to get you here.
Well, I don't like being
summoned like piece of
luggage.
Oh.
It's a nice coat.
Is it new?
This?
No.
I've had it for hours.
Jeez.
Oh lover you're
so predictable,
never late and always shocked.
Look, I'm really
tired from the trip.
But I bought this
especially for you.
Anyway, you don't get
jet lagged flying from London.
This will wake you up.
Oh lover we're going
to have a divine time.
This is going to be
a night to remember.
Now you just relax and I
will do all of the work.
I will show you
the French way.
This house is the only
brilliant thing that Leonard
ever created.
He keeps on babbling on about
all those scripts that he
sends to Hollywood and
they all end up on the reject
shelf.
Amazing.
And he does it all
with Vanessa's money too.
Look at the parrot.
Hello.
Bon Jour.
Come on lover,
they're waiting for us.
Well darling, here he is and
in excellent working order.
Tony, welcome to the feast.
Hello Leonard.
Come and sit down.
Vanessa.
This is Kamara
and this is Pierre.
How you do?
Kamara makes a fortune
painting by numbers and Pierre
helps them spend it.
Well, that's one way
of making a living.
What a remarkable young man.
Where did you
find him, Fontaine?
Inside a waiter's jacket and
trousers simply bursting to
explode.
So, I let him out.
Such an oral
strength and the eyes.
Put him down
Kamara, he's not yours.
No, you don't know
where I've been either.
I could, hazard a guess.
Then do if hazard
is the key to him.
I wouldn't say
hazard was the key,
Tony no.
Perhaps you could
tell us who he is.
Who needs a key?
I picked the lock.
And I, and to do this I'd
use either sex or money.
But suppose there are locks.
God Leonard not
philosophy, please.
You'll turn the
evening into a fucking bore.
Well, I like the
things Leonard says.
Thank you, Tony.
That makes you his
favorite listener,
after himself.
Oh, you English.
You use your smiles as seals
and your words are swords.
Oh, how profound.
Don't you wish you'd
said that Leonard?
I will.
Well, I think I'll go and take
a look around and leave you to
solve your crossword puzzle.
Now don't go straying
too far, will you lover?
I shall go with him, to be
sure that he doesn't darling.
Good.
Come Tony, let me show you
the palace of the light.
Don't worry about Kamara,
it's just another of Vanessa's
parasites, here,
drown your displeasure.
That's a very good idea.
Thank you.
I often wonder what
it is the winters buy.
One half so precious
as the goods they sell.
Drugs, could it be?
Well, you're not doing
too badly as a writer.
I wish I learned to
spell a bit better.
This is not good spelling.
This is a truce of
a cunning marriage.
I needed someone to support
me in my craft and seminar.
Vanessa needed
someone to support.
In some ways I'm more of a
tax loss than a husband.
You're not complaining
though, are you?
Come and see my
little paddling pool.
But mind the deep end.
Who are they Leonard?
I don't know but... they
are nearly always here.
Women bore me Tony.
Do they?
Much as I appreciate
an additional orifice,
they bore me.
Hey Tony, Tony hold
on, let's go for a swim.
Not just now, what
about the others?
Oh don't worry about them
they'll be long in a moment,
here.
I thought they'd never leave.
Where do you
find them, Vanessa?
Here...
So when do I get
it all together?
All we have to do is to
press, button number one.
And which button
would that be?
Well, darling all of
Tony's zones are erogenous.
You can choose anyone of
them and they are all good.
Vanessa, get here...
Come on Jess.
Coming.
Tony, I have got a
surprise for you.
Get in there.
He's wrapping up.
You're my Christmas present.
Don't you want to
see what's inside it?
Come on, come on, no come on.
I'm going to have you.
Oh Leonard, where
you've been all my life?
Take me, love it.
Ready?
Do it.
Tony, Tony, Tony don't go.
Tony, come on back.
What's going on?
It's an emergency.
Stop it.
Your cue.
That's enough darling.
Where's your husband then?
He's in Geneva.
What's he doing there?
He's meeting his daughter.
I'm supposed to be
working in his club.
It's my club.
"I can take a loss for an
hour and you're supposed to be
looking after me.
Ricardo residence.
Ricardo, wake him
if you have to.
It is in the middle
of the night, Sir.
Benjamin Khaled here.
Well Mr. Khaled, I'm sorry
Mr. Ricardo is not here,
he won't be back until...
I want him in my office
tomorrow morning at 9 o'clock.
9 o'clock.
Bon Jour.
Oh my God, what a dump.
Did I wake you?
Yeah.
Wasn't last night fun?
All that fun, you can keep it.
Nobody had a gun to
your head my pet.
You know what I mean.
I don't like being
put in that position.
And which position was that?
You were in so many.
I'm talking about those
nutters you call friends.
I hope you're not
reverting to type,
Tony.
I thought I've trained all of
that working class taboo out
of you.
Well, you haven't.
So it appears.
Vanessa was disappointed in
your performance too or rather
than the lack of it,
especially after the rave
reviews I gave you.
You mean you already had
that lot worked out between.
You cow, don't you
ever do that to me again,
ever.
I wouldn't dream of it.
As a matter of fact, I
think it's time that I started
looking for something
a bit more up market.
All right, all
right so I'm dismissed,
how do I get back home?
Fuck yourself there darling.
You could do with
a little practice.
Holy shit.
Ah, you must be Tony.
Yes, Mrs. Khaled,
right?
Ah yes.
But do come along.
Alex said you'd be arriving
but I'm afraid she's out for
the moment.
Nice little
place you got here.
Yes, well, we like it.
Now, Staton will show
you to a room and then,
perhaps you'd like a drink.
Fine, yeah, fine.
Who's that?
Tony Blake.
Your gin and tonic madam.
Thank you.
Scotch and soda sir.
Oh yeah, thank you.
Quite up here...
Would you like a drink sir?
Yeah, whiskey and coke please.
Coke sir?
Yes, cola.
That's a strange
drink young man.
With the whiskey sir?
Yes, I know its awful
shame to waste perfectly good
Coca-Cola.
Yes, quite certain.
Well, as I was saying, I'm
just down the road next to
Mrs. Haley Scott.
Do you know her?
No, don't know her.
Yes, well, her husband
died about three years ago.
They used to keep race horses.
Comme un cheval.
Thanks darling.
Oh well.
Very nice, did you
make them yourself,
don't you?
Sit there.
Next to you.
Thank to you.
That's right.
What are you doing here?
No, not here.
Okay, we'll just talk.
Not now.
What's going on Alex?
Going on?
I can't get near you.
Really, I...
Look, I came here for you
and not this country bullshit,
you understand.
Christ, Alex, I'm sorry.
I just never felt like
this about a chick before and
that's all.
A chick?
Get out of my room.
Get back in your nasty little
car and take your stupid words
back where you belong.
Go on, get out.
For Christ Alex,
what did I do?
What did you do?
You think I don't know about
you and that cheap slut who
owns you.
You think you can break my
father's heart between the
rotten pair of you and expect
me to love you on a one night
stand?
Listen Alex, Fontaine,
she's nothing to me.
Go and tell her then.
Go and tell the bitch.
Tell her I sent you back
again as a Christmas present.
You're just about
what she deserves.
A cheap gigolo in a
little night club,
a visit when she
feels like it.
Go on, get out.
Get back to your chicks
and your stupid friends.
You're pathetic.
Did you think I'd fall for
the irresistible Tony like the
rest of them?
Is that what you thought?
Is it?
Come on.
I'm home.
Where's everybody?
Who are you?
Where's my husband?
Who the hell are you?
My name is Rupert
Scott, Mrs. Khaled.
I work for your
husband in a legal capacity.
He asked me to give you this.
Your husband has instructed me
to inform you that he's taking
divorce proceedings against
you at the earliest possible
opportunity in the New Year.
Also that your clothes and
effects have been removed from
this property and placed for
your convenience in a suite at
the Connel hotel all
reasonable care was taken.
Further that as
from midnight tonight,
this property reverts to the
holding company and all the
keys and locks will
therefore be changed.
A notice has also been
promulgated to the effect that
your husband is no longer
responsible for any debts
incurred by you in his name.
My God.
Is there anything
you'd, you'd wish to ask me,
Mrs. Khaled?
You, no.
Very well then.
I'll bid you goodnight.
Oh, by the way
Merry Christmas,
Mrs. Khaled.
Mr. Thane is not
in at the moment.
If you wish to leave a message
please speak after the tone.
Merry Christmas here my lad.
Its Tony Blake here, sorry
I couldn't get you before
Christmas but you
know how it is.
Give us a call will
you, you got the numbers.
Don't forget about
our little deal.
Hark the herald angels
sing Glory to the newborn King
Peace on earth and mercy mild
God and sinners reconciled
Hello.
Yes?
It's, its Tony Blake
here, Mrs. Khaled?
Yes, it's I.
Yes, we did meet briefly.
That's right.
I was wondering if I
could speak to Alexandra,
please.
Well, I'm afraid
she's out at the moment,
Tony.
Can I get her to ring you?
Yes please.
Does she know your number.
Yes.
Well, goodbye then.
Bye-bye and Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas.
What was that?
Oh, it is nothing important.
Friends, this is one
of the happiest moments
of my life.
I propose a toast to
my daughter, Alex.
2p, love.
Goodbye darling.
Mr. Thane is not in.
Sammy Marks.
Hello, Sammy, it's Tony.
How are you?
I heard you were dead and
doing the club circuit up
north is that true?
No, that's an ugly rumor.
I'm alive and well,
living in South America.
Pick the right
time of year for it,
didn't you?
What are you doing down here?
Well, Christmas
with my mom and dad,
who may or may not be alive,
you can't tell till you switch
the box off, then
you hear them snoring.
Well, I was supposed to be
tucked up with Alex but...
I don't know.
Not that mother
and daughter act.
No way.
I had enough with that
lunatic woman in Paris.
Did she have enough of you?
Yeah, her and her mate.
I got to get out of that one
Sammy and I thought if I could
just talk to Alex.
You are thick my
old fruit ain't you.
I mean, I love you
but you are thick.
Thanks.
Listen my son, there's two
sorts of ladies in this world.
The first sort will
pick you up and screw you,
second sort will pick your
brains and screw you up.
Your Alex belongs to the
latter half as far as you're
concerned.
You're not from the
same planet you two,
I mean, she might fancy
you or she might not.
When it comes to any
kind of permanent fixture,
you've got all your assets and
eligibility of a piece of very
rough trade.
I'm not hurting
your feelings, am I?
I don't believe you, Sammy.
All right, so my name is not
hopely stopley and I didn't
make head boy at Gordonstoun
but I can still handle myself
can't I, but if I couldn't
that club wouldn't be nothing
without me for a start and
it's not going to end there
either, not by a long way.
They're going to be eating off
of my tables for very shortly,
you'll see.
Oh yeah, yes.
Yes, if Thane came through.
Yeah, firm?
The contract has been drawn.
Oh, not firm.
A verbal agreement worth
exactly the paper it's
written on.
Listen Tony, with a
schmuck like Thane,
you don't believe till the
money is in the bank and then
checked by experts to make
sure the Queen's picture ain't
winking at you.
Thane is the
serpent in the garden,
my son.
I'm not worried.
Yeah, that's what
I like about you.
Come on, let me buy you a
drink for the New Year,
you're going to need it.
You don't often meet a
winner who loses like you.
Let's go disco Let's go disco
Having fun, Tony?
Don't know whether you know
but Alex and I are engaged,
getting married in
the spring probably.
Don't you think
it is a good idea,
but we thought we'd hold
our engagement party here?
Yes, I know it's a bit
of a delicate subject,
see you later old chap.
Excuse me, excuse me.
Have you seen Madeline?
Are you all right?
Here, where you
been all my life?
I tell you what,
play your cards right,
you could have me tonight.
Ooh amazing lips, amazing.
Let's go disco Let's go disco
The night is
still young Let the DJ play
your song Let's go disco
Tony, give us a kiss.
Tony, you're
looking very well.
You know Ian of course.
We've met.
Perhaps next time
you'll be a little wiser.
As a matter of fact, you
saved me some problems.
Ben wants to sell and Ian
has offered to buy his share.
Since you're going to go
into business for yourself,
all I need to do is to find a
new manager for this place and
don't be here
tomorrow will you, Tony?
There's a good boy.
Is life beautiful man.
Ain't it beautiful?
Five minutes everybody.
Hello Charlie, how are you?
You bastard, you
cock sucking bastard.
You and that whore stab me
in the fucking back with your
bloody night club punks.
Well, I'll tell you what, I'm
fucking finished with you and
this bloody dump...
You are a filthy runt.
Here we go.
Get him out of here.
Come on you.
Get up.
Tony.
Come here.
Give us a call
champ,
anytime.
Nine, eight, seven,
six, five, four, three
Mr. Blake, Mr. Blake.
Two, one, Happy New Year.