Custom subtitles created by Spicediver for MP4 release.
AVI subtitles also available with slightly adjusted sync.
In the year 6041, before the
reign of the Padishah Emperors
the Universe was ruled by thinking
machines with human minds...
computers and conscious robots.
The people deteriorated
into a state of apathy.
Then they became victims and
slaves of other men with machines.
Finally came the Great Revolt
- the religious crusade against the machines.
After the Great Revolt, human beings
were forced to develop their minds.
Thus, mental training
schools were established.
These schools would change
the history of the Universe.
Only two of these ancient
mental training schools remain.
One is the Bene Gesserit school, which was
established primarily for female students.
The function of the Bene Gesserit school
is to carry on a selective
breeding program among humans.
Now the other existing school
The Spacing Guild, or The Guild
emphasizes pure mathematics.
The Guild's space Navigators, through
the use of the orange spice drug
are able to fold space.
That is, to guide spaceships without
moving, from one planet to another.
It is through the Guild's monopolies
on the economic life of the Universe
that makes it so powerful.
Know then, that it is the year 10,191.
The known universe is ruled by
the Padishah Emperor Shaddam IV.
For many years the Emperor Shaddam
IV has ruled on planet Kaitan
over all the Great
Houses of the Landsraad.
The Great Houses of the Landsraad
are members of the royal families
who rule or govern over the
major planets of the Universe
according to the ancient
feudal system of government.
In this time the most precious substance
in the Universe is the spice melange.
The spice extends life.
The spice expands consciousness.
The spice is vital to space travel.
The CHOAM company controls
the mining of the spice.
The CHOAM company is controlled
by the Padishah Emperor Shaddam IV
and the Great Houses of the Landsraad
with the Guild and the Bene
Gesserit as silent partners.
This combine is the key to the wealth
and political power of the Universe.
The spice exists on only one
planet in the entire Universe.
A desolate, dry planet
with vast deserts.
The planet Dune.
Also known as Arrakis.
We are the secret of the Universe.
Bi-la kaifa.
We are the secret.
We know of CHOAM in the Universe
Combine Honnete Ober Advance Mercantiles
controlled by the Emperor Shaddam IV
and all the Great
Houses of the Landsraad.
We know of CHOAM...yet
we are the secret.
We know of the Bene Gesserit sisterhood
their selective breeding
plan for 90 generations
to produce the Kwisatz
Haderach, whom they will control.
The ones they call the
witches...yet we are the secret.
We know of the Guild and their
Navigators' power to fold space
and their control over
all interplanetary travel.
We know they have they seeing
eye...yet we are the secret.
The Bakka shall weep no more, for
there is now at work a higher power.
Bi-la kaifa.
And now
the prophecy.
One will come,
the voice from the outer world,
bringing the holy war,
the Jihad,
which will cleanse the Universe
and bring us out of darkness.
Four planets have come to our attention
regarding a plot which could
jeopardise spice production.
Planet Arrakis: source of the spice.
Planet Caladan: home of House Atreides.
Planet Giedi Prime:
home of House Harkonnen.
Planet Kaitain: home of the
Emperor of the known Known Universe.
Send a third-stage Guild Navigator to
Kaitain to demand details from the Emperor.
The spice must flow.
Father?
Irulan, you must leave.
Why does the Guild send a
third-stage Navigator here?
Spice! It has to be.
He senses my plan.
My Lord...
The Reverend Mother is here.
All entrance corridors and
chambers have been cleared.
We are dismissed?
Yes, yes, he'll sense any surveillance.
No eavesdropping of any kind!
A third-stage Guild Navigator
will be here within minutes.
We felt his presence.
I shall want telepathy during his visit
and a report when we're finished.
Their minds are so...
they move in strange directions.
Yes?
Forced spice evolution of
humans changes many things.
I must sit close to him.
He will not permit anyone but me to
see him. You must be outside this room.
I am your Truthsayer, my Lord.
Here's here, my Lord.
The Bene Gesserit witch must leave.
Leave us.
Yes, my Lord.
We have just folded space from Ix.
Yes? How was your journey?
Many machines on Ix. New machines.
Oh? Yes?
Better than those on Richese.
You are transparent. I see many things.
I see plans within plans...
Is there a problem? Usually there's a
problem when one of you makes a visit.
The answer is within the problem.
I see two Great Houses
House Atreides, House
Harkonnen, feuding.
I see you behind it.
Yes.
You must share with us.
The Atreides House is building a secret
army using a technique unknown to us
a technique involving sound.
The Duke is becoming more
popular in the Landsraad.
He could threaten me.
I have ordered House Atreides to
occupy Arrakis to mine the spice
thus replacing their
enemies the Harkonnens.
House Atreides will not refuse
because of the tremendous
power they think they will gain.
Then, at an appointed time, Baron
Harkonnen will return to Arrakis
and launch a sneak
attack on House Atreides.
I have promised the Baron five
legions of my Sardaukar terror troops.
So the Harkonnens will rid
you of House Atreides...
Yes!
Listen to me. The spice must flow!
The spice has given me accelerated
evolution for 4000 years.
It has enabled you to live 200!
It gives the Bene Gesserit sisterhood
the metaphysical ability to see beyond,
to have superior powers.
Our power to fold space is in the spice.
Without us your empire would be
lost on isolated, scattered planets.
YOU would be lost.
One small point...
Here it comes.
We ourselves foresee a slight
problem within the House Atreides.
Paul...Paul Atreides.
You mean of course Duke
Leto Atreides, his father.
I mean Paul Atreides.
We want him killed.
I did not say this. I am not here.
I understand.
Why would they want
the Duke's son killed?
Well?
They fear that putting House Atreides
on Arrakis will hurt spice production.
For us, a small amount is enough
to greatly extend our lives
but they consume tremendous quantities.
A great deal is needed
to evolve the seeing eye.
They worry.
The Universe worries when
they worry. What else?
So much was unclear.
You may go, Helen Mohiam
Bene Gesserit.
Yes, my Lord.
She's Bene Gesserit.
There's nowhere in the
Universe you can escape them.
Her loyalty to the sisterhood is
stronger than her loyalty to me.
Watch her carefully.
Why would they want
the Duke's son killed?
We must have a look at
Paul Atreides, on Caladan.
The powerful Bene Gesserit sisterhood
for 90 generations
has been manipulating bloodlines
to produce the Kwisatz Haderach.
A super being.
On Caladan, Jessica,
a member of the sisterhood
and the bound concubine
of Duke Leto Atreides
had been ordered to bear only daughters.
Because of her love for the Duke,
she disobeyed and gave
birth to a son, Paul.
Paul Atreides.
Here we are now. Caladan.
And 19 light-years beyond
beyond Bene Tleilax
The training planet of the Mentats,
the human computers.
Know a Mentat by his red-stained lips.
There, Arrakis.
Carryalls lower the
harvester to the sand
and lift it off to safety
when a worm attacks.
Worms attack all rhythmic vibrations.
Never one drop of rain on Arrakis.
And the Harkonnens are near. There.
Giedi Prime and the Baron Harkonnen.
The enemy.
The Baron Harkonnen has sworn
to destroy House Atreides
and steal the ducal
signet ring for himself.
Saguaro
burrow bush
creosote bush
barrel cactus...
Gurney Halleck, a troubadour-warrior
is companion and
teacher to Paul Atreides.
Dr. Wellington Yueh,
Royal Physician to
the House of Atreides.
He wears the diamond tattoo
of imperial conditioning
on his forehead.
This signifies that he has
had the highest conditioning
against taking human life.
Therefore, this makes him safe
enough to attend to even an emperor.
Among those who serve Duke Leto Atreides
is Thufir Hawat,
Mentat Master of Assassins
to the House of Atreides.
A Mentat is a human being
who is trained and conditioned
for supreme accomplishments of logic.
A human computer to
perform certain duties.
I know, Thufir, I'm sitting
with my back to the door.
I heard you, Doctor Yueh,
and Gurney coming down the hall.
Those sounds
could be imitated!
I'd know the difference.
Yes. Perhaps he would at that.
My father sent you to test me.
Music, then?
No music.
I'm packing this for the crossing.
Shield practice.
Shield practice?
Gurney, we had practice this morning.
I'm not in the mood.
Not in the mood?
Mood's a thing for cattle and love play.
Not fighting!
I'm sorry, Gurney.
Not sorry enough.
Now, guard yourself for true!
Is this what you seek?
Good.
The slow blade penetrates the shield.
But, uh, look down.
We'd have joined each other in death.
You did seem finally to get in the mood.
Would you really have drawn my blood?
If you'd have fought one
whit below your abilities,
I'd have given you a
good scar to remind you.
Things have been so serious here lately.
Soon we'll leave for Arrakis.
Arrakis is real.
The Harkonnens are real.
Doctor Yueh,
do you have any information
on the worms of Arrakis?
I've obtained a filmbook
of a small specimen.
Only 125 meters long.
Only?
There have been documented
sightings of worms
as large as 450 meters
in the deep desert.
That's far from where
we'll be in Arrakeen.
The desert belt and
the south polar region
are marked forbidden.
The storms and the worms.
Is it true that the sand
can blow at 700 km per hour?
It can render flesh
into dust in minutes.
And these dry winds can also generate
tremendous amounts of static
electricity in the atmosphere.
Our body shields won't have enough power
to operate in the open air on Arrakis.
How do the Fremen survive there?
We don't know much about the Fremen.
They live in the deep desert,
some of them in the cities.
They have
blue-within-blue eyes.
The eyes.
Yes.
Saturation of the blood
by the spice melange.
Could the spice affect us in other ways?
Many dangers exist on Arrakis.
For one,
the Harkonnens would not have given up
their CHOAM Company contract so easily.
The Harkonnens are our enemies, yes.
But behind them, I
suspect, is the Emperor.
You'll make a formidable Duke.
Now, remember,
the first step in avoiding a trap
is knowing of its existence.
I know, but if it is a trap
then why are we going?
We have our new army.
Doctor Yueh,
put the weirding module on him.
Clear and lock the room!
Detachment, stand down.
Activate a fighter.
Make the range 2 meters.
Precise control.
It's not Duncan's style.
Nor mine.
That's his mother's influence.
Another member of the Duke's household
is Duncan Idaho,
friend and swordmaster to Paul Atreides.
Duncan!
Paul, I was just on my
way to say goodbye to you.
I have to go on ahead, alone,
I won't be seeing you for a while.
I wish you were coming with us. Why?
Something for your father.
He wants to talk to you.
I'll see you on Arrakis.
May the hand of God be with you.
May the hand of God
be with us all, Duncan.
Father.
Thank you for joining me, Paul.
It will be good to get to our new home
and have all this upset behind us.
Thufir Hawat has served House
Atreides three generations.
He swears you are the finest
student he has ever taught.
Yueh, Gurney, and Duncan say the same.
Makes me feel very proud.
I want you to be proud of me.
I'll miss the sea.
But a person needs new experiences.
They jar something deep inside,
allowing him to grow.
Without change,
something sleeps inside us
and seldom awakens.
The sleeper must awaken.
Arrakis, Dune...
desert planet.
I will kill you.
The second moon.
Tell me of your home world, Usul.
Jessica, you were told to bear
only daughters to the Atreides.
Jessica!
It meant so much to him.
You thought only of a
Duke's desire for a son?
Desires don't come into this.
An Atreides daughter could have been wed
to a Harkonnen heir
and sealed the breach.
We may lose both bloodlines now.
I vowed never to regret my decision.
I'll pay for all my own mistakes.
And your son will pay with you.
Is Arrakis...
Is it really so terrible on Arrakis?
My Duke...
You entered into this
with full knowledge of the
delicate edge you walked.
Jessica.
Girl.
I wish I could stand in your place
and take your sufferings.
But we must each of
us take our own path.
I know.
I understand.
About Paul...
What you did and why
you did it, we both know.
But kindness forces me to tell you
there is little chance you will
be the Bene Gesserit totality.
However, I will observe him.
In a few minutes, Jessica,
your son will be proved
to be a living human being
or he will be a dead animal.
He's here.
Arrakis, Dune
desert planet.
Moving...
moving...
We'll salvage what we can.
But I can tell you, dear God,
for the father, nothing.
Did you really think you could
bear the Kwisatz Haderach?
The Universe's super being?
How dare you!
My greatest student.
And my greatest disappointment.
He's awake. He's listening to us.
Good! Ready yourself,
young Paul Atreides.
I want to see you in your mother's
chambers in one-quarter of an hour.
Paul.
This is very important.
Remember you are a duke's son.
This is the Reverend
Mother Gaius Helen Mohiam.
She's going to observe you.
Please.
Jessica,
you know it must be done.
Your Reverence.
What does she fear?
What about my father?
Paul,
listen to the Reverend Mother
and do what she tells you.
Now, you,
come here.
She's using the Voice.
No.
Some strength there.
Surprising.
Come here!
Come here...
Do you see this?
Put your right hand in the box.
What's in the box?
Pain.
Stop.
Put your hand in the box.
I hold at your neck the gom jabbar.
Don't pull away or
you'll feel the poison.
A duke's son must know
about many poisons.
This one kills only animals.
Are you suggesting the
Duke's son is an animal?
Let us say
I suggest you may be human.
Your awareness may be powerful enough
to control your instincts.
Your instinct will be
to remove your hand from the box.
If you do so,
you die.
You will feel
an itching
there.
Now the itching becomes burning.
Heat upon heat upon heat.
It burns.
Silence! Silence!
I must not fear. Fear
is the mind killer.
And fear is the little death
that brings total obliteration.
I will face my fear. I
will permit it to pass
over me and through me. I must not fear.
You feel the flesh crisping.
Fear is the little death that
brings total obliteration.
I will face my fear.
Flesh dropping off.
Fear is the little death.
I must not fear...
Fear is the little death. I'm...
The pain!
No! Enough!
Kull Wahad!
No woman child ever withstood that much.
Take your hand out of the box
and look at it, young human.
Do it!
Pain by nerve induction.
A human can resist any pain.
Our test is crisis and observation.
I see the truth of it.
Could he be the one?
Maybe.
But will he be ours to control?
You know when people speak the truth?
I know it.
Tell me of your homeworld, Usul.
Your mother wants you to
tell me about your dreams.
I only want to know one thing:
Do they come true?
Not all of them.
I know which ones will.
Perhaps you are the Kwisatz Haderach.
What is that?
The person who can be
many places at once.
The one who bridges time and space.
He will look where we cannot.
Do you know of the Water of Life?
The bile from the
newborn worms of Arrakis?
I have heard of it.
It is very dangerous.
The Bene Gesserit sisterhood
use it to see within.
There is a place
terrifying to us,
to women.
It is said
a man will come.
The Kwisatz Haderach.
He will go where we cannot.
Many men have tried.
They tried and failed?
They tried and died.
Jessica.
I sense your teachings in him.
Ignore the regular order of training.
His safety requires the Voice.
I've heard enough of my safety.
What about my father?
I heard your talking.
You speak as if he were dead.
Well, he's not!
But he's not.
And he won't die. Tell me he won't die.
What can be done has been done.
Mother, tell me!
The Voice could save you.
The Baron Harkonnen sent Duke Leto
a gesture of peace.
No way would the Duke
forego the art of Kanly,
as vendetta was known.
This then, is the Duke's response
as he sat writing at his desk:
"Your offer of a meeting is refused.
"I have ofttimes met your
treachery, and this all men know.
The art of Kanly still has
its admirers in the empire."
Then he signed it "Duke Leto of Arrakis"
knowing full well that
this would annoy the Baron.
With his ducal signet ring,
the Duke put the seal of the House
of Atreides under his signature,
"Duke Leto of Arrakis. "
Vas!
Mentat Piter De Vries.
Message for Mentat Piter De Vries.
The Baron is impatient for Leto's reply.
It is by will alone I
set my mind in motion.
It is by the juice of Sapho
that thoughts acquire speed,
the lips acquire stains,
the stains become a warning.
It is by will alone I
set my mind in motion.
It is by the juice of Sapho
that thoughts acquire speed,
the lips acquire stains,
the stains become a warning.
It is by will alone I
set my mind in motion.
My lord.
Piter.
The Atreides will be
leaving Caladan soon, Baron,
and I have here your
answer from Duke Leto.
What does Leto say, Piter?
He wishes to inform you that "vendetta,"
as he puts it, using the ancient tongue,
the art of Kanly, is still alive.
He does not wish to
meet or speak with you.
I've made my peace gesture.
The forms of Kanly have been obeyed!
Bring in Feyd and Rabban.
As you instructed me,
I have enlightened your
nephews concerning my plan...
My plan!
The plan...to crush the Atreides.
Feyd.
Rabban.
Go quietly.
No other great house of the Landsraad...
must ever know of the
Emperor's aid to the Baron.
The entire Landsraad would
turn against the Baron...
and the Emperor.
Put the pick in there, Pete,
and turn it 'round real neat.
You are so beautiful, my Baron.
Your skin, love to me.
Your diseases, lovingly cared for...
for all eternity.
I will have Arrakis back for myself.
He who controls the spice
controls the universe!
And what Piter did not tell you...
is we have control of
someone who is very close,
very close to Duke Leto.
This person, this traitor,
will be worth more to us
than ten legions of Sardaukar!
And who is this traitor?
I won't tell you who the traitor is...
or when we'll attack.
However, the duke will
die before these eyes,
and he'll know, he'll know that it is l,
Baron Vladimir Harkonnen,
who encompasses his doom!
This is what I'll do to
the duke and his family.
I once told you a
daughter would be conceived
at a time of parting.
I remember.
Conceived in love at a time of parting.
Arrakis is a hostile world, though.
I must be sure you want this.
It has to be tonight,
under these influences.
I didn't hear you with the wind.
I whispered yes.
And I whispered:
"I love you."
Soon they will begin to fold space.
Far off in the control
rooms of spice gas.
Traveling without moving.
And now,
the prophecy.
One will come.
The voice from the outer world.
Bringing the Holy War,
the Jihad.
Which will cleanse the Universe
and bring us out of darkness.
A mother and a son.
House Atreides took control of Arrakis,
63 standard days into the year 10191.
It was known that the Harkonnens,
the former rulers of Arrakis
would leave many suicide troops behind.
Atreides' patrols were doubled.
Each trooper will be charged
with responsibility
for preserving water.
Our existence as an
operating army depends
on these following
water-saving procedures.
Remember, water is life.
Why is the shield not yet up?
Sir, we found and removed
another sabotage device.
I think it'll go up now, sir.
They're finding these
sabotage devices too easily.
House shield activating.
My lady, the local people,
the maids and servants,
await your inspection.
Hawat has cleared them.
Excuse me, my lady.
The Harkonnens may have
tampered with them medically.
When you said Harkonnens,
I didn't know you had so
much reason to hate them.
Well, my wife...
But, of course, you didn't know my wife.
The
Har--
Forgive me.
They must have killed her.
Please excuse me if
I can't talk about it.
He's holding something back.
Yet there's the Imperial conditioning.
Assurance of trust.
The Bene Gesserit mother, the legend.
Where is your son?
I must warn you. You
are in great danger.
My message, it's here.
There are more enemy bodies coming in
for your inspection, Doctor Yueh.
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine.
Thank you, Thufir.
My Lord.
My Lord?
Thufir.
Haven't you heard from Duncan Idaho yet?
No, Sire.
I have, however, discovered
what the city Fremen
called out to Paul when
we entered the city.
Mahdi
and...Lisan al-Gaib, yes.
It is a prophecy
that a young leader will come to them
with a Bene Gesserit mother.
It follows the familar messiah pattern.
But Mahdi?
Yes.
It seems it is written
that he will lead them to true...
freedom.
One carryall handles
four spice mining teams.
However, it will fly only
two harvesters at a time.
Today, we have 930 harvesters
and 981 carryalls.
Safe.
Spice.
The second moon.
The sleeper must awaken.
A hunter-seeker!
It can't get me if I don't move.
It's too dark in here
for it to see clearly.
It would have killed me.
I was its target. It went to the motion.
Who are you?
I am the Shadout Mapes,
the housekeeper.
I must cleanse the way between us.
You saved my life,
and we Fremen pay our debts.
It is known to us that you've
a traitor in your midst.
Who it is, we cannot say.
But we are certain of it.
A traitor.
Set up a sonar probe immediately.
Thufir!
did you find anything?
Nothing yet.
Keep looking.
And the traitor? God help us.
Harkonnen.
My lord...
Again, my lord, I wish
to tender my resignation--
Silence, Thufir. Stop acting the fool.
I told you yesterday.
If you made a mistake,
it was in overestimating the Harkonnens.
Their simple minds came
up with a simple trick.
Paul survived this largely
because of your training.
You didn't fail there.
Sit down, Thufir.
My lord.
Thufir,
there's this traitor.
I know you've cleared everyone,
especially those close to us.
But recheck and find him.
Sector 6 through 80
progress report, Sire.
Take it, Thufir.
Sector 680, copy the 6th, the
summit, the 8th, quadrant over
the 9th plus 84 circles, weave
the 80 and call the 4th. Copy.
8. Thufir Tawat, Mentat,
Master of Assassins.
The palace is now secure.
The city of Arrakeen
is under martial law.
We have troops here
headquartered underground
on sub-floors 6 through 10.
The rest of the troops
are stationed in Arrakeen
and we have some on the airfield.
Our new army is still in training,
but everything, everything is shielded.
And with this shielding
we are impenetrable.
Kynes...
Dr. Kynes is waiting.
He is the Emperor's Judge of the Change
monitoring the evacuation
of the Harkonnens
and our taking control.
He plans on taking you
on an inspection of the
spice mining operation.
Now, he may or may not
be sympathetic to our cause. But, Sire,
with the attempt on the young master,
I am against your leaving the palace.
The attempt failed.
Harkonnen captives
have already been taken.
We must crush the Harkonnen
machine on Arrakis.
You all know what to do!
Gurney, we desperately
need more spice miners.
Many are threatening to
leave on the next shuttle.
We need spice drivers,
weather scanners, dunemen.
Any with open sand experience.
You must persuade
them to enlist with us.
"They shall come all for violence.
"Their faces shall sup
up as the east wind.
And they will gather the
captivity of the sand."
Very moving, Gurney.
On your way.
And take care of Doctor
Kynes until Paul and I arrive.
We will not be prisoners
here in this place.
Behold, as a wild ass in the
desert go I forth to my work.
Yes?
I am the Shadout Mapes.
Your housekeeper, noble-born.
What are your orders?
You may refer to me as "my Lady."
I'm not noble-born.
I'm the bound concubine of Duke Leto,
mother of the heir designate.
"Shadout."
That's an ancient word.
You know the ancient tongues?
I know many things.
I know you came prepared for violence
with a weapon in your bodice.
My lady,
the weapon was sent as a gift,
if you should prove to be the one.
And the means of my death
should I prove otherwise?
Do you know this, my Lady?
It's a Crysknife.
Say it not lightly.
Do you know its meaning?
It's a Maker.
Did you think I wouldn't know the Maker?
My lady,
when one has lived with
prophecy for so long,
the moment of revelation is a shock.
Mapes!
You sheath that blade unblooded.
Yes!
Take the Water of my Life.
You are ours.
You are the one.
So you are Doctor Kynes.
The Judge of the Change.
And the lmperial Ecologist, Sire.
Our intelligence informs us
that there's still a
strong Harkonnen presence.
The process of removal continues.
This is my son, Paul.
Are you a Fremen?
I've been on Arrakis
in the service of the Emperor
long enough for my eyes to change.
In the service of the Emperor...
We are in your hands, Doctor.
Your gift of the stillsuits
is much appreciated.
Would you give us an
explanation of their workings?
Well, this is a stillsuit
of Fremen manufacture,
the most efficient type on Arrakis.
Basically--
It's all right, Gurney.
Yes, Sire.
Basically, it's a
high-efficiency filter
and heat exchange system.
Perspiration passes
through the first layer
and is gathered in the second.
The salt is separated.
Breathing and walking
provide the pumping action.
The reclaimed water
circulates to catch pockets
from which you can
drink through this tube
around your neck.
Urine and feces are
processed in the thigh pads.
Should you be in the open desert,
remember to breathe
in through your mouth
and out through this nose tube.
With a Fremen suit in
good working condition,
life can be sustained for weeks,
even in the deep desert, Sire.
My thanks.
With your permission.
You've worn a stillsuit before.
No.
Your suit is fitted desert fashion.
Who told you how to do that?
No one.
It seemed the proper way.
That it is.
He shall know your
ways as if born to them.
We're wasting time, Sire.
Battle language?
Translate it.
Very faint.
Harkonnen.
Air speed, zero-five.
Ambient temperature, 300 degrees Kelvin.
Air speed, three-zero.
Ether bender, 75 percent efficiency.
That's where I told your sandmaster
to concentrate the harvesting today.
Southeast, over the Shield Wall.
Ambient temperature, 350 degrees Kelvin.
Air speed,
one-three-zero.
Caution. You've now cleared
protective Shield Wall
and entered open desert.
Will we see a worm?
Where there is spice and spice
mining, there are always worms.
Always?
Always.
Why do they come?
To protect their territory.
Vibrations attract them.
Is there a relationship
between the worms and the spice?
As I said, they defend the spice sands.
As to their relationship with the spice,
who knows?
Dust cloud ahead, Sire.
That's it. Spice mining.
No other cloud quite like it.
See the spotters over it?
They're watching for wormsign,
the telltale sand waves.
Seismic probes on the
surface, too, Sire.
Worms can travel too deep
for their waves to show.
Looks like a good patch of spice.
Wormsign?
Is it wormsign?
Yes. Worm. Big one.
You've got sharp eyes. May I?
Calling Harvester Pad Nine. Wormsign.
Who calls Pad Nine?
Don't mention the Duke.
This is an un-coded channel.
Unlisted flight northeast of you.
Wormsign on intercept course.
Estimated contact, 15 minutes.
Have sighting confirmed.
Stand by for a fix.
Contact in 16 minutes minus.
Very precise estimate.
Who's on that unlisted flight?
What happens now?
The carryall will come and
lift off the spice harvester.
Try to get in close over the harvester.
You'll find this interesting, Sire.
They work until the very last minute.
Spotter control, there's
no sign of the carryall.
It isn't answering.
The worm is eight minutes away, Sire.
Spotter control, give me
a report by the numbers.
Report One.
No contact.
Report two.
Negative.
Report three.
Negative, sir.
Report four.
No contact. Repeat, no contact.
I think they've got our carryall.
Damn it! Harkonnens.
We're coming down to take
you off the harvester.
All spotters are ordered to comply.
Ordered by whom?
Duke Leto Atreides.
Yes. Yes, Sire.
How many men do you have?
Full crew, 26 men.
But, Sire, we can't
leave all this spice.
Damn the spice!
Get out of there!
Two men in each of the spotters!
You, over here!
Run!
I can't see him yet,
but he is very close now.
Damn sloppy. Really damn sloppy.
Come on, boys. Come on.
We're going to be heavy, Sire.
Spice.
Pure unrefined spice.
Here he is! We've got to go!
Bless the Maker and his water.
Bless the coming and going of Him.
May His passing cleanse the world.
What's that you're saying?
Nothing.
Gods, what a monster.
Someone is going to
pay for this, I promise.
He's more concerned over
his men than the spice.
I must admit, against
all better judgment,
I like this Duke.
Duncan!
The Fremen have sent
a message to you, Sire.
Have you read this?
No, I was instructed it was for you.
It says:
"A column of smoke by day,
a pillar of fire by night."
A warning.
An obscure one, at best.
What have you discovered
about the Fremen, Duncan?
Tell me.
Why haven't we heard from you?
My lord, I suspect so much.
I think they are the allies we seek.
They are strong, fierce.
They do not give their
loyalty easily or quickly.
As you know,
the lmperium has never been able
to take a census of the Fremen.
Everyone thinks that there are but few
wandering here and there in the desert.
My lord,
I suspect an incredible secret
has been kept on this planet.
That the Fremen exist in vast numbers.
Vast.
And it is they who control Arrakis.
Dr. Kynes,
being in the employ of
the Emperor, as you are,
perhaps it isn't wise
for you to associate
too closely with us Atreides.
On the contrary,
I feel very comfortable here.
Remember how precious water is here.
It was a token of respect.
Are you enlisting with us?
You see through to the
truth of the thing, Sire.
That means a dual alliance.
He's in with the Emperor.
A dual alliance, yes.
But not with the Emperor.
The Fremen.
Then let water be a bond between us.
Sorry you have to sleep
so far underground,
but we can't take any chances.
I see you're studying.
Knowledge is strength.
Yes, so says Thufir Hawat.
One must have more than that
to hold Arrakis against
our many enemies.
Much more.
Much...
more.
Paul,
if anything should happen to me...
Father, nothing's going to happen.
Yes.
But if it
should, l--
Yes?
Unknown objects on screen.
We are attempting to identify.
I'll be back, son.
Sleep well, my son.
Father...
drugged...
Jessica, what is wrong?
Forgive me, my beloved concubine.
I should have married you.
Why hold a dream to ascend to the throne
through a political marriage?
I should have married you.
What happened?
Yueh!
He sabotaged the house generators.
We are wide open!
House shield deactivating.
I've destroyed the new
army's weirding modules.
I've brought House Atreides down.
Why?
I wish to kill a man.
Not you, my dear duke.
You were already dead.
But you'll get close to
the Baron before you die.
You'll be tied and drugged,
but you can still attack.
You can still attack!
When you see the Baron,
you'll have a new poison gas tooth.
He'll want you close,
so he can gloat over you.
One bite on this tooth
and a strong exhale...
Refuse.
No! You mustn't!
Because, in return, I'll save the
lives of your Paul and Jessica.
For Paul.
When you see the Baron,
remember the tooth.
The tooth!
Attention! Attention!
We are approaching target area.
The bomb scopes are set.
The shield is down! The shield is down!
Open the doors!
Signals!
Get that shield up!
The shield!
The weirding modules...destroyed!
Man the planes.
Release the bombs, release the bombs.
Long live Duke Leto!
The drug was timed.
Dr. Yueh has been very valuable to us.
What a pity you must remain gagged.
We can't let ourselves be swayed
by your witch's voice, now, can we?
Leto, where are you?
Bring him here!
You've done a very good job.
He hardly feels a thing.
Open your mouth.
Open it! Open it!
You've done a good job, traitor.
They are alike, this mother and son.
Paul.
Dangerous.
The training they have had...
beyond most people's imaginations.
Leto.
I leave them in your hands, Piter.
Goodbye, Jessica.
And goodbye to your sweet son.
I want to spit once on your head.
Just some spittle in your face.
What a luxury.
We were ordered to
kill them. So kill them!
What are your orders, Piter?
Take them to the desert,
as the traitor suggested.
The worms will destroy the evidence.
Their bodies must never be found.
I knew Yueh's wife.
I was the one who broke
his lmperial conditioning.
I've thought of many pleasures with you.
It is perhaps better that you die
in the innards of a worm.
Desire clouds my reason.
That is not good.
That is bad.
They're down on this floor somewhere.
Down there.
Duncan!
Back! Keep him back from me!
You wish now to join your wife?
Is that it, traitor?
She lives?
You wish to join her?
Join her.
You think you've defeated me?
You think I don't know what
I've gained for my wife?
Take him away.
Guards!
Where are they?
They're over the great desert.
Continue reconnaissance.
Yueh's sign.
He's left us stillsuits.
Don't touch my mother!
He's trying the Voice.
The Reverend Mother
said it could save him.
Did you hear a noise
from the little one, huh?
I didn't hear anything.
The little one.
Remove her gag.
Excellent!
Remove
her gag.
There's no need to fight over me.
...to fight over me.
A poisoned blade.
First cut my son's bonds.
...my son's bonds.
That's it.
Oh, my God!
Duke Leto Atreides.
Someone's torn the
insignia off your uniform.
That's careless.
It was Feyd.
It was Feyd?
Duke Leto Atreides.
Where is the ducal signet ring?
I must have his ring.
The ring!
He was brought to us
as is, my lord Baron.
You killed the doctor
too soon, you fool!
The doctor, Yueh, what did he say?
Paul and Jessica safe.
Yes. The tooth!
He's coming around, Baron.
Where's your ring?
Huh?
You do not answer?
Wait! Wait!
You must come closer.
The water of my life
for Paul.
He's crying. He's crying!
What does that mean, Piter?
Come closer, Baron.
Jessica!
Paul!
Leto!
Leto, he's dead!
Oh, he's dead!
I know.
Am I alive?
I'm alive?
Yes,
you're alive, my Baron.
I'm alive, eh?
I'm alive!
I'm alive! I'm alive!
I can't maintain any altitude.
We'll never reach the safety of rock.
Maybe that small rock.
Where are we, do you think?
The south polar regions.
The forbidden area. Hold on.
Hurry!
Take the stillsuits!
This crash might bring a worm.
The signet.
A million deaths are
not enough for Yueh!
Where are my feelings?
I feel for no one.
The second moon.
I mean Paul Atreides.
We want him killed.
He who controls the spice,
controls the Universe!
This moon holds my future.
Never one drop of rain on Arrakis.
The sleeper must awaken.
They will call me
Muad'Dib.
Listen to me. Listen!
You wanted to know about my dreams.
Well, I've just had a waking dream.
Do you know why? The spice!
It's in everything here.
Calm yourself.
Like the Truthsayer drug.
It's a poison.
You knew the spice would change me.
But thanks to your teachings,
it's changing my consciousness.
I see it! I can see it!
Is he the one?
You carry my unborn sister in your womb.
He knows.
You and your Bene Gesserit sisterhood.
I'm not your Kwisatz Haderach!
I'm something different.
Something unexpected.
I am so much more.
You don't begin to know me.
Father!
Father, I promise,
one day the sleeper will awaken.
Father.
Go now.
Take him to his desert to die.
Go.
Yueh's left the plan
for the weirding modules.
We have to get to that mountain of rock.
We have entered the time
when all will turn against us
and seek our lives.
It's further than I thought.
A worm is sure to come.
I'll plant this thumper.
That should divert it.
Remember...
walk without rhythm and
we won't attract the worm.
It will go to the thumper.
I'm ready.
Faster!
It's deafening!
The spice!
Do you smell it?
Yes!
Paul!
A thumper.
What's happened?
Why did it leave?
Someone started another thumper.
We're not alone.
Man-carved steps.
Yes.
Such stealth. I didn't hear them.
Perhaps these are the ones
the Shadout Mapes told us of.
I will take the boy-man.
He shall have sanctuary in my tribe.
Stop!
Get back! She has the weirding way.
Great gods!
If you can do this to
the strongest of us,
you're worth 10 times
your weight of water.
As the leader of my
people, I give you my bond.
Teach us this weirding way,
and you both shall have sanctuary.
Your water shall mingle with our water.
Then I will teach you our way of battle.
I give you the word
bond of a Bene Gesserit.
It is the legend.
I am Chani, daughter of Liet.
I would not have permitted
you to harm my tribe.
From my dreams.
So beautiful.
Come with me.
I'll show you an easier way down.
He surprised me.
It was an accident.
Stilgar, I invoke the Amtal Rule.
Jamis, you force this fight.
These people have my countenance.
If you should win, I will cut you down.
Jamis, I don't want to fight you.
Maybe if
I explain--
Explain?
Explain death.
I am going to sheath
my knife in your blood.
No shields.
I'm used to shield fighting.
Take my crysknife.
Jamis turns to the right
with his knife after a parry.
And watch for a knife switch.
May thy knife chip and shatter.
How does it feel to be a killer?
He gives water to the dead.
My son has never killed before this day.
You have strength.
You shall be known as Usul,
which is the strength of
the base of the pillar.
This is your secret name in our troop.
But you must choose the name of manhood,
which we will call you openly.
What do you call the mouse
shadow in the second moon?
We call that one Muad'Dib.
Could I be known as Paul Muad'Dib?
You are Paul Muad'Dib.
And your mother shall
be a Sayyidina among us.
We welcome you.
The dream unfolds.
The wife and sons of Jamis.
This water belongs to Usul.
May he guard it for the tribe.
May he be generous with
it in time of need.
Jamis carried 33 liters and seven
and three thirty second drachms.
Do you accept them?
Yes.
Water masters.
Moisture!
Wind traps.
Huge ones.
Water. Millions of decaliters.
A treasure.
Greater than treasure, Usul.
We have thousands of such caches,
and only a few of us know them all.
And when we have enough,
we shall change the face of Arrakis.
Tell me of your home world, Usul.
What is it?
Liet, Chani's father,
the leader of our people, is dead.
Killed by the Harkonnen.
For the father, nothing.
Both of us have lost our fathers.
Rabban! Rabban!
Rabban!
We're knee-deep in Atreides blood!
We've gutted them!
Rabban! Rabban!
I place you in charge of Arrakis.
It's yours to squeeze, as I promised.
I want you to squeeze
and squeeze and squeeze!
Give me spice! Drive them!
Drive them into utter submission!
Do not show the slightest pity or mercy!
Never stop! Go! Go!
Show no mercy!
Yes, Baron!
Feyd.
And when we've crushed
these people enough,
I'll send you.
Feyd.
Lovely Feyd.
Where's my doctor?
Jessica,
our Reverend Mother is too old.
She has been calling
through space and time
for you to come and let her rest.
She asks that you pass within
and become our Reverend Mother.
Do you know the Water Of Life?
Come watch the mystery of mysteries.
The end, and the beginning.
The Water Of Life.
If you be a Reverend Mother,
let Shai-Hulud judge now!
But what of my unborn child?
Following the Bene Gesserit tradition,
the old Reverend Mother
surrendered her life
as she surrendered her knowledge.
Jessica had successfully transmuted
the poisonous Water of Life.
Every man who has tried has died.
The sleeper must awaken.
The tremendous power
of the Water of Life
caused the premature birth
of Jessica's daughter, Alia.
Alia was born with all the knowledge
and powers of a Reverend Mother.
Feyd, even though he's aging,
Thufir is one of the finest
Mentats in the Universe.
And he's mine, Feyd, all mine.
Quiet now.
I will.
Come.
Oh, Thufir,
I see they've installed
your heart plug already.
Don't be angry. Everyone gets one here.
But this is not why we're here.
We've brought you a little cat, Thufir.
You must care for it
if you wish to live.
A poison has been introduced
into your body, Thufir Hawat.
By milking this-- this
smooth, little cat's body,
you receive your antidote.
It must be done each day.
All I can see is an
Atreides that I want to kill.
Feyd, no. No!
Thufir's a Harkonnen now.
Aren't you, Thufir?
My Duke, how I've failed you.
Chani, I love you.
I've always loved you.
We sense that you may be the
voice from the outer world.
Both moons told us of you.
You must pass tests before we will know.
You must conquer the
beast of the desert,
both his outer and his
deadly inner powers.
Speak to us from the outer world.
The Holy Warriors.
No one ever dreamed there were so many.
I am Usul. Paul Muad'Dib.
Our shared enemy, the Harkonnens,
are once again in control of Arrakis.
Stilgar, your leader,
has asked me and my mother
to teach you the weirding
way to crush the Harkonnens.
We must do more than this.
We must totally destroy all
spice production on Arrakis.
The Guild and the entire
Universe depends on spice.
He who can destroy a
thing, controls a thing.
I will take 100 of your
warriors and train them.
This 100 will train the
thousands that remain.
When the spice flow stops,
all eyes will turn to Arrakis.
The Baron and the Emperor himself
will be forced to deal with us.
Arrakis will become the
center of the Universe.
Orato!
This obelisk is of your hardest stone.
Kick it.
Hit it.
Yell at it.
Break!
Korba, cut it.
Move back.
This is part of the weirding
way that we will teach you.
Some thoughts have a certain sound
that being the equivalent to a form.
Through sound and motion,
you will be able to paralyze
nerves, shatter bones,
set fires, suffocate an
enemy, or burst his organs.
We will kill until no
Harkonnen breathes Arrakeen air.
Muad'Dib!
Stilgar.
Muad'Dib.
Hmm?
Muad'Dib. Muad'Dib. Muad'Dib. Muad'Dib.
My name is a killing word.
They are ready to fight.
Yet in order to lead them,
I must conquer the
worm, conquer Shai-Hulud.
Usul, it is time you become a sand rider
and travel as a Fremen.
Take the kiswa maker hook of our sietch
and ride as a leader of men.
Two thumpers are planted.
The worm may not surface for the first.
He will rise for the second.
And remember,
when the worm approaches,
you must be utterly still
and close enough to plant the hook
firmly under a ring segment.
The worm will turn to
lift this exposed area
as far from the abrasive
sand as possible,
and it will take you with it to the top.
Do not get too close.
As he approaches, the
sand will engulf you.
Wait till the head of the worm passes,
then go quickly.
Shai-Hulud.
I must not fear. Fear
is the mind killer.
Only the very strong
ones travel this deep.
Usul has called a big one!
Again, it is the legend.
Muad'Dib!
Now we are ready for battle.
Usul, these are 15
of our finest warriors
to serve you as your guard.
The Fedaykin.
Now.
Muad'Dib.
When the spice flow stops,
all eyes will turn to Arrakis.
The Baron and the Emperor himself
will be forced to deal with us.
Muad'Dib. Muad'Dib. Muad'Dib.
Muad'Dib.
What happened?
What happened to you and your men?
Muad'Dib! Muad'Dib!
What are you saying?
Muad'Dib! Muad'Dib! Muad'Dib! Muad'Dib!
He's been repeating that
name ever since we found him.
Who is this Muad'Dib?
In the two standard years that followed,
Muad'Dib and the Fremen brought
spice production to a standstill.
Fearing for his life,
Rabban did his best
to hide this fact from
his uncle, the Baron.
Paul's sister Alia matured
at a frightening rate.
Her small body harbored
tremendous powers.
Paul and Chani's love grew.
We surprised a band of smugglers.
Too bad. I thought they were Harkonnen.
Gurney!
You've no need of your weapons
with me, Gurney Halleck.
Paul!
Paul.
Don't you trust your own eyes?
They said you were dead.
They...
They said...
Gurney.
You young pup.
Gurney!
You young pup!
Emperor Shaddam IV,
you have one last chance to
take matters into your own hands
and bring the situation
under control on Arrakis.
What do you mean one last--
Do not speak.
Listen. You do not have
more than this one chance.
I represent the entire
Guild in this matter.
Our Navigators warn you that spice
production is in great danger.
A new Fremen leader, Muad'Dib,
has stopped spice mining on Arrakis.
Our Navigators suggest
he is not of Arrakis.
No one on the outside world
has been able to see him.
We do not know who he is.
The Harkonnens cannot stop him.
Remedy this situation,
restore spice production,
or you'll live out your
life in a pain amplifier.
The Emperor will stop him.
He won't take the Water of Life.
I want 50 legion of
Sardaukar on Arrakis at once!
50 legions?
That's our entire reserves as well.
This is genocide,
the deliberate and
systematic destruction
of all life on Arrakis!
The Emperor is coming!
Chani! Chani!
You were calling my
name. It frightened me.
Oh, Chani.
All the images of my future are gone.
I have to drink the Water of Life.
No, Paul, please.
I've seen the men who have tried.
I've seen how they died.
I'm dead to everyone unless
I try to become what I may be.
Only the Water of Life
will free what can save us.
Paul.
I must drink the sacred water.
We must go now.
Hurry. All I see is darkness.
Paul.
I will love you forever.
You are my life.
Many men have tried.
They tried and failed?
They tried and died.
They're not attacking. Why?
Alia...
Mother.
It's Paul.
He's taken the Water Of Life.
Paul's voice!
The Guild,
they're fighting me
in the mental worlds.
They're behind everything.
They fear the one who'll come.
Who'll know more.
Who'll see more.
The Guild is behind everything.
It's not finished yet.
I'm not formed.
There is a place terrifying to us,
to women.
This is the place they cannot look.
Traveling without moving.
Now I truly control the worm
and the spice.
And I have the power to
destroy the spice forever!
Paul.
Father!
Father.
The sleeper has awakened!
Muad'Dib.
Arrakis,
Dune,
desert planet.
Your time has come.
A storm is coming. Our storm.
And when it arrives, it
will shake the Universe.
Emperor, we come for you!
We come for you!
Long live the fighters!
Meanwhile, the Baron Harkonnen
having been alerted
to trouble on Arrakis
is on route to check
on his nephew Rabban.
Suspicion confirmed.
The Emperor's had Rabban seized.
Stand by the main control room.
Gurney, when the storm
hits, set off the atomics.
I want an opening through
the entire shield wall.
Stilgar, do we have wormsign?
Usul, we have wormsign the likes
of which even God has never seen.
Bring in that floating
fat man, the Baron.
Why have you brought me here?
Your Highness, there
must be some mistake.
I never requested your presence.
Ah.
But your lack of action demanded it.
Your dreadful mismanagement,
your bad judgment
in assigning to Rabban the governorship.
You've forced me to come here
and set things straight, personally.
And why did you not tell me of the
fighting ability of these people?
We've just flushed out a nest
of them in the open desert
and the women and children
overpowered some of our Sardaukar.
We managed only one hostage.
Bring in the hostage!
Only one.
I am a messenger from Muad'Dib.
Poor Emperor.
I'm afraid my brother won't
be very pleased with you.
Silence!
Kill this child. She's an abomination.
Kill her.
Get out of my mind!
Not until you tell them both
who I really am.
...who I really am.
Alia,
daughter of Duke Leto the Just
and the royal Lady Jessica.
Sister
of Paul Muad'Dib.
Paul's sister? Paul is Muad'Dib?
Alia keeps pace with the storm.
With the storm,
their air power will be useless.
On Arrakis, it's desert power.
Gurney.
Now!
Atomics!
Our army awaits us.
My brother is coming
with many Fremen warriors.
Impossible!
Not impossible.
I told you. He is here now.
Father, today I will avenge your death.
An impassable storm has descended.
The Shield Wall has been
penetrated by atomics.
Release the Sardaukar.
Baron, give this little
abomination to the storm.
Wait for my brother, Baron.
Wait for my brother.
Muad'Dib!
Alia, now.
Come to me, Baron.
Muad'Dib!
Feyd Rautha.
My God. They've taken your mind.
Gurney, I see Thufir
Hawat among the captives.
Let him stand free.
The antidote...
Thufir.
Come.
A knife.
In payment of many years
service to my family
you may now ask of me anything you wish.
Anything at all.
Do you need my life, old friend?
It is yours.
I mean this, Thufir.
If you are to strike, do it now.
Three generations of...you.
Carry this noble Atreides warrior away.
Do him all honour.
Emperor Shaddam IV,
there are Guild Heighliners above us
containing many Great
Houses of the Landsraad.
Send them back.
How dare you
speak to me in--
Stop your speaking.
You have some idea of what I could do.
Don't try your powers on me.
Try looking into that place
where you dare not look.
You'll find me there
staring back at you.
You mustn't speak--
Silence!
I remember your gom jabbar.
Now you'll remember mine.
I can kill with a word.
And his word shall carry death eternal
to those who stand
against the righteous.
The righteous?
There is a Harkonnen among you.
Give the Harkonnen a blade,
and let him stand forth.
If Feyd wishes, he can meet
you with my blade in his hand.
I wish it.
This is a Harkonnen animal.
Let me. Please, my Lord.
The Emperor's blade.
Why prolong the inevitable?
I will kill you.
I will kill him!
Paul.
Who is the little one? A pet, perhaps?
Will she deserve my special attentions?
You see your death.
My blade will finish you.
I will bend like a reed in the wind.
Chaaksa!
Muad'Dib.
Usul no longer needs
the weirding module.
Irulan shall be my wife,
opening the way for an
Atreides to take the throne.
I sit on the throne!
You will sit on a throne on Salusa
Secundas, your prison planet.
Either that or you will die.
The princess shall have
no more of me than my name.
No child of mine
nor touch, nor softness of
glance, nor instant of desire.
This is my promise to you
my love.
Think on it, Chani.
We who carry the name of concubine,
history will call us wives.
Muad'Dib had become the hand of God
fulfilling the Fremen prophecy.
Where there was war,
Muad'Dib would now bring peace.
Where there was hatred,
Muad'Dib would bring love
to lead the people to true freedom
and to change the face of Arrakis.
We Fremen have a saying.
God created Arrakis
to train the faithful.
One cannot go against the word of God.
And how can this be?
For he IS the Kwisatz Haderach!