Something is wrong
with Gizmo lately.
He's morose, distracted.
Like a man with a secret.
I mean, he's still
a perfectly adequate familiar.
But there's just something
not right about him.
What it is, I don't know,
but I intend to find out.
So we're all here.
That's good.
- If I can have
your undivided attention
-  What?
- for a few minutes?
- Absolutely not.
-  No.
So, aren't you
actually a vampire now?
- Hmm?
- Didn't you pay
your friend Derek
- to turn you into a--
- We're not talking
about that right now.
He's behaving unusually.
If there's anyone that can get
to the bottom of this
kind of thing, it's me.
Why? 'Cause I'm
the king of bottoms.
♪ Don't sing if you want
to live long ♪
♪ They have no use
for your song ♪
♪ You're dead, you're dead,
you're dead ♪
♪ You're dead
and out of this world ♪
♪ Now your hope and compassion
is gone ♪
♪ You sold out your dream
to the world ♪
♪ Stay dead, stay dead,
stay dead ♪
♪ You're dead
and out of this world.♪
- As I was saying--
-  Couple of questions.
First one:
- Why? And also,
- Okay, you know what?
- who gives you the right?
-  Okay, I was just--
I have a follow-up
to that.
Okay.
Yeah.
Nadja, Laszlo,
Colin Robinson, please.
I would like to hear
what Guillermo has to say.
A lot has changed
since you last saw me.
I'm in a really good place.
And it is all thanks
to an ancient book of wisdom
I discovered
that laid buried in Laszlo's
library of precious volumes
for years and years.
This book has
taught me to focus
on what is really important,
like who is okay
and who is not okay.
Thank you for sharing, Guillermo.
You are okay.
- I didn't say anything yet.
- Then that is okay.
Okay. I want to talk about
something very important.
If this about
my sexual intercourse,
I saw the doctor
and took the test.
No, that was a Cosmo quiz
that you took
called "Which Sex and the City
Icon Are You?"
- And I was Kim Cattrall.
- Ooh.
-  Now, I haven't
got a clue who
that is,
but as long as she's sexy
and down to fuck, bingo.
- Fine diagnosis.
-  Okay, the thing
I want to talk about is
- vampire safety.
-  Go on.
You're all becoming very sloppy
covering your vampirisms
in public, okay?
It's becoming very dangerous.
What is the big deal?
If anyone notices,
we just hypnotize them
- like we always do.
-  No,
you've been doing that
way too much lately.
Yes, but I have getting
really okay at it.
- You okay?
- I am fine.
No, no, no. No, no.
- You will all forget
that someone tripped
and who it was.
I just fear that
the hypnosis is making
the borough dumber and dumber.
We live in Staten Island.
Nobody will notice.
There are just some things
you will never understand
- because you're not a vampire.
-  Yeah.
-  Very good point.
But even if I was a vampire, I--
We are not laughing with you,
we are laughing at you.
You know what?
Enough, okay?
Don't count on me to always
be here to protect you.
I'm not gonna be around forever.
Really? Where will you go,
David Attenborough?
-  Right now?
- Yes.
- Out of this room.
- Oh, finally.
And that is okay.
Look, guys, please, can I just
have, like, a minute?
Please, can--
You know what, fine.
Fine.
Let's get this over with.
Lock the door.
Lock the--
Please look the door.
So, yeah, 16 days ago,
I made an impulsive decision
to have Derek...
Make me a vampire.
Sure, man.
- Oh. Whoa. Not yet, sorry.
-  Just a...
I know, but just
gonna take my...
- cardigan off.
- Yeah, of course, of course.
Just don't want anything on it.
- My grandma gave it to me.
- Mm.
And...
I was a little nervous at first,
and your first time
I guess always... is?
Uh... Okay.
- Here we are.
- Yes.
- Yeah.
I'm ready.
-  Derek,
customer toilet
is clogged again.
You know what?
I got to take care of this.
Wait, what? Now?
If I don't do it now,
people just go
on top of what's already there,
and believe me,
- then no one's happy.
- Derek,
later.
After...
Oh, yes, of course, yes.
You know what?
Trevor's always telling me
I have bad task management
skills, you know?
First, turn you into a vampire.
- Yes.
- Then I'll clean the toilets.
I'm ready.
Derek moved in,
and finally--
What are you doing?
Just... showing off your...
your sound machine.
Why do you have it on
"rainy night at
the leaky castle" setting?
- Ah...
The creatures of the night.
Such beautiful music they make.
It also has a setting
for "banshee wail"
- It's white noise.
- and "abandoned orphanage."
"Twinkle, Twinkle, Little Star."
- Very creepy.
- Master, is there something that
you needed to discuss with me?
Yes.
There is.
Guillermo...
we know why
you have been acting so
oddly lately.
- You do?
- Mm.
Are you-are you mad?
Yes.
We are mad at ourselves
for forgetting your birthday.
I am okay and you are okay,
but this is not okay.
For a human,
a birthday is a terrible day.
- We have forgotten his birthday.
- Oh, yes.
No, I really don't think
it's about his birthday.
And if it is, what a bitch.
- When is his birthday?
- Uh...
I don't know, to be honest.
Poor creatures
only live for, like,
two, 300 years, tops.
So we are taking you out
for a birthday dinner.
Change into your nicest
shitty sweater
- and we will see you
at the restaurant.
- What...
What restaurant?
So, full disclosure:
I am back in the workforce.
I'm Colin Robinson.
I'll be taking your order today.
So, what are we thinking about
munching on?
I decided to take a break
from the office life.
How about we set you two up
with some pro-sexy?
It's a fun way
of saying prosecco.
- Prosecco is...
Simply because
the opportunities to feed
in the service industry
are so incredible.
Dressing on the side. Ugh.
Uh, I can ask the chef,
but it's probably a no go.
- I hate to see you cry.
- I'm not crying.
I just...
I want...
Pardon my reach.
Oops.
Just wanted to check in
on you two,
see how everything's tasting.
Think about desert.
- Strip steak.
- Uh-huh.
Medium-well.
The Caesar salad
but with no croutons.
Are you sure
you're getting all this?
Yeah, I-I never
write anything down.
I got it.
I think I know you want.
Bon appétit.
Hey, folks, my name is Colin.
I'll be your server
this evening.
Has your whole party arrived?
No. Tonight,
Gizmo arrives upon an Uber.
- Mm-hmm.
-  Okay. They're really
not supposed to
seat you until your
entire party has arrived.
Can I ask you to go stand
in the crowded alcove
where the cigarette smoke
comes in?
Fuck off.
Just get us anything
so it looks like we're eating.
Okey dokey, jalapeño poppers,
jalapeño poppers,
and one more per la tavola.
Koúkla mou, do you want
to come up and join us?
- No, I hate you
and I want to die.
When I was running
the vampire nightclub
I may have got a little bit
too much into the old, uh,
liquor blood.
And then, one night,
I got so shit off my faced...
...that I sat on my dolly
and I minced her legs
with my wagon.
Don't be such a Debbie Downer.
- Come and join in the human
birthday party.
- Yes, eh?
What you've done to my legs
is unforgivable.
Nadja absolutely crushed
my lower body.
There's nothing wrong
with my butt.
Eh, I'll be the judge of that.
And Colin Robinson's solution
is something I very much
do not like.
Come on, you can be the queen
of the restaurant, huh?
- Push the button, my darling.
-  Don't you dare
press the button on my toe.
Oh, come on, it's so fun.
-♪ I feel good... ♪
- No! I don't actually
feel good at all!
♪ I knew that I would, now... ♪
I will never forgive you for
destroying my-- ♪ I feel good ♪
- Wow! Peekaboo!
Queen of Soul in the house.
-♪ So good... ♪
- Fuck-fuck-fuck you all!
♪ So good ♪
-  I think so.
♪ I got you. ♪
Ow!
- Ow! Stop!
Put me back under the table.
- Oh, what have I done?
- You know what you did.
You're never
going to forgive me, are you?
Colin Robinson.
- Yes, sir?
-  Are those
"yalapeño" whatevers--
are they coming any time soon?
Oh, I'll ask your server
to check on those.
I thought you were our server.
I'm on break.
- My darling,
what is on your mind?
-  Yes.
It's nothing, I just...
I can't get something
out of my mind that
that little pipsqueak Gizmo
said about
not being around forever.
I mean, he could mean
that he's gonna die soon.
- Right.
- That's something that, uh,
- humans do.
-  All the time.
Or he could get his old job
at Panera Bread back.
That's another thing
all humans do
- at some point. Or...
- Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
I suppose eventually,
perhaps, he could...
...become a vampire himself.
- Fuck, no.
- What an idiot.
- It could happen.
It could happen.
I don't understand why.
Why do you keep asking that?
You were there,
you saw what happened.
- Why are we going to--
-  Guillermo,
we're just trying to
understand it from
your point of view.
Derek leaned in...
Wait, stop!
- Oh, what?!
- Sorry.
Have you done this before?
Yeah.
Tons of ti--
Like, many dozens of times.
- Derek.
- I'm-- No.
I haven't. No.
Um, have you?
Why doesn't Andy just do this?
- Who?
- Your master.
You mean Nandor?
Oh-- Okay.
That clears up so much for me.
I mean, I kept thinking,
"A vampire named Andy?
That's so random."
It's not like
he doesn't want to.
It's, like, he always says
he's gonna get around
to it, you know?
He actually cares
about me a lot,
and he does a lot of
- really nice things for me.
- Oh.
Oh, sorry, I'm just pausing.
It's for the editors.
They insert, probably, like,
a cute montage or something,
of all the stuff
he's done for me
- over the years,
so, might take a second.
- Okay.
- Oh, okay.
- Yeah.
Are you sure
you want to do this?
Yes.
No, I still absolutely
want to be a vampire.
I just didn't think it would
- happen like this.
- Mm.
I don't know, maybe it's, like,
deep down inside,
my psyche is just
telling me that
I'm really not ready to, like--
Oh, shit!
What the fuck are you doing?!
- Oh, oh, oh.
I'm sorry, I-I thought
you said you were ready.
I wasn't ready!
I heard "ready!"
I just heard "ready!"
I think he hit an artery.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
!¡Puta madre!
Oh!
And it was just like...
Aah! Fucking shit! Oh!
Be honest with me. Is it bad?
Hold still, let me look.
Uh, yeah, it's bad.
- Oh! !¡Puta madre!
Okay, I got to drink your blood.
Ooh. That is gonna be
a sticking point for me.
- Why is that?
- Because I'm a bit of a fainter.
- I have low blood pressure.
- What?
If I'm being honest, you people
can be real parasites.
I mean, why do I need
to repeat myself?
You were there,
you saw the blood.
- Thank you so much, and
I will be giving you five stars.
- Yeah.
And you know what? I'm done.
I'm off to my birthday dinner
when it's not really
my birthday.
Imagine Guillermo
flying around
in his little short legs.
- I enjoy that joke.
- That's made my night.
What's so funny?
What'd I miss?
Hey, gang.
Hi. Do you mind if I borrow?
Thank you so much.
- That's me.
- What's so funny?
Oh, nothing.
We were doing the joke
where we imagine
that you have become a vampire.
I don't know why
that's so laughable.
- Could you imagine
Grahame as a vampire?
- I know!
He would be just a little bat
with diarrhea, like...
Flying and then...
Why do I always shit
in your scenarios?
Guillermo, I'm sorry.
Eventually, of course,
I will definitely be
turning you into a vampire
when the time is right.
But you got to admit,
it's a funny image.
With the big glasses.
Or a shitty woolen cape.
What if-what if I didn't wait
till I felt like you thought
the time was right?
-  What do you mean?
-  What if, hypothetically,
walking down the street,
and then Dracula--
- Dracula?
-  He says,
"Do you want me to make you
into a vampire?"
And I said yes?
A familiar going to a vampire
who is not his master
and asking him to turn him?
Now, I am a fan of edgy comedy,
but that is no laughing matter.
I'm not entirely sure
we should be
talking about any of this
out loud.
But it's okay.
I was just saying hypothetically.
Hypothetically,
what you are talking about
is the greatest humiliation
a familiar could bestow
upon his master.
If that were to happen, Guillermo...
...then I will kill you.
I would not like to do it,
but I would have to do it.
And then I would kill myself,
which I would not like either.
There are some things
about which
we do not joke.
Obee-kaybee.
I have six plates
of veggie dumplings
and a chocolate pudding.
-  That looks...
-  Mm, brown.
- Thank you.
-  ...like shit.
Well, it was a nice dinner,
so you have had a happy birthday
to distract you from the fact
you will soon die.
- You are welcome.
- Hear, hear. Well said.
And, for your birthday wish,
we all promise
to do a much better job
of blending in,
as you requested.
I guess I'll see you
back at the hou--
Okay. I'm just gonna
get some stuff at the mall.
What is "mawrl?"
-  [gasps] I have heard
-  Oh, ho!
about this thing called mall.
But I thought
it was a myth, a rumor,
a fairy tale made up
by an insane child.
- This, I have to see.
-  Maybe I shouldn't
have mentioned anything
about the mall. That's on me.
I take responsibility for that.
Okay, this is the mall.
Just sit down and people-watch,
do whatever you want
while sitting down.
I'm gonna get some new glasses
and a footlocker
- and then we can go home.
- It is rising!
-  That's an elevator.
- Ah.
So just stay here.
- Great.
- Yes, we understand.
-  Okay, great.
- I'll be right back.
-  All right. Yeah.
I'm gonna get you
some new knickers.
What is Sephora?
Gilly's Gifts. Very nice.
This mall has
a Guillermo's Gifts?
Uh, I'm not sure.
That is fine.
I will explore.
I would like you to tell me
more about this product.
-  Well, that's Shrek.
- Great.
Ring me up.
And also...
I would like you to honor
these special coupons.
I will honor this coupon
for a free oil change
that expired 18 years ago,
- Yes.
- and this one that's
just a cut-out photo of
Ryan Seacrest from a magazine.
- Will it work?
- Yes, of course it will work.
We are going to fix this,
and this is how we do it.
Sorry about that.
- So, did we make a selection?
- Yes.
I am looking for
the exact proportions of
Venus herself when her pussy
was serving witches tea,
nipples so sharp they're on
the most wanted list,
and a taint that can sign
its own checks.
Uh... I meant more like,
which hat did you want?
Oh, yes.
Rainbow sombrero for sure.
-  Okay.
- What is wrong now?
You didn't even
ask for my opinion.
What the hell are you
talking about?
Did you not hear
what I said about the taint?
Malls are fascinating places
full of fascinating things.
That's a baby village.
Makes sense to keep them all
in one place.
That's called London Shoes.
Now, if those shoes
were really from London,
they'd be covered in shit.
Bikini Warehouse.
- Must be a front for a brothel.
-  Excuse me.
- Hi. Would you like to sample
our new scent, Noir?
- No, fuck off.
Can't be sidetracked
with cheap sex potions.
Question still remains.
What is Gizmo up to?
Hyah!
Prepare to be pillaged!
- Laszlo!
- Shut up.
- I found John!
- Idiot.
-  It's John!
- Fucking idiot.
Make this thing go faster!
That was, uh, some pretty
heavy stuff at dinner, huh?
Just stuff I did not even,
I didn't even...
...know.
Sorry.
Where was I? Um...
I was hemorrhaging profusely,
uh, about to die.
- You good?
-  Yeah.
- Yeah, I think so.
- Well, that's good.
- 'Cause I haven't done it yet.
- Oh, dude.
Other people's blood
I'm fine with.
But the sight of my own?
No, thank you.
You know, when I think
about fainting, I faint.
It's really hard
to break the skin.
- Um...
- I'm running out of time
here, buddy.
Here. Why don't you slice me up
with this box cutter?
Are you sure?
It's gonna hurt.
- I'm a vampire.
I think I can handle it.
- Okay.
- Did you do it?
- Yeah, I did.
- But don't look because--
- Don't look at what?
- Oh, shit.
- No, Derek.
No.
The deed is done.
The die is cast.
There's no turning--
Derek. Toilet again.
Oh...
Okay, sorry, dude,
I got to go take care of this.
Oh, shit. Dude?
- Dude?
So, yeah.
That's where we're at.
It seems to be
a process.
I thought the transformation
would be faster,
but I haven't drank blood.
I can still eat human foods.
In fact, my appetite
for very rare meat is ravenous.
My teeth are
totally normal and...
I don't feel any sexier.
I can still go out into the sun.
I can't fly or turn into a bat.
Yet.
Bat!
Human form.
I thought the transformation
would be overnight,
but it's been 16 days.
Which is why I've been
keeping it a secret.
I was kind of holding off
for that big
"wow factor" for the reveal,
but at this point,
I don't even think
I should tell them because--
-  Mr. de la Corz?
- Uh, so sorry about that.
De la Cruz? That's me.
- De la Cruz.
- Hi.
How long have you been
wearing glasses
with this prescription?
Oh, since I was three or four?
I-I don't know
who screwed up here,
but you actually
don't need glasses at all.
According to the eye exam
you just did,
you have 20/20 vision.
It's actually better than
20/20 vision.
- Whoa.
- Yeah.
Well, that is...
a super power.
- Wow, that's... Wow.
- So, right now, you're wearing
a very strong prescription
for no reason.
- Let's stop doing that.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, okay.
Would it be possible
to just get a pair
without a prescription?
Just, I don't want
people to think
I look... different.
Uh, yeah. Sure.
You want the same frames or...
Did you enjoy your birthday?
It was all right, Master.
I guess I wasn't really
that hungry.
And that is okay.
Do the other side.
- Master?
- Mm-hmm?
If I accidentally
got made into a vampire...
- Mm-hmm?
- by somebody else,
you wouldn't really...
kill me, would you?
Accidentally, you say?
- Yes.
- Not intentionally?
No, I guess... not.
I'd still have to kill you.
What choice would I have?
What about "vampire shall not
kill other vampire"?
Guillermo, I don't like
hypothetical brain-ticklers
before bedtime.
- You know this.
- Right.
Makes my head heat up.
How's about
a nice bedtime story?
Okay. I did see
this very interesting movie
the other night.
- Oh, tell me.
- It was about this guy.
- And he got turned
into a vampire.
- Really?
- Yeah.
But then he realizes that maybe
he wasn't ready
to be turned into a vampire.
Why not?
He had his reasons.
But then
he tries to find a way to
stop the process of becoming
a vampire and rever--
Guillermo, please.
I don't like
science-fiction stories
before bedtime either.
- Yeah.
- That reminds me.
I got you a birthday present.
I heard you when you said
you wanted a footlocker.
So I got you
a footlocker.
-  Thank you, Master.
- Yes.
You are welcome.
Close the lid.
Being a vampire is
no different
than being a human.
We're all just doing
what it takes to survive.
We go on about our day.
Blend in.
Act like everyone else.
But the truth is
we're all just hiding
in plain sight.
♪ Secrets in the moonlight ♪
♪ Whispers in the dark
with you ♪
♪ Secrets in the moonlight ♪
♪ Silent fire kiss or two ♪
♪ When there are moonbeams ♪
♪ Dancing on your cheek ♪
♪ My darling, every dream ♪
♪ I've ever had ♪
♪ Comes true ♪
♪ When I share secrets
in the moonlight ♪
♪ With you. ♪