I do as I please!
Oh, hey, what do we got here?
You got Riggs.
Hey, Neil.
I just scouted it.
How is it?
It's a gold mine!
Yeah, once we gut the forest, baby,
you got prime-A real estate, I'm telling you.
Sanders? I don't know.
My men say he's doing fine,
but I plan on swinging by tomorrow
and letting him know
that I'll be taking over operations.
Hello? Mr. Lyman?
Hello?
Give a hoot, don't pollute.
Whatever.
Oh, what's this?
Out of the way, fuzzball.
You got to the count of three,
little man. One...
That was awesome.
No, put that down.
Ha, ha. Very funny. Bad raccoon.
Bad, bad, raccoon.
Mr. Lyman, I quit!
Nature.
Look alive, people, the capitán on deck.
Morning, Frank.
Men seem to be making good progress.
There's nothing like having the boss
living on site. Duck.
I have a question, you have the answer.
That's the way you get things done
around here.
These past few months
have been a blessing for me.
Look out, there.
Hop.
So, good progress on unit number five.
I don't know if I can say the same thing
about number three.
It's the beaver dam.
It's a good one, too.
It's blocking the drainage about 30 yards in.
How long's that gonna set us back?
- There we go.
- Back.
Well, you want me to keep the beaver dam?
You're looking at a week.
If not, we can bust it up.
The beavers, they're not home.
I don't know. We're a green company, Frank.
I can make it look like an accident.
Oops. I accidentally left a stick of dynamite
inside the beaver dam.
I don't know. I don't want to rock the boat
before Mr. Lyman gets here.
So, tell you what. Why don't you work up
some numbers, get back to me?
Hey, while you're at it,
pull the boys off of number three
and get them started on the plumbing
on number five.
You heard the captain!
We're moving on to five!
- Really?
- Great.
Psst! Shoo!
Those are my blueberries.
Hear it coming
I know you feel it
We both got it
No need to steal it
Nature.
Don't mind much
Maybe not today
In your heart
Can't wish it all away
Fight for it
Careful what you say
- Homesick much?
- I'm working on it.
Whatever you want
We got it all!
Rise and shine, Tyler-iffic.
First day of school.
Yeah, yeah
Let's go home
What's that, fatty? You gonna cry?
Take it up to seven with an incline of five
on the double!
And no cheating!
Yeah, yeah, yeah
We got it all!
- Morning, honey.
- Morning, sweetie.
So, what's new in the world?
Well, crime rate's going up in Chicago.
See? That's another thing to be grateful for.
No crime here. Nothing but peace and quiet.
- That is temporary.
- Mmm-hmm.
Oh, Dan, wild turkeys. Wild turkeys.
Dan, stop. Hey.
You can't eat that in front of them.
Put it down. It could be their mom.
How do they know it's turkey bacon
and not bacon-bacon?
They have a sixth sense. Put it down.
Hey, honey. How'd you sleep?
Not good. I had this awful nightmare
that my insensitive parents uprooted me
from my wonderful home
and dumped me in the middle of nowhere.
He just misses his friends.
How can he miss his friends?
He spent the whole summer
cooped up in his room
talking to them online with his computer.
He knows the deal, all right?
We're here for a year,
and then we go back to Chicago.
Maybe you should talk to him.
What for?
That'll just irritate him more.
Dan, you're his dad. Try.
So, Tyler, care to join me outside
for some fresh mountain air?
Come on, Tyler, I bet there's probably
some really cute girls at your school.
And they really dig your hip city vibe.
Yeah. I bet you're right.
I bet there are some cute girls out there.
- There you go.
- You know what else there are?
Poisonous rattlesnakes!
Yeah, they're all over the forest.
I'm gonna end up like this guy.
All right, you win.
I'll quit my job, we pack up the car
and we go back to Chicago.
Would that make you happy?
Don't answer that question.
- No, no, no. Don't touch.
- What?
For my boss.
- All of them?
- Yeah, all 38 of them.
- I don't know what kind he likes.
- Seriously?
Hey, are we cool?
Yeah, never better.
Great.
Johanna drove slowly into the city
The Hudson River all filled with snow
She spied the ring on His Honor's finger
A thousand years in one piece of silver
She took it from his lily-white hand
Showed no fear
She'd seen the thing
In the young men's wing at Sloan-Kettering
Have a good one.
- Three months down.
- And nine to go.
Yeah.
Look outside
The raincoats coming, say "Oh"
$50,000 for the overage on a beaver dam?
You're sure the beavers aren't home?
All right, just take care of it.
Make it look like an accident.
I'll call you later, Frank.
Johanna drove slowly into the city
The Hudson River all filled with snow
She spied the ring on His Honor's finger
Mr. Lyman, welcome to Rocky Springs.
Hey, Dan.
Hope we didn't keep you waiting.
Just bought the plane yesterday
and wanted to see
how she handled warp factor two.
And this is for your son.
Oh, thank you. That's really very kind of you.
He's going on four, right?
No, actually, he's gonna be 16 next month.
- No.
- No, memo says four. You sure?
Yeah, I'm pretty sure.
Actually, no, the toy's...
- Excuse me?
- The toy is great and he's gonna love it.
- Isn't it crazy how time flies?
- Isn't it?
- I have two kids of my own.
- Three.
Three, and I remember when
- what's-his-name and...
- Tony.
...John and...
- Yoko Junior.
...were just babies.
- Memories.
- They're my kids.
So, I got the car here.
I brought some sandwiches
and it's about an hour to the site.
An hour? Both ways?
Two hours round-trip.
I don't think so.
Sandwiches? Gross.
Now just be sure to check
your curriculums carefully.
The board is very strict about
no child being left behind. Capisce?
Okay, first things first.
I'd like to give a warm welcome
to our brand new science teacher,
Tammy, from Chicago.
Now, as I'm sure many of you already know,
one of our math teachers, Mr. Bowen,
is out sick for the rest of the year,
so we find ourselves without a chairman
for the Forest Festival.
Either one of you volunteers,
or I say we just junk it.
But we've always had a Forest Festival.
The children love painting the pinecones
and playing "Mother May I?"
With Bessie the Cow.
Claire, Bessie the Cow
was put down in 1972.
That's nice. Nice.
Bessie the Cow, Bessie the Cow
Isn't tenure wonderful?
Will you ever retire?
Excuse me, I...
- That's so great! We have a volunteer.
- No, I...
Tammy Sanders is officially in charge
of the Forest Festival.
Yay, Tammy.
We're gonna have so much fun.
Bessie the Cow, Bessie the Cow
Bessie jumped over the moon
Oh, boy.
Click. Page down, page down, page down,
page down, page down. Page up.
As you can see from the photographs here,
we are 16% under budget.
Good, good.
Which I'm very pleased about,
because at this rate,
we are going to be completed
with the construction by March.
- Guaranteed.
- That's great.
Now you'll be ready for phase two.
Oh.
Sorry, what's phase two?
Show him the plans.
All right. You are in charge of phase one,
which is this right now.
- Right.
- And this is phase two.
So you're just gonna take out
the whole forest?
Yeah.
Mmm?
Huh?
But we're replacing it with a shopping mall
with a forest theme.
Dan, do you know why they call me
"The King of Green"?
Because I love this planet.
Unfortunately, I have to deal
with these eco-hypocrites.
They say they want to save
the planet, but only if it's convenient.
You ever notice that? They always drink
venti latte with recycled cups,
and all of a sudden
they're part of the solution?
What I need from you
isn't a commitment to green,
but a grasp of the shades of gray.
I understand.
Great. So you'll be heading up phase two
for the next four years.
Four years?
Sir, I relocated my family here for one year.
Yeah, that was until
Riggs disappeared on me.
My wife and my... My son are...
Oh, God.
Dan, this is a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity
for you.
I'll double your salary. Think about it.
You have 10 seconds
or I'm pulling the offer.
Ten,
nine-eight-seven-six-five-four
three-two-one!
All right, I'll do it.
You're doing the right thing, Dan.
Oh, no, you're crazy. What?
- Felder.
- Okay, big guy, this meeting's over.
Hold on for a second, Mom.
Just let me... What?
Bye-bye.
My wife is going to kill me.
Dan, we're a family, all right?
We make decisions together.
Look, it's not such a bad thing.
Think of it as a promotion.
Yeah. If anybody needs me,
I'll be at a friend's house.
Oh! Oh, wait, I don't have any friends here.
Look, guys,
this is an opportunity
to do something good for our family
and for the environment, too.
How is ripping out the forest
good for the environment?
It's not like that.
We're Lyman Enterprises.
We're the good guys. We're green.
Yeah, as in the color of money.
And speaking of money.
Who wants a new Wii? Huh?
Oh, come on.
Birds.
Hey.
You, go away.
Hey, guys, can we just take a look
at the sprinkler system?
No problem, Mr. Sanders.
Hi.
Check out Mr. Pee-Pee Pants.
Just had a little problem with a raccoon.
Well, that's funny.
He must have scampered off.
Hilarious.
Are you still mad at me?
What do you think?
Well, excuse me
for caring about the environment.
Hello, jefe.
The beaver dam problem is gone. Yes. Yes!
Oh. Blowing up beavers, are we?
They weren't home.
Well, that was eco-friendly of you.
- Let go
- Give in
- Give up
- Surrender
- Let go
- Give in
- Give up
- Surrender
Hello, sir.
Dan, Neil Lyman.
Listen, our plane got in early.
I was thinking about scouting the site.
Oh, jeez!
How's everything on your end?
Hot! Hot!
Oh, come on!
Okay, little buddy, come on, move along.
Move it!
All right.
Hey!
Come on, shoo. Beat it.
Go on, beat it. Scat. Go.
I'm late for work.
Thank you.
Come on!
All right, what is your...
Rabies!
You wanna play games?
Let's play games.
All right. You asked for it.
I'll do it. Don't think I won't.
Mr. Lyman.
Dan, if this is some kind of stall tactic,
I'm not finding it very clever.
That's because there's a very good reason...
Miley Cyrus!
Seriously?
Please.
Come on, please, one. Just one bar.
Two bar, three bar. Good.
Mr. Lyman, it's Dan Sanders.
Sanders,
do you like working for me?
Yes, sir. I'm just...
I'll call you back!
I'm stuck on this plane,
and I'm very hungry.
I want a veggie burrito,
hold the guacamole, no cilantro.
I repeat... Are you taking this down?
All right, well, clearly,
something went wrong,
because his office called
and said he never made the meeting.
Maybe he ran into an old friend
or an old flame.
Thank you, Frank.
Keep your hands
away from the vehicle.
Do not freak out. Stand down.
Hi, Mrs. Sanders. My name is Wilson.
I run security for Lyman.
I protect his assets, if you will.
I'm here because I got a 425 call
over my walkie-talkie.
What's a 425?
A four...
Ow!
You know, now is not a good time
to field questions from civilians.
- This your husband's car?
- Yes, we both know that. Is he okay?
You tell me.
I tell you?
Yeah, we found his car and his phone
abandoned 2.7 clicks
into the Meriweather Pass.
Well, did you notify the police
about my husband?
I think
we both don't want to call the police.
You tell them and the next thing you know,
you'll have 60 Minutes up here
trying to sensationalize the murder.
- Murder?
- What murder?
- You said "murder. "
- There something you want to tell me
about the murder?
Dad got murdered?
Come here, Skippy.
We're gonna find old Daddy,
whether he's in one piece
or lots of little tiny chopped up ones.
- What?
- In the meantime,
how would you like to be my deputy? Huh?
Look at him.
Yeah, a hat.
- Dan. Dan!
- Huh?
What happened?
I was so worried about you.
- What happened?
- Well, there was a ravine and a boulder,
and then this maniacal raccoon,
and then I lost my phone.
Oh.
I'm gonna borrow your charger.
I have to call Lyman.
What happened? Wait, honey, what...
- Dan? What...
- Mr. Lyman, it's Dan Sanders. Listen...
Well, that was touching.
Well, well, well. I guess you're off the hook.
Excuse me?
Dismissed.
Just don't leave town.
I got eagle eyes, Amazon woman.
Yeah. Don't freak out.
Come on.
Freak.
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Tomorrow.
Absolutely. That's right.
I know. Uh-huh.
Great.
Yes, sir. Yes, sir, we will be ready
for Mr. Gupta and the Indian investors.
I see.
Yes, sir. I know. All right.
Have a good night.
Was it something I said?
Tammy, can I come in?
It's your house.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have called Lyman first.
I don't know what I was thinking.
Do you have any idea
how worried I was about you?
I'm sorry. I wasn't thinking.
It's just, I figured that
if I can keep Lyman happy,
then I can give you and Tyler the world.
Dan, we don't want the world.
We just want you.
I get it. So, if anyone needs me,
I'll be on the couch.
You don't have to sleep on the couch.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Wow, that's a lot of work for third graders.
I got roped into being in charge
of the local Forest Festival.
Cool.
I would tell you more, but you are
in desperate need of a shower.
I'm on it. Watch this.
I'm married to a lunatic.
Shut it.
Lady Gaga!
What the... Hey.
Shut up! Go be a pecker somewhere else!
Go on, get out of here.
Dan?
Good riddance.
Who are you talking to?
This crow.
What crow?
The one that flew away.
Is that all my Forest Festival stuff
on the lawn?
No.
Yes.
I'll go get it.
Ow!
I'm all over it. Just go back to bed.
Darn it!
Stupid crow.
I get up in eight hours.
Shut up!
Oops.
Idiot.
You got to be kidding me.
I don't care. It doesn't bother me.
Nope.
It's on!
Oh.
Hi, there, cutie pie.
Who's the pretty birdie?
Oh, you are, aren't you?
You make pretty sounds.
That's a nice little song you're singing.
Do you know any more?
I wonder what it would sound like
with your beak wrapped in duct tape.
Mom,
found him.
Honey, come on,
there's nothing wrong with me.
I'm telling you, I'm fine.
Dan, chasing crows onto rooftops
is not what I would consider "fine. "
What, exactly, are you talking about?
Tyler, Mommy and Daddy need to talk.
Right, 'cause the car
has soundproof windows.
Come here.
All I am saying is
I think you should take a day off
and consult a professional.
You're obviously going through something.
I can't do that. I can't afford to miss
another meeting with Lyman.
The guy's flying hundreds of miles
out of his way just to see me.
Mr. Eco-Developer is flying
hundreds of miles out of his way
in a private jet in order to have a meeting
about eco-development?
Right.
Hey, that's funny.
Look, honey, just 'cause a crow
kept me up all night's
no reason to throw in the towel.
It's gonna take a lot more than that to keep
Dan Sanders from building his utopia.
Nature. Nature, nature, nature.
Okay, Private, on my count,
we're gonna charge up that ridge
and shoot some commies.
Take it up to eleven!
Three, two, one.
It's fun!
Don't bring me down
You're looking good
just like a snake in the grass
One of these days
you're gonna break your glass
Don't bring me down
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no
I'll tell you once more
before I get off the floor
Don't bring me down
Hello.
- Hi, Frank.
- Mr. Sanders,
I am happy to report that everything
will be ready for the investors.
Hey, can you have the guys go take a look
at the electrical in the basement?
'Cause something shorted out
and it could have killed me.
That's no good.
I will have my boys right on that, okay?
- You do that.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- What's wrong?
- Well, to tell you the truth,
ever since I took this promotion,
it's just been one long string of bad luck.
No, no, no.
You know the great Ralph Waldo Emerson?
You know what he said?
He said, "Shallow men believe in luck. "
Okay?
"Brave men believe in cause and effect. "
That's profound.
- Yes, mister. Okay.
- Okay.
P.U.
- Sanders, you okay?
- Oh, my God, he's dead!
- Come on. Hold on.
- Move, move, move.
It's all locked.
- Open the door.
- Here we go.
You all right?
- Help me!
- Captain, you all right, buddy?
- It's Frank.
- Unlock the door.
Captain.
Easy.
Mr. Sanders,
what did you have for breakfast?
Get the hose. Get the hose, please.
Gross.
Towel. Towel.
Towel.
Holy smoke.
Oh, no. Oh, my God. I'm sorry. I'm gonna...
This isn't what you think. You got to...
Where the heck are my clothes?
No one will see me, get in the car,
get some clothes, everything will be fine.
Get in the car, clothes, fine.
Car, clothes, fine.
Hello! Right behind you.
Oh, jeez, he's at it again.
I had it detailed and it's very, very clean.
Hey, guys. Good work on number three.
Anybody see the game?
Nice fit, pound cake.
Get to the store, get a new suit,
get to Lyman.
Frank, he did it again.
Not again. Mr. Sanders, why? Why?
Then we take the pinecone and...
We take the pinecone and...
Oh! No, I remember. I remember now.
We take the pinecones and...
And we...
Oh! Now I have it.
We take the pinecones...
I'm sorry if this seems impersonal, sir,
but I'd better stay outside the aircraft,
because the German measles
are going around my kid's school.
We can't get a shot anywhere.
Yo, Petey. What up, brother?
No, no, no, dude. I am in hell here, bro.
No, seriously, I feel like I'm stuck
in the Discovery Channel.
- Excuse me.
- No, I don't get how people with half a brain
- could live in this town.
- Excuse me.
I don't even think
they've heard of Starbucks, man.
Excuse me.
Like, come on, where can a brother
get some coffee?
Excuse me.
- Seriously, it's ridiculous.
- Hey!
Hello.
Can I help you find something?
Find something?
I am the student librarian.
I help people find books.
I love books. Stupid.
Okay, you wanna narrow that down
for me, Sanders?
Wait, how do you know my name?
Oh. I know all about you and your dad.
He's the developer, right?
Yeah, that's us.
The tree killer.
That's us.
Mmm-hmm.
I'm Tyler.
Total cheeseball.
Amber. You're funny.
Not to mention extremely sophisticated.
Got any plans for dinner?
Okay.
Dan,
the Indians will be here in 10 days.
We need to show what a truly special place
Rocky Springs is.
Thinking caps, thinking caps
I got it. We could have
an Indian-themed barbecue.
What does that even mean?
Lots of things. It could mean...
Oh! Instead of burgers,
we have buffalo burger!
And we have wigwam, and teepee
and squaw.
Squaw.
You were talking about
the Gandhi type of Indians.
Uh-huh.
Wait, wait, we could sponsor
the local Forest Festival.
Forest Festival? That's a great idea!
Well, you see, my wife is running it.
- And they're strapped for cash.
- You're dead to me.
It's a great way to show the community
how much we care.
Gold star, Dan.
I'll call the publicist and the media.
Yes! Excellent, sir.
Why are you shouting at me?
No, sir, I'm not shouting at you.
Okay, fine, but use your inside voice.
Leave me alone!
What is his problem?
Hey! Polly want a cracker?
Polly want a cracker?
Did we not vet him?
Did we do a mental status exam on him?
Mr. Lyman?
Are you still there, sir?
Yes, I'm still here! All right?
Where's your brain?
Sir, it's just... I'm very sorry...
Oh, dear.
I won't take up any more of your time,
so I'll tell you what,
I'll pick up a budget and a proposal
and then I'll give it to you tomorrow
after I huddle up with her on it.
Great! Bye!
Bees!
Honey, I'm home,
and I am the bearer of some good news.
Guess who met a friend today,
and guess who's having dinner at...
Oh, honey, what happened to your face, Dan?
And why are you wearing
my Yum Yum sweats?
I had a really long day.
Gonna find you anyway...
You shoddy little...
You're not fooling anyone.
Let me guess. The crow?
I found your clothes in the garbage,
- so I put them in the wash.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
I also made an appointment for you
with a Dr. Burr. He's a local therapist.
Tammy, I'm fine.
All I need is a good night's sleep.
All right, fine, I'll cancel,
but one more episode and you're going.
This should help you sleep,
however. Okay?
- What is it?
- I got it from a fellow teacher at work.
"Mrs. Martin's
Mushroom herbal sleepy-bye tea. "
Mmm-hmm. Give it a try.
Mmm.
Okay.
Tammy.
Tammy. Tammy.
I think there's somebody downstairs.
Find a spot out on the floor
Ah, freak out!
Le freak, c'est chic
Freak out!
How did you get in here?
Get out of my house!
Tammy, wake up.
I just had the worst nightmare.
No banging until 7:00.
Oh, no.
Okay, if you don't wanna go in there,
go over there.
Dan,
what are you doing?
Oh. Defending my home.
Okay, you need to try to explain to me
what you're talking about.
Okay.
But you got to promise me,
no matter how crazy this sounds,
that you'll believe me.
I promise.
Okay, here goes.
The animals are out to get me.
And what animal
are we talking about, Dan?
That's the thing.
There's more than one of them.
There's like this whole posse of them.
I think they're in cahoots.
Cahoots?
See, you got the skunk.
He's silent but deadly.
Then you got a crow.
Master of psychological warfare.
Then there's the brains of the operation,
the raccoon.
Now if I take him out,
the whole thing falls apart. Game over.
Well, you've done
your homework, certainly.
- I just have one question.
- What?
Are you taking crazy pills?
- You promised.
- I take it back.
- Tyler, man the switch.
- No, thanks.
Operation Rodent Retreat
in five, four, three, two, one!
Oh.
Tammy?
New Day Medical.
I'm sorry, he's in a session right now.
Now, I'd like to begin with some ink blots.
Tell me what you see here.
First thing that comes to mind.
Look, I know I'm not supposed to say
it looks like an angry squirrel,
but that looks like an angry squirrel.
Oh, boy.
What about this?
An owl. An angry owl.
Is this supposed to be helping?
All right, Dan,
how long have you been afraid of animals?
I'm not afraid of animals.
Dan, Dan, Dan,
denial is not just a river in Egypt.
Now, I want you to listen very carefully
to what I'm gonna say to you.
The animals are not out to get you.
I know the animals are not out to get me.
- You do?
- Yes, except for these three.
This one does all the talking.
These ones follow his orders.
Jesus.
Dan, you're suffering
from work-related stress
and we need to find your happy place.
Now, we'll start by closing your eyes
and taking a deep breath.
And now another deep breath.
In and out.
In
and out.
How do you feel?
I feel great.
And you're not seeing things anymore,
are you?
No, and...
Dan?
Are you okay?
Is something out there bothering you?
Is it the animals?
Because you and I both know that
there's nothing outside that window, right?
Dan?
Hey, stop! That's my hybrid! Hey!
Stop, stop, stop! Come here, you!
I knew it. This is my car.
Get out of my car.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
No, don't touch that... Don't...
I'm going to crush you!
Thank you, sir, may I have another?
I love it.
Get off.
Uh-oh.
Why are you doing this to me?
What did I ever do to you?
I don't have a problem with animals,
even when they bite.
I like animals. Where are we going? Wait!
Ooh. That just hit the ball boy.
- Okay, what do I do?
- Okay. So, angle it up. There you go.
- Okay.
- There we go.
- And spike it! Nice.
- Yeah.
- You know, we could always play
- on an actual tennis court.
- Yeah, but where's the fun in that?
Amber, how long have you lived up here?
I was born here, Mrs. Sanders.
Oh, really?
I love it here.
- Yeah, right.
- Mrs. Sanders.
Now what?
Dan?
Therapy went well.
What happened?
If you really need to know,
I got carjacked by a raccoon and a skunk.
You must be Amber.
Yeah.
It's nice to meet you. If you'll excuse me,
I need to remove a leech
from my no-no zone.
Oh, my God.
Bye-bye.
Dan.
I'm telling you,
these animals are out to get me.
I don't know why you won't believe me.
Because it's not possible.
Raccoons do not carjack SUVs.
Well, this one did, and I will prove it to you.
- Hey, Tyler.
- Hey, Dad.
Are you okay?
I think we both know
that I'm way beyond okay.
See, I got these Indian investors
coming to town,
and there's a maniacal sociopathic raccoon
that's been ruining my life,
but no one seems to believe that it exists.
For whatever it's worth,
I don't think you're crazy.
Amber gave me this book on local folklore.
Mmm-hmm.
I think there's something you should see.
Look, you're not the first person
to ever try and settle Rocky Springs.
This area was first settled
by Tookoo the Caveman in 9,000 BC.
Tookoo disappeared without a trace,
and many others in history
have tried and failed.
There was Sigurd the Viking.
Jedediah the Puritan.
We are all God's children
And there was Terrance the Hippie.
Hey, little fella.
Where are you going with this?
Look, I did a bunch of research, okay?
It seems like your buddy, Lyman,
has pretty deep pockets in Washington.
He got them to rezone what was supposed
to be a preserved forest.
No, I don't know.
I'm sure that's not the case.
It is, okay?
You're building on a nature preserve
and frankly, it's ticking nature off.
Are you telling me that
the animals are trying to get me
to stop developing Rocky Springs?
No, I think they're past that.
I think the animals are out for revenge.
Beasty biting thing!
Got you.
I knew your luck would run out.
It's a setup.
Oh, there you are.
Hi, little fella. This is a cute trick. Yeah.
It's supposed to be you?
My turn now.
You're his friend.
No, no, no.
No, no, no! No!
Go steal a picnic basket!
No!
Frank, have you seen my husband
this morning?
I'm sorry, Mrs. Sanders,
I have not seen him.
Have you seen my toilet?
I just don't think this can get any worse.
Don't freak out. Don't freak out.
- I stand corrected.
- Nobody move.
Well...
Well, well, well, well.
Mrs. Sanders.
You have no idea
where your husband is, do you?
Guilty as charged.
You know, I'm getting a little tired
of your dumb-dumb show
and your poppycocks and your jiggery...
- I don't want you to speak anymore.
- Don't do that.
- I found him.
- Dan.
Oh.
Where?
- You have got to be kidding me.
- Hello?
Dan? Dan, honey, are you in there?
Does anyone have some Purell?
Don't worry, Mr. Sanders,
we'll have you down in no time.
Sooner than you think.
Come on.
You might wanna cover your eyes.
Get the hose.
- Tammy?
- Fire!
- Are you okay, boss?
- Yeah, yeah, real good.
Nothing like a cold shower
to wake you up in the morning.
So you guys are making
really good progress on unit three,
and I was thinking about laying
some pipe right about...
You are mine.
Dan.
This ends now.
I don't know where he thinks he's going
without my keys,
Unless I left them in the car.
Let's end this now.
Ready,
aim,
aim again.
I can't do it. I'm not a killer.
Come on, can't we just figure this out?
I was trying to make this work, and you...
Now, you look here! I've got...
Bull's eye.
Lucky for you, I got LoJack.
Is it dead?
No, just shot him with my tankalizer gun.
He's just taking a tankalizer-gun nap.
How many more of these things
have you got?
I got a whole warehouse
stocked down in Harrison. Why?
What are you thinking?
I'm thinking about
cleaning house.
Tree skunk.
They live in the hollers.
It's a beautiful morning
Bring them in, boys!
Put those possums on the top.
- All right.
- Yeah.
And watch out for them ferrets.
No sense in staying inside
If the weather's fine
and you got the time
It's your chance to wake up
and plan another brand new day
Either way
It's a beautiful morning
Stack them high, boys.
Stack them high. Hey!
Not so tough, are we now, Mr. Tom Turkey?
- Morning, Mr. Sanders.
- Morning, guys.
Not a raccoon in sight.
It just ain't no good if the sun shines
When you're still inside
- Shouldn't hide
- Still inside
You know, with our animals locked up
and under control,
I think we could speed up phase two
by several months.
That would be correct.
- Mind if I join you?
- Please. Do sit down.
Thank you. So, Dan said you wanted
to go over a few of the festival details.
Well, first of all, Tammy,
I mean, you've done a fantastic job.
Thank you.
I just have a few tweaks.
Tweaks, tweaks.
Our current plans for the festival,
well, they're depressing.
Huh?
And this whole thing about pollution
and the trees.
Please. If my Indian investors
wanna be reminded about pollution,
they'll stay home in Calcutta.
Stink-o.
Well, what do you want me to do?
Get eco-go-go dancers?
Great idea. Jot that down.
Write this down.
Hey, Mom, you owe me 25 bucks.
Yeah, ma, 25 bucks. Stupid!
Wait up. Wait. Stop. Stop.
You holding up?
You kidding? I love cross-country running.
Well, come on, we only got 10 more miles.
Awesome.
Hey, so, how's your dad? He feeling better?
Much. Yeah, I really think
he's turned a corner.
Look, I know you see him as
Mr. Evil-Let's-Develop-The-Ozone
And-Destroy-The-Rain-Forest guy,
but he really means well.
Look, I don't think your dad's a bad guy.
I just don't like what they're doing.
Well, they are sponsoring the festival.
That has to count for something.
Well, yeah.
Amber, is everything okay?
Yeah, you know,
I was just thinking about midterms,
my allowance, when you were gonna
get up the guts to kiss me.
Is everything okay?
Hello?
- I knew it.
- No, no, This has to be a mistake.
Really? 'Cause it makes
perfect sense to me.
God, the things people do for a dollar.
- Amber, wait up.
- Just leave me alone.
Don't lump me in with my dad.
Kind of hard not to.
Thanks, Dad.
- Keep it straight. Easy.
- Okay, I am.
Good job with the Moon Bounce,
guys. Put the Ferris wheel over here.
Yeah, I got it. I got it.
Just give me a minute, okay?
Dan, we've got to do something.
Your boss is ruining the whole festival.
Tammy, it's not that bad.
Yeah, it is. It's going against everything
it's meant to be.
It's a disaster. It's embarrassing.
Calm down, will you? What do you
want me to do, Tammy? He's my boss.
- So, were you ever gonna tell me?
- Tell you what?
About your four-legged prison.
Oh.
It's not what you think it is, all right?
It's just for a couple of days
until the investors leave and then...
Then what?
Well, we let the animals free
and everything's fine,
and you know what?
They're probably a little bit better off
right now because they're safe.
Wow!
You are so blind to the facts.
You work for a green company
and you're signing orders
to cage little animals.
You're such a hypocrite.
- Hey, Tyler.
- No, Mom.
Wait a minute.
What, I'm the bad guy?
Oh, come on. No.
Well, I hope it was worth it.
You know, my family
has completely turned against me.
Why me? What did I ever do to you?
Great, I'm trying to get sympathy
from a raccoon. Like you'd understand.
Found your kids.
You have a family.
All this time,
you were protecting them from me.
Hold still, Beatrice.
There!
Way to go, Cooper!
Pickle hit!
Come on, come on.
Stinky loves pickles!
Once we break ground on phase two,
Dan here will be able to build
a dozen residential areas,
which will all be gated communities.
All right, be strong.
Stop developments in Rocky Springs!
Keep our forest green!
Sign the petition.
Stop development in Rocky Springs.
Hi, Mr. Houston.
You, take one. It's really important.
Amber! Amber!
What?
What are you doing?
Gandhi said to be the change
that you want to see in the world.
Well, did Gandhi ever talk about
you not returning my phone calls
or my text messages?
Well, excuse me, I've been a little busy
trying to stop your dad.
You know what? If you're gonna
do something, then do it right.
Tyler. Tyler.
Stop the development of Rocky Springs!
Sign our petition and keep our forest green!
Show-off.
Now if we use solar energy,
we can raise rental prices
at least 10% over market value
while generating free publicity
for being economically conscious.
Speaking of economically conscious,
Dan's wife, and our festival coordinator,
Tammy Sanders.
- Tammy.
- Thank you. I'm proud.
The first Forest Festival
that has nothing to do with the forest.
That's not true.
Dad!
Oh, and this is Dan's son, Tyler.
How's it going, kids?
Yeah, we're trying to stop the reckless
development of the forest
by Lyman Enterprises.
Funny. Kids these days.
Tyler, I know you must be
very angry with me right now...
- Look, this has nothing to do with you, Dad.
- The animals are gonna be killed.
Killed? No.
There must be
some sort of communication breakdown.
Lyman Industries, we don't kill animals.
We're just going to relocate them.
Yeah, but that's just the same
as killing them.
I mean, you can't just relocate animals.
Enough.
I've heard all I need to hear.
Lyman, you got a deal.
- What?
What about the animals?
Less animals, less hassle.
- Let's get rid of them.
- What?
Great, I'll call business affairs.
We'll get the contracts here.
Do you have a fax machine, something?
- So now we're killing animals?
- Hey, I...
Congratulations. Well done, Dad.
Wait. I thought that relocating the animals
wouldn't be a problem...
I'm gonna go take care of our son.
- Where are you going?
- There's something I've got to do.
I'll do what I can to create a diversion,
so what I want you to do
is get your families and get out of here.
All right? Good luck.
Darling, over here! Look at the
camera. Darling. Say cheese, darling.
Come on. Come on, honey.
Come on, look over here.
Show me your punim, honey.
That's a very large owl.
All right! All right, freeze!
Oh. Oh, there's a lot of you.
Don't freak out.
Freaking out!
How about a hand for the band,
ladies and...
Friends and...
It's broken. It's broken.
Hayseed.
Friends and neighbors,
my name is Neil Lyman,
and on behalf of Lyman Enterprises,
it has been a privilege
to be a part of your little community.
Today... Thank you. Thank you.
Today marks a new beginning
for this little town of yours.
Some have called it backwater.
- Some have called it irrelevant.
- Irrelevant?
Two-teeth maximum.
But I see your little corner of nature
for what it could be,
a center for a new suburbia.
Thank you.
With me today is a great man
who will change your little world.
So, without further ado...
Stop the development of Rocky Springs.
My son, Tyler, here,
he was right.
You were right.
This man's a fraud.
He's not eco-friendly.
He's not even friendly.
All right.
That's a little below the belt, okay?
I forced my family to move here.
I said it was for the fresh air,
for them to have a better life.
I was just trying to further my career.
I came here because I thought
that I was building a community,
but the truth is
I was just stealing one.
- I'm sorry.
- Thank you.
I'm sorry.
Sorry about this. Security. Security, please.
Okay, what if I told you people
I was about to pour in
$100 million into the local economy?
Who's friendly now, huh?
Who's friendly now?
- Don't listen to him.
- Mr. Sanders.
Okay, folks. All right, nothing to see here.
Let's not let a few rotten apples
spoil a great time, all right?
So, Mr. Gupta,
if you will kindly take my pen.
Drum roll, please.
Is that all you got?
Shoo! Shoo! Shoo!
- Okay. Sign, sir.
- I'm not signing this.
Do it.
- No.
- Do it.
- I don't want to do it.
- I don't care!
- Fine.
- Good.
Okay.
Drum roll, please.
Now what?
Purkles.
Look!
It is raccoon.
- Sweet pea.
- You complete me!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
My contract!
- Now do you believe me?
- I will never doubt you again!
I remember our first Forest Festival.
Amber! Amber!
Get off. Move. Get off!
I got the key.
- Look, Brad Pitt.
- Where?
I got it!
So I started this business, oh, years ago,
way, way back when you were just an egg.
Tammy!
Goodbye, raccoon.
It was an accident. Oh, my God!
The deal is...
No, it's not off! No!
We're good.
It's right here, right here.
"Mr. Gupta. " Good, good, good, good.
Good enough.
Deal! Sweet dreams.
This is not what you think.
Hey!
Dan, I'll be right back.
Bruce Lee from the grave.
So long, suckers.
You ain't so bad. You ain't so tough.
There's a bear driving a golf cart.
Doing a good job, too.
Put that tail down.
That's gross.
Can I just say that I'm really sorry?
I got my priorities completely out of order,
and I love you, Tyler.
Dad. Dad, not cool, okay?
Tyler, tell your father that you love him.
- What?
- Do it.
- Do it. Do it. Do it now.
- Tyler.
Tell him.
Tyler.
- I love you, Dad.
- Come on, say it.
Hmm?
- I love you, too, Dad.
- Oh, you do.
- I love you, too.
- I love you.
Hey, your parents are right there.
Are we gonna be all right?
We're gonna be just fine.
Now, this is a pinecone,
and I'm painting it for Christmas.
So you can hang it on your door,
in case you ever have a door.
Who you trying to get crazy with, ese?
Don't you know I'm loco?
To the one on the flamboyant tip
I'll just toss that ham in the fryin' pan
like spam
It's done when I come and slam
Yeah, let me tell you who I am
Don't make me spell it
Watch me get reckless
Burning up the track like I was electric
Damn, the lights are blinkin', I'm thinkin'
It's all over when
your brain starts shrinkin'
Oh, makin' my mind slow
But I can't stop when my body says go
Bro, I gotta maintain
'Cause a freak like me is goin' insane
Insane in da membrane
Insane in da brain
Going insane
Got no brain!
Insane in da membrane
Insane in da brain
You know I rhyme like no other
Now it's time for the blubber
Blabber, watch that belly get fatter
Fat boy on a diet, don't try it
Steppin' to me is like steppin' to a giant
Much too fast like a sumo
Hitting that mat
Leaving your face in the grass
You know, I don't take this thing lightly
Punks just jealous
'cause they can't outwrite me
So kick that style, wicked, wild
Happy face clown never seen me smile
Rip dat mainframe, I'll explain
A freak like me is goin' insane
Insane in da membrane
Insane in da brain
Going insane, got no brain
Insane in da membrane
Insane in da brain
Going insane, got no brain
Insane in da membrane
Insane in da brain
Don't freak out. Don't freak out.