I make it as rich.
Oh, hey, a guy here.
You communicate with me.
Hey Neal, I just know.
How To was?
It is the ordinary!
If once you cut the forest boy,
have time on this, I tell you.
¿Sanders?, Oh, no.
I can say that it will do
well, but play tomorrow
let him know that I will be
overseeing the operation.
Alo Mr. Lyman. Alo.
Take that, do not
lose, whatever.
Oh, ¿Qué is this?
Stripping out of my way.
You have to calm small. Run.
That was amazing.
Do not put that ...
Very funny, poor raccoon.
Evil, evil raccoon.
Mr. Lyman, quit!
Nature.
Look people, my captain
has awakened.
Good morning Greg.
- Let's see if they made the reprogramming.
- There's nothing like having
the chief legal officer.
I have a question, you have the answer.
It's like I get the idea.
This in months have
been a disaster.
You see that gate is not good.
I do not know if I can say
the same for that tree.
It's what people do, is good,
helps with things.
I do not like.
Good for you to stay with
this view and say it.
If not we just be done
and then home.
I do not know if you are worried
or agree in this regard,
Well.
I can make it look like an accident.
I expect this to happen
accidentally.
I do not know.
The rocks are hard to get
here so take your time.
I want you to work on that and come back to me.
Hey I love the guys in the # 3.
I guess it must be
around the park.
They heard the captain!
Build quickly.
zIn serious?
Those are my berries.
MODEL HOUSE
Sure.
- Still sleeping.
- I was awake.
It's time. Bring your tools.
Tyler misses his old life.
¿Qué say? Do you want to thank?
Come and get the largest double.
And do not give up.
- Hello Tammy.
- Good morning sweetness.
- Not the world.
- Well I have seen something
in Chicago.
The fabulous time that was earlier.
We have a great time here.
Peace and tranquility.
And some builders.
Wild turkeys.
Dan, let's not fret you can eat
it in them, because that's bad.
How To may be turkey
is cooked bacon?
They have a sixth
sense that low.
Hey baby. How To sleep?
Nothing good, I had a nasty nightmare
that my parents took me
wonderful home and put her
in the middle of nowhere.
- He just has fun.
- How To may be having fun
if you have spent all summer in her room
talking on the internet on your PC.
He knows everything, we will be here for
a year and then return to Chicago.
- You must talk to him.
- That's just irritate it more.
Dan, you're his dad, try.
Tyler, Do you want to join
me for a walk outside?
Tyler We want the girls to
see how strong you are.
They will believe you're
a city dweller.
- I did today, there are beautiful girls out there.
- There it is.
¿Sabes with which we began?
Poisonous Snakes.
They're all over the forest.
How To him be gone this guy?
Okay, you win, I will resign my job,
packed up and returned to Chicago.
¿Eso would make you happy?
But it's not a question.
- No, do not touch.
- Why?
- It's for my boss.
- ¯Todas?
If I will try them all, do
not know what you like.
zIn serious?
- ¯Hey we agree?
- Yeah, never better.
Well.
Get a good one.
- And you will.
- He.
80 000 dollars for it.
Are you sure that is?
All right, just, take care of that, you have
to look like an accident, I'll call Frank.
Mr. Lyman. Welcome
to RockySpring.
Hey Dan.
Do not keep waiting, I bought the plane yesterday
and I see the work of the factory as well.
And this for your child.
Oh thanks Mr.
Lyman is very kind of you.
FEZ will be 4 right?
No, actually turn 16 next month.
April says here you sure?
If I'm very sure.
Actually ...
The toy is great, I love it.
- Is not it crazy all this
- very crazy.
- I have two children.
- 3.
3 and can not remember their names which are y.
..
- John.
- If Junior.
They're just babies.
- They are rich.
- Can not be.
Well, I brought the car brought
some beer and sandwiches
and them as they please.
Now, in both how long it takes.
They arrived two hours later.
I think not.
¿Sanguches? Very bad.
Now just make sure to review
their actions carefully.
I'm very strict about no
children in my back.
¿Entienden? Ok.
Prmero Prmero what I would like to
warmly welcome our new teacher.
Tammy of Chicago.
I'm sure you all know that
one of our teachers
Mr. Valwin math is sick for
the rest of the year.
Then we had to find a chamberlain
for the festival.
I want the volunteers
to rise faster ...
They have always done this, children do not
paint something or play with Betty the cow.
- This game dates back to 1972.
- It's nice.
Lindo.
Betty the cow, the cow Betty.
It is wonderful, ¿Por
what ever you retire?
- Sorry, I ...
- I'm glad we have a volunteer.
- No.
- Tammy Sanders, is in
charge of Festibal.
- Hey Tammy.
- We are both going to have fun.
Betty the cow, the cow Betty.
Bety jump there.
Click, lower page, page down,
page down, page down, ok now.
As you can see photos here we
are at 16% of the project.
Well, well.
What is very good.
We have completed construction
guaranteed.
It's fabulous, and it's
great that front.
- FEZ rest?
- Show the plans.
Well you re in charge of
Phase 1, which is this.
And this is the phase 2.
- ZUD. will remove all the wood?
- Yes.
But replace that store
for the better.
You know who is the king of this.
Because I love it.
Unfortunately we have to deal with
this, but only this inconvenience.
Who invent this with something psychological
is part of the solution
but I need someone with
a commitment to this.
Requirement, all that.
- I understand.
- Fabulous!
There will be a place for
you in the next 4 years.
Z4 years?, Mr.
I have relocated my
family for 1 year.
- That's something I do not like.
- My wife and my son ...
- Oh, God.
- This is an op
ortunity for you.
Do not leave your salary,
you have worth.
- In 10 seconds the bid just 10, 9, 876 543 ...
- Ok.
I will.
Dan is right.
You're crazy, ¿Qué?
Done.
Ok, big boy, it's time to leave.
That per second that?
Adios.
My wife will kill me.
Ok we were a family, we make
decisions together.
Look, this is a bad thing, but
think of the promotion.
Oh, and if anyone needs me
I'll be with my friends.
Oh, wait, I have no friend here.
Look, guys this is an opportunity to
do something good for the family.
And for the environment as well.
How To might cut the entire forest
is good for the environment?
Not so, we live here, we're
the good guys, we will.
- Yes, it is the color of money.
- Speaking of money.
¿Quién want a new Wii?
Oh, come on.
Birds.
You, go away.
Hey Guy, ¿Puedes come to see
your irrigation system?
No problem Dan.
Hello.
Look daddy is pissed.
I just had a little problem
with the raccoon.
That's funny, and escaped.
- Ilarante.
- ¯Sigues upset with me?
- ¯Qué what you think?
- Well excuse me for caring
about the environment.
I got out, I did thousands of pieces.
Yes, Yes
- Oh, now fly the beavers.
- It is the house.
That's a friend of yours.
Hello Mr.
I'm Dan Lyman.
Listen, I miss our colleague
and thought to call you.
Oh, Jesus!
¿Todo right?
Come on.
Ok, little buddy, let's move on.
Move!
Come on, grain, salt.
Let go, go!
I get late for work.
Thank you.
Go!
Okay, ¿Cuál is your problem?
Do you want to play?
Let's play.
Very good. Thou quicisite.
What I do, I already won.
- Mr. Lyman.
- Dan, Zest is a kind of joke?
- I hate jokes.
- There is good reason.
God!
3 losses.
PENDING
Come on.
- Mr. Lyman, I'm Dan Sanders.
- ¯Hey, you'll work for me?
Yes, but I ...
I'm sick of this place and
I have very hungry.
I'm going to cook, no matter if
you go, I want mo problems ..
Clearly something is wrong, because they
say it never arrived at its meeting.
Maybe he met an old friend
or an old friend.
Thank you.
... And bring the South
African Sanders!
I'm Sergeant Wilson.
I Lyman safety
because it is the will.
I'm here because I have a
425 call about my order.
- ¯Qué is a 425?
- A book.
Ms. now is not a good
time to civilians.
- ¯Ese is your car?
- Both know that, Zel is fine?
- Well you tell me.
- ¯Yo I say?
If we find this car abandoned
2.7 kilometers of forest.
¿Sabe if I should call the
police about my husband?
I think we both know you do not
want to call the police.
He says that and the next
16 minutes here.
Treating the feeling of
lying in a murder.
- ¯Asesinato?
- ¯Qué murder?
- You said murder.
- Did not want to tell
me about the murder?
ZES murder?
Come here, go friend.
There is a mountain that lies
ahead, climbing and hunting.
In the meantime because
you're not my charger.
- Look you have.
- Go is a cap.
Dan.
I was so worried about you.
- Oh, Two, ¿Qué happened?
- There was a Abichuela and
then left the raccoon,
And then I lost my
cell phone ...
I'm going to call someone.
¿Qué happened, Carian, waiting?
That was touching.
- Okay. well, I guess you missed.
- Sorry.
Dame.
Is a small town and I have
eagle eyes in you
Yes, do not panic
Tomorrow. ... Absolutely it is.
I know.
Fabulous.
We must be ready for cooking.
I see, Mr.
I know it very well.
Have good night.
¿Fué something I said?
- ¯Tammy I can pass
- No thanks.
Sorry.
I should call you first, I do not know
which were being kept thinking.
I must wash any idea
how worried I was?
Sorry, I was thinking.
It's just that I thought if I keep them
happy I could give you the world.
Dan, we do not want the
world, we want to you.
I understand, so if you need
me I'll be in the cabinet.
- You have to sleep on the furniture.
- Thank you.
I'm busy seeing who is
overseeing the forest.
Well.
I would say more but desperately
need a shower.
Working on it.
Very cute.
That is all.
¿Qué hell ... Hey.
Stop doing this.
Well run.
- ¯Con Who are you talking about?
- There was a crow.
- ¯Cuál crow?
- I blew.
That's all my work on
the ground flying.
No. .. Yes I'll bring it.
And then back to bed.
Damn!
Stop!
Shut up!
You must be kidding.
OK, that does not bother me.
No.
That's all!
Hello pretty bird.
Come bird, come.
How nice, you're a good bird.
I will return in a bag ...
Mom.
I found it.
Honey there is nothing
going wrong with me.
I'm telling you I'm fine.
Ok, but want to scare crows for the
roof is not considered good.
ICTY's what you mean exactly?
- Tyler, let me talk to your father.
- Of course the goal is that.
I think you're going through a process
of stress and conflict.
I can not do that, I can not afford
another meeting with Lyman.
The guy has flown hundreds
of miles just to see me.
Are you saying that Mr.
Lyman has traveled hundreds
of miles in his jet.
So you can have a
meeting with you.
Yes.
That's funny, baby was only
a crow kept me awake.
It is a matter outside the city.
It will take more than that to me
that this poor bird expires.
Nature, nature, nature.
Ok, well we all can.
We will continue to see
ourselves beautiful.
Hey we are going faster.
3, 2, 1.
Hello.
Mr. Sanders'm happy to report that
everything is ready for this.
¿Puedes see some security
against animals ...
That's not good, I'll have
my boys in this, ok.
Thank you.
Telling you the truth, this promotion
should be bringing some bad luck.
Men without faith believe in anything.
The man with faith believe
in God and have faith.
- That's deep.
- Yes
God is San.
Help me.
- Get the door lock.
- Assist.
¿Puedes say who I am?
Clean everything,
clean everything.
Oh my God, this is not
what they see ...
¿Dónde hell are my clothes?
Nobody would believe it enters the car.
Nobody would believe
it enters the car.
Nobody find you.
Get in the car before
someone finds you.
Hello. To your after!
I have the details and
is very, very good.
¿Hey boys, see you at
3 lost the game?
Go directly to your
home is everything.
No again. Forget it.
- Why?
Then we see what the cake.
And we see what the clown y. ..
I remember, I remember,
we bring the cake.
And we ...
I have it, we bring the cake.
Do not want to sound desperate but I can not Mr.
I can not get anything anyway
Hey PD, ¿Qué such a brother?
No, friend I'm so sorry.
Seriously it's like being stuck
on the Discovery Channel.
Do not understand how people
can live in this town.
- Sorry.
- Not even have a Starbucks.
- We is best in quick coffee.
Really ridiculous.
Hello.
¿Puedo help you find something?
¿Encontrar something?
I am the librarian.
I help people find books.
I love books.
Ok, that's all Sanders me?
How To do you know my name?
I know everything about you and your dad.
The book is the true?
- Yes, we are.
- The murderer of trees.
That ...
I'm Tyler, is quite good.
- I'm Amber, you're funny.
- Absolutely end.
I must wash plans for lunch?
Dan, the Indians will be here
in 10 days, we need to show
this is a special place.
Think about it ...
I have it, we can have
a barbecue Indian.
¿Qué mean?
We hope this can sgnfcar hamburgers
and buffalo hamburgers will.
And we will have this
and that and one way.
ZUD.
is talking about the
Indian reservation?
Wait, we have the festival.
The festival is a great idea.
Well see this is close ...
- Do not cling to me.
- It is a great way to show
- As a community we care.
- Start all Dan.
I'll call-publicized
and the media.
Yes, that is Mr.
¿Por do I always cry?
I'm not yelling at you
- Good but you have your kids ...
- Hell no!
¿Cuál is whether the problem?
Bad bird, bad bird.
¿Hiciste what I said?
Mr. Lyman.
- Mr. ¿Sigue there?
- Yes, I'm still here.
- Okay, ¿Por be interrupted?
- Sr. is just a bird.
- Oh, dear.
- I have more time.
Look, let me say that I will find
out more and tell him later.
- Good but not delay.
- Well, goodbye.
Bees!
Honey I'm home.
I have good notcas, I found some friends
today and we will have a lunch ...
Baby ¿Qué happened to your face?
How To is that you're
using my Buso?
I had a real bad day.
Do not fool anyone, let
me guess, the raven.
That's hard.
I want someone to see you,
I've got an appointment.
Dr. Burr is a local therapist.
Baby, I need sleep.
Well I'm going, but one
more episode and go.
I hope you can sleep,
I have this.
This will improve your mood.
Fungi of the facts and Mr.
Martin.
Try it.
Tammy, I think there is
someone on the stairs.
How To's to get in here?
Get out of my house!
Tammy awake, I had the
worst nightmare.
No hammer dawn.
Oh, no.
Dan.
¿Qué you doing?
- Defendendo m house.
- Ok, I need to try to
explain what you mean.
Ok, but you do not believe me,
I know things are crazy.
- Trust me.
- I promise.
Ok, here goes.
Animals love me actions reach.
ZY what animal we're
talking about Dan?
That's the thing, is better
off an entire forest.
- I think skunks.
- ¯Mofetas?
If you see this is a damn
that I did this ...
It is something like a
psychological attack.
Then the brains of the operation
is a raccoon.
Now I'll take and
will depart at 2.
- You've done your homework.
- Yes.
- I have only one question.
- ¯Qué?
- Zest superloco?
- You promised.
I retract.
- Tyler, turn on the switch.
- No thanks.
Ok, then I will do it
in 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
Tammy.
Now let's start with some forms.
Tell me what you see here.
The first thing that
comes to your mind.
I know that is not supposed to say
this but it's like an angry skunk.
But that looks like this.
Wow.
- ¯Qué about this
- is a bear is a nuisance.
¿Eso help?
Well Dan, ¿Cuánto long have
you been afraid of animals?
I have no fear of animals.
Dan, Dan, Dan.
The denial is part of nature.
Now I want you to listen carefully
to what I'm going to Dreco.
- Animals do not want acabarte.
- I know that animals
do not want to.
- Zen serious?
- Yes
Except for these three
this comes up.
These through the door.
Dan you are suffering a stress related
and need to find your happy place.
Now start closing your eyes.
And taking a deep breath.
And now another breath
pronfundo.
Inhale, exahala.
How To you feel?
- I feel fabulous.
- And you never see
things ¿cierto?
No. ..
Dan.
Zest right?
Thay something bothering you?
ZES this animal?
Because you and I know that
anything unusual out there.
Dan.
Hey stop the car.
I warn you.
Do not, is my car.
You're stealing my car.
No, do not do that.
I will delete you!
No, again.
¿Por what I are doing this
to me what have I done?
Wait.
It almost hits the ball.
You have to make an angle,
there you have it.
OK.
- There it is. Hit.
- Ok.
You know we can play this
after playing sports.
ZSI, but what is funny
about that?
Amber, ¿Cuánto time
you live here?
- I was born here Ms. Sanders.
- Oh, Zen serious?
- I love it here.
- It is not.
Ms. Sanders.
Dan.
The therapy was well.
¿Qué happened?
If you really want to know, I was attacked
by a raccoon in the car and another.
You must be Amber.
- Yes.
- Nice to meet you.
Sorry I need to remove
a leech from my ...
My God.
Dan.
I want to say that animals achieved.
We
- Do not know why I do not believe me.
- Because raccoons do not try.
Well this did it and
I'll prove it.
- Hello son.
- Hello Dad.
Zest right?
We both know I'm beyond the ok.
You see I have these Indian industry
'coming from the city.
And I have a raccoon antisocial
fuck my life.
But nobody wants to believe.
Well I do not think
you're crazy.
Amber gave me this book.
From a local history.
I think there is something
you should see.
You're not the first person
to have that experience.
Natuka The first was a man
of the caves in 9000 BC.
Sn disappears trace.
And many in history have
tried and failed.
The Crete, the Vikings.
How nice ...
Jared, the ancestor.
And Stan hippie.
Hey little buddy.
ZA where you going with this?
Look I made a lot of
studies and see.
Your friend Lyman has a
privilege of Wasington.
He can not cut and build on
what is a forest reserve.
LYMAN COMPANY MAKES PURCHASE LAND
IN FOREST PROTECTED RISKS.
- I'm sure that's not it.
- It is.
Okay, you're building
in a nature reserve.
And frankly you take
out to nature.
¿Me're saying that animals struggle
to arrest me for not doing that?
No, I think I passed that.
I believe that animals
seek revenge.
I do not bite.
Gotcha.
Now I see you're
not fast enough.
Oh, there you are.
Hello little friend.
Look, this could be you.
It is now.
Is your friend ...
No, no, stop that.
I hate them!
Hello, Zhas seen my husband
this morning?
Ms. Sanders Sorry, I have no
time, has seen my daughter.
That is something that
can not get worse.
No Aloque. Aloque not.
Someone came.
Well, well, well.
They have no idea what
is happening today.
Position of guilt.
I know I canzo of their
show or their pets.
I do not want to talk more.
Dan.
¿Dónde?
They must be kidding.
Stan, Stan. ¯Cariño're inside?
Is there any way I fall.
Mr. Sanders not worry it will
go down in a little.
Served.
You might want to
cover your eyes.
Bring the hose.
Fuego.
- Zest good boss?
- If I feel great.
Nothing like a shower on
a freezing cold morning.
They have made good progress
in these home.
Pienza at his home in Lyman ...
You're dead.
Dan.
This ends now!
I do not know where you think
it goes without my keys.
And he left everything.
This ends now.
3 ... 2 ...
Do it again.
I can not do.
I am not a murderer.
Let's just fix this.
I came to fix it and you ...
Oh God!
You do not care about me ...
You fell.
Lucky for you I came.
- Zest dead?
- Not only gave him
the gun reassuring.
You can download
a tiger with it.
¿Cuántas more you have?
I have a whole house full
of these things.
- Zen what you're thinking
- I am thinking of
cleaning my house.
It's time.
They start their cages.
MODEL HOUSE
More boys.
Put them on top.
Ok.
¿Qué happened to the other?
Take him away boys, take them.
I have not had turkey.
- Good morning, Mr. Sanders.
- Good morning.
There are no raccoons.
You know with the animals confined
and under control.
- I think that we will reduce months.
- That would be fabulous.
- No account yet something else?
- Please sit down.
Thanks, Dan said I was going
to explain the details.
- First place has done a fantastic job.
- Thanks.
Only a few things.
We are dealing with the best.
And this whole thing
from the trees.
Please none of those things
better be disturbed.
Sure.
- Oh, I see that they are dancers.
- Great idea.
Well done.
You owe me $ 25, if
25, do not forget.
Wait.
- ZLO leave?
- You're kidding,
I love running.
Well we even need 2 miles.
Amazing.
Hey, How To's your daddy?
ZSE feel better?
Much seems to have
turned the corner.
Look, I know you see it as Mr.
Ego does not help.
But this saved the forest,
it feels good.
Well, I do not think your
dad is a bad guy.
Just for what it does.
There will be trees in the Festibal,
that should tell you something.
Yes.
Amber, ¿Todo right?
Yeah, you know, I was just thinking
in the middle, my dance.
And no one has invited me.
And you kiss me.
¿Todo right?
Hello!
- Whatever.
- There must be a mistake.
Seriously, it makes perfect
sense to me.
- It's a good job of your father.
- Amber expected.
Just leave me alone.
- Do not blame me it was my dad.
- I intereza.
Stay boy, do not have all day.
Here it is, waiting.
Dan you have to do something, your boss
is ruining the whole festival.
- Meat is not so bad.
- Yes, because everything was
going to be a disaster.
But everything I say
my boss has done.
- ¯Cuándo hibas me to say?
- Tell you.
- On your forest eviction.
- Not what you think, ok.
It is only a couple of days.
... That's then
¿Luego what?
Liberate animals and everything
will be fine.
Know what I think are better
now because they are safe.
You are so blind to the facts.
Working for a company ecologist
giving orders to kill
the animals.
You are so hypocritical.
Tyler ...
Wait a minute.
¿Qué I'm the bad guy? Come on.
No, I'm tired.
It's working.
They know that my family is
completely against me.
¿Por Why me?
¿Qué have I done?
Well I try to talk to a raccoon.
As if you understand. "
And your children.
I must wash a family?
All this time has been
protecting me.
Festibal ROCKY SPRING SPRING
SPRING FOREST Festibal
Well do not complain.
Enter.
I love tickling, tickle master.
We think we're doing
reengineering.
It's a good thing.
Now.
They try to destroy the forest.
Inform yourself, is big.
Amber, Amber.
- ¯Qué wrong?
- ¯Qué you doing?
Well I continue my way to not
end up with the forest.
dcho ¿Bueno never have not returned
my calls or my text messages?
Excuse me if I am a little
busy with my dad.
If you want to do something
you have to do it right.
Stop to end the forest.
They are destroying the forest.
Smug.
Here we can raise more things
and get on with the markets.
And this is a new concept.
Speaking of the economic
conscience.
Dan's wife. Tammy Sanders.
Thanks in first place this Festibal
has nothing to do with the forest.
Not true.
Oh, and this is the son of Dan.
Tyler.
- Tyler ¿Qué this?
- You know we have found that
they give it to the forest.
- Busy day.
- Tyler I know you must be
very upset right now.
- It has nothing to do with you dad.
- Van to kill animals.
zMate?
There must be some kind of
error in communication.
Lyman industry does not kill animals.
Only we will relocate.
Yes but that is the same as killing them.
Will leave no trees to animals.
Enough!
Heard everything you
needed to hear.
Lyman earned it.
- ¯Qué?
¿Qué about animals?
Fewer animals, less discomfort
only take charge of them.
¿Qué?
Great, because it is just like
the contract says so.
- Now you're happy
- Hey guys.
- Congratulations, well done dad.
- Wait.
Reubicabamos I thought that if the
animals would be no problem.
I'll take care of something.
ZA where are you going?
There is something I have to do.
You were the one who created all this.
Now I want to do
is that you continue as you did.
Come on.
Guys around here for the photo.
Say whiskey.
Come on, come down here.
That is all.
Hey you still!
Many of you Do not panic.
Thanks to the band.
Ok, just kidding.
Thank you.
Friends and neighbors.'m
Neal Lyman.
And for us Industry Lyman has been a privilege
to be part of the community.
Thank you.
Today is a new start
for this small town.
- You can call bad, irrelevant.
- ¯Irrelevante?
2 teams of raccoons.
I see nature as it is.
The beginning of a
new leadership.
Thank you.
And here is a great man.
Who will change their
little world.
So with this ...
Stop the predation environment.
People, Tyler here, right,
you were right.
He is a fraud.
Not even have thought
of anything natural.
- No part of this.
- Very well.
That's something small ok.
Forced my family that I mudarna
here a bit of fresh air.
Having a better life.
I was just trying to
grow in my career.
I came here because I thought
it would make a community.
But the truth is that
I just felt one.
I've seen, I've seen.
Safety, safety, please.
Ok, ¿Qué if I said that the forest
will have 100 million dollars?
¿Quién is winning now?
Do not listen.
Ok, folks, we'll see that Mr.
Gupta sign the contract.
Mr. Gupta, amblemente
take the pen.
And roll please.
I have them, I have them.
Go, go!
- Ok, here.
- I will not sign this.
- Do it, do it.
- No, no.
- Forget it.
- Do it.
Well.
Please.
Zahora what?
Oh, well.
Mira.
It is the raccoon.
- That sucks.
- You know.
- Zahora believe me?
- I never doubted ...
I remember my first said ...
- I have the key.
- Watch a portfolio.
Well ...
I started this business
4 years ago is ...
Tammy.
Adios raccoon.
Oh my God. ... I'll kill you
Come strong, steady ...
well done.
It's not what you think.
Sanders Hey, right back.
Bruce Lee emerged from the tomb.
Come on. Come on.
I think it's fair. What to eat.
It is good that too.
That curse is wrong.
¿Dije was sorry?
I had my priorities
completely wrong.
- And just ... I love you Tyler.
- Dad, it's cool, ok.
- Tyler hug your dad.
- ¯Qué?
Do it, do it.
Tyler.
Come on.
I love you too dad.
Oh, really.
This went well.
Everything will be fine.
AFTER 3 MONTHS