You want to make a statement?
- You want to gangsta up, homie?
- Yeah
You got to go bold, all right?
Double action old school
It's sweet, it's simple, accurate
never jams Here we go, give it a try
- Where? - I don't know-
just-just shoot the pipe
Nice shot
What else you got?
All right, got the homie's
best friend here, all right?
It's a nine mill, it's
Beretta it's Italian
All right, it's 15
plus one in the snout
I'll throw in a box of
hollow point hot loads
Trust me, your stuff
will be safe, okay?
Here, here we go
Bad boy is tight!
You ain't seen the
baddest boy yet, all right?
Sweet mother of God
The pagans shall quake
It's a Tech 9 It's
top of the line
Fully automatic
You can empty the clip
in four seconds flat
- Are you man enough for this?
- Yeah
- Yeah?
Yeah, all right, give it
a shot, give it a ride
- You like that?
- Yeah
- You're looking taller already, buddy
- Yeah!
Let's get the hell out of
here! Let's go! Let's go!
Miss anything, McLovin?
Just this It's from a woman
named Melinda She had to postpone
Postpone what?
I don't know Figured
that you'd figure it out
How did she sound?
I ask the question, you give
the answer How did she sound?
- I don't know, Tony
- You don't know
Well, why don't you try using
your words, Mr Gem City?
Devastated? Despondent?
Delighted
All right What's
her number, McDetail?
She didn't leave one
It's customary to get a name, a
number and a complete message
This is not a complete message
This is a complete mess
Melinda
How many Melindas do
you have in that thing?
I don't know It could have been
the girl I talked to at the gym
You don't go to the gym
Maybe it was the girl I
talked to at the dog park
You don't have a dog
Oh, it could have been that girl I met
at the concession stand
While my date was in the bathroom
You need a secretary
Or a therapist
Or both
Shots fired in Liberty
Heights Saddle it up
If we were called every time shots
were fired at Liberty Heights
Yeah, Well, Metro responded
They found a dead Marine
Victim is Private First
Class Emilio Salazar
Joined the Marines four months ago
Scheduled for deployment next week
Ducky?
Stuck in traffic Should
be here in about 20 minutes
Nine millimeter shells
Possibly two guns
And based on the level
of penetration on that wall
I would say 357
No shells, which means a revolver
One shooter, three weapons
There's two sets of footprints
Shooter could have had a spotter
- Or a lookout
- Or a witness
Hey, DiNozzo
McGee
New Marine regulations
don't allow for exposed ink
He had his tat removed, laser
Looks
like- "P "
It looks like this
PCS
All right, I'll check
with Metro's gang unit
Bullets hit the skylight
killing our Marine
Sending him on a very
short bungee plunge
But why shoot your
hostage from down here?
Maybe they were sending a message
The kind McGee takes-
cryptic, hard to decipher
Blood
This blood is dried
But Metro made their "shots
fired" call less than an hour ago
Looks like the West
just got a bit wilder
Cuffs, boss
Skin, blood
This guy was strapped
up here for a while
That's why prefer
the fur handcuffs
Not really, boss That's for her
I don't wear the cuffs
Someone was trying
to send a message
Written in blood
Phone number?
Not a phone number
I don't know what the "G"
stands for, but it's nine digits
Could be a military
service number I'll run it
You don't have to
It's mine
Where is he?
Um, I'm not exactly sure, Director
Tell him I need to see him
I will give him the message
And the nature of the message
I'll include who it's
from, and the number
Why would anyone leave Gibbs' Marine
service number on a rooftop crime scene
Agent Gibbs' desk
No, he's not here
But I'd be happy to
take a detailed message
Flight arrives at 2:30
Can I take a name
or a return number?
Oh, okay I will
A name and a number
Enough, okay? I understand
I am sorry, but what
do you want me to do?
You want me to sort through
the database
Of every call that came into
the switchboard this morning
And match incoming call to your desk
phone using a date and a time stamp?
Yeah, actually That'd
be great Thanks
Oh, hey, boss, got two messages for
you, actually, right there Sorry
Director Vance wants you to
call him back ASAP, and the, uh
the other is, uh And then
there's-there's that one
Um, it says that the flight arrives
at 2:30 It's from M Street Travel
I assume that's a travel agent
Didn't say where the flight was
from or who the passenger was
But if you want to share
that, you can feel
Dead Marine?
PFC Emilio Salazar Service record
18-year-old Completed basic training
at Parris Island two months ago
And was stationed at Quantico
Had more than a service record
Criminal record goes back
to 2003, when Emilio was 12
All juvenile offenses
All gang-related
Gang tattoos
Or Pecados Capitales
Capital Fish?
Deadly Sins, you
idiot Fish is pescado
Don't scoff at me
Lots of gangs are
named after deadly fish
There's the Sharks, there's
the Barracudas
Rumble Fish
These guys are also
known as the PCs
Sounds like your kind
of gang, McMotherboard
Kid lives through six years in a gang
can't survive four months as a Marine
Maybe someone didn't want
him to leave the gang?
Maybe a rival gang killed him?
Though that wouldn't explain
your service number, boss
Focus on tracking the killer
And what about the other person
who may have been held there?
Find the shooter
Vance wanted to call him ASAP, boss
Heard you the first time, DiNozzo
Private Jackson, do not shut your
eyes when you squeeze the trigger!
Eyes off the toys, David
We didn't come here to play
I have not been to
the range in days
No talking on the range, please
Well, that's going to be a real
problem, Staff Sergeant Medina
'Cause I'm real talky
and I have a badge
Is there somewhere we can talk?
Cease fire! Cease fire!
Clear and lock 'em! Stand by!
Thank you
A man in your unit
was killed last night
- How'd it happen?
- Firefight He lost
- Someone shot him?
- Several times
You know who did it?
If we did, we would not be here
Thought you could help
Any way I can
He was killed in the
neighborhood where he grew up
He ever talk about his
past? Gangs, trouble?
All the time He was
trying to escape it
So you knew he had a record
before he joined the Marines?
Some of these kids grew up in a jungle
A lot more dangerous than the desert
we're sending them to, you know?
Salazar ever drop names, gang
affiliations, enemies?
Nothing specific
He had troubles like any kid
who runs in gang circles
But he didn't name anybody
If you can think of
anything, let me know
- Berettas- nine
millimeter - Feel free
- Do you mind?
- Not at all, ma'am
Do your best
Oh, God
Stand by, station two, for live fire!
I prefer the SIG
A lot of women have
trouble with the Beretta
Thing's got too much of a kick
Your sight is a
few millimeters off
- Really?
- Really
Prior to PFC Salazar's demise
Handcuffs made these
abrasions and lacerations
Yeah, well, he wasn't
held there long
No He was executed almost
immediately upon his confinement
- As to the cause of
death- - Gunshots
Well, yes and no
These wounds were made
by machine-gun fire
The spacing is too symmetrical
for random shooting
Also, they showed no signs of
redness or braiding and bruising,
indicating that our private was
long dead when he was strafed
How long?
About six hours based
on his liver temperature
And here
single round, nine millimeter
punctured the pericardial sac,
causing a cardiac tamponade
He suffered greatly, Jethro-
perhaps for 20 or 30 minutes-
and he did not die quickly
The bullet that killed him?
In the capable
hands of Abby Sciuto
You've never left a scene of a crime
before I arrived until this one, Jethro
Yeah Had something else to do
Something to do with your
Marine Corps service number?
I was wondering the
same thing myself
You're avoiding me
I've been busy
solving a murder, Leon
When I have something, you'll
be the first to know
I'm looking for a Marine file
A classified one
Top secret, eyes only
Black Ops
Gunnery Sergeant
Leroy Jethro Gibbs
Next time you having guests, probie
have some scotch in the house
Ah, you couldn't sweet-talk
the flight attendant
Out a few of those little bottles?
- He wasn't my type
- Right
What's so urgent?
You pulled me away
from my granddaughter
Just celebrated
her second birthday
I'm looking for somebody
Rose
Vance know I'm here yet?
Not yet
Maybe I should borrow a tie
Colombia was a long time ago, gunny
Only one person knew about her
You
18 years is a long time, probie
She's in DCToday
Mike
What do you want me to say?
Whatever you're not saying
Well, how do you know
she's here, for sure?
My Marine service number was
written on the roof of a crime scene
In blood
That could have been anybody
I put a "G" on the
end of it, just for her
I brought her here 17 years ago
Where is she now?
I haven't seen her since
the day I dropped her off
Let's start there
You put her here?
Wasn't such a hellhole then
Que paso?
Que es lo que miras?
I'm looking for Rose Tamayo
Ma, alguien esta a la puerta
Que se les ofrece?
Buscando Rosa Tamayo?
Ella se murio hace diez años
We're a little late
She died ten years ago
Guess somebody else knows your
Marine service number, probie
Howdy, Leon
Mike
He has information
on a current case
And I need his help
Thanks for sorting out that
little pension problem, Leon
Appreciate it
I didn't do anything I wouldn't
have done for any former agent, Mike
All by the book
Absolutely By the book
That's how we operate now
Wouldn't have it
any other way, Leon
Think he noticed my tie?
What do we got?
We canvassed the area
No one is talking
- There is a smurf war
- Turf war
between two competing gangs, the
PCs and the Verde Psychos
Ballistics
We matched the slug that
killed PFC Salazar to a gun
that was used in an unsolved
robbery two weeks ago And
Metro's chief suspect is
Victor Carmado, a k a Popeye
Victor Carmado is a
known member of the PCs
He was hanging out with his
posse at Liberty Heights today
DiNozzo, Ziva, bring him in
Abby!
- Howdy, darling!
- Franks! What are you doing here?
Probie thinks I'm here helping him, but
it was just an excuse to come see you
Abs, turn it down
This is so cool
Someone writes your service number
on a roof, and then you just show up
It's like sending out the bat signal
and having Batman just show up
And his mentor, Ra's al Ghul
Or-or like Princess
Lela sending a hologram
"Help me, Obi-Wan "
And then getting Obi-Wan
with his mentor, Qui-Gon Jinn
You know, it's weird 'cause Liam
Neeson played both the mentors
You gonna tell me why I'm here?
Oh, um, I ran the blood
from the service number
It does not match our
dead Marine, Emilio Salazar
I already know that
Of course you do
Well, hopefully
it'll be news to you
That the blood
did belong to another Marine
Private First Class Tomas Tamayo
Judging by the look on your
face, that is news to you
Um, he comes from the same
neighborhood as PFC Salazar
According to his records
His mother died ten years ago
after emigrating from Colombia
Rose had a son?
Uh, yeah He was about a year
old when I brought her here
You knew?
I'm guessing you didn't
I need an address, Abs
57 Kensington Street
The home belongs to a
woman named Maggie Scott
Might want to take
this slow, probie
Might not like where it leads you
Popeye Carmado? NCIS
Are we all listening
to the same song?
Let me guess Ricky Martin fans
"Livin' La Vida Loca "
You ought to leave, man
But we just got here
Yeah But this is a very
dangerous neighborhood
That's why I brought her
La Bonita es una federale
Federales saben buenas
La Bonita will kick your ass
Is that right?
You know, bad things happen
in this place, mamita
But it's so homey, homey
I love what you've
done with the wall here
"Snoopy loves Chiquita?"
Which one of you sleeps on a
doghouse and which one's a bana?
I'm guessing the love is
between you two Am I wrong?
Think they want to play
rock, paper, scissors?
- You got them?
- I've got them
What's the matter? Popeye didn't
eat his spinach this morning?
Rico! Chuy!
Rico Suave's stuck in the '90s, and
Chewie's back with theMillennium Falcon
Let's go see how La Bonitadid
What took you so long?
McGee!
What are you doing? Why are you
digging through the NCIS database?
This woman called for Tony, and
I didn't get the number
It was blocked by the carrier, so
I am trying to coordinate a trace
Well, drop the call This
is much more important
Okay, what's up?
I heard something
Not a complete something, a
partial something
But enough of something to make
me think it means something
So I need to know if there's any
other something that you know about?
What-
I'm-I'm lost
Okay It's something about Gibbs
And Colombia And
a woman named Rose
And a son she had 18 years ago
That would been 1991-
before Gibbs joined NCIS
Come on, McGee
Type something about the
something into something
Open, he's open
Give me the ball
Shoot it
Nice shooting, lady
Get a lot of practice around here
You Maggie Scott?
Hey, Henry, come in for me, okay?
What happened? You guys Metro?
NCIS
Who got hit? Somebody
from this block?
I understand this is the
home of Thomas Tamayo
Why? Is he all right?
He was involved in a murder
Oh, my God
No, he wasn't the victim
Someone a couple of streets over
Emilio Salazar
Emilio Yeah, he's a, uh, he's
a friend of Tomas's
His mother, has anyone
contacted Emilio's mother?
Being done now Where is Tomas?
He's on leave, Cape
Hatteras Before Afghanistan
Wrong He was at a crime
scene last night in DC
Hold on
You were his legal guardian?
Legal guardian to
a lot of these kids
Keeps them out of the system
I just watch them till their
moms get home from work
Most of them don't have fathers
Two of them lost
siblings, past couple months
War?
Gang war
You're not from
around here, are you?
I moved here after college
Part of the Vista program
I never left
How'd you become Thomas's guardian?
Tomas moved in about 12 years back
Then when Rose got sick-
his mother has cancer-
she asked me to look after him
He's a good kid He's
a really good kid
Oh, my God, It's okay He's here
It's Tomas It's Tomas
Tomas!
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine What is this?
I was so worried about you
What's going on?
You want to tell us where you
been for the past 48 hours?
Cape Hatteras with friends
We checked
Your cell calls were all made
from a two-block area of DC
Why were you being held here?
I wasn't
My military service number
Your blood on the roof
You got my attention, Thomas
I'm here What do you want?
It wasn't me
I cut myself traing
Gibbs and the kid
It was your damn blood on the roof
- What's the connection?
- We tested it
And why the kid gloves?
Hey, let me out!
Our friend from the hood
- Think he's chilled long enough?
- Let me out of here, man!
Time to unpop his cork
Let me out of here!
Cool it, Coolio! No
gangbanging on the walls
Sit down
- I ain't sitting down
- Sientate!
Or do you want La Bonita
to sit your ass down?
I thought you all forgot
about me, that's all
You in a hurry to
get somewhere, Popeye?
'Cause you sure ain't going home to
Olive Oyl and Sweet Pea any time soon
You're going to prison
Says who?
Says the nine-millimeter slug we
pulled out of PFC Emilio Salazar
Matches the slug from another
shooting you were involved in
If witnesses put me there, I'd
have been locked up already
We have a dead Marine, former
gang member of yours
This is the murder weapon
Found dumped in a storm
drain Recognize it?
That's it? That's all you got?
It's all we need
It's all circumstantial
I think you got nothing
I think what you
need is a confession
You are looking at ten years for
accessory to a murder of a USMarine
More if we tag you for murder one
Your sweat was on that roof
Your pee was on that roof
Your blood was on that roof
You gonna tell us what
happened on that roof?
You're gonna tell us
who else was there
Who put that bullet in PFC Salazar
We're gonna have to
assume it was you
I didn't kill Emilio
- Who did?
- Me
I killed the little bitch
You killed PFC Salazar?
Yeah, I did it You got me
The fool deserved to die
How'd it go down, Victor?
I shot him That's
how it went down
Put the gun to
his head- pow
Blew his brains out
You shot him in the head?
Lights out, baby
JFK style
Back and to the
left, know what I'm saying?
One shot to the chest
That's what killed
your friend Emilio
But he didn't die right
away It took time
Maybe 20 minutes
Bullet nicked his heart
Blood poured into his lungs
- Remember, Tomas?
- No
He would have had
trouble breathing
The pain must have
been excruciating
But you know all this
don't you, Marine?
I wasn't there
Popeye didn't pop the guy
No way a kid like that
took down two Marines
Probably taking credit for a
street kill to elevate his stature
Get anything on PFC Tamayo?
- He's scared
- He's hiding something
They both are
Something more going on than that
You're right, probie
Gangbangers don't
kidnap their enemies
They shoot them in the street
Somebody's pulling
strings, calling shots
I think I know who
I've been crosschecking the Metro Gang
Task Force's list of known PC members
against cell numbers
registered in their names
One common phone
number keeps popping up
It's a number from outside
the neighborhood
That called almost every member
of the PC gang
That's the COfrom
the shooting range
Staff sergeant Vicente Medina
That's not all I looked into
the staff sergeant's history
It seems he shares a bit more
than phone records in common
He wasn't just
recruiting from the PCs
He was a member
Get him in here
- Yeah, Gibbs
- Meet you in my office
I'll be right there
- Marine file
- It's yours
I haven't read it yet, and I
won't if you'd prefer I didn't
I thought it might shed some light
on what the hell happened in Colombia
18 years ago
unless you'd prefer to
I got nothing to hide, Leon
Everybody's got something to hide
Franks a part of this?
A little part
Some good stuff in
the last five pages
How many men have you killed?
Seven confirmed
Where?
Three in Anbar, two in Fallouja, one
in Baghdad, one in Tora Bora
How about Washington, DC?
None
You knew Emilio Salazar?
His platoon sergeant, sir
He's a gang member
just like you are
That was a long time ago
That was last night!
Sir, I did not kill that Marine!
Whatwereyou doing last night?
I was at home watching TV
Anybody watching you watching TV?
No
Your place is 20 minutes
from our crime scene
Phone records
You made contact with half the
PC posse over the past six months
Rap sheet; yours
Shot caller for the
PCs for three years
Once a Marine, always a Marine
Or once a PC, always a PC
I lived the life
It's not a secret
I liked it, till I saw what
was happening to my friends
In dead or jail by 17
so I joined the Marine Corps
Made me a better person
came back to the hood
And tried to convince others
to make something of themselves
Ran a system-wide facial
recognition search
I thought you'd want
to see this right away
Okay, let's try this again
Where were you last night?
I... I told you I was at home
Baltimore! That was
taken last night!
You couldn't have killed him
Why are you lying?
I went to visit my son
When I was 15, I made some mistakes
I got a girl pregnant
And my wife
she doesn't know I have a kid
I know what we got; nothing
Guess we all make
mistakes, huh, probie?
Got two Marines chained
to a roof Don't know why
Got somebody behind it pulling
strings Don't know who
Can we wind the clock back
to the part
Where we find out what
Gibbs was doing in Colombia?
Or how it is connected to the gang?
Got a punk who didn't kill
anybody who says he did,
and a kid who wrote probie's service
number in blood saying he didn't
You done?
Done watching you shave
with a butter knife
Let me talk to that kid
I'll get him to tell us what
the hell's going on here
I can't do that, Mike I let him go
You what?
If you want to find
something, you follow it
I learned that one from you
You two
- MTAC with McGee
- Got it, boss
Think I don't know
what you're doing?
Trying to get that boy off?
Yeah, gonna lead us to the truth
The truth
Yeah, which you should
have told me 17 years ago
When I got Rose out of Colombia, you
were happily married again
- Or so I thought
- What's the truth?
The truth is, she
didn't want you to know!
She knew you were still putting
the pieces back together
After Shannon and Kelly
Didn't want to
complicate your life
Guess she didn't get
her wish after all
Maybe Gibbs was on a covert mission
to suppress the Fujimori coup
That was Peru, not Colombia
Okay, boss, we're still following the
GPS signal from PFC Tamayo's cell phone
He drove to Quantico He's
been there about 20 minutes
Quantico's that way, probie
We're not going to Quantico That's
his first stop We're going to his last
Like the lady
said, Mike "It's a war "
So he's down in Colombia in Bogota
He saves President Clinton's life,
but nobody can talk about
it because it's super secret
Clinton did not serve until '93
Stop obsessing!
I'm not obsessing! I'm
a little preoccupied
I'm a tad fascinated by the whole
subject, but I amnot obsessing
What was he doing in
Colombia 17 years ago?
18 years ago- and
it's classified, DiNozzo
Is that classified, too, or can
you share with your director?
We're, uh, tracking a
suspect for Gibbs, Director
Franks is with him?
That's what I thought
PFC Tamayo's just left Quantico
He's now headed
towards Liberty Heights
So, what do you want us to do?
Whatever you were doing
before I walked in
What's Tamayo's duty
assignment at Quantico?
Guard duty at the base armory
And the dead Marine?
PFC Salazar was also
a guard at the armory
Means they both had
access to the armory codes
Stepping back Excuse me
- Get base security on the phone
- Yes, sir
Hey, if this kid starts shooting
you're gonna shoot back, right?
This is a really bad time, Leon
I just got off the phone with
the Armory OICat Quantico
Four crates of M-4
assault rifles are missing
That's your PFC Tamayo, Gibbs
Gangs, guns It adds up
We're still monitoring his GPS
- He's headed back toward the projects
- The projects?
Yeah, we got him, we got him
I did what you wanted, okay?
No, you listen to me!
You want 'em, you come get 'em
Second floor-
I'm waiting
This is about to get
real interesting, probie
McGee, building across the street
Traffic camera, 3837 Ashton
- Got it
- Record it
Recording
You alone, homes?
Zoom in on those guys
In Those two
Aren't those the two guys?
Chuy and Rico I should
have hit them harder
You got 'em?
Freeze! Freeze! Freeze! Put your hands
in the air! Put your hands in the air!
You thought you were gonna use
Marine guns to kill my friends?
Something's going down
Somebody's behind him
McGee, zoom out, zoom out
No! This ends here!
What the hell?
Don't move, Sergeant
DiNozzo, call for an
ambulance and backup
Everywhere you
go, kid, somebody gets shot
3832 Ashton shots fired
Possible multiple casualties
Keep pressure on it, Sergeant
Hey, Leon
Let me talk to him
He's busy Can I take a message?
You just shot somebody, Franks
Yeah All by the book, Leon
Retired-agent-
involved shooting
That's still a form KJ-65, right?
- Nice talking to you, Leon
- Fra
It was me
I ordered him to take those weapons
off the base
And bring 'em here like they wanted
Why?
- Because I was
- No, not you You
They held me on the roof
Said they'd hurt everyone I love
unless I got them the assault weapons
I... I didn't believe them
They used to be my friends
Then they threatened Emilio
Shot him in front of me
I thought they were
gonna kill me, too
That why you wrote
my service number?
When I found out you were
NCIS, I wanted to tell you, but
I ordered him not to
Why?
Using Marine guns
to kill kids in my hood
Kids I was trying to save
it made me sick
I wanted to handle it myself
We take care of our own
Those guys are just the hired help
- That is all you have to say?
- Yes
I did it, I admit it I'll
give you a full confession
Can I talk to him?
No, he's going to prison
Please, I
He stole weapons from a Marine
base to arm a street gang
People died
He confessed to everything
All of it, his idea
And he's going away
Unless you've got something to say
Wait He didn't do
anything He's lying
Hold up
Nobody was supposed to get hurt
They were supposed to scare them so
that Tomas or Emilio would get the guns
For the PC's Emilio
wasn't supposed to get shot
That was an accident, I swear
Who need weapons, Maggie?
Our kids
In the neighborhood, on our block
They were getting killed every day
Slaughtered by drug
dealers and bigger gangs
They are dying every day!
I had to protect them
By what, arming them
with assault rifles?
I grew up in the Cold War
My dad talked
about deterrence-
if you build up an arsenal that rivals
your enemy's, they won't attack you
You understand?
Case closed- my
case, and you being on it
"Melinda 555-0199"
Hold the phone, Malone, I
know that number
You should- it's
your dentist's office
They rescheduled your appointment
Ooh, thatMelinda
The one with the man hands
Well, I hope you
learned a lesson, probie
Yeah- never to pick
up your phone again
Wait a second
It was right in front
of me the whole time
Franks! I've got
a question for you
Got a plane to catch
18 years ago, Colombia
Gibbs was doing drug
interdiction down there
Tomas is 18, from Colombia
Knows Gibbs's Marine
service number
Question?
Is Gibbs Tomas's father?
Tell probie thanks for the lend
No Sit down As you were
Your orders
Shipping out to Afghanistan
I... I'm not going to jail?
You helped the investigation
My mother used to tell me
this story about a Marine
He came to help out our village
But the drug cartel
came after him
shot him He almost died
She hid him, helped him heal
That was you
And when you finally got well
you told her that if
she ever need any help,
she could give that number to
any Marine and you would find her
She made me memorize that number
You're the reason
I became a Marine
When your mother saved my life, she
was already pregnant with you
Most people, they don't
get a second chance
Good luck
Semper Fi
Ooh-rah
Read about the mission
to eliminate Cesar Castillo
From the Cali Cartel in Colombia
Good read?
It was impressive
Took out your target with one
shot to the heart from 1, 200 yards
This Castillo was a piece of work
Drug dealer, torturer, rapist
I did my job
And the mission would've gone
off without a hitch
If you hadn't been wounded
Well, I guess you're
all caught up now, Leon
Must've been poignant helping out the
son of the woman that saved your life
Did you tell the boy that the
man you killed was his father?