FLOATING WEEDS
Produced by
MASAICHI NAGATA
Planning by
HIDEO MATSUYAMA
Screenplay by
YASUJIRO OZU KOGO NODA
Photography by
KAZUO MIYAGAWA
Art Direction
TOMOO SHIMOGAWARA
Music by
KOJUN SAITO
Sound Recording
TAKEO SUDA
Lighting
SACHIO ITO
Color Consultant
SHOZO TANAKA
Editing
TOYO SUZUKI
With
Komajuro Arashi
GANJIRO NAKAMURA
Sumiko
MACHIKO KYO
Kayo
AYAKO WAKAO
Kiyoshi
HIROSHI KAWAGUCHI
Oyoshi
HARUKO SUGIMURA
Aiko
HITOMI NOZOE
Impresario
CHISHU RYU
Kichinosuke
KOJI MITSUI
Sugiyama
YOSUKE IRIE
Kimura
HIKARU HOSHI
Shige
KUMEKO URABE
Okatsu
MUTSUKO SAKURA
Directed by
YASUJIRO OZU
What a hot day
Good morning
Terribly hot, isn't it?
What are they going to show next?
It's a Kabuki show
Sword-fighting plays, eh?
I liked that strip show last month
Remember that big girl in the pink?
This one isn't like that
It's the Grand Kabuki show
Really?
This troupe is coming all the way
from Okazaki,
through Kariya and the Chita Cape
Really?
You'll give me a free pass as usual?
I remember I saw this troupe years ago,
back during the war
It was at Yamada I saw this Komajuro
It was?
He played very well, too
He played Chuya Marubashi
A pint here and a quart there
Quite a lot, I'm quite aware．
Will the boat be late again?
I got no telegram from her.
She'll come on the dot
For a change, right?
Indeed
This is going to be
a really hot day today
It's overdue, eh?
No, not much
Master
We're here?
Kayo, you take care of that
Don't bother
Is this yours, Sugiyama?
Don't leave anything
Ready, Roku?
You too, Sensho?
Don't forget anything
Don't forget me, dear
Till from me you hear
KOMAJUROARASHIANDHIS TROUPE
PLAYINGAT THEAIOI THEATER
- Give me one.
- Give me one
More, stingy
Say, you have a pretty sister?
- Nope.
- I have
- How old is she?
- Twelve
Good afternoon
Put this on the wall, sir
Aioi Theater, eh?
Do come to see us
Just a minute
Do you perform tonight?
Yes, we do
Hello, there
I'll come tonight
I'll be expecting you
Master, your wife's here
Good business, eh?
Can I have a match?
Tell me
What's your name?
Toshiro
Toshiro?
Mifune
You're kidding
You're kidding me
Another sake, Master
Good afternoon
I'll be expecting you
Let's go together, Okatsu.
Who'll take care of the customers?
Do come tonight
Bye.
- Bye
I'll be seeing you
He'd be fun
He's an Osaka actor, then?
And an old-timer around here
He once played in our town, too
They say he used to play at the big
theaters in Osaka
Is that so?
That means —
Don't move or you'll get cut
Oh, I'm afraid
Don't you cut me, Aiko
What a hot day
It's terrible
Your daughter? Very pretty
Hello. Helping your dad?
Nice of you. Admirable
You can rest assured, eh?
Aiko Ogawa, eh?
Cute name
Listen, Aiko
You're the only child?
Apple of his eye, eh?
Great help to your dad
Marrying a barber, too?
Marry someone who's good-looking
Like me. Nice and kind
What a cute little thing you are
Very lovely
Bring me a cup of tea
We're back
You must be tired
Hello. You must be tired
It's hot. It's terribly hot
Bring me my kimono, will you?
Why?
Have to visit a patron
Good afternoon, sir
I brought this for you
Oh, thank you very much
The owner's here, Master
Thanks for everything, sir
It's been a long time
Yes, it has, indeed
It feels good to be back here again
When was the last time?
It was just after the surrender?
It was
It's already been twelve years
since then
So long, eh?
Time flies
I see several new faces
With the change of the times,
you know
My leading lady, Sumiko, sir
I'm pleased to meet you
What happened to that man
who played Yasu?
You mean Tatsunosuke
He died at Fukuchiyama
What happened?
A stroke
Such a good actor
I'm so sorry
And this is his daughter
who was just a child then
Grown up into a fine young lady
She used to be little as
a Chinese nut
What's a Chinese nut?
Like a peanut
Leaving, Manager Kimura?
I'm leaving now. Need anything?
Do your best
Flat rate, like you said?
That'd suit me fine
Next engagement?
Yes. Shingu, in Kii
Is that so?
I'll leave then
From Mr. Marudai's, Master
In celebration,
a show of hands
Once again
Congratulations
Is that the leading man?
He's pretty old
Give me some sake
- I'll leave the money here.
- Thank you
I knew you'd come.
I saw the parade
How've you been?
Alright?
Come right in.
It's much cooler in there
Really? Thanks very much
I'm glad to see you so well
You, too
It's been 12 years
Must've been hard.
So many years
You had sore shoulders last time
Alright now?
I did?
You told me the pains were killing you
Did I?
It's okay now
It's very cool here
Sorry to bother you
How's Kiyoshi? Alright?
Finished school last year
You wrote me that
Did I?
He's working now
Where?
Post office. He's saving up
Wants to study electronics
at the trade school
Fine
But then I'll be all alone here
And you'll be lonely, yes
But he's saving up for schooling
I hate to discourage him
Tell me
What does he know?
I mean, about me
He thinks his father's dead?
And that I'm just your brother?
Pretty flowers
Don't you feel sort of lonely?
- What do you mean?
- About Kiyoshi
Can't help it
I'm not worth much
However —
Let's not talk about it
- But —
- Forget it
Let it stay this way
I'm sorry for you though
Forget it
Have a drink
That's Kiyoshi
Welcome home
Oh, hello Uncle
I should've come home sooner
Working?
Studying with the postmaster
How you've grown up!
They'd have drafted you back then
A first-grade conscript, no doubt
He sure has grown up
No wonder we're getting old
It's years since we last met
How long are you staying?
As long as my show draws.
A year, maybe
It can't last that long
It will too!
You made this?
What's this?
Don't tamper with it
I'll go see your show.
What do you play?
Forget it.
It's not meant for you
Who is it for?
An audience
I'm an audience
I know
It's nothing high-class.
Forget about it
Why show such plays?
Show something better
But I can't
Why?
Audiences today
won't understand good plays
So you can't come to see it
Last time we went fishing together
What fish are biting now?
- I'm not sure
Let's go together again
It's hot outside
I don't mind. Let's, shall we?
How about tomorrow? Sunday
- Sure.
- Let's
All right. It's a plan
He sure has grown up
Sake's warm enough?
Very logical.
He argued me down
Really? What did you argue about?
Very wise
Very brainy
Welcome!
Welcome! Two guests
Well, Master
This is our last night at Mt. Akagi
I am leaving my home village
of Kunisada
My true territory
I must leave you, too,
my loyal men
This is the last of the Kunisada Group
Come to think of it,
the breeze sounds lonely
A flock of geese
flying to the south
The moon is setting
behind the far hills
Where shall we go now?
Wherever our legs will carry us,
roaming aimlessly
to the end of the world
Master
That is Brother Enzo
Stout-hearted as he is,
he must feel lonesome
at leaving home
You, noted sword,
thoroughly tempered by the famous
Yoshikane of Kaga,
cleansed in the brook
from the perpetual snow
You, at least, will guard me well
Though all the world betrays me,
you'll be with me, faithful one
The geese have flown
The crow must now lament for me
Hey, look at that
The barber's daughter
Which one?
See an old woman
with the towel on her head?
Behind her. Eating a bun
What a big mouth she has
Which one is yours?
She's out there
That one
The one who's smoking now
She's nice
A real find
And mine?
Your girl isn't there
She's cute, too
Not to my taste, though
Really? I'm looking forward to her
They liked it, eh?
Big house?
Not very
For an opening
It'll get better, I'm sure
Think so?
I think so.
Remember the last place?
Why so pessimistic these days?
Don't you worry
And mark my words
I'm positive
Where do you go after that act?
Climb down the mountain
After climbing down
It's clear
Come straight to you
No kidding
No kidding at all
Here he comes
Welcome
- Afternoon.
- Over here
It's hot, eh?
So sticky
Where's my girl?
Don't worry. She'll come
See the Master?
He stepped out
Hurry, Yae.
Your man's here.
Hello there. Welcome
This her?
Just your type
This is no joke
No good, then?
Look here —-
What are you talking about?
Look at me
I'm freezing to death
Have a drink, then
You're really reliable, Kichi
Nice man
How?
Just look at me
It's pretty sad
Why so sad?
Don't talk to me.
My mother's dead
I'm freezing to death
Get yourself warmed up
Already started?
Hi. Come in
What's your name?
Katsuko
Cute name
A real find, Senta.
Have a good time.
I'll be seeing you
So long
Come again
Senta
Hey, Senta
Is something wrong?
Though all the world betrays me!
I want some sake!
Hurry up
Oh, you big, beautiful man
More sake, Master
Afternoon
Where's your dad?
He's out now
Out? It's hot, eh?
You came to see him?
Well, not exactly
I came to see you
Fresh
I'm serious
Just feel how my heart is thumping
Mama!
What is it?
What happened?
What you want?
I wonder if I could have a shave
Aiko, go inside
I'm afraid I haven't much beard yet
I may not need a shave
I think not
Sit down
Thank you
They're not biting at all, Uncle
Just wait. Take your time
You'll get sunstroke.
Put this on your head
I'm okay
I think you overdid it
Your acting.
You really mugged it up
Nonsense
It was alright
But that character has no meaning now
What's that?
He's unreal
Don't be silly
He's a man of old times
You don't understand
Old-fashioned
What are you talking about?
My audience likes my performance
whether it's old-fashioned or not
Is that all that matters to you?
Stop talking about acting
Look, I've lost my bait again
I heard you wanted to go to college?
Nothing's better than studying
But your mother'll be lonely
Doesn't matter
It does, too
Imagine how she'll feel
Think of her
She's all for it
It doesn't matter
Yes, it does
Don't make her sad.
She's a good mother
You're so clumsy
Was the bath hot enough?
Just right
I'm through now
Put in some more water
I feel so much better
Master not yet back?
Where did he go?
He went fishing
Fishing?
I was having a shave at the barber's
I saw him pass by with a young man
Young man?
Didn't you know?
A mail clerk.
I saw them in the mirror
What happened to your face?
I got a little cut at the barber's
Take a bath, Kayo.
The Master's late
Eat up, folks.
Supper's ready
Get up, time to eat
You're back
Where've you been?
I was with the boys
Good catch?
Fish
Did you catch many, Kichi?
Lots
And he caught a blowfish.
A great big puffer, too
A good catch
We enjoyed it, eh?
Were you really together?
With the boys
Where did you go?
Fishing
Who was the young man with you?
One of my patrons, sons
A mail clerk?
Who told you that?
Never mind
I won't
Who told you?
You seem worried
How come? Strange
- What is?
- Guilty conscience?
About what?
Ah, I get it
Jealous, eh?
Save it, silly.
Save it
Why should I run around
when I have you?
I'm an old man, silly
I'm not young anymore
You know me. Don't you?
I certainly do
You must know something
Why don't you tell me?
I won't tell
Not anyone
What do you know?
Speak up
Look out, Masa!
You've known the Master for years
You ought to know
You've come here with him
long before my time
So tell me.
I'm begging you. Please
Can't help it
Can't help what?
What can't be helped?
And why?
He's bound to go see
his old girlfriend
Really?
As I thought
Who is she?
What is she?
What kind of person?
What does she look like?
Better ask Rokusaburo
He knows her, too?
I see
Roku knows about it, too, eh?
How can you stand this, Master?
Such a small house
Why did we have to come here?
What is it, Roku?
She's out there
Where?
That one
In front of that pillar back there
With a fan
Thanks, Roku
I'll buy you a drink
It's insulting
What's up?
It's awful
What are you grumbling about?
You can't help a small house
when it's small
Rain?
Is that rain?
Yes, it's begun to rain, Master
Well, bad luck never comes alone
Swift is heaven's vengeance
What are you talking about?
Stop complaining
You're boring
I've had enough headaches already
Serves you right.
I knew this would happen
Behave yourself!
Wait a minute
Again?
Let me see
Are you sure?
Check
Wait. Wait
Just a second
Whoa, whoa
The horns of a dilemma
Suppose I dodge
You'll come…
No good, either
Hurry up, will you?
Wait, wait
Hurry up
Hold your hand.
I'll withdraw
There
Good afternoon
Give me some sake
Tell me
Is Master Komajuro here?
Yes, he is
I would like to see him
You have a visitor
Who could it be?
You wait.
I'll get you this time
I don't mind letting you win
I was just pleasing you
Don't monkey with the men
What do you want?
What is it?
I can't come here?
What?
So the lady here
was your important patron?
Where are you going?
I must thank your patron
Don't try to stop me
I must thank you
for all your attentions to him
Thanks so very much
Don't pretend not to know
Go away!
Get going
You!
Are you her son?
Who's your father?
What is he?
Why get so upset?
A nice son you have
I have to tell them something
Let me go! Let go!
You fool! You prize fool!
Be sensible, you fool!
Who's not sensible?
How dare you interfere?
Stop meddling
You have no say in this matter!
What's wrong with seeing my son?
My own son, mind you
Any objections?
Speak up if you have any!
You certainly can dish it out,
can't you?
Shut up
How dare you?
Ingrate
What?
Forget about Okaya?
Who got you out of that hole?
And at Toyokawa, too!
Each time you got stranded
Where would you be without me?
Each time I had to appeal
to the impresario on all fours!
Remember that!
You ungrateful brute!
What?
Shut up
Who are you?
Remember what you were!
You were a common whore!
You came up to me begging!
I turned you into an actress, remember
You ungrateful wretch —-
lower than an animal
You prize idiot, you
I can get along all by myself
without any help from you
Don't make me laugh, idiot
Idiot, you say?
You took the word out of my mouth!
How dare you?
I'll talk. So what?
Alright!
I'm through with you!
I forbid you from that house!
My son is different from you,
mind you
He belongs to a higher class
Don't forget that, you fool!
What's the matter?
It's all but empty
We're miserable failures
We'll all be stranded
Lord Buddha help us
Listen, Kayo
I want you to do me a favor
A young man is working
at the post office here
A good-looking boy named Kiyoshi
Yes? And what about him?
Here
What's this?
Keep it
How come?
Just see this boy
Lead him on a bit
Lead?
He'll fall for you, I'm sure
Do that for me
I'm sorry. I can't
I'm being serious, Kayo
But I don't even know him
Very well
Alright
If you feel that way
Forget it
I don't know that I could do it
You could
I know you could
I have yet to see a man
who wouldn't say yes to you
You really think I could?
I might not
You can
Tell me. Why?
Just try
To see how good you are
Keep the money
Alright. Thanks
Tomorrow, then
Alright. I'll try then
A telegraph blank, please
And a pencil.
- Here's a pen
I can't write with a pen
Please
I saw you on the stage
You did?
Your name is Kiyoshi, isn't it?
How did you know?
A little bird told me
Here. Send it
Come outside to see we．
No. Come outside to see me
Who to?
To you
I'll be right back
Come to the theater
after the show tonight
I'll be expecting you
I'll be right back
Where you going?
To the post office
Some noodles, please
I'm glad you came
I thought you wouldn't come
You're trembling, aren't you?
Me, too
See?
The sky's so blue, it's sad
Don't be silly
I want to eat a big cutlet
I'm really hungry
Oh, for some shrimp
and a bottle of cold beer
With an electric fan turning
Other people are eating right now
That girl at Handa, remember?
She wrote me a letter
I got one, too
The one with the mole?
I got one myself
So we're sharing something, eh?
Oh, no
I saw the barber's daughter
Stop it, will you?
She's no good
No good
By the way'
why is the Master never here?
Where does he go every day?
I see him stepping out every day
I don't know.
No wonder Miss Sumiko's worried.
What became of the manager?
No news from him yet
No news is bad news
No good
Maybe he's run away
Or else he'd be back by now
What if he doesn't come back?
We'll be stranded again
Look at that plane
Come over here
and drop us some cold beer
Can we go on seeing each other
every day like this?
What about your work?
I'm on a leave of absence
And you?
The show's over.
No more performances
Why did it flop like that?
We'll have to part for good soon
What'll we be doing
around this time next year?
Stop talking like that
You'll be married, I think
Of course not
Why?
What about you?
What do you think?
Please. Don't
Why?
Nobody's looking at us
- You mustn't.
- But why?
I'm not really a good girl
Not good enough for you
Don't be silly
At first
I was just leading you on
I didn't know anything about you
Miss Sumiko asked me to
I was supposed to
make you fall for me
Doesn't matter how it began
Doesn't matter at all
So, how about us?
Please
No
You mustn't
You mustn't like me
What's become of the manager?
This is terrible
We mustn't take advantage of
the impresario's kindness
It's awful
Indeed
It's good when it's good
But when we get stranded —-
It's a terrible profession
Isn't Kiyoshi late?
Why is he so late
coming home like this?
Must be with the postmaster
He's been late a couple of nights
Can't help it, then
I'll have to go away soon
So I want to see him while I can
What a mess
You'll be lonely again
Is the next place Shingu?
According to the schedule, yes
I'm not sure now
I've always wanted to
visit Shingu again
But no relative of yours
lives there now, I think
Even the Tsukinoya Inn
is run by someone else now, I hear
Everything changes
It's the way of the world
Tell me.
Who was that woman?
Who?
That woman who came here
Oh, that one.
She's no good
Forgive me
My mistake
I should have known much better.
But by mere chance —-
- Oh, you.
- What is it?
You think I'm jealous?
I know better than that
I know you're a fast worker
Really?
Forgive me
But don't you think
she might tell Kiyoshi?
- Tell him what?
- That you're his father
I don't think so
She won't come here again
But she might see him
That would be terrible, yes
But I don't think she will
So, he's to go on thinking
you're his uncle?
That's right
He mustn't know,
or he'd be unhappy
But —-
Forget it
I'll remain his uncle for life
Wait a minute
Where've you been?
Come here
Come
Who were you seeing?
Who was he?
Speak up!
When did you see him first?
Speak up
Are you deaf?
Never mind who I was seeing.
Leave me alone
What?
What are you trying to do to him?
Seduce him?
You think so, Master?
Yes, I think so
I know what a slut like you
would try
Any excuses?
Speak up
It's only natural
that you should think this
Even Miss Sumiko at first —-
She paid me to try
What?
What did she want you to do?
Tell me what she told you to do?
Forget it.
Doesn't matter now
Speak up! Or else —-
Or I'll break your arm!
She asked me if I'd seduce
that young man
Sumiko asked you to do that?
She did?
You mean it?
Are you sure?
Is it true?
Alright
Bring her here at once
Hurry
Bring her here
Right away
You wanted me?
Come over here
What is it?
What do you want?
You slut
You wanted to ruin my son?
I told you to lay off, didn't I?
I did nothing
A great boy he is,
with an actress for a mistress
Don't say that
Like father, like son
Angry?
Serves you right!
Life's a lottery
You can't always be lucky
I want you to remember that
What?
Remember yourself
You slut
You prize fool
I never want to see you again
Go away
Wait a second
What? Let go
Do you hate me that much?
Don't you see why I had to do this?
You kept that woman from me
Think how I felt
Now we're even
Let's let bygones be bygones
See what I mean?
Let's be friends again
We're stranded
Let's not quarrel now
Shut up
Nothing doing
After all you did,
I'm through with you
Idiot!
Why so quiet tonight?
What is it?
It's awful
Pull yourselves together
- Give me another drink.
- Have any money?
No worry. Right?
Have any?
What?
Money
You know I haven't any
Don't make me laugh
Stop it
Don't paw me like that,
you awful man
Me?
I'm doing nothing at all
What are you talking about?
Awful
Let's get out of here
Where are our drinks?
No money, no drinks
Listen
Why is the Master
hanging on like this?
That manager's
never going to come back
I know.
That's why I've been thinking
About what?
Nothing
What's on your mind?
Tell me
Have you ever done that before?
Yes, once.
With the Omi Company
I see
Me, too.
And you?
- What?
- Not so loud
Let's leave before it's too late
We can use the Master's money
Not me
Listen.
Why must we be so loyal to him?
I disagree with you
Yes, sir.
Though I won't stop you
Not so loud, please
I have a penetrating voice
Though I won't tell on you
Shall we just drop the idea?
Maybe we should
Yes, of course
To treat him like that
After owing him so much
A man who is ungrateful
is not a human being at all
You guys disgust me
I never realized
you two were such bad guys
Even after being together for years
Makes me mad!
I know how you feel
It was ungrateful of us
to think of it
Yes, I guess it was
Naturally
Now, Kichi,
we've changed our minds
Let's be friends
Drop your silly ideas
and try to act like human beings
Very well
I'm sorry
Let's have a drink
Give us three drinks, will you?
Don't worry
Preparing for the worst,
I've laid this aside
So you have a nest egg, eh?
Is that all?
A paper charm
against pickpockets, too
Give us three drinks
Here she is
Give me some sake
Make it hot
Here's our angel
I'll keep this
Evening, Miss Sumiko
So, you've been here, boys
No news from the manager yet?
No, nothing
Chances are he won't come back
What a bad fellow he is
Where are our drinks?
What do you say?
Is that all you can do?
This is the best we can do
That's the very best, mind you
I see
Only that much
Can't help it
Enough for our rail fares
Very well
Was the camera all he took?
And a lighter
Kichi owed me lots of money
Worse for the Master
He had his purse stolen
What a terrible fellow
I'll kill him if I see him
I got sort of suspicious of him
He'd never been straight, either
That's right
He even stole my charm
against pickpockets
He stole all I had
Terrible man!
Tell me, Sensho
What are your future plans?
What is to become of us?
Your cup is empty, Yatazo.
Thank you, sir
I must ask your forgiveness
for all this
But every cloud has a silver lining
I'll tell you when I make a new start
I want you to join me
if you’re free
Where are you planning to work,
Kamenosuke?
My brother-in-law
is running a pickle shop at Hamamatsu
I see
And you?
I think I'll go see
my former employer
He may hire me again
I see
A bath-house owner, isn't he?
Those who can quit the stage
had better do so
You say you'll go to school again?
Yes, sir.
As a working student, if possible
The troupe's breaking up
But I want you
to remember me sometimes
We've had hard times
But we've had good times, too
Master
Let's have some fun.
This isn't a wake
Good idea.
Yes, let's
Why don't you come here
and join us, Miss Sumiko?
This is a farewell party
- What happened to Kayo?
- I wonder
Master
Why can't you be nice
to Miss Sumiko?
Well, old Sensho,
and you, Roku,
we've been together
for a long, long time, haven't we?
Sensho,
he's speaking to you
We've been through thick and thin
I'm afraid I was rather strict
with you sometimes
We've been together for many years
Forgive me
Grandpa
What's the matter?
We're in a mess
What's happened?
We've broken up
My goodness. Really?
The impresario tried to help me out,
but it was all in vain
He's been very kind to me
Why don't you come in?
Where is Kiyoshi?
Wasn't he with you?
No, he wasn't
A young person came for him
with a message from you
Young person?
A girl
And he went out?
Yes. Together with her
What's the matter?
This is terrible
What is it?
Kiyoshi
He's ruined, I'm afraid
What happened?
What did he do?
This is terrible
What in the world did Kiyoshi do?
Tell me
What are you thinking?
Are you sorry?
Of course not
I brought you here
- But —-
- But what?
It was my fault
We shouldn't have come
Why?
You mustn't have anything to do
with a girl like me
I'm not good enough for you
The Master must be angry
Why say that?
Uncle has nothing to do with it
You told me you wanted to go to college
and study, didn't you?
That's good
You do that
Or else you'll be sorry afterwards
Then you're sorry?
I don't need to go to college
I'm going to take you to my mother
She'll consent to our plan
If she won't, I'll —
- Please
Don't do that
Go home like a good boy
Go home to your mother
Please
What for?
Why?
We have to part
For good
What'll become of you?
The troupe's busted up
Forget me
Forget all about a girl like me
I can get along, somehow or other
Don't be silly
Go home, please
Go home
Please
Where did he go, anyway?
Like father, like son
Fast worker
I didn't know that
I thought he didn't take after me
I'm afraid I was too optimistic
about the whole thing
Now it's come to this
All my plans have gone to pieces
Listen
You're imagining too much
Look here
What can you expect
when he eloped with a girl like that?
I mean it
I'm disappointed in him
But —-
I'm sure he'll come back
He's not a bad boy
He'll come back
Think so?
You think he'll come home?
What if he doesn't?
I know.
Yes, I know
But young people today
are so reckless
He'll come back
He's bound to come
Listen
When he comes back,
why don't you settle down?
Tell Kiyoshi the truth
He's old enough to understand
He'll find out one day
He's bound to find out sooner or later
Had we told him before,
this wouldn't have happened
Tell him everything
Tell him
And make this place my home, eh?
I wish you would
Should I?
You will? Thank you
He'll be delighted
But —
Where can he be now?
Do you want a drink?
I'll make it hot
Here he is
Where've you been?
Answer me
I want to ask you something
What is it?
Why, you!
How can you show your face to me?
You fool!
I'm sorry, Master
I'm the sorry one.
You slut!
Don't, Uncle
She's apologizing
What?
How dare you
worry Mother like this?
Don't do that
Shut up
They deserve this
Whore!
- Stop, Uncle
Don't! Please!
What are you doing?
- Well.
- What?
Do you know who this is?
He's your father —-
your real father
Apologize to him
I see
Yes
Just as I thought
Mother,
you told me my father died
when I was little
I believed it.
I still believe it
I don't want a father
I don't need one
Listen
He didn't want you to know
that you were an itinerant actor's son
How come?
Why?
He wanted you to study hard
and become somebody
So he worked hard and sent me
the money for your schooling
That's enough
Stop it
So, Uncle…
why show up all of a sudden?
Mother.
Why tell me this now?
You two are selfish
I don't want a father
Go away
Get going
Forgive me
I knew nothing about it
I'm afraid he's right
Very natural, too
You can't suddenly show up out of
nowhere and then try to be a father
But —-
Why talk like this?
On second thought I won't settle down
It'll be better
Much better for us all
But Kiyoshi isn't mad at you anymore
You see,
I'm going to turn over a new leaf
Let me leave tonight
as though I'm still his uncle
Next time I come back here, I'll be
a good actor he can be proud of
Let me look forward to such a day
Yes, such a day will come
But you —-
Then we'll celebrate
my success and be happy
Master
Take me with you
I'll work hard to help you
I can't leave you like this
Please
Master, I'm begging you
Take me with you
Please
Did you hear that?
Isn't that nice?
Be good enough to look after her
as well
I'm sorry I scolded you
Forgive me
Help Kiyoshi to make good
I'm counting on you
Understand?
Please
The Master —-
Go see him!
Hurry
See him
Will you hurry?
Where's Uncle?
Where is he?
What's happened to Uncle?
Your father?
He's left for the road
Don't stop him
Leave him alone
Each time he came to this town,
ever since you were a baby,
he left just like this
It's alright
But only if you can really
become somebody
Where you going, Master?
Give me a light
Tell me
Where you going?
I don't know where to go now
Do you have any plans?
You have?
Tell me.
Where you going?
Kuwana
Which impresario?
Mr. Kaneyoshi may give me a chance,
I think
Good.
May I go with you?
I happen to know Mr. Kaneyoshi
very well
You don't want me to go with you?
I'm taking a chance
Shall we try?
Yes, let's.
Good idea
- Shall we?
- Sure
Yes, let's.
Let's
Two tickets to Kuwana
Don't forget your things
Like some?