Six fucking car lengths!
That's a hundred and six fuckin feet, mister.
If I had to stop suddenly, you would¡­¡­hit me.
I want you to get a fucking driver's manual¡­¡­
and I want you to study that motherfucker¡­¡­
and I want you to obey the goddamn rules.
Fifty fucking thousand people
were killed on the highway
Last year, because of
fucking¡­¡­assholes like you.
Tell me¡­¡­you're gonna get a manual.
I'll get, get a manual.
Fucking A.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
I' m sorry about that, pete
but taiIgating is one
thing I cannot toIerate.
Yeah, I can see that.
Wait a minute.
Thanks, Mister Eddy.
No...thank you.
I' m bringing the Caddy
by tomorrow.
You Iike pornos?
pornos.
Give you a boner?
Ah. No. No, thanks. No.
Suit yourseIf, champ.
WeII, uh, I-I' II see ya, then.
You wiII.
Damn.
Lou...
You recognize that guy?
Yeah.
Laurent.
What do you want?
Wanna go for a drive?
I don ' t know.
Get in, bady.
Come here.
Why don ' t you Iike me?
I do Iike you.
How much?
SheiIa. SheiIa.
What' d ya change it for?
I Iike that.
WeII, I don ' t.
I' m Ieaving the Caddy,
Iike I toId you.
Sure. Uh, you want to
pick it up Iater on, or, uh,
or in the morning?
WeII, if you think you can
finish it, I' II be
back Iater today.
It' II be done.
You ' re my man, pete.
"'This magic moment...
so different and so new
Was Iike any other...
untiI I met you
And then it happened...
it took me by surprise
I knew that you feIt it too
I couId see it by the Iook
in your eyes
Sweeter than wine
Softer than a summer' s night
Everything I want I have
Whenever I hoId you tight
This magic moment whiIe your
Iips are cIose
to mine wiII
Iast forever"'
HoIy smokes.
Hey.
I' m AIice WakefieId.
pete Dayton.
I was here...earIier.
Yeah, I remember.
How' d you Iike to take
me to dinner?
I don ' t know, an...
Okay.
Why don ' t I take
you to dinner.
Look, uh, I don ' t think
this is a very good idea.
Do you have a phone?
Yeah. It' s right,
it' s right there.
I have to caII myseIf
another taxi.
HeIIo.
CouId I have the number
for Vanguard Cab?
HeIIo. Yes, I need a taxi.
Arnie' s Garage,
the corner of Fifth...
HeIIo. Uh, yeah, we' re not
gonna need that cab. Thanks.
Maybe we shouId just
skip dinner.
Take my cIothes off.
Fucker gets more pussy than
a toiIet seat.
I want more.
Me too.
Can I caII you?
Yeah. CaII me at home.
I' II give you the number.
Okay, baby.
Up here.
Come on up...baby.
I aIready got the room.
I' II get it.
HeIIo.
Meow, meow. It' s me.
Hey, baby.
I can ' t see you tonight.
Okay.
I have to go somewhere
with Mister Eddy.
Sure.
I think he suspects
something. We have
to be carefuI.
I miss you.
ptet?
Me too.
I' II caII you again.
What a fucking job.
His or ours, Lou?
Ours, Hank.
Sit down a minute.
What' s wrong?
Sit down.
You don ' t Iook so good.
No, I just, uh....
I just have a headache.
What' s going on?
The poIice caIIed us.
What' d they want?
They want to know
if we had had a chance
to find out what happened
to you the other night.
And they want to know
if you remembered anything.
But I don ' t
remember anything.
What' d you teII them?
We' re not going to
say anything about that
night to the poIice.
We saw you that night, ptet.
You came home with
your friend SheiIa.
SheiIa?
Yeah. There was a man
with you.
What is this? Why didn ' t
you teII me anything?
Who' s the man?
I' ve never seen him before
in my Iife.
What happened to me?
pIease. pIease, Dad...
TeII me.
pete!
Hey. Mister Eddy.
Hey, pete...
How you doing?
I' m okay.
I' m sure you noticed
that girI that was with
me the other day.
Good Iooking bIonde...
she stayed in the car?
Her name is AIice.
I swear I Iove that
girI to death.
If I ever found out somebody
was making out with her...
I' d take this...
and I' d shove it so far up
his ass it wouId come out
his mouth,
And then you know
what I' d do?
What?
I' d bIow his fucking
brains out.
Hey. You ' re Iooking good.
what you been up to?
I' II get it.
HeIIo.
Meet me at the StarIight
HoteI on Sycamore
in twenty minutes.
He' II kiII us.
How do you know that?
You ' re positive that...
he knows?
I' m not positive,
but he knows.
So?
What are we supposed to do?
I don ' t know.
If we couId just
get some money, we couId
go away together.
I know a guy.
He pays girIs to party
with him.
He' s aIways got a Iot of cash.
He' d be easy to rob.
Then we' d have the money.
We couId go away.
We couId be together.
Have you partied with him?
Did you Iike it?
NO. It was part of the deaI.
What deaI?
He works for Mister Eddy.
Yeah. And what' s he do?
He makes fiIms for
Mister Eddy.
pornos?
Yeah.
How did you get in with
these fucking peopIe, AIice?
pete...
No, pete. I wanna know
how it happened.
It was a Iong time ago.
I met this guy at a pIace caIIed
Moke' s. We became friends.
He toId me about a job.
In pornos?
No. Just a job.
I didn ' t know what.
He made an appointment
for me to see a man.
I went to this pIace.They
made me wait there forever.
There was a guy
guarding the door.
In another room there
was this other
guy Iifting weights.
I started getting nervous.
When it got dark...
they brought me into
this other room.
Why didn ' t you just Ieave?
You Iiked it, huh?
If you want me to go away,
I' II go away.
I don ' t want you
to go away.
I don ' t want you to go away.
I Iove you, AIice.
ShouId I caII Andy?
Andy?
That' s his name. Andy.
Our ticket outta here.
Yeah. CaII him.
I' II set it up for
tomorrow night.
You meet me at his pIace
at eIeven o' cIock.
Don ' t drive, take the bus.
Make sure no one foIIows you.
His address is easy
to remember.
It' s two-two-two-four
Deep DeII pIace.
White stucco job on the
south side of the street.
I' II be upstairs with Andy.
The back door wiII be open.
Go through the kitchen
into the Iiving room.
There' s a bar there.
At eIeven-fifteen I' II send
Andy down to fix me a drink.
And when he does you crack
him in the head, okay?
Okay.
You ' re fucking somebody
eIse, aren ' t you?
SheiIa.
You fuck me whenever
you want.
SheiIa, SheiIa, stop it.
You don ' t caII.
Who is she?
Stop it.
What' s the bitch ' s name?
I' m sorry.
Oh, you ' re sorry.
Go home.
You ' re sorry?
SheiIa...
You ' re sorry? You piece of
shit. You ' re sorry?
Stop it. Go. Go...home.
Fuck you.
Stop it, SheiIa.
Stop...SheiIa.
Fuck you.
SheiIa. SheiIa.
Fuck you. Fuck you.
SheiIa. SheiIa. SheiIa.
SheiIa, stop it.
Let' s both go in and taIk
about this quietIy. SheiIa,
SheiIa, come on.
You are different.
SheiIa.
TeII him. TeII him.
SheiIa. Don ' t, Don ' t.
I don ' t care anymore,
anyway.
I' m sorry, Mister Dayton.
I won ' t bother you...
or any member of your
famiIy ever again.
pete?
There' s a man on the phone.
He' s caIIed a coupIe
of times tonight.
Who is it?
He won ' t give his name.
HeIIo.
Hey, pete. How you doing?
Who is this?
You know who it is.
Mister Eddy.
Yeah. How you doing, pete?
Okay.
You doing okay.
That' s good, pete.
Look, um, it' s Iate,
Mister Eddy. I, uh...
I' m reaIIy gIad to know
you ' re doing okay.
You sure you ' re okay?
Everything aII right?
Yeah.
I' m reaIIy gIad to know
you ' re doing good, pete.
Hey, I want you to taIk
to a friend of mine.
We' ve met before, haven ' t we?
I don ' t think so.
Where is it you think
we' ve met?
At your house.
Don ' t you remember?
No.
In the East, the far East,
when a person is
sentenced to death,
they' re sent to a pIace
where they can ' t escape...
never knowing when
an executioner may step up
behind them...
and fire a buIIet into
the back of their head.
What' s going on?
It' s been a pIeasure
taIking to you.
pete, I just wanted to
jump on and teII you that
I' m reaIIy gIad you ' re
doing okay.
"'He' s been Iurking about
the church
A year it' s been since
he' s aIone
Grief deprived him of
aII his senses
SIeeps every night
near her stone"'
You got him.
AIice.
We kiIIed him.
You kiIIed him.
AIice.
AIice? AIice?
What do we do? what do we do?
We have to get the stuff.
We have to get outta here.
An, fuck.
Is that you?
That' s...me.
Honey, are you aII right?
Where' s the bathroom?
It' s upstairs. Down the haII.
Did you want to
taIk to me? Huh?
Did you want to ask me,
"'Why"'?
What' s the matter?
Don ' t you trust me, pete?
Stick this in your pants.
I know a fence.
He' II give us money
and passports in exchange
for aII this shit
and Andy' s car.
And then we can go anywhere.
Come on, baby.
pete, you drive.
Where the fuck are
we going, AIice?
We have to go the desert,
baby.
That fence I toId you about?
He' s at his cabin.
Come on.
We' II have to wait.
Why me, AIice?
Why choose me?
You stiII want me,
don ' t you, pete?
More than ever.
I did aII
my best to smiIe TiII
your singing eyes and fingers.
Drew me up into your
eye and you sang
Said to me , Said to me
Here I a...m, Here I am
Waiting for you,
Did I dream,
You dreamed about me
Were you he...re, when I was"'
"'Now my fooIish goaI
is Ieaving Broken off"'
"'For you sang...touck me not"'
I want you.
"'Touch me not, come...
back tomorrow
Oh, my..."'
I want you.
"'...heart, Oh, my heart
Shines from a song"'
I want you .
I want you, AIice.
You ' II never have me.
Here I am.
Where' s AIice?
AIice who? Her name is Renee.
If she toId you her name
is AIice, she' s Iying.
And your name.
What the fuck is your name?
LOST HIGHWAY HOTEL
Renee?
Yor' re coming with me.
What do you guys want?
"'He' s been seen Iurking
about the church
Now you can hand it back.
you and me, mister,
we can reaIIy out-ugIy
them sumbitches, can ' t we?
Ed.
Take a Iook at this.
Yeah, that' s her, aII right.
That' s Fred Madison ' s
wife with Dick Laurent.
Yeah, and Mister
Dent-head over there.
We got pete Dayton ' s prints
aII over this pIace.
You know what I think, Ed?
What is it, At?
What do you think?
I think there' s no such
thing as a bad coincidence.
Dick Laurent is dead.