"Huayi Brothers Media Corporation and
Huayi Brothers International Limited present"
"a Film Workshop Co Ltd and
Huayi Brothers Media Corporation production"
"a Tsui Hark film"
"In 689 A. D.,"
"upon Emperor Tang Gaozong's death,"
"Empress Wu, a regent for 7 years,"
"would soon be coroneted"
"as history's first female emperor."
"Royal clansmen and founding officials"
"resented a woman usurping the throne"
"and colluded"
"to overthrow her reign."
"Behind its peaceful facade,
the capital was lurking with danger."
"All hell was about to break loose. . ."
< Detective Dee
and the Mystery of the Phantom Flame >
The Empress hereby decrees:
The Court of State Ceremonials shall
welcome Umayyad diplomat Aspar
and escort him to the Towering Buddha
to revere the Empress's divine glory.
The Buddha is sixty six yards high,
which means there are thirty three heavens
beyond the first thirty three heavens,
symbolizing reaching the ninth cloud.
I already explained it to the General.
Will it be ready before the Coronation?
Sure, otherwise. . .
my life cannot be spared.
This is so spectacular!
Huge resources have been spent on this.
2 million catties of metal were used.
More than 1 000 catties are burnt each day.
The temperature is too high here.
Bring water and a towel for the General!
The General asked of whom the portrait is.
This is Lu Li, our Imperial Chaplain.
He's very potent and trusted by the Empress!
These are amulets bestowed by the Chaplain.
They can dispel evil and thwart disaster...
It's unbearably hot inside the Buddha.
We need to drink at least 2 liters of water a day.
We have to report this!
This is serious and we should do it
before lives are lost!
Shatuo, you better go.
Let's go up from here.
Today's so clear we can see miles from here!
This tubular pillar is crucial to the Buddha.
It's 72 yards long and made from one casting.
It is surrounded by. . .
81 steel chains.
In the face of hurricanes or earthquakes,
the chains will pull in the opposite
direction to prevent collapsing.
General, these are the Buddha's two eyes.
Master Jia... Master Jia. . .
Don't you see we have guests here?
Please. . .
- What's the matter with you?
- When you...
inspected the pillar yesterday,
you removed some amulets.
Should we put them back?
They haven't been put back?
Moving the amulets will bring bad luck, so...
After you have moved them,
- we all feel so scared that. . .
- I know.
nobody dared to put them back.
Our work has been stuck.
Put them back right away. Hurry up!
It's needless to say.
This way, please.
The General says we can see
the coronation stage here.
The General says...
Sir... Sir...
Master Jia
"Produced by Wang Zhongjun"
"Producer Wang Zhonglei"
"Executive Producer Nansun Shi"
"Executive Producer Peggy Lee"
"Starring Andy Lau"
"Starring Carina Lau Li Bingbing"
"Starring Deng Chao"
"Special Appearance Tony Leung Ka Fai"
"Action Director Sammo Hung"
"Executive Producer Chen Kuo Fu"
"Produced & Directed by Tsui Hark"
Master Xue.
Yes. . .
Sir, the corpse has been burnt to ashes.
No flesh was left.
So strange?
We must find out the cause of the fire.
Any forensic findings from the corpse?
Sir! We found this on the corpse.
Phosphorus! The corpse is filled with it!
Much phosphorus is stored inside the Buddha
to melt the copper.
I bet this gave the murderer the opportunity
to use what's already in the scene.
Master Jia was burnt by yellow phosphorus!
No, not the phosphorus.
The flame exploded from inside the body.
Pei? How could the flame explode from inside?
Sir, look at his shoe.
The bones were burnt to ashes
and left inside the shoe,
but its outside remains unscathed.
The flame must have been burnt from inside.
Otherwise, how could this have happened?
Perhaps not!
But the corpse is dense with phosphorus.
Someone must have poisoned his food!
Phosphorus stinks. He couldn't miss it.
Even if he had taken it by mistake,
the symptoms should be. . .
shortness of breath and bodily pain,
but not be aflame.
Cut the crap. The murderer is among you.
Nab them all back for interrogation!
Sir... Sir.
Don't panic!
We can continue our work after the interrogation.
You... the supervisor.
Sir, if you arrest me,
our work will be delayed and we're doomed.
What's in your left hand?
What is this? What happened to your hand?
I was punished by the Ministry of Justice
and had been jailed for eight years
for involving in Detective Dee's treason.
Treason?
A dork like you in treason?
Then you had to be involved.
Sir, if the Buddha can't be finished on time,
the Empress will blame us.
Supreme Court won't be better off either.
You dare to threaten us with the Empress?
Good. I'll give you want you want.
I'll chop your right hand off as well.
He was struck by divine intervention!
Master Jia was struck by divine intervention!
Out of my way!
You bugger, cut this crap!
What superstition are you trying to say?
What divine intervention? Spit it out!
Master Jia moved the amulets
during his inspection a few days ago.
Bestowed amulets should never be moved.
Stop spreading these fallacies!
Amulets? Can't be moved?
Let me do it.
What's up? You want to try too?
Do you believe it?
Let me move one and you'll all see
if divine intervention would strike me now!
Nab all those who went to the top today
and take them back.
Handcuff them up at the main gate.
Donglai, you come with me to the Palace
and report the case to the Empress.
Everybody else guards over here.
Arrest them all when you've order
from the Empress.
Yes, Sir!
Your Majesty, General Yao just entered,
leading 200 soldiers from Longzhou.
Following behind is General Qiu,
with an army of 600 to protect Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, Master Xue of Supreme Court
and his subordinate Pei request an interview!
Let them approach!
Your Majesty, Pei Donglai of Supreme Court.
Regarding the torched death of Jia Yi,
- my preliminary investigation indicates. . .
- He's on fire!
What's wrong with Master Jia?
How come he's on fire?
- Protect Her Majesty!
The Empress hereby decrees:
2000 more Guards shall be garrisoned
inside the palace.
Those without permits shall be killed
without reprieve.
The Palace becomes so dark by night.
Fire is not allowed in the palace any more.
All flames were replaced by night pearls.
Nobody knows what had happened to the Empress.
All food and drinks came from outside...
and they all turned cold
when delivered to the Empress.
We all worry about her.
Your Majesty... Your Majesty.
I don't want to smell that again!
The coronation is imminent.
Your Majesty should mind your health.
I've even ordered your favorite soup.
You don't need to test-eat anymore.
Leave that to your subordinates.
Your Majesty has to rule the world.
I live and die for Your Majesty.
Remember you have to stay alive.
Only then can you defeat your enemies.
Since I entered the palace at the age of 14,
I've braved through crises after crises.
Had I been careless, I'd have been crushed
I would never think of ascending
the throne by a woman.
Your Majesty, dinner is safe to eat.
Your Majesty, the Imperial Chaplain is here.
- Hurry up... - Where?
Everything is transient;
follow Heaven's Mandate.
Welcome, Chaplain. Everyone, on your knees!
Yes, Your Majesty.
The astronomical phenomena have been chaotic.
An evil availed of my spiritual sabbatical
to disturb the royal soil against nature.
Would the Chaplain please enlighten me?
The evil has been committing crimes
as Venus has left the Palace for 8 years.
It's being locked up and has not returned.
Locked up? Is Venus a prisoner?
Venus originated from Yang Qui of Dee City.
Left the Palace for 8 years?
Originated from Dee City?
Does the Chaplain mean Detective Dee?
8 years ago, Dee opposed your regency
and was jailed for treason.
If we release him,
the dissenters will become more recalcitrant!
Please think twice, Your Majesty.
As soon as Venus has returned,
chaos will end and all stars are at peace.
Find out whether Dee is dead or alive?
May I know who you are?
"MINISTER OFFICE"
Welcome, Officer Shangguan.
LIAISON OFFICE, for filing provincial memorials
The East needs 6,000 soldiers
to suppress the barbarians.
The South reported floodings along Yao River.
Memorial to Public Works Dept.
The South has been such a mess lately.
After the flood came the starvation.
Tie your tongue and get the memorials.
Here come the memorials. Talk later.
The earlier we burn them, the earlier we can rest.
Memorials are prescriptions for the state.
We know the state's illness by reading them.
But the memorials in recent years show that
people are living in contentment.
people's livelihood has improved
and they are living in contentment.
You might as well save your breath.
Ling. . .
we might get involved this time.
What?
Listen.
Yes!
I hear that! Quite a number of men. . .
You said if you were to leave here alive,
you might have to fight a big battle. . .
A battle of life and death.
Do what I taught you.
Yes, I'm ready for it.
Push the cart down.
20cm to the left!
1 cm below!
Turn around and swing. . .
Do it again!
Surround the furnace!
Get them alive!
Don't let anyone flee!
Protect the Officer!
Get lost!
There's ambush on the roof!
Hidden arrows! Bend over!
Nab them alive! Check who they are!
They're killing themselves as their last resort.
Don't let the assassins jump! Stop them!
Help me to grab them back from the furnace.
Yes.
You! Go after the archer on the roof!
Didn't you hear? Go after the archer!
Yes.
No need to chase.
They can come and go at ease
in this maximum security prison,
They must be abetted by someone inside.
Nonsense!
How can the killers be our men?
They can even kill themselves in the end.
The leader behind is way too powerful for you.
Perhaps not for her.
This official is elegantly dressed
with an impressing bearing.
I bet you're from the Palace.
No need. He's really blind.
Why did you feign blindness?
A peaceful heart will enhance my observations.
To observe by heart is different from by eye.
You're speaking my words.
A blind like him
sees the world clearer than we do.
Forget it, Dee.
You are no longer a prisoner.
Can I call you Detective Dee now?
Good or bad luck, only I myself will know
This furnace is very hot
but it's nothing when compared
to the outside world.
A single mistake will make myself on fire.
If I don't leave, the fire will also come for me.
Struggling for power starts the fire.
No power means no fire, heaven for everyone.
The outside world is really on fire now.
Watch out for fire!
Military examination in the year 689!
On the right is Chen from Xiangzhou;
his weapon will be the iron rod.
On the left is Yen from Yangzhou;
his weapon will be the meteor hammer.
The tournament begins!
Your Majesty, Dee has been brought here.
You knew you're coming to see me,
but you're still in prison clothes
and you didn't even shave?
Years ago when I opposed your regency,
I had already been accused of treason.
Now that your coronation is imminent,
I might have to put them on again soon...
So I decided not to change.
Leave us alone, Jing'er.
Yes.
The Crown Prince was very little then.
I helped him rule as an Empress Dowager.
What's wrong with that?
And yet you had to oppose.
During my rule for the last 8 years,
the state is incorrupt and the people rich.
Even the Crown Prince begged me
in writing to ascend the throne.
What more can you say?
Nothing.
You men are just not used to women in power.
One can't be conservative in state matters
but has to reform constantly.
Reform is good,
but all new things will turn old one day.
While the old are being replaced by the new,
if it also involves their lives as well,
then rebellions become inevitable.
Not only men. . . even dogs will try to flee.
Detective Dee is still Detective Dee.
Your precious words are so hurtful to the ears.
That was your badge 8 years ago.
I'm returning it to you.
You shall be my Imperial Commissioner
in charge of the Phantom Flame Case.
You shall work with Supreme Court
to crack the case before my coronation!
Why do you keep following me?
Her Majesty knows you've suffered in jail
and specifically ordered me to serve you.
You have such a deadly look.
It must be a pain to be served by you!
So lively here?
Who's having dinner in the inn?
The Prince of Lanya is having a banquet.
Li Xiao commands an army of 1 00,000
and is haughty because of his royal status.
He is at loggerheads with the Empress
and has long intended to revolt.
He must be involved in this case.
You better check him out.
Having the intention to revolt
does not mean he's involved in this case.
You better get it right.
These are your clothings before you were jailed.
Her Majesty ordered me to find these for you.
Only my Dragon Taming Mace is missing.
It's getting late and I won't go out any more.
You don't have to keep an eye on me too.
Have you forgotten?
Her Majesty has ordered me to serve you.
Without the order from the Empress,
I will not go back tonight.
To serve me. . .
Where's the water?
That's how you serve people?
How can the Empress stand you?
You are too weird to serve people
and you're so impetuous.
Yes, I am.
I've given you the blade.
Come, shave for me.
Stop dodging if you have guts!
The Empress asked you to serve me,
but don't take it in face value.
She wants you to spy on me but also to test you. . .
For every single word you've said,
I'll report to Her Majesty.
All right, let me tell you this.
She always overestimate herself and
she does not believe in anyone.
If we really become together,
her suspicion will turn her against you.
She won't let you off.
Why do you stop shaving?
My beard is not there. . .
It's here.
I suggest you tell her we can't get along.
That will set her mind at peace.
Let me see if she is what you said she is.
Don't make it difficult for yourself.
If you don't want it, don't force yourself.
But do you want it?
Come over!
What do you want?
Hold this.
Why didn't you tell me sooner?
I gave you the whip. You still didn't get it?
Don't touch me.
Who are these people?
- Protect the Prince!
- Assassins!
I've been waiting for you, Brother Dee.
Why aren't you on your knees?
I'm chasing suspects. No time for formality.
The Phantom Flame was staged by
the Chaplain under the order of the Empress!
She wants to usurp the throne
and eliminate old officials like us.
I'm occupied. See you later!
Dee, receive the Military Tally!
With this tally, you can deploy any troops.
In view of your loyal nature,
I'm inviting you to join my Army of Justice.
I'm in command of 1 00,000 soldiers
and have a fail-proof plan
to overturn the evil empress!
- Assassins? Who is it?
- Who is it?
That's outrageous.
Li Xiao!
How dare you rave like that?
I won't chat with you now that she's here.
But remember, one of these days...
you'll grovel before me
and take my orders.
It won't be far.
Grovel before me and take my orders...
You'll ruin your integrity.
He must have ordered the kill just now.
Why kills me if he wants to buy me off?
He wants you dead as he can't buy you off.
No.
No?
He doesn't want me dead.
It's someone else who does.
The Empress hereby decrees:
Mysterious cases are rampant lately.
Theses are works of villains to cheat people.
I hereby appoint Dee as Imperial Commissioner
to lead Supreme Court
to solve the Phantom Flame Case
before my Coronation.
I humbly receive the Imperial Edict.
Commissioner, you do have a unique style.
You bring your bird out while on duty?
I must bring this along with me.
We can't solve the case without it.
Where does the sun go this morning?
This is the mortuary. This way, please.
The bird is afraid to go in.
Find someone outside to take care of it.
The deceased was Jia of the 4th rank,
Vice Minister of Public Works.
On the 1 7th day of the 8th month, 1 -3pm. . .
he was self-burnt to ashes. . .
- inside the Buddha,
- What do you think of this case?
leaving remains of...
- Go watch over the bird outside.
- left fibula...
I was ordered to follow you closely.
You want to return this badge to the Empress?
Just keep an eye on it but don't touch it.
Don't get too close too!
Shut the door!
Keep reading.
The deceased was Xue of the 3rd rank...
Louder!
You can speak now.
The murder technique is not human.
Cut the generality. You're not to the point.
Who do you think it is?
Rumor has it that the Chaplain Lu Li
is on a murder spree before the Coronation
to set an example.
To warn the dissenters
not to act rashly.
Jia was sent by the Empress. Why betrayed her?
He's unfathomable.
I read Jia's memorials before.
He inspected the Buddha every month.
The schedule for the Buddha is very tight.
Wouldn't killing him hinder the Coronation?
You read Master Jia's memorials?
I read memorials at the Liaison Office
before they were burnt every day.
Moving the amulet causes divine intervention.
The Chaplain is killing with black magic.
You believe all this nonsense?
It's evident. Why can't I believe it?
You're lying.
We both know the amulets are just a front.
The murderer is trying to hide the truth.
I thought only I got that.
So you also think likewise.
She's still spying on us.
Let's play her.
What I think of is. . .
you'll be promoted after Xue died.
That makes you a suspect as well.
Then why do you think I killed Master Jia?
You killed Master Jia as a diversion.
Your real target is your superior.
You may have another reason for killing Jia.
You can also thwart the Coronation.
Don't stop.
I'm done. . .
Start again till I ask you to stop.
The deceased Detective Dee
had a fierce fight with Minister Pei...
You're framing me!
Didn't you ask us to play her?
Why are you so serious?
I was acting. Couldn't you tell?
Master Pei, the birdcage is on fire!
Sir... the birdcage is on fire, Master Pei!
What's the cause?
No cause at all.
The bird is aflame
like those officials.
How could this have happened?
Let's go to the dining room.
What are you cooking?
Stir-fried cucumbers with snow lotus.
Any chicken blood?
Over there.
What's he doing?
He probably found out why the victims caught fire.
Master Xue caught fire at 3-5pm?
Right.
The Buddha was surrounded by shadows
as the sun decended.
But once he entered the drill ground,
he's on fire.
It is because the drill ground was not covered.
So I infer that the sun triggers the poison!
Let's stay away from this.
Detective Dee!
Fancy seeing you again before I die!
We're kept alive for a purpose.
You're back in Supreme Court?
The Empress put me in charge of
Dee's position is unclear.
We can't let him dupe us.
Let's join forces to check him out.
Join forces?
I work directly under the Empress.
It's not up to you to make suggestions.
What's the matter?
Before the accidents, both officials
did one thing besides
moving the amulets.
What is it?
Water!
Before the incidents took place,
they both drank the water here.
It is because the heat here
make them thirsty.
But that can't be! I was supposed
to move the amulet first.
Master Xue just happened to come before me.
If the murderer killed because of the amulet,
how did he know Master Xue would snatch it
and poison the water beforehand?
It should have nothing to do with the water.
You work directly under the Empress.
Do you need to hear my humble opinion?
How have you been all these years?
After I was in jail,
I kept professing my loyalty in writing.
Eventually the Empress pardoned me.
I joined the Department of Public Works,
in charge of repairing royal palaces.
I was then made supervisor of the Buddha.
In other words, I've been promoted.
How magnificent!
The Tubular Pillar in the Book of Fanyanna?
Yes, I was inspired
by the Fanyanna Buddha.
The pillar's base is 1 00 feet underground.
It can withstand earthquakes
and hurricanes.
This is the top level of the Buddha.
Master Jia died inside the Buddha's left eye.
You were also re-enacting the case?
After working under you for so many years,
I've been used to case re-enactment.
So what do you think?
Fire turtles...
What are fire turtles?
Are they related to this case?
You also read Book of Fanyanna.
Remember the section on fire turtles?
You think so too?
You haven't answered my questions!
The most venomous beetles in Western Regions.
They feed on yellow phosphorus
and their bodies catch fire under the sun.
So the beetles are related to the two deaths?
I witnessed what happened that day.
Only later did I think of the fire turtles.
You think!
Stop it, Donglai!
You knew this clue all along.
Why did you rant about divine intervention?
As a menial
I used my wit when threatened.
To be honest, even if I'd told you my theory,
given your wisdom, you wouldn't believe it.
Bullshit!
Calm down. I've known him for years.
That's how he is.
Come!
Detain him for extreme torture later.
Yes!
Stop it!
The Empress has asked me to lead the case.
I can decide everything without intervention.
All of you stand down!
What other clues do you have? Spit it out!
I'm only speculating.
After all, fire turtles are not indigenous.
For more details
we need help. . .
Phantom Bazaar.
What is Phantom Bazaar?
It's a spooky pandemonium.
High officials like you would never go there.
Shatuo
you still remember Donkey Wang?
Luoyang City was built
a thousand years ago.
The old city subsided during Han Dynasty.
A new city was built on top in Sui Dynasty.
The underground became
a black market.
They call it Phantom Bazaar.
Who ordered a boat?
We are looking for Dr Donkey Wang.
You know the place?
Wang the Donkey with Scabies?
Five silver coins. Nonrefundable!
Anybody here?
Who's been so noisy? It's hell here.
I've never seen in a true villain here.
Speak up.
One... Two. . .
you're still alive, Dee!
Scram! This is no place for you people!
I'm here to save you.
Save me? No, I'm fine!
I don't want trouble!
It's you who are in trouble. Cut the crap.
- Yummy... yummy.
- Now that I'm here
your good days are over.
Dee, you always bring me troubles.
My luck will help me overcome them.
Since you're here, I better move out now.
Don't be so mean!
Pei! Give me the money!
Put it right here.
Look what I've got here.
What exactly do you want to know?
Ever heard of fire turtles?
Fire turtles? This creature. . .
It has been reported that they're extinct.
Could it be they exist in Central Plains?
Can you see
the power of money?
You won't solve this case! Don't even ask.
You haven't answered me. Answer again.
- I've answered but you didn't take it.
- Up there.
You don't believe in me at all.
- What's that sound?
- Then why. . .
asked me?
Pay more for additional questions.
Better settle the old bills first.
I'll pay after you've told us.
But you're not trustworthy.
Don't worry about this.
I promise I'll pay after you've told us.
Something is still above!
What are you looking at?
Dee is chasing Dr Wang! I'll go to see it.
It's the Imperial Chaplain!
Impossible!
Split! Can't you split? Split!
Jing'er is in trouble! I'll help her!
Donglai! Jing'er! Run!
Who is this Wang?
Why does the Chaplain want to kill him?
He's not the Chaplain!
How can you be so sure?
I'm sure because I've seen the Chaplain before.
You don't believe in me?
Hey! The Chaplain is over there!
Told you he isn't.
You're so stubborn.
Don't chase. Something weird.
Why?
But Jing'er is by herself...
She wants to find his identity more than we.
Their target is Wang. We need to protect him.
Jing'er knows where to find us.
Stop wasting time and let's go!
Jing'er
Almighty infinity?
Infinity Monastery?
There's nobody here. Stop pretending.
Take your pins out.
Dee, you shouldn't put your fingers in every pie.
I was fine down there.
Why dragged me up?
Speak up! Where can we find fire turtles?
If I can crack this case,
I'll help you get back to the Palace.
To hell with it!
Who wants to go back? Did I say it?
I advise you not to take up this case!
You can't mess with the people behind it.
It can't be done. . . and then. . . and then. . .
Look!
Your transfiguration makes you inarticulate.
Let me see.
Don't touch
these two acupoints!
They are anathema to transfiguration!
Don't you know that?
Don't touch me!
What's the matter?
Nothing. These acupoints
remind me of someone.
Who is it?
It's all right. It's Donglai and Jing'er.
Who is he?
The Imperial Physician, Wang Bo.
A. K.A. Donkey Wang.
He's Donkey Wang?
Could that be the so-called transfiguration?
Well, it's my first time.
That's petty stuff. What's so special?
We wasted our whole evening on him.
What's this piece of crap good for?
Who is she? So arrogant!
Officer Shangguan, the Empress's favorite.
So you are Shangguan Jing'er?
You are the Empress's bitch?
Bitch?
Speak up! Tell me all you know.
Let go of me!
We need torture to make him talk!
A confession under torture is useless.
The Empress created many cases of injustice
because of torture and this will only
alienate people from her.
The fire turtles you're looking for
were used for the late Emperor's asthenia.
I heard about them from Western people
and decided to use them to treat asthenia.
I presented a memorial to the late Emperor.
The late Emperor personally commanded
Western merchants to present him 20 of them.
We soon discovered that
they had no medical value
but a very lethal poison.
Once ingested, one would burn under the sun.
That's the symptom of the Phantom Flame Case!
After this failure, I fled for my life.
Before I fled, I exposed them under the sun,
hoping they would be exterminated.
But in a rush, I'm not sure if they died out.
So where did you keep the fire turtles?
It's where Infinity Monastery is now.
You try to frame Infinity Monastery
You're mongering rumours. Let me kill you now.
Jing'er,
the Chaplain can help this case.
Can you tell him
I want to talk to him?
I want to ask the Chaplian face to face. . .
why he wants me to handle the case.
The Chaplain is so powerful.
Couldn't he just tell me who did it?
The Chaplain is on spiritual sabbatical.
Then I'll go to the Monastery to find him.
Detective Dee, you can't just go there.
I know,
without the Imperial Edict,
trespassers will be killed.
Please tell the Chaplain I must see him,
whether he wants to or not.
You're swayed.
How dare you help him pass the Chaplain a message?
Apparently, Dee is at the end of his tether.
No need to see him anymore.
I'll handle it myself.
Remember! To achieve greatness,
everyone is expendable!
One needs to be committed absolutely.
If fire turtles are found in the Monastery,
then the Chaplain has to be involved.
But what's the Chaplain's murder motive?
Both men moved the amulets before they died.
I don't believe in divine intervention,
but there might be a clue behind the amulets.
Xue moved it during investigation;
Jia moved them while inspecting the Buddha.
I think during his inspection,
Jia must have found something.
The clue...
may be in Jia's inspection diagram.
We have to find this diagram.
Pei of Supreme Court welcomes the Prince!
Detective Dee, receive the mace. . .
The late Emperor gave you this weapon.
It was confiscated when you were in jail.
After I got hold of it, I've kept it for you!
I give you back as I hope you still
respect the late Emperor.
Dee, I'm bestowing this mace on you.
If I make mistakes in my rule in future,
you should advise me frankly with this mace.
The Empress has informers everywhere.
And you are returning the mace to me in public.
You want the Empress...
to suspect me?
My agreement with the Empress
is for investigation only.
Power struggle is none of my concern.
The bitch was right to put you in jail.
You've become an obedient dog.
Dee, do you know how the late Emperor died?
The Empress ordered the Chaplain to kill him!
Detective Dee!
Get up! Detective Dee!
I've won!
You Highness, you've won this time!
No matter how good Dee is, he can't beat you!
He kneeled before you after all.
Detective Dee is a talent.
- Instead of crushing him, we can win him over.
- That's right.
But some of our people believe
he's a threat and must be eliminated.
Nonsense! So short-sighted!
Who needs force to subdue Detective Dee?
To win without fighting, what do you need?
Here!
Since you're here, why not show up?
This is the mace the late Emperor gave you?
What's so special about it?
It can detect the crack in a weapon.
How?
By hitting the enemy's weapon with this mace,
you can hear the crack...
When you strike it, it will break!
Men have weak points like weapons.
They will break when struck.
Dee, this is your last chance!
Your Majesty,
please answer me facing this mace.
How did the late Emperor die?
You still suspect me after all?
As reported, he died of liver disease.
Contrary to rumors, I didn't poison him!
I'm ascending the throne on Heaven's Mandate.
But since I'm a woman, I'm being vilified.
You know why I came to see you?
To dissuade me from going to the Monastery.
The Monastery is the Chaplain's retreat.
And it is also where the spiritual energy
of our Kingdom lies.
Nobody ever dared to disturb it.
I order you not to investigate the Monastery!
The Chaplain is on spiritual sabbatical.
After my coronation,
he will leave the palace.
There's no need to visit him.
Will the Chaplain vanish forever?
Master Dee
Something bad happened.
Who is it? Get down and say your visiting purpose.
I'm Pei from Supreme Court.
Her Majesty has ordered
the visitor to see her immediately.
Please report to me directly.
Pei from Supreme Court
humbly welcomes the Empress.
What's so urgent that
you have to report at midnight?
I've just received the news that
the Prince... was poisoned to death. . .
in his residence.
Detective Dee has fled!
Archers! Move Quickly!
He's gone to the roof top! Outflank him!
Go arrest him and the rest stay for the Empress.
Yes.
I think during his inspection,
Jia must have found something.
The major clues of this case
should be in Jia's inspection diagram.
Madame Jia, I know you're in mourning,
but our investigation is very urgent.
My apologies for such a late visit.
- Let's go. - Yes.
Two days after my husband's death,
a mysterious fire broke out
and burnt down his whole study.
Why didn't you report it?
I have no idea about this.
Was I supposed to report it?
Of course, the cause of fire is suspicious.
Someone wants to destroy the evidence.
It's so important and you...
- Madame...
Is your residence being under renovation?
There are leaks everywhere at the study.
So, we're fixing the roof earlier.
It's been going on for more than a month.
More than a month?
That means before Master Jia's accident,
renovation has already begun.
Correct.
During the long renovation of the study,
where did Master Jia work?
He moved to the east wing for work.
Show me the way.
Detective Dee!
You know it's a capital crime to come here.
Why do you walk right into the trap?
But you Chaplain are such a lofty personage.
Why do you need to resort
to ventriloquism?
Detective Dee! You tried all means to see me.
Here I am. Say what you have to say.
I heard fire turtles were bred here.
I must ascertain this for my investigation.
Nonsense.
I've been in retreat here for years.
I've never seen any fire turtles.
Leave right away and I'll spare your life.
My life or death is still undetermined.
But Jing'er, your life is in real danger.
Am I right, Officer Shangguan?
Under the Empress's instructions,
you threw yourself into my arms
and tried to have sex with me.
But you gave away the show unexpectedly.
You wouldn't let me touch your acupoint...
That smacked of transfiguration.
When I entered the Monastery just now,
You spoke for the deer with ventriloquism.
Every time the deer appeared,
it's you who spoke for it, right, Jing'er?
In Phantom Bazaar,
you knew right away the Chaplain was a fake.
Is it because you're the same person?
Jing'er, it's time to show your real face.
In order to ascend the throne,
the Empress eliminated clansmen and old officials.
But she never knows that the Phantom Flame case
is so complicated.
In order to crack the case,
she even brought me back for it,
never expecting that I would suspect her.
She told me the Chaplain would disappear
after her coronation.
That's her way of doing things all along.
To achieve greatness, everyone is expendable!
Jing'er,
You know too many of her secrets.
Once the Chaplain's gone, what about Jing'er?
It's ecstacy scent.
Break!
Remember!
To achieve greatness, everyone is expendable!
I told you not to come here but you did!
Don't think I'll be grateful
because you've taken the sword for me.
You smart ass!
They should be snared!
Where are they?
Couldn't be far.
Go find them!
You're awake.
It's good you woke up.
Did I hurt you?
Detective Dee, you're so pathetic.
The world is so big, but you can't fit in.
Why does everybody want to kill you?
The Empress also asked me to kill you,
but I cannot.
Can you take me back?
Your guess is right on track.
The Empress set up Infinity Monastery
to use the Chaplain to eliminate dissenters.
At that time, we did kill many people.
But we didn't cause the Phantom Flame!
The murderer will strike again.
You have to help the Empress!
Find out who the real culprit is.
Her Majesty is here!
I humbly welcome Your Majesty.
Call the Imperial Physician! Hurry up!
Go find the Imperial Physician immediately!
Yes, Your Majesty.
Stand down.
Yes.
Call the Imperial Physician.
Can I ask you one question, Your Majesty?
Go ahead.
Have you ever
loved one person in your life?
Yes.
But the price was too high.
So. . .
was it worth it?
Was it worth it?
It's worth it.
Jing'er.
Detective Dee!
We don't have time. No need to untie me.
I know why Jia had to die.
I saw his inspection diagram.
That Buddha...
will be used to kill the Empress.
Rein buckle. . .
With the righteous sky above me, I am fearless.
Like the sea waves,
the new always supersedes the old.
I am the only one who dare to challenge
the tradition.
You, the witch Empress
has upturned our whole Kingdom.
But I will be the one
who destroy all your venomous plans.
I know the winner takes it all.
And the heaven above will help me
fight for justice.
Today
at day break
let's see how I combat with you.
It's the signal.
Let's start!
This is the inspection diagram by Master Jia.
Pei found it in Jia's residence.
Jia found out the Tubular Pillar is different
from the original design.
According to Jia's memorial before his death,
holes were found underneath all amulets.
Although he did not know the reason,
he was murdered nonetheless.
The Towering Buddha is 66 yards high,
overlooking the palace.
It can fall right upon the coronation stage
The Coronation Ceremony is the best timing.
Xue's death was a camouflage.
You wanted to divert our attention,
linking the death to the amulets,
blaming it all on the Imperial Chaplain.
You also took advantage of our relationship,
preempting my every move.
Be it to Donkey Wang or to the Monastery,
you managed to set up ambushes beforehand.
So I am sure that
it's you who killed Jing'er outside the Monastery.
I would never underestimate your ability.
Dee, what more do you know about this?
Six years ago, you were the supervisor
when the Monastery was under renovation.
I discovered the remnants of the fire turtles
left by Donkey Wang.
Donglai was right.
The poison entered the body through water.
Jia drank the water
but Xue did not.
After he snatched the amulet,
he didn't drink any water.
So the poison must have come
from outside.
The poison must have seeped through his body.
Dee, what else do you know?
Stop it, brother!
It's baneful to the empire and the people.
Don't make continuous mistakes.
Since 8 years ago,
I have made up mind long time ago.
I've only lived for one thing.
She gave me this; I have to repay her!
I know you will be back.
Getting in here is easy but not going out.
Archers.
Kill him!
Tubular pillar...
Molten fluid. . .
8 years ago, you led a revolt against her.
Now you're giving your life for her.
Why did you go back on your words?
If you destroy the palace like this,
many more officials will be killed
at the same time.
So you'll be killing more than her.
Release the molten fluid!
The die is cast.
The fluid will run into the tubular pillar
and melt its base.
The Buddha will fall upon the coronation stage.
No one will survive in the Palace.
I know you too well.
I heard you were brought back for the case,
so I advised the Prince to kill you,
or you would ruin our plan.
But that old fool refused to listen.
He even called me a flunkey,
so I killed him.
1 00,000 soldiers are outside the city.
Once the Buddha falls down,
they will enter the city to kill the bitch.
Even you can't survive this.
Break!
The fluid will run into the tubular pillar
and melt its base.
The Buddha will fall upon the coronation stage.
No one will survive in the Palace.
The time is ripe and Heaven has spoken.
Empress Wu is wise, gentle and generous.
For unification, she shall become Emperor.
Let this be known to the world!
Detective Dee. . . You can't get out!
Once the Buddha falls down,
I'll let you be buried with the bitch!
Shatuo, your plan has failed!
I can't stop the Buddha from collapsing,
but the fluid from the southwest has stopped.
The angle of the collapse will change.
It won't fall upon the coronation stage.
Oh!
I haven't failed!
After the Buddha has fallen,
the guards will be in panic!
I'll now go to the palace and kill her myself.
Shatuo! Give up!
This is your last chance!
Your Majesty!
The Towering Buddha is wobbling.
It's falling towards the palace.
Please take shelter, your Majesty!
I'll go to see it.
How could this be happened?
Is it an omen?
Run! The Budda is collapsing!
I haven't failed
Go check what happened.
Is it really collapsing?
Your Majesty, it's not safe here
and please leave at once.
Your Majesty!
Protect Her Majesty!
- Protect Her Majesty to leave here immediately!
- Protect Her Majesty
The Buddha is falling towards the palace.
Hey!
It's falling towards you. Don't go that way!
Go save the Emperor
It's Detective Dee who saved me. . .
A rebel army is gathered 30 miles from here.
They will invade once the Buddha collapses.
Where's General Yao?
Yau is here!
Report the situation outside the city!
60,000 Imperial Guards
were in ambush in Bianzhou before daybreak!
Call General Zhang to lead 1 00,000 soldiers
to attack the enemies in the east
until the rebels are totally demolished.
Yes, Your Majesty.
You were well prepared indeed.
Detective Dee,
from this day onwards,
the whole world shall know you're my savior.
May I venture to say a few words to you
in front of the mace?
Preposterous!
Stand down.
Your Majesty!
I asked you to stand down!
- Stand down, everybody! - Yes
Under Heaven, with this mace as the witness,
would the sacred Empress Wu please listen:
On the pretense of magic,
you wantonly killed clansmen and officials.
This is unpardonable!
But society is on the brink of extinction,
So your punishment is hereby suspended.
Ruling requires power and stratagems,
but right and wrong cannot be confused!
May the Emperor know her every move,
and let Tang clansmen succeed her,
so that everything will be back to track.
You called me "Emperor"?
Long live the Emperor! Long Live!
Officials are lazy; nobody can help me.
For the people, you stay and help me.
I've been in rebellion several times.
How dare I meddle with state affairs?
My assignment is over.
I'm returning this mace to the late Emperor.
The truth has come to light...
The world is at peace finally. . .
But Detective Dee is in Phantom Bazaar.
Whether your fire turtle poison is curable
will depend on the will of Heaven.
The will of Heaven is bright and clear,
but I'm travelling alone.
Heaven and Earth have no space for me,
but my heart is at peace.
The sun is up. Let's go down.
"In 690 A. D.,"
"Empress Wu became the first and only"
"female emperor in the history of China."
"1 5 years later, in 705 A.D. ,"
"Empress Wu retired from the throne,"
"returning the title to the Crown Prince,"
"in honor of her promise to Detective Dee."
"Co-starring
Richard Ng Teddy Robin Yao Lu Liu Jinshan"
"Screenplay by Zhang Jialu"
"Cinematography by
Chan Chi Ying Chan Chor Keung HKSC"
"Image Designer Bruce Yu
Production Designer James Chiu"
"Edited by Yau Chi Wai
Additional Editing Xiao Yang"
"Music by Peter Kam
Sound Supervisor Wang Danrong Zhao Nan"
"Vfx Producer Edward Chiyun Yi Chang Ik Jeong"
"Vfx Supervisor Yong Gi Lee Sang Woo Nam
Miniatures Director Andy Ma"
"Co-Producer Bernard Yang
Co-Executive Producer Zhang Dajun"