(Man) 'They will say that I have shed
innocent blood.
'What's blood for
if not for shedding?
'With my hook for a hand
'l'll split you from your groin
to your gullet.
'l came for you.'
(Woman) This is the scariest story
I've ever heard
and it's totally true.
'lt happened a few years ago
near Moses lake in lndiana.
'Clara was baby-sitting
for the Johnsons
'and Billy pulls up
on his motorcycle.
'She wasn't even
going out with Billy.
'She was going out with Michael
for about six months
'but she always kind of had
the hots for Billy
'because he was like a bad boy
'and Michael was...
he was just so nice.
'So anyway, she decides
that tonight's the night
'that she's going to give Billy
what she never gave to Michael.'
Have you ever heard of Candyman?
No.
His right hand is sawn off.
He has a hook jammed
in the bloody stump
and if you look in the mirror
and you say his name five times
he'll appear behind you,
breathing down your neck.
You want to try it?
'So Billy began.
'He looked in the mirror,
and he said...'
Candyman...
No one ever
got past four.
Not here.
Go downstairs.
I have a surprise for you.
'She looked in the mirror
'and I don't know why
'but she said his name
the last time.'
Candyman.
'She turned out the lights...'
(Clara screaming)
...and what he saw turned
his hair white from shock.
Killed her.
Split her open with his hook
and then killed the baby too.
And Billy got away
but soon after,
he went crazy.
My...my roommate's
boyfriend knows him.
So when did you first hear this story?
My friend heard it on the radio.
It's true. Sick, huh?
The baby-sitter just roasted the kid
like it was a turkey or something.
So, what's the deal?
You guys doing a page
on serial killers?
Something like that.
Well, that's it.
We're done.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
See you.
(lmitates young man)
(Chuckles)
Seems like they're getting
younger every day.
(Man) Does anybody remember
the craze for the pet baby alligators?
(Woman) When they got too large to keep
people flushed them down the toilet.
They live in the sewers.
Some or them are 30 feet long.
- Where did this happen?
- In Miami.
They went blind and albino
from living in the dark.
(Audience laughs)
(Boy) It wasn't Miami. It was New York.
I read it in the paper.
Then it must be true.
(Audience laughs)
Why would Danny and Diane
both be suffering
from the same delusion
in two cities
over 1 ,000 miles apart?
Let's face it, folks.
There are no alligators in the sewers.
No, it's...it's round the campfire.
It's bedtime stories.
See, these stories are...
modern oral folklore.
They are the unselfconscious reflection
of the fears of urban society.
(Bell ringing)
That's lunch.
(Man) Like the primordial reptile
it's formed into a monster. Why?
Ouch! Oh...
- The dashing professor.
- The lovely wife.
Helen, you
know everybody?
Crème de la crème...
Harold, Diane, Danny, Stacey.
- Hi.
- Hello.
So, keep up the good work.
Thank you for your contributions.
- Thanks. Bye.
- Awesome lecture.
Bye.
See ya.
So, you want to tell me
about this girl?
What's her name? Stacey.
She could barely look me
in the eyes, Trevor
and she was blushing.
Well, I guess it's because
she's madly in love with me.
All those bursting
adolescent hormones.
- You don't really think...
- No, of course not.
Good. I should hope not.
So, what's the matter?
Trevor, you promised
you wouldn't do
the urban legends lecture
until next semester.
You knew Bernadette and I
were gathering data.
Why did you have to ruin it?
I love you dearly
but I can't hold up their education
while the two of you
complete your thesis.
I have a curriculum
to follow here.
Yes, I know.
Well...so don't
be mad at me.
(Woman) 'lf you look in the mirror
and say his name five times
'he'll appear behind you,
breathing down your neck.'
(Typing)
Can I clean your room?
Oh, sure. Don't mind me.
'So Billy began.
'He looked in the mirror
'and he said, "Candyman,
Candyman, Candyman..."'
Candyman, huh?
Yes. Have you heard of him?
- You doing a study on him?
- Yes, I am.
What have you heard?
Everybody scared of him
once it get dark.
He live over at Cabrini.
My friend told me about him.
Cabrini Green?
Yeah, in the Projects.
I live on the South Side
so I don't know much about it.
But my friend know all about it.
Her cousin live at Cabrini.
They say he killed a lady.
Can I talk to your friend?
Sure.
Kitty?
- Yeah, what do you want?
- Lady down here want to talk to you.
All right.
She coming.
I'm Helen Lyle.
Pleased to meet you.
Henrietta Mosely.
And this is Kitty Culver.
Tell her what you told me
about the Candyman.
All I know is there was some lady in a tub,
and she heard a noise.
Do you remember her name?
Her name was Ruthie Jean.
She heard banging and smashing like
somebody was making a hole in the wall.
So Ruthie called 91 1 .
She said, "Somebody is coming
through the wall."
And they didn't believe her.
They thought the lady
was crazy, right?
So she called 91 1 again
and they still didn't believe her.
When they finally got
there, she was dead.
Was she shot?
No.
She was killed with a hook. Schhht!
(Henrietta) It's true.
Yeah, I read it in the papers.
(Henrietta) Candyman killed her.
(Kitty) Yeah, but...
I don't know nothing about that.
(Bernadette) Helen, this is sick.
This isn't one of your fairy tales.
The woman got killed here.
That's not the half of it.
That's Cabrini Green
not that you'd recognise it today.
Yeah, no kidding.
I won't even drive
past there.
- A kid got shot there the other day.
- Everyday.
OK, now look carefully
at this picture
and then this one.
You spot it?
No.
That's not Cabrini Green.
That's this building,
Lincoln village.
My apartment was built
as a housing project.
No.
Yeah.
Now take a look at this.
Once finished the city realised
there was no barrier
between here and the Gold Coast.
Unlike over there
where the highway
and the el train
keep the ghetto cut off.
So they made some
minor alterations.
They covered the cinder block
in plaster
and sold the lot off
as condos.
How much did you pay
for this place?
Don't ask.
Now, wait till you see this.
Here's the proof.
The killer, or killers...
they don't know which...
smashed their way through
the back of this cabinet.
See? There's no wall there.
There's only a medicine chest
separating us from
the other apartment.
Hey, hey, what are you doing?
There could be somebody on the toilet.
- No, the apartment is vacant.
- Are you sure?
There.
OK, now take a look.
(Bernadette) That is amazing.
- What?
- There's somebody there. I saw a light.
There's nobody there.
Psych.
That's not funny.
- You didn't scare me at all.
- Yeah, right.
Ow.
You don't believe
all that nonsense, do you?
I don't. Do you?
No.
All right.
(Both) Candyman, Candyman,
Candyman, Candyman...
...Candyman.
Oh, you chicken!
You have to do it five times.
Come on.
- (Helen) I did it.
- (Bernadette) Better safe than sorry.
(Rattling)
Trevor?
No, no!
What's the matter?
Oh, Trevor!
Who were you expecting?
What time is it?
It's late and I'm smashed.
Sorry I scared you.
What's with the arsenal,
Bernadette?
We're only going eight blocks.
You're the one who got us
dressed up like cops.
I just said dress conservatively.
We look like cops.
Why are you trying to scare me?
I'm not trying to scare you.
I just want you to think.
The gangs hold
this neighbourhood hostage.
OK, let's just turn around then.
Let's just go back
and we can write a boring thesis
regurgitating the usual crap
on urban legend.
We've got a real shot here,
Bernadette.
An entire community
starts attributing the daily horrors
of their lives to a mythical figure.
Now, if Trevor and Archie were in on this
do you think they'd chicken out?
In a second.
Exactly.
All right.
- You want to wait here for me?
- No.
Well, let's go.
(Helen) And lock the car.
(Man) Hey now.
Want something, baby?
I got it for you.
Yo, baby...
Which way you going?
Just going inside.
Yeah?
Hey, come up in here.
Who you looking for?
A friend of ours.
Sure you not the police?
Look like five-oh to me.
Ask blondie where she going.
Who you going to see?
Let's take the stairs.
Come on.
(Boy whistling)
Hands up, people!
Five-oh coming up
the back door.
It's OK
they think we're cops.
They're not going to follow us.
Hang on.
Look at this.
This is great.
(Bernadette) "Sweets to..."
(Helen) "...to the sweet."
(Bernadette) "Sweets to the sweet."
Hurry up, Helen.
Let me just get the door.
(Barking)
Sorry.
Jesus, Helen.
- Here it is.
- Don't go in there.
Come on.
Jesus, it stinks.
See, I was right.
The layout is identical
which means the bathroom
is over there.
- Helen...
- What's the problem?
A woman died in there.
Leave it.
It's all right.
There's nothing to see.
Wait a minute.
This is where he crawled
through, right?
Yeah.
Well, we found it.
Let's go.
Wait a second.
OK, hang onto this.
What?
I'm just going to go through
and when I get back,
we're out of here.
You've got to be kidding.
It's just a derelict apartment.
What if somebody's
packing drugs in there?
You just going to apologise
and give them your card?
All right, let's listen.
(Helen) There's nobody in there.
OK, but hurry up.
Be careful.
Give me the camera.
You've got five minutes.
OK, five.
(Camera motor winding)
Dammit.
Bernadette...
I ran out of film. I've got to back.
- No way.
- You can't believe...
No way, Helen.
We're out of here.
What you all doing in there?
We're just leaving.
You here for the sweep?
No. We're not cops.
We're from the university.
Well, you don't
belong here, lady...
going through
people's apartments and things.
I'm Helen Lyle
and this is Bernadette Walsh.
We're doing a thesis
and were wondering if we could
talk to you for a few minutes.
Here, this is my card.
(Baby crying)
My baby.
Come on.
Come on, let's go.
You know, whites don't never come
here except to cause us a problem.
Believe me that's not what we want to do.
Let's go in.
So you say you're doing a study?
What you gonna say?
That we bad?
We steal?
We gang-bang?
We all on drugs, right?
We ain't all like them
assholes downstairs, you know?
I just want to raise my child good.
He's a beautiful little boy.
And he's all I got.
- What's his name?
- Anthony.
I'm Anne-Marie.
Anne-Marie McCoy.
Nice to meet you.
Sorry we disturbed you.
We'll just get out of your way.
It's OK.
I mean, I don't mean
to be rude, and it's...
you know, it's just...
the white folks
that come around here
ain't too hand-shaking
with us, you know?
(Spitting up)
- Hey, what you doing?
- Let me help you.
You making
a mess here?
Thank you.
Thanks.
You got kids?
No, but I'd love one.
Hey.
Got my eye on this one big time.
Yeah.
They're not going to get him.
You want to know
about Ruthie Jean?
They all been here,
you know.
Newspapers, cops,
case workers...
They all want to know.
I heard her screaming.
I heard right through the walls.
I dialled 91 1 .
Nobody came.
Everybody scared.
He could come
right through these walls,
you know?
I'm scared.
Scared for my child.
They ain't never gonna catch him.
- Who?
- Candyman.
(Man laughing)
(Man) lf they asked for something, if they
saw something they liked, and you point...
They thought
it was rude to point.
So what did
they do?
(Grunting)
Spat over people.
It was quite extraordinary.
- Be nice.
- I am being nice.
So, how are the two most beautiful
graduate students getting along?
Trevor tells me you've been
dabbling in my favourite subject.
I can't wait to review your data.
I can fit you in tomorrow morning.
We're not ready yet.
That's precisely the moment
in which I can be
of greatest assistance
before you disappear down
a path to academic Bolivia.
(Trevor) I've been there.
Actually, Purcell,
we're about to bury you.
- Helen...
- What?
We'll have something
in a week or so.
It's just that we only
went to Cabrini today...
Ah! Cabrini Green?
Candyman country.
Well, if you're after
the hook man, Helen,
you must read the paper
I wrote about him ten years ago.
You do know the story,
don't you?
No.
Then how are you going
to bury me?
The legend first appeared
in 1 890.
Candyman was
the son of a slave.
His father had amassed
a considerable fortune
from designing a device
for the mass producing of shoes
after the civil war.
Candyman had been sent
to all the best schools
and had grown up
in polite society.
He had a prodigious talent
as an artist
and was much sought after
when it came to
the documenting
of one's wealth and position
in society in a portrait.
Well, it was in this
latter capacity
that he was commissioned
by a wealthy landowner
to capture his daughter's
virginal beauty.
Well, of course,
they fell deeply in love
and she became pregnant.
Poor Candyman.
Her father executed
a terrible revenge.
He paid a pack of
brutal hooligans to do the deed.
They chased Candyman
through the town to Cabrini Green
where they proceeded
to saw off his right hand
with a rusty blade.
No one came to his aid.
(Distant screaming)
But this was just the beginning
of his ordeal.
Nearby there was
an apiary.
Dozens of hives,
filled with hungry bees.
(Distant crying and pleading)
They smashed the hives
and stole the honeycomb
and smeared it over
his prone, naked body.
Candyman was stung
to death by the bees.
They burned his body
on a giant pyre
then scattered his ashes
over Cabrini Green.
Hello.
Anne-Marie ain't in.
Are you sure?
Yeah. She said you'd be back.
What's your name?
Jake.
Listen, Jake, maybe
you can help me out.
I wanted to find out about
that woman who got killed.
Do you know
anything about that?
Her name was Ruthie Jean.
I don't know nothing.
Did anybody else talk about it?
You know, it's OK
to talk to me, Jake...
because I'm not a cop
so nobody's going
to get in trouble.
I can't say nothing
or Candyman will get me.
Candyman?
You scared of him?
I ain't scared of nobody
but you're crazy
walking here on your own.
It ain't safe around here.
Yeah, I know.
But I don't scare
too easy either, Jake.
You know,
you don't have to tell me.
You could just show me.
And if you show me
where Candyman is
I'll make you a promise.
It will be our secret.
Unless you're too scared.
Somebody building
a bonfire?
Yeah, for the party.
In there.
Candyman's in there?
My friend Charlie say so.
A boy got killed there.
- Who was he?
- Ain't sure.
Charlie tell me he was weird.
He was crazy?
No, a retard.
His mom was in the store...
and the boy, he need to go,
you know, to the bathroom.
His mom was
taking her time
choosing this,
looking at that
so the boy start moaning.
His mom get mad at him
send him across the street.
His mom is at the checkout.
She hears her boy screaming.
(Screaming) Mommy!
Mommy!
There's a big tough guy.
He runs over to check it out.
He come out of there
shaking and crying.
He only been in there five seconds.
Come out of there
and his hair turned white.
I mean, it turned white
just like that.
Was the boy murdered?
Worse.
He's lying on the floor
in a pool of blood holding himself.
(Screaming) Mommy! Mommy!
They found it floating
in the toilet.
Can't fix that.
Better off dead.
Did Candyman do this?
Listen, you wait here for me, OK?
OK.
Hello?
(Coughing)
(Buzzing)
Candyman.
Oh, excuse me.
I'm done here.
I'll just get out of your way.
Listen, I don't want
to interfere with your business.
I'm not a cop.
I'm from the University of Illinois.
I'll just get out of your way.
Come on!
Let me go!
You're not being very smart.
My colleagues know where I am
and they're expecting me back.
Now let me go!
I hear you looking
for Candyman, bitch.
Well, you found him.
(Helen moaning)
(Men laughing)
We hear you're looking
for Candyman, bitch.
Step back.
Number four
step forward
and say the line.
We hear you're looking
for Candyman, bitch.
Step back.
Number five
step forward
and say the line.
We hear you're looking
for Candyman, bitch.
Step back.
Take 'em out.
It's number five.
Good work.
How d'you catch him?
We swept the place.
We start from the top floor
and work our way down.
That way you can
flush 'em all out.
Whole of Cabrini
is locked down now.
You're very lucky to be alive,
Ms Lyle.
Did he kill Ruthie Jean?
No question.
Killed that poor kid as well.
He ran the overlords.
We knew everything about him.
Only reason why we didn't
bring him in before
because we couldn't find
anyone to testify.
We can't protect them
down at Cabrini Green
and they knew that.
What about
the little boy...Jake?
We don't need him.
We have you.
Hey, Jake.
I just wanted
to thank you for saving my life.
I wanna go home.
We'll get you out of here.
You did good.
You said it was our secret.
You lied!
It still is, Jake.
You won't have
to go to court.
Candyman will get me.
Candyman isn't real.
He's just a story.
You know, like Dracula
or...or Frankenstein.
A bad man took his name
so he could scare us.
But now he's locked up
everything's going to be OK.
Candyman ain't real?
No.
Hey there!
Whoa. Slow down.
You're supposed
to be the invalid here.
Look, see?
It's much better today.
Yeah, it looks great.
Come sit down.
You haven't eaten already?
No, of course not.
OK, good.
(Bernadette) Hey!
Welcome back.
Thanks.
Let me see.
I'm so glad you're OK.
But you know what bugs me
about the whole thing?
Two people get brutally murdered
and the cops do nothing.
A white woman gets attacked
and they lock the place down.
This was a bad guy.
You got him put away.
That's what matters.
Oh! I've got
a surprise for you.
What?
You're not going to believe it.
The pictures.
My friend in
the photography department
managed to save most of them.
I'd written them off.
The camera was smashed.
(Door opens)
I've been talking
to some publishers
and there's a lot of interest
since you made the local section.
We're going to be published.
I'll come over
tomorrow at 9:00.
- We'll get started?
- Yeah.
(Horn honks)
(Deep, resonating voice) Helen...
Yes?
Helen...
Who is that?
I came for you.
Do I know you?
No...no...
but you doubted me.
I'm sorry.
I have to go.
No need to leave yet.
But I'm late.
You were not content
with the stories
so I was obliged to come.
Be my victim.
I am the writing on the wall
the whisper in the classroom.
Without these things
I am nothing
so now I must shed
innocent blood.
Come with me.
(Woman screaming)
(lncoherent screaming)
(Hysterical crying)
(Woman) No!
Anthony!
No! No! No!
No, Anthony!
Anthony!
(Hysterical screaming)
Anne-Marie?
No! You did it!
You! You did it!
You murdered my baby!
(Screaming)
You murderer!
No! No!
Stop! Please, stop!
(Screaming)
Now stop!
Stop!
Police! Open up!
All right,
hold it right there!
Back away! Now!
(Screams)
Look out!
(Helicopter flying overhead)
Remove your sweater.
(Weeping)
Drop it and slide it over to me.
Take off your brassiere.
Can I please take a shower?
Oh...
Oh, God...
Drop it,
slide it over to me.
Lift up your arms.
(Crying)
Lift your left breast.
Your right.
Remove your underwear.
Can I please speak
with detective Valento?
Remove your underwear.
Frank.
Ms Lyle, you're under arrest.
Do you understand?
Please let me explain.
Yes, but...
You have the right
to remain silent.
Do you understand?
This is crazy.
I was attacked.
Respond to the question.
I understand.
(Frank) At approximately 1 0:00 pm.
Anne-Marie McCoy
returned to her apartment.
She discovered her dog
with its head cut off.
She cried for assistance
at which point you attacked her
with a meat cleaver.
You were still in possession
of this weapon
when the arresting officers
came to her aid.
(O'Malley) Where's the baby?
I...l don't know.
You're sick.
(Frank) Before I ask any
further questions
would you like
to have counsel?
(Pounds hand on table)
Yes or no?
I...l'd like to make a phone call.
(Ringing)
(Phone continues ringing)
(Trevor) I'm sorry,
we can't take your call.
Please leave a message
after the tone.
(Tone beeps)
Trevor, are you there?
Pick up.
It's an emergency, Trevor.
Pick up the phone.
I've been arrested.
I'm at the 1 8th district.
Can you...
can you please come pick me up?
That's it.
Do you know what time it is?
3:00 am.
(Door clangs shut)
(Keys jingling)
(Cooing)
(Anne-Marie crying hysterically)
Noooo!
No!
(Door being unlocked)
Oh, God.
There's got to be
another way out.
(Attorney) Cover her face.
Don't say anything.
(Trevor) OK.
(Attorney) All right.
You'll be fine.
(Reporters shouting)
Just keep your head down.
It's going to be fine.
All right, people,
back off, back off!
We have no comment.
No comment.
Nothing to say.
Do you know
the baby's whereabouts?
My client has
not been charged
with a thing!
(Woman) lnformation has indicated
that baby Anthony was abducted
and may still be alive.
The blood may have come
from the dog.
A suspect was released
this morning after questioning
and I guess we'll just
have to follow this one...
Well, at least they didn't
mention your name.
That's good.
Now, they haven't charged you,
because they think
they'll find the body
which means, I'm afraid
they're shooting for murder one,
but I don't think they have a chance.
Do you think I did it?
No. Nobody believes that.
But it's crossed your mind?
Is there anything,
any detail, however small,
that you can recall,
that would help us substantiate
your version of events?
I...l blacked out.
I mean,
I don't know what happened.
I just woke up in that place
and there was blood everywhere.
Can I get you anything?
Are you sure?
Look, honey...
I was supposed to go to the campus
and pick up some work.
I'm concerned about
leaving you alone though.
I'll only be
about 20 minutes.
Trevor...
Where were you last night?
I was here.
I was fast asleep.
I thought you were
with Bernadette.
Look, honey...
I'm going to stand by you.
We're going to get through this OK?
I'll be right back.
(Door closes)
(Screams)
Believe in me.
Be my victim.
Do you believe in me?
Keep away from me.
I have the child.
Allow me to take you
or he will die in your place.
Your disbelief
destroyed the faith
of my congregation.
Without them,
I am nothing.
So I was obliged to come.
And now I must kill you.
Your death will be a tale
to frighten children,
to make lovers cling closer
in their rapture.
Come with me
and be immortal.
(Groans)
Helen?
Bernadette...
Bernadette, go.
Helen?
Helen, honey.
It's Bernadette.
Let me in.
He's here.
Bernadette, go!
Helen!
Helen?
(Helen) Go! Get out!
(Moans)
(Helen) Oh, no, no....
(Bernadette screaming)
(Flesh ripping)
(Candyman grunting)
(Footsteps approaching)
Trevor...
Trevor, he's here.
He's here. He's...
...here.
(Thinking) Don't let him kill me.
Trevor...
Trevor!
Trevor! Trevor!
(Moans)
Take her outside.
Trevor...
Hold me, Trevor, please?
(Dispatcher) 'That's correct.
'Unit 212, come in, please.'
(Candyman) 'Why do you want to live?
'lf you had learned
just a little from me
'you would not beg to live.
'l am rumour.
'lt is a blessed condition,
believe me.
'To be whispered about
at street corners,
'to live
in other people's dreams
'but not to have to be.
'Do you understand?'
(Baby crying)
(Helen) 'Please, God,
'don't let him kill the baby.'
Trevor!
Trevor?
Where are you going?
No, you can't leave me here.
I can't defend myself!
No.
What do the good know
except what the bad teach them
by their excesses?
Murderer.
Allow me at least a kiss.
Just one exquisite kiss.
(Crying)
Murderer!
Help!
Listen, he's under the bed!
Bring me 1 ,000 mils!
Listen, he's here.
He's under the bed!
No, don't.
(Baby cooing)
(Coughing)
She's coming around.
Good morning.
I'd like to speak
to my husband.
(Chuckles)
So would l.
Here we go.
What time is it?
Where are we going?
We're going to Disneyland.
Clyde, open it up.
Winley?
What the hell you all
doing back there, huh?
A little reading?
Break.
Dr Burke?
Yes?
Miss Lyle,
I'm Dr Burke.
(Door opens, closes)
I'd like to speak to my husband.
I'm sure we can arrange a visit.
A visit?
Have I been committed?
Do you really think
these restraints are necessary?
Helen, this...
is a writ of detention
from the state
attorney's office.
Now, for
the past month...
- Month?
- Yes.
...we have been stabilizing you
on a heavy dosage of Thorazine.
You probably remember
very little or nothing.
Get me my attorney.
I'm working for
your defence.
We have to assess
your ability to stand trial.
Helen, you've been charged
with first-degree murder.
Why don't you tell me
what happened in your apartment?
'Oh!'
The night
you were admitted
did the killer
appear to you?
'Murderer!
'Help me!
(Grunting)
'He's here!
'He's under the bed!
'No!
'Help me!'
I don't understand.
'Help! Please!
'He's here!
'Help me! Help me!
'Please!
'He's under the bed!
'He's under the bed!'
That's not possible.
(Man) 'Bring me 1 ,000 mils!'
Bernadette...
I'm not capable of that.
No matter what's going wrong...
I know one thing...
...that no part of me,
no matter how hidden
is capable of that.
I can prove it.
How?
I can call him.
Candyman...
...Candyman.
(Grunts)
(Flesh ripping)
Oh! Oh!
(Yelling)
(Grunting)
You're mine now.
Tonight our congregation
shall witness a new...miracle.
(Flesh tearing)
(Alarm ringing)
(Woman) Dr Burke?
(Knocking)
Dr Burke?
Dr Burke!
Please answer us!
(Grunts)
Code nine to ward b-5, stat.
Check the west wing.
Let's go!
Go, go, go!
Do we have a direction on this one?
Where is she?
(Elevator bell rings)
Please be home, Trevor.
Please be home.
(Creaking)
Get out of my home.
(Agitated) Trevor!
What's the matter, sweetie pie?
Did you make another little boo-boo?
What are you doing here?
I live here, remember?
Call the hospital.
Don't touch the phone.
What's the matter, Trevor?
Scared of something?
I hate the color scheme.
What were you going to do?
Wait till I got out
before you told me?!
Helen...
But you knew
I was never coming out,
didn't you?
I think we should call the hospital.
OK.
(Dial tone)
Go on.
Is that what you want to do?
Call them.
I'm not a murderer.
I'm not.
Trevor, you were all I had left.
Oh...
(Fast busy signal)
It's over.
(Busy signal stops)
If you'd like to make a call,
please hang up and try again.
(Candyman) They will all abandon you.
All you have left
is my desire for you.
(Laughing and chattering)
(Many voices in the distance
shouting "Candyman!")
(Laughter and shouting
in the distance)
(Rasping, heavy breathing)
Helen.
You came to me.
The child.
We had a deal.
Surrender to me now
and he shall be unharmed.
We have a bargain.
But I'm afraid.
Do you fear the pain
or what is beyond?
Both.
The pain, I can assure you,
will be exquisite.
As for our deaths,
there is nothing to fear.
Our names will be written
on a thousand walls.
Our crimes told
and retold
by our faithful believers.
We shall die together
in front of their very eyes
and give them something
to be haunted by.
Come with me
and be immortal.
(Screaming)
No!
(Crunching)
(Candyman) Hush.
Hush.
You're mine now.
It's time for a new miracle.
(Baby squeals)
(Metallic clattering)
(Candyman) It was always you, Helen.
It was always you.
(Baby crying)
(Crying continues)
(Crying gets louder)
(Crying)
He's here.
I'm coming.
It's OK.
Check it out, man.
Oh, yes.
(Man) What happened?
(Man #2) We got the Candyman out there.
(Jake) I saw him go in there.
Candyman's in there.
I saw him.
(Crying)
I knew you'd come.
Burn him.
Hush.
Burn him, burn him,
burn him, burn him...
(Muffled cry)
(Crowd chanting)
Burn him, burn him!
Help!
Burn him, burn him, burn him!
Help...help me!
Burn him, burn him!
You lied to me!
We must be on our way now,
you and l.
Our bones will soon be ashes
and we shall never
be separated again.
Let me go.
I cannot.
We are already dead.
(Baby crying)
Helen!
(Screaming)
(Screaming in pain)
(Angry yelling)
(Groans loudly)
Come back to me!
Come back!
(Baby crying)
(Screaming)
(Minister) We commend to almighty God
our sister Helen
and we commit her body
to the ground.
Earth to earth,
ashes to ashes, dust to dust.
The lord bless her and keep her
and give her peace.
God of holiness and power
accept our prayers on behalf
of your servant Helen.
Do not count
her deeds against her.
For in her heart she desired
to do your will.
May almighty God bless you
the Father and the Son
and the Holy Spirit.
(Man) My God, look at that.
Trevor?
(Stacey) Trevor?
What is it?
Trevor, are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Aren't you hungry?
No, I'm OK.
I'll eat a little bit later.
I was going to make us
a nice dinner.
OK, whatever.
Hey, why don't you help me
make the salad?
OK, I'll be there
in a minute.
Helen...
Oh, Helen.
Helen.
Ow.
What's the matter, Trevor?
Scared of something?
(Flesh tearing)
(Death rattle)
Trevor?
My God, Trevor?
Trevor!
(Screaming)