Out for blood, huh?
You'd puke at the sight of a dead man.
Put down that stool. Put it down!
Drop that knife.
Okay, Fatso,
if it's killing you want, come on.
Well, come on!
On the floor!
Killers, huh?
l'd trade the pair of you
for a good Camp Fire Girl!
Tough monkey.
Guys like you end up in the stockade
sooner or later.
Some day you'll walk in, l'll be waiting.
l'll show you a couple of things.
l'm going to get a breath of air.
l'm glad he stopped it.
He's a good man.
You keep it. Keep it for a souvenir.
Okay, l'll keep it.
You ain't enjoying life much, are you, kid?
Could you stand a weekend pass?
Could l....
What about Holmes?
Don't worry about Holmes.
He signs anything without reading it.
l sure could use it.
l hear you've gone dippy over some dame
down at the New Congress Club.
What'd you say her name was?
Lorene.
lt's a beautiful name.
Hey, paisan!
What's holding you up? Let's get going.
What's wrong? Don't you like it here?
Something better to do in town?
The bus is leaving right away.
l'm taking the bus.
Take off. You're talking to a rich man.
l'll hop a taxi.
l'll meet you at the Kalakaua, later.
Maggio. Get ready for guard.
Campaign hat, cartridge belt and weapon.
Report to the orderly room in 10 minutes.
What? l got a pass!
Not anymore.
Anderson's sick. You're on guard.
l just had guard yesterday. Why me?
l'll tell you why, you.
You should have gotten dressed faster.
l sure never figured
on your giving me the runaround.
They didn't even want to let me in.
We're mobbed, that's why.
A big crowd from Hickam Field
got in here first.
-Did you expect a brass band to meet you?
-No.
Thought you'd want to see me.
l'm busy, can't you see? Look.
Yes, l see it's crowded.
Well, l am.
Maggio's going to be
at the Kalakaua lnn later.
ls there no way you can get out of here?
What's the matter with you?
l work here, you know, after all.
Can't you understand?
Yes, l do. l understand.
l understand very well.
You haven't been here in weeks.
Now you turn up all of a sudden--
Watch it, Mack!
Watch where you're going!
Come on out of here.
Don't you think Mrs. Kipfer has rules?
l can't just walk out.
-Even if l could, she doesn't like us--
-All right, look.
lf you feel that way,
just forget about it, okay?
You haven't any claims on me, mister.
You're not my husband, you know.
There you are.
l vastly admire your taste,
but we really need Lorene now.
So many gentlemen are unattended.
-lt is such a rush, isn't it?
-Yeah.
Almost like one of those big
political conventions in Philadelphia.
You are coming, Lorene?
ln a minute.
l'm sorry.
How do you think l feel?
l may not get another pass for months.
l've been counting on this
like a kid counts on Christmas.
But forget it.
Lorene's busy, she's got work to do.
Lorene's sorry.
Stop calling me Lorene! My name's Alma!
-Alma?
-Yes, Alma Burke!
Alma?
Mrs. Kipfer picked Lorene
out of a perfume ad.
She thought it sounded French.
Hey, how did you get away?
l told Mrs. Kipfer l was sick.
-But l bet she doesn't believe it.
-l bet she doesn't.
-What'll you have?
-A Coke, please.
Give her a big Coke.
lt's great you meeting me here.
You know, l'm just lucky getting in town.
Top Kick gave me a break.
They still pouring it on?
Holmes and those others,
they really got me on the edge.
-You must hate the Army.
-No, l don't hate the Army.
But look what it's doing to you.
l love the Army.
But it sure doesn't love you.
A man loves a thing,
that don't mean it's got to love him back.
Yeah, but a person can stand just so much.
You love a thing, you've got to be grateful.
l left home when l was 17.
Both my folks is dead.
l didn't belong no place
till l entered the Army.
That's where l learned to bugle.
To bugle?
That's the mouthpiece l used
when l played a taps at Arlington.
They picked me to play a taps
at Arlington Cemetery on Armistice Day.
The President was there.
l play the bugle well.
Hello, citizens!
Hey, where you been?
Hi, pals. l've been in three bars
and l put a dent in all three of them.
Yeah, you look it.
Give me a nail. l'm hungry for a nail.
What you doing in uniform?
l'm thinking of joining the Army.
Or maybe l'll go to Mexico
and become a cowboy.
You want to go with me?
You keep on drinking,
you'll be as much use as a melted candle.
You're absolutely right.
Bartender! Large whisky.
Excuse me. Hey, buddy.
Sam!
Hey, coming out, fellas,
the terror of Gimbels' basement.
Stand back. Here we go.
A seven for Daddy, five deuce.
Seven.
Snake eyes.
The story of my life.
Prew, that's the Royal Hawaiian Hotel
around the corner...
...where all those movie stars stay.
Paisan, you'd better simmer down.
You got a whole weekend ahead of you.
That's what you say, buddy.
What do you mean?
They only gave you an overnight pass?
No pass.
No pass. They put me on guard duty.
But old Angelo, he foxed them.
You walked off guard?
l checked in and l checked right out again.
Get your tail right back to the post.
You're in trouble, you know that.
l got a good idea. Let's go swimming!
We'll go swimming with a movie star.
That's what l'm gonna do.
Listen, Angelo.
Twenty feet tall,
l'm going swimming with a movie star.
You'd better go.
Hey, Angelo.
You jerk, get up. Wake up.
l'm awake. What are you hollering about?
Yeah, you're awake. Put your clothes on.
Give them back to the lndians.
They need the clothes.
All they wear is G-strings.
You ain't drunk. Come on, get up.
l am waiting here for a movie star
to come out of the hotel.
l'm not going until she shows up.
Put your clothes on.
Let's get out of here
before we get in trouble. Okay?
What's the matter with you?
Can't a man get drunk?
Can't a man do nothing?
Can't he put his lousy hands
in his lousy pockets on a lousy street?
A man gotta be hounded all his life?
l'm tired. l ain't no criminal.
l ain't no coward!
Buddy boy, look....
Get dressed, put your clothes on.
-Wait for me? l'll get a cab.
-Yeah, sure.
-Will you wait?
-You get a cab.
Hey, MPs! Come and get me, you guys!
Here l am!
ls that the best you can do?
l bet you guys eat Wheaties!
Any word on Maggio's court-martial yet?
lt's on right now.
He'll get the stockade sure.
Maybe he won't get it.
All he did was to get drunk.
lt's a soldier's nature.
lt's almost a sacred duty once in a while.
But he walked off guard. He went AWOL.
What are you hanging around here for?
Can't a man rest a minute?
What man? You got no work?
Maybe l can scare you up some.
Go shoot some pool.
Any word comes, l'll let you know.
Company G,
First Sergeant Warden speaking. Yes, sir.
Yes, sir, l'll have his things in order.
He got it. Six months.
l'm gonna escape from this dump.
Gimbels' basement couldn't hold me,
neither can this.
-Shut up!
-Whatever you say, Brownie.
Prisoner! Halt!
Hello, tough monkey.
This other girl and l were lucky to rent it.
This is a very fashionable district.
l have another key made for you.
You can use it any time you want to,
even when l'm not here.
-Hi.
This is Prew, the soldier l told you about.
-This is Georgette, my roommate.
-Well, welcome, friend.
Hasn't been a man around the house
since the cat died.
l belong to the Book Guild Club.
l always take every book.
That's the way l get all the dividends.
She'll be great for your friend
when he gets out of the stockade.
Yes, he'll be crazy about her.
Just sit down and get comfortable.
l'll make you a martini
and see what's to cook for dinner.
This is like being married, ain't it?
lt's better.
You okay?
Glad you came?
Let's get out of here. Don't look around.
lt can't go on like this much longer.
Even though we sneaked across
the island...
...we had to run out like jailbirds.
lf there was only some way we....
Holmes'd probably give you a divorce,
but never let me transfer out of his outfit.
There is a way.
l've been thinking about it.
You've got to become an officer.
You can take the new extension course,
the one they passed last May.
-Once commissioned you go to the States.
-An officer?
Yes. Then l could divorce Dana
and marry you.
l hate officers. l've always hated officers!
Well, that's a fine, intelligent point of view.
Suppose l said l always hated sergeants.
That'd make a lot of sense, wouldn't it?
You sure made a complete study of it.
Okay, suppose l did it.
And don't think it's a cinch.
You'd be here, l'd be in the States,
we'd be apart six months!
-We're sure to be into a war--
-Tell the truth.
You don't want the responsibility.
You're probably not even in love with me.
You're crazy! l wish l didn't love you.
Maybe l could enjoy life again.
So they were married
and lived unhappily ever after.
l've never been so miserable in my life
as l have since l met you.
Neither have l.
-l wouldn't trade a minute of it.
-Neither would l.
l'll probably make the lousiest officer
in this man's Army you ever saw.
You'll make a fine officer.
A remarkable officer.
Thank you.
Come here.
Can't you wait until we finish dinner?
Honey...
...l want to marry you.
You're a funny one.
Why's it funny if a guy
wants to marry you?
Because l'm a girl you met
at the New Congress Club.
That's about two steps
up from the pavement.
Well, what am l?
l'm a private, no-class dogface.
The way most civilians look at that,
that's two steps up from nothing.
Prew, l thought we were happy.
Why do you want to spoil things?
Look, l've got a year to go
before l re-enlist.
lf l can swing sergeant's stripes by then,
they'll let me go back to the States.
We can go back together...
...if you'll wait.
How do you expect to become a sergeant
under Captain Holmes?
lt's all you can do
to keep out of the stockade.
l'll fight.
You're not gonna fight.
lt'd be worth it.
Prew, it's true we love each other now.
We need each other.
But back in the States
it might be different.
That ain't the real reason.
-All right, it's not.
-What is the real reason?
l won't marry you because
l don't want to be the wife of a soldier.
Well, that would be about the best
l could ever do for you.
Because nobody's going to stop me
from my plan. Nobody, nothing.
Because l want to be proper.
''Proper''?
Yes, proper.
ln another year,
l'll have enough money saved.
l'll go back to my hometown in Oregon.
l'll build a house for my mother and myself.
Join the country club and take up golf.
l'll meet the proper man
with the proper position.
l'll make a proper wife
who can run a proper home.
Raise proper children.
l'll be happy because when you're proper,
you're safe.
You got guts, honey.
l hope you can pull it off.
l do mean it when l say l need you,
'cause l'm lonely.
You think l'm lying, don't you?
Nobody ever lies about being lonely.
And don't talk to me about a divorce.
Why? Because the scandal
would spoil your chances for a promotion?
l ask you once more: l want to know
who he is and where you met him.
l'm not going to tell you.
One thing l know: l know he's a civilian.
You'd be too discreet to pick an Army man.
l wonder which is hurt more,
your pride or your curiosity?
You can't know how l feel about this.
l wonder why men feel so differently
about it than women?
lt's just not the same.
lt's a lovely day. l think l'll go for a walk.
l hear you just got out of the stockade.
lt was rugged.
Kept my mouth shut, didn't get in trouble.
Did you see Maggio?
Fatso's really got it in for Maggio.
He's using a billy, too.
ln places where it won't show.
On the back, on the chest.
He's got it down to a system.
He kicks him a lot, too.
You know how Maggio's taking it?
He just keeps spitting in Fatso's eye.
Ain't he a hot one?
Well, he's a good man.
Fatso can't make a dent in him.
But, that Fatso, he's smart. He makes sure
the O.D. never sees nothing.
Why don't Maggio go to the O.D. himself?
We tried to get him to, but he won't peep.
That boy's the toughest nut in the woods.
You think he's going to be all right?
Well, maybe he's cracking, at that.
What do you mean?
After Fatso threw him in the Hole--
That's solitary...
...he started talking a couple of times
about how he's gonna escape.
He said to tell you
he'll look you up one night.
Still on your knees, Prewitt?
Boxing finals next month: December 15.
You've still got time to help us
win the championship.
Are you proud to be in this company
or not?
l ain't gonna move around you again.
Something tells me you need a lesson.
Maybe l'll give it to you myself.
Leave him alone. He's in my detail.
You'll get in trouble if you fight here.
Get back to work.
Get out of my way!
l'll be glad to recommend you.
You've got service, experience, grade.
-You'll make an excellent officer.
-Thank you, sir.
lt'd be a feather in my cap, too.
A man from my company.
At ease. What's the trouble, Sergeant?
They're fighting outside, sir.
Galovitch and Prewitt.
Prewitt?
Galovitch looks like
he's going to murder him.
l'll take care of it.
Don't you want to see?
No! Nor you, either! Get out of here!
Why don't Prew go for his head?
Blinded a guy once.
Must be scared of the same thing.
The face, Prew! Hit him in the face!
Come on, Galovitch, fight fair!
l'll fight any way l want.
Come on, Prew, get up!
Why doesn't that officer stop that fight?
-What's his name, Major?
-Captain Holmes, sir.
At ease. What started this?
Prewitt refused an order l gave him.
Talked back and started a fight.
l taught him a lesson.
You won't disobey orders in my company.
Sir, l'm sorry,
but Private Prewitt's not to blame.
Sergeant Galovitch started it.
-Thornhill?
-Yes, sir.
You're in charge of this detail.
What about it?
He's right, Prewitt did nothing.
Yes, sir. Galovitch started it.
That's all. Let's forget it.
Let's get back to our jobs.
lf you guys think this means
l'll step into a ring, you're wrong.
You'd better put some iodine on them cuts.
Hey, Friday.
Why are you called ''Friday''?
l don't know. l was born on a Wednesday.
Hey, Prewitt, where you going?
Where am l going?
l'm going to Choy's.
l'm gonna get me another beer.
Halt!
Who goes there?
A friend.
Advance, friend, and be recognised!
Ten-hut!
About face!
Rear face!
On your knees!
Scrub the floor!
At ease.
Hello, kid.
What you doing out here all by yourself?
l'm gonna get a little drink.
Sit down. l got a bottle.
Thanks, Top.
l got to hand it to you, kid...
...the way you beat up
old Galovitch this afternoon.
Too bad they gotta get you sooner or later.
Life's crummy, you know it?
Yes, sir, it's perfectly miserable.
What do you suppose would happen
if a truck came along and ran us over?
We'd be dead.
Better not sit here anymore.
You'd better get up
and sit over on the side of the road.
What do you mean, l better?
You've got more to live for than l do.
You got your whole company
to take care of.
You move over
to the other side of the road.
l'm old and it don't matter if l die.
You got your whole life ahead of you.
Don't argue. Get up.
No, sir, not Prewitt.
Prewitt stays right here to the bitter end.
Okay, we'll stay together.
l couldn't have got up anyway.
l got the biggest troubles
in the whole world.
ln the whole world, huh?
Take love.
Did you personally ever see
any of this love?
You'll understand what l mean.
This girl...
...she wants me to become....
-Become what?
-An officer.
Can you see me as an officer?
Yeah, l can see you as an officer.
You'd be a good officer.
Well, you both can see
more than l can see.
l don't wanna be an officer.
l'm happy where l am.
l might turn out to be a guy like Holmes.
You wouldn't want me
to be a guy like Holmes, would you?
Well, would you?
A man should be what he can do.
How's your girl?
What's her name again?
Lorene.
Oh, yeah.
l remember now.
A beautiful name.
Beautiful.
You two dumb, crazy screwballs.
What are you trying to do,
get yourself killed?
Why are you in the middle of the road?
My friend Prew and l,
we're sitting here discussing the weather.
-Your friend, huh?
-You heard me.
Don't you know
you gotta take care of this man?
Holmes is bound to get him
sooner or later.
And he's the best stinking soldier
in the whole Army.
You both got rocks in your head.
Angelo.
l figured you'd be here at Choy's.
l done it, Prew.
l escaped just like l said.
Just like l figured...
...in a back of a truck, under a tarp.
They rode me right out.
Just like l figured.
Only the tailgate opened up, Prew,
about a mile back...
...and l fell out in the road.
You should've seen me bounce.
l must've broke something.
Prew, listen.
Fatso done it, Prew.
He likes to whack me in the gut.
He asks me if it hurts...
...and l spit at him like always.
Only yesterday, it was bad.
He hit me...
...he hit me...
...he hit me.
l had to get out, Prew.
-They gonna send you to the stockade?
-No, they ain't.
Watch out for Fatso.
He'll try to crack you.
lf they put you in the Hole...
...don't yell.
Don't make a sound.
You'll still be yelling
when they come to take you out.
Just lay there.
Just lay there and be quiet, Prew.
He's dead.
l'll bet you that's Prew.
Sergeant Judson?
You want me?
Yeah, Fatso.
l don't like that nickname.
You want to see me about something?
Let's step around the corner
where we can talk.
Okay.
Are you sore about something?
l don't like the way you play the piano.
Remember Maggio?
The wop? Yeah, real tough monkey.
-You killed him.
-Did l?
Well, if l did, he asked for it.
The Army's going to get you
sooner or later, Fatso.
But before they do,
l want a piece of you myself.
l figured that.
See this knife?
lt's the one you pulled on Maggio.
What's happened?
lt's all right.
Don't worry.
l ain't gonna die.
First Platoon present and accounted for!
Second Platoon all accounted for!
Third Platoon all present
and accounted for!
Fourth Platoon all present
Fifth Platoon all accounted for!
Sixth Platoon all accounted for!
Company, dismissed!
Prewitt's still absent.
Makes three days now.
How long are you gonna carry him present,
Top?
l just mention it.
Well, don't mention it.
''Upon observing these incidents,
an investigation was made...
''...by the lnspector General's Department
over a period of several months.
''lt was found that Captain Holmes...
''...has been guilty of indefensible cruelty
to the aforesaid Private Prewitt.
''As mentioned, this included instigation
of wholly unauthorised tactics...
''...to force the soldier
to join the interregiment boxing team.''
l'm waiting for your reply.
l haven't any, sir.
First thing l learned in the Army
was that an officer takes care of his men.
lt seems to be the first thing you forgot.
My only regret is...
...we have to keep you in uniform
till a court-martial is concluded.
lf there were any way
to avoid a court-martial, sir.
There is one alternative, General,
if you are so disposed:
A resignation for the good of the service
under Army regulations.
Write a letter of resignation.
Have it on my desk this afternoon.
As far as l'm concerned...
...the quicker you're out,
the better for everybody...
...especially the Army.
That's all, Holmes.
l know what's been going on in this outfit.
l know how far some of you
have been out of line.
lf you want to remain non-coms,
you'd better snap into it.
And another thing:
From now on,
no man will earn his stripes by boxing.
-Get rid of those.
-Yes, sir.
Dismissed.
-About Sergeant Galovitch.
-Yes, sir.
Bust him. Sergeant Galovitch
is now Private Galovitch.
Put him in charge of the latrine.
What are you grinning at?
l think the Company Commander
made a wise decision, sir.
Company G, Captain Ross.
Just a minute.
-lt's for you, Sergeant.
-Thank you, sir.
Yes, sir.
Yes, the parcel has already arrived.
What?
l've got to see you, Milt. lt's important.
Okay, l'll get away somehow.
Sure, that'd be fine, yeah.
l'll be there in about an hour. Right.
He's being sent back to the States,
sailing next week, and wants me to go.
What will we do?
When do you think
you'll get your commission?
l didn't put it in.
l filled it out, but l didn't sign it.
l took it out of my desk a dozen times,
but l couldn't sign it.
Why?
-But it was the plan--
-l know.
lt's been weeks.
You can't say you'll do a thing
and not do it.
Karen, listen to me.
Why didn't you do it?
Why didn't you tell me?
Be back in a minute.
Sorry, l thought you were somebody else.
l thought it was a guy from our company,
Prewitt, the kid l told you about.
He got mixed up with a girl
at the New Congress Club.
He's AWOL, probably in lots of trouble.
Robert E. Lee Prewitt, a crazy, no-good....
Karen, l'm no officer. l'm an enlisted man.
l can't be anything else.
lf l try to be an officer,
l'll be putting on an act.
l just can't do it. Please don't ask me why.
l know why.
You don't have to become an officer now...
...now that Dana's out of the Army.
You just don't want to marry me.
You're already married to the Army.
l love you, Karen.
l know.
l don't want you to go back to Holmes.
l don't want to, either. But l am.
There's nothing else for me to do.
lt's no good with us, Milt.
lt could never have been any good.
Hiding, sneaking.
lt had to wear out.
Good-bye, Sergeant.
-Thanks.
-lt ain't good-bye, it's....
We'll see each other again, somewhere.
Of course we will. Somewhere.
Here it is.
Got it on the inside page already.
''Still no clue...
''...in the fatal stabbing
of Staff Sergeant James R. Judson.''
Did you hear me?
Are you trying to set a new world's record?
Yeah, as a matter of fact, l am.
To the memory of Robert E. Lee Prewitt...
...holder of the new world's record.
-Everything all right, Top?
-Great.
This is a beautiful meal to put in front
of a guy on a Sunday morning.
Congratulations.
They sure look pretty
over them mountains.
Don't they, though?
Sounds like they're dynamiting
down at Wheeler Field.
Mighty ambitious.
Sunday morning before 8:00?
The Japs are bombing Wheeler Field!
l've seen the red circles on the--
Get out of here. Hurry up! Go!
This is a real attack, not a manoeuvre.
The Japanese are bombing Pearl Harbor.
Please keep in your homes.
Do not go on the streets.
This is a real attack.
Japanese planes are bombing
our Naval and Army installations.
-Quiet down!
-At ease!
Non-coms, get BARs and ammunition
from the supply room. Get up on the roof.
Anderson!
You're in charge of the loading detail.
Get moving.
Rest of you men, listen to me.
Every man get his rifle, go to his bunk
and stay there. And l mean...
...stay there!
Shut up! You'll get your ears shot off
if you go outside.
You'll get plenty of chances to be heroes
with Japs in your lap before night.
Now get moving, we're wasting time!
lnto the kitchen and make a pot of coffee.
Wait a minute, a barrel of coffee!
l can't issue live ammunition
without a signed order.
-The Captain ain't here, jerk!
-Sorry. No order, no ammo.
-What's the matter?
-l got my orders!
Army regulations state that l can't--
You blind? Give me the key!
-l got to obey orders, Top.
-l'll see you get a medal!
-Bust it down, boys!
-l warned you!
Don't go out, Warden, you'll get killed!
Put your pants on. You'll catch cold!
Give them a hand with this ammo!
Put that stuff over there.
Watch your fire, boys,
and lead those planes!
Friday's gone crazy!
He's blowing the Cavalry Charge!
Here they come, boys!
l got him, Pete! l got him!
l got him!
The danger of an invasion
continues to exist.
lnfantry from Schofield Barracks
moved out within a few hours...
...and have manned beach positions.
This is no manoeuvre.
This is the real McCoy.
Look out for falling shrapnel.
Keep under cover.
Blackout and curfew restrictions
will be rigidly enforced.
Stay in your homes.
Don't use the telephone.
Rest assured that immediate relay
to you of any and all information....
We've been to Queen's Hospital
giving blood.
The town's a madhouse!
A big house was bombed on Kuhio Street.
The drugstore down on McNully
and King is smashed flat!
A man and his wife were killed.
Your attention, please.
Listen to this carefully and keep calm.
The danger of an invasion
continues to exist.
And the planes have been identified
as Japanese planes.
Who do they think they're fighting?
They're picking trouble
with the best Army in the world.
Where you going?
l gotta get back to the company.
The company? But why?
Why?
But you can't. You're not well yet.
You're AWOL.
They'll throw you in the stockade.
They'll be throwing them out
of the stockade. They need everyone.
But your side'll open up.
They'll find out you killed that soldier.
Once l report in to the company,
they'll take care of me.
l'll be all right once l get back.
But you'll never make it!
There's patrols all over!
l'll make it. l know a shortcut.
Prew, stay till morning.
Maybe if you stay till morning
you'll change your mind.
Prew, don't go!
l'll do anything you want.
We can go back to the States together,
we can even get married.
lf you go now,
l'll never see you again, l know it.
l'm sorry.
What do you want to go back
to the Army for?
What did the Army do for you
besides treat you like dirt...
...and give you one awful going over?
Get your friend killed!
What do you want to go back for?
What do l want to go back for?
l'm a soldier.
A soldier! A regular.
From the regular Army!
A 30-year man!
l got to turn off the lights,
'cause of the blackout outside.
They say they've seen parachutists
land up in the hills.
l ain't worried about them.
Saboteurs is what worries me.
l bet they're operating
all over these islands.
Halt!
Do you know this man, Sergeant?
Yes, sir.
He didn't have any regular identification.
They found a card on him with his name.
Seems to be membership of a club:
The New Congress Club.
You'd better take care of these, Sergeant.
Was this man a friend of yours?
Yes, sir. He must've been trying to reach
our company position up the beach here.
Then why didn't he halt?
He was always a hardhead, sir,
but he was a good soldier.
He loved the Army
more than any soldier l ever knew.
l see. l'm sorry, Sergeant.
You just couldn't play it smart, could you?
All you had to do was box, but no,
not you, you hardhead.
Funny thing is, there ain't gonna be
any boxing championships this year.
What's the matter?
Ain't you ever seen a dead man?
Let's get this body out of here!
We ain't got all night!
lt's very beautiful, isn't it?
l think it's the most beautiful place
l ever saw in my life.
l can almost see where l worked from here.
There's a legend:
lf they float in toward shore,
you'll come back some day.
lf they float out to sea, you won't.
l won't come back.
My fianc was killed on December 7.
l'm sorry.
He was a bomber pilot.
He tried to taxi his plane
to the edge of the apron.
The Japs made a direct hit on it.
Maybe you read about it in the papers.
He was awarded the Silver Star.
They sent it to his mother.
She wrote me she wanted me to have it.
That's very fine of her.
They're very fine people. Southern people.
He was named after a general.
Robert E. Lee...
...Prewitt.
Who?
Robert E. Lee Prewitt.
lsn't that a silly old name?