Subtitles by explosiveskull
Enjoy the sweet
taste of my lazor beam!
No, not the lazor beam.
Engage force field!
PJ.
Put your seat
belt on, young lady.
No. It's uncomfortable.
Samantha Pepper
I will not ask you again.
Sam, now.
Okay, fine.
Mom!
Open your textbook, please.
Hopefully, we can do better
on the next test.
Electricity was considered
nothing but a dangerous idea
or fad when Edison
was born in...
Anyone?
Ms. Pepper?
1847.
We can't hear you, Smalls.
But, by 1931,
the time of Edison's death,
cities were powered
by electricity.
PJ... no gum, please.
However, still today,
many do not understand
not only the basics
of electricity,
- but the potential of its power.
- Pathetic.
Electricity can
be made from water, wind,
the sun,
and even animal poop.
Okay. The homework assignment
is written at the end
of the chapter
in your textbook.
Trish, that sounds
like so much fun.
We'll invite everyone.
Well, at least those
who've hit puberty.
Great.
Hey.
Hey. Uh, where's Dad?
Oh, he's busy
with the sink again.
How was school?
Fine.
You sure?
Yeah.
Hey, Dad.
Hey! Can you give me a hand?
Sure.
- Hi, babe.
- Hey.
Can I talk to you
for a second?
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
- You got this?
- Already on it.
- All right.
- Okay.
Hey, sweetie.
What's goin' on?
I don't think you
had a chance to notice,
but she has gum in her hair...
again.
I think she's being bullied
at school.
I think you need
to talk to her.
Okay, okay.
I'm on it.
- Okay.
- All right.
All right.
I gotta go back.
Okay. I'll see you tomorrow.
- Bye.
See you.
- Bye, Sam!
- Bye!
All right.
How we doin' here?
Hey, um...
How was, um...
How was school today?
Fine.
Channellock.
Gotcha.
Just, um...
Just fine?
Yep.
Okay.
Hey, what are you feelin'
for dinner tonight?
Whoa! Whoa there!
I'm gonna have to give you
the Heimlich.
What's the matter
with you?
That was pretty great of Sydney
to pick you up today.
- Right? I mean...
- Yeah.
That, uh-that sink took me
a lot longer than I expected.
Oh.
I helped. Right?
Mm-hmm.
You like her.
Don't you?
Sydney?
Yes, Dad.
She's practically
part of the family.
What are you doing?
Nothing. What do you mean
what am I doing?
You always do this.
Do what?
Eat your veggies.
Well, you eat yours first.
On three.
One...
- Two...
- Three.
Mmh!
So good.
Back to spaghetti.
- That was a bad piece.
That was for water.
I was thinking we could all
go out to-
to eat, tomorrow night.
You know, the three of us.
Okay.
To our spot.
Our spot?
But we haven't been there
since Mom.
Well...
We haven't been to
a lot of places since Mom,
Sam, but...
...you can't avoid every
little place in this town
that reminds us of her.
You know?
We-we have to allow ourselves
to go out and...
...make new memories.
You're always trying to do that.
Excuse me?
You're always trying
to make new memories.
Samantha.
I'm full.
Sam.
Sam, sit down.
Hey, sweetie.
Hey.
It's bed time.
You're my little girl.
Dad...
But you are.
I can't wait
for dinner tomorrow.
It's gonna be great.
It's gonna be...
...really good for you.
We're gonna have fun.
I love you.
Love you, too.
Well, you know, I...
...have to eat your face.
Okay.
Okay, good night.
- Good night.
- See you tomorrow.
See ya.
It could be anything.
It could be anything at...
Hey, Sam.
Hey.
Again?
It looks like
you have too many
different screw types
going on.
Hmm, I dunno.
It looks to me like
it might be
how I mounted my sensor.
Everyone!
Can I have your attention,
please?
Thank you.
Okay, so Trish's birthday
is this weekend
and we're having
a girls only birthday party.
Sorry, boys.
We haves stacks
of invitations here
for those we're inviting.
Aw, Smalls, don't leave.
You might miss your name.
My mother
gave this to me when I was your age.
She gave it to me
as a reminder
that no matter what,
she will always be here
to protect and guide me.
I'm always here.
Hey, Sammy, let's go!
We're gonna be late!
Thank you.
Thanks.
Hey, now.
Ew.
- Hey, now.
So, what do you think?
I like it, you guys.
I really do.
And I thought you only like
it because of the name.
- Well...
- Still...
- Yep.
- Still kind of a big part of it.
Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
- Yes.
Yeah.
I think I like hers
the most.
Yeah, um...
- Let me just...
- Hey!
[Aw...
So, I got you something.
Just a little something.
A random thing.
There you go.
If you don't like it,
we can take it back.
No big deal.
It's just that Jim said
it was one of the rarest ones.
No, no...
I really like this.
You do?
Yeah.
Nice.
Not now.
Can't read it now.
After dinner.
Come on.
Eat.
Food just got here.
Fine.
Whoa, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Slow your roll!
You forgetting something?
- Good night.
Good night, good night,
good night!
Mm!
- I love you.
- Love you, too.
And?
Thanks, Sydney! Night!
Good night.
"Get your very
own Mail-Order Monster.
Don't be the schmuck
who's pushed around.
Don't be the wallflower
in the crowd.
Frighten your enemies
and amuse your friends.
Send this ad with $20
to Merlin's Emporium
of Monsters and Magic."
Okay, so...
Oh, Samantha!
Just in time. Come on in.
Take your seat.
Mommy forget to drive you?
Oh, wait...
That's... No.
All right. All right.
We are
collecting homework today.
Tommy, would you please collect
the homework assignments?
The rest of you,
please turn
to page 34 in your books.
We're on a new chapter today.
Samantha!
Hi, Mr. Thomas.
Hello, Samantha.
How are you?
Fine.
Good, good.
Um...
How do I put this?
A few of the teachers were...
...in the lunch room yesterday,
and saw what happened
with the whole...
...PJ thing.
Now, we know it
should've never happened,
and PJ knows that now.
So, I just want you to know
that we spoke
to Trish's parents, and...
Here you go.
You're welcome to go.
Okay, good.
Little shrimp got
Mr. Thomas to feel bad for her.
Didn't she?
If I were you,
and I'm really glad I'm not,
I wouldn't come.
There's a height requirement.
Well, at least from down here,
I can see how stuck up
you and your...
fake friends really are.
You think you're so
much better and smarter
than everyone else,
don't you?
Well, news flash,
you're not.
Just go back to your
stupid little comic books
and superheroes.
Wasn't that long ago
you used to dress up like them.
In fact, I still have
your Superman costume.
Wasn't that long ago
you killed your mom.
Hey.
I'm gonna go get ready
for bed.
- Oh.
- You sure you don't wanna come play?
Sydney could use your help.
She said she's good at cards
and she's horrible.
I'm horrible!
No. I'm okay.
Okay. Hey!
How's the comic?
It's... one of a kind.
Good. All right.
I'll, uh-
I'll ask Jim
to give me a call the next
time he gets a new one in.
Baby steps.
I think I did good.
You ready?
You're going down.
Not at cards.
Hey.
What are you doing?
Well, Sam,
you know what I'm doing.
We've talked about this.
I mean, there's so
many pictures.
It's... There's...
We can't have all of these up.
You know?
It's not fair.
To who?
Sydney?
I'm sorry my mom
makes her uncomfortable.
Sam! Sam, you know
that's not true.
Hey.
Have you seen a package
or something like that?
No. Why?
You expecting something?
Could you just tell me
if you do?
Yes, ma'am.
Thanks.
Hey, do you wanna, uh,
go to the movies
tonight with Sydney
and me?
Um... I can't.
I have...
...Science Club.
I found this.
School's been fine.
Well... not that fine.
My grades are still good.
It's-it's just, well...
You know.
I don't know if
Dad's told you yet, but...
...he met someone.
I guess it's...
been a while now.
She's nice. I just...
I don't know...
...why he's trying to...
move on.
We don't need anyone else.
We have you.
We'll always have you.
Hey, babe.
How was court?
Well, it's finally over.
That went significantly
longer than I expected.
Well, are we still on
for a movie tonight?
Yes, yes, I would love to.
Is Sam gonna make it?
Yeah, not tonight.
She's being held hostage
by Science Club.
Oh...
I don't remember her being
in Science Club.
Simple enough.
I can see why this
never took off.
Just add water.
All right. That's it.
I'm callin' it a night.
Okay.
Dress shirts come
out neat and professional.
Pants and slacks...
Good night.
Good night, sweetie.
I love you.
I'm just gonna...
...be here a little longer.
That's fine. Okay.
I'll see you
in the morning.
Okay.
...wrinkles inside
your dryer than Mister Steamy!
Forgot about that load
for hours?
That's a wrinkled mess!
No problem!
Simple toss in Mister Steamy,
and, in minutes, your clothes
are ready to wear!
Bye-bye, Bigfoot.
Ew!
- Wah wah!
- ...everywhere!
Sammy!
Dad?
What are-what are you
doing here?
I'm pickin' you up.
I rode my bike.
Well, no biggy.
We'll throw it in the back.
C'mon. I got something
really special planned
for you and Sydney tonight,
so we gotta go get ready.
What are you talking about?
Dad, I can't. I...
What do you mean?
What do you mean you can't?
We'll throw your bike
in the back.
Come on. I obviously have to shower.
Let's go.
Dad, I-I can't go.
I have...
...detention.
Since when do you
have detention?
Since now.
So I can't go tonight.
Sorry.
Well, hey.
We will, uh...
We'll pick you up
after detention.
Dad, I don't wanna go.
When was the last
time that Sam got detention?
Something's going on with her.
I feel it.
You know?
And I think you do too.
You know, that's one of the
things I love about you the most.
What's that?
You're not afraid
to call me out.
Sydney, you are the...
...most intelligent,
intuitive, caring woman...
We don't really fit in here.
We're... different.
I like that,
and I wouldn't anyone
to come into our life
and change that.
You're exactly what she needs,
and exactly what I need.
When Wendy died...
I never imagined
that I would...
...share my life
with anyone else.
Especially with Sam.
When I see you with Sam,
it gives me hope.
And I thought
all hope was lost.
Would you marry me?
Yes.
Wow, detention
runs late these days.
Yeah, sorry!
Be right there!
Hey.
You make dinner?
No, you-you missed it.
Remember?
Sydney and I
went to Salt & Pepper.
Wow.
There again?
You know, I'm really disappointed
that you couldn't be there.
Well...
Okay...
I mean, we were just there
the other night.
What was that for?
Samantha...
Okay, Dad, I'm sorry
I was...
...rude to you earlier today,
and I...
...promise it won't
happen again.
Keep watching.
Okay...
Now I'm confused.
Sam, I need to talk to you.
Okay.
I, um...
I know it's been hard,
you know,
really hard,
these past few years,
just having me.
I-I like just having you.
Okay, yeah.
But as you get older,
you know,
you're gonna wanna have,
um...
...another female,
a woman,
in-in your life.
You know, someone that you
can talk to,
and trust and rely on.
But, I have-
I have you.
Sam...
Okay. What are you saying?
I proposed.
To...?
I asked Sydney to marry me.
Sam...
Sammy.
No, no, no, no.
This isn't real.
Hey, what are you doing?
Come on, now.
Don't be like that.
How could you do this
to me?
Because I'm your father,
and, Sammy, I know
you're a really smart girl,
but believe it or not,
I know what's best for you.
You know what'd be best
for me?!
Having my mom back!
Well, she is gone!
No! Get out!
Get out!
Get out! I hate you!
I asked Sydney to marry me.
Hello?
Hello.
Wow.
Wake up! Wake up!
I'm Sam.
Sam...
What's your name?
MOM.
That's a hammer.
You use it to smash things.
Hammer.
A lot of things.
Ha!
Interesting.
Whoa! No, no, no, no, no!
You can't go out there.
At least, not yet.
It's not safe.
Crap.
Did you sleep in there
last night?
I did.
Well, what are you...
You can't go in there.
What are you doing in there?
Science project.
I made a big mess in there,
so...
...I'm gonna clean it up.
Okay. I'll help you.
No, no, no, no, no.
It's okay.
Got it.
Okay, well, look, Sam...
We need to talk.
I don't think we do.
Okay.
Okay, well...
I will see you after school.
Okay, so, here's the thing.
I need to go to school,
so you need to stay here.
School.
I need to go to school.
MOM go school.
No, no, MOM.
You can't go to school.
Come on.
Come on. This way.
Okay.
Do not... leave this room.
Now, if someone come in here,
what are you going to do?
Yes. Good.
Okay.
So...
These usually
keep me pretty occupied.
Feel free to look through them.
I'll be back later.
Thanks.
What have I done?
So, was it you?
What are you talking about?
The monster in PJ's locker.
I still can't believe
Gigantor peed herself.
No, it wasn't me.
Sorry!
It's okay.
It's just me.
Sam!
We gotta get out of here.
That was a close one.
You're creating a
little whirlpool there.
Hmm. Yeah.
Sorry.
You okay?
Yeah, yeah.
It's, uh...
Everything's great.
What aren't you telling me?
Uh, well...
Sam didn't take to the proposal
as well as I'd hoped.
She isn't ready.
It's too soon for her?
No, no, no, no, no, no.
She's fine.
It's just, uh...
...she doesn't understand, yet.
You know,
we've never really had
any one-on-one time,
just the two of us.
What if we just had,
like, a girls' day?
Think she'd be open to that?
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah?
I mean...
- It's worth a try.
- Yeah.
Mmh!
MOM?
Who?
Where'd you find that?
Wendy.
Hey, MOM...
This is awesome.
All right.
We're almost done.
We just have
one more room left.
Come with me.
I have a feeling you're gonna
have some fun in here.
These are my action figures.
They're similar to the ones
you saw in the comic book.
Let's just...
And here is a...
...robot prototype
I've been working on.
It's not finished yet.
It still has
a few holes in it.
Hey, no! Hey!
Don't touch that.
Okay.
Oh, actually...
It was that
out of place, huh?
Yes.
What... is...?
Just a stupid invitation
from a couple of mean girls.
Bad?
Yes.
These girls...
...well, one in particular,
PJ is bad.
Pee Jay bad?
Yeah.
Which I always think is weird.
We used to be friends.
Friends.
Yeah.
Like me and you.
We're friends.
You want to go outside again?
We can't. I'm sorry.
It's too risky.
We gotta get you
out of here.
Dad's gonna be home
any second.
Sam, you home?
Yeah, Dad.
Be right there!
Step on there.
Come up here.
Gotcha. Come on.
Stay here.
Oh, and don't leave
or make too much noise.
- Hey.
- Dad!
You talking to someone?
Yes... Well...
Myself.
I was talking to myself.
What are you doing?
Well, I was looking for you.
Why?
Why-why is that?
What do you need?
Okay. Because...
Listen.
Sydney wants
to take you out tomorrow.
Sydney.
- I'm okay.
- No, listen. Sam, Sam...
Sam, Sam, Sam, Sam, Sam...
Please. Please, just listen.
Okay?
It would mean so much to her.
And to me, too.
And, I mean,
I dunno,
maybe you'll surprise yourself
and end up having
a good time.
You know what's best, right?
Hey, Sam!
Come back over here, please.
Listen to me.
I'm really sorry
about what I said last night.
I'm sorry, too.
Come here.
So, uh...
That means you'll go tomorrow?
Fine.
- Okay, okay.
- That's my girl!
Thank you, thank you.
- Okay.
- Thank you. I love you.
Sam...
Wendy...
Dad...
Sydney?
Who?
It's complicated.
Sydney bad?
Well, I mean...
She's not a bad person.
It's just that...
...she's really
changed my dad.
He can't see it,
obviously.
He keeps saying that...
...we should make new memories
and that she's gonna
be so good for me...
...but she's not.
I don't need new memories,
or a new mom.
MOM?
No, not you.
My mother, Wendy.
This way.
Wendy.
Yes. This is Wendy.
Wendy is...
...well, was my mother.
All I have left of her now
are those pictures
and memories.
My dad just wants
to throw them all away.
When I see those pictures of us
I feel like...
...she's still here...
...with us...
...with me...
...and I didn't cause her
to go away.
I just...
...I don't know what
I'm going to do.
Always here.
Come on.
We should be heading back now.
This way.
PJ...
PJ bad.
MOM, stop!
What are you doing?
Stop!
Come on! Come on!
No.
Now, MOM,
you can't just
go running around like that.
You might get caught.
PJ bad.
Protect Sam.
Thanks.
I got your back, too.
Okay, I'll see you tomorrow.
Roy, she's getting
too smart for her own good.
That's my girl.
That's our girl.
Hey, Sam, Sydney's here!
Not today.
Hey.
Good morning.
Morning.
Doughnut or fritter?
But, we have an appointment
in 15 minutes,
so we gotta hurry.
Appointment?
Yeah.
Hey! Try these on.
Yep. You were in need
of some new clothes.
Let's see.
Oh, my gosh.
You look amazing.
Do you like it?
You look great.
Can I use the bathroom?
Yeah!
You know,
I'll be right back.
Sam?
Sam?!
Hey.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay. It's okay.
- I'm so sorry.
- It's okay.
I don't
know where she went.
We're gonna find her.
We'll find her.
She said she had
to go to the bathroom.
I don't know what happened.
MOM, hurry up.
Sam!
Back to school?
No, not school.
Come on. Follow me.
Come on.
I pushed her too hard
with the clothes.
This isn't your fault.
Does she have any friends
whose parents we can call?
I don't know.
Okay.
I think it's time
to call the police.
Where Sam go?
Don't worry.
We're almost there.
We're here.
- Roy.
- Sheriff, come on in.
Go back home?
No, we can't.
That's a life I want
no part in.
Sydney?
Kind of.
A stepmom...
...bullies...
...no friends...
...a new life.
I don't want any more
part of that.
I don't need that
now that I have you.
We got each other's back.
MOM protect Sam.
Thanks.
I'll protect you, too.
I bet my dad's freaking out
right now.
Dad bad?
No.
Well, I mean, yeah,
right now.
I dunno.
It's complicated.
Good night, MOM.
Good... night.
Sam?
PJ?
Hey, whoa, MOM!
Stop, no, MOM!
No, stop, stop!
Calm down!
PJ...
...meet MOM.
Shh. There's nothing
to be afraid of.
MOM is friendly.
She won't hurt you.
Right?
Hello.
See? It's nice.
Everything okay, Roy?
No, Sheriff,
everything is not okay.
I'm going crazy
over here. Okay?
I can't just
sit here anymore.
I need to be out there
looking for my daughter.
I know it's hard.
Roy, listen to me.
You have to stay home.
If it were my kid,
I'd be wanting
to get out there, too.
But Sam's most likely
to call or come home
in the next 48 hours,
so someone needs to be there.
I promise...
...we'll find her.
Okay.
I... thank you.
Sir, we got
another report about a 10-31.
Roger. 10-31.
We're on our way.
Another missing kid.
You're gonna look so good.
Ow!
Looks like someone
made a new friend.
PJ friend.
Glad we could set aside
our differences, MOM.
Did you name it that
because of...
No.
It was the name
that was on the box.
It's a Mail-Order Monster.
Pretty lucky you found
that comic book, huh?
Stop!
Hey. We should collect
some supplies for a fire.
It's gonna be
another cold night.
MOM,
can you go collect some sticks?
Thanks.
Oh!
And don't get too close to the
road where you might be seen.
Stay close.
Good idea for packing these.
Sorry if I ate too much.
It's okay.
I guess I came a little
more prepared than you.
So, why are you here?
I could ask you
the same thing.
Well, my dad
is getting remarried,
and I'm hiding
a robot-like monster.
I just left.
Come on, PJ.
Look. My life hasn't been
all happy-go-lucky either
since...
...since we were...
Friends?
You're not gonna lose
whatever popularity you have
because you admit
we were friends.
It's already gone.
They weren't really
my friends, anyway.
Didn't take too long
for them to abandon me, too.
I didn't abandon you.
Sam, you completely shut me out
after the accident.
Well, my mother did die.
I'm sorry I didn't
give enough attention to you.
Whatever.
You always do this.
Do what?
Shut people out.
You completely shut me out
and left me with no one.
You know how my family is.
I had no one to turn to.
You were my only friend.
I had to make new friends.
Well, you didn't have to turn into
someone else and become a huge jerk.
I was angry.
So was I.
I'm sorry I embarrassed you
in front of everyone.
It's okay.
We both know
I deserved it.
Giant.
Dwarf.
- Giraffe.
- Mouse.
- Bigfoot.
- Hobbit.
- Stretch.
- Smalls.
Roy?
Babe?
Hi.
I did this.
No, you did not.
You are the best dad.
Your daughter does
need you right now...
...and...
...I think she's made it
pretty clear
that she's not ready
for a stepmom yet.
Yeah, but she will be.
I mean, she just needs
some more time.
No...
You can't force her
into something
she's not ready for.
It's not fair.
She's been through so much.
You know?
No, don't do that.
Don't do that.
Syd, don't.
She's not ready.
And I wanted nothing more than
to be a part of this family.
I'm so sorry.
Roy, pick up.
I think I know where Sam went.
She's at the lake.
We should get water.
Yeah. Something to drink.
Sam!
PJ?
Sydney?
Oh, my God.
I can't believe I found you.
You need to-
you need to go!
I need to go?
Protect Sam.
You don't need
to worry about me.
You're not my mom.
Hey!
Sam!
Hey.
I know I'm not your mom.
I could never be Wendy.
And I know you weren't born
to me, but I choose you.
I choose you
and your father.
So, forgive me.
I'm always gonna worry
about you.
And I need to make sure
the both of you
get home
where you belong.
Understand?
Sam!
Protect!
Stop!
What are you doing?!
Sam!
Get off her!
What's happening?
Has it done this before?
No. This isn't right.
We need to turn it off.
The off switch
on the back of the arm.
MOM, stop!
It's not working!
PJ!
Sydney bad.
MOM, stop!
You need to calm down!
She is not bad!
Sydney bad.
Sam?!
That's Sydney's car.
Wait, Roy.
There's supposed to be
a storm coming.
I'll drive us down.
Okay, all right.
Sam!
Baby, baby, baby!
Hey, hey!
Hey, sweetie!
Put her down!
My God.
We need to stop this.
Come with me.
You sure about this?
No! Stay back!
MOM!
It's time.
Sam...
I'm always here.
Sam, no!
Sam!
Sam?
Hey, she's awake!
Hey, Sam!
Hey, baby!
How are you? Huh?
- Dad?
- Yeah, baby!
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry...
...for what I said.
- No, shh. Look at me.
- For what I did.
None of that matters.
- I love you, Dad.
- I love you, too.
Sam, how you feelin', honey?
I'm okay.
You?
I'm just really glad
you're back.
Thank you...
...for finding me.
Where's your ring?
Oh...
...Actually, um...
Uh, actually, uh...
...I have it.
Sweetie...
...we've decided to...
It's okay.
Sydney...
Will you be my stepmom?
You don't have to do this.
I choose you, too.
When you turn
your pages to chapter six,
you will see we will now
be covering life science.
Yes, we are finally
going to do some dissections.
Dude, check it out!
Hey, guys.
What is it about?
Hey!
Do you need a ride?
I rode my bike.
I'll race you home.
Already there, slow-poke.
Ha ha ha.
Okay, I think we
can call that one a tie.
Ooh!
Don't be a sore loser, now.
What?
Well, you look out
for me next time, little miss.
Next time, I'll give you
a head start.
With my training wheels.
With your training wheels?
Wow!
Looking good.
Thanks.
Is it ready?
Well, let's give it a go.
You can do the honors.
Hey, hey, no big deal.
We'll just come out and...
...give it a try tomorrow.
Let's go in.
Subtitles by explosiveskull