♪ Fixed & Synced by
bozxphd.Enjoy the Flick ♪
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(SIGHS)
There he is again.
Almost two decades
and he still comes.
So sad.
How you doing, buddy?
Brought you all your
favorite candies.
Come on, Lloyd, you
gotta get over her!
Mary Samsonite was just a girl.
Besides, she's married.
And even if it had worked out,
would you really want
ginger babies? Ugh.
Gross.
Man, you gotta
give me something!
(URINATING)
(SIGHS)
Lloyd, I got something
important to tell you.
I can't come here anymore.
I got kind of a serious
medical problem.
(MUMBLING)
It's sort of complicated.
Basically, I'm gonna be pretty
busy for the next few months.
Anyway...
You're in good hands here. So...
Take care, buddy.
(BABBLES)
Lloyd, did you say something?
(MUFFLED) I got you.
That's it, kid. You can do it.
Come on, come on, come on!
Spit it out!
(YELLING) Got ya!
(LAUGHS)
(STAMMERING) What?
You should see the
look on your face!
I got you so good!
(STAMMERING) Wait a second!
(CHUCKLES)
Are you telling me that you
were faking for 20 years?
Uh-huh.
So you mean that you just wasted
the best years of your life?
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
Out the window!
And you let me come here every
Wednesday for, like, a thousand weeks,
and it was all just for a gag?
Uh-huh.
That's
awesome! (CHUCKLES)
I know!
You gotta admit, I totally
had you suckered, didn't I?
Hook, line and sphincter!
(BOTH LAUGH)
Oh, oh. (GROANS) On! Oh, oh. Oh.
Legs are a little rubbery after
all that time sitting here.
Why don't you roll me inside?
We'll get the nurse to take
the catheter out of me. Oh.
I wanna see if my lizard's
still spitting straight.
We don't need nurses for that.
I know how to do it.
But don't you have to...
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(YELLING)
Oh, God!
That thing's really taken root!
(COUGHS) Hey, fellas!
Give me a hand over here. Si.
(HUFFS)
Yankos los pee-pee.
Are you sure about this, Har?
Usually, doctors like to
do this sort of thing.
Oh, that's just for
insurance purposes.
On three. Three!
(ALL GRUNTING) (YELLING)
(HARRY LAUGHING)
You are a fricking
genius, Lloyd!
I mean, nobody else could
have pulled that off!
Eh! Nobody!
I mean, the shock treatments,
the partial lobotomy!
That's commitment! Yeah.
It broke up the monotony.
One thing I don't get, though.
Why did you play it out
for 20 whole years?
Because it wouldn't have been
funny if I stopped too soon.
Comedy is all about timing, Har.
Yeah, but wouldn't it still have been
funny if you quit after 10 years?
Oh, definitely. But not as!
(BOTH LAUGH) Whoa!
Pretty bird.
LLOYD: Crap on toast!
Is that grown-up Billy in 4-C?
Uh-huh.
Come on, Siskel, give
me a movie quote.
What did they say
in Jerry Maguire?
"You had me at hello."
Um, Titanic?
"I'm king of the world."
(CHUCKLING) Good job!
(SOFTLY) We better
tiptoe past him.
Oh, no, you can't
tiptoe past a blindy.
Their hearing's too good.
What? Mmm-hmm.
That's just an old wives' tale.
Like women shouldn't
smoke during pregnancy.
I turned out fine. My mom
smoked like a chimney.
Especially when she was drinking!
(CHUCKLES)
Whatever. Doesn't matter.
Billy's over the
whole Petey thing.
You should see his apartment.
He's got the best rare
bird collection in Rhody!
(SCOFFS)
I gotta see this.
Hey, Billy!
I hear you got a lot of flocking birds.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Is that you, Lloyd? (CHUCKLES)
Very good.
I didn't think you'd recognize
me after all these years.
So what have you been
up to, buddy boy?
Seen any good movies lately?
I mean, you know, like...
On the radio?
What was that? (SQUAWKING)
Did you just feed
them something?
Relax.
It's just a little candy.
You can't feed candy to birds!
Their stomachs will explode!
Even if it's just
a few Pop Rocks?
Are you crazy? Pick those up!
Pick them up! All
right, all right!
Sheesh.
Well, nice catching up.
See you later.
Not if I see you first!
LLOYD: Ha-ha! Good one!
No, no, no, it's okay, Siskel.
Daddy's not gonna let him
get anywhere near you.
BOTH: Booga! (SCREAMING)
See? I told you
that hearing thing
was a wives' tale. (CHUCKLES)
Oh, yeah!
Hey, who's this? Ah.
That's Butthole.
I found him out in the
alley a couple years ago.
Why did you name him Butthole?
Oh.
Because of this.
Oh, yeah. Good name.
Totally fits.
I like what you've
done with the place.
(HUMMING) Nice
cappuccino machine.
Who's the astronaut?
Oh, that's my roommate.
Roommate?
You got a new roommate?
I had to get somebody to
pay your half of the rent
while you were in the hospital.
How's it going, Ice Pick?
Best day ever. Greatest
day of my life, really.
Pick cooks up a rock candy
that will make you dizzy.
Folks come from all over
the city to buy it.
It's burning my eyes.
Must be Cajun style.
So what's this serious medical
problem you've been blabbing about?
And it better be good.
Lloyd, there's something...
I've known about
this for a while,
but I didn't wanna worry you.
Mmm-hmm? (SIGHS)
I need a kidney transplant.
No way! Really?
Wow.
So what do you wanna
do for dinner tonight?
Wanna hit Haven Brothers?
I could eat the mud-hole out
of a dead skunk! (SNICKERING)
Are you not listening
to me, Lloyd?
Getting a new kidney
is a really big deal.
There's waiting lists, lots and
lots of forms to fill out,
and if I can't find another
kidney real soon, I'm dead meat.
Yeah, well,
maybe, just maybe,
there's a person out there
who cares about you so much
that said person
would be willing
to give up a little piece of
himself to save your life.
Really, Lloyd? You'd do that?
Me? (LAUGHING) Yeah, right!
Nice try!
The nerve! Oh.
I mean, I would, in a
New York heartbeat.
I'm just not a urine match.
(MEOWS)
My wizz doesn't get
all sudsy like yours.
(INHALES) Ow.
Wait. Don't panic. (YOWLING)
I know exactly what we gotta do.
(CRASHES)
I don't know about this, Lloyd.
I haven't been home
in over 20 years.
Come on, Harry!
You need a genital organ match.
They're your parents.
I'm not gonna go crawling
back to them, Lloyd.
Not after what they did to me.
What did they do?
They threw me out of the house.
Why? Just because I
told them I was gay.
Why did you tell them that?
I was sick of mowing the lawn.
Oh, yeah.
Well, I don't see
what choice you have.
You either go home
and face the music
or you suffocate
in your own pee.
Yeah, I guess you're right.
Okay, let's do this.
All right. Hop on.
Engage super thrusters!
Don't, Lloyd!
(COUNTRY MUSIC
PLAYING) (GRUNTING)
Pardon me, Harry.
(INAUDIBLE)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
Here we are.
Place looks smaller
than I remember.
Oh, yeah.
Wow.
Lot of memories on this street.
Yeah.
Remember when we
pulled up on the bike
and parked it a
couple seconds ago?
Yeah, that was cool.
Oh, those were the days.
I remember one afternoon,
it was the first day of spring,
the flowers were blooming,
the sun was shining
and you and I were
doing cartwheels
right down that hill over there.
Yeah, I remember that!
We were in your dad's
Lincoln, right? Yeah.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
You totally lost it when I yanked
the wheel. (BOTH LAUGHING)
(BOTH GRUNT)
Come on! Pick it up!
Show a little hustle in there!
(BOTH GASP)
Wow. Rong time, Harry!
Oh, sorry. We'll
come back later.
Hey! No, no, no! I mean,
rong time, no see.
BOTH: Oh. (BOTH CHUCKLE)
HARRY'S DAD: Where you been?
Come! Come in!
(CHUCKLING) Oh! Thanks, Dad.
So you see,
my best hope for a donor match
is with a blood relative.
Family.
(CHUCKLES)
Harry, you not touch
your peanut butter.
Oh, that's okay. I'm
not very hungry, Dad.
(CHUCKLES) When Harry young,
oh, boy, he loves
the peanut butter.
Oh. (CHUCKLES)
Three jar a week disappear!
Good to know.
So anyway, which one of you
two's gonna cough up a kidney?
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
What? What was that? (LAUGHING)
Wait!
I know! You're the
gopher from Caddyshack.
Look at her! She's got it down!
We love you, Harry.
Do you love him long time?
(CHUCKLES)
But you know you're not
our real son, right?
You adopted.
Ouch. (WHISTLES)
(GROANS)
(MAKES CREAKING NOISES)
Dad, what are you saying?
(SIGHS)
Sorry, Harry.
We thought you know.
Wow.
What a nut punch.
Don't be glum, Har.
All this means is that your real
parents are out there somewhere.
And I will go to the
ends of the earth to...
Real parents dead.
You're boned.
James boned.
HARRY'S MOM: Harry, Harry.
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
(LAUGHS)
(SNICKERING)
No idea what you're saying,
Ma, but right back at you.
Harry, before you go, your
mail piling up for many year.
Oh. We saving for you.
Huh. Junk mail, junk mail.
(MUMBLES)
I got accepted to Arizona State.
Hmm? (CHUCKLES)
Oh, look at this.
It's a postcard from
Fraida Felcher.
The chick from Cranston?
(CHUCKLING) Ooh!
So, what'd she have to say?
"Harry, I'm pregnant.
Please call me."
(GASPS) Lloyd, I'm
gonna be a dad!
No way!
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Look at the postmark.
1991.
Do you know what
this means, Harry?
You have a grown kid. Oh.
With grown kidneys.
But, Lloyd, we don't have a
phone number or address,
or nothing. And who we fooling?
Even if I find him, my
kid's never met me.
Why would he wanna
give me a kidney?
Are you serious?
After all you've done for him?
It's the least he can do.
What have I ever done for him?
You gave him his space.
Kids love that.
I didn't wanna be a
helicopter parent.
And you filled him with wonder.
Wonder? Yeah.
Like, "I wonder who
my deadbeat dad is?"
Oh, it's okay, Lloyd.
I've had a full life.
I was a paperboy for a week.
I fathered a child.
I've seen every episode
of Full House.
(MOUTHFUL) Wow!
Every episode?
Okay, Okay- So how are
we gonna do this?
If we find Fraida,
we find your kid.
If we find your kid,
we find your kidney.
Simple.
Yeah, but I never even
knew where Fraida lived.
I didn't have a car. She always
had to pick me up in her van.
Didn't you meet her
through Pete Stainer?
Who? Pee-Stain!
He'll know how to reach her.
Yeah, but I haven't talked to
Pee-Stain in a hundred years!
I can't drop by his house
in the middle of the night
and ask him for some
chick's number.
Sure you can!
Oh, okay. But we gotta
be sub-tull about it.
(CHUCKLES)
The word is pronounced
"subtle," Harry.
It's a silent "B."
(GRUNTS)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
What was that for?
You had a gah-nat on you.
Maybe we should catch a
bus to Pee-Stain's house.
We can't. We got the bike.
Oh, that's okay. They got bike
racks on the front of buses now.
LLOYD: Cool.
(GRUNTING)
Perfect.
That's very convenient.
BUS DRIVER: Hey, guys!
You forgot your bike!
Oh, it's not ours. Somebody
abandoned it in front of our place.
Yeah. Just left it there
double-chained to a tree.
Hey, Har.
You wanna hear the second most
annoying sound in the world?
Sure.
(BELL DINGING)
Yeah, that's pretty annoying.
No, not that.
(SCREAMING) What the
hell are you doing
ringing our doorbell like that
in the middle of the night?
That! (LAUGHS)
Mr. Stainer. Mrs. Stainer.
Nice to see you.
Harry, Lloyd.
To what do we owe the honor
at this late hour, gentlemen?
We were just wondering
if Pee-Stain
wanted to come out
for some suds.
And maybe have his
ass handed to him
in a couple of games of Dig Dug.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Lloyd.
Peter is dead.
Yeah, right. Since when?
(BOTH LAUGH)
Since 1991. Remember?
The motorcycle accident?
But I thought he pulled through.
The obituary said he was
survived by his parents.
Uh, no. He did not pull through.
Are you sure?
Yes.
LLOYD: Oh, yeah.
You guys are right. (CHUCKLES)
Anyway. Sorry about
that whole thing.
Pee-Stain and I were
very close friends.
MR. STAINER: Yeah, we know.
You're the one who sold
him the motorcycle.
LLOYD: And if I recall,
I made him a sweet deal.
My bike for his
helmet, straight up.
(CHUCKLING) That
thing was a rocket.
A little squirrelly
on the corners,
but when you got it
on a straightaway...
(IMITATING ENGINE REVVING) Good
night, Lloyd. Good night, Harry.
That was awkward.
You're not kidding.
When somebody comes to
your door at 3:00 a.m..
put some pants on! (CHUCKLES)
Hey, wait a second.
That's where I met
Fraida Felcher.
She worked at the funeral parlor
where they buried Pee-Stain.
Wow.
Think about it.
If I hadn't sold that
crotch rocket to Pee-Stain,
you wouldn't have
a bastard child
who's gonna save your life.
God's got a pretty warped
sense of humor, huh?
Yeah. I bet he smokes weed.
Otherwise, why would he put our
testicles outside our bodies
where someone could do this?
(GRUNTS) (LAUGHS)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS) Ow! (LAUGHS)
Bush club!
(LAUGHS)
What are you doing, Lloyd?
I'm about to meet my kid!
Sorry, Har.
Bushes like that don't
come along every day.
(GROANS)
Excuse me, sir. ls
Fraida working today?
I'm Fraida. LLOYD: Oh.
Sorry for the confusion.
We meant your smoking-hot
daughter, Fraida Junior.
There is no Fraida Junior.
I'm the only Fraida
in the family.
(SCOFFS) That little hottie
must have given us a fake name.
Look, guys, it's me,
Fraida Felcher.
(LAUGHING) Yeah, right.
Like we'd be fighting over those
blowfish jowls. (BOTH SNICKERING)
No offense.
Harry.
Lloyd.
I'm gonna say this
one more time.
I'm Fraida.
(WHISPERING) Tattoo.
Oh, Yeah?
Then show us your tattoo.
Mmm-hmm.
Because Fraida had a cute
little smiley face on her back
right above her bikini line.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Well?
Hmm.
It's close. Mmm.
Oh. Hi, Fraida.
Oh, hey! How you been?
Have you been doing yoga?
Yeah, I'm kind of busy. ls there
a reason you guys are here?
Yes.
I just received this postcard
that you sent me 22 years ago.
Talk about snail mail.
(CHUCKLES)
You better come in.
So, did you, uh,
ever have the baby?
I had a daughter. Named her Fanny.
(EXHALES)
You hear that, Har?
A little girl.
Fanny Felcher! Ow!
Are you all right? Uh, bad back.
Oh, I have so many
questions for you.
FRAIDA: Like?
HARRY: For starters,
how was the pregnancy?
Was it a tough one? Did
they have to saw you open?
Whoa, Har. Dial it down!
We're talking about the
miracle of childbirth here.
What my insensitive
friend meant was,
did you have a C-section
or were you able to have
the baby au snatch-urel?
It went smoothly. (SCOFFS)
So, uh, where is she?
Can I meet her?
(SIGHS)
I gave her up for adoption.
What?
Why? Because I was
broke and scared.
I regretted it as
soon as I did it.
But it was too late.
I'd already signed
away all my rights.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Then a couple years ago
I wrote her a letter.
But she never wrote me back.
Wait here.
What do we do now?
What do you mean,
"What do we do now?"
I mean, at this exact moment
in time, what do we do?
Harry, don't you hear that?
It's the fat lady singing.
It's over!
I need something to drink.
But... Harry, enough!
We tried and we failed!
As Vince Lombardi used to say,
you gotta know when to quit!
Hey, you should pick out one of
those coffins while we're here.
What if... Darn it, Har!
I cannot live on this emotional
roller coaster any longer.
I feel bad saying it,
but you're slunk meat.
Here's a picture I found
of my daughter online.
(GASPS)
Or, we could suck it up,
pick ourselves up
by our bootstraps
and go find that little girl!
(CHUCKLING)
(MUMBLES)
Hold on.
You wrote her a letter. You
must know where she lives!
Yeah. I tracked her down through
this adoption search site.
She was raised by this
hotshot scientist.
Why didn't you just go
find her in person?
If she doesn't want to meet me,
I am not going to
force myself on her.
Maybe she didn't
get your letter.
She got it, all right.
LLOYD: What if we go
track her down for you?
There's no lawsuit against that.
Are you guys serious?
You'd help me out?
Of course we'll help you out.
We're gonna need some wheels.
I'll lend you a car.
Then it's done.
Yeah, using this address and
our superior instincts,
you and your little girl
are gonna be having
a family reunion in no time.
Cheers!
Whoa! Wait. Where
did you get that?
The Slurpee machine in the back.
That's embalming fluid.
Oh.
Does it have aspartame?
No.
Cool.
(CHUCKLING)
Hey, guys, check this out!
(CHUCKLES)
(GROWLS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(LAUGHS)
(ALL LAUGH)
What about the blue roads
with the big numbers?
Those are rivers.
They're rivers? Yeah.
We could get a boat.
Boats are dangerous.
(TIRES SQUEAL)
This is it.
6765 Elmwood.
(SIGHS)
You look nervous.
I am nervous! I'm
about to meet my kid
and I don't know
what to say to her.
That's real easy, Har.
You make a little small talk about
why you missed all those birthdays,
holidays and graduations.
Maybe a couple of dick
jokes to put her at ease.
And boing, you hit her
up for the kidney.
Okay. What if she says no?
She's not gonna say no.
She's the fruit of your loom.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(GASPS)
Suck me sideways.
You're the spitting image of your mother.
(CHUCKLES)
You morons.
This is the return address.
Hers is on the side
with the stamp.
Oh.
But it's still uncanny!
(CHUCKLES)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
Oxford, Maryland, huh?
So that's where my little girl's
been living all these years.
Hey, Har!
Look it. Giant nutcracker.
(WHIRRING)
Oh. (CHUCKLES)
(IN DEEP VOICE) I want
your nuts, Harry!
(CHUCKLES)
Boy, I sure wish I could have been
there for her when she was little.
Whatever.
That's all water under
the fridge now, Har.
Think of the bright side.
You're finally
getting to meet her
and you never had to change
all those poopie diapers.
That's called being
a parent, Lloyd.
Besides, I changed your
poopie diapers for 20 years.
(LAUGHS)
I totally sucked you in.
Half the time, it
wasn't even my poop.
(CHUCKLES)
I wonder what it would have
been like to raise a child.
Maybe I couldn't afford to send
her to the best public schools,
but I'll bet I would have
been a pretty good dad.
You don't need training wheels.
You can do this.
Here we go!
MAN: Come on, come on!
(ALL CHEERING) No way!
That was awesome!
Awesome!
Perfect. Okay.
One,
two,
three.
(GROANS)
(CHUCKLING)
Hey, Mr. Dunne.
Hello, Baxter. How are you?
Good to see you.
Here you go, honey.
Thank you, Mr. Dunne! Bye, Dad!
Isn't that good? Mmm-hmm.
LLOYD: Mr. Dunne!
Mr. Dunne!
Hey, Mr. Dunne!
Do you mind?
Bon appétit, kid!
(MUNCHING)
(SQUEAKING)
Lloyd!
What are you doing?
I was trying to clean
off this smudge!
But you know what?
I think it might be on the inside!
(LAUGHS)
(EXHALES) (HORN HONKING)
ANNOUNCER: This type of
evening always provides
nonstop surprises.
Ah, look who's arrived.
Tom Brady
with his gorgeous wife,
Gisele, by his side.
Doesn't she look radiant?
Tom's in agreement, I think.
Now that is hot.
Yep-
That's why he gets
all the girls.
(TURNS OFF TV)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
It sure would be nice. (EXHALES)
What would be nice, Lloyd?
Oh! You know,
if she introduced me to one
of her hot girlfriends.
(CHUCKLING) Girlfriends.
She's 22!
So?
So, that's a lot
younger than you.
Don't worry, when we get home,
I'm gonna fix you up with
someone your own age.
My age? Gross!
I mean, what would
we talk about?
I don't know. Same stuff you
talked about in high school
when you took chicks down to
Oyster Swallow Cove. (LAUGHS)
Oyster Swallow Cove.
There's a trip
down Mammary Lane.
(BOTH GIGGLING)
Oh, crap!
We gotta get back to Providence!
What? Why?
Remember I told you
Ice Pick had to make
that rock candy run
down to Maine?
Yeah.
I forgot to get someone to
feed Butthole. (SCOFFS)
Relax. I took care of it.
You did?
Yeah. Billy in 4-C's
gonna feed him.
(CHUCKLING) Oh, great!
Did you give him the
key to our apartment?
No.
You think I want wheel
marks all over the rug?
I just wrote him a
note, left some food
and threw Butthole inside his
place when we were leaving.
But, Lloyd, Billy has over a
hundred rare birds in there!
So?
They're not gonna mess
with a 30-pound alley cat.
(CHUCKLES) Sheesh!
Hey, gang! I'm home!
Guys?
(WHISTLING)
You sure are quiet.
(PARTS)
(SQUAWKS) Speak to me, Siskel.
The horror! The horror!
(HORN HONKING)
Are you sure you don't
wanna come, Dad?
It's not gonna be nearly
as much fun without you.
Oh, of course I
wanna come, monkey,
but it's out of the question.
(COUGHING)
I'm way too flu-ey to travel.
But all the geeky science guys
are gonna be so disappointed.
They were finally gonna get
to meet you in person!
PINCHELOW: So sorry, honey.
Ms. Pinchelow, your car is here.
PENNY: Thanks, Travis!
Okay!
Take care of my dad, Adele.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, whoa!
Penny, do you have the
speech I wrote for you?
I do.
Good. Oh!
I almost forgot. There's
one more thing.
I want you to take this box
and personally give it to the head
of the conference, Dr. Walcott,
and say how sorry I am
that I can't be there.
Got it.
Oh, what's in the box, honey?
Mmm.
Just a small gift.
Wow, Penny. You're
giving a speech?
Oh, it's only a couple of
sentences on the last day,
but then I'm picking up
a reward for my dad.
Award, honey.
Did you remember to bring
the ATM card I gave you?
Yes. But what's my PIN number again?
I keep forgetting.
It's 11-11.
I thought it had to
be four numbers.
There are four numbers.
One-one-one-one.
(HORN HONKING)
Time to go! Come on, Penny.
(BARKING)
Aw!
Are you smiling at me?
He's a good boy! Yes, he is!
Let me see your purty teeth!
Oh! Say it, don't spray it!
(CHUCKLES)
(MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
We're almost there. The guy told
me to get off at the next exit.
Shh. They're picking
the lottery balls.
ANNOUNCER: Here's today's Mega-Lottery
picks, worth 34 million dollars.
The first number is 44.
The next is 2.
38, 24, 21 and 54.
Cripes! I was so close!
I had all the right numbers,
but in the wrong order.
PINCHELOW: Honey, my
stomach is killing me.
Can you bring me
some more Pepto?
I'm making you some
nice warm oatmeal.
It will settle your tummy.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
What are you doing?
I'm fixing lunch for my husband.
That's not enough.
(SCOFFS)
We gotta pick up the pace a little bit.
We want him dead
before Dumbelina gets back from
that egghead convention, remember?
Slow it down.
If we put too much in at once,
it could show up in an autopsy.
Not this stuff.
I got it from my twin brother.
He's Special Ops.
It's totally undetectable.
Now come on. Let's
hurry this up.
That way we have a few
extra days to ourselves,
to enjoy our inheritance.
Oh, there's gonna be
plenty of time for that.
Five million dollars
buys a lot of champagne.
(MOANING)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(WHISPERING) Give it to me.
(SIGHS)
(MOANS)
You like that, don't you?
Yeah. It's all right.
(MOANS)
I'll be honest. It's
not my favorite thing.
(DOORBELL DINGING RAPIDLY)
Who the hell is that?
Boy, this is quite
a shack, huh, Har?
Yeah, but I bet if you pulled
the weeds off the walls
and slapped up some aluminum
siding, it wouldn't be half bad.
Yeah. Those things
are rat ladders.
ADELE: Please stop that.
There's a very sick man in
here who's trying to rest.
I'm sorry, lady! We're
looking for Fanny Felcher!
The one with the kidneys.
Is she there?
There is no one here
by that horrible name.
Now go away.
Is this 6765 Elmwood Avenue,
Cranston, Rhode Island?
ADELE: You're in Maryland.
(GROANING) The side
with the stamp!
(STAMMERING) I mean, uh, is
this 1111 Foothill Road?
That's right.
But there are no Felchers here.
This is the Pinchelow residence.
Wait a second. My
friend Harry here
gave his daughter up for
adoption 20-something years ago
and we were told this
is where she lives.
It's kind of a medical
emergency that we find her.
As long as she doesn't have AIDS.
(INTERCOM BEEPS)
PINCHELOW: Adele, darling,
whoever they are,
they must be talking
about Penny!
She was adopted.
I'll see them. Let them in.
(INTERCOM BUZZING)
What the hell was that?
That's exactly the kind of
random crap we don't need!
Relax.
Would you like some
hot tea with lemon?
Oh, no. I can see why
you might think that.
Two gentlemen
traveling together.
But we're straight.
PINCHELOW: I must
tell you, Harry,
this is an unexpected treat.
Yeah! Me, too.
You know, I always wondered what
Penny's natural father was like.
When my late wife
and I adopted her,
we weren't given much information
about her birth parents.
We were only told that her mother
was single and that she was...
You can say it, dear.
She was rumored to
be a titanic whore.
That's a lie! Fraida never
stepped foot on the Titanic!
They must be talking about the
time she did the night crew
on the Block Island Ferry.
(PINCHELOW LAUGHING)
That's good!
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
So, is Penny here?
Unfortunately, no.
She flew out this
morning to El Paso.
She's going to the
KEN Conference.
What? Who's this Ken guy?
No. No.
The KEN Conference
is a symposium
where the year's
newest technologies,
creative concepts and ideas
are introduced and discussed.
Wow.
That's the single most boring
sentence I ever heard.
Adele, what do you say
we call Penny right now
with the news that her biological
father is looking for her?
She'll be so excited.
She might not be as excited
as you think, Doc.
When her mother tried to
get in touch with her,
she sent this letter right back.
PINCHELOW: Mmm.
That's interesting.
What's that, dear?
Uh, nothing.
She just, uh, never
mentioned it.
But that was a
couple of years ago.
I'm sure she'll appreciate all
the trouble you've gone to
to find her. Let's call her.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
It's ringing! (CELL
PHONE BUZZING)
(BEEPS)
(WHISPERING) Whoever this is,
we're in the middle of
something really important.
Can you call back later?
No, I can't call back later.
I have something to tell you that
might freak you out a little bit,
but this is your dad.
(WHISPERING) What? Hold on.
Hey, guys, I know this is weird
timing, but I gotta take this.
It's my dead dad.
She's got me on hold.
Dad, what did you do with
all those Penthouses?
Did you throw them out?
No, they're under my mattress.
Why?
You idiot, that
is Penny's phone!
Oh.
Oh, no. No.
No! This is awful!
She forgot the package!
What are you doing?
You shouldn't be up!
Just relax. We can
overnight it to her.
No! No. We can't.
The culmination of my
life's work is in this box.
It's much too valuable to ship.
(STAMMERING) I thought you
said it was just a gift.
Oh, it is.
A gift to all humanity.
I wanted it to be a surprise, Adele.
(EXHALES)
That's why I was unveiling
it at the KEN Conference.
Wow.
Something like that's gotta
be worth millions, huh?
Try billions. Billions?
PINCHELOW: Oh, yes. But
I won't get a dime.
It would be morally wrong
to profit from this.
Huh?
This box contains one
of the most important
discoveries in human history
and all mankind deserves
free access to it
and that is why I
have relinquished
all proprietary rights.
Wait, when did you do that?
It's all in the speech
that Penny's going to read
at the award ceremony.
Oh, my God, that's so nice!
(CHUCKLES)
What in God's name?
You guys sounded busy, so
we built a couch-fort.
You wanna come in, Dr. P?
Sorry, no girls allowed.
Boys rule, girls drool.
(LAUGHING)
Wait a minute.
I have an idea.
Why don't we have
Harry and Lloyd
hand-deliver the box to Penny?
(GASPS)
That way Harry will get to
meet his daughter in person
and you'll be assured the
box gets there safely.
(CHUCKLES)
(WHISPERING) Are you insane?
You think I'm just going to hand over
my invention to these 10-year-olds?
Oh, don't you worry. We'll
have Travis go with them.
He won't let anything
happen to the box.
And he will lead them
straight to Penny.
LLOYD: You can count on us, sir.
Our word is our bond.
(IN DEEP VOICE) James Bond.
(YELLS)
(BOTH GIGGLING)
I'm going with them? Why the
hell did you tell him that?
Do you not realize what
just fell into our laps?
Our five million just
turned into a billion.
LLOYD: What's wrong
with this thing?
Yeah, but he said he was
gonna give it all away.
Not if we get to Penny before
she reads that speech.
LLOYD: Hey,
when is this KEN thing, anyway?
It actually starts today,
but Penny doesn't give her speech
until the night of May 2nd.
So that gives us...
How many days are in April?
"Thirty days have September,
"all the rest I can't remember."
Must be 31 because nothing
rhymes with August.
LLOYD: No, I think it's 32, Har.
April's a leap month.
31. 32.
31.31,1,1,1! 2,2,2!
30! There's 30!
Thank you!
You said 31.
Yeah, but I was closer.
TRAVIS: Hey, guys,
where's the box?
What box?
The box with the billion-dollar
invention in it.
Lloyd, what did you
do with the box?
Me? You had it.
No, remember we stopped
at that truck stop
and we were kicking
field goals with it
out in that parking lot?
LLOYD: Yeah.
I remember I kicked one over the
telephone wires, and you said...
You know what, you're right.
I did have it.
Look at that! (HARRY GASPS)
(SING SONG) I just
saved humanity!
You know what? Maybe I
should hold on to that box.
I don't think so, mister.
Dr. P encrusted that to me.
And I'm gonna make sure it gets
to my daughter, safe and sound.
Yeah, well, you're doing
a great job so far.
You guys wanna play
"He Who Smelt it"?
Yeah.
What's that?
It's complicated,
so pay attention.
We put the windows up, first one
who smells a fart gets a point.
If you say who dealt
it, double points.
But if you say you
smelled a fart
and nobody farted,
like if we were just passing
a slaughterhouse...
False fart!
...you lose a point. And you can't
smell your own farts, either.
Are you guys kidding? No! No!
I'm not gonna sit around sniffing your
farts like some kinda truffle pig.
Forget it! (CHUCKLES)
Okay, fine. Lloyd and I
will play one-on-one.
Yeah, head-to-head.
How can you play one-on-one?
If you smell a fart,
and you didn't do it,
isn't it obvious
the other guy did?
I thought you said you
never played before.
Yeah. Sounds like he
wrote the rulebook.
I think we might have
a hustler here, Har.
Uh-huh.
What are you doing?
I forgot.
TRAVIS: Uh, you know what?
I'm going to make a rule.
There will be no fart games
while I'm in the car, got it?
Wow.
Who made you king of the car?
I know how to settle this.
I'm thinking of a number
between one and three.
Whoever guesses it gets
to be king of the car.
One! No.
Three? Nope.
Okay, what is it?
Two.
(GROANS) (YELLING) I swear
I was gonna say that!
All right, so it's agreed,
I'm king of the car, right?
Fine.
Excuse me, Your Highness,
would you grab me a Slim
Jim out of the back?
One of the long ones.
TRAVIS: Yeah. (GRUNTS)
(BOTH FARTING)
TRAVIS: Oh, hey, what the hell?
On, God! Hey!
No! Hey!
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMING)
What is that? Oh, God!
(GROANING)
Look, Harry.
He's hooked on crack.
(LAUGHING)
TRAVIS: For the love
of God, have mercy!
HERBERT: Hello, you've
reached Herbert Felcher
at Felcher and Felcher
Funeral Parlor.
Please leave a message at the beep.
(BEEPS)
Hi! This is a private
message for Fraida Felcher.
Would you please tell
Fraida that Harry called?
Harry Dunne.
The guy who knocked her up
20-something years ago.
Um, pleasure finally meeting
you all, by the way.
Anyway, would you tell her that
I've located our daughter.
(CAMERA CLICKS)
She's at a thing called the
KEN Conference in El Paso.
The town named after
the bean dip.
(BABY CRYING)
Oh, that's sweet!
Bye, Grandma!
(IN MAN LY VOICE)
Have fun, sweetie.
WOMAN: Now, there's a real man.
I bet you he don't
pee sitting down.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
Don't touch that joystick!
(STRAINING)
(AIR HISSING)
(BOTH GASP)
STUDENT: Wow, look!
Let my people
go! (ALL SCREAM)
Harry!
(GRUNTING)
It hurts, Lloyd.
It hurts so bad.
Which one hurts, Harry? This one?
Or this one? (GROANS)
Stop it! Lloyd, please,
save my daughter.
And then
I want you to bone her
like a chicken cutlet.
You hear me, mister?
(GASPS) (CHOKES)
(ALL GASP)
(SCREAMING)
Huh?
(ALL GRUNT)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS) (GROANS)
(GASPS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
Looking for these?
(LAUGHS) (SNIFFLES)
(CHOKING)
(WHISTLES) Oh!
What are you doing?
Oh. Uh...
She's all clean, sir.
You're good to go.
(MUTTERING) Nutcase.
Hey, guys.
(SPITS)
(SIGHS) Let's call a truce, huh?
I think we got off
on the wrong foot.
I don't wanna argue with you guys
all the way down to El Paso.
So what do you say? Peace?
Come on, bring it in!
(CHUCKLES) Yeah, why not?
Hmm.
Okay-
Hey, all right. All right,
that's good. Mmm...
All right, all right, all right.
Aw.
Hey! Have you guys ever
played "Funnel Nuts"?
What?
Oh, come on. You guys have
had to play Funnel Nuts.
This is the best
game ever invented.
Check it out, you
take the funnel,
you put it in the front of
your pants like that, right?
Okay? Then you put a peanut
on your nose like this,
and then when you're ready...
No way!
You gotta be kidding!
That's not right!
(TRAVIS CHUCKLES)
The person who gets
the most nuts wins.
Now, who's gonna play me first?
I'll do it. I got it.
This is mine! You
always go first!
I got it first!
Guys, hold on, all right? Look.
You guys play each other first,
and then I'll play the winner.
All right.
All right. Here you go.
Take your time. It takes time.
Get a good balance on that.
Okay. Look way up high.
Good. Okay, keep looking at the sky.
When you're ready.
Now don't drop it until
you're ready, guys.
I got it!
(BLOWING RASPBERRY)
That's weird. Ooh!
The smell of peanuts makes
my weenie cold. Ooh!
It shrank mine.
(CHUCKLING)
Oh!
Hey!
(CHUCKLING)
Do you believe that? Did
you see what he did?
It's on!
Oh, yeah.
He's going down!
Right after we finish
playing Funnel Nuts.
(WHISPERING) Shh. Don't wake him up!
I know.
How many did you put in there?
Just enough to get
a rise out of him.
(BOTH GIGGLE)
(SNORING)
(FIRECRACKERS BURSTING)
(SCREAMING)
No! Oh, God!
No! Oh, my God!
(SCREAMING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(GROANING)
Oh, my God!
Wait, Lloyd. I think
he might be hurt.
(GROANING)
Man, you okay? It
was just a goof.
Yeah. By the way, we're even.
I want them dead, now!
Now! Do you hear me?
ADELE: (WHISPERING) Calm down.
No! No, I can't
take it any longer!
(EXHALES) If you don't
let me kill them now,
I am quitting, and I mean it!
Okay. Give me some
time to think.
I'll come up with a plan.
Plan? You don't need a plan!
These guys are morons!
Besides, I told you, my
brother's in Special Ops.
I know how to get stuff done!
All right. But make sure nobody
knows they paid us a visit.
I don't want this
coming back to us.
God, shut up! (BEEPS)
I wonder what's in this sucker.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
That thing is worth a fortune!
Be careful!
Give it to me.
It would be nice to know
what's in it, though.
I've been racking
my sack about that.
I have a theory.
(CHUCKLES) Oh, yeah?
He said it was something that would
help everybody in the world, right?
Yeah.
I think it might
be a baked potato.
How does a baked potato help
everybody in the world?
That's the only part I
haven't figured out yet.
You'll get it, Lloyd.
We should pick up some sour
cream and chives, just in case.
Do you guys have any
idea where we are?
Not really.
You're the one who told us to take
the shortcut off the highway.
Yeah. It's like you wanted to get
us alone, so you could kill us
and take the billion-dollar box.
But what would be the motive?
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
I better get a map
out of the bag, huh?
Sure. Okay.
TRAVIS: So, guys, who else is
helping you look for your daughter?
HARRY: No one. LLOYD: Mmm-hmm.
TRAVIS: Nobody?
Not even some friends to lend a hand?
Mmm-mmm.
Nope, just us.
What about your wives?
LLOYD: Wives?
How stupid do we look?
(CHUCKLES)
Harry?
Easy.
(INHALES)
(SIGHS)
Close one. Any girlfriends?
Been there, done that.
See, we don't want to be tied
down by anything or anyone.
We don't even have
social security cards.
We sold them for 30 bucks
to two Brazilian guys.
And the good thing about
having no identity
is that you never have to
worry about identity theft.
He can't even be
identified by his teeth
because he's never even
been to a dentist.
And I've never joined anything.
Ever.
That's how you keep a low-pro.
Yep, there's no actual
proof that we even exist.
LLOYD: If we died, no
one would even miss us.
We are truly blessed.
(EXPLOSION) (TIRES SCREECHING)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(MUFFLED) What the
hell happened, Harry?
What?
What the hell happened?
(LAUGHING) Whoo! HARRY:
I can't hear you!
So long, boys. (SCREAMS)
(INAUDIBLE)
We may have been involved in
an alien abduction, Harry.
Is your butt okay?
(GASPING)
Harry!
Holy crap!
He took off on us!
What?
He took off on us.
LLOYD: I can't believe that
douchebag stole our hearse.
I hope something really
bad happens to him.
No, but I tried ostrich once.
Harry, holy cow.
I'm worried about you.
You're as deaf as a bat.
That's not exactly how
it happened, Lloyd.
Your mother got
into bed with me.
That's it. We're getting
you hearing aids.
RECEPTIONIST: May I help you?
Um...
My friend here would like to
visit his sweet ol' grandma.
What's the name?
LLOYD: I'll give you a hint.
She's the one with the
biggest hearing aids.
Ms. Snergle, your grandson
and his friend are here.
This is stupid, Lloyd!
I'm not gonna steal an
old lady's hearing aid!
(SHUSHING)
Relax!
We're just looking
for a backup pair.
There's gotta be
some around here.
Mikey?
Yeah, Gran.
It's Mikey.
MRS. SNERGLE: Oh, thank
God you're here.
I've got the diamonds.
Did she say diamonds?
(CLICKING TONGUE)
Go ahead, Granny.
Mikey's listening.
I want you to take all the
diamonds with you when you go.
I've been hiding them from
those thieving lawyers.
That's good.
Granny did a good thing!
So, where are the rocks?
They're underneath me.
You mean, under the bed?
No, under the blanket. Oh.
(MOANS)
I'm not finding anything.
(CHUCKLES)
Go up more.
Up here? Keep going.
Did you hide them
inside this turkey?
Yeah, right.
(INHALES) Wait.
There's no diamonds here!
And you're not my grandson!
Harry, she's got me.
She's really clamping down!
(GRUNTS)
Ahhh! (GASPS)
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
Lloyd?
(GIGGLING) I think that
was her gran-gina.
That's right!
So you can cross that one
off your bucket list!
(BLOWS) (BOTH COUGHING)
Hey, Goldfinger!
Here. (CHUCKLES)
You've earned them. (GIGGLING)
Are you serious?
Travis is dead?
LIPPINCOTT: That's right.
The Kansas state police
informed me this morning.
I thought you'd want to know.
(SIGHS)
Thank you, Captain Lippincott.
I know it's never easy to
relay this kind of sad news.
But I want you to know
that your brother, Travis,
was more than just
a handyman to us.
He was
family. (CHUCKLES)
LIPPINCOTT: Really?
Do you suck the toe jam
off Mommy and Daddy, too?
Um, I beg your pardon?
My brother told me everything.
(GASPS)
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Look, lady, I know you're
terminating your husband.
I'm the one who supplied
you with the untraceables.
Remember? I also know
that my brother was supposed
to eliminate those two idiots,
but somehow they turned
the tables on him.
Relax.
I'm not here to turn you in.
I'm here to help you out.
So how are those things working?
Not bad. I can
hear you a little.
Here, let me turn them up.
Honey, would you
like some pancakes?
Yeah, I'd love some pancakes.
What? (SCREAMS)
Stop yelling! (GROANS)
I'm not yelling.
Why would you say I'm yelling?
(YELLING) This is yelling!
(GROANING)
Harry!
I think I might have
turned them up too high!
Oh, look! Barbara Hershey Highway.
(CHUCKLES)
Wait a minute.
I think I know where we are.
Follow me.
Are you sure about this, Lloyd?
Positive. The kid worked at the
hockey rink just past the museum.
Come on, Harry!
He drove a Zamboni!
(BOTH GASP)
Oh, my God. I never thought
I'd see her again.
I don't know if I
told you this, Har,
but that kid kinda porked me when
I traded him for the mini bike.
And he only gave me a
quarter-tank of gas.
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
(TIRES SQUEAL)
(BRAKES SCREECH)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(HORN HONKING)
Yeah!
(SNORING)
Bush club!
Bush club! Bush club! Bush club!
(GROANING)
(LAUGHING)
I feel really good, Har.
Me, too!
Really good!
You might want to
step on it, Har!
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(HORN HONKING)
Wow, look at all the brains.
(SING SONG) They're
blinding me with science!
Okay, Lloyd. I'm gonna find out
what time this thing starts.
You keep an eye out for Penny.
Roger that.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is an AMBER Alert.
Has anybody seen this
lovely, delicate angel?
Have you seen her?
Lovely and delicate.
This girl is slammin'.
Oh, yeah, sure, I know her.
I got a hit.
It's, uh, Penny Pinchelow.
I met her at the bar yesterday.
What's that supposed to mean?
Whoa! Easy, hoser!
We just hung out a little.
Oh.
Do you happen to know
where she is right now?
Yeah, my, uh, friends just went
to meet her at her hotel room.
They're walking her over here.
She's giving a speech tonight.
When you see her,
tell her that Lloyd and her
dad are looking for her.
And get her to call me on this.
LLOYD: There you are!
I've been looking
all over for you.
Cool!
I just ran into a Mexican
guy who knows Penny.
He said she's on her way!
Come on, let's get in line.
(SOFTLY) Dressed like this?
Harry, people who come to
these things are smart.
We can't go in there looking
like a couple of goofballs.
Oh, yeah. Let's go buy
some smart stuff.
How's your day?
Living the dream.
Ooh, that mac and
cheese looks good!
Um, I think I'm gonna
need some chopsticks
or a really, really skinny fork.
You got it.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
It's open!
Hey, Penny!
Hey, Tom! Hey, Gus!
Hey, uh, Penny. Um...
What are you doing
in your undies
in front of the room service guy here, eh?
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
You don't know him.
Oh, no. Someone told me this great
trick about how not to get nervous
when you're giving a speech.
All you do is imagine that
you're in your underwear.
So I've been practicing
all afternoon.
Will there be
anything else, ma'am?
Oh, no. Just that skinny fork.
Right.
Okay. Burning daylight.
Yeah. Oh! Great news. Your dad
showed up for the conference.
(GASPS) What? Yeah,
Gordy just called us.
He ran into some guy named Lloyd
who was with your father.
They were looking for them out
front of the convention hall.
BARBARA: Oh, my goodness.
Are you absolutely certain?
And there's no way
you're mistaken?
All right, um, yes,
then I'll have someone
meet him at the door in a hurry.
(CHUCKLES) Yes, okay. Goodbye.
What is it?
Dr. Pinchelow is coming.
What? Are you certain?
I thought he was sick!
Apparently he's better.
I just spoke with his
daughter, Penny, on the phone
and she's headed right
over here to meet him.
Oh, the man didn't even show
up for his Nobel ceremony.
He showed up for us.
Go find him.
Uh, yeah, yeah, I'm on it.
Lloyd, look!
Penny is speaking soon.
That's so hot. (CHUCKLES)
ADELE: Is it done? (SIGHS) No.
Some Canadian douchebags barged
in before I could finish her.
Okay-
You follow Penny, and the next
chance you get, kill her.
I'll take out the
guys, get the box.
What if they have already
gone into the KEN conference?
Not a chance.
The event's been sold out for over a
year, and the security is insane.
Tickets, please.
No, thank you.
We're not much for
boring speeches.
We just have to make sure that
his daughter gets this box.
No tickie, no entry.
No exceptions.
BARBARA: Have you found Dr.
Pinchelow yet?
No. I don't even know
what he looks like.
This is ridiculous.
How am I supposed to find
the man in this throng
when all I know about him is
that he wears hearing aids?
Great. It's sold out. I'm dead.
So much for higher education.
(GROANS)
Relax, Har.
We're gonna find her. Don't get
that dying kidney all worked up.
Oh, it's not the kidney.
I think I gotta pinch a loaf.
Pinchelow? Did someone
say Pinchelow?
Oh, my goodness, it is you!
You're really here!
I'm Dr. Meldmann.
How was your trip from Maryland?
Not so great.
Somebody stole our car and he
finger-bombed an old lady.
(CHUCKLES)
Sounds terrible.
We'll take really good care
of you now that you're here.
Uh, would you like
to go into the foyer
for the cocktail reception, Dr.
Pinchelow?
Oh. Yes, Dr. Pinchelow
would love to go
to the foyer for the
cocktail reception.
Yeah, cool. Let's get ripped.
(CLEARS THROAT) Uh,
this way, please.
I'm sorry, your name is?
I'm his associate, Dr.
Christmas.
Ah, Christmas like the holiday?
No. (CHUCKLES) Like the tree.
(DR. MELDMANN CHUCKLES)
May I ask you a
question, Doctor,
and I don't mean
to be insensitive,
but, uh, does Dr. Pinchelow
have Asperger's?
Probably.
I know he doesn't
wipe real well.
Why don't you gentlemen
make yourselves at home.
I'm gonna go fetch the, uh,
director of the conference,
Dr. Barbara Walcott.
She can't wait to meet you.
Dr. Barbara? A lady doctor?
Seriously?
Lady doctor, that
always cracks me up.
Yeah, doctor of doing
the laundry, maybe.
Am I right?
(BOTH SNICKERING)
I'll be right back.
What were you thinking, Lloyd?
Now he thinks we're doctors.
At least we're in the door.
Now all we gotta do is act intelligent.
We'll fit right in.
Okay- (MUSIC PLAYING)
Hi, barkeep.
How much for a beer?
It's gratis.
Ooh.
That sounds expensive.
Can you give us a moment?
Lloyd, we blew our money
on the graduation robes.
Maybe we shouldn't drink.
No way. I need booze, man.
If I meet your daughter
without a buzz on,
she'll think I'm an idiot.
(HUFFS)
LLOYD: Hey, wait a minute!
What about the old Stinkeroo?
(SIGHS) Yeah, I'm in. (CHUCKLES)
(SCRATCHING)
(EXHALES)
Excuse me, ma'am. Yes?
This beer smells funky.
Can I have a new one, please?
What do you mean "funky"?
Go ahead, take a sniff.
(SNIFFS) Ew!
I'll get you a freshie.
Mine is stinky, too.
(GAGGING)
Yours smells even worse!
(CHUCKLES) I'll be right back.
"Yours smells even worse."
Thanks! (BOTH CHUCKLING)
You're really good
at that, Lloyd.
I learned from the best.
Thanks, Mom.
I can't wait to see
what's in this.
Yeah. Hey, Har? Mmm?
Do you know how long
you have to wait
after kidney surgery
to have sex?
I don't think I'll
have to wait too long.
No, not you. I meant
the donor chick.
What are you talking about?
Okay! Fine!
Let's just drop it!
Here you go, doctors.
Fresh beers.
And I also brought you some
hydroponically grown goji berries
with vegan barbecue sauce
and some organic pumpkin chips.
Enjoy.
Why, thank you! Mmm.
BOTH: Mmm.
Mmm.
These are salty. Mmm-hmm.
Try these.
Mmm.
Yours are super tangy.
I like it a lot.
DR. MELDMANN: Gentlemen.
I'd like you to meet the
director of the conference,
Dr. Barbara Walcott.
And, Barbara, this is Dr.
Pinchelow
and his associate, Dr.
Christmas.
Wonderful. It is a high
honor to meet you both.
Wow. Great accent, doc.
Where you from?
England. Surrey.
Oh, no need to apologize.
That was years ago.
We kicked your butt anyway,
so we're cool with it.
(BOTH LAUGH)
(LAUGHS)
BARBARA: Oh, you're
a leg-puller!
(CHUCKLES) Let's get you
both to your seats.
Professor Garabedian's KEN
talk is about to begin.
Now, the existence of dark
matter is largely inferred
from the gravitational
effect on visible matter
and the gravitational lensing
of background radiation.
We saved two seats for you at
the end of the second row.
Just there.
...because they were trying to
figure out the discrepancies...
You could actually
go in the front.
HARRY: Coming through.
LLOYD: My bad!
Here we go. Oops!
Wow. Is that silk?
(LAUGHS)
That sucks!
That's good. Sorry.
Watch my knee.
We make a better door
than a window, don't we?
(TALKING)
LLOYD: I hope this isn't
your favorite part.
HARRY: There are a couple
of hotties over here.
I got it! (YELLING) Oh!
(CHUCKLES)
That was easy!
That Dr. Pinchelow is certainly
a fascinating character.
Of course he is. He's a genius.
Indeed, the Large Hadron
Collider has already shown us
that dark matter is likely...
Especially when you eat prunes!
(FARTING NOISES) (CHUCKLES)
Yes. (CHUCKLES)
(STAMMERING) That dark
matter is likely...
(FARTING NOISES) (CHUCKLES)
...the missing piece
of the puzzle
that physicists have been
searching for, for years.
BOTH: (CHANTING) Nerd!
Nerd! Nerd! Nerd!
(CROWD MUMBLING)
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Holy crap!
(CHUCKLING) Did
that come from you?
Dr. Garabedian is a
world-renowned astrophysicist
and many of us are interested
in hearing his findings.
I'm reading his mind. Mmm-hmm.
I'm picking it up, too.
Who is that?
(WHISPERING) It's Dr. Pinchelow!
Bernard Pinchelow?
AUTOMATED VOICE: Dark matter
is not a joke. (SQUEAKS)
Your antics are proving
to be disruptive.
Thank you, Dr. Dilbeck,
but Dr. Pinchelow is right.
My dark matter data was insufficient.
(CROWD MURMURING)
What the fuck?
My methods were sloppy.
I'm a hack. (CROWD GASPS)
(SOBBING) I'm really sorry.
See?
Eat me. Suck it!
You wish. Lloyd. Lloyd.
Thank you, Professor Garabedian.
That's what the KEN
Conference is all about.
Truth.
But I will ask that
everyone please behave
in a professional
and dignified...
BOTH: Show us your tits!
(CROWD GASPS)
HARRY: Both Of them!
LLOYD: (CHUCKLING) Yeah!
We're just gonna take a short
two-minute break. Thank you!
(CHUCKLING)
Man.
Hey, this is great!
We're learning so much
about dark matter.
(FARTING NOISE) (LAUGHING)
Yes, indeed.
Uh, I'm sorry, Dr. Pinchelow,
but we can't seem to find Dr.
Christmas on the roster.
Oh, that's okay. He's with me.
Due to security concerns everyone
must be on the list to get in.
It's all right, Doctor.
I think I know a shakedown
when I see one.
I'll tell you what.
I'm gonna write an IOU and
I'm gonna leave it blank.
Anybody have a pen?
There are no exceptions.
Really?
I'll tell you what, warden.
If I'm leaving,
then my steamed colleague
is leaving with me.
No, he's not.
Quick conference.
(WHISPERING) What
are you doing, Har?
You're killing me!
Lloyd, I can't leave.
Penny is gonna be speaking soon.
I wanna meet her!
What?
How come you get to
meet her before I do?
Lloyd, this is about me.
Me, my daughter and my kidney.
That's why we're here, remember?
How can I forget? It's
all you ever talk about.
Penny and my kidney.
My kidney and Penny.
To tell you the truth, I'm
getting a little sick of it.
Wait a minute.
I know what you're
up to, mister.
(CHUCKLING)
You wanna stay because
you're hot for my daughter!
What? Am I right?
That's insane!
Don't deny it, Lloyd!
You have been drooling over her
ever since you first
saw her picture.
So what?
I'm not gonna apologize for letting
nature take its course, Har.
I hate to burst your
butthole, mister.
It ain't gonna happen.
It's my job to
protect my daughter.
Protect her?
(CHUCKLING) Look who's talking!
You're trying to swindle
her out of a kidney!
At least I'm gonna marry her.
Marry her? No.
You're not gonna marry. Why not?
No! Lloyd, you are not going
to marry my daughter.
Why? Because she's a tick younger than me?
Get over it.
Age is just a letter, man.
It's got nothing to do with age!
It's got to do...
With what?
I'm her father, Lloyd,
and, frankly,
I think she can do better.
Oh...
Okay-
(GAGGING)
(CLICKING TONGUE)
Time to go, Doctor.
All right, buddy.
(WHIMPERING) Harry?
GUARD: Let's go.
LLOYD: Harry?
Harry?
Dr. Walcott just had
a wonderful idea.
How would you like
to come with us
and judge the Young
Inventors competition?
Yeah, cool. Let's judge shit.
Hey! Hey!
So this is what rock
bottom feels like.
Mmm, not that bad. (CHUCKLES)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(GASPS)
Hello?
(VOICE BREAKING) Hello? Hello?
(STAMMERS) Hello?
Penny?
I can't hear you,
you're breaking up.
Penny?
Penny! How's this?
(VOICE BREAKING) Just hang on.
Don't go anywhere.
(STATIC)
Can you hear me now?
Yes, I can hear you now.
LLOYD: Good! I can hear
you loud and clear.
This is Lloyd, your
dad's good buddy.
Unfortunately, I don't
have him at the moment,
but, uh, he wanted me to ask you
to find a nice, romantic place
where we can all meet.
No, by "romantic" I
meant convenient.
And it has to be some place
outside the convention center.
(GRUNTS)
The fountain? On Main Street?
In 10 minutes?
Perfect!
Yes!
BARBARA: It's marvelous to meet you, Mrs.
Pinchelow.
I trust you had a
safe journey in?
It was lovely.
Great. We have a seat saved
for you in the front row.
We're just about to introduce
your charming husband.
My husband?
DR. MELDMANN: So let's
give a warm, KEN welcome
to our very distinguished judge,
Dr. Bernard Pinchelow.
(APPLAUSE)
(WHISPERING) Hi!
Hello!
How about a hug?
Sure!
(GRUNTS)
Oh!
I love hellos.
Oh, me, too.
(GRUNTING)
Wow!
You're really sweet, mister,
but I'm waiting for my dad and his
friend, so if you'll excuse me.
No, it's me, Lloyd!
Hi, Lloyd, I'm Penny.
On! Lloyd! Hi! (CHUCKLING)
It's so nice to meet you!
Um, where's my dad?
Uh, he was delayed, so, uh,
he asked me to come by
and entertain you...
(BLUBBERING)
(CHUCKLING)
...until he can meet up with us.
I think he wanted us to
have a chance to bond.
James Bond.
Great!
Are you hungry? Can I get
you something to eat?
Sure! (EXHALES)
(CHUCKLING) Awesome!
Wow!
We can go somewhere nice.
Sounds yummy!
Here, try this.
This is incredible popcorn.
And I know popcorn. I'm the
second-best popcorn maker I know.
All right, I'll take the bait.
Who's the third-best?
I know, right? I've
always wondered that!
(GRUNTS) (LAUGHS)
Shrub club! (LAUGHS)
Sorry!
It's just this game that I play
with my friends back home.
I love you!
What?
Um...
That's a direct
quote, from your dad.
(EXHALING) "I love you."
His words.
Hey, wait a second.
How do I even know
that you know my dad?
You could be one of those foreign
guys who always calls me up
and makes me get undressed
in front of the computer
because he lost his
passports and money.
No, no, that's not me.
Look, I can prove it.
I have your cell phone.
Oh, my gosh! No wonder no
one's been calling me!
Oh.
LLOYD: I, uh, plugged
my number in there
in case you need
me late at night.
Oh, and we brought your box. You left
it at the house, you stupid idiot.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Hey, you wanna see
something neat?
Okay!
(GASPS)
Wait, are you sure that it's okay
for birds to be eating Pop Rocks?
I mean, you'd think it would
be bad for their teeth.
Nah! That's just a
suburban legend.
Oh. (GUNSHOT)
Shit!
Spontaneous combustion,
however, totally real.
Oh.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
What? ADELE: You gotta
get back here right now.
One of those idiots
is in the building
and he's pretending
to be my husband!
Why don't you tell them
he's not your husband?
Because I don't even
know what they're up to.
He must be trying
to sell the box.
Just get back here!
This microscopic
robot, or nanobot
can be injected
into the human body
to detect and cure cancer.
(CROWD GASPS)
Interesting.
Can it sing? (CROWD LAUGHS)
Uh...
What?
They got a large-mouth bass now
that you hang it on the wall.
When you walk past it, it
sings Take Me to the River.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Are you saying...
What I'm saying is,
you're this close,
but there's a drawing board you
should be getting back to.
Next! (CROWD LAUGHS)
But it cures cancer.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Ni hao.
Listen to this.
"You will do important
things in the world."
(GASPS) That's so weird
because I actually want to do
important things in the world.
Wow. That's neat.
Someday, I wanna do
important things, too.
Oh, yeah? Like what?
I'm thinking about
getting new speakers.
Oh. (SLURPS)
I've always wanted
to go to India
and volunteer at one of
those leprechaun colonies.
I think you mean Ireland.
Oh.
So what does your cookie say?
"You will have an
amazing romance
"with the person sitted
across from you."
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
It's a good thing
I'm not your uncle.
"And don't be concerned
about the age difference.
"Just shut up and make out.
"It will all sort itself out later.
You'll see!"
That's ridiculously specific.
Let me see that.
If you don't eat it,
it doesn't come true.
Hey, where's my dad?
Do you know if Adele
came with him?
She's probably the one
slowing him down.
Adele?
His wife.
Harry doesn't have a wife.
Who's Harry?
Your father.
My father's name's not Harry.
It's Bernard.
Oh, yeah, but I'm talking
about your real dad.
Harry Dunne!
The guy who abandoned you when
you were a little, tiny baby.
You're gonna love him!
Wait a second.
So you're saying we're
supposed to be meeting
my biographical father?
Yes.
Here.
This is a letter from your real mother,
Fraida, that you sent back to her.
Nice.
"Do not contact again."
This isn't my handwriting.
I don't even know cursive.
"Dear daughter, I gave you
up for adoption 18 years ago
"because I thought it was
the right thing to do.
"I hope and pray I made
the correct decision.
"You were conceived in Rhode
Island on a chilly autumn night
"in the parking lot at
Oyster Swallow Cove.
"We were young and
stupid, especially him."
(SOFTLY) Oyster Swallow Cove?
FRAIDA: Are you ready, baby?
(BLOWS)
(SNIFFS)
Mmm-hmm.
Whoa! Whoa!
Slow down.
Let's be responsible here.
I brought some protection.
(CLICKS)
(SIGHS)
Let's do this.
(GRUNTING)
"So, if you ever wanna get in
touch, I would love to meet you.
"All my love, Fraida
Felcher, your mom."
That means I'm your...
And we almost... Lloyd?
Are you okay?
(GRUNTS)
I'm sorry, Lloyd, but I gotta
get back to the convention.
I'm supposed to be giving a big
speech for my dad any minute.
But, wait. We have so
much to talk about.
It's an emergency!
It's all a big misunderstanding!
I've gotta go!
(YELLING) Not dressed
like that, you're not!
You're grounded!
(WHISPERING) Wait a minute.
If she's my kid,
then she's not Harry's kid,
and he can't take her kidneys.
What have I done?
Hi, I need to get in.
Credentials, please?
Oh, I'm giving a speech.
(CHUCKLES)
Credentials, please.
What is that?
Is it that thingy that they
gave me to get in here?
I think I've got it
here, somewhere.
Mister, l am appealing to
your sense of God and family.
I got a message
that my daughter,
who I have not seen in 22 years,
is in there.
The event will be
letting out soon.
After 22 years, what's another
couple of hours, right?
Okay, buddy.
There's got to be a, uh,
broom closet around
here somewhere, huh?
I'm sure we could
work something out.
I didn't take 34 years to
come out of the closet
just to go back
into one with you.
Okay, this device will give us a visual
rendering of your cognitive processes.
Could you repeat the question?
(CROWD LAUGHS)
This device will show
us what he's thinking
right on this screen.
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
(CHUCKLING) Yeah, really.
STUDENT: Go ahead, Dr.
Pinchelow.
Think of a pleasant memory
from your childhood. (BEEPS)
(SIGHS) okay-
(CROWD GASPS)
(CRACKLING)
(CROWD EXCLAIMS)
Oh!
YOUNG HARRY: Here, Biscuit!
Biscuit, come here, boy.
(WHISTLING)
The door, buddy. Get the door.
(CROWD GROANS DISGUSTEDLY)
(SIGHS)
(GROANING)
Oh, okay.
(STUTTERING)
No! This gadget is way off!
(CROWD GASPS) First of all,
my bedspread was orange.
(CROWD LAUGHS)
Are you okay, honey?
No, not really.
Boyfriend trouble?
No. I need a ticket to get in
and I lost the ticket that they
need to take, plus, I lost my pass.
And I thought that I grabbed it,
but when I looked in my purse,
all I saw was the toothbrush.
So maybe I took...
Okay, okay, okay- (SIGHS)
All right.
What's going on?
My father's supposed to
be getting a huge reward,
and I'm supposed to
be making the speech,
and the speech is supposed
to start right now,
and there's no way they'll
let me in without a ticket.
Oh, honey.
There is always a way.
I admit, it's thought-provoking.
An invention that
ends world hunger.
But, have you considered this,
where does all the
extra poop go?
(ALL LAUGHING)
What? No.
The point is that
there's no more hunger.
Excuse me, ladies and gentlemen.
We're gonna take a
very brief break.
Uh, please stay in your seats
and we will resume, uh, shortly.
Why?
We're gonna have to take a walk.
Come on. I'm judging.
You're out of here. Okay!
You're out.
Mrs. P, what are you doing here?
Do you always call your wife Mrs.
P?
Oh, uh...
How you doing, sugar tits?
I missed you.
This man is a fraud.
And that box belongs
to my husband.
He stole it from us.
Hand it over, buddy.
Uh-uh. I swore I'd only
give this box to Penny.
Give me the box! Here you go.
(ALARM WAILING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
ADELE: What's happening?
BARBARA: I have no idea.
Hey!
Hey, hey! Get back here!
Out of my way!
Thanks a lot, lady!
It's the least I could do.
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
(STUTTERS)
There's something I
need to tell you.
(STAMMERS) You're my...
Okay. The reason I'm here is...
HARRY: Fraida!
FRAIDA: Harry? (CHUCKLES)
You made it! Oh!
Oh, and you found Penny.
Hey, how do you know my...
Oh! You're Harry?
Yes! And I'm your mother!
(GASPS)
He's got a gun! (ALL SCREAMING)
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
Why you standing in the toilet?
So you wouldn't see my feet.
Why not just stand on the rim?
There's ball hairs
all over that thing.
I'm not stupid.
Get out of there! Move it!
Now!
Please don't hurt Penny, Mrs. P.
She's young and still has most
of her future ahead of her.
Get the box.
Harry! There you are!
(CHUCKLES) Good
thing you're loud.
What are you doing, Mrs. P?
I'm about to kill you.
Wait, wait, wait!
Can't you kill someone else?
My daughter, Penny,
needs me now.
What are you talking about, Lloyd?
Penny's my daughter.
No, Harry, she isn't. Mmm-mmm.
What?
Why would you think that
she's your daughter?
Because of the postcard.
I was about to be a single
mom and I needed money.
And you owed me 40 bucks
from that stupid worm farm loan.
LLOYD: It's true, Har.
I'm the deadbeat dad, not you.
(YELPS)
I'm Penny's baby-papa.
(HOWLS)
But don't judge me
till you see this.
Oh, yeah, like a cooler
of cold brewskies
is gonna make everything okay!
It's not beer, it's my kidney!
Your kidney?
I figured
since you can't get
one from Penny,
I'd give it to you myself.
Holy shit.
How did you get this? (PANTING)
I crossed the
border into Mexico.
Turns out, the medical regs are
a little more chill down there.
Pardon me for bringing this
up, but I don't give a shit!
Yeah, but, Lloyd, she isn't
your daughter either.
Nice try, Fraida,
but Penny read me the letter.
I know all about
Oyster Swallow Cove,
which is exactly where
you took me in the van!
So?
That was my spot.
I must have taken
hundreds of guys there.
What can I say?
I was a titanic whore.
That's enough bullshit.
Go ahead, Lippincott, kill them.
LIPPINCOTT: Oh, I will.
But first, why don't
you join them.
(BREATHING HEAVILY) What?
You heard me. Drop it!
Get over there! Get over there!
You're kidding. She's
on our team now?
Don't do this, Lippincott.
You're a military man.
I know you've got more
integrity than this!
What is this?
Huh?
Two cupcakes?
Actually, there were
four cupcakes, sir.
I ate the two chocolate ones.
Lloyd!
It's okay. I left the
vanilla ones for humanity.
Where's the invention?
Where's the goddamn
billion-dollar invention?
(INDISTINCT YELLING)
Put the gun down! Freeze!
Put the gun down, Lippincott!
(CLATTERS)
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
Well! Hello.
Dad!
Bernard. Oh, thank
God you're here.
God, and you're okay!
Stop right there.
What?
I appreciate your
concern, Adele,
but it's a little late for that.
You see... I couldn't
stop wondering
why every time I ate your
cooking, I was getting sicker.
And then when Harry
and Lloyd showed me
the letter from
Penny's birth mother,
I recognized that
the handwriting
sending it back was yours.
And the cruelty of this
got me to thinking.
So l laid a little trap, and lo
and behold, you took the bait
like the toe-sucking
rat that you are.
After you left for El Paso,
I called the FBI to make
sure Penny was protected.
I thought those Canadian
accents were a little shaky.
Yeah? You try it.
But what about the invention?
It was just cupcakes.
A gift for Dr. Barbara Walcott
for my having canceled
at the last moment.
This is great, Dad!
Now you can pick up your Lifetime
Achievement reward in person!
It's "award," you stupid bitch!
No!
(GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
(INDISTINCT YELLING)
BOTH: Break it up! Get off!
Hands behind your back. Hands
behind your back. (GRUNTING)
I'm the good guy here!
All right.
(PANTS)
Are you okay, Har?
I think so.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Oh, yeah, it's just
a little graze.
Uh, Har?
You might wanna put a
dab of Bactine on that.
(SIREN WAILING)
Hurry, he's been shot!
MAN: We need a trauma room.
You're gonna be okay.
What have we got?
Gunshot wound, left shoulder.
Lloyd, the kidney!
Kidney?
Oh, yeah.
Would you, by any chance,
have time this evening
to swap out a kidney?
I'm sorry, sir. What is this?
It's a kidney. My kidney.
It's for him, my best pal.
(GROANING) Ah!
He needs it.
Gentlemen, this is not a kidney.
What is it?
Better not be my heart.
DOCTOR: No.
I believe it's a pork chop.
In a baggie. (CHUCKLING)
I wondered why my
kidney had grill marks.
And a bone.
Hey, wait.
Does that mean I still
have all my kidneys?
Let's have a look.
Ah.
I'm going to say probably not.
That's it.
I am gonna give that
quack an earful
at my follow-up
appointment next Tuesday.
(SOBBING) I'm sorry, Harry.
I failed you again!
(SNIFFLES)
It's okay, Lloyd.
(SNIFFLES) I forgive you.
(SNICKERS)
LLOYD: What's so funny?
Got ya!
(MUMBLES)
I never needed a kidney!
(LAUGHS)
What?
Oh, you should have seen
the look on your face!
I got you so good!
(LAUGHING) (EXHALES)
Wait a minute.
You mean, I had
my kidney removed
in the backseat of
a Toyota Tercel
and you were faking? Uh-huh.
That is awesome!
(LAUGHING)
That is a good one.
Totally worth it!
Gentlemen, I hate to break
up this Mensa summit,
but we've gotta get this
man's shoulder cleaned out.
Do you remember,
you've been shot?
That was a good gag, Harry.
(LAUGHING)
But don't you think it still
would have been funny
if you had told me you were kidding
before I lost my vital organ?
Oh, definitely. But not as!
(LAUGHING)
That's true.
You guys are so cool.
How can I ever thank you
for what you did for me?
Got any cash?
Oh, yeah.
I think I've got a couple...
Thanks.
Score.
(PINCHELOW LAUGHING)
(LAUGHING)
(PINCHELOW CLEARS THROAT)
Oh, uh...
I'm sure those janitors
will thank us later. Mmm.
We were just straightening
up their broom closet.
FRAIDA: Penny, wonderful news!
Your father has invited me to
come stay with you for a while,
so we can really get
to know each other.
That's fantastic!
So let me ask you
something, Fraida.
If I'm not Penny's father
and Lloyd's not her father,
then who's her father?
Funny you should ask.
Honey,
how would you like to
meet some relatives?
LLOYD: Mr. Stainer?
Oh, I should have known.
(YELLING) You horny, old goat!
No, Lloyd!
Mr. Stainer is
Penny's grandfather.
Come on.
So, you mean Pee-Stain
is the dad?
Duh!
(CHUCKLING)
Hi!
Oh...
She's beautiful!
Sweet Jesus, look at her.
She's got Peter's eyes.
You're kidding!
He donated them?
Hi, Pee-Stain!
Stainy!
Hey, sorry you got killed!
Let's get you away from these guys, huh?
Let's go.
PINCHELOW: Yeah.
Guys, there's still one
thing I don't understand.
How could either of you
have possibly thought
that you were Penny's father?
(SCOFFS) Why wouldn't we? Yeah!
Because we never had sex.
Oh. (CHUCKLES)
(SNICKERING)
You could have fooled us.
Yeah, nice try, Snow White.
Does the word "hot
tub" jog your memory?
If I recall,
I played with your boobies
for a long time that night.
The motor boat, the
windshield wipers,
the punching bag.
You know, Harry,
you can't get a woman pregnant
by man-handling her breasts.
Oh, really?
Then why did your doorbells get so hard?
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Yeah. And did you forget
about the French tickler,
in the back of the van?
Putting a frilly, glow-in-the-dark
condom on your finger
is not the same as having sex.
But what if I go like this?
(GIBBERING)
No.
Okay, Dr. Picasso, what's
your definition of sex?
(WHISPERING)
No way!
That's just... Not my mom!
But that's where she pees!
It's in my head and
I can't unlearn it!
You're bad!
Can you show us?
I call sloppy seconds!
(SIGHS)
Looks like everyone else
ended up with someone.
Yep- And I got this pork chop.
(CHUCKLES)
So let me get this
straight, Har.
When you visited me in the
nuthouse the last time...
Uh-huh... you knew
about Penny already?
No, I found out about her
when we visited my parents.
But I had finally figured
out that you were faking.
Really? How? Mmm-hmm.
What gave it away?
A few months ago, I was changing
your diaper before bedtime
and you just seemed a
little too upbeat.
Lloyd, even though
it's Christmas Eve,
I want you to know that there's
no place I would rather be
than right here, wiping
my best friend's dookie.
(PARTS)
Oh. (CHUCKLES)
Looks like we got another
stocking stuffer.
(CHUCKLES)
(CHUCKLING) I remember that.
That was the night I had all
that eggnog and lamb, right?
Yeah. Whoa!
Lloyd!
Check out the hotties
at 12 o'clock.
That's almost three hours away.
Can't I check them out now?
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SPUTTERING)
Okay, Lloyd,
This time we're not gonna be
stupid and pass up a sure thing.
I hear you, Har.
We'll never get another
chance like this.
Our time has finally come.
(BOTH SCREAM)
BOTH: Bush club!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(FOLK MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh, crap!
I ordered a vanilla shake and
they gave me a chocolate one.
Tell me about it. I ordered
a chocolate shake.
Those dopes gave
me a vanilla one.
They do that a lot.
What the hell?
Kick his ass, Seabass!
SEABASS: Arr, the dirty
sons-of-bitches!
[ENGLISH - US - SDH - BOZXPHD]