(# "Martha"
composed by Friedrich von Flotow)
(applause)
(# sings in French)
(# singing in French)
- Good evening, Vercheres.
- Sh!
Oh, good evening, Inspector. You have
missed half of the opera, as usual.
- I didn't come to see the opera.
- As usual.
(applause)
- Raoul!
- Christine.
I just got back from Rouen.
No, I must talk to you for a moment.
But I...
Raoul, I shouldn't have left.
Christine, dear,
I hurried over to tell you something.
- What?
- That I love you.
- Again?
- Still.
- What a wonderful audience tonight.
- And you were marvellous, Biancarolli.
We're having supper tonight
at the Café de L'Opéra.
- I'm sorry, Raoul, but I can't tonight.
- Why not?
Chris? Christine!
- I'm coming, Jenny.
- If you've another engagement, break it.
You've had your fling at this for two years.
But I don't want to give up the opera,
not until I've had a chance to really sing.
Anatole says he has great faith in
my voice, and he's going to help me.
Naturally. That's what baritones are for(!)
- You were in wonderful voice tonight.
- Thank you, Marcel.
Christine! Why weren't you on
the stage for the end of the act?
- You're all right?
- Oh, yes.
Mademoiselle DuBois, come here please.
Don't worry.
Why weren't you onstage
for the curtain calls?
- Well, erm, I was ill...
- No, you were not.
You were entertaining a friend.
A friend, mind you!
For a singer to absent herself
from the stage during a performance
is a gross breach of...
- Oh. You wish to talk to me, monsieur?
- With your permission,
I'd like a few words with MIle DuBois
in my office after the performance.
- Yes, she will be there.
- Thank you.
- Now, you bear in mind what I told you.
- Yes, monsieur.
Terrifying fellow, that Vercheres,
when he wants to be.
I'm very grateful, monsieur. I promise you
I'll never miss a curtain call again.
It's a promise. Now, uh,
this young man who is more important
to you than your career... Who is he?
But he isn't, monsieur. That is,
I am very fond of him. I mean...
Oh.
Well, he's Inspector
Raoul Daubert of the Sûreté.
Inspector? You mean a policeman?
Oh, but he's not an ordinary policeman.
Even an extraordinary policeman seems
a strange sweetheart for a soprano.
Does he sing?
I'm afraid you don't
understand, monsieur.
He's a graduate of
the military academy at Saint-Cyr,
and he's very intelligent and very clever.
For a man who means nothing to you, he
seems to have made quite an impression.
Oh, but I didn't say he meant
nothing to me. What I said was...
I know. I know what you mean.
You have promise, Mademoiselle DuBois,
but you must choose
between an operatic career
and what is usually called "a normal life".
Though why it is so-called is beyond me.
You can't do justice to both.
The artist has a special temperament,
and he must live his life exclusively
with those who understand it.
I understand, monsieur.
You'll find that music has its
compensations, my dear. Good night.
Good night, and thank you.
Oh, mademoiselle, please tell Mr Claudin
to come in. He's in the anteroom.
Certainly. Good night.
Good evening. Monsieur Villeneuve
asks that you come in now.
Thank you, mademoiselle.
Mademoiselle,
may I speak to you for a minute?
Certainly.
You weren't on the stage tonight
for the third-act curtain calls.
Everyone in the theatre seems to have
noticed it. It's really quite flattering.
Why weren't you there?
Oh, forgive me, but I've
been here so long that you...
Everybody, everything connected with
the Opera is so much a part of my life.
Of course... But Mr Villeneuve is waiting.
Yes.
You weren't ill, were you?
You're not in any trouble?
It's impertinent of me, I know, but, uh...
You're very kind.
Good night.
Uh, Christine!
I'm sorry.
Good night.
- (knocking)
- (Villeneuve) Come in, please.
You know why I sent for you, Claudin?
I think so, Maestro.
For some time now I have sensed
discord in the violin section.
It was not until tonight that I definitely
located the source of the trouble.
Let me hear you play,
if you please, Claudin.
Yes, Maestro.
(# mournful tune)
- What was that, Claudin?
- A little song.
A lullaby, from Provence,
where I was born.
You played it very well.
Perhaps I was wrong.
No, it was you.
What's the matter?
You're an accomplished musician.
Come, come, now.
Let me hear you play the opening
movement in the third act of Martha.
It's no use, Maestro. Something has
happened to the fingers of my left hand.
- But you played that lullaby perfectly.
- It's a simple melody, Maestro.
That's why I played it.
You were trying to fool me, eh, Claudin?
Well, perhaps it's only temporary.
Perhaps it'll get better.
I hope so, but in the meantime...
You know, Claudin,
the aim of the Paris Opera is perfection.
I'm sorry, old fellow, very sorry. You've
been with us a long time, haven't you?
20 years.
What am I to do, Maestro?
I know it's hard, Claudin.
No doubt you've saved
a tidy little fortune to retire on.
- Yes, of course.
- In appreciation of your long service,
I shall arrange with the directors
to have a season ticket issued to you.
Thank you, Maestro.
(knock at door)
(door opens)
Why don't you eat before the opera,
instead of keeping me up all hours?
You're rich enough. Same soup,
night after night, week after week.
- Please don't disturb yourself, Marie.
- You're a fine one to say that!
Why wouldn't I be disturbed?
I'll come right to the point.
What you do with your money
is not my business.
If you want to hoard it
and starve, it's your affair.
But you haven't paid me for six weeks,
and that's as long as I'm going to wait.
I haven't any money.
If you'll be patient, just a little longer...
You haven't any money? After working
for the Paris Opera all these years?
What will you do with your money?
Bury it with you?
If you do, they'll dig you up and steal it.
If you think you can add a few francs
to your fortune at my expense,
you're very much mistaken.
Marie, you've been very kind, you've been
very patient. You'll be paid, I promise you.
Now please leave me alone.
It makes me sick to think of all
that money doing nobody any good.
Either I get my money or out you go.
That's my last word, Claudin.
(# sings ascending scale)
(bell tinkles)
You're late, Mr Claudin.
The lesson is almost over.
I didn't come about that today,
mademoiselle.
- She's not in voice.
- I'll tell Signor Ferretti.
- Please don't interrupt the lesson.
- Of course not. I understand.
But I must announce the time to Signor
Ferretti, or he'll keep students for hours.
- It's 11 o'clock, Signor Ferretti.
- Thank you.
Mademoiselle, you disappoint me.
I'm sorry. I'm a little upset.
If a man is upsetting you,
pitch him out of your life. Music is first.
- Music is everything.
- I understand.
You don't understand. Women
never understand. But they are docile.
Perhaps you're not getting enough sleep.
Come later tomorrow, say midday.
Thank you, monsieur.
Remember you have responsibilities
to others as well as yourself.
I know.
I can never repay you
for what you've done for me.
- Good day, monsieur.
- Good day.
Would you come this way, monsieur?
Monsieur Claudin is here, Signor Ferretti.
Come in, Claudin, come in.
- Won't you sit down a moment?
- Thank you.
I suppose you noticed
your protégée was disappointing today?
Well, an off day now and then.
You've done a lot for her, Signor.
Nevertheless, she is making
definite progress, eh?
I was dismissed from
the orchestra last night.
Oh. Then you will have to withdraw
your support for Mademoiselle DuBois?
Only for a little while, just until
I can secure another position.
I had hoped that you would
continue to instruct her.
Claudin, if you don't mind me
saying so, you are a fool.
A man of your age might win
a girl like Christine DuBois
if he happened to be the director of
an opera company, but a poor violinist...
We agreed never to discuss my motives.
Please, won't you continue
to work with her?
Why should I assume your burden,
after you spent all your money on her?
She means nothing to me.
But her career means
more to me than anything else.
I would never let you lose
anything on her account.
I'm sorry, Claudin, really sorry.
If I had time... But my expenses are great.
And you must remember there are many
who can pay waiting to study with me.
I'll let her come a few times, and then
I will tell her she no longer needs me.
But that isn't true.
As a matter of fact, if you had the money,
she might be launched on a career soon.
I assume that MIle DuBois has not the
means to pay for her own instructions?
A month's salary wouldn't be enough
to pay for one of your lessons.
But... I have written a concerto.
Will you trust me if I can
arrange to have it published?
Every violinist has written a concerto!
Come, come, my dear Claudin.
But I have faith in this one,
as much faith as I had in MIle DuBois
when I came three years ago.
Now, I was right about her,
Signor, and I'm right about this.
Pleyel and Desjardins will publish it,
and they'll give me
a substantial advance. You'll see!
(man) It's a shame.
Pleyel's in there with his etchings.
Why don't they tell the poor devil he won't
see anyone, instead of torturing him?
Claudin?
He'll see me?
No. He is too busy today.
- Has he seen my manuscript?
- Manuscript? What manuscript?
- My concerto.
- I know nothing about it.
- But you took the portfolio into him.
- If I did, you will receive it in due time.
Now, my dear, the acid. Be careful,
or you'll burn yourself horribly.
- Monsieur Pleyel?
- What are you doing here?
- I've been waiting since this morning.
- Weren't you told I couldn't see anyone?
Yes, but my manuscript.
I must find out about my manuscript.
Give this fellow
his manuscript, Georgette.
You'll find it on the desk, if it's anywhere.
- What is your name?
- Uh, Claudin. Erique Claudin.
Claudin...
No, it wouldn't be there. It's a large
manuscript in a portfolio. It's a concerto.
- I'm sorry, but I don't know where it is.
- But it must be here.
Well, if it is, it will turn up.
You might call again in a few days.
You don't understand. It's my only copy.
It represents two years' work.
- You heard what the lady said.
- But it was brought in.
It must be here. It must be found.
Did we ask you to bring
your music to us, Claudin?
I've seen samples of
your compositions before.
Perhaps some employee has thrown it
into the wastebasket, where it belongs.
Good night!
(# piano playing)
- Do you think I was right, Monsieur Liszt?
- It's magnificent. Tell me his name again.
- Erique Claudin.
- Claudin?
I've tried for years to persuade
Pleyel to publish his work,
but you know
Pleyel and unknown composers.
Pleyel will publish this, I promise.
(continues playing piano)
That's my music.
I thought I told you to get out.
Thief!
You've stolen my music.
- Thief!
- (Georgette) Maurice!
- You're choking him!
- You've stolen my music!
Thief! Thief!
- (Pleyel chokes)
- You've stolen my music!
What happened?
- Stop him!
- What's happened?
Monsieur Pleyel's been murdered by that
madman, Claudin! Get a doctor, quickly!
You, get a doctor. Call the police!
Get a doctor! Call the police!
Police! Police!
- What happened?
- Monsieur Pleyel has been murdered!
- He ran down that way.
- Come on, let's go!
Not here.
Sorry, monsieur.
Move on, and don't come back
into this district tonight.
(howls)
Lecours, how were we ever induced
to accept the management of this place?
It's not an opera house. It's a madhouse.
And now this:
"Wanted for murder: Erique Claudin,
former violinist at Paris Opera House."
"Age 48 years, height 5ft 8in."
"The face has recently
been disfigured by acid."
It's an outrage.
After 20 years with the Paris Opera,
this miserable Claudin has
the insolence to commit a murder.
After 20 years with the Paris Opera,
- A man is capable of anything, Amiot.
- (knock on door)
Come in, come in, come in!
Monsieur, there is a thief
in the opera house.
A costume has been stolen,
and two masks.
Impossible. The wardrobe
woman must have lost them.
- She should have been dismissed.
- She's too fat.
That's not all. The thief has
broken into the restaurant.
- The restaurant?
- Yes, monsieur. There is missing a...
There is missing a bucket of pickled
pigs' feet in vinegar, a ham and a pâté.
Call the police. This must be stopped.
Monsieur, I am afraid
the police can't stop that. It's he.
Who?
Oh, please don't start that
nonsense again, Vercheres.
You ought to know
there aren't any ghosts.
Monsieur, you are sceptical, but
I don't like ghosts. I am a busy man.
What's that?
Our brilliant stage manager insists
there's a malicious ghost prowling about.
If anything goes wrong,
he thinks this ghost did it.
Oh, monsieur...
- It has a long nose and a big, red beard.
- You make me nervous.
It's gone!
Did you hear that, Lecours?
My master key is gone.
Do you realise what that means, Lecours?
With that key in his possession,
the thief can open 2500 doors,
to say nothing of thousands
of closets and cabinets.
Perhaps the pickled pigs' feet will kill him.
Oh, you don't seem to understand.
Why, he can hide everywhere.
The entire police force couldn't find him.
You don't realise the extent of this place.
You've never troubled to find out.
Why should I? I have troubles enough.
- What are you waiting for? Get the police!
- Yes, monsieur.
A pâté, a ham, pickled pigs' feet
and 2500 rooms!
What is the Opera coming to?
(# angry chords)
(# "Provence Lullaby")
(# hums the tune)
That's lovely. What is it?
It's a lullaby of Provence.
I've known it all my life.
# Hear those bells ringing soft and low
# Bringing peace through the twilight glow
# According to everyone
# Night has begun
# Turn from your weary toil
# Day's work is done
# Hear them ring while my love and I
# Drift and dream to the lullaby
# Hear those bells ringing soft and low
- (bell)
- # Bringing peace
# Through the twilight glow
# According to everyone
# Night has...
- Monsieur Daubert.
- Madame.
They call this rehearsing, monsieur.
Well, I'm sorry to intrude,
but I must see you, Christine.
- Well, you see I'm busy right now...
- Christine!
Please remember that you
are speaking to a gentleman.
Well, uh...
- Come in, Raoul.
- Rehearsals!
Anatole... Well, he's been helping me.
- Monsieur's very kind.
- Not at all, monsieur. I find it a pleasure.
- I'm Anatole Garron of the Opera.
- I'm so sorry.
This is Inspector Daubert,
of the Sûreté.
I've heard of you, Inspector.
Your work must be very exciting.
Oh, not so exciting as yours, monsieur.
It doesn't lend itself to self-expression.
I didn't recognise that
delightful song you were singing.
But as you know,
I am no connoisseur of the opera.
It's not from an opera, Raoul. It's a lullaby.
A lullaby?
It didn't seem very effective, as a lullaby.
Well, you see, Monsieur Inspector,
a song is capable of many interpretations,
- By a musician.
- By a detective, too.
Though no doubt
the detective is usually mistaken.
I must see you alone, Christine.
I'm here on business from the Sûreté.
With me?
What business could mademoiselle
have with the Sûreté?
What is it, Raoul?
If you don't mind,
I'd rather Anatole stayed.
Very well, Christine.
- You know Erique Claudin?
- Why, yes.
How well?
I knew him only as
a violinist in the orchestra.
I encountered him a few times in the foyer
or on the stage or outside
the Opera, but that's all.
He acted a little strangely, but I assumed
he was that way with everybody.
- Strangely?
How do you mean, "strangely"?
Well... I don't know.
He just seemed... eccentric, but harmless.
I thought he was a rather kind old fellow,
until I read of the murder.
- What is it, Raoul?
- He was a kind and inoffensive man.
Until he thought Pleyel
was stealing his life's work.
Then something snapped,
and he became a homicidal maniac.
In his state, he may
commit other murders.
It's urgent that we capture him
as soon as possible.
But what has all this to do with me?
We found something in his room
that connects you with him.
No doubt you can explain.
So that's what became of it!
- Be good enough to explain yourself.
- Certainly. That statuette is mine.
- Yours?
- Definitely. I made it.
- I intended to make you a present of it.
- How nice of you, Anatole.
It disappeared from my dressing room.
It's an extraordinary likeness.
My compliments on
your versatility, monsieur.
You must have posed for this
many times. Every detail is you.
I never posed for it, not once.
- You did this from drawings?
- And from memory, Monsieur Inspector.
To see Christine is to carry her image
in your heart and mind for ever.
- Claudin must have stolen it.
- Why?
Isn't it obvious?
Well, speaking purely as
an inspector of the Sûreté,
even the obvious
often needs confirmation.
But as a man, Mr Daubert,
you can understand
that sitting there in the orchestra pit
night after night and looking at Christine,
Claudin probably fell in love with her.
You admit that is possible, no?
Christine, did Claudin ever seek more
than a casual acquaintance with you?
No, never.
Can you imagine so diffident a lover,
monsieur? Claudin was barely 50.
Well, no doubt he lacked... assurance.
No doubt.
- This is yours, Christine.
- You're giving it to me?
- Yes.
- Well!
Then I'll accept it
as a gift from both of you.
Well, I seem to have got
the worst of this bargain.
In the future, Monsieur Inspector,
I detect, you model.
- In any case, that was a bad clue.
- Oh, not so bad as it seems.
It enabled me to recover
mademoiselle's statuette.
Thank you, Raoul.
Is that your carriage
at the door, monsieur?
Why, yes.
Would you be good enough
to give me a lift?
- Where are you going?
- It doesn't matter.
As inspector of police,
I have business all over Paris.
Yes, well, in that case...
- Au revoir,  Christine.
- Au revoir.
You've been most helpful, Christine.
- I hope you catch him soon.
- Thank you.
- Ready, monsieur?
- At your service.
- After you, monsieur.
- After you,  monsieur.
(laughs)
(orchestra tuning up)
- Madame looks beautiful tonight.
- Don't I always, Yvette?
But especially tonight. Monsieur Garron,
if he has eyes in his head...
- (knocking)
- (man) Madame Biancarolli!
Thank you! Madame...
(practises vocal exercises)
Good evening.
Marcel, do you think
I lead an enviable life?
- Yes, monsieur.
- I do, but not for the reasons you think.
I'm a very happy man because I'm having
supper tonight with Mademoiselle DuBois.
(Claudin) Christine?
You're going to be a great
and famous singer. I'll help you.
(# singing in French)
Marie, Comtesse de Bretonne.
(Garron) Christine, you're going to be
a great and famous singer. I'll help you.
- What's the matter?
- Someone just said the same thing to me
- A moment ago, in my room.
- Someone? Who?
I don't know. It was... just a voice.
- I knew you'd hear me sooner or later.
- It was you?
Of course. I don't mean actually,
but I've been saying it
ever since I saw you and heard
you sing. At last you heard me.
- Your cue, monsieur.
- I'll tell you again at supper.
Armand, Duc de Montaigne.
(applause)
What is it, madame?
I don't know. I...
Help me!
Monsieur Vercheres!
Oh, madame!
You, get a doctor, quickly.
Take her to her dressing room.
- What could have happened?
- What?
Ohh!
MIle DuBois, you must go on at once.
Madame Biancarolli has been taken ill.
Please get changed quickly. Claire!
Where is that clumsy wardrobe woman?
Claire, get MIle DuBois changed at once.
There isn't a moment to lose.
She was drugged, there's no doubt.
- Who the devil would want to drug her?
- I'm sure she overate.
- You're certain she'll recover, Dr Lefours?
- Definitely.
What am I doing here?  I...
I should be onstage. I...
- Doctor!
- Madame...
She'll be all right now.
Camarades, I'empereur nous appelle.
(# Christine sings)
Why is she singing?
What is she doing out there?
- What's happened?
- Madame, control yourself.
- I assure you...
- Come to the point, Amiot.
You were seized with
a touch of indigestion.
As your understudy,
MIle DuBois took your place.
A touch of indigestion! Why, I was
perfectly well when I went on the stage.
Why, I was drugged!
And you all know by whom.
Anatole Garron did it
to make room for that baggage!
- Madame, consider what you're saying,
- Madame, please compose yourself.
I demand Garron's arrest.
And hers too. She had a hand in it.
I demand an investigation!
- Let me go!
- Madame, consider our position.
You were wonderful!
(cheering)
I assure you, monsieur. The property man
swears that there was no opportunity
for any human being
to tamper with the drink.
Monsieur Inspector,
what are you waiting for?
I demand the arrest of Anatole Garron.
You know he did it.
I know nothing of the sort, madame.
I am a police officer, not a psychic.
It is my duty to collect evidence,
without prejudice.
Haven't you evidence enough?
Everyone knows...
Madame!
Will you be seated, please?
Mr Garron, you had the opportunity to put
the drug in Madame Biancarolli's glass.
Certainly, Monsieur Inspector.
We all did.
- It becomes, then, a question of motive.
- The motive is very simple, monsieur.
He wanted to get me out of the way
so he could make room for that...
- Are you referring to MIle DuBois?
- I am.
You heard, Monsieur Garron.
Madame is in good voice...
and most explicit.
Have you anything to say, monsieur?
I deny madame's accusation.
Do you deny, monsieur, that you had
any motive in drugging madame?
I deny that I drugged her.
I don't understand your reluctance
to make the arrest, Inspector.
- You're not an examining magistrate.
- Can you substantiate
that Mr Garron had a motive,
and that the motive was MIle DuBois?
- Anyone with half an eye could tell you...
- Hearsay is not evidence, madame.
I'll go over your head, Monsieur Daubert.
I have influence at the Sûreté.
I was drugged tonight
to the point of death.
I insist upon the arrest of
the criminal and his accomplice.
- And if you don't, I...
- One moment, madame, please.
You have heard Mr Garron
deny that he drugged you.
As the inspector says,
there is no evidence.
- And remember, madame...
- Are you suggesting that I...
If you insist upon his arrest
and fail to obtain a conviction,
you will find yourself in
a very difficult predicament.
- Quite right.
- And no matter what the outcome,
don't forget that your career
is bound to the Paris Opera.
Whatever scandal injures us,
or any member of the company,
- Will injure you as well.
- (Lecours) Precisely.
Are you suggesting that
I forget the whole affair?
Yes. For your own sake, as well as ours,
and purely as a matter
of business expediency.
That is exactly what
we propose, madame.
(Lecours) Exactly.
Very well.
That is, under certain conditions.
I want a new understudy.
Christine DuBois goes back to the chorus
and stays there for the two years
my contract has to run.
I won't permit such an outrage!
If any such arrangement is made, I'II...
- Now, madame...
- My dear Anatole, I have not finished.
You suggest I forget
I was drugged tonight?
- Madame.
- Very well. I'll go a step further.
I suggest that you forget
anything happened afterwards.
- For once, madame, I do not understand.
- Oh, monsieur, it's so simple.
Nothing happened tonight. I wasn't
drugged and Christine DuBois didn't sing.
- But...
- There are always critics in the house.
You'll send word to the papers that
no mention of her is to be made.
You'll do nothing of the sort.
It's ridiculous.
Besides, what about the public, madame?
Shall we send word to the public to
forget that MIle DuBois was a sensation?
If you're willing to ruin the Opera for the
sake of Christine DuBois, it's your affair.
But you'll either do as I say, or I'll charge
both of them with trying to murder me.
Do you understand that? Murder me!
- Madame was magnificent tonight.
- I was good, wasn't I?
Monsieur Garron must be biting his nails.
Ah, let him. He'll come crawling
back to me on his hands and knees,
confessing the whole thing
and begging my forgiveness.
Madame!
Who are you?
Christine DuBois will sing tomorrow night.
Leave Paris. This is your last warning.
Take off that prop-room mask.
(screaming)
- What was that?
- I don't know.
- (man) Something must have happened.
- Silence, please.
- (woman) What happened?
- Sh! Monsieur?
Madame Biancarolli and her maid
have been murdered.
Murdered?!
- Are you hurt, monsieur?
- What happened? What were you doing?
- I was chasing him.
- Chasing whom?
The murderer, of course.
There was someone else up there?
Certainly. Everyone must have seen...
You saw him yourself, didn't you?
No, monsieur. I was chasing you.
How long will the Opera
remain closed, Inspector?
- Yes, how long?
- I do not know.
- Any suspects?
- Yes, whom do you suspect?
- No one.
- What is your theory on the motive?
I am not a theorist. All I can say is that as
long as the opera house remains closed,
everyone in Paris, in all France,
will think only of the murder,
hounding us to make an arrest.
Inspector Daubert.
I came directly I got your message.
What has happened now?
Listen to this, monsieur.
"Christine DuBois must replace
Biancarolli, who ignored my warning."
I found this mysteriously placed on
my desk after we got back from supper.
There is an excellent suggestion in this,
monsieur. You must reopen the Opera.
- But your orders...
- Are countermanded. Reopen.
- With MIle DuBois, monsieur?
- Of course! It should pacify this madman.
If he doesn't harm anybody, his
being in the building doesn't matter.
- Christine DuBois must not sing.
- What?
And the murderer must
not remain in the building.
- It is my duty to apprehend him.
- I don't understand.
If Christine DuBois sings, that will satisfy
the murderer, and he may never appear.
To lure him from his hiding place,
someone else must sing.
Are you suggesting we reopen the Opera
with a murder as an added attraction?
- Please, Lecours...
- I'll post police throughout the building.
Even with the chorus onstage,
with a bodyguard for the singer.
- But, monsieur, our reputation...
- I am reluctant to do this, monsieur.
Particularly on MIle DuBois' account,
but I can see no other way.
And whom do you suggest as "bait",
Monsieur Inspector?
Whomever you decide.
Madame Lorenzi.
She has nerve, that woman.
- Too much.
- Very well, then.
- The Opera will reopen.
- Yes, monsieur.
(bell)
- Oh.
- (both) Good morning, Christine.
- Good morning.
- (both) May I come in, Christine?
Yes, do.
- Well?
- (both) Christine, I...
- Yes?
- (both) If I might have a word...?
- Well, what is it?
- After you, monsieur.
- (both) Christine, I...
- Well, now, one at a time, please!
You first, Anatole,
as your name begins with an A.
They're going to reopen the Opera.
At last we will sing...
You are wrong, monsieur.
I'm sorry, Christine.
They are going to reopen the Opera,
but without you.
Circumstances
connected with the murder
demand that someone else
sing the leading role.
- But Anatole...
- You may like to know, monsieur,
that circumstances connected with
the murder demand that she does sing.
Really? I am aware that your profession
requires a certain self-assurance,
- But aren't you going too far?
- Not at all.
I have a plan for
apprehending the murderer.
- So you have turned detective, monsieur?
- I have.
Very well, if it amuses you,
but I advise you to confine your hobby
to the entertainment of your friends.
Well, let's not waste words, monsieur.
I've been assured by
Messrs Amiot and Lecours
that as soon as the Opera reopens,
MIle DuBois will sing.
And I might add that
my plan is strictly confidential.
I'm sorry, but in my official capacity
I ordered Messrs Amiot and Lecours
not to permit you to sing.
- But Raoul...
- At least, not for the present.
And I am not in the least
interested in your plan.
May I have a word with you alone?
That's what I came for.
May I speak to you alone?
- But... I'm going out.
- (both) My carriage is outside.
Well, I'm not going right now.
I mean... I'm going later.
(both) I'll wait.
Mr Villeneuve suggested you'd perform
this service in the cause of justice.
Do you think Claudin would be tempted
to leave his hiding place and risk his life
merely to hear his own concerto?
Played by Franz Liszt himself?
Do you doubt it, Maestro?
So many crimes have been
committed in the name of music.
It seems only fair
to use it now to avert one.
- I am at your service, monsieur.
- Thank you, Maestro. Thank you.
Most exciting, this detective work,
most exciting.
It's more than exciting to me. I had the
honour of being suspected of the crime.
Monsieur Daubert, please.
- Listen, monsieur.
- Another note.
How this phantom knows
everything is beyond me.
"If Madame Lorenzi sings,
you are responsible for what happens."
Our plan is working.
I don't like it, monsieur. What will become
of the Paris Opera? Police everywhere!
- How is Madame Lorenzi?
- Oh, she's enjoying it.
- Nothing would keep her from singing.
- Well, you know how opera singers are.
With your matron in her dressing room
and that fellow of yours waiting to escort
her to the stage, she feels quite important.
Madame Lorenzi,
I trust you are entirely composed?
Composed?
What are you talking about? Why not?
- Maestro!
- The piano has been tuned, Maestro.
- When do we introduce the concerto?
- Probably after the opera.
Inspector Daubert has a plan of his own,
and we must give it every chance.
You may enjoy seeing the opera
from the orchestra pit.
I'll be quite comfortable here.
I can look through the score.
- Excuse me. The overture.
- Thank you again, Maestro.
Remain onstage
throughout the performance.
Make yourselves inconspicuous, and
be on the alert for anything suspicious.
The only persons backstage are
the members of the opera company,
all of whom you know. Now, that is all.
(# overture begins)
Christine, I'd rather
you'd stayed at home.
You understand why
I asked them not to let you sing?
But I couldn't stay away.
We're introducing a new opera
- And Madame Lorenzi's a great artist...
- And Anatole Garron is the baritone!
I'm sorry, Christine, but I'm concerned
about what may happen tonight.
I know. I am too.
Wait for me, please,
in your dressing room.
(# singing in Russian)
Sorry.
He's here, Gerard. He murdered
one of our men and stole his cape.
He's probably wearing a mask.
Watch everyone closely.
Of course, monsieur.
Sorry.
(# singing in Russian)
(# sings in Russian)
(# Madame Lorenzi sings)
(screams)
(screaming and shouting)
What is it?
Come with me, mademoiselle.
Are you one of the police?
- Where is Inspector Daubert?
- Investigating the accident.
I will look after you.
- You're not one of the police.
- I'll watch over you.
- I've always watched over you. Come.
- (screams)
- Sh!
Shh.
You'll stay here with me,
my child, won't you?
It's been so Ionely without you, but
you've come to me at last, haven't you?
Now you'll sing for me, and I'll play,
and we'll be together for ever.
It's beautiful down there.
Beautiful.
Come now, my little one.
Christine!
- Where's Christine?
- I don't know. Isn't it horrible?
- Hasn't she been here?
- I haven't seen her.
There. You're not
frightened now, are you?
You know I'll not harm you, don't you?
How could I harm you?
I've always helped you, haven't I?
- Yes.
- Yes what?
Yes, you've always helped me.
Of course I have. Biancarolli knows.
She wouldn't let you sing.
She didn't know how much I love you.
Now she knows.
But it doesn't matter now. Nothing
matters except you and me, Christine.
Now you'll sing all you want...
but only for me.
You will, won't you, my darling?
Of course.
There's a piano in the Opera foyer.
Let's go there.
You play and I'll sing for you.
But you don't understand.
We can't go back there... ever.
It was I who made the chandelier fall.
l, for you, Christine.
But I warned them. I said there'd be death
and destruction if they didn't let you sing.
Come.
See? Didn't I tell you it was beautiful?
You didn't know we had a lake
all to ourselves, did you?
They've poisoned your mind against me.
That's why you're afraid.
Look at your lake, Christine. You'll love it
here, when you get used to the dark.
And you'll love the dark too.
It's friendly and peaceful.
It brings rest, and relief from pain.
It's right under the Opera. The music
comes down and the darkness distils it,
cleanses it of the suffering that made it,
then it's all beauty.
And life here is like a resurrection.
This is more than just
a performance of a new concerto.
The future of the Paris Opera
may depend upon it.
- Garron, have you seen Christine?
- No, she's at home.
She came to the opera house earlier
this evening. Now she's disappeared.
Play, Maestro. Play.
Christine? Christine!
Christine! Christine!
Christine!
George, you two search that passageway.
Gerard, go that way.
Be careful.
This madman may do anything now.
Christine!
(# Claudin's concerto begins)
My concerto!
(# plays along with concerto)
Liszt is playing.
That was a brilliant idea of yours, Garron.
Claudin may be up there now, listening.
That sounds in front of us.
It is in front of us.
The whole place is ready to crumble.
Sing, Christine.
Sing!
Don't move.
- The whole place is caving in.
- The shots must have started it.
He called that his concerto, and yet it's
written around the melody of my song.
- Who was he?
- He came from your district, in Provence.
Everybody there must have
known that old folk song.
He was almost a stranger to me, and yet...
somehow I always felt drawn to him
with a kind of pity, understanding.
His suffering and madness
will be forgotten.
His music, his concerto, will remain.
I'm glad he heard it, before he...
Poor Claudin.
Oh, mademoiselle,
you were magnificent tonight!
Thank you, Celeste. I was good, wasn't I?
Oh, wonderful!
- (knock on door)
- Celeste!
Monsieur.
You were magnificent, Christine!
- Incomparable, beautiful-a sensation!
- Is that all?
I've just begun. It would take days and
years to tell you how superb you were.
We're having supper tonight
at the Café de L'Opéra.
Well, I'm terribly sorry,
Anatole, but I can't tonight.
Why not? Have you another engagement?
- Yes.
- With whom?
With Raoul.
- That policeman?
- (knock at door)
- Come in.
- Christine!
- Oh.
(both) Christine...
- You two know each other, of course.
- (both) Of course.
How soon will you be ready?
The carriage is waiting.
- I know Monsieur Garron will excuse us.
- Anatole has just asked me to supper too.
No doubt. You won't be long,
will you, Christine?
I have an idea. Why can't we three have
supper together? It's all ordered, isn't it?
I am not in the habit of
taking baritones to supper.
And I do not care to be
seen in public with the police.
Christine, you'll have to
make up your mind finally between us.
Precisely.
(Vercheres)
Don't push, monsieur! Oh, no, no.
- Excuse... Mademoiselle...
- Excuse me.
Don't push, monsieur, please!
Will you join me for a bit of supper
at the Café de L'Opéra?
With pleasure, monsieur.
Think we can get through this crowd?
Certainly. After all, who'd pay any
attention to a baritone and a detective?
Quite right.
- After you, monsieur.
- After you,  monsieur.