Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
The nurse.
- Do you have any money?
- No.
Interpreter.
Where are you from?
- What is your name?
- Maria.
What is your name?
Come on, son. What is your name?
Vito Andolini from Corleone.
Vito Corleone.
Okay. Over there.
Next. Your name.
Tell him he has smallpox.
Quarantine, three months.
Vito Corleone?
Here he is. This is him.
Did you bring the car keys?
- Look who's here.
- Father Carmelo.
- This is Father Carmelo.
- I'm Merle Johnson.
Nice to meet you. Hi. Excuse me.
- Here I am.
- After one week?
I sent the car out to the
airport last week to pick you up.
It was chaos.
Anyway, here I am, just one week late.
And this is for my mama.
- What is this?
- You remember Merle, don't you?
- Hello, Mama.
- Yeah, hello.
How are you? Thank you.
Where's Michael? I gotta talk to him...
and get a few things straight,
and I can't wait on line.
You go see your children first...
and then you worry about waiting
on line to see your brother...
Like everybody else.
- Ladies and gentlemen.
- Frankie, wake up.
A most distinguished guest
would like to say a few words.
Would you please welcome Senator
Pat Geary of the state of Nevada.
And there's Mrs. Geary.
Thank you very much,
ladies and gentlemen.
And this is a very,
very happy day for me...
and my wife, Mrs. Geary.
We see Nevada far too seldom...
but particularly today...
when we can join with old
friends, we can make new friends...
and we help celebrate a
young man's first communion...
and also to thank that boy's family...
for a magnificent
contribution to the state.
I have here in my hand a check...
made out to the university...
and it is a magnificent endowment...
in the name of...
Anthony Vito Corleone.
And the check is signed by
that young man's parents...
whom I think we should recognize now.
Mike,
Pat, Kay--
Stand up, please. Let the folks see you.
Folks, I want you to join with me...
in giving a real Nevada thank-you...
to Mr. and Mrs. Michael Corleone!
We also have, as a
special added attraction...
the Sierra Boys Choir...
who have chosen...
a certain special song and
a special arrangement...
to honor their host,
Mr. Michael Corleone.
Boys.
- Why this feeling
- Why this glow
-Just why this glow
The plaque.
Okay, fellas, I got that one.
Okay, this is yours.
Senator, just you and Mrs. Corleone.
- Excuse me.
- This is my lawyer Tom Hagen.
- Senator Geary.
- Mr. Hagen.
He's the one who arranged this whole
thing through your man Turnbull.
- Yes, yes.
- Sit down.
I was under the impression
that you and I would talk alone.
I trust these men with my life, Senator.
If I were to ask them to
leave, it would be an insult.
It's all right with me, but I
should tell you I am a blunt man...
and I intend to speak
very frankly to you...
more frankly than anyone in my
position's talked to you before.
The Corleone family has done
very well here in Nevada.
You own, or you control,
two major hotels in Vegas...
one in Reno.
The licenses were grandfathered in...
so there was no problem
with the gaming commission.
But now my sources tell me that...
you plan to make a move
against the Tropigala.
They tell me that within a week...
you're gonna move Klingman out.
That's quite an expansion.
However, it will leave you with
one little technical problem.
The license will still
be in Klingman's name.
Turnbull is a good man.
Yeah, well, let's just--
Let's cut out the bullshit.
I don't want to spend any
more time here than I have to.
You can have the license.
The price is $250,000...
plus a monthly payment of
five percent of the gross...
of all four hotels...
Mr. Corleone.
Now, the price for the
license is less than $20,000.
- Am I right?
- That's right.
Now, why would I ever
consider paying more than that?
Because I intend to squeeze you.
I don't like your kind of people.
I don't like to see you come
out to this clean country...
in your oily hair...
dressed up in those silk suits...
and you try to pass yourselves
off as decent Americans.
I'll do business with you,
but the fact is that...
I despise your masquerade...
the dishonest way
you pose yourself--
yourself and your whole fucking family.
Senator...
we're both part of the same hypocrisy...
but never think it applies to my family.
All right, all right.
Some people have to play little games.
You play yours.
Let's just say that you'll pay me
because it's in your interest to.
But I want your answer and
the money by noon tomorrow.
And one more thing: Don't
you contact me again, ever.
From now on, you deal with
Turnbull. Open that door, son.
Senator, you can have my
answer now if you like.
My offer is this:
nothing.
Not even the fee for
the gaming license...
which I would appreciate if
you would put up personally.
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
Ladies. I didn't know you were out here.
- We have to go. We're late.
- Really? I'm sorry.
It's been a delightful party.
Thank you for inviting us.
It's been our pleasure. It
was wonderful talking to you.
Fredo, you son ofa bitch!
You look great!
Frank Pentangeli!
I thought you was never
coming out west, you big bum.
I gotta check on my boys, huh?
- What's with the food around here?
- What's the matter?
Kid comes up to me in a white jacket...
gives me a Ritz cracker
and a chopped liver...
he says "canapes."
I said, "Can of peas my ass!
That's a Ritz cracker
and chopped liver."
- Bring out the peppers and sausage.
- Hey, Freddie.
Seeing you reminds me of
New York. The old days, huh?
Hey, Fredo, you remember Willi Cicci?
We was with old man
Clemenza in Brooklyn.
We were all upset about that.
Heart attack, huh?
No, there was no heart attack.
That's what I'm here to
see your brother Mike about.
- But what's with him?
- What do you mean?
I mean, what do I gotta
do? Do I have to get...
a letter of introduction
to get a sit-down?
You can't get in to see Mike?
He's got me waiting in a lobby!
-Johnny Ola.
- AI Neri.
Do you know my lawyer
Tom Hagen? Johnny Ola.
Sure. I remember Tom from the old days.
Rocco, what's this?
It's an orange from Miami.
Take care of Johnny's men. They
look like they might be hungry.
- Good to see you.
- Tom isn't gonna sit in with us.
He only handles specifiic
areas of the family business.
- Tom?
- Sure, Mike.
What are you drinking, Johnny?
Anisette.
If you need anything I'll
be outside, all right?
Just tell Rocco we're waiting.
I just left Mr. Roth in Miami.
- How's his health?
- It's not good.
Is there anything I can
do, anything I can send?
He appreciates your concern,
Michael, and your respect.
That casino you're interested
in, the registered owners are...
Jacob Lawrence, Allan Barclay,
both Beverly Hills attorneys.
The real owners are the Lakeville
Road group from Cleveland...
and our friend in Miami.
Meyer Klingman runs the store.
He owns a piece of it
too, and he does all right.
But I've been instructed to tell
you that if you move Klingman out...
our friend in Miami will go along.
That's very kind of him.
You tell him that's greatly appreciated.
Hyman Roth always makes
money for his partners.
One by one, our old friends are gone.
Death, natural or not...
prison, deported.
Hyman Roth is the only one left...
because he always made
money for his partners.
My God! I can't believe...
out of 30 professional musicians...
there isn't one ltalian
in the group here.
Come on. Let's have a tarantella.
You, up! Come on! Up, up, up!
I'll see my sister alone.
It concerns me too.
Is it okay if I stay?
How are you, honey?
You've met Merle. He
was with me in Vegas.
- I saw him with you.
- Could I have a drink or something?
Al, would you please get him a drink?
We're going to Europe. I'd like
to book passage on the Queen.
So what do you come to me for?
Why don't you go to a travel agent?
We're getting married first.
The ink on your divorce isn't dry
yet, and you're getting married?
You see your children on weekends.
Your oldest boy was picked up in Reno...
for some petty theft you
don't even know about.
You fly around the world with
men who use you like a whore.
- You're not my father!
- Then what do you come to me for?
'Cause I need money.
I wanna be reasonable with you.
Now, why don't you stay here
with us, with the family?
You can live here on the
estate with your kids.
You won't be deprived of anything.
You can have everything you want.
Now, I don't know this Merle.
I don't know what he does.
I don't know what he lives on.
Tell him marriage is
out ofthe question...
and you don't want to see him anymore.
He'll understand. Believe me.
If you don't listen to me...
and marry this man...
you'll disappoint me.
What's cent'anni?
Cent'anni. It means a hundred years.
It means we should all live happily
for a hundred years, the family.
It'd be true if my father were alive.
Merle, you've met my
sister-in-law Deanna.
- Fredo's wife.
- A pleasure, Merle.
- How do you do?
- My pleasure.
What did she mean by that?
What's the matter? I just wanna dance.
Dancing is one thing. You're
falling all over the floor.
I know what's the matter. You're
jealous 'cause he's a real man.
I swear to God, I'm gonna
belt you right in the teeth.
You couldn't belt your mama.
You know something? These dagos are
crazy when it comes to their wives.
Michael says that if you
can't take care of this...
I have to.
- I think you'd better.
- Never marry a Wop!
They treat their wives like
shit! I didn't mean to say Wop!
Stop that!
What are you doing to me?
You big slob! Help!
I can't control her, Mikey.
You're my brother, Fredo. You
don't have to apologize to me.
Clemenza promised the Rosato brothers...
three territories in
the Bronx after he died.
You took over, and you
didn't give it to them.
- I welched?
- You welched.
Clemenza promised them "ugatz. "
Clemenza promised them nothing.
He hated those son ofa
bitches more than I do.
Frankie, they feel cheated.
You're sitting high up
in the Sierra Mountains...
and you're
drinking--
- What's he drinking, Cicci?
- Champagne.
Champagne cocktails.
And you're passing judgment
on how I run my family.
You're a good old man.
I like you.
And you were loyal to
my father for years.
The Rosato brothers,
they're taking hostages.
And Mike, they spit right in my face...
all because they're backed
up by that Jew in Miami.
I know. That's why I
don't want 'em touched.
- You don't want 'em touched.
- No.
I want you to be fair with them.
You want me to be fair with 'em?
How can you be fair to animals?
Tom, for Christ's sakes, listen.
They recruit spics.
They recruit niggers.
And they do violence in their
grandmothers' neighborhoods.
And I tell ya, everything
with them is whores.
Whores and junk. Dope.
And they leave the gambling to last.
Now, I wanna run my family
without you on my back...
and I want those Rosato brothers dead.
Now, I have business that's
important with Hyman Roth.
I don't want it disturbed.
Then you'll give your loyalty
to a Jew before your own blood?
Come on. You know my father
did business with Hyman Roth.
He respected him.
Your father did business
with Hyman Roth...
your father respected Hyman Roth...
but your father never
trusted Hyman Roth...
or his Sicilian
messenger boy Johnny Ola.
And I want everybody here to know...
there's not gonna be no trouble from me.
Don Corleone.
You want him to leave now?
Let him go back to New York.
I've already made my plans.
The old man had too much wine.
It's late.
How's the baby?
Sleeping inside me.
- Does it feel like a boy?
- Yes, it does, Michael.
I'm sorry about all the people today.
Bad timing.
It couldn't be helped, though.
It made me think of
what you once told me.
In five years, the Corleone family
will be completely legitimate.
That was seven years ago.
I know.
I'm trying, darling.
Did you see this?
Michael, why are the drapes open?
- Kay, you all right?
- Yeah.
- Are you hit?
- No.
It's over. It's over.
Now! Shut it off!
Hold it!
They're still on the
property. Please, stay inside.
- Keep them alive.
- We'll try.
Rocco! Alive!
Stay by the door.
Check by the boathouse!
Yeah, come in.
- Mike, are you all right?
- Yeah.
Yeah?
There's a lot I can't tell you, Tom.
Now, I know that's
upset you in the past.
You felt it was because of some
lack of trust or confidence...
but it's because I admire
you and I love you...
that I kept things secret from you.
That's why at this moment you're
the only one I can completely trust.
Fredo?
Well, he's got a good heart...
but he's weak and he's stupid...
and this is life and death.
Tom, you're my brother.
I always wanted to be thought
of as a brother by you.
A real brother.
I know that.
You're gonna take over.
You're gonna be the don.
If what I think has
happened has happened...
I'm gonna leave here tonight.
I give you complete power
over Fredo and his men--
Rocco, Neri, everyone.
I'm trusting you with the lives
of my wife and my children--
the future of this family.
When we catch these guys...
do you think we'll be able to
find out who's back ofall this?
We're not gonna catch 'em.
Unless I'm very wrong,
they're dead already.
They were killed by
somebody close to us.
Inside.
Very, very frightened they botched it.
Yeah, but your people, Rocco and Neri...
you don't think that they
had something to do with this?
See, all our people are businessmen.
Their loyalty's based on that.
One thing I learned from Pop...
was to try to think as
people around you think.
Now, on that basis, anything's possible.
I seen them! Right out my window!
I wanna get out of here!
They're lying there dead!
Get her inside!
Over here. There's two of'em.
Looks like they were
hired out of New York.
I don't recognize 'em.
We won't get anything out of them now.
Fish 'em out.
All right, get rid of the bodies.
- Where's Mike?
- Rocco.
Anthony, everything's
gonna be all right.
Try to sleep.
Did you like your party?
I got lots of presents.
I know. Did you like 'em?
I didn't know the people
who gave them to me.
Well, they're my friends.
Did you see my present for you?
It was on my pillow.
Anthony, I'm going to be
leaving very early tomorrow.
Will you take me?
- No, I can't, Anthony.
- Why do you have to go?
'Cause I have to do business.
I could help you.
Well, someday you will.
Get some sleep.
Good night.
Vito. Come on.
We'll go see her backstage.
Come here.
Vito. Come here. Come on.
You speak ltalian?
Yeah, sure.
Come on in.
It's all right. Come
on. Hyman's in there.
I was just making some lunch.
Would you like a tuna sandwich?
Uh, no, thankyou.
Pickup of two by Holden.
Second and eight for S.C...
and the ball is at
the Trojan 38-yardline.
Mr. Roth?
Come in, Michael.
Sit down. Make yourself comfortable.
It's almost over.
You follow the football game?
- Pickup offive.
- Not for a while I haven't.
I enjoy watching
football in the afternoon.
One of the things I
love about this country.
Baseball too.
I've loved baseball...
ever since Arnold Rothstein
fixed the World Series in 1919.
...47. Marked down
there, say the officials.
And at that point
it'll be first and ten--
I heard you had some trouble.
It'll be third and ten, another
of those big plays now...
- Stupid.
- coming up for S.C.
People behaving like that with guns.
...but it looks like
it could stall here.
The important thing
is, you're all right.
Good health. The most important thing.
More than success. More than money.
- Now he's back to pass.
- More than power.
Rolls up field for
Hayes. He's intercepted.
Hurd has it to the lrish 40. To
the far sideline. Gets by the 45.
He's hit and dropped
at the S.C. 42-yardline.
Notre Dame's first bigbreak of the game.
I came here because there's
gonna be more bloodshed.
I want you to know about
it before it happens...
so that there's no danger
of starting another war.
Nobody wants another war.
Frank Pentangeli came to my home
and he asked my permission...
to get rid of the Rosato brothers.
When I refused, he
tried to have me killed.
He was stupid. I was
lucky. I'll visit him soon.
The important thing is
that nothing interfere...
with our plans for the future.
- Yours and mine.
- Nothing is more important.
Good.
You're a wise and considerate young man.
And you're a great man, Mr. Roth.
- There's much I can learn from you.
- What can I do to help, Michael?
To the 32, and is downed
there by Danny Zika.
- Excuse me. Lunch.
- Oh.
- Okay.
- Ohh!
Hyman, you're gonna break my ear drums.
- Okay, enjoy it.
- Thanks.
You're young. I'm old and sick.
What we'll do together
in the next few months...
will make history, Michael.
History. It's never been done before.
Not even your father would dream
that such a thing could be possible.
And Pentangeli is a dead man.
- You don't object?
- Pickup of four.
He's small potatoes.
What's up?
We got company, huh?
Don Corleone, I wish you would've
let me know you were comin'.
I could've prepared something for you.
I didn't want you to know I was coming.
You heard what happened in my home?
- Mike, I almost died myself.
- In my home!
In my bedroom where my wife sleeps!
Where my children come
and play with their toys.
In my home.
I want you to help me take my revenge.
Michael, anything.
What can I do?
Settle these troubles
with the Rosato brothers.
Mike, I don't
understand. I don't--
I don't have your brain for big deals...
but this is a street thing.
That Hyman Roth
in Miami. That--
He's backin' up those
son-of-a-bitches.
I know.
Then why? Why do you ask
me to lay down to him, Mike?
It was Hyman Roth that
tried to have me killed.
I know it was him.
Jesus Christ, Mike.
Jesus Christ, look, let's get 'em all.
Let's hit 'em all now,
while we got the muscle.
This used to be my father's old study.
It's changed.
I remember there
used to be a--
A big desk was here.
I remember when I was a kid, Frankie...
we had to be very quiet
when we played near here.
I was very happy that this
house never went to strangers.
First Clemenza took it over. Now you.
My father taught me many things here.
He taught me in this room.
He taught me, keep your friends close...
but your enemies closer.
Now, if Hyman Roth sees that
I interceded in this thing...
in the Rosato brothers' favor...
he's gonna think his relationship
with me is still good.
That's what I want him to think.
I want him completely relaxed
and confident in our friendship.
Then I'll be able to find out
who the traitor in my family was.
- Yeah?
- Fredo. This is Johnny.
Johnny Ola. We need some more help.
Johnny?
Jesus Christ, what the hell time is it?
- Who is that, honey?
- Listen good, Fredo.
What are you callin' me here
for? I don't want to talk to you.
Pentangeli's set up a meeting
with the Rosato brothers.
- He's gonna go for their deal.
- Oh, God.
- Will he come alone?
- I don't know anything.
- You got me in deep enough already.
- Just go along.
Everything will be allright, Fredo.
Pentangeli says he's
willing to make a deal.
All we wanna know is
if he's on the level.
You guys lied to me. I don't
want you to call me anymore.
Your brother's not
gonna find out we talked.
I don't know what you're talkin' about.
Who was that?
Uh, wrong number.
Frank, I got nobody here.
- Wait in the car,
Cheech. - Frankie--
It's okay, Cheech.
- What's this, Rosato?
- A lucky "C" note for our new deal.
Richie. Give us a taste, huh?
Yeah, we're all real happy
about your decision, Frankie.
- You're not gonna regret it.
- I don't like this "C" note.
I take that as an insult.
Michael Corleone says hello.
Get him in! Close the fuckin' door!
Your friend the
cop. What the--
Hey, Rich, it's dark in here.
- Are you open or closed?
- I just come in to clean up.
What's the matter?
- Is that somethin' on the floor?
- Carmine, no, no. Not here!
- Not here!
- Not here, Carmine! Not a cop!
What?
You open your fuckin' mouth,
I'll blow your head off!
Freddie. Good to see ya.
Where is he?
He's okay. He's in the back.
Come on, girls. Take a hike, huh?
In this room here.
- I wanna talk to him alone first.
- Come on, huh?
I thought I could help you, Senator.
Hagen?
- Listen, Hagen,
I did not-- - No.
- It's all right.
- I didn't do anything.
It's okay.
You're very lucky.
My brother Fredo operates this place.
He was called before anyone.
Now, if this had
happened someplace else...
we couldn't have helped you.
When I woke up I was on the floor...
and I don't know how it happened.
You can't remember?
I passed out.
I'll fix it.
Okay.
It was just a game.
Jesus.
Oh.
Jesus! Jesus!
Jesus God.
Oh, God.
I don't know and I don't
understand why I can't remember.
You don't have to
remember. Just do as I say.
They're putting a
call in to your office.
Explain that you'll be
there tomorrow afternoon.
You decided to spend the night...
at Michael Corleone's
house in Tahoe as his guest.
I do remember that she was laughing.
We'd done it before...
and I know that I could
not have hurt that girl.
This girl has no family.
Nobody knows that she worked here.
It'll be as though she never existed.
All that's left is our friendship.
- Yes?
- I'm sorry, Mrs. Corleone.
- We're not to let you through.
- I'm just going to the market.
Well, if you'll just give us a list,
we'll pick up anything you want.
- Whose orders are these?
- Mr. Hagen's, ma'am. He's coming.
All right, well, I'm just gonna
have to speak to Mr. Hagen.
I wanted to explain this, but
I had business in Carson City.
Now, this is Michael's
request for your safety.
- We can send out for anything.
- I see.
I'm supposed to stay in my house.
No, within the compound would be fine.
I was going to take the children
to New England next week.
- That's off now.
- Am I a prisoner? ls that it?
- That's not the way we look at it.
- All right, come on, kids.
We're going back to the house.
Joe.
Cuba! Cuba!
Most respected gentlemen...
allow me to welcome you
to the city of Havana.
I want to thank this distinguished
group of American industrialists...
for continuing to work with Cuba...
toward the greatest
period of prosperity...
in her entire history.
Mr. William Shaw, representing
the General Fruit Company;
Misters Corngold and Dant...
of United Telephone
and Telegraph Company;
Mr. Petty, regional vice president...
of the Pan American Mining Corporation;
Mr. Robert Allen of
South American Sugar;,
Mr. Michael Corleone of Nevada...
representing our associates in
tourism and leisure activities;
and my old friend and
associate from Florida...
Mr. Hyman Roth.
I would like to take this opportunity...
to thank United
Telephone and Telegraph...
for their lovely Christmas gift:
a solid gold telephone.
Perhaps you gentlemen would
like to take a look at it.
- Mr. President.
- Yes?
Perhaps you would discuss the
status of rebel activity...
and what this can
mean to our businesses.
- Of course.
- Very lovely.
I want to assure you that
although the rebels...
have mounted an impressive
campaign in Las Villas...
my staff indicates with assurance...
we'll drive them out of the city
of Santa Clara before the new year.
And I want to put you all at ease.
We will tolerate no guerillas
in the casinos or swimming pools.
He say that they are making arrest...
and in a few minutes
he'll let us through.
Johnny.
Well, I hope my age is correct.
I'm always accurate about my age.
Make sure that everybody sees
the cake before we cut it.
I'm very pleased...
you were all able to come
from such distances...
to be with me today.
When a man comes to
this point in his life...
he wants to turn over the
things he's been blessed with--
turn them over
to friends--
as a reward for the friends he's had...
and to make sure that everything
goes well after he's gone.
- Not for years.
- Hear, hear.
The doctors would disagree,
but what do they know?
These are wonderful things
that we've achieved in Havana...
and there's no limit to
where we can go from here.
This kind of government knows how
to help business, to encourage it.
The hotels here are
bigger and swankier...
than any of the rough
joints we've put in in Vegas.
And we can thank our friends
in the Cuban government...
which has put up half of the
cash, with the Teamsters...
on a dollar-for-dollar
basis;
has relaxed restrictions on imports.
What I'm saying is that we have
now what we have always needed:
real partnership with a government.
Smaller piece.
You all know Michael Corleone...
and we all remember his father.
At the time of my retirement or death...
I turn over all my interest
in the Havana operation...
to his control.
But all of you will share.
The Nacionale will go to
the Lakeville Road boys.
The Capri to the Corleone
family. The Sevilla Biltmore also.
But Eddie Levine of Newport will
bring in the Pennino brothers...
Dino and Eddie, for a piece...
and also to handle the
actual casino operations.
And we've saved a piece for
some friends in Nevada...
to make sure that things
go smooth back home.
I want all of you to enjoy your cake...
so enjoy.
- Happy birthday.
I saw an interesting thing happen today.
A rebel was being arrested
by the military police...
and rather than be taken alive...
he exploded a grenade he
had hidden in his jacket.
He killed himself, and he took a
captain of the command with him.
- Right,Johnny?
- Those rebels, they're lunatics.
- Yes, I agree.
- Maybe so.
But it occurred to me...
the soldiers are paid to
fight, the rebels aren't.
What does that tell you?
They could win.
This country has had rebels
for the last 50 years.
It's in their blood. I've been
coming here since the '20s.
We were running molasses out of
Havana when you were a baby...
the trucks owned by your father.
Michael.
I'd rather we talked about
this when we we're alone.
The two million never got to the island.
I wouldn't want it to get around
that you held back the money...
because you had second
thoughts about the rebels.
Ah, sit down, Michael.
Sit down.
If I could only live to see
it, to be there with you.
Ohh.
What I wouldn't give for...
20 more years.
Here we are,
protected--
free to make our profiits
without Kefauver...
the goddamn Justice
Department and the FBl--
90 miles away, partnership
with a friendly government.
Ninety miles. It's nothing.
Just one small step,
looking for a man...
that wants to be President
of the United States...
and having the cash to make it possible.
Michael...
we're bigger than U.S. Steel.
Mikey, how are ya? Okay?
Hiya. Freddie Corleone.
Jesus Christ, what a trip.
The whole time I'm thinkin'...
"What if somebody knows
what I got in here?"
Imagine that. Two million
dollars on the seat next to me.
All right.
- Whoops. Excuse me.
- No, it's okay.
You wanna count it?
Mikey, what the hell's goin' on anyway?
The family's making an
investment in Havana.
- This is a gift for the president.
- Oh.
Well, that's great.
Havana's great.
It's my kind of town.
- Anybody I know in Havana?
- I don't know.
Hyman Roth? Johnny Ola?
No. I never met them.
Listen, Mikey...
I'm kind
of, uh--
kind of nervous from the trip.
Uh, can l-- can I get a,
uh, drink or somethin'?
I thought maybe we'd--
we'd go out together.
I know a place we can spend
some time together. Okay?
Sometimes I think I should've
married a woman like you did...
Like Kay.
Have kids, have a family.
For once in my life be more like...
Pop.
It's not easy to be a
son, Fredo. It's not easy.
Mama used to tease me. She'd
say, "You don't belong to me.
You were left on the
doorstep by gypsies."
Sometimes I think it's true.
You're no gypsy, Fredo.
Mikey,
I--
I was mad at you.
Why didn't we spend
time like this before?
You want a drink, right? Waiter.
- How do you say banana daiquiri?
- Banana daiquiri.
- That's it?
- That's it.
- Uh, uno banana daiquiri.
- Banana daiquiri. Si, senor.
And, uh, a club soda.
Senator Geary's flying in from
Washington tomorrow night...
with some people, some
government people...
and I want you to show
'em a good time in Havana.
It's my specialty, right?
- Can I trust you with something?
- Ofcourse, Mike.
In the evening, we're all invited
to the presidential palace...
a reception to bring in the new year.
After it's over...
they're gonna take me
home in a military car...
alone, for my protection...
and before I reach my
hotel I'll be assassinated.
- Who?
- Roth.
It was Roth who tried
to kill me in my home.
It was Roth all along.
He acts like I'm his
son, his successor...
but he thinks he's gonna live
forever and he wants me out.
How can I help?
You just go along as
though you know nothing.
- I've already made my move.
- What move?
Hyman Roth'll never see the new year.
He says you have to take it easy
and he'll give you a prescription.
He'll be back tomorrow.
I want my own doctor.
Fly him in from Miami.
I don't trust a doctor
can't speak English.
Honey, go down to the casino.
- If you're sure you're better.
- Feel fine.
- Play the bingo game.
- Nice to see you, Mr. Paul.
-Just make yourself at home.
- Thank you.
My sixth sense tells me...
your brother Fredo brought
a bag full of money.
Where is it?
You're pulling out?
Just wanna-- I
just wanna wait.
How do you feel?
Terrible. I'd give four million...
just to be able to take
a piss without it hurting.
Who had Frank Pentangeli killed?
The Rosato brothers.
I know. But who gave the go-ahead?
I know I didn't.
There was this kid I grew up with.
He was younger than me.
Sort of looked up to me, you know.
We did our first work together.
Worked our way out of the street.
Things were good. We
made the most of it.
During Prohibition...
we ran molasses into Canada.
Made a fortune. Your father too.
As much as anyone...
I loved him and trusted him.
Later on he had an idea...
to build a city...
out of a desert stopover for G.I.s
on their way to the West Coast.
That kid's name was Moe Green...
and the city he invented was Las Vegas.
This was a great man...
a man of vision and guts...
and there isn't even a plaque or
a signpost or a statue of him...
in that town.
Someone put a bullet through his eye.
No one knows who gave the order.
When I heard it I wasn't angry.
I knew Moe; I knew he was headstrong.
Talking loud, saying stupid things.
So when he turned up dead...
I let it go...
and I said to myself...
"This is the business we've chosen."
I didn't ask...
who gave the order...
because it had nothing
to do with business.
That two million in
a bag in your room--
I'm going in...
to take a nap.
When I wake...
if the money's on the table
I'll know I have a partner.
If it isn't, I'll know I don't.
All right, does everybody
know everybody here, huh?
- This is Senator Geary.
- How are you, Senator?
Good to see you, Mike. I'm glad
we could spend time together.
- Senator Payton from Florida.
- How you doing, Mike?
- And Judge DeMalco from New York.
- How do you do, sir?
- Fine, thank you.
- Senator Ream from Maryland.
- I've been looking forward to this.
- This is Fred Corngold from U.T.T.
- I know Fred. How are you? -
Fred does a mean cha-cha-cha.
- Oh, he does, huh?
- Gentlemen, it's refiill time.
Try some of them local drinks--
uh, cuba libre, pina colada.
I think I'll try one of
those redheaded Yolandas.
- That you got. Congusto.
- Johnny.
You don't know my brother Fredo,
do you, Johnny? Johnny Ola, Fredo.
- We never met. Johnny Ola.
- Pleasure.
Gentlemen, to a night in Havana.
- Happy New Year.
- That's right, huh?
- Checkin' in now. Right now.
- Never fear! Pat Geary's here!
- Hey, Fred.
- Cheers! Hey!
- Hey, Freddie, why are we standin'?
- Come on, man!
Everybody stands, but it's worth it.
- You're not gonna believe this.
- I don't believe it already.
- That's right. Fifty dollars.
- You got a bet, mister.
That's him. That's Superman.
- Jesus Christ!
- Did I tell ya, or did I tell ya?
- I don't believe it.
- That thing's gotta be a fake.
That ain't no fake. That's real.
That's why they call him Superman.
Hey, Freddie. Freddie. Where
did you find this place?
Johnny Ola told me about this
place. He brought me here.
I didn't believe it, but
seein' is believin', huh?
- I see it and I don't believe it.
- Fifty bucks, Pat.
Old man Roth'd never come here...
but ol'Johnny knows these
places like the back of his hand.
Now watch him. He's gonna
break the cracker with it.
I wanna see him break a brick.
He could knock down a building.
Relax, Senor Roth. We're
taking you to the hospital.
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player