Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
-Get me a cab, will you?
-Yes, sir.
The most
brilliantly written
play I'Őve seen in years.
The man'Ős a born wit.
The whole play was
tremendously exciting.
I hear he'Ős writing a new one.
I can hardly wait to see it.
Cab!
Well, gentlemen, the English
theater has just given birth
to a genius.
I feel sure
Wilde would be the first
to agree with you, Harry.
I wish I could approve of
the playwright as much as
I approve of his play.
Who cares about him as long
as he continues to give us
plays like this?
Well, Oscar, how does it feel
to be a success?
Did you have
any doubts, Robbie?
Congratulations, Oscar.
Brilliant play! Brilliant!
Ah, there I'Őm bound
to agree with you,
Lord Sonning.
My dear Mr. Wilde, I was
simply delighted with
your play.
I even enjoyed the interval.
Dear Lady Sonning,
she has the remains
of a remarkable ugliness.
I'Őve always been
a great admirer of
your work, Mr. Wilde.
And I'Őve always
been a great admirer
of my work, Mr. Shaw.
-Frank!
-Oscar!
-Wonderful play.
-Thank you.
-My dear lady mother.
-Oscar.
My dear boy, a triumph.
A magnificent triumph.
Ada, what are you going to say
about my play in that woman'Ős
magazine you run?
I shall praise
it as highly as you
would yourself, Oscar.
You'Őve always been
the best critic
of my work.
-But I never
criticize your work.
-Exactly.
I'Őm so proud, Oscar.
And I'Őm so proud of you.
You look wonderful.
Oscar, people are watching.
I hardly think Oscar
is the type of man
to worry about his behavior
in public.
And how did brother Willie
like the play?
Or couldn'Őt you
see it from the bar?
Ooh, I'Őm perfectly sober,
thank you, Oscar.
I'Őve ordered a table
at the Savoy.
OSCAR: Get a cab, Robbie,
there'Ős a good chap.
ROBBIE: Of course.
Constance, you don'Őt mind
not coming.
-But you know,
these supper parties.
-Very well, Oscar.
-Mother will take you.
Now, won'Őt you, Mother?
-Yes, of course.
-Willie, get my wrap.
-Goodbye, my dear.
Ada.
Come along, Bosie.
Good night, Mrs. Wilde.
Good night, Bosie.
A green carnation.
How delightfully eccentric.
Damned ridiculous,
if you ask me.
But who'Ős the handsome
young boy with him?
Good heavens, Edith,
you are out of touch.
Why, the whole of London
is talking about them.
It'Ős a damn disgrace
the way the fellow
is carrying on.
These artistic fellows
think they can get away
with anything.
But who is he? Well, you...
He'Ős Lord Alfred Douglas.
Queensberry'Ős son.
If I were Queensberry, I'Őd...
You'Őd do what, sir?
What would you do?
Excuse me.
Lord Alfred, you remember
my daughter?
-Oh, Mrs. Somers.
How do you do?
-Phyllis.
Poor Mrs. Somers.
Still trying to get
that daughter off
her hands.
Well, she'Ős wasting
her time with him.
Oh, my lord.
You wicked man.
Bosie!
Don'Őt you even
acknowledge me anymore?
What do you want, Father?
Have you any idea
how sick it makes me
to watch you making
a fool of yourself?
A fine spectacle you are, sir,
fawning and crawling round
this fellow, Wilde,
like some damn little lapdog.
Are we going to
have another one of
your scenes, Father?
Scenes or no scenes, sir.
I'Őll not tolerate
this behavior.
Would you sooner I went
around with professional
boxers and sporting gentry?
At least my friends
behave like men.
-Father, I'Őm over 21...
-Only just.
I don'Őt see that
I have to answer to
you for my behavior,
nor seek your permission
for the choice of my friends.
You are a disgrace to
the name of Queensberry!
I really don'Őt have...
Bosie, is the cab ready yet?
Oscar, this unpleasant
little man is my father.
-Lord Queensberry?
-Yes.
Pleasure to meet you, sir.
The pleasure is entirely yours,
Mr. Wilde.
-Oscar, let'Ős go.
-Just a minute.
-I have a few things
to say to this gentleman.
-Father!
-You listen to me, sir.
-Oh, really, Lord Queensberry.
I think the public
have had enough play
acting for one night.
I demand to be heard!
You are being heard, sir,
by the entire theater.
I should...
Well done, Wilde.
Most entertaining.
We both thought so,
didn'Őt we, my dear?
You'Őre very flattering,
Your Royal Highness.
And Mrs. Langtry,
you'Őre very beautiful.
I adore flattery almost
as much as you do, Oscar.
I didn'Őt know
you were a patron
of the arts, Queensberry.
I thought
fist fighting was
more in your line.
Well, thank you for a most
enjoyable evening, Wilde.
We shall look forward
to the next play.
Good night, sir.
You coming, Bosie?
Let me just say this, Father.
You'Őve been hounding me
long enough.
If you try and interfere
with me again,
or write anymore of
your abusive letters,
I shall have no hesitation
in seeking the protection
of the law.
You may have the law on your
hands much sooner than you
think, my boy.
Good morning, Edward.
Good morning, Mr. Wilde, sir.
Lovely morning.
Yes, I think I'Őll
walk a little. Follow.
Where to, sir?
The Cafe Royal.
Cafe Royal? Very good, sir.
Mr. Wilde. Mr. Wilde, sir.
Mr. Wilde, one thing my
readers are anxious to learn.
-What paper do
you write for, sir?
-The Echo,sir.
Well, if your readers
were anxious to learn
anything,
they wouldn'Őt take the Echo.
May I ask you, sir,
why do you always wear
a green carnation?
REPORTER: Mr. Wilde,
your book Dorian Gray...
Wait a minute.
What did you say, sir?
Why do you always
wear a green carnation?
I consider nature
to be quite inadequate.
Why she never thought
of a green carnation,
I can'Őt imagine.
REPORTER: Mr. Wilde.
No doubt she will
get around to it in time.
Mr. Wilde, your book
Dorian Grayhas been
severely criticized.
Not by me.
Yes, but, many people
do consider it immoral.
Ah, now, sir.
What is immorality?
I consider that to conform
to the narrow
moral standards of
this Victorian age
the grossest form
of immorality.
Yes, but, you know,
it is said, sir,
that much of your writing
and indeed your basic
philosophy
is fundamentally immoral.
What have you to say to that?
I may have offended
some people,
but I'Őm sure that in 50 years,
the works of Oscar Wilde
will be standard literature
for every fifth form schoolboy.
Hear! Hear!
My only regret is
that I shan'Őt be there
-to collect the royalties.
I must say I hardly
think a newspaperman
is in a position to
speak of immorality.
-What?
-Indeed, Lord Alfred.
Well, what could be more
immoral than a newspaper?
It condemns gambling
on the front page
and prints racing tips
on the back.
Brilliant, Bosie.
I wish I'Őd said that.
You will, Oscar. You will.
When you go back to Oxford,
you can say you outwitted
Oscar Wilde.
If I ever go back,
I certainly will.
What do you mean?
Well, didn'Őt you know?
I'Őve been sent down.
Congratulations!
All the best people
are being sent down
these days.
What did you do, Bosie?
Set fire to the
dean'Ős trousers?
Waiter! Waiter!
More champagne.
Frankly I believe too much
education'Ős a bad thing.
Don'Őt you agree, Oscar?
I certainly do.
Ignorance is
a delicate blossom.
Touch it and it'Ős gone.
You didn'Őt tell me
that you'Őd been sent down.
-Didn'Őt I?
-No.
-Oh.
-Why?
It was all rather tedious.
Tedious or not,
I'Őd like to hear about it.
Well, there was
some scandal over
a boy in the town.
You know how
provincial Oxford
can be in some ways.
Frankly, I find
the whole thing
rather amusing,
but unfortunately
my father didn'Őt.
He was so disgusted with
his "so called son"
as he put it,
that he'Ős disowned
me completely.
So now, I haven'Őt
a penny in the world.
MAN: Frank, you'Őre drunk.
FRANK: Drunk? Who'Ős drunk?
Oscar, have you
ever seen me when I had
more than I could carry?
No, but I'Őve seen
you when you should have
taken more than one trip.
Why didn'Őt you tell
me about this before?
Well, you were so busy,
what, with your play and...
If you'Őre in any trouble,
you only have to come to me.
And if it'Ős
money you need,
you needn'Őt worry.
You'Őre very kind to me, Oscar.
I'Őm very fond of you.
Besides, what is
friendship for?
Come on, Mr. Wilde,
we'Őre running out
of conversation.
As long as we'Őre not
running out of wine.
Waiter! Waiter!
You know, gentlemen,
in the past few years,
I'Őve made
a remarkable discovery.
What was that, Oscar?
Alcohol, if taken in
sufficient quantities,
produces all the effects
of intoxication.
Gentlemen, I give you a toast.
To youth.
HARRIS: Oscar,
you talk as if
you'Őre an old man.
I am. I'Őd do anything
to regain my lost youth
except take up exercise or
get up early in the morning.
Waiter! Waiter,
where'Ős that champagne?
MAN: Ah, thank you.
Here we are.
-Good evening, sir.
-Hello, Arthur.
Oscar! You said
you'Őd be in for lunch.
Yes, I had a meeting
with my publisher.
The children have
been asking for you.
OSCAR: Oh.
They refuse
to go to sleep until
you tell them a story.
Oh, very well.
BOYS: Daddy! Daddy!
Now, what'Ős all
this about your not sleeping?
We want you to tell us a story.
I see.
Well, now,
what shall I tell
you tonight about?
Not too long, Oscar.
Giants or dragons?
You told us the story
about giants last night.
Well, have I told you
the story about
the Happy Prince?
No.
High above the city
on a tall column
stood the statue
of the Happy Prince.
He was gilded all over
with thin leaves
of fine gold.
For eyes he had
two bright sapphires
and a large red ruby
glowed on his sword hilt.
He was as beautiful
as a weather cock.
Yes, sir?
Mr. Oscar Wilde?
I don'Őt know that
he'Ős at home, sir.
Ah. My name is Wood.
-Wood, sir?
-Yes.
I'Őm a friend of
Lord Alfred Douglas.
Oh, I see, sir.
Would you step
inside, sir?
I'Őll enquire if Mr. Wilde
will see you, sir.
"Dear little swallow,"
said the prince.
"You tell me marvelous things,
"but more marvelous
than anything
"is the suffering
of men and women."
Excuse me, sir.
There'Ős a person
to see you, sir.
Very well.
-He gave his name as Wood, sir.
-Wood?
Said he was a friend
of Lord Alfred'Ős, sir.
Oh, I see.
He'Ős in the front room, sir.
Thank you, Arthur.
Mr. Wood?
That'Ős right, sir.
Oh. Very delicate.
Very delicate indeed.
I understand you are
a friend of Lord Alfred'Ős.
Uh, well, I suppose
you might say that,
sir, yes.
A very friendly gentleman,
His Lordship, sir,
very friendly.
Well, he didn'Őt mention you,
Mr. Wood, but...
Uh, Alfred Wood, sir.
Same name as His Lordship, sir.
I'Őm no lord, of course, sir,
but as a poet like
yourself might say,
"What'Ős in a name?"
Cognac, Mr. Wood?
Thank you, sir.
You knew Lord Alfred at Oxford?
Well, not
exactly at Oxford, sir.
No, sir,
not in the way
that you might mean.
I used
to do odd jobs
for His Lordship.
Oh, very kind he
was to me, sir. Yes.
A gentleman
like yourself, sir,
in every particular.
Thank you, sir.
Well, I'Őm very glad to
meet any friend of Bosie'Ős.
Bosie?
Oh.
Yes, of course, sir.
Your health, sir.
Very fine brandy this, sir.
Drives the cold from
the bones.
Well, I, uh...
I won'Őt beat about
the bush, sir,
as the saying goes.
Quite by accident, sir,
I assure you, I a...
I came across
that letter from you
to Lord Alfred Douglas.
Very beautiful letter,
if I might say so, sir.
Only I think that perhaps
there are parts that
could be "misconstrued,"
I think is the word, sir.
How did you come by this?
Ah, yes, well, I used to...
Used to press
Lord Alfred'Ős clothes.
Very particular
about his clothes, sir.
As well you may know.
I, uh, found it
in one of his pockets.
Are you asking me to
purchase my own work,
Mr. Wood?
Well, sir, I...
Come, sir, that'Ős not
very sound economics.
Well, I'Őve already
been offered Ł60
for it, sir.
Then I suggest that
you sell it at once.
I myself have seldom
been offered so much
for a prose work
of that length.
You take the letter, sir.
It was stupid of me
to try and rent you.
The thing is, sir,
that I'Őm desperate
for money and...
A hungry man gets
driven to do stupid things.
Oh, would you like
a ham sandwich?
Now you'Őre making
fun of me, sir.
On the
contrary, Mr. Wood.
You'Őre doing
remarkably well yourself.
Well, I think I'Őll
be going now, sir.
No, no, no, no.
Please stay and
finish your drink.
That'Ős very kind of you.
You'Őre a very poor criminal,
Mr. Wood, if I may say so.
The fact is
I came to London
to look for some work.
Ah, work, Mr. Wood, is the
curse of the drinking classes.
The secret of maintaining youth
is an inordinate
passion for pleasure.
Ł40, sir?
I'Őm going
out to dine in a moment.
Perhaps you'Őd care to join me.
Well, that'Ős very kind
of you, sir.
There'Ős a fascinating charm
about your halfhearted
criminal tendencies,
Mr. Wood.
I suspect that you lead
a wonderfully wicked life.
Ah, well,
there'Ős good and
bad in all of us, sir.
Mr. Wood, you'Őre
a born philosopher.
I'Őm sure we shall
get along extremely well.
Your health, sir.
Shall I serve dinner, madam?
I can'Őt understand it.
I'Őm sure Mr. Wilde said
he would be in for dinner.
Well, perhaps
he'Ős been detained
on business, madam.
Yes.
Shall we wait?
No, Arthur, I'Őll dine alone.
Very well, madam.
Bosie, you'Őre
nearly an hour late.
Yes, I know.
Oh, I know what
that face means.
It usually heralds
an unpleasant scene.
It would be nice
if it could be avoided.
I'Őm in a singularly good mood.
-Are you?
-I was.
No doubt, having
entertained your friend
at the Savoy last night.
You mean Mr. Wood?
Really, Oscar, have
you no sense of propriety?
The man is a valet.
A very amusing valet.
Thank heavens, Bosie,
I am not inhibited
by your sense of class.
So it seems.
Anyway, he was your friend.
I hardly knew the man.
That'Ős not the impression
that he gave to me.
WAITER: Good morning, My Lord.
What did he want anyway?
Money. What do
the poor usually want?
Would you like to
order now, My Lord?
And you gave it to him?
For a valuable
piece of property.
A letter I wrote you at Oxford.
WAITER: May I recommend
the lobster, My Lord?
-I'Őll have the sole meuniere.
-Very good.
Do you mean he blackmailed you?
Leaving that letter
around for anyone to find
was not only careless of you,
but singularly
lacking in respect
for something
that I'Őd hoped was
private and personal.
Waiter, bring some
champagne right away.
Very good, My Lord.
It'Őd seem, Bosie,
that I am forever paying
for your indiscretions
and your extravagances.
Money, is that all
you ever think of?
Ah, when I was young
I thought money was
everything.
Now that I'Őm older
I know that it is.
My God, Oscar,
you'Őre never satisfied.
You have a successful book out,
a play running
in the West End...
Playing to packed
houses of creditors.
Have you any idea
how much money I'Őve spent
since we'Őve been together?
I'Őm sure you've
kept an account.
Luncheon every day here,
dinner at the Savoy,
supper at...
-Oh, look what you'Őve done.
-I'Őm sorry, sir.
-Please.
-Oh, go away, stop fussing.
And always the best champagne
because you have
a very delicate palate.
Bosie, you seem to think
that you have a right to
live at my expense
in a profuse luxury to
which you have never
been accustomed.
I pay
your hotel bills,
your tailor'Ős bill,
your gambling debts.
You demand
without grace and you
receive without thanks.
Have you finished?
Now tell
me honestly, Oscar.
What did you expect, hmm?
Did you think I was
some common street Arab
to be bought
with cheap trinkets
and an occasional supper
in some Soho restaurant?
I'Őve given
you my friendship
for two years, Oscar.
I'Őve admired your genius,
laughed at your jokes,
flattered your vanity.
And now you question the
price of such a friendship.
It isn'Őt worthy of you, Oscar.
-Good evening, Mr. Wilde.
-Evening, William.
Sydney.
Thank you, sir.
-Good evening, Mr. Wilde.
-Good evening.
I want you to take
this to this address.
It'Ős just around the corner.
-Straight away, hmm?
-Right away, sir.
Hello, Robbie.
Hello, Oscar.
What will you have?
Brandy, and a large one.
John. A large brandy.
Give me a cigarette,
there'Ős a dear fellow.
I seem to have
left mine at home.
-What?
-A cigarette.
Oh, yes, of course.
Thank you.
What is it, Oscar?
Are you not well?
No, just very tired,
that'Ős all.
Your brandy, sir.
Thank you.
Oscar, did you know that
some of the club members
have approached
the Committee
to get you to resign?
Well, I hope not. I shall
have to find somewhere else
to sleep in the afternoons.
Have you any idea how much
people are talking about you
or what they are saying?
I adore scandal
about other people,
but about myself
I find it extremely dull.
It hasn'Őt the charm of novelty.
I don'Őt think you'll
find this gossip dull.
Robbie, are you being
solicitous about my welfare?
That is very
impertinent of you.
I don'Őt mean to be.
Oscar, I realize
that much of your
extravagant behavior
is done purely for effect.
You'Őre an artist.
The public expects
you to be different.
But you'Őre no longer
an ascetic young poet
just down from Oxford.
-Relax.
-You'Őre a highly
successful playwrighter
at the peak of your career.
You dine with royalty.
You mix in the highest
social circles.
Ah.
You'Őre walking along
a precipice, Oscar.
Just as long
as you continue
to play court jester,
society will accept you.
But tax their tolerance too far
and they'Őll send you
crashing from the heights
-to the depths of obscurity.
-Oh, really.
A halo doesn'Őt have to fall
very far, Oscar, to become
a noose.
Really, Robbie,
this all very tedious.
Just tell me one thing.
These stories I hear about you.
There isn'Őt any truth
in them, is there?
As I don'Őt know
what the stories are,
I'Őm hardly in a position
to answer you.
They say that you...
You'Őre being
blackmailed because of
your association with Bosie.
That you consort with
criminals, stable boys.
This sounds all very
exciting and intriguing.
Do go on.
I just want to hear
you tell me it isn'Őt true.
Robbie,
I'Őm deeply hurt
that you use our friendship
to pry into my private life.
I thought
you were a gentleman.
I now see that you are not.
I just want to
hear you deny it, Oscar.
You must think
what you will, Robbie.
Mr. Wood to see you, sir.
Thank you.
Robbie, because
I'Őm very fond of you
I shall forget everything
you'Őve said tonight.
Good night.
Hello, Oscar.
Lovely club you'Őve got here.
-I like that.
I'Őd like some
champagne tonight.
Oh, you shouldn'Őt
have bothered.
You must eat something.
All right?
You know, I'Őve eaten in all
of the best restaurants
in Europe
but I'Őve never tasted
anything like your
sweetbreads.
Where'Ős the wine?
They didn'Őt deliver
any this week.
For heaven'Ős sake, why not?
Perhaps the fact that we
owe the wine merchant Ł85
might have something
to do with it.
We'Őre living on credit,
Oscar, and that can'Őt
go on much longer.
Well, if I can
finish this play,
everything will be all right.
If that'Ős Bosie,
tell him I'Őm not at home.
QUEENSBERRY: I wish
to see Mr. Oscar Wilde.
ARTHUR: I'Őm sorry, sir,
but Mr. Wilde is not at home.
Well, I'Őm sorry,
but I demand to
see him.
You can'Őt go in there, sir.
If you please, sir.
Wilde, I want to have
a word with you. Sit down.
Well, Lord Queensberry.
It'Ős all right, Arthur,
you can go.
It seems
the peerage don'Őt have
a monopoly of good manners.
To hell with good manners, sir.
What I have to say
to you has very little
to do with good manners.
Indeed?
And I presume you'Őve
brought your ugly friend
to lend you moral support.
When it comes
to morals, I have
all the support I need,
thank you very much.
I'Őve seldom
come across anybody in whom
the moral sense was dominant
who was not heartless,
cruel, vindictive
and completely lacking
in the smallest
sense of humanity,
Lord Queensberry.
Personally,
I'Őd sooner have
50 unnatural vices
than one unnatural virtue.
Yes, I can
well believe that.
Now, you listen to me, sir.
I presume you have
come to make a speech.
If so,
I hope it'Ős a short one
because I have work to do.
Wilde.
I'Őve come here today
to protest against
your disgusting
relationship with my son.
That is a revolting
and slanderous statement,
and I demand an apology.
I refuse to apologize.
I refuse to apologize for
saying something which is
common knowledge
to every cab driver
and messenger boy
in London.
Lord Queensberry,
are you seriously
suggesting that
there is improper conduct
between your son and myself?
I do not say that you are.
I say
that you look it,
which is just as bad.
But I'Őll tell you this.
If I catch you
two again together,
I shall take a whip to you,
sir, and I shall thrash
you to the ground.
I see that when
it comes to fighting,
you choose to ignore
the Queensberry rules.
-Yes, well,
I give you fair warning.
-And I give you fair warning.
If you'Őre not out of
my house in two minutes,
I shall throw you out.
I refuse to leave
until I'Őve had my say.
On the contrary, sir,
you are leaving now.
Hit him! Hit him!
Arthur, open the door!
This gentleman is leaving.
Gladly, sir.
This, Arthur,
is the Marquis
of Queensberry.
The most infamous brute in
London and you'Őre never to
let him in my house again.
-Is that clear?
-Perfectly, sir.
Now get out.
Very well.
But you'Őll regret this,
I promise you.
Go back to your room
this instant.
Will that be all, sir?
I hope so, Arthur.
Now, this has got to stop.
You are the only one
who can stop it, Oscar.
My God, am I
not allowed to get on
with my work in peace?
What with creditors
knocking at the door
and Bosie dropping in
as if this was some
sort of club.
And now this coarse brute
with his hired pugilists.
I can stand brute force,
but brute reason is
quite intolerable.
It'Ős like hitting
below the intellect.
Oscar, I beg of you
to give up this friendship
with Bosie.
Not for me,
but for your own sake.
He takes up
too much of your time,
demands too much
of your emotions.
I know.
The truth is the boy has
a strange fascination
for me
that I can'Őt get free of.
He needs you more
than you need him.
He needs you
because he is
weak and conceited.
And you give him
a stature he could
never acquire alone.
And he will
go on taking and taking
until there'Ős nothing left.
He'Őll destroy you, Oscar.
When I married you,
I didn'Őt believe
it was possible to love
anybody more than I loved you.
I still love you, darling.
To me you are higher and
greater than any man in
the world.
Help me, Constance.
Help me.
Why not go away
for a little while?
At least until you
have finished your play.
Maybe it will
give you a chance
to think more clearly.
Yes, I may.
You always liked the sea.
Why not go down to Brighton?
It should be very quiet
at this time of year.
It'Ős a wonderful idea,
Constance,
but we'Őve hardly enough money
to pay the tradesmen,
let alone hotel bills.
I haven'Őt
touched my father'Ős
allowance for some months.
-It isn'Őt very much,
I'Őm afraid.
-No, no, Constance.
Please. Please.
I love you.
Goodness Lordy, Mr. Wilde,
wherever have you been?
I'Őve been conversing
with the elements,
Mrs. Burgess.
Oh, goodness me,
you'Őre soaked
to the skin.
Listening to the wisdom
of the sea, Mrs. B.
Out all night
in weather like this.
Now, you come upstairs
and we'Őll get those
wet clothes off
-before you catch your death.
-It'Ős all here.
Every word and every epigram,
Mrs. Burgess.
Oh, I'Őm very glad, Mr. Wilde,
but do come on.
Every move and every curtain.
It'Ős all here.
And the
important thing
is who is Ernest.
Oh, yes, that will be nice.
Ernest and his little aunt...
But upstairs now, like
a good boy, please,
Mr. Wilde.
You'Őre very kind, Mrs. Burgess.
Well, if we can'Őt show
a little kindness
on this earth,
we might
as well not be here,
that'Ős the way I see it.
Now, you keep nice and warm.
Are you sure this is
the right place,
my dear chap?
This is where
I brung him, sir.
No mistaking him.
Proper artistic
gentleman he was.
Just wait here, will you?
Right, sir.
Good morning, madam.
Is it remotely possible you
have a Mr. Oscar Wilde
staying here?
Why, yes, sir.
How extraordinary.
-Ah, may I step inside?
-Certainly, sir.
Which is his room?
It'Ős just at
the top of the stairs.
Oh, but I'Őd rather
you didn'Őt disturb him, sir.
You see, he was out
all night and he'Ős
not at all well.
Indeed?
I was wondering if
I'Őd send for the doctor.
A doctor, madam,
would probably
prescribe
a little less brandy
in his soda.
Well.
So this is
where you'Őve been
hiding yourself, hmm?
Bosie.
Really, Oscar, you are
the most tedious person.
I'Őve been all over Brighton.
From one hotel to another,
tracking you down like
some private detective.
-What do you want?
-What?
What do I want?
I don'Őt want a thing,
I came to see you.
Good heavens,
it'Ős so dark in here.
Well, I must say
you don'Őt look
any too good.
Oh, yeah.
I think I'Őve got a chill, I...
You must
be out of your mind
coming to a place like this.
I can'Őt imagine what
the food must be like.
Of course,
as soon as I knew
you were in Brighton,
I naturally went
straight to The Grand.
Naturally.
I have a most delightful
suite there overlooking
the sea.
And I shall get the bill,
no doubt, in due course.
Seriously though, Os,
I won'Őt allow you to stay
in this dreary little hovel
another minute.
Besides, the most fascinating
people are staying at
The Grand.
Just look
at this picture, really.
Bosie, can'Őt you understand
that I came here
to finish my play
in peace and quiet?
I was driven
nearly frantic in London
with you and your father.
Bosie, I'Őve got to work.
I'Őm the last
person in the world to want
to interfere with your work.
Whether you mean it or not,
you do.
What are you looking for?
I'Őm looking for
my handkerchief. What do
you think I'Őm looking for?
Here it is, for heaven'Ős sake.
Really, Oscar,
when you are ill,
you'Őre singularly unamusing.
I can'Őt help being ill.
But you can help being a bore.
Is this your new play?
"The Importance
of Being Earnest."
Yes, it'Ős nearly finished.
I'Őm glad to hear it.
Poverty ill becomes you.
Frankly, I think you'Őre being
very unreasonable about this
whole thing.
You disappear,
leaving me in town
without a penny piece.
Are you trying to end
this relationship, Oscar?
Is that what you want?
I don'Őt know what I want.
I just want to be left
in peace.
"Thank you for your company.
"It was charming while it
lasted. Now kindly get out."
Bosie, can'Őt you see that I'm
ill and I hardly know what
I'Őm doing?
And what about me?
I don'Őt care what you do,
but as long
as you go away
and leave me alone.
You mean for good?
It can'Őt go on,
your insane tantrums
and your extravagances.
It'Ős got to stop, Bosie.
Wouldn'Őt my father
be delighted to think
he'Őd finally broken up
our friendship?
My God, it is stuffy in here.
I don'Őt know
how you can breathe.
Once and for all, I'Őm sick
to death of being a cat'Ős-paw
in this terrible war
between you and
your father.
And for heaven'Ős sake,
close the window.
Am I to be held responsible
for the ravings of my
lunatic father?
I sometimes think there'Ős very
little difference between him
and you.
You'Őre both insane.
Bosie, the window.
My God, I'Őve had
just about had as much
as I can stand of this.
-Oh, my God.
-Is this the thanks I get
-for devoting myself to
you these past two years?
-My God!
What is happening to me?
How I ever came to think
you were so marvelous...
-Bosie, for God'Ős sake,
go away.
-Oscar Wilde, the great genius,
the great wit.
Idol of society. And look
at you sniveling like
some kicked dog.
Do you think I'Őm
going to let you end
this so easily, Oscar?
You'Őre not going
to throw me aside
because you'Őve
no further use for me.
You'Őre not my father!
Bosie, are you insane?
Didn'Őt you know?
It runs in the family.
Bosie, put it down.
Bosie, please!
How insignificant you look
when you'Őre afraid, Oscar.
I never thought
you'Őd be afraid of me.
Oh, this place depresses me.
Oh, um...
I don'Őt suppose you could let
me have some money to pay the
cab, could you? I...
Oh, well.
Wait for me, will you?
Yes, ma'Őam.
Good afternoon, madam.
Good afternoon, Arthur.
Is Mr. Wilde at home?
Yes, he'Ős working
at the moment, madam.
But Mrs. Wilde is
in the front room.
-Mrs. Leverson, madam.
-CONSTANCE: Ada!
My dear,
I hope you don'Őt mind
my just dropping in.
Of course not. Arthur,
may we have some tea,
please?
Certainly, madam.
How nice to see you.
Good heavens, you'Őre freezing.
Come and get warm by the fire.
I was just embroidering
my birthday present
for Oscar.
Do you think
he'Ős going to like it?
Oh, I'Őm sure he will,
it'Ős most handsome.
Oscar has
the most expensive tastes,
even in the simplest things.
How is Oscar?
Oh, much better.
He just needed
looking after properly.
What about Bosie?
That'Ős all over now, thank God.
I can'Őt tell you
what it was like, Ada.
To have
a woman come between
yourself and your husband,
that'Ős something
a wife can understand.
But another man.
OSCAR: Constance,
is that Ada'Ős voice I hear?
Yes, it is, dearest.
I must hide this, I don'Őt
want to spoil the surprise.
Ada, my dear.
You'Őre looking
wonderful, Oscar.
Mm, what a delicious hat!
Constance, where'Ős that bottle
of champagne I'Őve been
hoarding?
Oscar, you'Őre not going
to start drinking so early.
Of course I am.
This is a celebration.
You finished the play?
The curtain fell
on the third act of
The Importance
of Being Earnest
as the doorbell rang.
I'Őll get the champagne.
Ada, your timing is impeccable.
-Is it a good play?
-Quite extraordinary.
Ada, I'Őm happier than
I'Őve been for years.
I'Őm working.
I'Őm seeing more
of the children.
Constance is a guardian angel.
In fact, I believe
I'Őm getting dull and
bourgeois and very old.
You miss him, don'Őt you?
Yes.
Sometimes when I see the
sunlight on an evening sky
or wander by the river
and watch the dark waters,
I seem to see him
flitting by me in
the darkness,
and then I feel terribly alone.
Have you seen this?
Couldn'Őt find
the champagne glasses.
It'Ős been
such a long time
since we used them.
Oscar, what on earth is it?
Bosie'Ős elder brother
was killed yesterday
in a hunting accident.
Oh, how terrible.
That would be Francis,
wouldn'Őt it?
Bosie was very fond
of him, wasn'Őt he?
-Arthur.
-Sir?
I want you
to go to the post office
presently and send a telegram.
Very good, sir.
I think he may need me.
For as much as it has pleased
Almighty God
to take unto himself
the soul of our dear
brother departed,
we therefore commit
his body to the ground.
Well...
It would seem it takes
a death to bring about
a family reunion in this house.
You'Őre all very silent.
I'Őve just lost a son.
Doesn'Őt that mean
anything to any of you?
Hmm?
You'Őre his mother.
Don'Őt you weep
for your son?
The only real male son
you ever bore.
-Really, Father...
-The only real man
among the three of you!
Goodbye, Mother.
Goodbye, Bosie.
Bosie!
Where the devil do
you think you'Őre going?
I'Őve buried my brother.
There'Ős nothing
to keep me here any longer.
This is
your home, damn you!
You belong here!
You were born here!
Kinmount has been
the House of Douglas
for more than 300 years.
-Goodbye, Percy.
-Bosie!
Bosie.
Don'Őt go, boy. Stay here.
Just for a few days, eh?
It gets so lonely
here sometimes
and...
Well, just for a few days,
eh, Son?
You call me son?
I'Őm not your son.
You disowned me,
or had you forgotten?
You disowned me
just as you'Őve disowned
the whole family.
You drove Mother
out of this house
with your abuse
and your immorality.
You persecuted me until I
had to keep away from you
for fear of what
I might do if I were
here to lay hands on you.
I tried to make
a man out of you.
I tried to protect you
against yourself.
It'Ős no more than any other
self-respecting father
would do.
You lost your self respect
the day you threw my mother
out of this house
and brought your mistress
here to live with you.
-Damn your insolence!
-Please!
I ought to take a whip
and thrash you to the ground.
I would welcome
the opportunity,
believe me.
You talk to me
of the moral issue.
-For heaven'Ős sake,
-Father!
Well, what about him and
that damned Wilde fellow?
Thank God I succeeded
in putting an end to that.
One of these days
you'Őll get down on your knees
and you'Őll thank me for it.
He sent me a telegram
this morning.
At least he has more sympathy
with my bereavement than you
seem to have.
I'Őm going back to London
this afternoon,
and I warn you,
if ever
you try and interfere in
my private affairs again,
I'Őll buy myself a pistol
and I'Őll hunt you down
and kill you.
Bosie!
You'Őre no son of mine,
do you hear?
You'Őre not my son!
Go back to your
precious friend,
but, I warn you,
I haven'Őt finished
with you yet!
Or him!
I'Őll see you both behind bars!
Do you hear?
Behind bars!
I have a great deal to
make up to you for, Oscar.
I'Őve been perfectly
horrible to you
in the past.
No, don'Őt mention it anymore.
Sometimes it takes
a good row to clear the air.
What are we going to
do about your father?
Believe me, it'Ős
only because of you
that I haven'Őt taken some
sort of legal action
against him.
And involve your
whole family in
a scandal?
That wouldn'Őt
help anybody except
perhaps the journalists.
Just so long as he
leaves me alone,
that'Ős all.
Good heavens,
what are we talking
about my father for?
Your new play
opens on Saturday.
We should be drinking
to its success.
Its success?
My dear boy,
you don'Őt doubt it'll
be a success, do you?
To The Importance
of Being Earnest.
To the importance
of friendship.
-Wait there.
-Yes, sir.
Lord Queensberry, sir?
Yes.
I'Őm sorry, sir, I've strict
instructions not to let you
into the theater.
You must be out of your senses.
I'Őm sorry, sir.
Who the devil are you anyway?
I'Őm a police officer, sir.
Are you indeed?
Police officer, are you?
Are you?
Don'Őt forget the cripple, sir.
I'Őm sorry, sir.
No unauthorized persons
are permitted to enter
the theater.
Do you realize
who you'Őre talking to?
Oh, I do indeed, Your Lordship.
Now look here, My Lord,
why don'Őt you run along
and forget the whole thing?
You don'Őt want to
go in there and spoil
everybody'Ős enjoyment.
I'Őm not
completely
without influence.
I'Őm quite sure
you'Őre not, My Lord.
No, I shall
report you to your
senior officer, sir.
Bit loose
in the upper story,
wouldn'Őt you say, sir?
Hmm.
Well, let'Ős hope that's
the last we'Őve seen
of him tonight.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have enjoyed this
evening immensely.
The actors have given
a charming rendering
of a delightful play.
And your appreciation
has been most intelligent.
I congratulate
you on the success
of your performance,
which proves to me
that you think
almost as highly
of the play as I do.
-That'Ős quite a wit...
-Cab!
There'Ős Queensberry.
Queensberry? What'Ős he up to?
Mad as ever, I suppose.
Mad.
QUEENSBERRY:
Excuse me! Excuse me!
Mr. Wilde,
may I present
you with this, sir?
How charming.
Every time I smell them,
I shall think of you,
Lord Queensberry.
The Albemarle Club.
Hurry. Hurry!
Can I help you, sir?
Give me a pen.
Now, I want you
to give this message
to Mr. Oscar Wilde.
Very good, sir.
Here you are, Edward.
Thank you, Mr. Wilde, sir.
-Good morning, Wilde.
-Congratulations!
-Thank you.
-Cab!
Wilde, my dear fellow.
Saw your
play last night.
Laughed myself sick.
You seem to have made
a remarkable recovery, Major.
Oh, Mr. Wilde.
A gentleman left this
for you last night, sir.
-Oh.
-I hear your play
was a big success, sir.
Congratulations,
if I may say so.
Thank you, Sydney.
Hello, old chap.
Enjoyed your play...
Well, there'Ős no doubt,
Mr. Wilde,
on the basis
of what is written
on this card alone,
you have the strongest
possible grounds
for an action against
Lord Queensberry for
criminal libel.
Does that mean,
Sir Edward, that
you will take the case?
Well, the question is,
of course,
do you want to proceed
with this action?
Well, of course!
Why do you ask that,
Sir Edward?
Well, no doubt,
Queensberry'Ős defense
will be that the libelous
statement complained of
was justified
and in effect true.
It most certainly isn'Őt true.
Nevertheless, the defense
will make every effort to
prove that it is,
and that could be extremely
embarrassing for Mr. Wilde.
I agree. Oscar,
it simply isn'Őt worth it.
Queensberry'Ős
obviously a lunatic.
To take
an action against him
is exactly what he wants.
That'Ős why he left that card.
But if we let
him get away with this,
there'Őll be no holding him.
We have to
draw a line somewhere.
It'Ős a matter of principle.
I'Őm afraid Lord Alfred
is right.
The man must be
stopped somewhere.
Then you
wish to proceed
with this action?
I do.
Can'Őt wait to see
my father'Ős face when
I go into the witness box.
When I tell...
You'Őre not going into
the witness box, Bosie.
Are you mad, Oscar?
I'Őve only got
to tell them
how he'Ős...
How he'Ős
persecuted me
these past two years,
how he drove my
mother out of the house
with his insane ravings.
I'Őm not having
you involved, Bosie.
I'Őm afraid, Mr. Wilde,
that Lord Alfred is
already involved.
Well, of course I'Őm involved.
I'Őm not having
you exposed to more
scandal than is necessary.
Oscar, don'Őt you realize...
Bosie, you'Őre not going
into the witness box
and that is final.
You'Őll have
to forgive Bosie.
He'Ős a little impulsive.
So it would seem.
Anyway, you have a very
strong case, Mr. Wilde.
What'Ős the matter, Robbie?
Are you determined
to bring about your
own destruction, Oscar?
Is that what you'Őre
trying to do?
I don'Őt understand.
I used to think
you had a mind
of your own.
A great mind. Oh, really.
Oscar, you mustn'Őt
let Bosie push you
into this thing.
-What'Ős the alternative?
-Go abroad.
Let Queensberry
and his son fight
their quarrel without you.
They'Őre well-matched.
It'Ős too late, Robbie.
Well, Sir Edward,
I'Őm entirely at
your disposal.
Any further information
you need?
There is one question
I feel compelled to ask.
Please do.
I can only accept
this brief, Mr. Wilde,
if you assure
me on your honor as
an English gentleman
that there is no truth in
the charges made against you.
I assure you as
an Irish gentleman
that there'Ős no truth
whatever in any of them.
Well, then, shall we say
here tomorrow morning
at 10:30, Mr. Wilde?
Good. Mr. Humphries.
Paper! Queensberry arrested!
Paper! Paper! Special edition!
Queensberry arrested!
Paper! Paper, sir! Paper!
COURT USHER: Silence!
That'Ős Edward Carson,
defending Queensberry.
We went to
Trinity College together.
No doubt he'Őll perform
his task with all the added
bitterness of an old friend.
COURT USHER: Silence!
Be upstanding in court.
All persons who
have anything to do
before My Lords,
the Queen'Ős justices
of oyer and terminer
and general gaol delivery
for the jurisdiction of
the Central Criminal Court,
draw near and give
your attendance.
God save the Queen.
Put up
John Sholto Douglas,
Marquis of Queensberry.
Are you
John Sholto Douglas,
Marquis of Queensberry?
I am, sir.
"The jurors for
Our Lady, the Queen,
upon their oath present
"that John Sholto Douglas,
Marquis of Queensberry,
"contriving and maliciously
intending to injure one
"Oscar Fingal O'ŐFlahertie
Wills Wilde,
"and to excite him to
commit a breach of peace,
"and to bring him
into public contempt,
scandal and disgrace,
"did on the
14th day of February in
the year of our Lord 1895,
"and within the jurisdiction
of this court
"unlawfully, wickedly and
maliciously write and publish
"a false and scandalous,
"malicious and
defamatory libel,
in the form of a card,
"directed to the said Oscar
Fingal O'ŐFlahertie
Wills Wilde,
"on which were
written the words,
"'ŐTo Oscar Wilde,
posing as a sodomite.'Ő"
COURT USHER: Silence in court.
"To the great damage,
scandal and disgrace
"of the said Oscar Fingal
O'ŐFlahertie Wills Wilde
"and against the peace of
our said Lady the Queen,
her crown and dignity,
"John Sholto Douglas,
Marquis of Queensberry,
"upon the
aforesaid indictment,
how do you plead?"
Guilty or not guilty?
Not guilty, My Lord.
If it please you, My Lord,
it is my client'Ős plea
that the alleged libel
according to the natural
meaning of the words thereof
is true in substance
and in fact,
and that it was for the
public benefit and interest
that the matter contained in
the alleged libel should
be published.
Such a plea has been
filed with this court?
It has, My Lord.
Thank you, Mr. Carson.
Let the jury be sworn.
Take the Bible
in your right hand
and read from the card.
"I swear by Almighty God
that I will well and truly..."
I put the card in an envelope,
which I addressed
to Mr. Oscar Wilde
and when Mr. Wilde
came into the club,
I handed it to him saying that
Lord Queensberry had asked
me to give it to him.
And did you look at this card
when Lord Queensberry
gave it to you?
I did, sir.
Thank you, Mr. Wright.
I have no questions, My Lord.
COURT USHER:
The witness may stand down.
I don'Őt think there's
any suggestion by the defense
that Lord Queensberry did
not leave this card at
the Albemarle Club,
nor that he wrote upon it
the words complained of
by my client.
In his plea of justification
in which the defendant seeks
to malign the character
of Mr. Oscar Wilde,
the defendant put
in evidence a letter
written by
Mr. Oscar Wilde to
Lord Alfred Douglas,
the son of the accused.
I now propose
to read the letter
to the court, My Lord.
"My own boy, your
sonnet is quite lovely,
"and it is a marvel that
those red rose leaf lips
of yours
"should have been made
no less for music of song
than for madness of kisses.
"Your slim guilt soul walks
between passion and poetry.
"I know Hyacinthus,
whom Apollo loved
so madly,
"was you in Greek days.
"Always with undying love,
yours, Oscar."
The words contained in that
letter may appear somewhat
extravagant
for those normally
engaged in the writing of
commercial correspondence.
Silence!
But Mr. Wilde is a poet
and that letter
is considered by him
to be a prose sonnet,
and one in which
he is no way ashamed.
I now ask
Mr. Oscar Wilde to
go into the witness box.
Take the Bible
in your right hand
and read from the card.
"I swear by Almighty God
that the evidence I give
to this court
"shall be the
truth, the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth,
"so help me God."
You are Mr. Oscar Wilde and
you are the prosecutor in
this case.
I am.
How old are you, Mr. Wilde?
I'Őm 39.
Are you married, Mr. Wilde?
I am, and I have two children,
one aged nine and the other
eight.
And when did you
first become acquainted
with Lord Alfred Douglas?
In 1891.
A friend
brought him to my house.
And since that time you
have become close friends?
He was a guest at
my house many times.
A guest of yourself
and your wife?
Certainly.
In March 1893,
did it come to your notice
that a letter addressed by
you to Lord Alfred Douglas
had come
into the hands of
a certain person?
Yes, a man named Wood
came to me
and said that he'Őd found it in
a suit of clothes belonging to
Lord Alfred.
Did he
demand money
for that letter?
He said a man had
offered him Ł60
for it.
And what did you say to that?
I said
I'Őd never received
so large an amount
for a prose work
of that length,
and I advised him to
sell it to the man
at once.
Prior to this time,
you had been subjected
to considerable annoyance
by Lord Queensberry,
had you not?
Oh, yes.
He'Őd written several
abusive letters to myself
and my friends
and on one occasion,
he forced his way
into my house
and I was compelled
to eject him.
And what
took place on
that occasion?
He made certain accusations
about my relationship
with Lord Alfred
and I said to him,
"Lord Queensberry, do you
seriously accuse your son
and me of improper conduct?"
And what did he say to that?
He said,
"I don'Őt say you are,
but I say you look it."
Silence in court!
If there
is the slightest
disturbance again,
I shall have the court cleared.
Mr. Wilde,
your attention has been
drawn to certain statements
made in the plea
of justification
filed by
the defendant,
Lord Queensberry,
with reference to different
persons impugning your
conduct with them.
Yes.
Mr. Wilde,
is there any
truth whatever in any
of those accusations?
None whatever in any of them.
Thank you, Mr. Wilde.
Mr. Wilde,
you stated earlier
that your age was 39.
-Is that correct?
-Yes.
You were born in 1854.
That makes you over
40, doesn'Őt it?
Oh, very well.
Hmm.
At what age was
Lord Alfred Douglas
when you first met him?
He was between 20 and 21.
Not yet 21. Hmm.
And since that time you
have been close friends?
Yes.
You'Őve stayed with
him at many places?
Yes.
At Oxford, Brighton,
on several occasions?
Yes.
And at various
hotels in London?
Yes.
You'Őve also been abroad
with him several times.
Yes, to Egypt,
Paris and Monte Carlo.
One could
therefore describe
your friendship as intimate?
Yes, very.
Indeed.
I have
here a magazine
called The Chameleon,
in which is
an article by yourself.
Also, two
poems contributed
by Lord Alfred Douglas.
Yes, I thought them
exceedingly beautiful.
Did you?
Do you remember
the titles of these
two poems, Mr. Wilde?
Yes. One was called
In Praise of Shame,
and the other, Two Loves.
Thank you.
These two loves,
they were two boys,
weren'Őt they?
Yes.
One boy calls his love
true love and the other
boy calls his love shame.
That is correct.
Do you think that made
any improper suggestion?
No, not at all.
Hmm.
There'Ős another article
in this magazine
entitled The Priest
and the Acolyte.
Have you read that?
I have.
Did you consider
that this article
was in any way immoral?
It was worse.
It was very badly written.
Was it not the
story of a priest who fell
in love with an altar boy?
Well, I read it only once
and nothing would induce
me to read it again.
Do you think the
story blasphemous?
I think
it violates every
artistic canon of beauty.
That is not an answer.
That'Ős the only answer
I can give.
I wish to know
whether you thought
the story blasphemous?
It disgusted me,
and the end was
completely wrong.
Will you answer the question?
Did you or did you not
consider the story
blasphemous?
I thought it was horrid.
Blasphemous is not
a word of mine.
I see.
Now, from the same
magazine here
are some of the phrases and
philosophies for the use
of the young
which you contributed.
"Wickedness is a myth
invented by good people
"to account
for the curious
attractiveness of others."
Do you think that true?
I rarely think anything
I write is true.
"Religions die hard when
they are proved to be true."
Is that true?
Yes, I hold to that,
but it'Ős too big
a question to go
into here.
Did you think
that was a safe axiom
to put forward for the
philosophy of the young?
I think it'Ős most stimulating.
"If one tells the truth, one
is sure sooner or later to
be found out."
A pleasing paradox, but I do
not set very much store
on it as an axiom.
Whether moral or immoral?
There is no morality
or immorality in thought.
There are immoral emotions.
Quite so.
Now then.
This is the
introduction to your book,
The Picture of Dorian Gray.
"There is no such thing
as a moral or immoral book.
"Books are
well written
or badly written."
That expresses your view?
My view on art, yes.
Then no matter how
immoral a book may be,
if it is well written,
it is in your opinion
a good book.
If it is well written so as
to produce a sense of beauty.
Then a well written book
putting forward perverted
moral views may be
a good book?
A work
of art doesn'Őt
put forward views.
Views are for people.
A perverted novel
might be a good book?
I don'Őt know
what you mean by
a perverted novel.
Then, I will suggest
The Picture of Dorian Gray
as being open
to the interpretation
of being such a book.
Only to brutes and illiterates.
The affection
and love of the artist
for the youth, Dorian Gray,
might lead
an ordinary individual
to believe
that it might have
a certain tendency.
I have no knowledge
of the views of
ordinary individuals.
Hmm.
I propose, if I may, to quote
a few passages from this book.
The artist Hallward is
speaking to Dorian Gray.
"It is quite true
that I have worshiped you
"with far more romance than
a man usually gives to
a friend.
"I have never loved a woman.
"From the moment I met you,
"your personality had
the most extraordinary
influence over me.
"I quite admit I adored you
madly, extravagantly,
absurdly."
Do you mean to
say that that passage
describes the natural
feeling of one man
towards another?
Dorian Gray'Ős was
a remarkable personality.
May I take it that you as
an artist have never known
the feeling described here?
No. It is a work of fiction.
Let us go over it
phrase by phrase.
"I quite admit that I
have adored you madly."
What do you say to that?
Have you ever adored
a young man madly?
I'Őve never given
adoration to anyone.
Except myself.
I suppose you think
that a very smart thing?
Not at all.
"I have adored
you extravagantly."
Do you mean financially?
Oh, yes, financially!
Do you think that we
are talking about finance?
I don'Őt know what
you'Őre talking about.
Don'Őt you?
Then I hope that I shall
make myself very plain
before I have done.
And we come now
to the letter which you
wrote to Lord Alfred Douglas.
It begins, "My own boy."
Now, why should
a man of your age
address a young boy
nearly 20
years younger
as "My own boy"?
I was fond of him.
I'Őve always been
fond of him.
Did you adore him?
No, I like him.
And that'Ős not
an ordinary letter.
You might as well
cross examine me
as to whether a Shakespeare
sonnet was improper.
Suppose a man
who was not an artist
had written this letter.
Would you say that
this was a proper letter?
A man who was not an artist
wouldn'Őt have written
that letter.
Well, I can suggest, for
the sake of your reputation,
that there'Ős nothing
very wonderful in this.
"Those red rose
leaf lips of yours..."
It largely depends on
how it'Ős read.
"Your slim guilt soul walks
between passion and poetry."
Is that
a beautiful
phrase, Mr. Wilde?
Not as you
read it, Mr. Carson.
You read it very badly.
I do not profess
to be an artist,
Mr. Wilde.
And when I hear
you give evidence,
I'Őm very glad that I am not.
My Lord, I don'Őt think my
learned friend should
talk like that.
May I suggest, Mr. Carson,
that you do not air your
personal opinions in
this court?
It is very difficult, My Lord.
JUDGE: Yet nevertheless.
Where did you first meet
the man Wood, Mr. Wilde?
He came to my house.
I think it was in
January of 1893.
And on the same evening,
you took him out to supper?
Yes.
Did you consider that
he'Őd come to levy blackmail?
I did, and I was
determined to face it.
By taking
him out to supper
and giving him Ł40?
Well, I saw that
the letter was
of no value,
and I gave him
the money after he
told me a pitiful tale
about being out of work.
I suggest that you
had immoral relations
with him first and
then gave him the money.
My Lord, I really must protest
at my learned friend'Ős
method of questioning
the witness.
I do not see
that Mr. Carson is
in any way out of order.
Thank you, My Lord.
Do you know a man named
Charles Parker, Mr. Wilde?
The witness will
answer the question.
Yes, he was a friend
of Lord Alfred'Ős.
And a man named Atkin?
Yes, he was a friend
of Parker'Ős.
A man named Grainger?
Yes, he was
a manservant
of Lord Alfred'Ős.
And Taylor, Mr. Wilde.
Do you know anyone
called Taylor?
Yes, I have been to parties
at his house. We...
Were all these, with
the exception of Taylor,
young men of about 20?
I like the society
of young men.
Have you given money
to any of them?
I may have.
Or presents?
A silver cigarette case
for Mr. Taylor,
gold-topped walking
stick for Mr. Parker,
a book for
Mr. Wood inscribed,
"To Alfred from Oscar."
Did you know, Mr. Wilde,
that Wood had been
unemployed for three years,
that Parker was a valet,
and that the man Taylor
was also out of work?
That would
not have affected my
friendship with them.
And yet you gave them presents
and entertained them to supper
on diverse occasions.
No doubt you drank
wine and champagne.
Iced champagne is
a favorite drink
of mine,
much against
my doctor'Ős orders.
Never mind
your doctor'Ős orders.
I never do.
And at these supper parties
your guests no doubt
had plenty of champagne.
I didn'Őt press them to drink.
You did not stint them?
What gentleman
would stint his guests?
What gentleman would stint
his valet and a groom,
Mr. Wilde?
My Lord, I really must protest
at my learned friend'Ős
sneering remarks.
Mr. Carson, I suggest
you confine yourself to
questions, not opinions.
Very well, My Lord.
Did you know, Mr. Wilde,
that Taylor, Atkin and Parker
had been arrested in a raid
on a house in Fitzroy Square?
Yes, I read about that.
You know
that they were charged
with felonious practices?
I understand
that the magistrate
dismissed the charge.
About the young man Grainger.
Have you ever dined with him?
No, never.
But you know him?
Yes, he was a manservant
at Lord Alfred'Ős house
in Oxford.
So you saw him on
several occasions?
I stayed in the house
on several occasions.
Grainger waited at table.
Did you ever kiss him,
Mr. Wilde?
Oh, dear, no.
He was extremely ugly.
Is that the reason
you did not kiss him?
Mr. Carson,
you are very insolent.
Did you say that
you never kissed him?
It'Ős a foolish question.
Then why, sir,
did you mention that
this boy was extremely ugly?
I don'Őt know
why I mentioned
that he was ugly
except that
you stunned me with
your insolent remark
and the insulting way
you'Őve treated me
during this hearing.
Why did you mention
his ugliness?
It was simply that I...
Why? Why? Why?
"I didn'Őt
kiss Grainger
because he was ugly."
Quite untrue...
I protest, My Lord,
at his accusations.
My learned friend
puts words into
the witness'Ő mouth.
The witness
is putting words
into his own mouth.
-I object.
-I will not have this
brawling between counsels.
If I may say so, My Lord,
my learned friend has no right
to make suggestions of
a certain behavior
with a group of persons
not represented in
this court
and whose evidence
we have not heard.
But you will hear it,
Sir Edward.
It is my intention
to produce every one of
the persons mentioned here
just now in
this courtroom
tomorrow morning.
Wood, Parker, Atkin,
Grainger and Taylor
will relate
their loathsome experiences
at the hands of the witness.
By your own admission,
a group of blackmailers
and police suspects, sir.
Nevertheless,
they'Őll be here
to give their testimony,
testimony that will prove my
client'Ős plea of justification
beyond any possible shadow
of a doubt.
Silence in court.
I think this would be
an appropriate moment
to adjourn.
The witness may stand down.
The court
will reconvene at
10:00 a.m. tomorrow.
Be upstanding in court.
All persons who have
anything further to do
before My Lords,
the Queen'Ős justices
of oyer and terminer...
Before this unfortunate
trial started,
you gave me your word that
there was no truth whatever
in any of these
dreadful accusations.
I know, Sir Edward. It was
unforgivably stupid of me,
but I was afraid you
wouldn'Őt take the case.
As it is,
you realize you'Őve
already lost this case.
But what is
infinitely more serious
is that when Carson
puts these young men
into the witness box,
as he obviously intends to do,
their evidence
will inevitably result
in your being arrested
on some extremely
grave charges.
Sir Edward,
may I just say one thing?
Please do.
The whole case started with my
father accusing Mr. Wilde
of carrying on an...
An immoral relationship
with me, isn'Őt that so?
Yes.
Then why in heaven'Ős name
can I not go into the
witness box
-and deny this
disgusting accusation?
-Bosie, for the last time.
-But it isn'Őt true, Oscar.
-You know it isn'Őt.
Such a denial
would undoubtedly add
considerable weight, Mr. Wilde.
In my opinion, not to
put Lord Alfred into the
box would be a grave mistake.
One that
you might regret for
the rest of your life.
Gentlemen, I have infinite
faith in the good sense
of the common man,
and if,
as you say,
this case hangs
on the evidence
of paid informers
and criminals
like Wood and Parker,
I cannot conceive
that a British jury would
take their word before mine.
I wish I could
share your faith.
Well, what must be must be.
But I want
you to understand
that Lord Alfred is not
to give evidence at this trial.
Very well.
Well, I shall endeavor to
salvage what is left of
your reputation
by withdrawing
from the case first thing
in the morning.
Incidentally, there'Ős no need
for you to be present in
court tomorrow.
Indeed there'Ős
no need for you to
be present in this country.
There is a boat train leaving
for Calais at 10:00 tonight,
Mr. Wilde.
You'Őd be well advised
to be on it.
Before you condemn
Lord Queensberry,
I ask you to
consider whether the
gorge of any father ought
not to rise in
such circumstances.
I ask you to
bear in mind that
Lord Queensberry'Ős son
was so dominated by Wilde
that he threatened to
shoot his own father.
I now have
a more painful part
of the case to approach.
It'Ős my unhappy duty
to bring before you
young men...
-Did Wilde get away?
-No.
...to tell their
miserable tales.
I first call Charles Parker.
May I claim Your Lordship'Ős
indulgence while I interpose
to make a statement,
which is, of course,
made under a feeling
of great responsibility?
By all means, Sir Edward.
Forgive me, Mr. Carson.
I'Őm sure it must be
apparent to Your Lordship
that those
who represent
Mr. Wilde in this case
have before them
a terrible anxiety.
A verdict given in favor of
the defendant Lord Queensberry
might be interpreted
as conclusive proof as to
the accusations of impropriety
brought against the plaintiff,
Mr. Oscar Wilde
and thus, we would be
going through,
day after day,
an investigation of matters
of the most appalling nature.
Under these circumstances,
I feel I am
not going beyond
the bounds of my duty
if I now interpose
and say on behalf
of Mr. Wilde
that I would ask to
withdraw from the prosecution.
If that is your wish,
Sir Edward, so be it.
COURT USHER: Silence.
And if I may say so
in the circumstances,
I think you have
made a wise decision.
Are you taking a cab?
Yes, come on.
Get this
to the office
as soon as you can.
"Oscar Wilde
withdraws from case."
-Take a cab and hurry.
-Yes, sir.
Either the words
complained of were
justified or they were not.
If they were,
then the statement,
"posing as a sodomite"
is true
and the publication
was for the public benefit.
You will now consider
your verdict.
We'Őve already agreed
upon a verdict, My Lord.
The prisoner will rise.
Gentlemen of the jury,
do you find
the plea
of justification
has been proved or not?
We do.
And do you
find the defendant
guilty or not guilty?
Not guilty, My Lord.
Silence in court!
Silence! Silence!
Usher, silence the court.
Usher!
Well, they haven'Őt
wasted any time.
Why, what do you mean?
A copy
of the evidence
has already been sent
to the Director of
Public Prosecutions.
Bosie, for God'Ős sake,
stop walking up and down.
Oh.
Oh, you haven'Őt
eaten a thing, sir.
I don'Őt really want it.
Thank you, Arthur.
Oscar, I'Őve just heard
from one of the reporters.
There'Ős a warrant
out for your arrest.
What about Constance
and the children?
I saw them off
on the train myself.
Thank you, Robbie.
Oscar, I beg of you.
There'Ős still time to
catch the 10:00 train.
I have a cab waiting outside.
You'Őre wasting
your time, Robbie.
I'Őve been trying
for the past two hours.
Oscar, will you
please listen to me?
-It'Ős too late.-It'Ős not too late, I tell you.
-Look, it'Ős 9:35.
-Oh, Robbie, have a drink.
In three hours
we can be in France.
You look as if you need it.
-Mr. Wilde?
-Yes.
We'Őre police officers.
We hold a warrant
for your arrest.
Really?
I must ask
you to accompany us
to the police station.
Bosie, do something for me.
Anything.
Leave the country.
If possible, tonight.
-I can'Őt desert you.
-Bosie, please.
Very well.
So it'Ős goodbye, hmm?
-Oscar, I can'Őt believe...
-Goodbye.
We'Őll come with you.
-There'Őll be no need
for that, sir.
-Thank you.
Why do you look
at me like that?
It'Ős not my fault.
I loved him just as much
as you did.
Don'Őt you think if there
was anything I could have...
You can do as
Oscar says, Bosie.
Leave the country.
And the sooner the better,
I should say.
"Lord Queensberry
is triumphant.
"Mr. Oscar Wilde is
damned and done forever."
And about time.
-"Public morality
will be vindicated."
-Hear, hear.
"And this evil in our midst
will, I hope, be removed
forever."
Damn good thing, too.
I never liked
the fellow from the first.
Couldn'Őt stand his plays.
Lot of immoral rubbish.
Damn it all, Bentley,
the fellow
hasn'Őt been tried yet.
Innocent until proved
guilty and all that
sort of...
If he'Őd been in
my regiment, sir,
he'Őd have been lashed to
a gun carriage and flogged.
These artistic chaps
are all the same.
A lot of long-haired
degenerates.
I think you fellows are
taking the whole damn
thing too seriously.
Live and let live,
that'Ős what I say.
Anyway, I don'Őt care
what they do
as long as they don'Őt do it
in the street and frighten
the horses.
All right.
Do you want me to
burn them, Mr. Brace?
Good heavens, no.
Fellow might get off.
Mr. Humphries.
Sir Edward.
I... They didn'Őt
tell me that it was you.
Mr. Wilde.
I don'Őt know what
arrangements you'Őve
made about your defense,
but if you wish it,
Sir Edward and I
would be most happy
to act on your behalf.
Thank you, I'Őm...
I'Őm very grateful.
There are certain legal
aspects of this case,
Mr. Wilde,
that have shocked me greatly.
The prosecution
has based its entire case
on the evidence of witnesses
who admitted crimes ranging
from assault, petty larceny
to blackmail.
Yet the Crown has
no intention of prosecuting
any of these witnesses.
They are to go scot-free.
Such a state
of affairs has
profoundly shaken
my inherent faith
in British justice.
In these circumstances,
I would consider it an honor,
if you'Őll permit me
to offer my services.
Thank you.
I'Őm afraid the cost
of the other case
is still unpaid,
and I'Őm in considerable debt.
Mr. Wilde,
Sir Edward and I are
agreed that there is
no question of a fee.
Thank you.
Well, there are many matters
we should discuss, Mr. Wilde.
CLERK: Put up Oscar
Fingal O'ŐFlahertie
Wills Wilde.
Oscar Fingal O'ŐFlahertie
COURT USHER:
Silence in court. Silence!
JUDGE: Order. Order.
CLERK:
Are you Oscar Fingal
O'ŐFlahertie Wills Wilde?
I am.
Oscar Fingal O'ŐFlahertie
Wills Wilde,
you stand charged on 25 counts.
On the first count,
the jurors for Our Lady,
the Queen, upon their oath
present that Oscar Fingal
O'ŐFlahertie Wills Wilde,
on 14th day of March in
the year of Our Lord 1893,
in the County of London
and within the jurisdiction
of this court,
being a male person,
unlawfully did commit
acts of gross indecency
with another male person,
one Alfred Wood.
And against the form of the
statuette in such case
made and provided,
and against the peace
of Our Lady the Queen,
her crown and dignity.
On the second count,
the juries aforesaid...
...against the form of the
statute in such case
made and provided
and against the peace of
our said Lady the Queen,
her crown and dignity.
Oscar Fingal O'ŐFlahertie
Wills Wilde,
on the aforesaid indictments,
how do you plead?
Guilty or not guilty?
Not guilty.
My Lord, gentlemen of the jury,
the first nine counts
in the indictment refer
to the prisoner'Ős misconduct
with a young man
named Alfred Wood.
The next three
to Frederick Atkin.
Two to the man Taylor.
Three to Charles Parker.
And the last
to Wilde'Ős conduct
with a lad named Shelley.
It will
be shown that Wilde
systematically endeavored
to influence these young
men'Ős minds towards
vicious causes.
And to mold them to
his own depraved will.
Gentlemen of the jury,
when you have heard the
evidence of these men,
I assure you that
you will be justified
in finding the prisoner
guilty on all counts.
I call first Alfred Wood.
COURT USHER: Call Alfred Wood.
Alfred Wood.
Take the Bible
in your right hand
and read from the card.
"I swear by Almighty God
that the evidence I give
to this court
"shall be the truth,
the whole truth and
nothing but the truth,
"so help me, God."
In all my years at the bar,
I cannot remember coming
face to face
with such a miserable
collection of witnesses.
Wood, Parker, Atkin.
The prosecution
must have scraped
the bottom of the barrel
to get that lot together.
What I cannot understand
is how a man of Wilde'Ős
taste and breeding
can come to associate
with such people.
Well, to understand that,
Charles,
you'Őd have to understand the
nature of Wilde'Ős perversion.
And I'Őm a lawyer, not a doctor.
To me, it'Ős loathsome,
degenerate and unnatural.
Yet I feel so sorry for him.
It is a terrible thing,
Charles, when a man of
Wilde'Ős talents and genius
is slowly crucified by
a lot of blackmailers
and common criminals.
There'Ős very little hope
for an acquittal, is there?
Well, the case
has already been judged
by the press and the public.
As far as
they'Őre concerned,
Wilde is guilty.
It only remains for him
to be sentenced.
The most we can hope for is
that, out of this hysteria
of prejudice and hatred,
there might shine
a glimmer of Christian
charity and forgiveness.
Do I understand
you to say then,
Mr. Wilde,
that there is no
truth whatsoever in the
evidence of Alfred Wood?
It'Ős true
that we had
supper together,
but the accusations of
impropriety are quite untrue.
Charles Parker,
what part of his
evidence is untrue?
He never came
to the hotel with me.
He never had dinner with me
and he never came to my room.
We had tea
at the St. James'Ős once,
but all of the rest...
Is untrue.
Then, Atkin.
What of his evidence?
My Lord,
my learned friend
seems to have forgotten
that the witness Atkin
perjured himself in
the box.
Your Lordship dismissed
this witness for that reason.
The witness'Ős evidence was
not struck from the record,
Sir Edward.
In my humble submission,
My Lord, it should have been.
That is for me to decide.
As Your Lordship pleases.
What of Atkins'Ő
evidence, Mr. Wilde?
The accusations of indecency
are quite untrue.
In fact,
these witnesses,
according to you,
have lied throughout the trial.
With remarkable ease.
As an experienced
writer and storyteller,
I'Őm lost in admiration
of their inventiveness.
You seem also to have been
lost in admiration for
their youth, sir.
I'Őm a lover of youth.
Yes, we have gathered that.
Now, let us turn to this
publication, The Chameleon.
My Lord,
are we to be subjected
to a further discourse
on the
literary morals
of the defendant?
I understood from
my learned friend that
he'Ős going to confine himself
to the specific charges
made in the indictment.
This is
cross examination
as to credit, My Lord.
I feel obliged to say that
questions which learned
counsel thinks
should go to credit,
he is entitled to put.
I shall not keep you long,
Mr. Wilde.
I trust not, Mr. Gill.
In this magazine, to
which you made a contribution,
there appears a poem
by Lord Alfred Douglas
entitled Two Loves.
It contains these lines.
"Sweet youth,
"tell me why, sad and sighing,
"does thou rove
these pleasant realms?
"I pray,
tell me sooth.
What is thy name?
"He said, 'ŐMy name is Love.'
"Then straight
the first did
turn himself to me
"and cried, 'ŐHe lieth,
for his name is Shame.
"'ŐBut I am Love, and I was to
be alone in this fair garden,
"'Őtill he came
unasked by night.
"'ŐI am true Love.
"'ŐI fill the hearts of boy
and girl with mutual flame.'Ő
"Then, sighing, said the other,
"'ŐHave thy will,
"'ŐI am the love that
dare not speak its name.'Ő"
And what, Mr. Wilde,
is the love that dare
not speak its name?
The love
that dare not speak
its name, in this century,
is such a great affection
of an elder for a younger man.
As there was between
David and Jonathan.
Such as Plato made
the very basis of philosophy
and such as you will find in
the sonnets of Michelangelo
and Shakespeare.
It is a deep,
spiritual affection
that is as perfect
as it is pure.
It is in this
century misunderstood,
so much misunderstood
that it may
be called the love that
dare not speak its name.
And on account of it,
I'Őm placed where I
am today.
But it is beautiful,
it is fine,
it is the noblest
form of affection.
There is nothing
unnatural about it.
It is intellectual.
And is repeatedly to be
found between an elder
and a younger man
when the elder man has
intellect and the younger
man has all the hope and joy
and glamour of life before him.
But it is so the world
does not understand.
The world mocks at it.
And sometimes puts
one in the pillory
for it.
COURT USHER: Silence in court.
Rubbish!
Silence in court!
Sit down, sir!
If there is the
slightest manifestation
of feeling like this again,
I shall have the court cleared.
I have no further
questions, My Lord.
JUDGE:
The witness
may stand down.
That concludes the case
for the prosecution,
My Lord.
May it
please you, My Lord,
gentlemen of the jury,
this is a serious
and grave question
for you to decide.
And yours is a position
of great responsibility.
Now, a great deal of
public feeling has been
excited against Mr. Wilde
by the
quotation of passages
of poetry and literature
and in particular
from Mr. Wilde'Ős book,
The Picture of Dorian Gray.
Now I ask you,
members of the jury,
is an author to be judged on
the morals of the characters
of his book?
Was Stevenson accused of
being a lustful and
depraved monster
because he wrote
Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde?
As to the affection which
Mr. Wilde expressed in
his letters,
he himself
has described it as
pure, true affection,
absolutely unconnected with
and completely alien to the
filthy practices
described in this court
by the prosecution'Ős
band of criminals.
Mr. Wilde is not
an ordinary man.
He is a man
who has written
poetry and prose,
brilliant dramas,
charming essays.
He writes letters in
a tone which to most
of us may appear
high-flown, inflated,
exaggerated, even absurd.
But he'Ős not ashamed
or afraid to produce
those letters.
When a man comes forward
with letters such as
these and says,
"I do not shrink
from the judgment of the
world upon these productions,"
has he not given the
best proof of his innocence?
Innocence,
gentlemen of the jury,
has courage and faith
in the ultimate
judgment of mankind.
As to the evidence
of the youths,
Parker, Atkin, Wood
and their associates,
I respectfully submit that
no jury can find a man guilty
on their tainted evidence.
It deepens
one'Ős horror to think
the prisoner'Ős freedom
is at the peril
of such persons.
Before you consider
this case, therefore,
I implore you to
let your judgment only be
affected by those witnesses
of whom you,
as true and honorable men
can say, with a clear
conscience have given
true, honest and
honorable testimony.
And if, upon the examination
of the evidence, you find
it your duty to say
that the charges
against the prisoner
have not been proved,
I know you'Őll be glad
that that bright reputation,
so nearly quenched
in a torrent of prejudice,
will have been saved by
your verdict from
absolute ruin.
And that
it will leave Mr. Wilde,a distinguished man of letters,
to live a life
of honor and repute
and to give, in the
maturity of his genius,
gifts to our literature
of which, already,
he has shown such
brilliant promise.
COURT USHER: Be
upstanding in court.
Gentlemen of the jury,
I understand that you are
unable to arrive at a verdict.
That is so, My Lord.
Is there any prospect
that if you retired
and continued your
deliberations a little longer,
you'Őll be able to
come to some agreement?
We have considered
the question
for three hours, My Lord.
And the only
result we have come to
is that we cannot agree.
Yes, I have no doubt
that you have tried
very hard
to come
to some agreement,
but on the other hand,
the inconveniences
of another trial
are very great.
My Lord, I fear there is
no chance of an agreement.
JUDGE:
Then, gentlemen,
you are discharged.
FOREMAN: Thank you, My Lord.
My Lord, on the
question of bail,
it may be some weeks
before a retrial...
Retrial!
Retrial! Retrial! Retrial!
Hello, Robbie.
Mr. Wilde, we managed
to raise bail.
Come on, Oscar.
Let me take you home.
Who put up the money
for my bail?
Bosie'Ős brother Percy
put up most of the money.
Percy? How kind.
The rest was put up
by the Reverend Headlam.
Ł5,000 in all.
It'Ős preposterous.
A common felon would not
be so heavily penalized.
The Reverend Headlam? Mmm-hmm.
Extraordinary!
I hardly know him.
-Oscar, let'Ős go to a hotel.
-No!
ARTHUR: Mr. Wilde!
Mr. Wilde.
Oh, sir, I'Őve done
everything I could.
Your manuscripts.
I'Őve managed to save
some of them,
but they'Őve been going
through the house like
vultures, sir.
AUCTIONEER: Ł20! 25!
Ł25 I'Őm bid for this priceless
first edition by Walt Whitman,
whoever he may be.
Now, now, come along,
gentlemen. Do I hear Ł30?
Ł30, 30. Ł35.
Ł35, 35. Come along,
we haven'Őt got all night.
Going then at Ł30.
Going once, twice,
three times.
Charles, the gent
over there with the cigar.
Now then.
Hello, hello, hello.
What have we got here?
A painting of
the dear boy himself.
Very pretty, I'Őm sure.
Very pretty.
Now what am I bid
for this masterpiece?
Do I hear 10 shillings?
MAN: Ten shillings.
AUCTIONEER: Ten
shillings I'Őm bid.
Do I hear a pound?
-Ł1.
-Ł1!
Ł1, 1.
Excuse me,
ladies and gentlemen,
I think we have company.
Perhaps His Eminence will
bid for this artistic
painting.
What about 30 bob, sir?
Come on, Oscar.
Haven'Őt you seen enough?
-No?
Well, all right, then.
Going at a pound.
Going, going...
40 guineas!
-AUCTIONEER: 40 guineas.
Well, then.
Any advance
on 40 guineas?
All right. Sold to
His Lordship for
40 guineas.
Charlie, give the
gentleman his painting.
-40 guineas.
-Thank you, My Lord.
-Thank you.
-What are you going to do
with it now you'Őve bought it?
Hang it in the bathroom!
Aw, blimey, governor.
What a waste of 40 quid.
MAN:
I say, a little
bit rash, what?
I feel like a drink.
Excuse me, please.
Excuse me. Thank you.
Excuse me, madam.
Excuse me.
Come on, Oscar.
AUCTIONEER: Well,
we weren'Őt very
quick there.
We should have
asked His Eminence to
autograph a few books, eh?
Now then,
an original manuscript
of that uproarious comedy,
The Importance
of Being Earnestby
the late Oscar Wilde.
-Now, then, do I hear Ł10?
Mr. Wilde.
I'Őm most dreadfully
sorry about this, sir,
but I'Őm afraid
we must ask you to leave.
Ask us to leave?
But how dare you
come up...
-I'Őm very sorry, sir.
-Don'Őt you realize
that Mr. Wilde'Ős...
It'Ős all right, Robbie.
Let'Ős go.
Remarkable, the sort
of people they allow
in here these days!
-I thought it was
a high-class place!
I think it'Ős
blooming disgusting.
Come on, my friends, drink up.
Pay the bill, will you,
Freddie?
Why, certainly, Q.
Cab!
God bless you, Mr. Wilde.
Hello, Amy.
Knightsbridge, cabby.
Yes, sir.
MAN 1: Blimey! It'Ős raining!
QUEENSBERRY: Get my carriage.
So long, Oscar!
Are we going to have
a bit of sport then?
Yes, I think so.
MAN 2: Come on, there we go,
let'Ős get in.
Come on.
Follow him. As fast as you can.
MAN 2: Tallyho!
By God,
they'Őre following us.
The man must be mad.
I should have thought it
was common knowledge
by now, Robbie.
Go faster, driver!
MAN 2: Tallyho!
Faster, driver, faster!
This is madness.
I'Őm going to walk.
Stop the cab, driver!
Oscar, don'Őt be foolish.
I'Őm not
going to put you
through all this.
Oscar, where will you be?
-I'Őm going to my mother.
-Right.
Carry on, driver.
Well, now,
my old darling,
where'Ős your friend?
Why are you doing this,
Queensberry?
Why are you hounding
this man in this way?
Haven'Őt you had
your pound of flesh?
You don'Őt know me
very well, do you,
Mr. Ross?
I'Őm not so easily satisfied.
That'Ős quite evident.
Tell Wilde that
I shall not be happy
until I see him
under six feet
of earth.
Six feet of earth,
Lord Queensberry,
puts us all very much
on the same level.
I'Őve not finished with him yet!
I shall hound him
until his dying day!
Until his dying day!
Well, what now, Q?
Is the hunt still on?
Let'Ős go to The Savoy.
Ah, let'Ős go to The Savoy.
Go to The Savoy.
Oscar!
Oscar, is that you?
Willie!
Dear darling Mother.
Yes, what is it?
Dearest Mother,
you know you should
have been an actress.
I doubt if the great
Sarah Bernhardt herself
made a more imposing
Lady Macbeth.
But aren'Őt you just
a little premature
to wear mourning?
Oscar isn'Őt quite
dead yet, you know.
They crucified him.
Now, Mother,
if you'Őre going to
go on like this, I...
Who'Ős there?
OSCAR: Willie, let me in,
for God'Ős sake.
Willie, let me stay.
Let me stay.
Or I shall die on the streets.
Are you drunk?
Here you are.
Is this my son?
Is this Oscar Wilde,
cringing in the dark
like a frightened animal?
Mother, for heaven'Ős sake!
Stand up, sir.
Stand up and face them, sir!
For God'Ős sake,
don'Őt let them in, Willie.
Willie, open the door.
My son is ready for them.
Robbie. Thank God you'Őve come.
Ada.
-Robbie, what'Ős
to become of me?
-It'Ős all right.
Couldn'Őt you have
taken his coat off?
He'Ős soaked to the skin.
He'Ős ill. He should be in bed.
But he... He can'Őt
stay here, you know.
Well...
I mean,
it would be awkward,
you see.
There'Ős been mobs hanging
about in the street all day,
and if they were to
find out he was here,
well, there'Ős no
knowing what they'Őd do.
My son is not afraid of them!
He'Őll stand up and face them
like a true Irish gentleman.
I can find him a bed
at my house. Come, Oscar.
Don'Őt sit up too late, my son.
You need all the sleep
you can get
in this terrible time
we'Őre all passing through.
Come on, Oscar.
I'Őm not thinking of
myself, you understand.
He is my brother.
But it'Ős my mother.
She'Ős not very well and
any sudden shock might...
The prisoner will rise.
Gentlemen of the jury,
have you agreed upon
a verdict?
We have.
Do you find the
prisoner at the bar
guilty or not guilty?
Guilty, My Lord.
COURT USHER: Silence in court!
And is that
the verdict of you all?
Yes. Guilty.
COURT USHER: Silence!
Oscar Wilde,
the crime for which
you have been convicted
is so bad that one has to
put a stern restraint
upon one'Ős self
to avoid describing,
in language I would
rather not use,
the sentiments that must
rise in the breasts of
every man of honor
who has listened
to the details of
these terrible trials.
That you have been
the center of a circle
of the most terrible
corruption among young men,
it is impossible to doubt.
And under the circumstances,
I shall pass the severest
sentence the law allows.
Although, in my judgment
it is totally inadequate
for a case of this sort.
Sentence of the court is
that you go to imprisonment
and be kept
to hard labor
for two years.
COURT USHER: Silence!
Be upstanding in court.
All persons having
anything further to
do before My Lords...
Come on, back! Back.
Come on, back!
He'Őll get his hair cut now,
won'Őt he?
OSCAR: "I never saw sad men
who looked with such
a wistful eye
"upon that
little tent of blue
we prisoners call the sky,
"and at every happy cloud that
passed in such strange
fre edom by."
My dearest, your hands.
I'Őve
never been so idle
and worked so hard.
Please, my dear,
we have so little time.
Oh, Constance,
I'Őve waited all these
months for you to come.
I would'Őve come
before, Oscar, only...
I don'Őt know, it's all been
so confusing.
Why have you come now?
I have some bad news
for you, Oscar.
I didn'Őt want you to hear it
from anyone else.
Your mother...
She'Ős dead, Oscar.
There was no pain.
She passed away
in her sleep.
I wish I could
leave here in that way.
No, Oscar,
you mustn'Őt say that.
You must be patient.
It'Ős not patience that's
needed here, it'Ős apathy.
And apathy is the
most pitiful of vices.
Constance, I don'Őt
think I can survive
another year of this.
Oh, my dear.
It'Ős only the thought
of the children
that keeps me alive in
these terrible months
of waiting.
How are they?
They'Őre well.
It'Őll be
Vyvyan'Ős birthday soon.
-Oscar, I...
-Is he 9 or 10?
The time passes so slowly.
Oscar, I cannot
allow you to see
the children again.
I'Őm only trying to do
what I think is right.
I'Őve thought and thought
about it and I...
Forgive me, my dearest.
Please. Forgive me.
Oscar.
I brought you some cigarettes
and some delicacies,
some chicken.
I know what the food
must be like.
Goodbye, my dear.
Will he have time to catch
the boat train?
If we hurry.
Goodbye, Mr. Wilde, sir.
Goodbye, Dick. Thank you.
Thank you, my dear.
Oscar.
Come on, we must hurry.
You look well, Oscar.
The children send their love.
Thank you.
I told them
you were very ill.
I hope you understand.
Yes, of course.
Well, I suppose
we'Őd better get
down to business.
There isn'Őt very much time.
I'Őve arranged
with my lawyer to
pay you Ł150 a year.
It'Ős not much, I'm afraid,
but it'Ős all I can afford.
I am very grateful
to you, Constance.
Only I'Őm sorry I had
to make one condition.
If you see or communicate with
Bosie again, the payments
will stop.
Yes, I... I understand.
I know that may sound harsh,
but I promise you
I'Őm doing it to help you.
Hmm.
Porter.
-Boat train, sir?
-Yes.
Ada.
You look lovelier than ever.
Oh, it'Ős good
to see you, Oscar.
Ticket, madam?
The gentleman has them.
Thank you.
Oh, Robbie,
I can'Őt bear to
see him looking so ill.
I was talking to the
prison doctor yesterday.
Another six months in there
and he'Őd never come out alive.
Constance.
I want you to remember this.
I have always loved you,
and I always will.
You talk as if...
You'Őre going to get well again
and you'Őll forget
about these past two years.
You'Őll start work again.
I know you too well, Oscar.
Once you start writing, you...
Ada, don'Őt be so depressed
on my behalf.
What better reward
for one'Ős sins than
to be exiled to Paris?
Where no doubt
I shall die as I have lived,
beyond my means.
What a gorgeous hat.
Oh, Oscar.
Goodbye, my dear.
Take care of the children.
Hello, Oscar.
I never understood it, Ada.
I just never understood it.
OSCAR: "Yet each man
kills the thing he loves.
"By each let this be heard.
"Some do it with a bitter look,
"some with a flattering word.
"A coward does it with a kiss,
"the brave man with a sword."