Who are these people?
Raylan, who... who's out there?
Miami gun
thugs, I suspect.
What do they want?
Me.
Is my daddy moving?
No.
You didn't happen to bring
your rocket launcher, did you?
I didn't think to pack one.
All we want is Raylan Givens!
How about I come out unarmed
and you come out unarmed and we talk?
The second he clears, you
shoot him in the gut.
Maybe we can get him
to Gio before he dies.
Gotcha.
Why don't we all just run?
Well, someone's got to keep them
here for the other two to have a chance.
I'll stay, then.
Boyd, I'm asking you...
Take Ava out of here.
Come on.
My hands are empty.
Me too.
Where's your friend?
Is he dead?
Yeah, I think so.
Where's Ava?
She's running
through the woods.
Where you going?
I'm going after the young
lady with the automatic weapon.
I'll get her.
What are you gonna
do after you get her?
I ain't quite
figured that out yet.
You gonna shoot to stop me?
Maybe.
I'm pretty
sure you're empty.
You gonna bet
your life on that?
No, Raylan, I'm gonna
bet my life on you being the
only friend I have
left in this world.
♪
Where's your boyfriend?
Which one?
Holy shit.
Where you headed?
C-cincy.
Not anymore.
You going to kill me?
Do I have to?
No.
What's that?
Aah!
Boyd!
How long you
been following me?
Truck stop.
I'll take it from here, all right?
I believe I got
it from here, Raylan.
You just
gonna execute her?
I wouldn't call
it an execution.
More like retribution...
She killed my daddy.
Which is what
you wanted to do.
And besides, the gun thug behind the
tree killed your daddy, and I got him.
Are you gonna
split hairs with me?
I'm just saying.
Well, what's to stop me from
pulling this trigger, Raylan?
That it would be a sin?
Don't get me wrong.
I have no moral objection
to you killing her.
You understand, miss,
the life you've led.
But I need her... alive.
And if I don't comply?
Aah!
Boyd, nice shot.
- Can you get my friend to a hospital?
He's been shot. Let's go. - Will do.
What do you need?
My God, she needs a doctor.
She's needed one for a
while, but I don't think these
next two minutes are
gonna kill her.
What do you want?
What I did, the way I
killed your man, Tommy Bucks,
I understand you feel like
you need to come after me.
Trouble is, there are people I
care about
that are getting caught in the crossfire.
So this ends right
here, right now.
What would you give me in return?
You leave me alone,
and we will leave her alone.
You have my word.
I need more.
Well, I'd give you more, but
everyone else you've sent my way is dead.
Let's go, Gio.
She needs a doctor.
I need guarantees
about my business.
All right, look.
I've tried to be reasonable.
You give me your word in 10 seconds,
or I shoot you in the head.
Just...Time-out.
Maybe I should...?
Just let it ring.
We can't get to the
phone right now.
Leave a message. Bye!
Raylan, I'm walking in.
Whatever you're thinking
about doing, don't.
Mr. Reyes, my name's Dan Grant.
I am the Chief Deputy
of the Miami Marshals office.
There's an ambulance on the way
for your niece.
'Til it gets here we're gonna talk.
The three of us, like civilized men
see if we can't work something out, ok?
- Ok, let's talk.
- Not here.
The kitchen then, I could use a drink.
Not the kitchen.
In the den?
No,
and not the master bedroom,
not your office...
This far enough?
A little further.
Okay.
Here's what I'm thinking.
See if this makes sense.
You come after Raylan, harm him
in any way,
I'll kill you myself.
Go ahead. Say it.
I thought that went well.
Okay.
Get 'em up.
So, Art called you?
Yeah.
You want to stay?
Hmm?
The AUSA has long forgotten
about Tommy Bucks.
O'Neill's retired.
I got a slot open.
I didn't
think you missed me.
Well, you know, I had a wart once,
when I was a kid...
Right. And when it was gone,
you missed it?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, I get it.
Wait. Hold up.
Is this your idea, or
did Art suggest this?
Suggest what?
Shit.
He did.
I owe him one.
What for?
Well, he took you
off my hands, didn't he?
Dan, I went to Kentucky.
I did my job, and, as far as
I'm concerned, I did it well.
What's your point?
My point is, this
trouble I'm in is bullshit.
I don't understand.
I don't know
why they give us guns.
Raylan...
I'm trying to
offer you your old job back.
I thought that's what you wanted.
Right now, I just want
to go home and go to bed.
♪ On this lonely road ♪
♪ trying to make it home ♪
♪ doing it by my lonesome ♪
♪ pissed off, who wants some? ♪
♪ I'm fighting for my soul ♪
♪ God get at your boy ♪
♪ you try to bogard ♪
♪ fall back, I go hard ♪
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Disappointed?
Dan says the cartel's
gonna leave you alone.
Yeah.
Well, I'm still gonna
sit facing the door.
What about Boyd?
What about him?
He agree to that... Not gonna
run out and avenge his daddy?
Well, I figured I'd talk
to him tomorrow at the hospital.
Well, you're a
little late for that.
Slipped out in the
middle of the night.
Well, that's good news.
He must be feeling better.
So...You want to transfer me.
Honestly, Raylan, I don't
know who would take you.
Everything I
did, I saw no choice.
You should have
called for backup.
Bo said if he saw
anyone but me, he'd kill Ava.
And so you took Boyd?
It made sense at the time.
Well, you know what
happens now, don't ya?
We get legions of AUSAs all up in our ass.
Tim!
We're gonna do the gun thing.
Relinquishing a firearm can
be a very emotional moment,
and there always must be
another deputy in attendance.
Add in some premium alcohol,
what could possibly go wrong?
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
What are you
going to get next?
Probably the same thing.
You should
think about an uzi.
♪
How'd your father get that bullet
in his arm... in the motel?
Um...
I don't clearly recall.
A lot seemed to happen at once.
What did Arlo say?
Your father said you shot him by accident
when the bad guys started shooting.
He should know.
We're looking for the $20000 that
the Marshal service
- gave to your father to give to Bo Crowder
- Mm-hmm.
Your father said he passed it on, but we
didn't find it in Crowders things.
Arlo has it.
You know this?
I know Arlo.
What, you guys think I stole it?
Just cause I've shot the occasional
person, doesn't make me a thief.
Hey, Harlan man.
- You think you might be interested
in possibly..? - Yes.
- You don't even know what I was gonna ask.
Is it gonna get me out of here?
So, who we going after?
Jimmy Earl Dean.
Three first names...
triple winner right off the bat.
Sex offender...
statutory rape.
Got his release two weeks ago.
State police got a
call on the tip line.
Man matching his description was
aggravating a teenage girl.
Why'd you ask
me to go with you?
I'm not...
Comfortable with these people.
What people?
Perverts?
People in Harlan.
Anytime I've gone to coal country,
everyone was all polite...
- I'd prefer to do paperwork.
- ..."Yes, ma'am. No, ma'am."
Trying to keep in mind it's the
21st century and what's expected.
But when the cuffs come out...
Then I'm a black bitch.
So you want me to
help you with my people.
You know, throw 'em a pork
rind or some ding dongs?
If you wouldn't mind.
No, ma'am.
Hey...
You can't take those.
My daddy told you two
days ago to stay away from me.
I told him about you
creeping up again yesterday.
You see me coming near you?
Mnh-mnh.
I'm way over here, and I'm
gonna stay over here.
But you stop harvesting.
Why should I?
This is my daddy's weed
and my daddy's shed.
You're trespassing.
I don't care
whose shed it is.
That's not your weed.
Not yours, either.
It belongs to
the folks I work for.
Oh, really?
They didn't grow it.
Grown on their land.
Grown on state land.
Oh, you gonna
be a lawyer now?
Is this how come
you been perving on me?
Now, how have I
been perving on you?
Have I exposed myself?
Have I made any lewd or
unwanted comments toward you?
No, I have not.
Well, right now you're
talking to a 14-year-old
girl you have no reason
to be talking to.
I have a reason
to be talking to you.
You're trying to steal
something don't belong to you.
Hey!
I told you to stay back.
Yes, ma'am. Okay.
Wow.
Where's your mama?
Hmm?
Did she die, or did she run off?
You miss your mama?
At your age, I imagine you do.
I mean, a girl your age, she
needs somebody to talk to.
It's not like your daddy
could do a good job of that.
It's not like you could talk
to him about your period.
You gonna be the one
to talk to me about that?
Well, I'm closer in age.
Not by much.
Oh, come on.
I just turned 30.
Any man over 18 talking to
me about my period is a pervert.
Shit, any man period talking
to me about my period.
Period... That's funny.
You're very funny.
That's good stuff.
Is this gonna be your new line...
How we got the same sense of humor?
What's in your mind?
How do you think this is gonna go?
You thinking, "maybe we'll fight
a little, then it'll turn to
wrestling and tickling and
laughing, then she'll say,
'ooh, don't touch me there,'
and then she won't stop me"?
Is that how it runs in your head?
You don't even know what
to say now, do you?
Even me talking about wrestling
and tickling and "ooh, don't
touch me there," it's like a spell's
been cast, and you won't break it.
Well, maybe you're just dreaming
and you don't wanna wake up.
Well, wake up!
God damn it!
I tried nice with you...
hell I tried friendly.
It ain't worked yet.
You know when people ask me
why I came back here to Harlan,
I tell 'em it's cause
the Bennett boys gave me a job.
But honestly,
that's not it.
That's not it at all.
I came back here because of you Loretta.
Aah!
He works for them?
When he came by here, he just
said he was some bank man.
Well, he
followed me to the shed.
Oh, Jesus.
What's wrong?
I called that tip
line this morning.
Oh, daddy, I
told you not to do that.
Don't worry.
It's anonymous.
Well, I'll go talk to Mags,
she likes me.
Rettie.
When you talk to her, don't say anything
about us growing.
Well, with the perv working
for her, she already knows, daddy.
With our little convoy,
you listen closely enough, you
could have heard toilets
flushing up and down this holler,
everybody dumping their stash.
Hey, you or any of your people
have any sightings of Boyd Crowder lately?
No, but we're
looking for him.
State police!
Why are you
looking for him?
Well, you took
out Bo Crowder.
Miami gun thugs flipped his switch.
I was just a spectator.
At any rate, Bo's gone.
Open up, McCready.
I saw you at the window.
You think Boyd's gonna
try to fill his father's shoes,
take his place as
the crime lord of Harlan?
What's that old
saying from science class?
Nature abhors a vacuum?
What?
Sir, I'm trooper Tom Bergen.
These are deputy U.S.
Marshals Brooks and Givens.
They're on a detail, looking
for a sex offender.
Jimmy Earl Dean.
Well, what business
is it of mine?
Well, Mr. McCready,
you called the state tip line.
The hell I did!
Sir, you might have thought it
was an anonymous call, but it's not.
When you call, your name
and your address pop up.
On the recording you left,
you said that a man
from Rabbit Holler was
bothering your daughter.
The fella we're looking for,
he's from Rabbit Holler.
Well, I didn't call any
line or make any recording.
Is your
daughter home, sir?
No, ma'am.
But you do have a
daughter who's of the same age
of the girl mentioned
on the tip line.
Would you please leave?
Sir, you change your mind,
if you want to help us put away
a known and dangerous sex offender,
you...give us a call.
Why so scared?
Well, there's about 10 sets of
eyes that saw us roll up to his house.
Does James
Earl Dean have a job?
He put something
down on his registration.
Green Mountain ATV tours.
Oh, shit!
That's why McCready's so nervous.
The guy who's perving on his daughter,
works for the Bennetts.
Who are the Bennetts?
Hold still, still...
Unless you want to bleed some more.
I am holding still!
Well, hold stiller.
Anybody want some cheese?
Ho-ho-ho!
Here. Now you can stick on the
band-aids yourself.
I am gonna
teach them a lesson.
Hey, Doyle and me, we're
gonna take care of McCready.
All right.
Well, I'm gonna take
care of the girl.
What? Loretta?
What for?
Seems to me she showed craftiness
and guile protecting her stash.
Well, it ain't your face.
Did I not tell you that
there would be booby traps?
Stop by the store, see
what kinda cheese mama got.
How about you spending
the 10 minutes I'm gone
cleaning up this shithole?
Hmm?
Maybe get it from hideous
to just plain awful.
Hey, there, Walt!
You know why we're here?
No.
Where's Loretta?
Down at your mother's
store, getting some flour.
Let's take this inside.
All right.
Look, Doyle, when I called that line,
I didn't know he worked for you.
- I never would've...
- What the hell you talking about?
Called what line?
Huh?
Why are you here?
Aah!
Ow!
What the hell?!
This is more
Dickie's business.
I'm just standing by, make sure
you don't do anything stupid.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You've been planting
on our land, Walt.
It's state land!
Oh, now, you've been
planting on our land,
and any planting's by our say-so, and
you did not have our say-so.
I was just trying
to make a living!
Sally Ann's medical
about wiped me clean.
Find something else,
maybe even something lawful.
Hell, you could start
by selling that watch.
It ain't real gold!
Sally Ann gave it to
me on my wedding.
Walt!
You gonna come after us, hmm?
Maybe take a shot while
we're going to the car?
I ain't stupid!
Well, we're
just gonna make sure.
Oh, c-come on, now!
Aah! Ow!
It's okay, Walt.
Won't break the bone.
Hardly even break the skin.
It's so harmless, why
don't you put your foot in it?
Come on, now, Walt.
Put your foot in.
The hell I will!
Put your foot in, Walt.
I-I swear I won't
grow no more weed!
Where's that bud your
Loretta took from the shed?
It's behind the stereo.
I wouldn't lie.
What were you
talking about before?
Calling what line?
Nothing.
Put your foot in, Walt!
No!
Put your foot in, Walt.
He do anything to you?
I got away
before he could.
Did you tell your daddy?
I did.
How is your daddy, Loretta?
He still under the cloud
from your mother's passing?
Some days.
Some days or most days?
He taking care of you?
Keeping a proper home?
He sits in his chair, mostly.
When he's not growing
weed without my say-so.
Don't blame him.
I done most of the
work on that score.
You shoulda come to
me, Loretta, straight up.
We'll work something out.
As for the pervert,
you don't have to worry
about him no more.
Sir, would you think I'm bold
to inquire what you do as your job?
Well, which one's the question...
What do I think, or what do I do?
Loretta, don't you
know drug enforcement?
You see a man in a
suit of clothes?
They come around sniffin' the air.
Oh, no, no,
you got us wrong.
We're marshals service.
We go around smelling flowers till
we get turned on to wanted felons.
Raylan Givens.
Mrs. Bennett.
This is deputy Rachel Brooks.
Deputy.
Been away so long you
forgot to call me Mags.
Ah, I didn't
want to presume.
Loretta, this
is Raylan Givens.
He used to be a big baseball
player in high school.
Now he's a federal.
Oh, look at poor Loretta, eyes drooping,
us talking about the old days.
You run along home, Loretta.
Let us ancients catch up.
Can I interest you
in some apple pie?
I remember your apple pie.
I make it 180 proof.
Cut it with cider, some apple juice,
add some cinnamon and vanilla.
Reach me that glass, would you?
Coulda done with a
pinch more cinnamon.
Cinnamon really sells the pie.
As good as I remember it.
Would you like some, ma'am?
No, thank you.
How's business, Mags?
This place?
I get by.
And the rest?
So that's why you're here.
You go ahead and prove it.
I run a store, help these poor
people come up from the holler
with their food stamps.
When's anybody seen me cultivate a herb?
I told you, Mags.
We're not Drug enforcement.
As long as they
got nothing on you, we don't, either.
I hear you got a good thousand
acres, from here to west Virginia.
What's good about it?
You plant a third for the law,
a third for the thieves.
What's left you sell to the dealers,
the ones making the real profit.
Used to be, marijuana was the
number-one cash crop in Kentucky.
Now you got all the pills, worse
even than methamphetamine.
I don't have anything
to do with that.
I remember your granddaddy.
He cooked all week and
preached on Sunday.
Six years I came over to Harlan
and sold all the liquor he
cooked, and we did
better than fair.
How is your daddy?
He's at home,
far as I know.
I heard what happened
with the Crowders.
Ooh, that blew up big.
Have you seen Boyd?
No. Why?
Mm, just need a word.
You come here
looking for Boyd Crowder? That it?
Hey.
Hello, there, cowboy.
Hello, Doyle.
I'm guessing this
ain't a coincidence.
Well, word travels.
You and your hat are famous.
Doyle, this is deputy
Rachel Brooks.
Ma'am.
So what brings you
both to our town?
Raylan's looking
for Boyd Crowder.
Actually, no.
We're looking
for James Earl Dean.
Never trust a man
with three first names.
Not this one, anyway.
He some big
federal fugitive?
He's a sex offender.
I didn't know that was
on the marshals' purview.
It got added to
the plate this year.
Why you looking
for him here?
Word is, he works for you.
You think I
hire sex offenders?
It's not against the law.
Maybe your boys hired him.
I mean, not Doyle, of course,
but Coover or Dickie?
Neither me nor my
tads would do such a thing.
We're reefer farmers, Raylan.
We don't consort with
sexual deviants.
I respect how you feel,
Mags, and I know you love
your tads, but we're gonna
want to talk to them,
in your presence, if you'd like.
You can invite them here, or
we'll just go hunt them down.
You ever get to talk to them
face-to-face.
This might help ease the pain.
You sure ma'am?
I am.
Well, if you'll excuse me.
Hmm.
Don't take anything
without paying for it.
Mama, you really
are a mean, old coot.
So is this your uniform?
My day off.
Oh.
Still driving the
company car, though.
You think that's
a misappropriation?
You want to come back,
run against me?
Oh, I could
never do your job.
I just want to say hey.
You sure this guy
doesn't work for your clan?
I couldn't tell you.
I'm not in the family
business, as you know.
Good to see you, Raylan.
Good to see
you, too, Doyle.
Ma'am.
Either of you want to
take anything, go ahead.
Just leave a note.
I'll cover it.
Maybe we will.
Thank you.
Raylan Givens.
I seen you and your hat on
the TV some weeks back.
How'd I look?
Must have been official.
You weren't smiling.
That's just Coover shooting rats.
Okay.
Um, I don't know if
anyone called you,
we're looking for someone in your
employ,
Jimmy Earl Dean.
Is he here?
Was.
Took off.
When?
Few minutes ago.
For what it's worth, I never
knew he was a molester.
Hell.
All that shootin',
that's all you got?
Another one of them sumbitches
in there, you want to take a try at it.
I shot rats as a kid.
Used to chase 'em out
of the shit houses.
All's you have to do is
go in the kitchen, huh?
Where I know you?
Coover, this
is Raylan Givens.
So?
So, he is a federal.
Well, you can ask me, am I
growin' reefer, and I will tell you no.
Coover, you throw a dead rat at
my car, what are you trying to tell me?
Take it any
way you want, Raylan.
Long as you know I'm serious.
You're telling me
you're a mean son of a bitch.
You know how many wanted felons
have given me this look?
I say a thousand.
I know I'm low.
Something turn ugly as I put on the cuffs,
they're too late.
Some others, I swear,
they even try to draw down on me.
Dickie, you hear that?
He's threatenin' us.
No, he ain't.
He's got a
piece under his coat.
And you have one in
your hand, for Christ's sake.
Yeah, so does the negress!
Rachel, if Coover
raises his piece, shoot him.
If you'll move
a step either way.
Coover, put
the gun down now.
I said now, God damn it!
- Well, if you see your friend...
- Ex-employee.
Tell him, if he comes in
on his own, it's worth a lot.
If not, different story.
It's good to see you, Dickie.
You too, Raylan.
You too.
You and your hat.
Get up.
Get up slowly, quietly, because
if you wake him...
...I will kill him.
So things have changed.
I am no longer welcome here in
Harlan, which means
it's time for a little road trip.
Are you up for that, sweetheart?
This is where you nod.
There you go.
Now, you're gonna have to ride
in the trunk for a little while.
Anybody sees the two of us, they might
not understand our age difference.
Or the tape.
Get in.
Givens.
Listen.
Our bolo paid off.
Patrol clocked Dean on 75,
headed towards Tennessee.
What exit?
Passed 11 less
than five minutes ago.
Any sign of the girl?
Well, he didn't
get too close.
Didn't want to spook Mr. Dean.
All right.
Well that's a smart play.
If she's with him, and we should
assume she is,
get to a roadblock, or a strip.
That's right.
You want me to call
in some backup?
All right.
We got this far being smart.
Let's not blow it now.
You tell me if he comes back.
Loretta?
You all right?
You kick twice
if you're okay.
All right. We're gonna get you out
of there... one minute.
He left something.
He's on his way out.
Loretta, right now I need you
to make yourself as small as possible.
Hey!
What the hell are you doing?
What's it
look like I'm doing?
Are you stealing gas?
Yeah.
Shit, you caught me.
I'm stealing gas.
I don't know why I do it.
It's not like I can't afford it.
Yeah. Whatever.
Get out of here.
Can't I just
have a couple gallons?
Look, asshole.
I'm gonna tell you one more time...
What the hell?!
Hey!
That's it.
Whoa!
Okay, I'm just gonna
ask you one question.
Do you know how a firearm works?
What?
The key word
in firearm is "fire."
When the pin hits the cap, makes
the charge explode, meaning
there's a spark, which should be of some
concern to a man soaked in gasoline.
That's bullshit.
That spark's too far
away from the gasoline.
You didn't finish
school, did you, Mr. Dean?
It's not the liquid that burns.
It's the fumes.
Now, look.
Normally I would have just shot you
myself the second you pulled.
But I am doing my level best
to avoid the paperwork
and the self-recrimination
that comes with it.
The Lord knows,
you are the kind that
makes it worth it more.
Come on, Jimmy.
Can't we just try to end this
without you turning yourself
into the human torch?
You know my name.
Then you know what I
got in that trunk.
How about I just kill her?
Gasoline aside,
you aim that in any direction,
my partner's gonna pop
you in the head.
There you go.
Hey.
Slow.
This might hurt.
Would he have really
gone up like a torch?
Oh, I don't know.
But it sounded good.
I call it apple pie.
Go ahead.
Tell me what you think.
It's good.
It does taste like apple pie.
It does, doesn't it?
Loretta okay?
Fine, under
the circumstances.
Where is she at?
Down the holler
with a friend.
When the police brought her
back,
did they ask about your leg?
They did.
I told them that I
was fixing the trap.
When I was prying it
open, my leg slipped in.
How about the gunshot wound?
They didn't mention it.
Well Walt...
it's on the kind of all I had,
that I come here.
brought this
'shine as a peace offering.
I want Dickie to apologize to you.
Oh.
Right.
Um...
Walt,
I should not have shot you
in the leg or trapped your foot.
And um...Uh...
We could work
something out about you growing.
It was already in the
glass, not in the jar.
Why Dickie and me can
drink and be okay.
It's too late now, Walt.
Medicine already doing its work.
Even if you got on a helicopter right
now, you'd still be past care.
Why?
Why do you think?
Because I called
that police line?
You never go outside, Walt.
You know that.
I didn't know
he worked for you!
Gaahh!
Oh, this is the bad part,
but it doesn't last long.
The mixture's all natural,
from up in the hills.
All kinds of knowledge
in the hills.
It's something my
grandmama taught me.
She learned it from her grandmama.
- Loretta...
- I'll raise her myself.
Don't you think that'll be better for her?
The way it's been around here with you
and her sadness.
All the troubles of your hard life,
it's all gone now.
You get to know the mystery, Walt.
You get to see
your Sally Ann again.
Find the girl.
Beer?
So, how's work?
Exhilarating.
What do you think?
Did you really call me here
to talk to me about work?
Not unless
it's exhilarating.
I was starting to think you
were never gonna call me.
And don't say you've been busy.
No one's that busy.
- I like the ambiance.
- I pay extra for that.
Did I scare you off, when I
said we should get together and talk?
No.
Then why am I out
here, breathing diesel?
Last time you were in there,
you took off your wedding ring.
Oh, yeah, and as I recall,
you put up a hell of a fight.
I mean, if you really wanted to
talk, we'd have met on neutral
ground and not five feet and a flimsy
door away from that lumpy bed of yours.
Okay. No.
I invited you here because I'm
tired,
and I wanted to have
a word before I went to sleep.
So what's keeping you?
Son of a bitch!
Yeah, that's what a girl wants
to hear for pillow talk... regret.
Oh, you're gonna get that?
Givens.
Raylan, it's
trooper Tom Bergen.
Oh, hey, Tom.
What's up?
Am I catching
you at a bad time?
No, no, no, it's fine.
Okay. Well, I got a line on
Boyd Crowder for you.
Finally surfaced, huh?
Yeah, in a
manner of speaking.
Fire in the hole!
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
www.tvsubtitles.net