Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Hey, Wiglow!
Yes, sir.
Can you hear me?
Can you find the holes?
Yes, sir.
Make sure you get the big ones.
Ain't you got nothing to do?
Not a thing.
Ain't you going to help him?
I'm retired.
Baby Doll.
Archie Lee, you're a mess.
Do you know what they call
such people? Peeping Toms!
Ain't there a name for a woman
that sleeps in a baby's crib...
to stay away from her husband?
I'm gonna plug up the hole
in that wall...
and if I ever catch you again
peeking at me in my sleep...
I'm moving into the
Kotton King Hotel.
And keep your filthy dogs
off my furniture!
Let me talk with you.
I want to talk with you.
Save your breath to drum up business
for your cotton gin...
Close that door
so I can get dressed.
Go on, get dressed.
Not until you get on the other
side of that door and close it.
Today is the 5th of November,
tomorrow's the 6th...
and the day after is the 7th.
You know what day that is,
don't you?
November 7th is your
20th birthday.
Sweet of you to remember.
Where's my birthday present?
You'll get your birthday present...
providing you haven't forgotten
the agreement between us...
which comes due on that day.
The agreement?
Yes, the agreement.
You swore on the Bible
to keep your side.
If you kept yours.
Have I laid a hand on you?
Yes, as often as possible...
Have I? Have I ever once
forced myself on you?
As your husband, by law.
Or don't the law mean nothing to you?
How about your side
of the agreement?
You talked mighty big
when you were courting me...
you told my daddy you'd put me
in the grandest house in the county.
I put you in Tiger Tail,
I bought it and put you in it.
Tiger Tail is the grandest house
in the county.
Yes, the biggest old wreck
of a place in the whole delta.
You said you were going
to restore this place...
exactly how it was before,
only better...
make a show place, you said.
Yeah, a freak-show!
I've got my man on the roof now.
Can't you hear the hammer?
Is that a hammer? I thought
it was a king size termite.
If you ain't the most
ungrateful little...
I have mortgaged myself
to satisfy your demands.
You told lies to my daddy
in order to get me.
Get you?
I ain't got you yet.
And you ain't about to either.
I'm telling you that if
the Ideal Furniture Company...
removes those five sets
of furniture from this house...
that agreement you spoke about
is automatically cancelled.
Now, would you kindly
go back in your own room?
I'm gonna get me a good job
while I'm in town today...
just in case,
just in case.
Admiring yourself in the mirror!
Just look at yourself.
You're not exactly a young girl's
dream come true.
There was an old witch
named Granny Crow...
wherever she spit,
no grass would grow.
That old witch must've spit
on the top of your head.
Thank you, thank you.
You're a woman not grown,
therefore I'll make allowances.
Aunt Rose screams
every time the phone rings.
What does she do
a fool thing like that for?
The phone ringing scares her.
Aunt Rose, why don't you
answer the phone?
Aunt Rose.
Aunt Rose Comfort!
Why don't you answer?
I can't catch my breath
when it rings.
Answer it!
Hello?
This is Miss. Rose Comfort.
No, the lady of the house
is Mrs. Archie Lee Meighan...
They don't want to know that,
who is it and what do they want?
I can't hear well, could you
speak a bit louder?
The Ideal Pay As You Go Plan?
Give me the phone.
Now, what is this, boy?
Yes.
Today? No, you've got to
give me a little more time.
I've had a little set back
in business lately...
The syndicate built their own
cotton gin, and I lost their trade.
It's going to take me a little
longer to recover from that...
Then take it out!
Take it out, out, out!
You'll never get my business again,
never.
Honey, you ain't gonna lose
your fine furniture...?
Will you shut up
and get back in the kitchen?
And don't you speak a word
of what you heard to my wife.
Don't holler anymore in this house,
and don't cackle...
or I'll pack you up and haul you off
to that home at Sunset.
Did you say something to me
Archie Lee?
Yes. I said shoot!
What made her holler this time?
How do I know what made her holler
this time...
or last time,
or the next time?
The last time was because
you throwed something at her.
What did I ever throw
at Aunt Rose?
A glass of water, for singing
church hymns in the kitchen.
Water?
This much water.
I barely sprinkled her.
She don't hear nothing.
I know.
You've got to do something
to get the old woman's attention.
Hey, hey, cut that out!
Archie!
Get your hands off me!
Get them off!
I'm moving to
the Kotton King Hotel...
the next time you try to break
our agreement, the very next time...
Baby Doll!
Come down, if you're going
into town with me...
I've got to be at the doctor's
ten minutes ago.
Baby Doll!
If you're so impatient,
go ahead without me.
I've plenty of ways of
getting to town without you.
That's true.
You come on!
Get your cotton-picking tail
down here.
Take your time.
Morning, Sam.
What are you waiting for?
Come on, get into the car.
I'll get into the back seat
of that skatterbolt...
when you get out, walk around,
and open the door like a gentleman.
You'll wait a long time
if that's what you're waiting for.
I declare, my father
would turn over in his grave.
I never once saw your father
open a door for any woman...
especially not your
water-legged mother. Get in!
Sid, come here.
Why are we stopping here?
What are you doing here?
Vacarro's got me working
for him now.
For him? You're working for him?
What could I do? The syndicate
shut my gin down.
What's going on?
A celebration of some kind...
Why shouldn't they celebrate?
It's got every last bit of business
in the county.
Every last bit of what
you and I used to get.
They've got an up-to-date gin,
not like your pile of junk.
When are we getting out of here?
Would you mind
moving your arm?
Happy anniversary.
She's sure grown up.
I'm as fond of Aunt Rose as you are,
but I'm in no position to feed and...
Look here, the day Aunt Rose
is unwelcome under your roof...
her and me both
is moving out.
She can't cook...
If you don't like her cooking,
get me a regular servant...
don't think I'll cook for
a big fat old thing like you.
Quit saying fat...
Lose weight
and I'll quit saying it.
Right, but I'm serving you notice,
if that old woman dies in my house...
I ain't gonna pay for her funeral.
I'll have her burned up. Cremated.
I'll pack her ashes
in an old bottle...
and I'll pitch the bottle
into Tiger Tail Bayou.
Mr. Meighan,
you're late for your appointment.
The doctor will see you anyway,
I don't know why.
Hey.
Hi.
Are you the dentist?
Yes, ma'am, I'm the dentist.
I was scouting around for a job
and I noticed your sign...
and I thought I might
help you out.
What are you doing?
A boy in here a while ago
beat me playing checkers.
I still can't figure out why.
Well, what do you do?
Can you type?
No, I don't do no typing...
but I print a real good hand.
I don't know whether
we can use that.
You're awful young
to be a dentist.
I'm just getting started.
What's the matter with you?
I haven't been myself, John.
In what way?
Well, you're not an old man,
but you're not a young man either.
That's the truth, it's no lie.
How long have you been married?
About a year.
She's pretty.
Yeah, I guess so.
Youth.
Been under some sort of a strain?
No, no strain at all.
You look mighty nervous to me.
I'm not nervous.
You'd have to know typing.
It's typing.
Awfully nice talking to you.
Yes, ma'am.
Mr. Meighan, come back in here.
The doctor's going to give you
a prescription.
Archie Lee, all I think you need
is a harmless sedative.
Take this down to old man Hogg,
and take it according to directions.
Here you are.
Don't forget your sweater.
It won't help what's wrong
with you one bit.
How you doing, Archie?
I've spent just about the whole day
sitting on Main Street.
Why didn't you bring me
a double dip?
How long are we gonna sit here?
I've got to wait
for my prescription.
What the hell's so funny?
Chinamen. People know
the situation between us.
Yesterday on Front St,
a man said to me...
"Has your wife
outgrowed her crib yet?"
Three or four others haw-hawed at me.
It was public humiliation.
Private humiliation
is just as painful.
There's no torture to equal
the torture...
which a cold woman
inflicts on a man.
There's no torture
to compare with it.
I've staked out a lot in hell,
with a rotten house on it...
and five sets of furniture
not paid for.
You've bit off more
than you can chew.
Archie Lee, is that our furniture?
No, no it isn't.
They're taking away our furniture,
go after them.
I've got to wait
for my prescription.
Prescription?
Mister, stop.
Come here. Come here.
Stop, please.
Let's get home before
they get the rest of it.
Baby Doll!
You better go get her?
I guess I better.
What would you do?
Get tough with her.
Easy to say.
Come on.
Look out, here comes trouble.
- What about those people, boss?
- Just keep loading.
Get out of my chair,
out of my chair!
Stay off my furniture!
That's my rose lamp,
get off!
She better not hit me again.
Put that down!
I thought I heard
something rattling.
Leave me alone.
I don't want to be with a man who'd
make me live without furniture.
Honey...
My daddy would turn over
in his grave if he knew.
Baby Doll, if your father turned
in his grave as often as you say...
the old man would
fall off the graveyard.
Look at Aunt Rose, picking roses
as if nothing had happened.
I'm moving to
the Kotton King Hotel.
I'm gonna get me a good job.
The hotel manager helped carry
my daddy's coffin, he'll give me one.
What sort of work
do you think you could do?
I could curl hair
at a beauty parlour.
Or I reckon I could be
a hostess...
Second floor's all clear now.
Smile at people coming in a place.
What place?
Any place.
I could be a cashier.
You can't count.
Well, I could pass out menus
or programmes or something.
Say hello to people.
I can say hello.
Sign here.
Kotton King?
This is Mrs. Meighan...
I want to reserve a room
for tomorrow morning.
I want to register
under my maiden name...
which is Baby Doll
Carson McCorkle.
My daddy was
T.C. Carson McCorkle...
he died last summer,
when I got married...
he was a very close personal friend
of the manager of the hotel.
What's his name?
Archie Lee,
look at these flowers.
Poems of nature.
When are we going to gin out
some more cotton, Mr. Archie?
Oh, my.
That's the strongest brandy
I ever had.
It must've come right out
of Tiger Tail brook.
Young man, Mr. Vacarro...
this is a mighty fine party
you're throwing tonight...
in honour of your first anniversary
as manager of the syndicate gin.
Just a minute there, sonny,
hold it.
I've got something I ought
to get off my chest.
Us good neighbours appreciate...
Just a second.
Gentlemen, there'll be
a fish fry Saturday night.
Catfish, hush puppies,
dancing...
bring your ladies.
You go right on.
I want you to know us neighbours
appreciate your achievement...
in bringing in the biggest
cotton crop ever picked...
on this blessed soil
of Tiger Tail County.
Senator, my old dad once said...
"Blessed is he who has nothing to say
and cannot be persuaded to say it".
A couple of boys
don't look too happy.
They've no reason to be.
You put them out of business.
- They've got plenty of good liquor.
- I'll drink my own.
When you first came here...
I'll admit us old-timers
we a bit standoffish.
We didn't know you all that well.
Naturally, what's profitable to some
is unprofitable to others.
As the fella says, one man's meat
is another man's poison.
We all know some folks here
have suffered financially...
due in some way to this man's success
with his syndicate plantation...
but as a whole, the community
stands to reap a nice fat profit.
Senator, next time,
run on a Republican ticket...
we'll get the nigger vote
out for you.
Silva! Silva!
Mr Silva!
Move the wagons!
Move them!
Get that cotton moving!
Get the cotton moving!
Get those wagons out!
Mr Silva, where are you?
They're trying to kill me.
I found this...
kerosene can.
Marshal, what are you going to do
to find the men that burned my gin?
What makes you sure your gin
was set fire to?
Look around you. You ever seen
so many happy faces?
It's like a rich man's funeral
with all his relations attending.
I'd hate to have to prove that.
I'd hate to have to depend on you
to prove it.
I can't honestly imagine, if it's
a case of arson, who done it.
Every man you put out of business was
in that gin when the fire broke out.
One wasn't,
I know of one that wasn't.
Naming names just on suspicion
is a risky business.
I didn't name a name. But whoever
did it forgot to take this with him.
Marshal, he's your deputy.
I'll take this can
and examine it very carefully.
See if there's a basis for thinking
it was used for starting a fire.
I ran through fire to get this,
I mean to keep it.
Lock it in the pick-up truck.
Ginnie, sing us a song.
I shall not,
I shall not be moved.
I shall not be moved...
like a tree that's planted
by the water...
I shall not be moved.
How are you going to gin out
the rest of your cotton?
I'll truck it over to Sunset.
Collins will gin it out for me.
Collins has got his own cotton
to gin.
Well, I'll truck it over
to Bolivar county.
No one around here's
gonna gin it out for me.
I shall not be moved.
Silva!
Get off...
It's me.
They got the can, boss.
Who?
Somebody jumped me
from the rear.
Stay back, stay back.
Boy, take the advice
of an old-timer...
who was born and raised
in this county...
and knows every nigger,
every hound dog...
every toadstool and every tree stump
in 50 miles around.
My advice is not to make
any more reckless charges.
Being a foreigner, you already
got strike one and two...
I want no advice, no law
and no court in this county.
I'm from an old country where
it's tradition for each man...
to make his own justice...
like bootleg liquor,
private, in secret.
Because there was corruption
there too...
and justice was executed by
each man himself, alone.
I mean Biblical justice.
Eye for eye,
tooth for tooth.
Let's go.
I've got to know who did this.
I think I know.
Which one did it?
You know.
They were all in the shed
except one...
the one who wasn't,
I figure did it.
He's the one who's
going to gin out my cotton.
Get her up.
Furniture's coming back today.
Have mercy...
Go on, get.
Don't say a word, a little bird
already told me...
you'd bring wagons full of cotton
straight to my door.
I want you to know
you're a very lucky fella.
How come?
I'm in a position to hold back the
other orders and give you priority.
Come on, get out of that truck
and have some coffee.
What's the price?
You remember, it hasn't changed.
How about your equipment?
A1 shape, always was.
You ought to remember that.
You needed a new saw cylinder.
You got one?
I can't find one on the market
to equal the old one yet.
Come on, have some coffee.
We're ready for you.
When you saw my gin burn down
last night you must've figured...
you might get a good deal of business
your way in the morning.
You want to know something?
I'm always glad to know something
when there's something to know.
I never did see that fire of yours.
No, sir.
No, sir. Come on. Come on
in my house and have some coffee.
You, you come too.
Come on, come on.
No, I never did see that fire.
We hit the sack after supper and I
didn't know till this morning.
Baby Doll, come out here.
Come here, Baby Doll.
I want you to meet Mr. Vacarro,
from the syndicate plantation.
Say, what's your first name?
How do you spell it?
S, I, L, V, A.
Sure enough?
Like a "silva" lining?
Every cloud has got
a silver lining!
What's that from, the Bible?
No, the mother goose book.
That name sounds foreign.
It is, Mrs. Meighan...
I'm known as the wop that runs
the syndicate plantation.
Don't call yourself names,
let the others do that.
You sure are a lucky fella, Silva,
gold or nickel plated...
you're lucky I could take
a job on of your size now.
You're my neighbour and I believe
in the good neighbour policy.
You do me a good turn,
and I'll do you a good turn.
Tit for tat and tat for tit
is the policy we live on.
Aunt Rose Comfort...
Baby Doll...
Get your daddy's old maid sister
to bring coffee for Mr. Vacarro.
Get her yourself?
Honey...
Honey, honey, honey.
I want you to entertain
these gentlemen.
Look, look at her blush.
Look.
Look at her blush.
This is my Baby...
My little girl, every precious
ounce of her is mine.
Aunt Rose!
Aunt Rose Comfort!
Excuse my yawn, we was up
awful late last night.
So, you're a wop?
I'm a Sicilian, Mrs. Meighan,
a very ancient people.
Sicilian...
I'm from Corpus Christi.
How unusual.
Honey, at noon, I want you
to take Mr. Vacarro...
to the Kotton King for a chicken
dinner. Sign my name...
When bad luck hits you...
you find out who your friends are.
I mean to prove it.
Baby Doll, I want you to entertain
this gentleman in the house...
it's the good neighbour policy,
tit for tat and tat for tit.
You do me a good turn
and I'll do you a good turn.
That's right, come on, honey.
Now, make those wagons move now,
get them rolling.
I can't make nobody comfortable
in that house...
you're lucky if you can find
a chair to sit down on.
You want coffee?
No, just a cool drink of water,
thank you, ma'am.
The house water runs warm...
but if you've the energy to work
that old pump...
you can get a nice cool drink
from that cistern.
I've got energy to burn.
They dump their garbage in the yard.
Ignorance, indulgence and stink.
Well Mrs. Meighan
smelled pretty good.
You keep your nose
in the cotton.
Sometimes, water comes,
sometimes it don't.
This time it will.
Bring me a drink of that nice
cool well water, please.
"So, you're a wop?"
I don't have the strength anymore
to draw water out of that well.
Would you like a cool drink
of water?
How do you do?
I'm Aunt Rose Comfort.
My brother was Baby Doll's daddy,
Mr. T.C. Carson McCorkle.
I've been visiting here since...
I can't remember
just when it was.
I hope you don't mind
drinking out of a gourd.
Excuse me please, that old hen
has got back in my kitchen.
I could think of worse ways
to spend an afternoon...
than drinking cool well water
with Mrs. Meighan.
Stay with the cotton.
Go on, stay with the cotton.
There's such a difference
in water...
you wouldn't think so,
but there certainly is.
I take it you've not had
this place long, Mrs. Meighan?
No. We've had it long.
Don't you have garbage collectors
on Tiger Tail road?
Oh, it costs extra for them
to come out here...
and Archie Lee...
I don't know,
I almost give up sometimes.
You say you've got a bunch of
unfurnished rooms in this house?
Five complete sets of furniture...
hauled away by the Ideal Pay
As You Go Plan Furniture Company.
When did this misfortune
fall upon you?
Yesterday. Ain't that awful?
Yesterday.
Both of us had misfortunes
on the same day...
You lost your furniture,
my cotton gin burned down.
Yes...
Quite a coincidence!
What's that?
I said it was a coincidence
of misfortune.
Sure. What can you do with
a bunch of unfurnished rooms?
Well, you could play
hide and seek.
Not me, I'm not athletic.
When I arrived in this county to
take over the syndicate plantation...
this house was empty, I was told
it was haunted.
Yes, that's why Archie Lee
got it for almost nothing.
Sometimes I don't know where
to go or what to do.
That's not uncommon, people enter
this world without instructions.
I said...
Is that your breakfast?
I said, people come into this world
without instructions...
where to go or what to do.
They wander a little
and then go away.
Drift for a while
and then vanish...
they make room
for newcomers.
Old goes, new comes.
Going and coming, back and forth.
Rush, rush.
Permanent, nothing.
Anything living...
that lasts long enough
to take it serious...
What's this?
It's that old car
belonging to Mrs. Dobarn...
the lady that used to own this house
and haunts it now.
Where to, madam?
We're gonna play chauffeur.
Drive me along the river with all
the windows open to cool me off.
The chauffeur sits in the front.
That seat's got no cushion.
Come on! Get on your feet,
let's go!
Look out, get on your feet,
let's get in there.
Let's cut some cotton.
It's hard to find a place to sit
since the Ideal Furniture Company...
lost patience,
to sit in comfort.
It's hard to sit in comfort when the
Ideal people lost their patience...
and your gin burns down.
Would you move your leg?
But it's cool in here.
Comfortable to sit in.
What's this here?
It's my charm bracelet.
My daddy gave it to me.
They're the Ten Commandments.
And these here?
My birthday.
How many charming birthdays
have you had?
As many as the charms
on the bracelet.
Do you mind?
Count them.
That's all.
I'll be 20 tomorrow.
Tomorrow is election day
and my birthday...
and the day that Franklin Roosevelt
was elected for the first time.
It's a great day for the country
for both reasons.
He was a man to respect.
And you're a lady to respect.
Me?
I never got past the fourth grade.
Why did you quit?
Well, I had a great deal of trouble
with long division.
The teacher would send me up to the
blackboard to work on a problem...
and I would go up to the blackboard,
lean my head against it...
and cry and cry.
Would you move your leg?
You want me to move my leg?
Otherwise, I can't get out.
OK.
Well...
I'd just cry and cry and cry.
Well, finally I left school...
and a girl without education,
a girl without...
Mr. Vacarro?
Just picking up a few
pecan nuts.
Excuse me...
Excuse me, Mr. Vacarro...
but I wouldn't dream of eating a nut
a man had cracked in his mouth.
You've got many refinements.
Thank you.
I don't think you need worry about
your failure at long division.
After all, you got through
short division...
short division is all a lady ought
to be called on to cope with.
Well...
I ought to be going in now.
I get so depressed going through
all them empty rooms.
Are all the rooms empty?
Except the nursery and kitchen.
The stuff there is paid for.
Do you have a child
in the nursery?
Me? No.
I sleep in the nursery myself.
I let the slats down
on the crib.
Why do you sleep
in the nursery?
Mr. Vacarro, that's
a personal question.
Well, I ought to be
going in now.
There are rooms in that house
I've never been in...
like, for instance, the attic.
Most of the time I'm scared
to go in that house by myself.
Just take last night,
when the fire broke out...
I sat here for hours waiting
for Archie Lee to come home...
I was scared of going in
the house by myself.
It must have been scary, without
your husband to look out for you.
I'm telling you. The fire broke out
and lit up the whole sky...
with crazy shadows.
And we didn't have a Coke
in the house.
I was mad at Archie Lee.
You were mad, why?
He went off and left me
without a Coke in the house.
He left you without a Coke?
Yes, he did.
And he didn't get back until
way after the fire had broken out.
I got smoke in my eyes,
in my nose, in my throat...
I was in such a worn out
nervous condition, I cried.
Finally, I took two teaspoons
of paregoric.
Sounds like you passed
a very uncomfortable night.
Sounds like?
It was.
So Mr. Meighan disappeared
after supper.
You say Mr. Meighan left the house
for a while after supper?
Yes, for a moment.
Just a moment?
How long a moment?
What are you driving at?
Driving at?
You're looking at me so funny.
How long a moment did he
disappear for, can you remember?
What difference does it make?
It doesn't matter...
Why should you mind my asking?
You make it sound like
I'm on trial.
Don't you like to pretend
like you're a witness?
Witness of what?
Say, for instance,
a case of arson.
Arson?
The wilful destruction
of property by fire.
What?
About my husband leaving after
supper, I can explain that.
Can you?
Sure.
Good, how can you explain it?
What's the matter?
Can't you collect your thoughts?
Your mind's a blank
on the subject?
Do you find it impossible to remember
just why your husband disappeared?
You can't imagine what kind
of errand he went on, can you?
But, when he returned...
the fire had just broken out
at the syndicate plantation.
I can't imagine what you could
possible be driving at.
No? You're a very unsatisfactory
witness, Mrs. Meighan.
Should we drop the subject?
I sure wish you would.
Well, sure.
It's no use crying over
a burnt down gin.
Besides,
like your husband said...
this world is built on the principle
of tit for tat.
What do you mean?
Nothing specific.
Do you mind if I...?
What?
Sit down.
Is it strong enough
to support us both?
I hope.
Let's swing a little.
You seem all tense.
Motion relaxes people.
It's like a cradle.
A cradle relaxes a baby.
They call you Baby, don't they?
That's sort of a nickname.
Well, in a swing you can relax
just like in a cradle.
I don't like to swing. Besides,
I'm relaxed as much as necessary...
No, you're not.
Your nerves are all tied up.
You make me nervous.
For swinging?
Not just that.
What else, then?
All those questions
about the fire.
I was only enquiring
about your husband...
about his leaving the house
after supper.
There's no reason why I should
have to explain things to you.
No. Should we just relax.
Would you move over and
make a little room?
Is that enough room for you?
It is for me, how about you?
It was a lovely remark
your husband made...
the good neighbour policy,
I mean.
"You do me a good turn
and I'll do you one. "
That was the way he put it.
There now.
Thanks.
There's a lot of fine cotton lint
floating in the air.
I know. It bothers my sinus.
You're a very delicate woman,
Mrs. Meighan.
Delicate, me?
There isn't much of you,
but what there is, is choice...
delectable, I might say.
You're fine fibred...
soft...
smooth...
This conversation really is
taking a personal turn.
You make me think of cotton.
No...
No fabric or cloth...
not even satin or silk...
no kind of fibre,
not even a cotton fibre...
has the absolute delicacy
of your skin.
Should I say thanks, or something?
Just smile.
You've got an attractive smile...
And dimples...
Oh, yes, you do.
Smile, Mrs. Meighan.
There, you see, you do have them.
Please, don't touch me,
I don't like to be touched.
Why do you giggle?
You make me feel kind of hysterical.
I do?
Mr. Vacarro...
Yes?
I think I'll go and make us
some lemonade.
What did you do that for?
I don't want to be deprived
of the pleasure of your company.
Not yet.
Mr. Vacarro, you certainly are
getting familiar.
Don't you have a little
fun loving spirit?
This isn't fun.
Why do you giggle, then?
Because I'm ticklish.
Ticklish?
Don't be so skittish.
All right, I'll get up then.
Go on...
I feel so weak.
My head is fuzzy.
Fuzzy?
Fuzzy and buzzy...
My head is swinging round.
It must've been that swinging
that done it.
Is there something on my arm?
No.
Cut it out, it feels funny.
How does it feel?
Feels funny all up and down.
Quit switching me.
I'm just shooing the flies off.
They don't hurt nothing.
Cut it out, or I'm gonna call.
Call who?
The boy on the road.
Go on, call then.
Boy...
Can't you call any louder?
I feel so funny.
What's the matter with me?
Just relax.
Give in, stop fighting it.
I'm not. I'm not fighting.
It's you.
and you're suspicions...
about my husband.
Suspicions? Such as?
That he burned down your gin.
Well?
He didn't.
Didn't he?
No, he didn't.
He didn't.
I'm going in the house now.
Do you believe in ghosts,
Mrs. Meighan?
I do. I believe in the presence
of evil spirits.
What evil spirits
are you talking about?
The spirits of violence
and cunning...
malevolence, cruelty,
treachery...
destruction.
Them's just human characteristics.
Evil spirits that haunt the human
heart and take possession of it.
They spread from one human heart
to another...
the way a fire goes springing
from leaf to leaf...
branch to branch
in a tree...
till the forest is
all aflame with it.
You've just got fire on the brain.
I see more than there seems to be
on the surface.
I saw last night was an explosion
of those evil spirits.
I fought it, I ran into it,
beating it, stamping it...
shouting a curse of God at it.
They dragged me out, suffocating.
I was defeated.
When I came to,
lying on the ground...
the fire had won the battle.
All around was a ring
of human faces.
I looked up,
they were illuminated...
their eyes and teeth
were shining like this...
yeah, like this...
Don't, please, don't scare me.
The faces I saw were grinning.
Then I knew...
I knew the fire
was not accidental.
And you know
it was not accidental too.
It was an expression, a manifestation
of the need to destroy.
That's why I say I believe
in ghosts, in haunted places...
in places haunted by the people
that occupy them...
with hearts overrun by demons
of hate and destruction.
I believe this place,
this house, is haunted.
Aunt Rose, Aunt Rose Comfort.
This house is haunted.
I think I'll go around the back door
and make us some lemonade.
Archie Lee.
Archie Lee?
Archie Lee...
Let's go and see Archie Lee now.
Archie Lee.
What's going on up there?
The contraption broke down.
You better stay away from Archie,
he's fit to be tied.
Come on, give me that key.
Do you hear?
Archie Lee,
I've got something to tell you.
You left me over there.
I told you never to come here
when niggers are working.
You know...
How's progress, Mr. Meighan?
Fine, fine, great.
Personally, I can't hear
the gin running at all.
Big shot!
What's going on?
Nothing.
What? Well, that figures.
I inspected your equipment
before I put in my own.
I put up my own gin because
this equipment was rotten.
Was rotten, and still is rotten.
It's quarter past two,
you've a lot of wagons out there.
You Italians...
Never mind about we Italians!
Take it easy, now.
Get a new saw cylinder
and get this contraption running.
If you can't get one in town,
go to Rosedale.
If you can't get one in Rosedale...
you better get across the river and
keep going right on to Little Rock.
One more crack, and the only cotton
you'll see will be in a drugstore.
Now, you better haul, brother.
I've got something to say to you.
I ain't got time.
Big shot! Big shot!
Big shot!
Boy, he's really getting it.
We've got a saw cylinder like this
in our commissary.
Sure enough?
Go and bring it here...
get Hank to help you put it in
and get this contraption running.
He won't get one in town. If he
crosses the river, don't wait.
Rock...
I'll leave the pick-up truck
with you.
Stay close to the house.
Stay there till I come out.
Archie.
Archie, wait!
Archie Lee!
Please, don't touch me.
Aunt Rose,
Aunt Rose Comfort.
I've got to go and see a mighty
sick friend in the county hospital.
You might as well shout at the moon
as that old woman.
You don't want her to go?
She's got no business
leaving me alone here.
But she has a passion
for chocolate candies.
She watches the newspapers
like a hawk...
to see if anyone she knows is
registered at the county hospital.
Hospital?
They pass out candy to the patients
at the county hospital, you know.
Friends and relatives send them
flowers and candy.
Aunt Rose goes to visit them and
eats up all the chocolate candy.
Last week, an old lady friend of hers
was dying at the county hospital...
and Aunt Rose Comfort
went to visit her...
and ate up all her chocolate candy.
All of it?
Right while the old woman
was dying.
I like old people, they're crazy.
Do you mind if I ask you
a personal question?
What?
Are you really married
to Mr. Meighan?
Mr. Vacarro, that is
a personal question.
All questions are
more or less personal.
Well...
when I got married...
I wasn't ready for marriage yet,
I was only 18.
But, my daddy was practically
on his death bed...
and wanted to see me took care of
before he died.
Archie Lee had been hanging around
like a sick dog for some time.
And the boys around here
are a sorry lot.
They ask you to the movies and
take you to a stone quarry instead.
You've got to get out of the car
and throw stones at them.
I've had some experiences
with boys...
that would just curl your hair
if I told you.
The experiences
I've had with boys.
Oh, but Archie Lee
was an older fella...
and his business was better
in those days.
He was ginning out most of the cotton
before you put up your gin, remember?
I remember.
Well, I told my daddy...
I wasn't ready for marriage.
My daddy told Archie Lee
I wasn't ready for it...
and Archie Lee
promised my daddy...
that he would wait
until I was ready.
Then the marriage was postponed.
No, not the wedding.
We had the wedding,
my daddy gave me away.
But you said Archie Lee waited?
Yes, after the wedding.
For what?
For me to be ready for marriage.
How long did he have to wait?
Oh, he's still waiting.
We had an agreement.
I told him that on my 20th birthday,
I'd be ready.
That's tomorrow.
And, will you be ready?
Well, that all depends.
What on?
Whether or not the furniture
comes back.
Your husband sweats more than any man
I know. Now, I understand why.
Well, let's see.
Well, I declare.
I'm sorry.
There, now you wait right there.
I'm going to make lemonade
and serve it on the porch.
Yes, ma'am, right here.
You wait right there.
Yes, ma'am, I'll wait.
I will stay right here.
Yes, ma'am.
I'm going to get a fridge
one of these days.
Stupid old thing.
Forgot to light the stove.
Mr. Vacarro?
We'll be having lemonade
in a minute.
Here, how did you get
that pretty dress all wet?
What a mess.
Mr. Vacarro?
You wait right there.
Archie Lee, is that you?
Needs something.
Get out of my house!
Mr. Vacarro, I know that's you,
and you're making me very nervous.
Help, help, help!.
Open, sesame!
Game's over, I quit.
No, you have to keep playing
till you're it.
Would you go back downstairs so I
can unlock this door and come out?
This attic is in awful
weak condition.
Shall I call the fire department to
come with a net to catch you?
There wouldn't be time.
I don't suppose they'd get here
on time.
Any more than they did last night
when a fire burned down my gin.
I'll tell you what
I'm going to do.
I'm going to slip a pencil and paper
under this door.
All I want is your signature
on the paper.
What paper?
An affidavit legally stating...
that Archie Lee Meighan
burned down the syndicate gin.
This floor is about to
give out right under me.
It'll just take a minute.
Just leave it there. I'll be happy
to sign it and send it to you.
I'm a Sicilian.
We're a very old race of people...
and ancient races are
untrustful races by nature.
Either you sign this piece of paper
or I'll break this door down.
Do you hear me?
I gather you don't believe it.
Either you agree
to sign this thing...
or I'm coming out here...
and my additional weight...
What am I going to do?
You'll do what I tell you.
I'll do what you want...
only hurry.
What have I got to do?
Write your name.
You can come out now.
What about the footsteps
on the stairs.
Hear my descending
footsteps on the stairs.
Mr. Vacarro.
Do you hear my footsteps
on the stairs?
Mr. Vacarro.
OK, you're home free
and so am I. Bye-bye.
Wait, where are you going?
Back to my little grey
Quonset home in the west...
to take a peaceful siesta.
But I want to...
I want to...
Is that all you wanted?
For me to confess that Archie Lee
burned down your gin?
What else did you imagine?
Well...
Mrs. Meighan...
you're a child.
That's why we played
hide and seek...
it's a game for children.
You don't have to go all
the way home to take a nap...
you could take a nap here.
It's going to rain anyhow.
But all the furniture has
been removed from the house.
Not the stuff in the nursery...
there's a small bed in there,
a crib.
You could curl up
and let the slats down...
I'll be happy to accept
the invitation.
Come up and sing me to sleep.
My daddy would turn over
in his grave.
Come on, I'm good for it.
You know I'm good for it.
I'll take it somewhere else
if you don't want it!
Listen, my daddy's watch.
Cash.
The letters of his name
instead of numbers.
I'll leave this watch with you.
- Cash.
- Give it him and get out of here.
Thank you, sir.
I'm much obliged to you.
Will you get this thing going?
Come on, will you?
Shut up.
We're going as fast as we can.
You all must've done some
mighty fast repairs.
No repairs, we put in
a new saw cylinder.
From where?
The boss had one at our place.
How come I wasn't let in
on this bit of information?
I just about killed myself.
Where is that wop?
I want an explanation.
Vacarro!
Where is he?
- Have you seen the boss?
- No.
- No, sir.
Where are my men?
I sent them home.
They're useless.
You keep operating.
You know,
this isn't a bad old gin.
Is anybody living here?
Is anybody still living
in this house?
It's Archie Lee.
What happened here?
The plaster broke.
But how, how?
How did that happen?
How does anything happen?
It just happens.
Ain't I told you not to
slop around in a slip?
Supper's almost ready.
Breakage alone in that kitchen
would ruin a well to do man.
Go up and put some decent
clothes on and come back down.
There's a new bureau in Washington,
the U.W. bureau.
Do you know what it stands for?
Useless Women!
They've got secret plans to...
lock them up and shoot them.
Shoot them. You heard me,
I said shoot them.
How about men
that's destructive?
Do you think they plan to round up
destructive men and shoot them?
What destructive men
are you talking about?
Men that blow things up
and burn things down.
Because they're too evil and stupid
to get along otherwise.
Competition is too much for them
so they turn criminal.
They do things like arson...
the wilful destruction
of property by fire.
Who said that to you?
Look what's up there on the porch.
There's men on the road.
Who said arson?
Who spoke of wilful destruction?
You never knew them words.
Sometimes, big shot, you don't seem
to think I'm very intelligent.
I've been to school
in my life...
and I'm a magazine reader.
Who gave that whistle?
Who gave a wolf whistle
at my wife?
You just stay on that
side of that fence.
Stay over there!
Men from the syndicate plantation,
white and black, mixed...
heading for the river
with rubber boots on.
I just hope they turn
downstream...
I just hope turn that corner...
I'll blast them away
with a shotgun.
Small dogs give a loud bark.
No one's going to insult
no woman of mine.
You take a lot for granted
when you say "mine".
I came to you today for protection
and what did I get?
Slapped and sent home.
I'm telling you, the agreement
between us is over.
You're darn tooting it's over!
In three hours, the terms of our
agreement will be settled for good.
Don't count on it.
Sharp, at midnight.
Too much has happened here
lately.
My credit is wide open again.
So is the jailhouse door,
if the truth be known.
Are you threatening me
with blabbing?
Archie Lee...
Mr. Vacarro says he might not
set up a new cotton gin...
he might let you gin out his cotton
all the time.
Ain't you pleased?
He'll come tomorrow
with lots more cotton.
And while you're ginning it out,
I'll entertain him...
I'll make lemonade for him.
It's going to go on and on,
maybe even till next fall.
It's the good neighbour policy
in practice.
How long have you
been on the place?
All this long fall afternoon,
I've imposed on your hospitality.
Where have you been?
Taking a nap on
the only remaining bed...
the crib in the nursery
with the slats let down.
Something sad about it,
know what I mean?
Sad?
An unoccupied nursery
in a house...
and all the other rooms, empty.
That's no problem of yours.
The good neighbour policy makes
your problems mine and vice versa.
Supper's ready, children.
Didn't you hear us
called into supper?
Are you going to eat here tonight?
Mrs. Meighan asked me
to stay for supper...
but I wanted to hear the invitation
from the head of the house...
before I'd feel free to accept.
What do you say?
Stay for supper.
You'll have to take pot luck.
I wouldn't be putting you out?
Excuse me, I better
get into my clothes.
Yes, that would be better.
Did I understand
you say that...
you wouldn't build a new gin but
would leave your business to me?
If that's agreeable...
I don't know.
I've got to consider the matter.
Financing is involved,
new equipment...
Let's go and eat now.
I've got a pain in my belly.
Sort of...
heart burn.
Hey, one more plate
at the table.
Mr. Vacarro of the syndicate
plantation is staying for supper.
I had no idea company was expected,
I'll just change...
Another place is all
that's called for.
Have you been here all day?
Have you been here or did you go
to the hospital to eat chocolate?
Yes, I visited a friend
in the hospital.
Then you were out...
while I worked like
the hammers of hell!
I come home to find the attic floor
fell through, my wife insulting...
and a supper of hog slops!
Sit down, I've got to
make me a phone call.
Hello, Miss Hopkins,
give me the Bright Spot.
I can't think of the number,
you give it to me.
Hello, Bright Spot?
He's on the phone. If I was you
I wouldn't hang around.
I've got the ace of spades
in my pocket...
and I'm not going to give in.
Don't count on the law court...
justice here is as deaf and blind
as that old woman.
I'll do my own justice.
Get Eddie, Bill,
Butch, Rhodes, anyone.
Go while he's on the phone.
You don't know his friends,
they're awful.
I've seen them.
I find you different this evening
in some way.
Never mind that.
Go, while he's on the phone.
Grown up, suddenly.
There's no place he can run to
in this county.
You can say that again, boy.
If you can't leave the place,
send someone.
Send someone to find him,
do you hear me?
I'll call you back.
Poems of nature.
Never mind poems of nature.
I'll call you later.
If I'd only known...
Put food on the table.
Just a minute.
We ain't gonna wait
no minute.
Bring out some food!
Is that what they call a Mona Lisa
smile you've got on your puss?
Put some food on the table!
Don't pick on Aunt Rose Comfort.
I'll talk to that woman right now.
She's outstayed her welcome.
What a pretty blue ribbon you're
wearing tonight, Mrs. Meighan.
Thank you, Mr. Vacarro.
There's so many shades
of blue.
What particular shade is that?
It's just baby blue.
It brings out the blue
in your eyes.
Food!
This was part of my trousseau.
I got my trousseau at various stores
in Memphis where my daddy was known.
What is this stuff? Grass?
Greens. Don't you know greens
when you see them?
Big department stores
on Main Street...
This stuff is greens?
Archie Lee dotes on greens,
don't you?
No, I don't.
You don't dote on greens?
Somebody did...
Probably, sometime, somewhere.
That don't mean it was me.
Eat your greens, big shot.
They put iron in the blood.
I thought he doted on greens.
His likes are hard to keep straight.
Archie Lee is easy to cook for.
Take this slop off the table.
I'll cook you some
eggs Birmingham.
These greens didn't cook enough.
I played a fool trick with my stove,
I forgot to light it.
I left my greens on the stove.
I thought they were boiling.
When I came home, I discovered
my stove wasn't lit.
Why do you say "my stove"?
Why is everything "mine"?
I think you've been drinking.
You stay out of this.
Sit down, Aunt Rose.
What was that, Archie?
Sit down.
Where?
Sit here.
I'm gonna ask you a question.
What sort of plans have you made?
What plans? What sort
of plans do you mean?
Plans for the future.
I don't think this discussion
is necessary in front of company.
Mrs. Meighan, when someone feels
uncomfortable over something...
it often happens he takes out
his annoyance...
on some completely
innocent person.
Now, Aunt Rose...
you've been here since August,
that's a mighty long stay.
It's my honest opinion that
you are in need of a rest.
You've been cooking here and
cooking there for how long?
Well?
How long have you been cooking
in people's houses?
I've helped out my relatives
whenever they needed me.
I was always invited, sometimes,
begged to come.
When babies were expected or
somebody was sick...
they called for Aunt Rose
and she was always there.
Nobody ever had
to put me out.
Would you excuse me
for a minute...
I'll go up and pack.
Miss Rose Comfort, wait.
I'll drive you home.
I've got nowhere to go.
Yes, you do.
I need a cook.
I'm tired of my own cooking.
And I'm anxious to try those
eggs Birmingham you mentioned.
Is it a deal?
Well...
Sure it's a deal, Aunt Rose.
Mr. Vacarro
will be very good to you.
You never can tell about
things in the future.
Yes. I'm going to pack
my things.
Is there anything else around here
you want to take away?
Well, is there?
Yes, Archie Lee.
Mr. Vacarro noticed that the house
was just full of furniture.
He'd like to borrow about
five complete sets of it.
Coloured folks call this
pot liquor.
I love pot liquor
Good?
I'm crazy about pot liquor.
Is it good?
Good.
I love it.
That hen thought she'd been
invited to supper.
Listen to me!
You all listen to me.
Quit giving those filthy looks
back and forth and listen to me.
Do you think I'm deaf,
dumb and blind? Do you?
Well, you're mistook.
Oh, brother.
Oh, brother,
you're mighty mistook.
I know, I know I guess
I look like a...
I guess I look like...
What do you guess you look like?
Some sweet, innocent,
Baby Doll of a wife...
not ready for marriage.
No, not ready for marriage.
But plenty ready to go out and...
Wait a minute.
How's it funny?
It sure is funny, huh?
There's one little thing
you've overlooked.
I've got position.
I've got position in this county
where I was born and brought up.
I hold a respected position.
Life long member of every
organisation in the delta.
And I have friends!
Friends!
Long standing business associates
and social.
See what I mean? You ain't got
that advantage, have you?
Have you? Have you?
Come on, speak up.
Ain't you a dago?
Excuse me, Italian?
I'm not a doctor, but I was in
medical corps in the navy.
You've got a very unhealthy look.
Call an ambulance.
I don't have to make a phone call
I can handle the situation myself.
What situation?
The situation I've come home
to find here under my roof.
Look here, now...
I'm not such an old fool
I couldn't size it up.
I sized it up the minute I seen
you were still on this place...
and her with that sly smile on her,
and you with yours on you.
Well, I know how to wipe off
both those sly smiles.
Meighan!
You know, and I know...
and I know you know
that I know...
that you set fire to
my cotton gin last night.
You burned down
the syndicate gin...
and I've got here in my hand
a signed affidavit...
a paper, signed by a witness...
whose testimony will hold up even
in the law court of Tiger Tail.
That's what I came here for
and that's all I got.
Whatever else you suspect,
you're mistaken.
Isn't that so?
Isn't your husband mistaken in
thinking I got anything...
but this signed affidavit which
was the purpose of my whole call?
I'm foreign, Meighan,
but not revengeful...
at least, not more
than is rightful.
We've got a workable good
neighbour policy between us.
It might work out. Anyhow,
I think it deserves a try.
As for the other side of the
situation which I won't mention...
all I'll say is a certain attraction
exists, mutually, I believe.
I needed a little shut-eye
after last night's excitement...
and I have a faint recollection
of being sung to by someone...
a lullaby that was sweet,
and the touch of cool fingers.
But that's all, absolutely.
You think I'll put up with this...?
Situation?
You went to a whole lot of risk
to get my business back.
Don't you want it?
It's up to you.
Very cool.
You just fixed your wagon...
with your smart talk
you just fixed your wagon.
I'm gonna wipe that grin off
your greasy wop face for good.
Is my wop face greasy,
Mrs. Meighan?
That's the last time you'll
ever lay your hands on me!
You stinking stinker!
Stinker!
Don't shoot him!
Rock...
Rock, where are you?
Where are you, Vacarro,
where are you?
If you're under there,
you ain't getting out.
My husband's got a gun
and I just don't know...
Hey, wop!
Yellow bellied wop!
Get the gun,
get the gun away from him!
Help!
Get away.
Where are you, Vacarro?
I'm right here.
There you are.
Oh, it's you. Excuse me.
Silva.
Here.
Where are you, Vacarro?
Come on.
Baby Doll!
Where are you, Vacarro?
Where are you?
Vacarro.
Vacarro!
Now, you put that gun away.
Baby Doll!
Baby...
Baby Doll...
Vacarro...
where are you,
you wop?
Baby...
Baby Doll...
I'm ready.
I'm all ready to go.
Who is that?
What's the matter, Sandy?
Tomorrow's election day, I'm running
for town marshal, I want your vote.
You've got my vote.
You're too old for
a job like that...
I'm 20 years younger and I wouldn't
run for a job like that...
Age is a factor that calls
for recognition.
I hope you recognise it's
a factor that calls for recognition.
A man grows old suddenly,
not gradually...
just, all of a sudden,
he's old.
Wait a minute,
where are you guys taking me?
You're acting as though
I'm under arrest.
You've been shooting.
There he is.
Get down...
- Get off me.
- Right, right, come on.
Hey, what about me?
Put the handcuffs on him.
OK. Put me in
that stinking black calaboose.
I ain't a white man?
No, so throw me in.
But, don't you leave
my Baby Doll here with him.
Don't you leave him here
with her.
You're a married man.
You understand how I feel.
Don't you, Sandy? Please.
As one white man to another.
Just for tonight,
don't leave them on the place.
Just tonight, Sandy.
I've scratched my leg
on the bark of that tree.
Vacarro, come here.
Excuse me.
What have you got on your mind?
Listen, we ain't got nothing
to hold that old boy on.
He's been shooting, but he says a
fox has been catching his chickens.
His chickens?
I've got a signed confession...
by a material witness
that amounts to an affidavit.
Let me see.
Not till it's witnessed
and photographed.
We'll have it photographed.
I don't need or want
anything from you.
I'm going to the county sheriff.
Rock!
Here, Silva.
Silva, what about me?
Now?
I'll be coming back tomorrow
with lots more cotton.
I'll be back
Well, he's gone.
What happens now?
He's shown us a signed confession
from your wife...
we'll have to go through this thing
for appearance sake.
I don't mean that,
I mean...
What happens tomorrow?
Well, a town marshal has no control
over tomorrow.
Today's my Baby Doll's birthday.
Your friend has forgotten me.
Archie Lee, it looks like
the celebration is over.
Let's go.
He's coming back tomorrow
with more cotton.
He's coming back?
Let's go in now.
We've got nothing to do,
but wait for tomorrow.
And see if we're remembered...
or forgotten.
Oh, my, oh my.
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player