♪ lush orchestral music ♪
♪ ominous choral music ♪
No. Please.
Stop! Please!
State your name.
Alexander Ilyich Rostov.
Address?
For the last four years,
I have resided
in Suite 317
of the Metropol Hotel.
Why?
My house was burned down.
Occupation?
It is not the business of
gentlemen to have occupations.
You do not seem to appreciate
the gravity of your position.
No, I fear I understand
it perfectly.
You left Russia for Paris
in the spring of 1914?
Yes, I remember apple blossom
in the trees.
In all likelihood,
it was spring, yes.
What concerns us here
is your return in 1918.
Why did you come back only
a year after the Revolution?
You must have understood
the reception a man of your...
nobility would receive.
I missed the climate.
Are you the author
of this poem of 1913:
"Where Is Our Purpose Now?"
Were you the author?
It was attributed to me, yes.
Many consider this poem
a call to revolutionary action.
Hard for us to equate with a man
who has clearly succumbed
to the corruptions of his class
and now is a threat against
Russia and her people.
I am one of her people.
You were.
It is our inclination to have
you put against the wall.
But there are those within
the senior ranks of the Party
who, because of your poem,
count you among the heroes
of the revolutionary cause.
Therefore, it is the judgment
of this committee,
now the Metropol is under
full Party control,
that you be returned to the
hotel of which you are so fond,
where you will remain
for the rest of your days.
And make no mistake,
should you ever set foot
outside of the Metropol again,
you will be shot.
Gentlemen, I think
I can find my own way.
Move.
♪ energetic orchestral music ♪
That day, the Count
thought his life was over,
but in truth it was
only the beginning.
Not just for him
but for me, too.
And in the years that followed,
Count Alexander Rostov would
come to mean the world to me.
Your Excellency,
we didn't think you'd--
Good to see you, Vasily.
My suite is on
the third floor, gentlemen.
The lift or the stairs?
How are we supposed to win
on the field of battle
if we can't decide between
the lift and the stairs?
Have you ever been
on the field of battle?
The stairs it is.
Ah, ah, ah.
It's a beautiful view
of the Bolshoi, isn't it?
All these things are yours?
S-Save for the floorboards
and the bed, yes.
I read your poem.
The tone of your voice suggests
that you are not
a great admirer.
I found it hard to believe
those words came from the mouth
of a man like you.
What is the meaning of all this?
I'm here to show you
to your quarters.
These are my quarters.
♪ sinister music ♪
What is this place?
Before the Revolution,
these rooms were
for the servants
of the hotel guests.
Well, it has a window at least.
And I'll just about fit
on this bed.
Ah, G-sharp, I believe.
Yes. This will do very nicely,
thank you.
Your diminished circumstances
won't allow you
to keep all of your possessions.
But I will allow you
to take a few personal items.
And the rest?
Becomes the property
of the people.
I should add, we've liberated
your currency
from the hotel safe.
Food and board will be provided.
Life for you and your kind
is over in Moscow.
You must never leave this hotel.
If you do...
I'll be waiting.
Apologies.
I never thought to ask
your name.
My name is not your concern.
Well, thank you.
You have carried out your duties
with the greatest courtesy
available to you.
♪ melancholy music ♪
You open the door,
raise the weights...
...once a week.
Without fail, Alexander.
Helena.
♪ string music ♪
Good evening, Andrey.
Your Excellency, bonsoir.
I wasn't sure if you would be
dining with us this evening.
I was assured food and board.
I'll show you to a table.
Thank you.
Imbeciles.
A saltimbocca requires veal
wrapped in prosciutto.
Where is the prosciutto?
Where is the sage?
We have no prosciutto,
Chef, or sage.
Then this is not a saltimbocca!
- No, Chef.
- It is merely badly cooked veal.
Sorry, Chef, we're out of veal.
Of course we're out of veal!
A saltimbocca on table seven.
For the Count.
The Count?
Is he here?
- What's he doing?
- I believe
he's refusing to be beaten.
Everything to your satisfaction,
Your Excellency?
The saltimbocca...
...with chicken instead of veal?
Mm-hmm.
And instead of prosciutto,
shaved Ukrainian ham?
In place of the sage,
and I must admit
this took me a moment,
but I think it's nettle.
A man with taste is
a rare thing these days.
Nettle it was, Your Excellency.
Your palate remains, uh, unsurpassed.
Bravo, sir.
Bravo.
Your Excellency.
I-I didn't expect you.
Yaroslav, for you,
I am happy to wait.
♪ jaunty music ♪
Hello.
I like your mustache.
Oh.
I like your, uh, hair.
Alexander Ilyich?
Is it really you?
Prince Nikolai, my dear friend,
it's so wonderful to--
It's just Nikolai now.
You're looking well.
How have you been?
I-I'll be with you in a moment.
Tell me everything.
The last time I saw you,
you were playing Bach
at one of your grandmother's
dinner parties.
I guess I'm still playing Bach
at dinner parties.
I-I'll be here most weeks.
And your mother and sister
are well?
They're in Switzerland.
Oh, yes, I think
I had heard that.
Are you still, uh,
living at the old palace?
They've taken it over.
But, um, they let me keep
a room.
Well, at least we have
our health.
Well, I-I'd better get on.
Of course. I'm sorry,
I didn't mean to keep you.
Perhaps w-we could have
a drink at the bar
after my dinner.
I'd like that very much.
Nikolai.
They can take away your house
or your rooms.
They can't take away
who you are.
I thought you were in Paris.
Why on earth did you return
to this madhouse?
To get my grandmother
safely on a ship to England.
Audrius, could we have
the same again?
Yes, Your Excellency.
Thank you.
I was sorry to hear
about your sister.
What are we still doing here?
When I was a young boy,
not long after my parents died,
my grandmother the Countess
invited a boy over
from the neighboring estate.
She thought it might
cheer me up.
Obolensky he was called.
He beat me
at a game of draughts.
I didn't take it well.
Tears were shed,
pieces were scattered.
I might even have uttered
a curse.
Later that evening,
she found me still full of rage.
And she said,
"There's nothing pleasant
to be said about losing,
and that Obolensky boy
certainly is a pill,
but, Sasha, my dear,
why on earth
would you give him
the satisfaction?"
Obolensky...
That's not Vladimir Obolensky,
is it?
Of the Nizhny Obolenskys?
- Yes, the very same.
- Oh.
Your grandmother's correct,
he is a pill.
He was.
They burned him alive
in his house.
They won't stop, Sasha.
I know someone wh-who can...
provide papers
ensuring safe transit.
We-we could leave the country.
Unless we were recognized
en route.
Well, you'd have
to clip your wings.
No, that alone is
a good reason to stay.
Sasha, how can you joke?
Because if I take it seriously,
I could fall into a dark despair
I could find no way out from.
There's no bars
across the doors.
Once you're out of the hotel,
we could disappear.
Go east, go west.
We could start again.
As who? As what?
Does it matter?
We would be alive.
This is still my country.
Thank you.
To Russia.
♪ ominous music ♪
Is it just us now?
Yes, you're so good.
Apologies for my tardiness.
What will it be today,
Your Excellency?
Just the usual,
if you'd be so kind.
I was next.
I will be with you
in just a moment, sir.
I was here before he was.
Oh, uh, I have
a standing appointment
at 12 on a Tuesday.
If you would just please wait.
Why should I?
Why should he go before me?
Well, as I explained, I have a--
He has a standing appointment.
I was here first.
You'll have your appointment
soon enough.
Your Excellency.
Hey!
Thank you.
Oh, that won't be necessary.
I know it by heart.
Oh, you must be the guest
from the top floor.
Yes, delighted to make
your acquaintance.
Oh, um...
Well, yes,
I will have the fillet of sole.
Would you like a glass of wine
with your fish?
A Sauternes, perhaps?
Oh, I think a bottle
of Chateau Baudelaire
might be more fitting.
Of course.
Thank you.
- Your fish, sir?
- Ah.
Ah, that looks delicious.
Thank...
Mmm.
- Where did they go?
- I beg your pardon?
- Your mustaches.
- Well, they, uh...
- I... it...
- Is it true that you're a count?
- It is.
- Have you ever known a princess?
I have known many princesses.
Was it terribly hard
to be a princess?
Terribly. Especially so
since our glorious revolution.
Is that any good?
Didn't you have a lunch
of your own?
- At a different table?
- I didn't like it.
With my compliments.
Hmm.
So, how would a princess
spend her day?
Like any young lady.
In the morning,
she would have lessons.
In the afternoon,
she would visit with friends.
And at lunchtime,
she would eat her vegetables.
My father says
that a princess personifies
the decadence
of a vanquished era.
Well, perhaps a few.
Not all, I can assure you.
Don't worry. Papa knows
everything there is to know
about the workings of a tractor,
but absolutely nothing about
the workings of a princess.
Have you ever been in a duel?
Not exactly.
But my godfather
was a second
on more than one occasion.
- A second?
- When two gentlemen
agree to duel,
they each appoint seconds,
lieutenants who settle upon
the rules of engagement.
What sort of rules
of engagement?
The time, the place,
what weapons will be used.
If it's pistols, how many paces.
One of the duels
my godfather seconded
sprang from a dispute
that occurred
in this very hotel,
between an admiral and a prince
whose differences came to a head
one night in the lobby.
Were they in love
with the same woman?
I don't think a woman
was involved.
A woman is always involved.
Yes, well, whatever the cause,
at the time,
the hotel was managed
by a fellow named Keffler.
And it was well known
that he kept
a pair of antique pistols
in his office behind a painting,
so that if a challenge
was accepted,
carriages could be summoned,
and parties could be
whisked away, weapons in hand.
In the hours before dawn?
To a secluded spot.
The reality, I'm afraid,
was not quite as romantic.
Hmm.
The hotel manager would like
to speak to you.
What? Might I finish
my lunch first?
Of course.
Thank you.
I appreciate your stopping by.
It's my pleasure.
It's been brought
to my attention
that certain members
of the staff, uh,
when addressing you,
h-have continued
to make use of certain...
um... amplifications.
Amplifications?
Yeah, "Your Excellency,"
and what have you.
Ah. Yes.
- I suppose they have.
- Hmm.
Well, if it, you know,
if it were up to me, um,
you know, naturally enough...
well, you know,
goes without saying,
but what with...
Uh, honorifics were
elegant things in their day,
but they, uh, they do seem to
have outlived their usefulness.
It is the business of times
to change, Mr. Halecki.
And gentlemen
to change with them.
Quite.
Might I ask who brought this
to your attention?
You know why
they allow this hotel
to continue operating,
serving the clientele
that it does?
So that everyone can be watched.
So they can find those disloyal
to the party.
It's been that way
since the Revolution.
It's only gonna get worse.
This hotel is a dangerous place.
Especially for you.
As you can see, Vasily,
I'm in the middle
of a conversation
with one of our guests.
My apologies to you both,
but if I could see you
for a moment...
Very well.
Um...
Eh...
♪ slow, somber music ♪
How do you propose
we go about it?
We'd have to wear a disguise.
I-I can steal some coats
from the Red Army soldiers
that are staying at my home.
You walk with confidence,
no one will pay us any heed.
- Just another Bolshevik soldier.
- Yes.
Outside, I'll make sure
there's a car waiting,
and from there,
we'll go to the train station.
There's Red Army soldiers
all over Moscow, but...
these papers
that I can have drawn up,
they should get us
as far as the train.
From there, we lose
our Red Army insignia
and we walk the 200 miles
to Minsk...
...and to our freedom.
And-and our belongings?
No.
We can't take anything with us
that might give us away.
Not even Helena.
How much will you need?
Do you think that might suffice?
- Well, maybe... some...
- Oh.
Thank you.
Will they really shoot you
if you go outside?
You appear and disappear
like a spirit.
- What's your name?
- Nina Kulikova.
Count Alexander Ilyich Rostov.
- Where is your father?
- He's working.
He's always working.
- And your mother?
- Dead.
Oh, I am sorry to hear that.
I lost both my father
and my mother at a similar age.
People aren't lost.
They're taken from us.
Ah, little Nina,
how are we going to survive
these endless days
stuck in this hotel?
I've found a way to escape.
♪ atmospheric, elegant music ♪
I have a passkey that opens
every door in the hotel.
It's important to remember that
there are rooms behind rooms
and doors behind doors.
Come on.
- Where are you taking us?
- You'll see.
This is the perfect place
to destroy secret messages
and illicit love letters.
You do receive
illicit love letters, Count?
Most certainly.
There's more.
- I'm not sure we should--
- Don't be such a fuddy-duddy.
Look, we can spy
on the ballroom.
Come on.
If you pull this lever,
it throws the ballroom
into complete darkness.
This way.
Oh, she's the maid who used
to change my sheets.
...eyes closed, eyes closed.
Her name's Marina.
Every day she collects
leftover food,
to make a feast
for her little boy.
His name's Yasha.
These are all the novels
and travel guides
hotel guests leave behind.
This was my godfather's
favorite chair.
They're just things.
All my memories
exist within them.
Through here.
Come on, there's more
I have to show you.
Come on.
♪ soft, contemplative music ♪
Look.
I didn't know this was here.
What's all this for?
Papa says some government work
is too important
even for the Kremlin.
♪ slow, somber music ♪
Come on, let's go.
Hide.
♪ slow, suspenseful music ♪
How many do we have
to get through tomorrow?
Uh, 14 in the morning
and 12 in the afternoon.
Only 12?
That we have gathered
evidence against.
Evidence?
What evidence do you need?
Give me a man
and I will find a crime.
Five more names.
♪ intense, operatic music ♪
♪ slow, somber music ♪
They're rounding more people up,
putting them on trial.
It doesn't matter to them
whether a crime
has been committed or not.
That's all the more reason
for us to go.
For you to go.
And quickly,
while you still have a chance.
I saw your name on a list.
I picked up the papers today.
A few more weeks and everything
will be in place for our escape.
We don't have a few more weeks,
it could be days.
Hours.
You have to leave now.
But you have to come with me.
I can't.
For the same reason
I couldn't leave before.
Helena?
Yes.
There's no use
me telling you that...
she'd want you
to live your life.
Perhaps I don't deserve to.
You ever change your mind...
...these will get you
safe passage.
You are a true friend.
But no.
Now, you must go. Tonight.
I will.
After I've played Rachmaninoff
on Russian soil one last time.
And would you know, Nina,
Nikolai Petrov is
a real-life prince?
Yes.
His father was a famous general,
but fighting wasn't
in his blood.
His one great love is music.
And they say that since
he was three years old,
he spent more time with a violin
in his hand than without.
♪ intense, dramatic music ♪
Nikolai.
Nikolai!
Your friend did some business
with an element
we've been watching.
I'm curious as to why he needed
two sets of travel documents.
Years later,
the Count would tell me
that he wished
he'd had the courage to do more.
In truth, had he left
the hotel that night,
he would have died on the
pavement a few seconds later.
And I would not be alive
to tell this tale.
♪ atmospheric, dramatic music ♪