(ambient music)
(slow piano music)
(orchestra music)
- [Man]
From the very beginning,
cars were designed to be
as powerful and
safe as possible.
And yet, the automobile
remains the most dangerous
vehicle on Earth.
With the Monolith we introduced
a whole new way of thinking.
A car as a completely
safe environment.
(guitar music)
Adamantine nanotech body armor,
ultra thin bullet proof windows.
25 different state of the
art anti-hazard sensors.
Our brand new
exclusive vault mode.
Cars are a place where
most robberies happen.
Where women are
subject to harassment.
So we decided to finally
build the Monolith,
allowing our drivers to
utterly eliminate any risk.
Our Monolith will feature
interactive artificial
intelligence, a live driving
companion and security manager.
Her name is Lilith, you'll
love to get to know her.
All these features make
Monolith quite simply
the safest car ever built,
and the safest place
for you and your family.
(electronic music)
(baby babbling)
- [Woman] Okay, let's find
some music for you, okay.
- [Car Voice] Good
evening, how can I help?
- David, look, we
have a talking car.
- [Car Voice] We haven't
met. My name is Lilith.
What would you like
me to call you?
- I guess just Sandra is fine.
- [Lilith] Justsandra, did
I pronounce that correctly.
(laughing)
- No, there's just,
my name is Sandra.
- [Lilith] Sandra, did I
pronounce that correctly?
- Yes, considering you're a car.
- [Lilith] Hi little
human in the backseat,
what's your name?.
- [Sandra] How do you know
there's a baby in the car?
- [Lilith] According to US
demographics, 30 pound person
is most usually a baby.
- Wow, I'm impressed.
That's David.
- [Lilith] Hello David.
(video game music)
(laughing)
- Hey, Lilith, do you
know how much I weigh too?
- [Lilith] 122.4 pounds.
- Okay, I got it's
that's enough.
- [Sandra] Lilith, do you
store that information
about the weight?
- [Lilith] Of course, for
safety and comfort reasons,
I customize and continuously
improve my interface.
- Have there ever been other
people with different weights
in this car?
- [Lilith] Displaying
latest available data.
- Okay, so, that must be Carl.
Then, that's T. Wayne,
and I guess his girlfriend.
Who's this starving bitch?
- [Lilith] Sandra,
I can't understand.
(sighing)
(car phone beeping)
Incoming call, Carl.
- Look who it is.
- Hey buddy (laughs).
- Daddy.
- [Carl] Oh I miss you.
- So I called you
about a half hour ago.
Guess your phone was
off or something.
- [Carl] Yeah, my batter died.
I forgot my charger.
- Sandra.
- Shh, sweetie,
mom's on the phone.
- [David] Turtle.
- Okay, you want to
play with turtle?
Here's turtle.
Play with turtle, okay.
So how was your flight?
- It was alright.
A lot of turbulence.
They made us keep
our belts buckled
til we got to LA, and
there was this woman.
- Where are you?
Are staying at the hotel
near the airport again?
- I like planes, you're the
one that's afraid of them.
- You like stewardesses.
- Can we talk about the
elephant in the room here?
How's the new car,
do you like it?
- Yeah, I mean the
car is fantastic.
It's just I don't know,
I wasn't really expecting
an armored super car.
I feel like one of your rappers.
- Anything to keep
my little man safe.
I installed the Monolith
app on your phone.
It can control every
function in the car.
Have you tried it?
- I haven't really
tried it much.
My little co-pilot won't let me.
- [Carl] You really shouldn't
let him use your phone, baby.
(laughing)
- It's easy for you to
say when you're hundreds
of miles away.
(door knocking)
- Look, I'm really
sorry baby, I gotta go.
- Sorry Carl, it's just,
it just doesn't feel right.
You being so far
away all the time.
(loud knocking)
- [Carl] They're waiting for
me at the studio to finish the
mix, so I'll call you
when I get done, alright.
- Don't even worry about it.
I'll be asleep by the
time you get home.
- Where are you going?
- Your parents house.
- Poopy, yeah.
- I love you, you
know that right?
- I know.
(electronic music)
Please, please, baby, please.
Shh, it's okay, I'm almost done.
I know, I know.
(baby crying)
It's good okay.
- [Woman] So, you end
up going out last night.
- I should have not have
gone out last night.
- [Woman] Where
did you wonder off?
- [Woman] I didn't even
get that drunk though.
- [Woman] I can't deal with you.
- [Woman] Yeah, where'd you go?
- I hung out with that
guy I came there with,
what do you mean?
- The guy, the for the--
- Yeah, the guy.
- Did you get it done?
- [Woman] Yes you did.
- Okay, fine, wait.
I'll show you.
(laughing)
- What does that say,
is that his name?
- You guys.
- [Woman] Do you have any more?
- No, it's not his name.
- Do we have to check your body?
- No, I'm fine, it's ridiculous.
Let's go.
Harassment.
- God, mommy misses Venice.
But mommy loves her
little boy, yes she does,
yes she does.
Okay, sweetie, this is the last
time before grandmas, okay.
Come on, one, two, three.
(inhaler blowing)
Oh.
(pop music)
(child babbling)
Uh, see what you want.
- It's my marble.
- What?
- It's my marbles.
- You want the marbles?
They're kind of
dangerous, sweetie.
Yeah.
- Yes.
- Okay.
What do you say?
- Thank you.
- Thank you, yes.
Thank you, momma.
Who am I?
- Sandra.
I want this.
- This?
- Yes.
- Okay, cute, let's go.
Hi.
- Hey, how you doing?
Good, just these, and this.
- Your autograph.
- Thank you so much.
- You're welcome.
- Hey, babe, let's go.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- My friend says she knows you.
- I really don't think so.
- You from LA?
- I was.
Now, I live here.
Why am I even telling you this.
- I knew I recognized you.
Your hair looks different.
You're a singer.
- I was a singer, yes.
- Hipstars, right?
- You got me.
- No way.
How's that song go,
the bicycle song?
- Oh, please don't.
- Hipstars, sing with me.
On a bicycle made for two.
- Okay, okay.
- You know what, you should
come party with us tonight.
Amazing place.
Airport One.
What's wrong, are you
here with someone?
- Yeah, my man.
- Uh hmm.
- In the bear suit.
That's my little man.
- You have a kid?
- Uh hmm.
- So he's the one who
shut down Hipstars huh?
- No, I did.
(door bell ringing)
- Guess that's it then.
Later, Hipstars.
- Bye.
Alright, David, let's go.
David?
Have you seen my son.
- No, I haven't.
- David?
David?
(dramatic ambient music)
David, David?
Oh boy, David?
David, are you in here?
David, David, stop.
David, David?
(dramatic ambient music)
David, David.
Oh, sweetie.
- There she is,
there's mom (laughs).
- [Sandra] Hi, sweetie.
- [Woman] You have
got such a cute kid.
- Come here, come here.
Hey, sweetie, you
can't run off, okay.
What did mommy tell you?
You can't go anywhere
like that, okay.
- He's okay, he's a
tough little buddy.
- You guys heard me
screaming, why didn't you
say something?
- Relax, nothing happened
to your child, thanks to us.
- Yeah, you're welcome.
- God, you guys saw me
freaking out.
Are you stupid?
- Yeah, you're welcome.
- Are you freaking stupid,
leaving your child?
- What is she doing?
- He's apparently hating
where you're taking him.
- [Woman] Bye, mommy.
- Have a great day,
dealing with your child.
You should have been
riled up when your child
was running off.
Unfit mother.
(laughing)
(crying)
- David, shut up.
It's okay.
- Hey, Hipstar.
- [Woman] She didn't
even say thank you.
- [Man] Hey, Hipstar.
- Got to be fucking kidding me.
- [Lilith] All secure.
Welcome back, Sandra.
David.
(thugs babbling)
(engine revving)
- Hey, that ain't cool.
- [Woman] Run.
Hipstar sucks.
- What the fuck is Hipstar?
You guys are insane.
What is that?
- [Lilith] Would you
like me to drive, Sandra?
- No.
(electronic music)
We were number four on the
top 100, you know that?
We got lots of radio play.
Your mom was good.
Yeah, even though she had to
do all those silly dance moves.
Yeah.
That wasn't bad at all.
Thanks to that song,
I met your dad.
He had another wife,
but he chose me.
I don't regret a thing.
(electronic music)
♪ Love's in the air, oh oh oh ♪
♪ Love's in the air, yeah ah ♪
♪ Cold in the winter,
sunny on the inside ♪
(laughing)
What are you laughing at?
Lilith, call Jessa.
(phone ringing)
Hey, stranger.
- I don't believe it.
What on Earth?
- Oh cut it out, you know
what my life is like now.
Oh, actually you don't but.
- [Jessa] Yeah, sorry.
- Hey, guess what?
I just met these kids
in the middle of nowhere
who remember us.
It brought back some memories.
- Are you having
second thoughts?
- No, don't worry.
So how's the record
coming along?
- [Jessa] Amazing, actually.
Carl saved our asses.
- Carl?
- Don't sweat it.
He just gave us the
name of a guy who does
the arrangements,
fucking genius.
I couldn't even believe it.
I'll have to figure
out a way to thank
your husband properly (laughs).
What are you doing?
- Jesus, Jess,
my son is in the car.
- Oh my god.
Sorry, someone here has
some unfinished business.
Jesus, stop it.
- [Lilith] You have
reached your destination.
- [Jessa] Are you there.
- Yeah.
Hey, how much do you weigh?
- What kind of a
question is that?
- No thanks, sorry,
I was just kidding.
So, who's gonna do lead vocals?
- Who do you think?
Moi.
I mean someone
had to replace you
and it's better me than
some random chick, right?
- Where are you?
- Why?
- Who are you with?
- Why do you care?
- Is it Carl?
- Are you out of your mind?
- Answer me, Jessa, is it Carl?
- No, it's not
fucking Carl, Jesus.
- I know you Jessa,
I know how you are.
You think you can just steal
my life just like that.
- Look, I have to go.
And for the record, I'm not
the one screwing your husband.
- What do you mean?
What the fuck do
you mean, Jessa?
Who's screwing Carl?
Jessa, bitch.
(phone busy signal ringing)
(phone ringing)
- [Carl] Hi, you've
reached Carl Jenkins.
- Fuck, David,
stop, David, stop.
- [Carl] I'm locked
in the studio.
I'll call you back,
just leave a message.
(crying)
- Okay, sweetheart,
everything's fine.
Sorry, fucking marbles,
I wasn't thinking.
(crying)
Okay (exhales).
- [Lilith]
New destination set.
Calculating route
for new destination.
(engine revving)
- Daddy.
- Okay, let's try daddy again.
(phone ringing)
Pick up for fuck sake.
- [David] Daddy.
- I get it.
- [Carl] Hi, you've
reached Carl Jenkins.
- Okay, there's no daddy.
- [Carl] I just purposely sent
your call to your voicemail.
Just kidding.
- Play with turtle, okay.
- [Carl] I'm locked
in the studio.
I'll call you back,
leave a message.
- Hang in there, sweetie.
Daddy's gonna be really
surprised to see us.
(soft piano music)
- [Lilith] There's an
accident on the freeway.
Delays to be expected.
- No, no, no. I don't want
to get stuck on the freeway.
- [Lilith] Would you like
to change the itinerary?
- Let's just take
the quickest route.
- [Lilith] Left turn,
1,000 feet.
(soft piano music)
- [Sandra] Are you sure
that's the right road?
- [Lilith] This is the
shortest route to avoid
traffic jam.
We will resume the
freeway in 50 miles.
Relax and enjoy the view.
(electronic music)
Don't forget Sandra, I can
drive when you are tired.
- [Sandra] Lilith, thank you,
but I think I can do this
on my own.
(soft piano music)
(engine revving)
Oh, finally a sign of life.
Maybe we can stop
and get some drinks.
(sighing)
Never mind.
(loud howling)
(rock music)
Sorry sweetie, mommy's
just really nervous.
(car beeping)
What is going on?
- [Lilith] Warning,
smoke detected.
Park safely, and
please evacuate.
- Fuck.
Gotta be kidding me.
- [Lilith] Warning,
smoke detected.
- Yeah, because I'm smoking.
Can you make the noise stop?
- [Lilith] Sandra,
I can't understand.
- Turn off that noise.
- [Lilith] Do you want
to switch to full manual?
- Yes.
- [Lilith] This will turn
off all assisted features.
Do you wish to continue?
- It's just a stupid cigarette
and I opened the window.
- [Lilith] Sandra,
I can't under...
(car computer beeping)
(coughing)
- Shit.
Happy now, Lilith?
Sweetie, I'm sorry.
Mommy knows it's bad to smoke.
Today, she just
really needed it.
I'll never do it again, okay.
(loud banging)
(tires screeching)
(crickets chirping)
(animal moaning)
Are you okay?
Are you hurt, are you hurt?
Okay good (gasping).
Come on, no, sweetie, okay.
You want turtle?
- Yeah.
- Where is it?
I'll get it for you.
(child crying)
Oh please don't cry
baby, please, don't
cry, please, please.
Okay, it's okay.
Here look, look
it's turtle, okay.
Play with turtle.
(animal moaning)
Okay.
I'm gonna go check outside
okay, just give me a minute.
And then we'll get going.
Okay, alright.
(door beeping)
(child crying)
(animal moaning)
Holy shit, oh my god.
(child crying)
Don't be scared,
baby, mommy's here.
Just play with turtle, okay.
Give me a break.
(door shutting)
(suspenseful ambient music)
(doors locking)
(suspenseful music)
No, no, no, no, no.
Ah, ah.
(window closing)
Oh god, no, no.
No.
No, no.
David.
What did you do?
What did you touch,
what did you push?
Don't, don't, don't.
Be a good boy.
Show me the phone.
Good boy, good boy.
I'm very proud of you.
Sweetie, you just have to
listen to what I say, okay.
Take your finger and
do this on the phone.
Go like this on the phone.
No, like the other,
like this, like this.
David, put your finger on
the phone, and do this.
Like, like this.
Like this, no, like.
David, no watch me, like this.
Put your finger on
the phone and do this.
No, David, look at me.
David, look at me, watch.
Like this, like that.
Look at me.
David, do this with
your finger now.
No, David, what, what.
Oh my god, no.
(dramatic electronic music)
(loud gasping)
Oh my god.
Help!
Somebody help, please.
(suspenseful ambient music)
Hey, Lilith, it's Sandra,
can you hear me?
Lilith, I'm locked out.
My baby is locked
inside the car.
Lilith, it's an emergency.
It's an emergency.
You stupid fucking car.
Lilith, open the doors.
Unlock the doors.
Do something.
Uh.
(loud slapping)
Stay calm, you're just a car.
Uh.
(loud smacking)
(wincing)
(sighing)
(animals howling)
(grunting)
(heavy breathing)
(car alarm ringing)
(child crying)
(loud grunting)
(alarm ringing)
(crying)
(loud smacking)
(child crying)
Fuck, Carl.
Fuck you.
(alarm ringing)
I have to go look for help.
Mommy will be right back.
(heavy breathing)
(crying)
Peek-a-boo.
(laughing)
(piano music)
Peek-a-boo.
I know you've never
been left alone before.
I'm gonna get help and
I'll be back so soon.
I'm gonna get you out of there.
This whole thing will be
over before you know it.
Okay.
(sniffing)
(soft piano music)
Is something there?
(ambient music)
Help.
Hello?
(gate rattling)
Hello.
(chain rattling)
Ouh.
(grunting)
Ah.
Uh.
Shit.
(door opening)
(phone ringing)
Hello, hello?
- [Woman] Hello, you've
reached American Electric
Power powering the
American dream.
Welcome to customer assistance.
Hi, thank god.
I had an accident and my
son is locked in the car.
I need help.
- [Woman] All of our
offices are closed until
Tuesday, July 5th.
From all of us at AEP....
- No, what?
- [Woman]
...happy Independence Day.
Hello, you've reached--
- No, no.
Fuck.
(loud smacking)
(heavy breathing)
Ugh.
(grunting)
(suspenseful ambient music)
(animal growling)
(crickets chirping)
(ambient music)
- Sandra.
Sandra.
- David, it's okay.
(heavy breathing)
(dog barking)
(suspenseful ambient music)
(Sandra yelling)
(alarm ringing)
David, just stay calm, please.
David, breathe.
You can breathe on your own.
Mommy just worries too much.
Even the doctor says so.
Show me how good you
can breathe on your own.
(crying)
(ambient music)
Sleep well, baby, it'll
all be over tomorrow.
(wind blowing)
(dramatic piano music)
Stay calm, stay calm.
It's all gonna be okay.
Carl's gonna come find us.
I mean, he must have
called home by now.
Although I did tell him not to.
He'll call anyway.
He'll be worried about us and
he'll come looking for us.
I mean, he has to.
Or maybe he won't.
This might be the perfect
way to get rid of us.
David, look.
It's a shooting star.
I wish.
Oh.
It's just a plane.
(laughing)
Of course it is.
Airport One.
Oh my god, there's
an airport nearby.
David.
David?
David, David.
David, where are you?
David?
David.
Sweetie, hi sweetheart.
David, it's okay,
everything's okay.
David, unzip your
suit, can you do that?
Can you unzip your
suit a little bit.
Sweetie, your bear suit,
try to unzip, please.
Just try, David.
It's okay, it's okay,
everything's okay.
I fucked up again.
Mommy has a gift for fucking up.
But I know what
I'm gonna do now.
There's an airport
nearby and I'm sure
there's someone there
that can help us.
Okay.
(heavy breathing)
Oh god.
Okay.
Let's get you some shade, okay.
Okay, sweetie, mommy has
to go now, but I'm gonna
come back with some help.
- Don't go.
Don't go.
- Sweetie.
- I'll get the phone.
I get the phone.
- There's no use,
just stay still, please.
- I get the phone.
- I know you're scared
in there all alone.
(crying)
I know it's tough but
you've got to be a big boy.
You've got to be brave,
you've got to be strong.
(child crying)
(dramatic synthesizer music)
Oh god.
You're gonna have a story to
tell when all this is done.
All your friends when you
go to kindergarten are gonna
think you're so cool 'cause you
spent a night in the desert.
Oh my god.
I need water.
Okay.
If I'd been a fucking girl
scout, I'd know how to get
water in the desert.
When you're older, I'm gonna
make sure you go to boy scouts.
When you're old enough.
(heavy breathing)
(ambient music)
Water.
(laughing)
(water rushing)
(spitting)
(heavy breathing)
Okay.
(dramatic orchestra music)
God, how far is this?
(laughing)
Yes, yes.
Help.
What is it?
Help, is anyone there?
What the fuck?
(metal creaking)
(curtain flapping)
(gulping)
(ambient music)
(piano music)
(grunting)
(water rushing)
(ambient chorus music)
Oh my god, oh my god.
David, David.
David, answer me, David.
(tapping)
Oh shit, oh shit.
(grunting)
(heavy breathing)
David, hey.
It must be a little
cool in there, right?
(heavy breathing)
(grunting)
Open dammit, open.
You make such a mess
over a cigarette
and this doesn't even phase you.
(car computer beeping)
Oh my god.
Oh my god, oh my god.
(heavy breathing)
(dramatic orchestra music)
(loud grunting)
(loud banging)
Ah.
(woman screaming)
(loud grunting)
(heavy breathing)
Go to hell.
(wind blowing)
(slow piano music)
(crying)
David.
My love.
- [Carl] We shouldn't
have come here.
- It was a mistake.
- [Carl] Get up.
- No, no.
- You know what happened,
and you know when.
- I was just trying
to keep him safe.
Just wanted to stay calm.
- You know why he's gone?
- I just wanted a cigarette.
I was going crazy that
day because of you.
This is all your fault.
- Really, Sandra?
My fault.
You know what happened here.
And if there's anyone to blame,
it's you.
- I didn't do this.
- Yes you did.
- It isn't my fault.
I didn't want this.
- This is all your fault,
you took my boy.
You killed him.
- I didn't want this,
no, I didn't want this.
- Say it.
(heavy breathing)
David, David.
(sighing)
(tapping)
(crying)
David.
(ambient music)
I wanted you so badly.
It's not your fault I
messed everything up.
I'm going to hell,
but you're not.
You're an angel.
Mommy's here, like when
you were in my belly.
You couldn't see me,
but I was there.
(dog breathing)
Please forgive me.
David?
(dramatic orchestra music)
David.
(heavy breathing)
Ah.
(crying)
(dog barking)
(woman screaming)
(dramatic rock music)
David.
Ah.
Stop.
No.
(dramatic orchestra music)
(heavy breathing)
This can't be it, this.
You have every right
not to call me mommy.
I'm nothing.
(fly buzzing)
(dog chewing)
(heavy breathing)
(ambient music)
(loud banging)
Ah, ah, uh.
Ah, uh.
Ah, ah.
Ah, god, ah, ah.
Ah.
(ambient music)
(loud rumbling)
(computer beeping)
(heavy breathing)
(rocks crumbling)
Oh god.
David.
(tapping)
Oh my god.
Breathe, okay, David.
(car computer beeping)
(slow dramatic music)
Okay.
(car engine starting)
- [Lilith] Good evening,
how can I help?
- Ah.
Ah.
(engine revving)
- [Lilith]
Auto drive unavailable.
No route available.
(suspenseful music)
(piano music)
I can't find any route.
Please update maps.
All terrain mode on.
(dramatic orchestra music)
Collision detected.
Clear.
Collision.
Map updated
Recalculating the route.
Please go on for 200 feet.
Please go on.
(engine revving)
(dramatic orchestra music)
New destination set.
(soft piano music)
- Is he gonna be okay?
Is he gonna be okay?
(machine beeping)
(crying)
(piano music)
- Mommy.
(uplifting electronic music)
(soft piano music)
(electro pop music)
♪ Love's in the air, oh oh oh ♪
♪ Love's in the air, yeah ah ♪
♪ I'm crazy like a monkey,
eeh eeh ooh ooh ♪
♪ Happy like a new year,
yeah, yeah ooh ooh ♪
♪ I'm crazy like a monkey,
eeh eeh ooh ooh ♪
♪ Happy like a new year,
yeah yeah, ooh ooh ♪
♪ That's right, everybody ♪
♪ This is glass candy making
her way around the world ♪
♪ Searching every place to
place with you one more time ♪
♪ Looking for a heart to
heart whenever you're ready ♪
♪ We want you to know
if you ever should ♪
♪ Look in the mirror
and wonder
who it is that you are ♪
♪ And wonder what it
is that you came for ♪
♪ Well, I know the answer ♪
♪ You're beautiful,
you came from heaven ♪
♪ You came to down this place
to fill up the dark corner
with the everlasting night ♪
♪ And that's why I love you,
we love you ♪
♪ I love you, we love you ♪
♪ Come on, shout, hey shout ♪
♪ Shout, shout, shout ♪
♪ Shout, yeah you ♪
♪ I love you, we love you ♪