I wanted really good to my mother
She was drug addict
She was an alcoholic
She was legally blind
She was schizophrenic
But I never forgot that she loved me
even if she did
all the time
Give me the money!
it's mine!
it's mine, the state gave this to me!
If you do not like us do not eat!
Do not touch me, touch me not!
Where are they, eh? Where are they?
Where is it ?
Please, give it to me
-I gave it to you, -Let go MoM!
I gave a 100 to you
When the check came I gave $ 100 to you to one of you.
to keep them from, you understand?
Those for us to live on
every month it's the same damn thing
so you can put it to your arms so we can starve
it's mine
I didn't have it.
You are a liar
Give it to me, it's mine!
it's mine!
We are hungry!
I can't We need food MoM
what do you ever do for me, hah ? I gave you life
Do you want me to go on the streets as prostituitmi hah?
do you want me to do that ? I know I do that sometimes, right?
I need it
what is Medina?
what is Medina, that gives you $ 15,200 at the end of the round of double jeopardy.
I wanted that smile,
Oh God, I wantedthat smile so much
I was pathetic, wasn't I?
don't take the Acquedotto
Mom!
Dady ...
-she's taking the Acquedotto. -What the hell difference does she make?
- she'll get mugged !! - Who cares!
Help her father, she can't see, she'll get mugged
always a big production
see, They said they'll fix the light for change
The muggers will break them again
No,No
No, you see she's okay the water runs down hill
There is no water
You are wrong, dont you know what the aqueduct is?
The aqueduct carried water to New York City Well, for over 100 years it did that
Then they closed it down but now
the ghost water,right? it carries your mother along.
My father, you could sitdown on a couch and talk to my father
He just couldn't talk to him for long
Hey Jane!
He knew so much, he got all the answers righ on jeopardy.
He's a genius, he've the answer every time!
Watch where you going
That's the thing
Your parents all you gots
I looked at them as example of what should I find every where in the world
and they paid so litle attention to my needs
but then it felt their needs was so powerful
it didn't make me feel gurt or angry but they didn't look into me
because I felt okay this, This must be the human condition to be so
And then the world came in
you took my husband Elisabeth I'll kill you!
No, Mom!
I'm not your mother I did you a favor
Help me cleanup Liz, if they see this they're gonna take us too!
No, noo! get out of my house!
you're not taking me
I do not come with you, you understand? Noo, noo!
what happen to the window?
she threw the cat out
leave me alone
Why don't you take the medication and be a good girl?
She takes it
she just take too many other things
- This place is a mess - what happened here
He took a knife!
I fell down
- she got a knife - put the knife down
Alright,Where's the phone? we don't have one
- This woman is unfit - you're kidding
look you girls have a choice clean this place up help your mother!
Tell our father!
Ignore her she's a feminist.
I can take you anytime I want
you keep skipping school you keep living like fealthy animal
hey, hey, Where you going? comeback here ,come back!
you're gonna go to a home and you don't know what it like ?
They've girls in there they'll beat you down take everything you got
you can't have anything
You'll have to clean bathrooms you'll work there if you don't work here
back off! back off! it's not a show
got nothing better to do, hah?
Mom!
mom
Couldn't they see?
anyone could see she was in so much pain
The strugle was so much on the surface so there if anyone cared to look
it wasn't like she was running of a good mother to somebody else or not that was a good mother
she just didn't have anymore to give
Let me go !
Alright, hey hey hey!
oh! something stinks!
what is that?
I was always the smelly kid in class
Lisa stood on the bucket shower but daddy left her doing she had to marry a doctor she had so many expectations
I didn't have any expectations, so therefore I guess I stunk
I scratched for lice, and burn between my legs
My teachers was always telling me not to fidge it
but my underwear...
I didn't know what to do about underwear
I just worried that it fell apart
Alright, people thank you resess is over
My teeth ached
I was hungry ...
The teachers words never seem to reach me
Words just seems .. fall on the floor
Give me the test,Liz. there's no point of taking that No, I'll take it.
But you been here what? three times this month?
I'll take it it doesn't look that hard
fine
oh Liz, stay here
you do smell, you know? doesn't your mother tell you...
No, no ... it is my fault I just forget
ok Well,when you wanna have shower tonigh will you wash back here?
I've been saving something for you
Here ...
And here, bhow did you do that?
you've never in school
I read a lot
yeah, what do you read?
The Encyclopedia
The lady of the upstairs, Eva, she found one in the dumpster
the whole set, well except from R to S
If you've asked me between R and S I would've done it wrong I was just lucky
Oh Liz, you have to come to school OK No, I mean it, look
it's redeculus you're way too smart not to be here
I do not understand why toy don't come. I will.
How can I tell her that school make me sad?
I had never talked to her, I don't know how to talk to anyone.
My house was not a place that you can come out of it and be normal. - you'll have to come everyday
It's not a threat, it's promise
and is not a threat, is a promise.
- Eva, look what I got, - a 100 - thanks to your encyclopedia!
Good, you gotta get a good marks! you don't wanna be an idiot
and you keep it up now, you hear me? now your mother's back
My mother is back?
Well, we had nice quite couple a months, did we?
The only good thing about taking my mother to the nutt house was that when she came back she was my Mom again
she cooked and she cleaned shorthand for the company in a for me, that was the good quite couple of months
Before the drugs came back in
Mom ..
momy
Lizzy
Are you OK? I'm okay
pumpkin, you look real good
I'm Glad you're home mom!
don't you glad you're home?
Well, that hospital
wasn't too bad
it's too green the walls and there were bars on the windows
I'm sorry, you had to see that, you know
and I'm glad you're home
Look, Look I got a 100
Ma. no .. 100 is a good good, 100 is the perfect
didn't you ever get hundred?
No !
hey, I go to school
I ran away too young. Do not ever run away from home
I won't
I ... I will always be here for you
I know, Mom
I will always be there ... always
I am sick ...
I'm sick ... I'm sick, I...
I have AIDS ...
No. .. no ...
No, no no ... baby, don't
They say don't be afraid the say I migh.. I could live forever, okay?
but I can't live here
- I gonna go home - This is home
No, home to my pops, I will take you and Lisa
No, no, you have to stay here
I gotta stop the drugs, and I can't do it when daddy around
But you'll be alone
Liz, Lisa is already gone over, just packup your things and let's go
No no, cause you said pops will beat you you said he raped your sister
this is the way it has to be now
No, stay here
I can't
stay mom!
Everything was falling apart
I thought If I stayed I could have stop it
I thought If I stayed everything some how could stay the same
just open the door, it's no use
I know you're in there
where is your mother and sister?
they're gone
where's your father?
he's gonna get some food help, he'll be right back.
your teacher called, you still not going to school
you never in school We gota do something about this
Miss Wanda warned you, I warned you, everyone in case workers warned you
this is been goining on for years
we said clean up this place and go to school, clean up and go to school,
and you haven't done either one of them had you ... Elizabeth, have you?
No
so, what are we gonna do?
I do not know
I do
you're going into the system I'm taking her
No! But things are better now, my dady buys me big potatoes everyday
you're not paying the rent, you're not getting her to school
I tell him to go, I told you to go to school
she's got a mind of her own, she's a feminist
this is not a joking matter, pack her a suitcase ... now!
No, no! I'll go to school, please!
This isn't working, we need an adult who is responsible
My grandfather is responsible! My grandfather will take me! My sister is there
- your sister goes to school. - I'll go to school! I'll go to school, please!
Not make noise
I'll talk to him and if he will take you you will be out in 24 hours
I'm sorry
and if he won't?
You will have time to figure out how to live life
figure out my life ...
do people really do that?
If they do that , they're falling down in a deep dark hole
buzzed in, locked in
it was like to visiting my mother
Only I was in the crazy house now
Get her!
I didn't get out in 24 hours, I didn't get out in 24 days, no one wanted me.
they just left me there
Why don't you go to school?
That's the big problem I got Here, why dont you go?
Forom what I can see you have got a discipline problem
Liz! Hey pops!
You call your mother Jean! Come out here, she's here
I'm late for school but I wanted to see you first
Thanks Lisa
don't screw this up we are doing okay
and don't expect too much, she is dying
Lizzy!
Mom
oh God
When I think of my life, this is the time I like to think of
when I got back and my mother's mind was clear
there was no cokain so her schizophrenia medicine kept on working
and we go to the cafe, and sit and talk
eat hamburghers, we were together
even with her bad eyes I think she could see me
well, she can see my outline
and for a while I had my mother again
even the park, yea I remember, we used to slide down the hill
remeber we put down that cart board and we pretend that we sled
- you remember that? - Yes
- how about the tickle monster ? - we screamed and laughed about that one
Yeah, I was a good mother, wasn't I?
yea, you were fine
yeah
well, I'm really glad we are all together you and me, and Lisa
what if dad went off drugs too would that be great?
Maybe we can go back to University Avenue
well,your dad is in a shelter for homeless
I'm afraid he lost the apartment
he kind of ignore the rent, so, you know ...
What about my stuff?
got thrown out
all of it? Even my encyclopedias?
I'm really sorry , they board up the whole place
there was nothing we could do, it just, crap happens I mean ...
Look, I gotta go around the corner and see few friends
just for a minute okay? You finsh your burger
and I ... I'll be right back just be a minute
just be a minute
so that was that, no going back
I hadn't kept anything together, I only made thaings worse
If I had only go to school ...
if I had only, if I had only ...
so that part of my life was over
I guess the new part have begun
Elisabeth Murray and you're her mother? Yes
-Ah Look, take you to your class now - Thanks
A moment
- Bye Mom - Bye
- are you gona get home okay? - Yes, I'm just gonna go see my buddies you know they'll take care of me
- Maybe I should come with you - No no, you gotta stay at school or they'll take you away again go, go ...
Bye
so we have nouns, verbs, adverbs and prepositions
who's that, duke?
Thank you
I wasn't the smelly kid anymore, I had learned to shower every day at the group home
and my clothes, even if they came from the shop, all fit
but still didn't know how to be in school
I just don't know how to be normal
people, can we try to settle down?, Chris would you like to try diagram number 12?
No
Bobby?
you find it a musy Miss ... Elisabeth?
please don't call me that
That's your name according to these forms
Liz or Lizzy
Liz or Lizzy is a nickname
aren't nicknames
No, I'm afraid not
chesus, call the girl she wants to be called!
Elisabeth is a fine name, is the name of a queen, the Elizabethan was the age of Shakespeare
What's you problem with it?
My mother calls me Elisabeth when she's going insane ...
Liz then
Bobby, the sentence
so Where do you go to school before this?
I didn't
how did you fall in here?
I was in a group home
is that freaky?
yeah
- but you are not a freak - No
it's too bad, I am
my Birthday is coming up yeah? when?
Ah, you'll know I'm gonna wear my dad's trunch coat
I'm gonna come to school with nothing on, but my trunch coat, and a pair of boots
and I'll flash all the teahcers Happy birthday ...
You do not believe me?
yea I do
No you don't
It's a great place, I never had a sopha before
My grandfather is a little crankie we'll have to be out by 6 by the way
Liz, where is your phone? Make that TV game show L?
Never gonna win
know what? shut up !! gotta call this number before I forget it
- Do you understand the theorem? - come on bob! give it a wrest the test isn't till like a week
- Can I take that chicken in the fridge? - Sure
is it 6 aleady it's only 4:30
some drunk lady oh, so disgusting she puked on the door
I'll go open the window
I don't feel really good, Liza, help me please
what, what happen come on This way
Alright, up
I am a good mom, I just need a hug, okay?
Come on!
Oh God!
here we go, All clean, you see
she couldn't take living straight, why should I expect her to take dying
isn't dying the hardest thing onyone have ever done?
Everyone is gone
- except you ... - yeah
So where does you grandfather sleep?
Here? safe to his daughter?
But I don't think like that
Yeah, but don't know
he Did some things to her when I was younger, she told me that
With her sister and not her?
I figure he did them both ...
so your sister is crazy too?
Yeah, and their mother too, that's why I didn't wanna come here
you know, My...Mom is getting back to my dad
I wish My mom would
He does staff to my sister
You do not have a sister
Lucky for her
did you tell your mother? Yes, I told her
but she left him, and cursed him
she said she's gonna call the cops, and now she's getting back with him
you know, I asked her how she could do that, and she said that she missed him
she missed him ...
I was 7 years whe he first stuck it in
Chris, Chris, don't!
move in with me
- What, stay here? - Yeah!
What .. what will your grandfather say?
He won't know We will work it out so will never see him
he won't get up until after this for work he's like a robot anyway, he's out by eight
I'm back at 6 out!
Pops! she had no place to stay!
This not my problem
Leave her alone!
Your mother is dying your peace of trash father walked out and stuck me with all of this
did I ask this in my old age? tell me!
What are you doing?
fine, that suits me, you'll end up trash anyway
just like your parents
So I left
you wanna go get your staff ? or you'll leave me here alone
do anyone of us bargain for our life
it seems to me that we're just gonna fall into them
and then we have to do the bets we can Let's go!!
My mother was dying, my father was gone
but I had to believe that I the road would rise up to meet me
I was 15 years, when I wen out of door
What is a home anyway, a roof, bed
A place when where you go there they have to take you
If so, I was 15 years when I became homeless
You get some change? Get a job
how are you doing tonight?
Good bless you kid
spend some changes
Sometimes I felt I had neverhad a home in my life
Bring it on
Let's go
what are you doing! come back here
At other times I knew where ever my mother was that's where my home was
oh god!!
but month by month she was fading away
Liz ...
yeah!
where did you go?
I've been staying with friends
I miss you
paps! he hit me and you know
I couldn't stay here
Alright
Look! your sister told me that you stopped going to school
I'm gonna go back
when?
when you get better
They tease me
they tease me at the bar cause I shake
I can't stop shaking
I think it is becuase of the drinking
you should propably stop
Ok, ok ..
you're gonna get better
I love you, mom
mom
I love you
get over there
sorry!
- Look out!! - Stop
hey guys, wait up I'll catch you later I'm just gonna ...
Bye
mom
We took up a collection
she isn't coming here anymore becuase she always think you're laughing at
she's dead honey she died yesterday morning
Sometimes I feel that there is a skin on the world
and those of us who were born under it can see through it
we just can't get through it
My mother was being buried in section 51 the charity plot
My mother was in there, strangers had put her in there
was she naked, was she frightent no, she was gone
come on, let's go No, wait a minute
there should be a service, there should be a priest, what supposed to happen?
When you go, we're gonna burry you, that's all
it's a she
it is my mother
- There is no priest? - Not in these cases, you did know that?
she is dead, put her in the ground
Priest or no priest, what does it matter, she was gone, she was already rutting
sorry
as I suppose to believe she had found a turnal Peace
you Coming with us?
will you just go?
Hey, wait
Ok ..
let us get out of here, okay?
Liz, you know ... I just .. I can't I can't do this anymore. you know.. so, I'm going
Where?
group home
A crazy house
You know Liz, it's this, this ??? this is crazy
you should Come with me
yeah, so see you around
People died, things decayed
everything that seems so solid is meaning less
all that we left is the gestures we make
gestures in air, that's what we remember
I remember riding with my mother through the leaves
the year ending put her arms around me, when I was little, and she was well
that was long ago,
maybe it only happened once
mybe she betrayed me a thousand times it didn't matter Math will always be as a subject
we remember what we choose
get out of there!
Where you gonna put the stone?
there's no stones here , there's no room
In a week there would be no trace over
but what did it matter, this wasn't the real world, and we really live in each others hearts
She lived in my heart, but I live nowhere, I was all alone in the world
You are 16 years old with an 8th grade education
and when you are down the world spiral that will end in the worst place than you ever dreamed
you've burned every bridge, you're ran out of every welcome
an everyone who has ever believe in you you have let down
Eva?
I don't want to be an idiot, I want to go to school
- Yes - Hi, I am ELisabeth Murray, I have an appointment
at 9:30, it's 10:30
I'm Sorry, the subway got stucked I'm sorry too ,but it's really late
The school started 3 weeks ago we are just about full kids get on time here honey
I read the brochure intensive Student participation for the Development of injust community calendar
I just need one chance
You can wait and talk to David, but he got this meeting right after
I knew at that moment I had to make a choice
I could submit to everything that was happening and live a life of execuses
or I could push myself, I can push myself and make my life good
- We'll get to you back on Friday. - Ok, thank you it's a pleasure guys
- Elisabeth - Liz
Liz I am sorry, we are making our last decision and I'm already late
can I just talk to you for a minute ? 30 seconds?
well, there's the application, and the whole big eassy question
I've already done the eassy I really want this
I haven't had a lot of gown ups that proved to be trust worthy or in it for the long run .. so...
Maybe I don't know how to talk to you
My parents both use drugs, alot of them, I won't go near them, but ... I guess I've kind of lived that life style
I'm embareced now, not how late back I've been I mean...
I've really never been in school except for the 8th grade, but...
but your grades are very good to enter school
I used to show up last week and take the test, and that's how I got promoted
I'm smart, I know I can succeed, I just need a chance
I need the chance I need the chance to climb out of the place I've born in, I mean...
Everyone I know they just, angry, tired they are trying to survive
But I know that there is a world out there that's .. better!! that's...
better developed and... I wanna live in it
Why now?
My mother died of AIDS, she died couple of months ago and ...
it was real .. slap in the face
I guess I always thought that she was gonna get better and take care of me ..
it's prety stupid, huh?
You had never take care of me, I took care of her ..
she was my baby
but now she's gone .. so ..
now it's time to take care of yourslef
can you get here on time Liz ??
I'll sleep here, If I have to
Ok, you're in
But you told the others you won't know before friday
-you're in - David
Thank you! He just changed my life!
that's word's man?
just take the file and start the paper work, got your transcripts ? it's just the easy staff
address, phone number we have to have a meeting with your parents or you guardian,
get that in, and you are good to go
Dad
hey, Lizzy!
I need your help, please ..
such a Production ... such a production why don't you just stay in Bronx Then you can go to Kennedy
I don't know how to go to a normal school
Why, this is not a normal school?
- Well, it is public, but it is like private - yeah
Dad, Dad!
I think I can do this
yeah?, that's good I don't think I can
hey, you can, you can
well just say you're a long time truck driver that's why they will never see you
you're living with your girl friend now or also
Already, a truck driver who travels, and then I have a companion buckle
- Eva - Eva !! that's not good Eva is old enough to be my mother
Dad! I just
I just need an address, you know?
A phone number they can call
Please, please, they can't know I'm homeless
they'll call the city and I will be locked again
- Ok .. - Yeah ? - Ok
Mr Murray I am Peter, Peter Fidelty, I never actually married Liza's mother
Sit down, please
I am grateful you take my daughter in this
This is a very nice place
well, we're still new, we have big ambitions
yea, so as Lizzy I guess, she's a feminist
I knew you excpected that already
her mother was actually beautiful, like a movie star but.. aher mother was also kind of feminist
or something like that
Anyway I thought when I met her she was just, you know ... spirited bu actually she was completly insane
- We just need you to sign right here. - yeah.
and give us contact information address and phone number
Yes, 3458 University Avenue
- There are a number of apartment? - Yep, 2b 3b, 3b! yea! That's right
That's right we moved upstairs
phone number?
718 5 85 57 67 555 55 67
Excuse me, are somewhat out of phase
so that's it ? wI got staff I got to do
yea, that's it
Thanks for coming
Can I start now?
It's *** to have someone actually want to come to school, yea
I'll walk him out
Alright oh, they give you token here?
No, I got a job
yea, I remember when you're a kid you used to bag groceries down in Foren Road put food in the fridge
- How old are you? - 8
- I am not a people person, you understand that - Yes
I'm just not a people person Liz
I got nothing to do with you, you know it's not personal
- But you came today though ... - yep!
I love you dad !
oh don't do that, don't love me, it is a waste of energy
You know, when I was litle you were the most interesting thing in my world
everyone was just talking about drugs or sex or... just trying to survive the day
but you always had ideas
it's becuase of you I know there's another way of being
- yeah
are you okay?
yea yea, I'm fine they take care of your dad fine in the shelter
Actually I'm gonna get my own apartment I would like to do that,
you can come stay with me visit me anytime
your own apartment...
Yes,they like to do that, they keep the people like me out of the shelters
you know,like the patients, you know, people with AIDS
Hey Listen, alot of changes than jean I got all this medicens now,
and I'm clean, So I'm gonna live forever
Ok, I'll be fine, I'm gonna live forever
stay in school, I blew this, but you can do this
Golf Tonkin Remember the Maine anybody? Franco-Prussian War?
You did you get Bismark? you didn't get Bismark I didn't get Bismark either
I thought this Bismark was kinda role so is this Bismark a kizar ?
stop talking about food, you're making me hungry
Dave are we gonna have book next year? cause I keep losing this things
hmm.. textbooks Why don't we use textbooks? anyone?
Too heavy !! Bzzt! they are, but no cigar!!
it's too expensive, the school is so poor Bzzzt! I'm keeping my cigar today
You, new girl Her name is Liz! chesus dave she's been here for a week, try to Remember
Liz, sue me ...
Here, Textbook, text ... book ...
Up, open it, what do you see?
Words
What kind of words?
the words of the author
No, no, it is important
and what do we have here?
alot of other people's words
and I want you to have them?
because one point of view gives you a one Dimentional-world
Cigars!! , Cigars!!
Bismarck, Marx, the guy who sold me the buble gums Cigars
why on earth we could find ourselves To his story ... history
but isn't that the deal dave? I mean, is there an official history
New girl, tell him what history is
History is all of us all our stories count
that's it, grap your papers I will be in the lounch if you want to talk about it
hey Liz, this is yours
- hey, new girl - you let me in and you don't remember my name
- oh, I remember your name, - I just like to gang up on your side
You are pretty smart hah, so as you
you gave me an A minus Yes, sounds a very good paper
How do I make an A Liz, an A minus is an excellent mark
This is your first working school in ..what .. forever?
If my words count I want them to be right
Okay well ...
Oh! What are you still doing here?
- Algebra - yea Well, it's after 11, I locking up
how many classes are you taking?
Um, the regular five, then the saturday programming, the night school French
and the after school sciences 10 ...
Now you see why I need the before school math
It's alot I'm 17, I do not want to be 21 before I finish high school
So you're trying to do what 4 years of high school in 3?
2 you need before math school too
Yeah, you're gonna kill yourself!
No. .. I'm gonna live
I had a down, the B train took 70 minutes to do that entire run
I've been back 4 times and I would be at school just a little early
Then David would let me in
For the first time my life had some order I can count on
Chris?
What are you doing here?
- hanging out - what about the home - I got hookie
- so how come you didn't look for me? - I did
I have been looking for a long time just that ... you haven't been in any other places
I'm here now and I'm going to a new school, you'd like it
Hey ... hey, come on it will be great, we are together
Last one out, first one in No, that describes you david
how did you get so dedicated
Well, I'm such a privilage jurk, I wanted to give something back
and this is ...? My friend Chris, my best friend
- Hi Chris - Hey
I want her to come here too it's not a party, you know .. it's a tough place
well, she's good for you, she's good enogh for me, come on in
so, what you were putting on the bored? oh we decided to send our top 10 students on schoolarship to Boston
Cool! you ever been? I've never been out of New York
we went to Queens once Well, you're going
-come on, Noway I'm in the top 10 students
well, you're not one of the top, you're the top you're not among the best, you're the best ...
You got the best grades in this whole place Liz
- yea, so what .. going to Boston? - All expenses paid
- how long? - 5 days
- you okay, Liz? - Yes
I've just was always been trash, you know..
You are not trash
This is to get you thinking about college
- what's college like - it's all crap, shut up!
You can come too Can't she?
sure, if she does the work
come on chris dream a little, what do you wanna be when you grow up?
boy, I was grown since I was 7
- Chris ... - I mean after high school, it's okay
No, it's not okay I'll be a garbage man, I'll be a prostitute
who cares what the hell I'm gonna be?
Welcome to Harvard guys
So, does it looks like you though it would?
Better, definitely better
Liz, they're just people
Not people like me
Why not people like me? What made them so different?
becuase of the way they were born?
I was working as hard as I could so so I didn't end up as food stamps or hustling
What if .. what if I worked even more?
I was so close to this skin that I can touch it
It would be a reach, it's not impossible
- dona, there any other scholarships? - yea,it's quite a few
Write 1500 words about the importance of the free market in the free world and win $ 500
yea, I would need only 70 of those, every year
Ah, there was something brand new from the newyork time, maybe I didn't put them in yet
- $ 12,000 every year for 4 years! - What do you have to do?
Attach a brief eassy describing what you believe to be the most significant academic achievement
and how you have overcome any challenges tor obstacles
can I have copy of this?
I want to stand beside the people in the sidewalk not be so far beneath them
I wanna go to Harvard, and become very developed read all the bets books
Then I find myself thinking: if I just go crazy?
even lose every *** of my potential to do that
I have to do it, I have no choice
- Am I late? - No, I'm early
- I made you some coffee one sweet ***, right? - Right!
Thank you
Can I have a stamp for this?
that's the New York Times schoolarship! you haven't mailed it yet?
- When is the dead line? - Tomorrow
I gave you that 4 months ago, Liz! What were you waiting for?
for today, for me to turn 18
it's your birthday?
Happy birthday!
but I don't think that an age required
No, Thank you
but now I can tell the truth, that I was a homeless and no one could come and take me away
Lisa
Liz!
Yes
What are you doing here?
I have this interview I am a finalist for a big New York times scholarship
But, I don't have anything to wear
you want my cloth?
Well, nothing fancy it's just .. something I can put over this
Thank you
Mom sold my coat once I couldn't go to school
I remember
I cried, I love going to school so much
you never went to school
how did they gave you the scholarship?
because I'm homeless and I'm doing really well in school now
You are not a homeless, Liz, you could stay here
No I couldn't, you know that ...
Grandpap hates you !!
I'm going blind
like Mom
I'm scared
Liz!
Liz, they kicked me out of the group home with all my stuff
They can't kick you out you are not 18 years
then group with me in Brooklin, I don't wan to go to Brooklin! You have to help me!
I have an interview
- No! Liz! - I have to!
- You can not leave - I have to
Chris!
just let me go through this one thing, and then you can go back and go to school with me
I don't want to go to school! I don't belong there, and either do you
Yes, I do
you think they like people like us into harvard
The world moves, you just a spec., it can all happen without you
situations are not conducive to what you want for yourself
someone else's needs someone else's plat is going to be stronger than yours is
I think people just get frustrated with how harsh life can be
So they spend their time ** on that frustrations and calling it anger
keeping their eyes shut from the wholes situation
to all the little tiny things that have come together to make it what it is?
because I was turn so inward by my Mom and Dad, I got a chance to see how
all the litle tiny things come together to make the final product
so, I was never ** to wonder why this or why that
I knew why
not that I was happy about it, in fact I was really sad about it most of the time
but I was very accepting
I was very accepting
I just always knew that I needed to get out
Is there anything else you would like to tell us?
I loved my mother,
so much .. I mean
She was a drug addict, was an alcholic
she was legally blind she was schizophrenic
But ..
I never forget that .. she did love me
even if she did,
All the time,
All the time ...
I hope you all know how much I really need this
how I can't go to college or anything without it
she earned a 95 average and finished at the top of her class of 150
she did alot completly 4 years high school in 2
she did it while homeless
her mother is dead her father is a drug addict and living in shelters
and anyway I can describe this can't do justice to her accomplishments
So, I'll just introduce to you our sixths New York time schoolarship winner
Liz Murray
everything is changed,
my life will never be the same
and I don't know what else to say except for thank you thank you very much
Liz! Liz, how did you do this?
How could I not do it .. my parents showed me what the alternative was
Didn't you even feel sorry for yourself
Sorry?
Sleeping in the subway, eating out of dumpsters
that had always been my life
I really .. I feel that I get lucky because any sensive security
awas pulled out from under so I was forced to look forward
I had to , there was no going back
And I reached the point I just thought: Alrigth,
I'm gonna work as hard as I possibly can and see what happens
And .. now I'm going to college
and the New York Times is going to pay
So you were lucky ... but is there anything you change if you were able?
Yes
I'd give it back
All of it
If I could have my family back
I got into harvard,
I got a job at the New York Times,
I got an apartment
I don't have to carry my whole life with me any more
I don't have to carry my whole life with me
but I do ...
Every one I have known, Everything I have done
pieces chip off, I forget the little things
I had still hard to carry
alone
so that's why I told you so,
That's why I've told you my story
Now I can lay that burden down, put it dressed AND...
and I can go on
Hi, Mom
Liz's father suffering from AIDS and lives in his apartment
Chris has a steady job and remained good friends with liz
Liz pays the rent of her apartment with the money she earned from making confrences
Liz has left Harvard in the spring of 2003. she continued her studies at college. She is convinced that her path will come by itself.
The End! For more wonderful movies, please visit en580.taobao.com