Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Calm down, your escort is right outside.
Sit down.
Sit. I said sit.
She tells us that you are her niece.
Is that correct? Are you her niece?
Where is your mother?
Do you know?
Look at me!
Do you understand me?
If you are from Budapest,
state the name and street number
of your former place of residence.
There's a pen and paper.
If you prefer not to speak to us,
write it down with your family name,
and we will try and confirm it.
Is it possible the woman outside
is not related to you,
but is simply an ally you made
along the way who is trying to help you?
You bear little resemblance
to one another.
We will not punish her for trying
to help an innocent young woman.
We want to help you get home.
Your true home.
László, I am alive.
Come on! Documents.
Attila tells me that you, too, are alive
and en route to him from Bremerhaven.
Rejoice!
I cried out in ecstasy
to have news of you.
Where are my things?
- What?
- Screw you!
It is not amusing to me!
Stop it! Don't look at me that way,
old man!
- It's right behind you.
- Where is my luggage?
It's tucked there under the mattress!
Now come on!
Hurry, László,
or we'll be last in the queue.
Zsófia is with me, though she is frail,
strange, and quite ill.
We anxiously await
our being repatriated,
but recently, she has not been herself,
which has, in turn, roused unnecessary
suspicions with local officials.
Fortunately, a few Soviet boys
have taken a liking to us.
They pity your poor niece in particular,
who has grown fuller, even lovelier,
since you last set eyes on her.
These lonesome young servicemen
are ostensibly entranced
by such a radiant creature's
commitment to absolute silence.
The Soviets have helped us relocate
to a nearby shelter
for displaced persons in Vas.
They encourage us
to "enjoy our freedoms",
but I am reminded of Goethe.
"None are more hopelessly enslaved
than those
who falsely believe themselves free!"
I make no mistake,
we are not yet free.
Come on already.
You, like myself, must be envisioning
so many terribly awful, awful things,
but it is better that your thoughts
do not get the best of you.
It is neither better nor worse
than you might imagine.
I have kept myself mostly to myself.
More importantly,
I have defended Zsófia
from unwanted advances.
Below is the address
I am told for mail in Vas.
Please write to me at once
when you have received this.
I am certain now
there is nothing left for us here.
Look at that!
- What did I tell you?!
- Yes!
Go to America and I will follow you.
Faithfully, Erzsébet.
Fuck her already!
Shut up.
Shut your mouth!
I'll see you.
Take care.
What did you say?
I have a letter from her.
Your Erzsébet is alive
and she is with little Zsófia.
Yes?
Thank you.
Gentile?
László, I am alive.
Attila tells me that you, too, are alive
and en route to him from Bremerhaven.
Rejoice!
I cried out in ecstasy
to have news of you...
- Good morning.
On the 29th of November, 1947,
the United Nations General Assembly
passed a resolution
calling for the establishment
of a Jewish state in Eretz Yisrael.
The General Assembly required
the inhabitants of Eretz Yisrael
to take such steps
as were necessary on their part
for the implementation
of that resolution.
This recognition by the United Nations
of the right of the Jewish people
to establish their state is irrevocable.
This right is the natural right
of the Jewish people
to be masters of their own fate,
like all other nations,
in their own sovereign state.
Accordingly we,
members of the people's council,
representatives of the Jewish
community of Eretz Yisrael
and of the Zionist Movement,
are here assembled
on the day of the termination
of the British mandate
over Eretz Yisrael.
And by virtue of our natural
and historic right,
and on the basis of the resolution
of the United Nations General Assembly,
hereby declare the establishment
of a Jewish state in Eretz Yisrael,
to be known as the State of Israel.
Come. Come.
What is it?
I take you into my home,
into my place of business,
and this is how you thank me?
Erzsébet,
I can be reached by mail
at a new address...
I wait for you. I wait and wait.
Do you need money?
What do you need?
Yours, László.
What? What?
You're welcome.
Erzsébet, I have become acquainted
with an influential American attorney
who says he can help you
and Zsófia with your situation.
Is there somewhere
we might find a photograph
of you and Zsófia pictured together?
Anything linking her to you?
I have reached out to colleagues
who sometimes attended parties
at the house.
I am waiting on return.
Whomever comes to mind, write to them
and explain how urgent this is.
Anything tying her to you,
and you to me,
can be of great assistance
to Mr Hoffman.
I have enclosed a list of items and
information requested by his office.
Please fill out what you can
of these documents
and return these originals
to me at once.
Here: some good fortune
may have fallen upon me.
In an unexpected turn of events,
I have been offered an intriguing
opportunity, a second chance.
I can feel you nearer to me now
than ever before.
Your love, László.
László!
It has taken some months to obtain
the items which Mr Hoffman requested
since receiving your letter.
I was at a loss at first,
but suddenly thought to contact our
upstairs neighbour in Buda, Mrs Horváth!
She was able to provide me
with several family photographs
that clearly picture you,
myself, and Zsófia
with her mother
on our wedding day.
The poor dear thought us dead
all these years,
so had kept them
on her mantelpiece in memoriam.
Zsófia could have only been
nine years of age at the time,
but her face and expression
are unmistakable.
I have included all but one
in case this letter
does not reach you.
I will keep it near my breast,
our family tree against my heart.
László,
does this mean
we might meet again soon?
Yours, Erzsébet.
What's happened?
I'm sorry I didn't tell you.
What happened?
It might not be permanent.
What happened? Did someone hurt you?
It's osteoporosis from the famine.
I'll dye my hair. I know it's ugly.
Where's Attila?
Zsófia, dear.
I'm sorry for the toys.
I remembered you as a little girl.
Look at your mother.
My sister was beautiful, wasn't she?
Are you angry?
Are you angry with me
for not telling you about my condition?
You can touch me.
Oh, my God!
Fuck!
I'm proud of you.
Make love to me tonight.
Don't go near him, Zsófia.
Oh, my God!
Fuck.
Fuck!
Damn it all to hell!
Hello, László, my friend!
Hello, Orazio.
I will take a coffee and we can go.
You are tough, Mr László, you know?
There aren't many people I see
anymore from before the war.
I'm not surprised to see you, though.
Some people, you just knew
somehow they would be all right.
Because you are stubborn.
And so am I.
I will never leave this place.
Because you are stubborn.
And so am I.
I will never leave this place.
I have left only once in 20 years
to go to Giulino, Azzano,
to beat the corpse of Mussolini
with my own hands.
Those of us here, my colleagues,
we are anarchists.
We were part of the Resistance.
No one knows the quarries like us.
We fought and captured
many members
of the National Republican Army.
We trapped them in these caves.
And we dropped
these very same stones on them.
The channelling here
will be done in one month.
If you like it, we can have it fixed
and ready for you in April.
We like it.
Hey! Come, come.
This is my great old friend.
Good evening.
My dearest Zsófia! Mazel tov!
She is so beautiful.
Your spitting image!
Don't be mad,
but your Uncle László insisted
I enclose a few banknotes
for you and Binyamin.
We hope he won't be offended,
and that it's not too difficult
to change these
into the local currency.
Here, I am so alone.
Perhaps more alone
than I have ever been.
Your uncle closed a door to me.
The man I married is inside,
but the lock's combination
I cannot decipher...
Your uncle no longer attends synagogue.
He prefers to roam obsessively
through the corridors
of his construction in Doylestown.
There, at last, much progress
has been made,
yet he seems no more content
than on the day the Institute
first broke ground.
I suppose that inside,
he worships at the altar
of only himself.
Tell me how you are.
How you really are.
All our love and warmth
to the three of you.
Erzsébet.
I love you.
Yes.
More.