Watch your step.
All Pulsar Four mining personnel
report to the resource expedition
office, level seven.
Not on a four-hour layover.
Operator. Can I help you?
Phone home. Phone home.
Please deposit $6 million
for the first 3 minutes.
All lunar passengers,
please check with Passenger
Processing, level three.
That's us.
Can Scraps sit with us, Dad?
We'll check, Jimmy.
The moon's a long way.
- Can I help you folks?
- Thanks.
Is that your puppy, son?
Yeah. Scraps is going
to the moon with us.
No dogs are allowed
on the shuttle.
I'm afraid Scraps
will have to be shot.
He shot him! He shot Scraps!
Just joking!
Blanks. See? Scraps is fine.
I says, "Whenever
you're in town, call me."
Dinner in first class will be
bean sprouts and broccoli.
Fine.
- Chanting or non-chanting?
- Chanting, please.
Don't worry about
the Viatex account.
We have a buy-or-sell option.
- Watch their legal people, Bob.
- Will do.
And Bob... feed the cats.
Will do.
I'm sorry, ma'am,
you're only allowed one carry-on.
All right.
Bye-bye. Thank you.
For the best computer
officer on the lunar mission.
Simon, you shouldn't have!
I guess I'm a pretty lucky woman.
Women and the space program
have come far,
but after the wedding, no more
complicated computers for my girl.
They've offered me a chance
to head the computer division.
You'll head up the baby division
for Mr and Mrs Simon Kurtz.
That's an order, Lieutenant.
Where's the passenger processing
lounge for the lunar shuttle?
Concourse lounge "C", fourth level.
- Thanks.
- Next.
How long is my parking valid?
- Two hours.
- Thank you.
- What's the fastest animal on earth?
- The cheetah. Next?
- Should I fake my orgasms?
- Yes.
Thank you.
This is mission control.
We have clearance on two-niner
for shuttle pre-launch checks.
You are clear to descend to 15,000
and hold until further notice.
A high-pressure front's
moving over Denver.
56 in the valley,
72 at the beaches.
The Supremes hit
the top of the charts
with this really
big one, Baby Love.
I have a collect call
for Michael Reese from his mother.
This is only
part of our mission control.
Right here we have re-entry
for all Earth-orbit ships.
That's handled by the computers
and simulated by these video units.
Now if you'll step this way...
Phoenix 6, you're programmed
on R two-niner and computer locked.
Computer lock acknowledged.
Over and out.
Well, gentlemen,
looks like it's out of our hands now.
- Janet, they need you in control.
- Right.
Shit!
Commissioner, we both know
that shuttle needs
another month of pre-launch testing.
Forget it, Bud.
- But Commissioner...
- I said forget it.
Mayflower is the first lunar shuttle
flying from a commercial terminal,
and the boys on the board
want her on schedule!
What do they know about safety?
The boys on the board
are under heavy pressure
from the boys downtown.
I'll be the one they crucify
if that shuttle screws up.
Not so fast. Frisk her!
These navigational charts seem OK.
I don't think
there'll be any problem.
Hey, why the long face?
I'm still worried
about the shuttle.
You saw Ted's report,
and he is the program's top pilot.
Was the program's top test pilot
until his mental breakdown.
Sweetheart, the opinion of a madman
doesn't impress me or anyone else.
The trial proved that.
Ted Striker's part of your past.
It's for your own good.
Please, may I have this bedpan?
I need it. I'll bring it right back.
Please, Mr Goldberg!
The company's doing pretty well.
The figures for the last quarter
show a 40% increase.
Visiting hours are over.
Doctor, will my brother be able
to come home to the farm soon?
It's hard to say.
He still thinks he's an accountant.
You must believe me...
invest in money markets!
And how are we this evening, Ted?
All right, I guess.
You can take off now.
We'll finish up tomorrow.
I thought you might like a paper.
Thanks.
- My God!
- What's wrong?
They're launching the XR-2300!
Know what that is?
The muffler bracket
for a '79 Pinto?
No. That's the XR-2200.
The 2300 is the lunar shuttle.
It's got to be stopped!
Don't you understand?
They put me here
to keep me out of the way.
The first step to mental hygiene
is admitting you're sick.
Now listen, Ted.
Our only concern is your condition.
Your alpha scan reading
seems to be leveling off.
Is that a good sign?
It does the job.
I can't stand it!
I refuse to pay $2,000 a day
for a hospital bed, rotten food,
horrible nurses, rotten doctors!
What's his problem?
The man's obviously crazy.
By the way,
I spoke to Elaine this morning.
Elaine? Was she here?
No. She called and asked me to
tell you that she's marrying Simon.
Tell me the whole story
from the beginning.
After all, that's why I'm here.
There's really nothing to tell.
My story is no different
than anyone else's story.
I'm sure you've heard it
a thousand times.
It all started during the war.
I lost most of my squadron
over Macho Grande.
Planes, too.
You're too low...
After the war, I couldn't go near
anything with a pair of wings.
Until fate dropped me in the seat
of a 767 into Chicago with no crew.
It's funny how fate can
make heroes out of cowards.
After that came the job offers,
then the publicity...
...then the crash and the trial.
Order! Order!
Now this.
Well, there's more, but I'm sure
you'd all be bored by it.
No, no, no. Continue.
This is mission control,
in "T" minus one hour, 43 minutes
ground crew report to stations.
This is Mayflower 1,
get me the sarge!
Hey, Sarge! Hold up!
Here it is.
Give me that radio.
Kruger, this is the sarge.
There's no way this wire passed
inspection without Simon Kurtz' OK.
What the hell's going on?
Patch up the damage.
Get that ship ready to fly.
- That's an order, mister!
- You got it, mister,
but you tell your boys on the board
that this thing stinks of kickback.
You heard it, boys.
What do you say?
Screw him!
Ted Striker was right
when he test-piloted that sucker,
and what did he get
for telling the truth?
A one-way ticket to the funny farm!
We don't have much time. Let's move.
Thank you.
May I help you?
Yes. I'd like this Time and Newsweek
and a Lifesaver and...
the second time bomb
on the right, please.
Certainly.
- There.
- Thank you.
- Will there be anything else, sir?
- No.
Hi, Grandma Rudy!
How good to see you!
Just a few more hours to lift-off.
I'm very excited, Simon.
- Guess this is a first for you.
- No. I've been excited before.
Ted, what are you doing here?
- Are you on that shuttle?
- Both of us.
When we return,
we're getting married.
Elaine, it has to be stopped.
Ted, the invitations
have already gone out.
No, the flight must be stopped.
Come on, sweetheart.
Simon, give me a moment
with Ted alone.
All right. You've got
exactly 10 minutes till we board.
I'd watch my step if I were you.
Ted, this whole thing's
all in your mind.
You should have never
left the hospital.
Elaine, whatever happened to us?
Ted, I guess I'll always love you,
but I need Simon.
He's stable and a good provider,
and I need that.
He doesn't run away
from every challenge.
He doesn't let every little setback
eat him up inside.
Now goodbye, Ted.
Gentlemen, I'd like you
to meet your captain... Captain Oveur.
Gentlemen, welcome aboard.
Your navigator, Mr Unger
and first officer, Mr Dunn.
- Unger.
- Oveur.
- Dunn.
Gentlemen, let's get to work.
Unger, didn't you serve under Oveur
in the air force?
Not directly. Technically, Dunn was
under Oveur, and I was under Dunn.
So, Dunn, you were...
under Oveur and over Unger.
That's right. Dunn was over Unger,
and I was over Dunn.
See? Dunn and I were under Oveur,
even though I was under Dunn.
Dunn was over Unger,
and I was over Dunn.
Do you have any tickets
for the shuttle?
There haven't been any available
seats for weeks now, sir.
What you want?
I got pairs and singles!
Check 'em out, y'all!
400-dollar lunar shuttle tickets.
Smokin'... what you want?
Lunar shuttle tickets - $400.
I got smokin', non-smokin',
first class, coach, economy,
by the aisle, by the window.
Take it easy, my man.
Lunar shuttle tickets!
Hi. Thank you.
Three of you to the left.
- Hi. Can I take your case?
- No.
- Howdy, girl.
- Hello.
Keep that thing moving.
- How's it going?
- Everything's fine, Sarge.
Well, I'll be a monkey's uncle!
Ted Striker.
Jack, I got a bad feeling in my gut
about this mission.
Number two checks.
What's happenin', bro?
Atmosphere control OK.
Atmosphere control... check.
- Antigravity check.
- All right.
- Checks out in positive mode, sir.
- Check.
- Checks out in negative mode, sir.
Neutral balance seems all right, sir.
- Good. That should do it.
- Antigravity off, sir.
Hope this weather
doesn't give us a problem.
Mr Dunn,
what's your temperature reading?
98.6, sir.
That sounds normal.
Sweetheart, you should have gone
before we got on the plane.
Sir, you're in the wrong seat.
That's mine.
Elaine, wait. Listen to me.
Why can't you
just let me live my life?
It's not just your life.
It's everyone on board this ship!
We must stop this flight.
Ted, we're taking off.
Why don't you trust me any more?
You're not the man you were.
You shouldn't have left the hospital.
Please, take your seat.
Well, it looks like
that weather's starting to clear.
Satellite photos look clear
over Wyoming and Connecticut.
- We just heard from Detroit.
- What about Reno and Buffalo?
Clear,
but check the New Jersey suburbs.
Mayflower 1, you're clear on
two-niner to taxi to launch position.
Roger. Ready to taxi. Over.
"T" minus 30 seconds and counting...
Mark "T" minus 20 seconds.
Ignition.
"T" minus 9...
8... 7...
6... 5...
4... 3...
2... 1...
You have lift-off, Mayflower 1!
Acknowledge.
Roger, Control. This is Mayflower 1 -
acknowledge lift-off.
We'll be serving breakfast
in a few minutes.
- Will all of you be eating?
- Yes, thanks.
Jimmy, when you're finished, you can
come up front and see the cockpit.
Gee, that'll be neat.
I'm glad they let
Scraps ride with us.
Scraps will love the moon.
Will things be much different
on the moon?
It'll be terrific - a whole
new world, new kids to play with...
So no more headlines
about the rape trial?
How many kids get a chance
to live on another planet?
No kids yelling, "Your old man's
a psychopathic sex pervert"?
So I made a mistake.
Anyway, she was asking for it.
They're all asking for it
all the time!
Dad never slaps me around
at home. It must be his coffee.
No. I've been serving Dad decaf.
Maybe he's just an asshole.
You know, dear? This reminds me of
the first train trip we ever took -
out to your mother's
house, remember?
How could I forget?
You were so nervous
about meeting my mama.
And I declare,
you were pacing the aisle
all the way from St Louis
to Sioux Falls.
And remember
when we hopped in the family car
and drove all the way to Woodstock?
That was a time.
And you got that bad acid
and didn't come down for two weeks.
You kept telling everyone
that you were Jesus Christ,
and then you jumped off a roof
'cause you thought you could fly.
- What a bummer.
- No shit.
You look a little green.
Are you all right, young man?
You know, some people get airsick,
but I never do.
I must have an iron constitution.
- I'm all right.
- Good.
I guess what's really bothering me
is my whole life.
I really can't figure
where Elaine and I went wrong.
You know what it's like
when two people share the same space.
Something happens.
Your vibes go out of synch.
I thought we shared
a very special kind of love.
I'm not sure
I know what love is any more.
I guess it all started at the trial.
They had to cover up for the crash,
so they made me the scapegoat.
I had no one to turn to.
I'm sure you've had
the same experience yourself.
I couldn't believe
what was happening to me.
I think it's important
we establish a few facts
so these people can make
a fair decision.
First, were you not the chief test
pilot for the lunar shuttle XR-2300?
Yes.
On the fifth of October this year,
that shuttle crash-landed.
Were you not the pilot
on that flight?
Yes, but I wasn't...
And, Mr Striker, is it not true
that that crash was a direct result
of your incompetence?
No! The problem was with that ship,
not with me.
The wiring was shorting out
under high temperatures.
That thing was a flying deathtrap.
The fact is, gentlemen, nothing
serious was wrong with that ship.
Ted Striker folded up
on the approach.
That's a lie!
Order! Order!
On March 5, 1980, flight 209 into
Chicago lost its crew in midair.
And on that fateful night,
Ted Striker saved that plane.
I'd like to call one of the
passengers from that flight,
if it pleases the court.
Do you swear on the Constitution
to tell the whole truth,
and nothing but?
I do.
Would you describe, in your own
words, what happened that night?
Mr. Striker performed exceptionally
The passengers were very concerned
The pilots were incapacitated
So Mr. Striker took control
And landed that plane safely
Golly!
I know I wouldn't be alive today
if it wasn't for Mr Striker.
I find it difficult even now to think
about that night over Chicago.
Please try, Mrs Hammen.
It's very important.
Well...
we lost the crew...
and...
the food poisoning
made us all very ill.
I lost control. We all did.
And then... the bad weather...
And the lightning...
I've got to get out of here!
Calm down! Get a hold of yourself!
Stewardess, please,
let me handle this.
I've got to get out!
Calm down. Now get back to your seat.
Calm down! Get a hold of yourself!
Doctor, you're wanted on the phone.
Everything's going to be all right.
Now just calm down.
I've got to get out of here!
This is very important!
Let the court handle this!
Will you please control yourself?
Bailiff, Valium.
I flew with Striker during the war.
I'll never forget the night
we bombed Macho Grande.
Striker was a squadron leader.
He brought us in low,
but he couldn't handle it.
Buddy couldn't handle it.
Was Buddy in your crew?
Buddy was the bombardier,
but Striker couldn't handle it.
- And he went to pieces.
- Andy went to pieces?
Andy was the navigator.
Buddy went to pieces.
- It was awful, how he came unglued.
- Howie came unglued?
No, Howie was the best tail gunner
in the outfit. Buddy came unglued.
- And he bailed out?
- No! Andy hung tough. Buddy bailed.
How we survived was a miracle.
Then Howie survived.
No. Afraid not.
We lost Howie the next day.
Over Macho Grande?
No. I don't think
I'll ever get over Macho Grande.
Those wounds run... pretty deep.
Ted and I were very close once.
We had the kind of relationship
where we laughed and laughed
and laughed all the time.
Do you know what that's like?
Yes. Yes, I do.
Then things started to come apart.
He was obsessed with that shuttle.
He started to talk about it
all the time, even at night in bed,
and I guess that's when
the real problems started.
Please elaborate.
Well...
at first...
sex between us
was a wonderful experience -
the way he touched me...
He was so gentle.
He'd unbutton my blouse...
and then...
We drifted apart.
I'm sorry. I can't go on.
At the request of this court,
Mr Striker has undergone
a psychiatric examination.
The court calls Dr Franklin Stone.
Can you give your impression
of Mr Striker?
I don't do impressions.
My training is in psychiatry.
Of course.
In your opinion, Doctor, was Ted
Striker competent to fly the shuttle?
The defendant suffers
from chronic psychological stress
and in a pressure situation
can snap like that.
- Like that?
- That's it.
He's a danger to himself and others,
and needs treatment.
Mr Striker.
This court recommends that
you be confined to an institution
for treatment until such time as you
are deemed fit to re-enter society.
But I was framed!
I'm not guilty!
That ship did have faulty wiring!
Would you hold for a picture?
I'm not guilty!
A photo for the Daily News?
Of course.
Thanks, counselor.
Picture.
It's for Ted's own good, Elaine.
I thought I was right
and they were wrong.
Now I'm not sure
of anything any more.
There's more to the story, but
you probably heard enough already.
I don't want to go on forever...
Captain, I'm picking up
an overheat in the computer core.
- How serious is it, Mr Dunn?
- I can't tell, sir.
You can tell me. I'm the captain.
I can't localize it, but
it's definitely in the computer core.
- Elaine, run a computer check.
- Yes, sir.
Voice interface.
There's an overheat in the core.
Please analyze.
There is no apparent overheat.
Yes, there is, Rok.
We read a core overheat.
Repeat analysis.
Analysis confirmed.
All systems compute positive.
Well, not from where
I'm sitting, they don't.
Look, Elaine,
cut the "not where I'm sitting" shit.
It must be a human error.
Captain, I think
we have a computer foul-up.
- I see.
- What do you recommend, Captain?
Run it through the computer.
- I already have!
- Good.
Just to be safe
should I check the rear data banks?
- No. You check the rear data banks.
- Yes, sir.
Sir, you should put that case
in the compartment above your head.
- I'll keep it with me.
- I'll help if you can't get it up.
I said I'll keep it with me.
- Ted, please.
- Elaine, listen...
- We can't do this.
- We have to go back.
I understand. We had
something special, but it's over.
- We can't go back.
- This flight has to go back.
That wiring could blow any second.
The problem's in your mind,
like always.
- Then you do think I'm insane.
- I'd never use that word.
- What word would you use?
- The word is sick, Ted.
Goodbye.
Sir, that overheat
is getting worse.
I'd better get back into the core
and check it out.
- I'd rather you check it out.
- Right...
Sir, we're carrying
emergency fuel back there.
You'd better go, too.
I'll fly the ship.
- Be careful.
- Yes, sir.
Captain, do you mind if Jimmy here
takes a look around?
Of course not, Mary.
Come on in, Jimmy. Hi there.
Boy, there's a lot
of neat stuff in here.
This is the nerve center
of the whole ship.
That's a cute puppy.
What's his name?
Scraps.
- Can I hold him once?
- Yeah.
Come on, Scraps. I used to have
a puppy like this when I was a kid.
- You like to play ball with him?
- Yeah.
You like to have him
fetch a stick?
Yeah.
Of course you do.
Well, my goodness,
Scraps is a boy, isn't he?
Yeah.
Jimmy, do you like it
when Scraps holds onto your leg
and rubs up and down?
God help us. Look at this place.
Check the fuel drums,
I'll do the computer.
Jimmy, did you ever wonder
why dogs sniff each other?
Well, Captain, everything A-OK?
Yes, everything's fine. Right, Jimmy?
Yeah. Everything's real neat up here.
That's strange.
What's strange, Captain?
It's an asteroid field. But there's
nothing in this sector, unless...
- Unless what, Captain?
- Unless we're off course.
- Captain Oveur, Dunn here.
- Come in, Dunn. Over.
There's been a fire here, sir.
We're going to have to disconnect
the damaged systems.
Mr Unger is attempting
a manual shutdown right now.
What are you doing, Dave?
The computer has suffered
some bad damage.
This is highly irregular.
Right. Right.
I hope we can still control
Rok's higher brain function, sir.
Do what's necessary.
I'll go to manual on all systems.
Yes, sir, we will.
Jesus! Hang on!
I'll try to override Rok's circuit
and shut the door from here!
Holy shit!
- Did you see that?
- Excuse me?
There's two crewmen out there. Look.
I'm afraid there's nothing out there
but empty space.
I swear I...
The defendant suffers
from chronic psychological stress
and in a pressure situation
can snap just like that.
Maybe they were right about me.
My God. Maybe I am cracking up.
What's happening, Captain?
We're off course and computer-locked.
That fire in Rok's core played havoc
with the brain functions.
Mr Dunn and Mr Unger
were sucked out an air lock.
Both together?
Mr Dunn and Mr Unger
were sucked out an air lock.
Don't panic. Calm down, ladies.
Are there any other problems?
Captain, we've run out of coffee.
Damn! I've told them
a hundred times - store extra coffee!
Captain, what should we do
if the passengers start to panic?
This is the way we'll play it -
Mary, you're here
in case there's a full-cabin press.
Testa, cover Mary's weak side
in case she gets double-teamed.
Right!
Captain, I don't think
we have any alternatives.
I see. What do you think
our alternatives are?
To disconnect Rok's
higher brain function
without disturbing
his regulatory system.
That computer
has a self-defense mechanism.
You heard what happened
to the others.
I know. Sucked out.
Still, it's our only chance.
We could try it from here.
You get back and monitor
the regulatory unit.
- Right. Good luck, Captain.
- Don't worry about me.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please calm down.
Please, listen to me.
I want to tell you what's
going on with the ship.
Thank you.
We've been thrown
off course just a tad.
What's a tad?
Miss, what exactly is a tad?
In space terms,
that's about half a million miles.
That's interesting.
The bumps you feel are asteroids
smashing into the hull of the ship.
Also, we're flying
without a navigational system
and can't seem to change course.
Miss, are you telling us
absolutely everything?
Not exactly.
We're also out of coffee.
Listen to me! Your crew is in
complete control of the situation.
Trust me.
There's nothing to worry about!
You're right. They're off course
and heading straight for the sun.
I've seen enough, Bob.
Get me Steve McCroskey, and fast.
McCroskey hasn't handled
a tower since the strike.
Since Reagan fired the controllers,
he's been completely senile.
Yeah, but what about McCroskey?
- Pretty much the same as Reagan.
- I don't care. Get him.
Father, I've led such a sinful life.
I'm married with two kids, and there
were these girls at the company.
I got them pregnant,
so I stole from the company
to pay for the abortions...
God bless you.
Thank you, Father.
I've always loved you, darling,
but I have to tell you
I was unfaithful to you, just once.
I understand, darling.
Remember Jill, my first secretary?
Forgive me.
That's all right.
I knew about it all the time.
I was unfaithful, too.
I understand, darling.
Remember Susan,
your last receptionist?
I don't mean to sound forward.
I mean, I know I don't know you,
but...
I don't think
we're going to live through this,
and... I've... never...
been with a man before.
I know this really
isn't the place.
No, no. I understand.
Who turned off the...
What are you doing, Captain?
This is highly irregular.
- Get me some coffee, miss.
- Yes, sir.
And a quart of Geritol
and a ham on rye.
Welcome home, sir.
Here's the navigational charts, sir.
Get me radio contact
with that ship. Pronto.
Here's all the information
on the sun. That thing is hot!
Get Bud Kruger immediately.
And some ice.
Yes, sir.
Jacobs.
I want to know absolutely everything
that's happened up till now.
First the Earth cooled,
and then the dinosaurs came.
But they got too big,
so they died, and turned into oil.
Then the Arabs came
and bought Mercedes Benzes.
Prince Charles started wearing
Lady Di's clothes.
I couldn't believe it! He took
her best summer dress, put it on...
Things sure haven't changed.
Captain, I think we've got...
Captain Oveur, what's wrong?
What's wrong?
What are you trying to say?
One... One what? One word!
First word? First syllable?
Captain, I'm not very good at this.
10 words!
How to Succeed in Business
Without Really Trying.
What am I saying? Throat.
Throat. Sounds like choke.
Choke. You...
Oh, my God!
You were gassed by Rok?
I got it! I got it!
Simon, the Captain's
been gassed by Rok.
Simon, we're way off course.
You're right, Elaine.
We are off course.
- My God! The sun!
- What is it, Simon?
The fiery ball in our solar system,
but that's not important now.
We're headed right for it.
We've got to leave this ship.
That's foolish.
We have to change course.
We're computer-locked, and the manual
navigational system is down.
Ted was right all along.
What will I do?
My career will be ruined.
What about the careers
of everyone on this ship?
The lawyers, the architects,
the dental hygienists?
Forget about them.
We have to think of ourselves.
What happened to the man I thought
I loved? I'm going to get Ted.
Don't come apart on me now.
I don't mean to sound forward -
I mean, I know I don't know you,
but I don't think that we're going
to live through this.
And I've never been
with a man before.
I know that this
isn't the right place.
Until we get through,
our hands are tied. We need plans.
I'm busy right through Friday.
- Stinson.
- But how about lunch Saturday?
Have you contacted the families
of those on board?
They're outside now, sir.
They're not too happy.
Try and calm them down.
For God's sake, be diplomatic.
Give them the lead!
Ted, listen to me.
We've lost the crew,
and Simon's turned to jelly.
Ted, we need you.
Elaine, you were right about me.
I folded up over Macho Grande,
and I folded up on the test flight.
I crack under pressure
just like they said.
You overcame your drinking problem.
I know you can overcome this.
It's no use, Elaine.
I just can't do it.
Ted, you were right about this ship.
I don't know how to say this,
but maybe in this topsy-turvy world,
they should take all the "sane"
people and lock them up
and let all the psychopaths
out of the asylums to run the world.
No... on second thoughts,
that's a bad idea.
What I'm trying to say is that I was
wrong and I hope you forgive me,
because we need you in that cockpit
now more than ever.
There's some banged-up people
back there.
I'll need some fresh sheets, gauze,
and all the Vaseline you have.
- Ted, please!
- Right now.
- Are you the nurse?
- Yes. Take this.
The washroom's just down there
on the right.
I don't mean to sound forward.
I mean, I know I don't know you,
but I don't think we're going
to live through this,
and I've never been
with a man before.
I know this isn't the right place...
Simon, I...
This is mission control.
Do you read, Mayflower?
This is the Mayflower.
Come in, anyone.
Now we're making some headway.
We read you, Mayflower.
Identify yourself.
Well, this is Elaine Dickenson.
I'm 5'8", 123 pounds,
I have... brown hair, blue eyes.
I enjoy surfing, backgammon
and men who aren't afraid to cry.
Would somebody tell me what a woman
is doing in charge of that ship?
Maybe she's got her ship together.
But he smells so bad...
- Can I sit here, mister?
- Yeah, sure.
- Be careful with that.
- I will.
- Can I ask a question?
- What is it?
It's an interrogative statement
used to test knowledge.
But that's not important
right now, mister.
Is my dog Scraps going to make it?
I'm scared, mister.
Somebody has to do something.
Scraps is going to be fine, son.
You'll both be just fine.
Striker, you got to listen to me.
They forced me to cut corners.
- Get out of my way!
- You gotta help me...
- Elaine. You're all alone up here.
- Yes, I am.
- What's going on?
- There's no time to explain.
- I was wrong about you.
- We all make mistakes.
- I'll never make that mistake again.
- Forget about it.
We're not living in the past
or the present any more.
This is the future.
Don't worry.
Everything's going to be OK.
I love you, Ted.
Here it is. Elaine Dickenson,
ship's computer officer.
Jacobs, what have you got
on Elaine Dickenson?
I'm taller, a better dancer
and much more fun to be with.
Ted, I have the feeling
we've been through
this exact thing before.
Except this time
I know exactly what I'm doing.
You mean...?
That's right. We're at the mercy
of that computer.
Then these things
are totally useless.
Mayflower 1 calling mission control.
Do you read me?
A man. That's more like it. Identify
yourself and give me your position.
The name's Striker.
I'm sitting down and facing front.
- Why would you want to know that?
- Striker?
Striker!
- Ted Striker?
- That's right, McCroskey.
I may be in the cockpit,
but there's not much I can do.
We're at the mercy of the computer.
- McCroskey, do you read me?
- Striker?
- McCroskey!
- You're fading out. Come in.
- Damn! Lost them again.
- Could be sunspots.
Or your detergent.
Striker flew that 767 into Chicago
years ago without a crew.
Now, would somebody tell me
what he's doing up there?
The radio's gone dead.
Elaine, try the emergency phone.
Help us, please.
Thank you for calling the mission
control emergency line.
All our operators are busy,
so please stand by.
- Ted, it's a recording.
- Let me have that.
We said all our operators are busy,
so please stand by!
The boys downtown
are taking heat from Washington.
The president will want
an explanation.
Bud, let the boys in Washington
handle the president.
Sorry to pull you out of bed.
- Forget it. I was reading.
- What's the story?
It's about an man who catches this
fish, but that's not important now.
We've restored radio contract.
Good. We keep losing their radio.
McCroskey, give it to me straight.
What's it look like?
A radio? It's about so big,
green, lots of knobs.
I mean the situation.
What do your people think?
They're screwed.
They're dead.
Did I leave the iron on?
- Come in, Control.
- We read you. Come in.
McCroskey,
I got to be straight with you.
I don't think I can regain
control of this ship.
Striker, this is Steve McCroskey,
chief controller.
Now, I want you to listen good.
A few years ago I helped a young
pilot through a storm over Chicago.
He said he couldn't do it, too.
But when the going got tough,
that kid pulled it together.
He made all the big papers
and the Canadian Jewish News.
I don't know if that kid's
still got it,
but if he has, I know one thing...
if he was there now, he'd find
a way to turn that bucket around
and get out of there, pronto!
You gave the wrong speech.
I'm not your problem. It's the ship.
The fire made the computer
go berserk.
We've lost the crew,
and we're en route to the sun.
Now here's what you do. Stay calm,
keep an eye on those gauges.
Things are going to heat up. We'll
figure out a way around the computer.
What are we going to do?
We're going to have to
blow the computer.
Blow Rok?
- That's right.
- Ted, you can't do it.
What do you mean?
It has a self-defense mechanism.
I can't get around it.
We've already lost three men.
I don't want to lose you, too.
Then I guess it's
in God's hands now.
I'm Father O'Flanagan.
I'm a man of God.
And you must trust me when I say
it's likely we're all going to die.
Our top story tonight,
fire rages through downtown Buffalo.
Also in the news, lunar shuttle heads
for the sun and certain disaster.
Our top story tonight,
fire rages through downtown Tokyo.
Also in the news, American lunar
mission locked in death struggle.
A fire in downtown Moscow clears way
for a glorious new tractor factory.
And on the lighter side of the news,
hundreds of capitalists are soon
to perish in shuttle disaster.
If this country was run by vegetarian
women rather than flesh-eating men,
this whole space disaster
would never have happened.
We're working
to raise the consciousness
of the vegetarian minorities
with diet sensitivity training
so that people will be able
to deal...
The key is their computer.
Until we put that ship on manual,
there's nothing we can do.
- Get me that computer program.
- Yes, sir.
- Who's in charge here?
- McCroskey, Control.
- Hallick, Homicide.
- Jacobs, Sagittarius.
We've got our own problems,
so make it good.
A passenger has a bomb
and is suicidal.
Good one.
His name is Joe Salucci.
He was flying to Des Moines for
an operation for sexual impotence.
- The Des Moines Institute?
- You know it?
We're familiar with it.
Joe gave his wife this insurance
policy then got on the shuttle.
Mrs Salucci thinks he's suicidal.
We had the boys in psychiatry
do a profile on him.
- Yeah, that looks pretty bad.
- It's not his good side.
Now, blowing up a plane in space
leaves no traces for investigators.
This is a $1-million policy.
Wait a minute.
This is auto insurance!
That's why we're worried, gentlemen.
This clown's impotent,
suicidal and incredibly stupid.
And that spells trouble in my book.
Trouble.
Stinson,
get me those Mayflower plans.
You, clear that table in there.
I'll get the cards
and the bridge bits.
And somebody get me the sarge.
The heat in this cockpit
is getting unbearable.
You can fry an egg
on this control panel.
I don't know what'll to happen to us,
but I love you and I always will.
That might be the news
we've been waiting for.
- This is Mayflower 1.
- Striker, I got news for you.
You got a passenger aboard
named Joe Salucci.
- He's carrying a bomb.
- A bo...
No, not a "bo," a bomb.
Do you hear me, Striker?
What am I supposed to do now?
Get that bomb. I don't care how.
That's our top priority.
All the other problems can just wait.
As if we don't have
enough problems already.
You'd better fasten your seat belt.
Sir, you'll have to put
your cigarette out.
- Which passenger is Joe Salucci?
- 16-C. Why?
- He's carrying a bomb.
- A bo...!
No, not a "bo," a bomb.
Now, as discreetly as possible,
move the passengers into the lounge.
- We don't have a lounge.
- That's not important now.
- Get everyone away from that bomb.
- What should I say?
Anything. Just don't let Salucci
think we're on to him.
I'll do my best.
Attention,
ladies and gentlemen, please.
Would everybody move to the lounge
who is not carrying a bomb.
Don't move!
Mr Salucci,
they know about you back home.
Stay where you are!
You don't want to kill
all these innocent people.
- I don't care about them.
- Joe, listen to me. It's hopeless.
No one's ever gotten away
with a stunt like this before.
Joe, the insurance is worthless now.
I don't believe you.
Joe, you got to trust me.
No one will hurt you.
No one has to know
about your problem.
No one has to know you're impotent.
Don't say that word!
Scraps!
Nice going, Striker!
We're not out of the woods,
but you got rid of that bomb.
- Not exactly, McCroskey.
- What do you mean?
- The bomb's here beside me.
- There, beside you in the cockpit?
Striker...
What the hell
are you doing up there?
I got an idea that might just work.
It's a long shot.
I want to use the bomb
to blow the computer.
Striker, you've got to be crazy
to try a stunt like that.
Maybe, but it's
the only chance we've got.
When that bomb blows,
we'll lose our oxygen fast.
I'll have to get us out
as quick as I can.
- I'm taking her to 0.5 worp.
- 0.5 worp?
0.5 worp.
I test-piloted this shuttle.
I know exactly what it can do.
Striker, listen to me now
and listen good.
That thing is bound to come apart
at that speed, and that's no good.
It's got to be
in one piece when you land.
You know that that worp drive
has never been tested!
You're putting yourself and everybody
else on that ship in jeopardy!
- Over here!
- Contestant 38.
I'll take air shuttle disasters
for 40.
The answer is... the Mayflower.
Ted, what are you going to do?
Elaine, I'm going back there
with the bomb.
You're my hero.
The bomb.
Be careful.
Listen good. If you got any ideas,
now is the time. I want to hear them.
How about Hollywood Squares but
with kids? Gary Coleman could host.
- Simon just ejected.
- Sit down, Elaine.
If this works, we might make it.
- Simon was a fool to eject now.
- You mean...?
That's right. Premature ejection.
Striker, listen and listen good.
You'll be on lunar radio range
any second.
The next transmission
that you receive
will be from Buck Murdock
at Alpha Beta Base.
- Not BUCK Murdock?
- No. Buck MURdock.
Who's Buck Murdock, Ted?
A guy I flew with during the war.
He was with us that day
I led the raid over Macho Grande.
And he's still alive?
Striker, son...
we're all betting on you.
5-1 they all die.
8-5 the women and children make it.
6-4 they lose the crew.
0.5 worp... God help them.
Nobody's ever traveled
at that speed before.
Last spring,
we did Europe in nine days.
Then we went
to Bakersfield and Fresno.
No one goes to Fresno any more.
All communication lines are clear.
Ready to transfer to Buck Murdock
at Alpha Beta. Over.
Gentlemen...
I don't find it easy to talk
at a time like this,
but I got to say something
about that guy up there,
and I can sum it all up
in just one word... courage,
dedication, daring, pride, pluck,
spirit, grit, mettle
and... G-U-T-S. Guts!
Ted Striker's got more guts
in his little finger
than most of us have in our large
intestine, including the colon!
When we're ready, we'd like you
to remove your eyeglasses and shoes
and place your head
between the knees.
Between your own knees, Father.
We've blown the computer.
Elaine, you'd better
check the readout.
We're slowing down.
- Set course change.
- Set.
Compute.
Here goes.
Elaine, we hit 0.5 worp,
and everything seems OK.
We've got gravity control back.
Sorry.
Elaine, you'd better brace yourself.
This is faster than man
has ever traveled before.
In case some of you are wondering,
we are traveling
at half the speed of light.
Some of you might experience
a temporary metabolic change,
but there's nothing to worry about.
Thank you.
- Commander Murdock.
- What is it, Lieutenant?
The Mayflower's in trouble. She's
coming in hotter than a firecracker.
Their computer's down. They've lost
their crew. They're on manual.
- We'd better get to the tower.
- We have no tower.
- No tower?
- Just a bridge, sir.
Why the hell aren't I notified
about these things?
Lieutenant...
How would you handle this?
- We could try ignoring it.
- I see.
Pretend nothing has happened
and hope everything's all right
in the morning.
Just a thought, sir.
I've considered that.
Must be a better angle...
If they've lost their crew,
who's in control of that bucket?
Some guy by the name
of Ted Striker, sir.
Ted Striker.
- Do you know him?
- Never heard of him.
That's not exactly true.
We were like brothers.
We flew together during the war.
We were close, real close, until...
Until, sir?
Until that day over Macho Grande.
Over Macho Grande, sir?
I'll never get over Macho Grande.
Forget it, Lieutenant.
It wasn't a pretty picture.
What have you found?
These red lights keep moving
back and forth.
Aside from that, this thing seems
to have no function whatsoever.
It must have some function.
Why would the government put all
that money into a thing with lights?
Sir, these lights keep blinking
out of sequence.
What should we do about it?
Get them to blink in sequence.
- Rorshack, what do you got?
- What do you make of these?
That's a bird.
That's a horse with a hat on.
I pulled Striker's record. I don't
think you're going to like it.
It's worse than I thought.
They'll hit our atmosphere in three
minutes. How do you want to play it?
I want a 6-foot trench dug around
the base. Fill it with gasoline.
Get women and children
to the shelters.
Contact the Japanese ambassador.
Rorshack, get me a complete file
on everyone who's seen the Sound
Of Music more than four times.
On second thought, kill those orders.
Down scope.
Fate can play a strange
game sometimes, Lieutenant.
Fate, sir?
Striker wipes out his entire squadron
over Macho Grande,
and now those people's lives up there
are in his hands.
I guess irony can be
pretty ironic sometimes.
But it's his ship now.
He's the top dog,
the big man,
numero uno honcho,
the head cheese.
I just hope he has
the right stuff. Up scope.
We have radio contact.
Yes, I'll take care of it right away.
We've had some problems
with the ship.
If you're going to use the washroom,
please be careful.
I've been on my feet all day.
I sure could use a little breather.
Striker, this is Buck Murdock.
Do you read me?
I read you, Murdock.
Hope he's not still bitter
about what happened between us.
If not for those people,
I'd say let Striker go down
in a fiery mass of molten metal.
Striker, let's just pray
you don't screw up here
like you did over Macho Grande,
so just follow orders.
We've got you locked on beam.
Prepare to kill auxiliary engines.
Roger, Murdock.
All right, Striker,
kill the auxiliary engines.
Ted, the lever!
The lever just came off.
We're still at worp.
Try another lever.
There are no more levers,
just switches.
- No buttons?
- Just switches, lights and knobs.
Cut the bleeding-heart crap.
We've all got our switches, lights,
and knobs to deal with, Striker.
Down here,
there are hundreds and thousands
of blinking, beeping,
and flashing lights.
Blinking and beeping
and flashing.
They're flashing
and they're beeping.
I can't stand it any more!
They're blinking and beeping...
Sir! Sir, control yourself!
- Pull yourself together, sir!
- I'm all right.
All right, Striker.
You'll have to pull that
lever panel off. Do you understand?
Just rip it off.
Elaine, screwdriver.
OK, the panel's off.
Find a piece of metal
and shove it in.
A piece of metal?
Any piece of metal will do.
I'd give anything
to get some metal up there.
Here we are surrounded by metal,
and it's useless.
Might as well write them off.
Let's close up the bridge.
Let's get outta here.
Close it up. Lights out.
Where am I going to find
a piece of metal here?
In space? At this hour?
Will this work, Ted?
Thanks.
Hold it, Murdock.
I've got something that might work.
- Wait.
- A bobby pin.
What the hell's a man doing
with a bobby pin?
Lights on.
All right, Striker, if a bobby pin's
all you got, it'll have to do.
Shove it in there
and short that thing out.
Ted, it's working.
We're losing speed.
She feels like
she's going to break up.
- She's starting to shake.
- Starting to shake.
- She's starting to shimmy.
- Starting to shimmy.
She's starting to...
What? What's she starting to do?
What's she starting to do?
- Shudder, Ted?
- She's starting to shudder.
Starting to shudder.
- How bad is it?
- At least she's not cracking up.
She's beginning to crack up.
All right! Quiet!
We're monitoring you.
Keep her nose up. Don't fight her.
She's fighting me!
Ted, there's Alpha Beta.
We're going to have to come
in low to land.
- Is that difficult, Ted?
- Sure, it's difficult.
Coming in low is part
of every textbook approach.
It's just something
you have to do when you land.
Striker, we don't have much time,
but I'll say this...
you pull this off,
and a lot of people just might forget
that Macho Grande ever happened.
We'll get her down and down safe.
Before we go any further, there's
something important you should know.
Slow down!
The base is straight ahead.
They've just hooked into
a communications satellite,
and as we speak, our transmissions
are broadcast all over the world.
Billions of people are hanging
on our every word.
The eyes, ears, noses and throats
of every American are on you,
each one of them hoping and praying
that you could put
that ship down in one piece.
Ted, we're not stopping.
Now, Striker, start
by positioning your landing gear.
Lower your flaps.
Just keep her level.
There's no looking back.
Put on your horizon sensor
and level her off.
Ted, we're going back up.
Elaine, you'd better get ready
for this landing.
Keep up your stabilizers.
Don't lose control.
Now fire both jets
and hang on with both hands.
Both hands, damn it!
I'll say one thing,
you bring down that flying hunk
of junk, you're OK in my book.
Don't fight her, Striker.
Hold her up.
I hope you enjoyed your flight.
Fly Pan Universe again.
You gotta hit the center
of that strip or you're a dead duck.
Let's go home.
Yes, thank you
for flying Pan Universe.
Have a nice stay.
Shift those turbo chargers.
Now check the sensors.
Deploy your secondary boosters.
Is there a courtesy phone
around here?
Hello. We'd like you
to have this flower.
We're with the Church
of Lunar Consciousness.
We'd like you to have this flower.
Would you like to make a donation?
You're almost home.
Hold her.
Stay with her, Striker.
It takes a soft touch.
Don't let her get away
from you this time, Striker.
I don't know
if this is a good time to ask,
but could I get my briefcase back?
Striker!
You know what it's like
to laugh like that?
Yes. Yes, I do.
What did he get?
A one-way ticket to the funny farm.
- Des Moines Institute?
- Then you know it.
We're familiar with it.
Just don't come apart on me now.
Jimmy, do you like it
when Scraps holds your leg
and rubs up and down?
You were gassed by Rok?
I got it! I got it!
Your navigator Mr Unger.
First officer Mr Dunn.
Let's get to the tower.
We have no tower.
No tower?
Just a bridge, sir.
Why the hell aren't I notified
about these things?
How would you handle this?
I want to know absolutely everything
that's happened up till now.
Well, first the Earth cooled.
Then the dinosaurs came,
but they got fat and died
and turned into oil.
Then the Arabs came
and bought Mercedes Benzes.
Give the court
your impression of Mr Striker.
I don't do impressions.
My training is in psychiatry.
Do you swear to tell the truth,
so help you God?
The second time bomb on your right.
Certainly.
That's exactly what they'll
be expecting us to do.