I got it. I n that song...
Naughty Cal sings
about the scary octopus.
Look at Putman!
Putman is the octopus.
- Hello?
- Dave, just go play with
the curtains or something.
-o, no, no. We can't dismiss
that song. What about Carlos and Cliff?
What about the fact that
Hank was buried in the sand like
the buried treasure in the song?
All right,
so maybe the octopus...
is the way
the next person dies?
How do you kill someone
with an octopus?
Octopus spelled backward is "supotco."
Juan, isn't that Spanish for something?
"Supotco"? -o.
The word for shoe is Zapata.
- Hmm. Shoe.
- Am I the only one who thinks
his head looks like an octopus?
- Shh, shh, shh. Here he comes.
- What did I miss?
- Apparently, somebody's gonna
get killed by a shoe.
- Hmm.
Okay, you guys, instead of
focusing on the song, why don't
we go look for those boats?
- Good idea.
-Jenny, why don't you and I
go search together?
- Um--
- Putman.
- Why don't you and I
go and look for that boat?
- Are you daft?
I'm not going out in the jungle
with you and your bloody shiatsu.
If you're the killer,
you'll snap my neck like a twig.
All right, stick to the shore.
There's no reason to go in the jungle.
The boats are probably
gonna be covered with sticks.
Or branches.
Thanks much, officer.
Aren't you taking any weapons?
- I have all the weapons I need.
- [ Scoffs ]
Piss on that.
I'm taking a machete.
Thanks for doing this,
Lars.
You're very brave.
Just be careful, all right?
Good luck, Putman.
Better believe I'll be keeping
an eye on you, Mr. Miyagi.
[ Chopping]
I know you guys are probably
a little intimidated by
cooking for the whole resort...
but I think you're gonna get
a big kick out of it, okay?
- [Insect Buzzing]
- I bet you watched Yu and Kelly.
And most of it's just common sense.
Like right now...
I'm making my famous
Coconut Pete's Paella.
Can anyone guess
the secret ingredient?
Come on.
Coconut Pete's Paella?
The secret ingredient?
- Coconut... Pete's--
- Eh--
- Coconut?
- Yes, goddamn it! Yes!
Yes!
[ Yells ]
Jesus! You think Eddie Money
has to put up with this shit?
- [ Chopping]
- [ Yelling, Indistinct ]
Goddamn it!
Coconut Pete's Paella!
Jesus Christ.
What you think?
I think Pete's under
a lot of pressure.
I don't think
we can say for sure. God, I don't know.
- What are you doing?
- Uh, you know.
Just, uh, hanging around,
uh, looking through the window.
Calamari?
- Uh--
- It's an aphrodisiac, Juan.
[ Chuckles ]
- Oh. Oh!
- What's wrong?
You're not afraid of
a little octopus, are you?
[ Muffled ]
Thank you.
When you're done here...
I want you to come inside
and find me...
'cause I wanna
wrap my little tentacles around you.
[ Chuckles ]
Okay.
- [ Spits Food Out ]
- -o way.
Think about it, the octopus.
Look, she's a weird little chick,
I'll give you that.
But, look, it still
doesn't prove that she's the killer.
All right. There is only
one way to find out.
## [Romantic Latin ]
- Don't be nervous.
- [ Chuckles ]
Eh, I just want our first time
to be wonderful.
[Penelope Chuckles ]
So I would say that
if you're the killer...
just, you know,
just maybe don't kill me.
Or at least make it,
you know, painless.
With those moves of yours, I bet
you could put me down nice and easy.
-Just, zip, and I'm out, right?
- Look.
The whole reason we're hiding
in this closet is because
we think she's the killer.
- Oh.
- [Penelope ] I'm gonna bite you.
- [Juan ] Well, not too hard, I hope.
- I really like Juan.
I remember when we first met, I was
kinda like, "Who the fuck is this guy?
Some local guy
comin' down here and--"
[ Grunting ]
- Mmm.
- [ Neck Bones Cracking ]
[ Knuckles Cracking ]
- I haven't been entirely honest with you.
- You mean...
you don't really go
to the Oral Roberts?
Aah!
[ Sighs ]
I mean...
I just wanted to leave
my past behind me when I came here.
What the fuck are you,
a praying mantis woman?
- [ Yells ]
- I--
I've never been
to a place like this.
I mean, it's just so free.
Juan, I have spent
my whole life in a gym.
I just wanted to party
like everyone else.
My coach, Orgrav,
would kill me if he found out.
He would hunt me down
like a deranged lunatic.
- He's really scary some-
- Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
- You are a gymnast?
- Yeah.
Oh!
Gracias.
- [Penelope Moaning Loudly]
- [Juan Shouting In Spanish ]
[Juan ]
No tushie! No! No!
[ Both Moaning Loudly ]
[Juan Moaning Loudly]
- [ Penelope Screams ]
- [ Glass Shatters ]
I'll be right back.
[ Moans ]
Okay.
Eh, I'm still not sure.
I may need a few more hours
to pump her for information.
You asshole!
Now you're just trying to get laid.
How would you like to be stuffed in this
closet while I go out there and have sex?
- That is a great idea.
- [Toilet Flushes ]
Shh! Here she comes!
What exactly
are your intentions with Jenny?
You know, Put...
during the Sung Dynasty, there was
a great mystic-- Master Tsu Tong Po.
And he once said
something very wise:
"If you love something, set it free.
- If it comes back to you--"
- Fuck off.
It's a bloody Hallmark card.
Just trying to help you, man.
Well, she has taken
quite a fancy to you, hasn't she?
But I have some...
ammunition of my own.
What kind of man would I be if I sat
idly by while you stole her from me?
Do not underestimate me, Lars.
I know things you don't.
All right, Lars,
let's see what you got.
- [ Whispering ] Look what I found.
- [ Gasps ]
- Wow.
- Yeah. Shiny.
[ Creaking]
Hey.
[Dave ]
Oh! I knew it.
Oh, sick fuck.
Dear God in heaven.
[ Snoring ]
[Putman ]
Lars?
[Sword Unsheathes ]
Oh, dear God!
[ Whimpering ]
- [ Whimpering Continues ]
- [ Snarling ]
[ Grunts, Whimpers ]
-o!
- -o!
- [Squishing Sound]
- [ Grunts ]
- Huh?
- [Twig Snaps ]
- [ Gasps ]
- You!
- That's right, love.
Now take that stupid bag
off your head and give us a kiss.
- What?
- Advantage, Putman.
Hey--
[ Moans ]
- [ Moaning Continues ]
- [Lars ] Putman!
- [ Babbling ]
- Putman!
Putman! Wake up, Putman.
It's a dream! It's just a dream, Putman.
[ Gasping ]
## [Reggae ]
Farewell.
[ Laughing, Chattering ]
[Dave ] Keep it clean,
keep it clean, huh, mister?
That's a point!
!Mira! The boat!
[ Grunts ]
- Whoo!
-!Ay Mami! He found the fucking boat!
[Jenny]
Whoo!
Hang on to your kudos.
- Oh!
- She's not going anywhere.
- What did you do to the propeller, man?
- I didn't do anything.
This is the one
that was pulling Carlos.
Well, we could send a group
to paddle out to the mainland.
- We've got plenty of strong guys.
- No chance.
The riptide'll take you out to sea.
[ Chuckles ]
You'll be drinking your own urine
in less than 20 hours.
- Where's Putman?
- He's not here?
He left last night.
He ran off into the jungle.
- Oh, by "ran off"
do you mean "got killed by you"?
- Ah!
What, did you really think we
wouldn't notice Putman was gone
if you came back with a boat?
- Sam, that's ridiculous.
- Why is that ridiculous?
Hey, look. Putman freaked out
in the middle of the night
and took off into the jungle.
Look, we went into your room
last night, Lars.
Mark David Chapman over here
has a shrine to Pete.
- It's unbelievable!
- So I'm a fan.
A fan?
Man, you're a fucking loon!
Look, nobody here
was killed last night...
because Lars
was in the jungle killing Putman.
Hey, look. I could never hurt
another person, okay?
- I don't believe in violence.
- Mm-hmm.
I touch other people
to make them feel better.
Come on. I have an obligation
to get to the bottom of that--
-!Ay! You are the fucking Fun Police!
-Juan!
- What the hell--
- Come on, take it easy!
Quit your bickering!
Now, we just get through one more night,
the boat will be here tomorrow.
We'll be all right. So, come on,
everybody, let's just have a drink...
- and... mellow out.
- I don't want to mellow out, Pete!
I want to know what Lars's deal
is, huh? You come here and
everyone starts getting killed.
Hey, I don't have to tell you shit,
Fun Pig! You wanna Fun arrest me?
You get a Fun-fucking warrant!
Until then...
stay out of my
Fun-fucking face!
Come on!
Jenny, you know
I'm not the killer, right?
Look, Lars,
it's not so bad in here, okay?
- I'll bring you some magazine.
- Yeah.
You familiar
with the expression "sitting duck"?
-o.
- You guys, this is totally fucked up.
- Look, Jenny...
if he's the killer,
then we have him in this room.
And if not,
then at least we know it's not him.
[Bird Squawking]
Did it stink?
You bet it stunk.
Oh, shit!
[Laughs ]
- Hey, you guys gonna be
hanging around for a while?
- Totally.
We're just getting started.
Anyway, that's my mom for you.
[Laughs ]
Any of you guys
have a mother?
Free drinks,
whoever catches me!
- Whoo-hoo!
- [ Laughing, Chattering ]
- [ Water Splashing]
- [ Gasps ]
Shit.
Oh, God!
[ Whimpers, Groans ]
[ Muffled Scream ]
[ Snickers ]
Your prayers have been answered.
- You asshole!
- -ah, I'm not an asshole.
I'm just young, dumb and full--
What the fuck?
- What?
- Something just brushed
against my leg. What the-
-o, there's seriously
something down here.
- What?
- Oh, no, wait!
It's just my gigantic cock.
[ Snickers ]
[Man On TV]Amy's got
some fantastic advice for everybody.
- Oh, my God.
- So, you want to get it on?
Dirk, get outta the pool!
- Huh?
- I'm not kidding!
- [Jenny] Hurry!
- Hey, that's what I cal I service!
- Now! Get outta the pool!
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Dirk Yelling]
- [Jenny Screaming]
- [ Dirk Screaming]
- [ Shrieking ]
[ Electrical Breakers Banging]
Hey, help me!
[ Screams ]
Putman! You're alive!
- [ Panting, Sobbing ]
- You've got your arms around me, Jenny.
I can only assume this means
every other man on the island is dead.
We got to get outta here! Dirk's dead!
He just got electrocuted in the pool!
Really? What was the look on his face?
He must have screamed bloody murder.
[ Quivering ]
You're scaring me.
I just want to know if smoke
came out of his ears. Is that so wrong?
- [ Shudders, Screams ]
- Hey! Oh! Putman, where have you been?
Running in circles through
this bloody jungle, that's where.
Thank God you're not dead. Now,
we need to get over to Pete's cabana...
- and get that auxiliary generator.
- Wait, hang on!
If Dirk just got killed,
then Lars couldn't be the killer!
All right now, be on guard.
He might be a little cranky.
Lars! Lars, we're here!
Oh, do give it a rest, Jen.
[Jenny]
He couldn't have.
He's far too large.
We gotta find Pete.
- [Sam ] Pete!
- [ Creaking ]
Pete?
You in here, Pete?
Peter! We need the key
to the generator box.
- [Banging]
- [ All Gasp ]
[ Rattling ]
[ Rattling Continues ]
- [ Crashing]
- [ Yelling, Squealing ]
- Damn it!
- Isn't somebody going to get
the fuckin' door?
[Rattling]
- Who's there?
- Who's out there?
- [ All Gasp ]
- Hey!
I think there's a problem with the lights!
[ Zooming Sounds ]
- Right?
- [ Disgusted Sigh ]
All right,
Lars will probably come after us here.
We don't know for sure
that it is Lars.
And we don't know if he got out
or if someone else got in.
What is it with you and Lars?
I'm beginning to wonder
if you aren't in cahoots!
I mean, let's see.
You had sex with Rolo, and he's dead.
You and Cliff, right?
He's dead.
Give me a break. I screwed Juan
and Pete, and those guys aren't dead.
Bloody hell, Jen!
Am I the only one?
All right, let's get back to the case.
What we have to do--
Why don't you drop
the bullshit cop routine, okay, Sam?
Oh, just as soon as you drop the "I've
got nothing to hide" routine, Juan.
Let me guess. You were in here
looking for this letter from
the Encarnacion prison facility?
- What the fuck, man?
- Fuck, why you are doing this, man?
"Juan shows no signs
of the bizarre and horrible behavior...
"that brought him to this institution.
"We believe him to be
fully rehabilitated...
and will be an excellent
addition to your staff."
- What did you do, Juan?
- I did nothing, Jenny.
What the fuck did you do, man?
Costa Rican prison--
that's some hard-core anal action, man.
-Juan, we have to know.
- What did you do, Juan?
- [Dave ] What the fuck
did you do, man, huh?
-[Putman ] What did you do?
- Tell us!
- I did nothing! Huh?
- [Screaming]
- [Juan ] El Chupacabra!
- [Jenny] Hey!
- [Juan ] No!
- [ Sobs ]
- [Juan ] Oh! Oh, my God!
[ Exclaims In Spanish ]
- How could you do that?
- Wait, wait!
I did not do this. I 'm not a killer.
What the fuck, man?
Then, what is this?
You want to know what I did?
Huh?
You all want to know what I did?
Juan Castillo...
went to jail...
for having sex with a goat.
All right?
What you want me to say?
We lived on a farm!
And I got lonely!
[ Sobbing ]
We were-
Oh, we were just
a couple of stupid kids.
No, it wasn't Juan.
It was Dave...
wasn't it?
You hated him
for what he did to your parents.
You see,
what none of us did know...
indeed,
what none of us could know...
was that David's parents...
were trampled to death
at a Coconut Pete concert.
What the hell's
wrong with you, Putman?
Everyone knows Dave's parents
got killed at a Pete show.
- [ Mouths Words ]
- Yeah, way to bring up a sore subject.
- What? I -- What?
- [ Dave ] You think
I could have killed him?
He's my Uncle Petey.
You all saw him as...
a mellow island songster...
and a resort owner, but...
how many of you knew that he-
he was afraid of dogs...
and that his favorite spice
was rosemary?
How many of you knew that...
he was uncircumcised
and smelled of oranges? [ Sniffs ]
Yes, that's all
well and good, David.
But I'll bet hind to horses...
that you inherit the island.
- The island is already mine.
- What?
Pete signed it over to me last week.
He was going back on the-
on the road where he belonged.
He was forming a super group--
Billy Squier and Eddie Money!
Don Henley was gonna play drums!
Fuck, that would've been tight! Fuck.
He was gonna sell the island
to the navy for test bombing.
But I told him I-I could handle
the responsibility.
-[Bead Curtain Rustling]
- Lars.
-o! -o!
Pete.
[ Convulsive Sobs ]
Oh, my God! Pete!
[ Sobbing Continues ]
- [ Retches ]
- [ Clapping]
Bravo, Lars, bravo.
Very convincing.
- You fucker!
- Lars! -o, stop it! -o!
[ Overlapping Shouts ]
- Stop it!
- Hold it, hold it!
- Let's lock him up again.
- -o! -o! Stop it!
Stop it!
We're not locking anybody up!
We're all gonna stay together,
in one room!
Look, the boat
will be here tomorrow.
We'll go to the club,
gather all the guests...
and wait until the morning,
and we're going to do this together.
And we're gonna make it
through the night, okay?
Screw this, man!
I'm not going anywhere with Lars.
[Laughs ]
Well, I'm not going anywhere with Juan.
- [Dave ] Ooh!
- What kind of a man has sex with a goat?
- Hey, I used a condom.
- Oh.
You told me
they were against your religion.
[ Chuckles ]
Ehhh, you know, I need to find Peenalop.
- I am sure you all understand.
- [ Indignant Scoff]
You come anywhere near
my cabana, I'm taking your head off!.
Let's get outta here, Dave. Come on,
Dave, let's get outta here, man.
I don't think so.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Crazed Laughing ]
-Jenny, you're making
a most grievous mistake.
- [ Laughter Fading ]
I'm still not sure what happened...
with all that dodgy business
back in the jungle.
But I'm plagued by the dreams.
I believe I'm safer on my own.
- Well, that plan went to hell.
- [ Sighs ]
[ Lars ] Well, at least
they left us a torch. [ Laughs ]
Jenny? Jenny?
[ Chuckles ]
I believe I know where the generator is.
- [ Clicks ]
- [ Turntables Whirring ]
## [ Hip-hop ]
[ Cackling ]
Damn it!
He must have taken my swords.
I don't care if I have to carve a spear
out of bamboo, this asshole's--
- Shh, shh, listen.
- -o, I'm not gonna shush!
- I'm so sick of running from this--
- ## [ Continues ]
I thought
we didn't have any power.
- [Distorted]# Naughty Cal#
- Dave?
- # Bongo and Tokey
got tired of livin' on land#
- Dave. Dave?
# So the three amigos
took an undersea trip #
# Never were seen--#
[Jenny] God!
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Phonon Needle Scratching ]
- It's me! It's me! It's me!
[ Record Repeating ]
# Die, we're all gonna die #
- # We're all gonna die #
- Holy shit!
Oh, my God!
The lock's broken!
[ Gasps ]
Oh, my God! He's out there.
Quick, under the bed,
hurry. Come on!
- Go, go! Hurry!
- You'll never fit.
- Go, go, go, go, go!
- [ Whimpering ]
- [ Grunts ]
- Come on!
- Hurry! Come on!
- [ Grunting Continues ]
What are you doing?
Lars, what are you doing? Hurry!
- [ Chanting ]
- Lars, please!
- Come on!
- [ Chanting Continues ]
- Lars, come on! He's coming!
- [ Abdomen Squishing ]
- Oh, my God!
- [ Chanting Quickens ]
- He's coming!
- [ Rapid Chanting Continues ]
[ Chanting, Grunts ]
- Whew!
- Holy shit!
Is that how you escaped
out of that window?
Why don't you
just do that all the time?
Is that a fat joke?
What the hell?
- What the hell, Jenny?
- [Banging]
[ Gasps, Shuddering ]
[ Grunting ]
Putman! It was you?
- What? What was me?
- Step back, Putman!
Oh, you actually believe that
I'm the killer. Oh, that's a laugh.
Then what are you doing here?
Well, I just popped by to say--
- Uh--
- You perv.
Really, Jenny, there's a
perfectly reasonable explanation
for all this. I mean--
Well, you see, it seemed like
such a good final memento and--
Well, I -- You know how good I think
you look in red, and that little-
- No!
- Oh, dear God! Oh, dear God!
- Where's the key?
- I don't know.
Lock the door!
[ Gasps ]
The lock's broken!
Broken?
You've manacled me to my deathbed,
you Piccadilly whore!
- I'm so sorry.
- I could never stay mad at you, Jenny.
Quickly!
Give me the racket! Give me the balls!
- [Lars ] Go! Go! Yeah!
- Quickly! Run!
[Jenny]
Get out!
- [ Whimpering ]
- [ Clanging ]
Machete Phil! I knew it!
- [ Groans ]
- [ Gasps ] Oh, God!
- Oh--
- Oh, God!
- Go.
- N-No!
- Go, dear Jen. Go.
- No!
[ Sobs ]
Namaste.
Fuck off!.
- Come on.
- [ Groaning]
I'm sorry.
- [ Grunts ]
- [Ball Bouncing]
[ Groans ]
[Putman ]Ahhh, you!
I should have known it was you!
- Doesn't surprise me a bit, really.
- Dam n it, Putman!
- Who is it?
- I'm sure you think
I'll go down without a fight.
But it's not yet game, set--
- [ Blade Slicing ]
- [ Howls ]
- [ Slicing Continues ]
- [Agonized Groan ]
- [ Whimpering Sob ]
- [ Gurgling ]
[ Body Thuds ]
- [ Creaking ]
- [ Footsteps ]
[ Footsteps Continue ]
- [ Clattering ]
- [ Squawking ]
[ Footsteps Continue ]
- [ Footsteps Stop ]
- [ Both Mouthing Words ]
[ Footsteps Resume ]
[ Mouthing Words ]
[ Footsteps Fading ]
[ Door Closes ]
Soap, please.
- [ Whooping, Shouting ]
- [ Bongos ]
Hey! Nice helmet, Lars!
About time you two perverts
showed up for the party!
[ Laughs ]
[ Burke ]
Pour it! Pour it!
Oh, Jesus Christ!
That's blood!
- What the fuck?
- [Jenny] Oh, God!
Oh, God!
- We're all gonna die!
- [ Screaming ]
Help! Help!
Penelope!
Where's Juan?
I don't know,
I haven't seen him all night.
What the hell is going on?
[ Chuckles ]
Juan! Juan!
- Hold on. Hold on.
- What are you doing?
- Let me go!
- Don't move!
Where the hell have you been?
I was looking for Peenalop.
Why you are looking at me like that?
'Cause you disappeared a half hour ago,
and now you show up covered in blood.
Because I just found Putman.
- He's dead.
- Oh, shit! Sam!
- [ Screaming ]
- [Jenny] Oh, my God!
- [Lars ] The mud bath!
- Let's go, Peenalop.
[Jenny]
Oh, God.
[Penelope Groans ]
- Oh, no.
- What?
- [ Mutters ] Oh, fuck.
- Sam. Sam.
- [ Whimpering]
- Sam!
[ Grunts ]
- Get out.
- What?
Get out, now!
- [ Screaming, Yelling ]
- [ Maniacal Laughing ]
Did you know that
I can hold my breath...
for three minutes and 33 seconds?
[ Chuckles ]
Nobody ever suspects
the Fun Police.
- Bullshit. I always have suspected you.
- Bullshit. You did not.
- You are the bullshit!
- [ Gasps ]
He's the guy from the campfire story--
Machete Phil, the kid with no dick.
-o. That's just
an old campfire story.
What do you piss out of,
your asshole?
It's just a story! I have a dick.
I'm not Machete Phil.
I'm Machete Sam.
- [ Laughs ]
- [Jenny] Sam, why are you doing this?
Oh, I remember it
like it was yesterday.
I asked Rolo if he had any grass,
and he said he didn't have any.
So then I followed him
into the jungle.
- Would you believe what I saw?
- -o.
He had grass. My grass!
- [ Laughing ]
- A huge bag of it.
And he was smokin' it
with those two little hussies...
even though
he said he had none.
So then--
-o, wait, that's not it.
I found out that Pete was
giving the island to Dave.
Oh, yeah. That's it.
It wasn't about the grass.
Although that was incredibly uncool.
It was about Pete giving the island
to that little shithead!
All-night raving,
pill-popping little son of a bitch!
What about me? H uh?
I deserved it!
I'm the best goddamned employee
this place has ever seen!
Dave was gonna run it
into the ground.
Not on my watch!
This is my home.
Pete thinks I'm just a clown,
good for fun and games.
Well, I got you guys
to do your jobs, didn't I?
Pretty good managerial skills,
don't you think?
Setting you guys up to decipher
that stupid "Naughty Cal¡¨ song.
[ Cackling ]
Who's the orca?
Who's the octopus?
[ Singsong ] I am the Walrus!
I am the Walrus! I am the Walrus!
- [ Yells ] Oh! Ooh!
- [ Grunting ]
Get outta here! Now!
I can't hold him for long.
Try putting him to sleep!
Try the Snoring Panda!
I can't reach it.
[ Panting ] I can handle this.
- He'll orgasm for
another few minutes. Go!
- Ooh.
- I'm not leaving you!
- I'll be okay.
- Get outta here. It's gonna get messy.
- Ooh. Ooh.
- Go.
- [ Panting ]
- Oh! Ohhh!
Oh! Ooh!
- Back to the club!
- Are you crazy?
It's the most secure building on
the island. It's where we keep the booze!
[Shouting, Screaming]
Look out, now.
Oh, oh-oh-oh! There you are!
- [ Screams ]
- Baba-boobie!
- Peenalop!
-Juan!
Oh, God!
Look, he's after us.
She's safer with them. Let's go!
Let's go!
[Jenny]
Get the gate!
[Sobs ]
Oh, God!
[Screams ]
Oh, God! Nooo!
- Oh, God!
- Peenalop!
- -o! -o!
- Peenalop! Peenalop!
- Stop!
- [ Panicked Grunt ]
God! Stop it!
What are you doing?
- You'll never make it!
- [Penelope ] Sam! Please!
- [Jenny] God!
What do you think you're-
- [ Grunts ] Watch out!
- [ Grunts ]
- [Jenny] Harder! Harder!
- [Jenny] She can't breathe!
- [Juan Grunting ]
- [Juan Groaning ]
- Penelope! Get up.
- [ Gasps, Coughs ]
- [ Groaning Continues ]
- Ohh!
-Juan! Juan! Juan, get up!
- [ Coughing ]
-Juan, get up.
Come on! Hurry! Come on!
[ Groans ]
Oh, God.
It's not a party until
someone breaks the Jacuzzi.
- [Laughing]
- [ Screams ] Oh, God! Juan!
[ Snickering ]
[ Yells ]
[ Groans, Coughs ]
- Lars!
- [ Panting ] The Fun...
is done.
- [ Groans, Chuckles ]
- [ Chuckles ]
What happened
to the hot tub?
[People Whooping, Laughing]
[Man ]
Here we go!
Oh, God!
- [Jenny] No!
- [Juan ] No, it's not possible!
- What do we do?
- We can lose him in the jungle.
- The jungle?
- I can get us through!
Come on!
- Hurry!
- Go, go, go, go!
I know where this goes!
Let's go! Come on, quickly!
- [ Grunts ]
- Go!
Oh, God!
This was your big plan?
We can do it. It's high tide.
All right, now listen.
I know this is going
to sound disgusting, but...
when you jump, keep your legs
together and clench your ass cheeks.
Or else, water will fly up your butt hole
and pulverize your intestine.
- Gross!
- [Laughter]
- [ Gasps ]
- [Sam ] Where are you?
- I trust you, Juan.
- I'm coming! I'm coming!
[ Gasps ]
Jesus!
Who is this girl?
She's...
my girlfriend.
[Jenny Yelling]
[ Yelling]
[ Gasps ]
- Did you see it?
- I saw it.
- Oh, my asshole!
- What did you see?
- The Randy Rumrunner.
He didn't take it. He sunk it.
Juan, any way you could
dive down and get the propeller off?
We could put it
on the Smilin' Smuggler.
- Consider it done, my friend.
- Come on, let's go.
Come on!
[Jenny Grunts ]
Juan!
- Come on.
- I n the boat. I n the boat.
Oh, God!
Where the hell is Juan?
-Juan? Juan?
- [Jenny]Juan, where are you?
- [ Yells ]
- [ Both Scream ]
- Oh, my God, you're bleeding.
- It's okay.
- You should see the other hombre.
- I'll put it on.
- Come on.
- [ Grunts ]
- [Screaming]
- [ Yells ]
Juan!
[ Whimpers ]
It's all right.
It's okay.
I cannot imagine
a more beautiful way to go.
[ Coughing]
Just remember, Peenalop.
I love you.
!Carajo de mierda!
- I love you!
- [ Sobs ]
[ Gulps ]
Maybe...
before I go...
one kiss.
-o, no, no.
I meant,
maybe you and Jenny could...
- kiss each other.
- [ Chuckles ]
I always...
wanted...
to see that.
- [Jenny] Oh, God!
- Juan!
Juan!
- [ Yells ]
- [ Women Screaming ]
- [ Punch Lands ]
- [ Squealing Groan ]
- [ Screams ]
- [ Grunting ]
[ Coughing, Gagging]
- Aargh!
- Come on!
- Son of a bitch!
- [ Grunting ]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Yells, Groans ]
[ Grunts ]
- [ Cries Out ]
- [ Groans ]
- [Lars ] Go! Go, Jenny, go!
- [ Engine Revs ]
- [Jenny] Whoo-whoo!
- [ Yelling ]
Shit!
Turn it, turn it!
- Lars, what are you doing?
- Trust me.
- Lars, stop it!
- Come on, come on!
- [ Screams ]
- Yeah!
- You're bringing us closer to the raft!
- I know.
[ Grunts, Yells ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Agonized Grunt ]
- [ Accelerating ]
- Ahhhhhh!
[ Screams ]
Yeah!
- Slowly, slowly.
- Okay.
[Sighs ]
We gotta untie these lines.
- [ Ferocious Yell ]
- [ Penelope Screaming ]
- Hit it, Jenny! Go!
- [Accelerating]
- [ Agonized Groan ]
[ Screaming ]
- Ahhhhhh!
- Yeah!
[ Groans, Whimpers ]
[ All Panting ]
[ Grunts ]
Let's get the hell outta here.
[ Panting ]
- [ Sighs ]
- [ Relieved Chuckle ]
- [ Yells ]
- [ Screams ]
- [Sam ] Come on!
- [ Screaming ]
- Oh, come on!
[ Growling ]
- [ Lars Grunting ] Die!
- [ Groaning ]
Son of a bitch!
[ All Panting ]
They'll probably kick me
out of the Pacifist Club now.
Or at least
ask you nicely to leave.
- [ Chuckles ]
- [ Laughs ]
Tian-tu--
- the Heaven Point.
- [ Pleasurable Moan ]
Oh.
[ Gasps, Shuddering Moan ]
- Let's go, Peenalop.
- [ Chuckles ]
## [Man Vocalizing]
## [ Continues, Repetitively]
## [Man Singing, Indistinct ]
[ Laughs ]
Gracias, Sheriff!.
[ Coughs ]
- [ Laughs ]
- Cut it.
- That is so whack!
- Knock that shit off, Juan.
You're gonna cause
a hysterical... thing.
[ Laughing ]
- That is so cheebah!
- [ Chanting ]
- [Laughter]
- I just lost it. Keep rolling,
keep rolling, keep rolling.
That is some trick shit!
That is so on time, off the hook!
Tight! And heavy!
That is so...
out of the planet!
- [ Laughs ]
- [Laughter]
[Howling Laughter]
What other dumb fuckin'
catchphrases can I say?
Man, I can't hear shit. I've been standin'
next to amplifiers my whole life.
- Hello.
- [ Laughs ]
[ Whistling ]
- Oh, God, no!
- Oh, God--
- Kinda scared me. Sorry.
- [ Cackling]
#Tokey took him
to a sea horse whorehouse #
Which-Which, something.
[ Laughs ]
Which seemed to suggest, uh--
Fuck, I don't know what it seemed
to suggest. Let me try that again.
# Naughty Cal
Bongo and Tokey#
- Aaah!
- # Got tired of livin' on land#
# So the three amigos
took an undersea trip #
-# And never were seen again #
- [ Laughing ]
# Started out all right
Went a couple of miles #
# Till they spotted a waterin 'hole #
# They had their wits about them
until they were served--#
Here we go, I ' I l do, um--
Okay, ready and action.
But what about the sign
on Cliff's neck?
- I t said, "staff only."
I mean, that clearly means--
- [ Laughs ]
[ All Laughing ]
- Mark!
- All right, well, tell us, then...
how the hell are we
supposed to do our jobs...
when somebody is killing
the dick out of everybody on the island?
- Yes.
- [ Laughing ]
- Hey, listen. Listen, sugar britches.
- All right. All right. Are we cutting?
- Just-Just do your job.
- -o, I'm not cutting.
- Okay, cut it.
- [Laughter]
- [Loud Beeping]
# Bongo chose himself
a pretty prawn #
- # Cal preferred a dolphin #
- # A dolphin #
# Naughty Cal and his pals
ran the waves to somewhere #
[ Gulls Squawking ]
# Land ho
They blew all their dough #
# And ended up nowhere #
# They pulled their shit together
cleaned themselves all up #
# And they set out on their way #
# They heard some talk
about buried treasure #
# Down in Mango Bay #
# But a big bad orca
and a scary octopus #
# Were guardin' the riverbed #
# Before you knew it
the fun was over #
# 'Cause Bongo and Tokey
were dead #
# I guess it seems
that everybody's lookin '#
# To find their own paradise #
# But it ain't on Earth
It's up there in heaven #
# And someday we 're all gonna die #
# La-la-la-la, lala-la-la-la
Lalala-lala #
- Yeah!
- # La-la-la-la, lala-la-la, lalala-lala #
- Come on, everybody!
- Pass that bong over here! Yeah!
- # La-la-la-la, lala-la-la, lalala-lala #
Whoo! Yeah!
(Subtitle Revised by HchC)
[ Laughing ]
- Whoo!
- [ Waves Breaking ]