Original Subtitle By lclclc
Resync by Kijang Loncat
Steady as you go.
Steady now, steady.
All right,
let's have it on the truck.
Is that all they need?
Yes, I think so. How long
will it take to fill the order?
- Probably 3 to 4 weeks.
- We need a better service.
A boat once a week
isn't enough.
At least they could
install telephones.
- Yes. They promised them this year.
- Yes, and last.
- Morning, Campbell, Peter, Ian.
- Morning, Dr. Landers.
I'd like to mail these people.
More books?
You islanders are too hardy.
I have to keep busy.
You know, you and I
should take up chess.
I've nothing to do either,
except when Andy McCracken
has a drop too much
and tries to brig up the pub.
Why not try talking
to Dr Phillips over there?
He doesn't like company. That's why
he picked this isolated place.
No contact with the mainland.
- He's an odd one.
- Not really,
he's one of the top
research men in the worid.
- Researchers are like that.
- We wouldn't mind a bit of contact.
They don't care about us,
we don't pay enough taxes.
- Right, Constable?
- Speak for yourself, Ian.
- It smells like fog.
- I think it'll be a lovely evening.
If you weren't a newcomer,
you'd feel it.
A newcomer!
I've been here for ten years.
A newcomer just the same.
Good.
The cell cultures are prepared,
we can begin.
Are we going ahead without hearing
from Rome, New York, Tokio?
I've mailed them full reports.
They'll start when they get them.
The potential across the cell
membrane must be maintained
during the radiation of the nucleus.
- Is the tritium state complete?
- Yes.
- And the vapour applicator?
- It's been corrected.
- The connect problem has been solved.
- Good.
Now we've received
the infusion equipment,
I'm certain they'll understand
my reasons for going ahead.
I've waited
a long time for this moment.
If we're successful today, it may
well be we have the cure for cancer.
- Mrs. Bellows, come in.
- Thank you.
Go over there by the fire.
- What brings you here?
- I'm so sorry to bother you,
but I'm worried about Ian.
He hasn't come home.
- Sit down. I'll get you some tea.
- No, thank you.
Now settle down,
and tell me all about it.
Lan hasn't come home, he's three
hours late and that isn't like him.
I'm afraid something's happened.
I'm sure it's nothing.
Did you try the pub?
They haven't seen him.
I've been all round the village.
I'll tell you what,
I'll look for him,
you go home
and I'll bring him.
- Do you think he's had an accident?
- No, I'm sure everything's all right.
I'll take a look at your north
field near Philips' house.
Go on home
and don't worry.
I'll do as you say.
Sorry for being a nuisance.
- That's what I'm here for.
- Thank you very much indeed.
Lan!
Lan Bellows!
Doctor Landers!
- Thank God.
- You're in a state.
- I am.
- Come in.
Sit over there.
Now, tell me, what's happened?
Now, listen. I'm not a man
that's easily shaken, Doctor.
- I know. Would you like a drink?
- No, no.
I've just seen something
and by all that's holy,
I just can't be sure,
but I think it's Ian Bellows.
You think it's Ian?
What's happened?
I don't know,
his body is all like jelly.
- Jelly!
- Aye. Like nothing I've ever seen.
There was no face just a horrible
mush with the eyes sitting in it.
Where did this happen?
Up near the peninsula,
on the path to Parson's Cove.
- Did anyone else see it?
- No, no, I don't think so.
Come on, I'll get my hat and coat.
We'll go over there.
It's a body,
but I can't recognise it.
- Those are Ian Bellow's clothes.
- Yes.
- What's happened to him?
- I don't know.
As far as I can tell, the body
doesn't seem to have any bones.
No bones?
Look.
You see.
I have to make a closer examination.
Let's get it back to the village.
- I'll get something to carry it on.
- I'll wait here.
Hurry up, will you?
It's definitely Ian. I recognised
the appendectomy scar and birth mark.
My God.
What will I tell Mrs. Bellows?
I'll come with you and give her
a sedative. She'll need it.
Don't mention the condition
of the body.
Of course not. I understand.
In fact, I don't want
this mentioned to anyone.
They'll have to know soon enough.
Not until I find out
what we're dealing with.
What are you going to do?
First, I'll go and see Phillips,
I need expert help.
- This is quite beyond my knowledge.
- What if he won't help, or can't?
I'll take the emergency launch and
visit Brian Stanley in London.
That's our only contact with
the mainland in case we need help.
Don't worry,
I'll come back immediately.
Who is this Brian Stanley?
He's the most eminent
pathologist in Britain.
Whatever this disease is, it's
virulent and could be contagious.
We might fly back, so build
a signal fire on Moor Heights.
That'll be all for today, gentlemen.
I...
I do hope some of what
I've been saying has penetrated.
From your last papers, I doubt if
you'll progress beyond first aid.
Good day.
- Oh, Dr. Stanley.
- Yes?
- This is Dr. Landers.
- Yes, I heard your telephone message.
- How do you do? Won't you sit down?
- Thank you.
I practice on Peter's Island.
- Where's that?
- Off the East coast of Ireland.
- And what can I do for you?
Do you know of any disease
that could dissolve human bone?
No, I don't. Why?
We've discovered a body
without any trace of bone in it.
- No bone? Are you certain?
- Quite certain.
That's unbelievable!
- Have you heard this before?
- Nothing even remotely like it.
I was hoping you could help me.
- There was no trace of bone?
- None.
If that's true, it's beyond me.
It's true.
I performed a complete autopsy.
- Have you heard of David West?
- I think so.
He's the most qualified man
on bone disease I know.
Let's try the Medical Library first,
then we'll go and see David.
- If you think he'll help.
- If anyone can, he can.
I couldn't find your bathrobe.
I'm sure you don't find the female
anatomy shocking.
It's different from Harley St.
How's your dress?
The spot's out,
but it'll take some time to dry.
- Cured beautifully, don't you think?
- The credit isn't all mine.
- Excellent cognac, David.
- From an expert, that's a compliment.
You shouldn't believe everything
you read, they exaggerate.
Everything about you
is exaggerated.
You're too charming. To think
I had to break a leg to meet you.
And write off a very expensive
Maserati.
Not every girl goes to such lengths
to meet a man.
Besides, I'm sure it's going
to be worth it, isn't it?
I may not get to places
as fast as a Maserati.
- But you do get there eventually.
- Eventually.
- When?
- I'll let you know.
Don't take too long. You might
run out of petrol on the last lap.
- A pitstop or the checkered flag?
- I don't know.
But in the meantime, my dressing gown
is in the bathroom.
Brian, what do you want
at this time?
Good evening, David. I hope
we're interrupting something.
- May I present Dr. Reginald Landers.
- How do you do?
He's brought you
an interesting problem.
Yes. I've already got
an interesting problem for tonight.
- Good evening.
We are interrupting.
Miss Toni Merrill, may I introduce
Dr. Stanley and Dr. Landers.
- How do you do?
Excuse my dress.
David is better with a scalpel
that he is opening a bottle of wine.
Reginald practices on some
little island off the Irish coast.
He's found a body
without any trace of bone.
No bones? Yes, of course,
this is quite a common...
- I'm serious, doctor.
- I'm sorry, doctor.
I wasn't implying any lack of ability,
but it's difficult to accept.
- I can show you the body.
- He did a complete autopsy.
- No bones?
- No bones.
- Any contusions or lacerations?
- Not a trace.
That's why we're tossing it
into your lap.
I hate to disappoint you, but I've
never heard of anything like this.
What was the medical history?
Practically no medical history.
He was a strong, healthy farmer.
- Interesting problem, eh?
- Very. I'd like to see the body.
I was going to have a look
at it myself. Like to come?
- Yes.
- Good.
I'm sure they'll call it
"West's Disease".
This sudden humility
astounds me!
They've named so many after me,
it'll cause confusion.
- When are you leaving?
- Tonight. We'll need a plane.
- You could use my father's plane.
- We need a sea plane.
- It's a helicopter.
- That's nice of you, Toni.
- There's a catch.
- I should've known.
- I'm going with you.
- We don't know what we're up against.
It's an unknown disease,
we can't anticipate the effects.
Nevertheless, I'm going.
- Time is important.
- Quite so, quite.
Yes, I know.
Very well, we accept
your offer and the condition.
If you'll excuse me,
I'll telephone my father.
We'll stop by my lab
and pick up some equipment.
I can't wait for you. Your father
needs the helicopter.
That's all right, is it?
We don't have much choice.
I'll come back in a couple
of days.
- Right.
- We'll be marooned on the island.
We won't have any contact
with the mainland.
I can't take
the emergency launch back.
It's too late for other arrangements.
We'll have to make do.
I had no idea my father
would need the helicopter.
What did Napoleon do on that island
of his to him busy?
He invented solitaire.
- I've a much better game in mind.
- Can three play?
Fascinating game, solitaire.
- Hello, John. How's Mrs. Bellows?
- Those pills did the trick.
Good.
Constable Harris,
may I introduce Dr. Stanley,
- Miss Merrill and Dr. West.
- How do you do?
- Does anybody know about Ian?
- No.
- Have you been in touch with Philips?
- No, he's not been down.
Philips?
Dr. Lawrence Philips.
Oh, Dr. Philips!
What's he doing out here?
- This is where he set up his lab.
- He could be of great help.
You've got to get to him first.
He's a recluse.
Who is he?
What does he do?
Top man in cancer research.
Before we do anything,
let's see that body.
Not a very pretty sight.
I intend to make
the first incision here. Agreed?
Agreed.
Here's something interesting.
There are a series of minute
punctures in this dermal segment.
That's odd.
Let's collect segments
from other parts of the body.
Try staining it with eosin.
- It's the same with all of them.
- They're all over the body.
I've never seen anything
like these punctures before.
Could something have entered
the body through them?
- Like what, for instance?
- It's possible some enzyme
was introduced into the body
through the punctures.
If they are punctures. I can't tell
if they're punctures or ruptures.
Something came out or some organism
producing an enzyme went in.
There's no trace of calcium
phosphate in the body.
Then this enzyme,
or whatever it is,
seems to attack and break down
the calcium phosphate.
A major component of human bone.
We don't know
if there's a connection
between the perforations
and the absence of bone.
They could be two evidences
of a similar syndrome.
We'll have to assume it.
If we only had more complete
facilities.
There's Philips' lab,
but I don't know if he'll talk to us.
- He'll talk to me.
- How well equipped is he?
I've never seen it,
but I believe it's complete.
Don't say the lights
are going to fail.
We've had trouble
with the generator.
- Let's get out to Philips' place.
- All right.
I'd better leave a note
for Constable Harris at his house.
What a climate!
How do they stay healthy?
Does that generator supply
all this island?
All the electrical power. I've been
after them for months to fix it.
- Is that the house up there?
- That's it.
Good Lord, it looks like
"Wuthering Heights".
Try again.
I don't think it'll do much good.
We must get into that lab somehow.
- I'll look around. Got a torch?
- Yes, I have.
- Here you are.
- Thanks.
Wait here.
I'll find a way in.
- I've found another body.
- The same as the other?
- Where's the laboratory?
- I don't know. I've never been here.
We'll find it.
Let's try down here!
Isotopes. He's got as much equipment
here as I have at the University.
There's the lab.
There's one over here, as well.
Were there signs of a struggle
with Bellows?
You couldn't tell,
it was in a cave.
Philips had no contact in the village.
It's not a contagious disease.
Whatever it was,
it must've started in this lab.
Bellows' body was found
not far away.
If it did start here, it might be
moving down towards the village.
Well, they were either fighting
something,
or the death throes
were violent.
Why don't we study
Philips' notes?
- It could give us a lead.
- All right.
All right, hold on, I'm coming!
Come in, you're in time for tea.
John, I found one of my horses dead.
At least I think it's one of
my horses, it's all soft and flabby.
- Where did it happen?
- In my field.
I've got to tell Dr. Landers.
He's at Philips' place,
according to this note.
Then I'll take a look
at your horse.
- Don't mention this to anyone.
- Why not?
Don't ask foolish questions,
do as I say. Now, go on.
I'll let you know everything
in a while.
You get started,
I'll tell Harris we're back.
Right. Meet us here,
we've a lot to read.
I'll be back shortly.
I could do with food and coffee.
It's been a hard day.
Doctor Landers?
Doctor Landers!
It was a horrible
looking mess.
- Good morning, doctor.
- Morning.
- Has anyone seen Constable Harris?
- He said he'd meet you at Philips'.
He's gone up to my fields
to look at my horse.
- What's that?
- He's gone to Philips' place.
My horse is dead
and he's gone up there.
- What happened to your horse?
- If it is my horse.
It's a bloody mess,
a pile of flesh.
- In your fields?
- Yes.
- The other side of the island...
- Pardon?
Nothing. Excuse me,
I've got to go.
- Wait, what's going on here?
- I can't explain now.
Some peculiar goings on
on this island.
It was a bit abrupt
on the doctor's part.
He may be right.
I'll go and see Campbell.
You're the head of the island,
what do you plan to do?
It's no good dithering about.
We better go and talk to the farmers
and then see Dr. Landers.
A farmer has found his horse
on the other side of the peninsula.
Harris has gone to Philips' place.
We must've just missed him.
- Did you find anything?
- Philips was doing cancer research.
He was creating a form of living
matter to counteract the cancer.
What do you think?
He might've succeeded in creating
some form of life in his lair.
- That caused these deaths?
- We haven't read all his notes.
Shall we take a look at the horse,
and pick up Harris?
We should let him know
at least what we know.
- Good morning.
- Hello, Toni.
You look like you've been up
all night.
We have.
- How about some breakfast?
- We've just had supper.
- We have to go to Philips' place.
- Right, let's go.
- I'm afraid you can't come.
- Why not?
- It might be dangerous.
- What might?
Look, last night we went up there
and found four more bodies.
We think they created something in
that lab that's causing these deaths.
- What do you mean "something"?
- Just that...
We don't know, yet.
If you there's something running
loose, you can't leave me alone!
- Toni, this could be...
- Please! Don't leave me alone.
Perhaps you're right.
Oh, no!
- What's happened?
- Something was on the rear window.
- What?
- I'm not quite sure.
- What did it look like?
- It was...
I don't know, it was greyish.
- Think, this is important.
- There was a strange sound.
- What kind of a sound?
- I don't know...
Let's have a look.
Brian, hold it!
Come back to the car.
We better not get too close
until we know what we're up against.
What do you think it is?
I don't know,
but let's not take any risks.
Especially with me.
We better get Harris and get back,
we might need help.
- He must be here, that's his bicycle.
- Toni, stay in the car.
No, not with those things
around.
Let her come, I wouldn't
want to stay here alone.
OK, but stick close together.
Harris?
Constable Harris?
Let's see if he's in the basement.
Harris?
Look! It's Harris.
Good Lord, what's that?
Let's get out of here.
Don't get too close!
They've divided!
- Let's get through them.
- Wait!
Let me try first.
Come on!
No, no.
- We've got to. Now. Come on!
- No!
Hurry! They may not remain
inactive long.
Listen! They're inactive
because they divided
but we don't know for how long,
So, come on!
- David, I'm so frightened.
- So am I.
- Are you all right?
- No!
- There's one out here.
- Into the car, quick!
Damn!
- Hurry!
- I'm trying!
I think that's got it.
Here, take this.
- Come on, drink it.
- Oh, David...
Come on.
I want you to get some sleep
and this will do the trick.
I'm so scared.
I've never seen anyone die before.
Now, don't think about it.
We'll find an answer, we've got to.
- I never saw anything so horrible.
- Me neither.
Now, you just relax
and try and get some sleep.
- What's going to happen to us?
- Nothing, we'll be all right.
- Are you sure?
- Of course.
- I'm sorry I ever brought you here.
- There's no reason to be sorry.
I wanted to come.
- David?
- Yes.
Are you really sorry I came?
- I won't let you down.
- I know you won't.
We'll get out of this somehow.
Somehow.
- How is she?
- I gave her a sedative.
Good. I could do
with a sedative myself.
What did you find out?
They're in chronological order.
The last one is a few days old.
What's the entry?
It's about Phillips' dog-getting
an overdose of radiation.
Anything else?
They attempted to fuse the nucleus
but look at this protein structure:
It isn't adenosine triphosphate.
Where have you been?
I've come for my goods.
Sorry, Jonesy,
the store's closed today.
- Have you seen Dr. Landers?
- Not since 7 this morning.
He left in his car
with two men and a girl.
- Strangers.
- What strangers?
The ones that came in
on the plane, last night.
What plane? Where are they?
- Maybe they've over at the inn.
- Come on.
What about my goods?
If you check that
with 404, you see?
Hello. Are you the folk
that are with Dr. Landers?
We've been working with him.
Who are you?
I'm Campbell, head of the island.
This is Argyle who runs the store.
I'm Dr. West
and this is Dr. Stanley.
How do you do?
And where's the Doc?
Dr. Landers?
I'm afraid Dr. Landers is dead.
Dr. Landers dead!
How did it happen?
Please sit down.
Well?
Now this is very difficult
to explain.
There are creatures loose here
and they're dangerous.
What do you mean?
What are they?
We're not sure, but we think they're
due to Dr. Philips' experiments.
What do you mean "creatures"?
I wish I could tell you more,
but we don't know what they are.
- Creatures?
- Doctor, this is a bit hard to take.
I assure you we're not mad.
Dr. Philips', created some kind
of living organism that kills.
That's what happened to Dr. Landers?
Yes.
We'll need your help
if this island is to survive.
- Survive?
- What do you want us to do?
First of all, I'll need
ten good men beside yourselves.
- I can find those for you all right.
- Good.
I want all the villagers together
in an hour.
That's short notice.
We can gather
in the meeting hall.
Right. I'll let you know
everything more fully then.
- We'd better tell the Constable.
- I'm sorry, you're late. He's dead.
- The Constable too?
- Yes, and Ian Bellows.
You know, we've had
reports of animals dying.
- It seems as if they had no bones.
- Where?
Several places.
In the northern part of the island.
- Has anything occurred in the centre?
- No, just north of the centre.
- We haven't time, they're moving.
- How many?
We'll explain at the hall,
we must finish these notes.
- We'll do as you say.
- Thank you.
- Now they tried experiment 1165...
- Yes.
And if you compare that with 1143,
the results were negative.
Quiet! Quiet, please!
Now, that's all we know
at the moment.
Your attention, please.
I'm Dr. West and this is Dr. Stanley.
We've completed going over
Dr. Philips' notes
and I must warn you that we're in
a dangerous situation. Dr. Stanley?
Let me explain what
we've discovered so far.
In order to understand
the nature of cancer,
Dr. Philips was trying
to create living cells.
Cells that he hoped
would attack the cancer.
He based this on the carbon atom
which is the basis of all life.
He didn't succeed.
But he probably created a form
of life based on the silicon atom.
Now these Silicates,
as we call them, eat animal bone,
human bone.
Dr. Philips' gave life
to some kind of organism,
something we know nothing about.
Their external skeletal structure
is tough and resilient.
We couldn't hurt it with an axe and
when run over, it was unharmed.
We haven't found
a way to destroy them yet,
but shall attack them
with everything we can.
From Dr. Philips' notes
and our own experience,
we calculate that these creatures
divide every six hours.
There are about 64 silicates
on the island at this moment.
There'll be 128
by six o'clock this evening.
- 256 by midnight.
- What?
And if this continues, at the end
of the week, there'll be a million.
Please, I must have your attention!
The only way to stop them if all
else fails, is to deny them food.
We want you to move
into this building with supplies,
round up the cattle
and bring it here.
We must keep calm.
Fear and panic will defeat us
just as surely as the Silicates.
We need your help and co-operation.
We must work together.
Thank you.
Right. The following men meet me
in the room out the back there.
Er... Morton...
Er... Dunley...
- Are there any guns on the island?
- Plenty.
- And dynamite?
- I've got three cases.
We ought to make petrol bombs,
we don't know what'll work.
We'll send out three scouts:
Here, here and there.
Dunley, you and two others.
The rest of you gather up
the equipment and meet here.
You all know
the groups assigned to you.
Williams and Martindale,
round up the cattle
and bring them along
to William's field there,
by the village.
Right, let's get moving.
Can I rely on you to see
that everything's fine at the hall?
- Yes, of course, I think I can cope.
- Fine.
Now make sure all the supplies
are organised properly
and try and keep them
from panicking.
- I will. David...
- Hm?
- Take care.
- I'll do my best.
Don't worry, we'll be back,
whether we destroy them or not.
- How many can you count?
- About 25, as far as I can see.
- Got everything?
- I think so.
- Where's the Geiger counter?
- Why?
If they're radioactive,
we'll have to protect ourselves.
Give us a hand.
Halsey,
your group take the dynamite.
Morton, you bring the petrol bombs.
It's no good,
we hit it several times.
They don't seem
to be moving very fast.
I'll cross that one's trail
and get a Geiger reading.
- Careful. Don't get too near.
- Don't worry.
Careful! Behind you!
- Nasty little creatures.
- We better try the petrol bombs.
There wasn't any sign
of radioactivity.
That's something, anyway.
The rest of you stay here.
- I'll get up closer.
- All right, but watch it.
Try another!
Hey, stop, come back here!
Let's try the dynamite.
Right, everybody spread out.
All right, light them up.
Nothing gets through to them.
At this rate, they'll reach the village
by midnight.
What else could we do?
- Starve them.
- Mr. Campbell!
- What is it, Dunley?
- In Parson's Cove...
It's one of the Silicates. It's dead.
- Are you sure?
- It hasn't moved in 20 minutes.
And another thing,
that Great Dane of Philips'
is nearby. Half eaten.
Philips' dog!
Remember, the dog
had an overdose of radiation.
Let's have the Geiger counter.
Here it is,
and the dog's over there.
It's loaded with radioactivity.
Radioactive too.
Let's put them on the truck
and take them to the clinic.
Take it round the back!
David, I'm so glad you're here,
they're starting to panic.
All right, take it easy.
Please listen to me.
Will you listen to me, PLEASE!
I've something
of great importance to tell you.
I think we've found a way
to destroy the Silicates.
But we'll need the help
of everyone here.
We'll examine a dead one and I think
it'll give us what we need.
Meanwhile, stay here
and do as Miss Merrill says.
Can you stop them?
Keep the people here,
and keep them busy at all costs.
- What have you found out?
- I've no time to explain.
We'll be in the clinic
if you need us.
The outer shell is impenetrable.
We've done everything to pierce it.
- But radiation will kill them.
- How?
The dog was contaminated with
strontium, that effects the bone.
It ate the bone plus the strontium,
that's why it died.
How can we introduce the radiation
into their systems?
Can it be done?
Philips' had a supply of isotopes.
If we can get enough Strontium 90,
we can contaminate the cattle.
The Silicates eat the cattle...
It's a hope.
Can you move the cattle closer,
to keep them safe until we're ready?
We can put them
in my cattle yard.
Then do so. Dr. Stanley and I
are going up to Philips' place.
Now if we don't come back,
you'll have to get the Strontium 90.
- But we don't know...
- We'll tell you what to do.
Dave, stop the car.
- What is it?
- Look over there. Silicates.
There are more of them.
I'm not keen on going down
in that cellar again.
It looks safe.
There must be some instrument that
they used to contaminate the animals.
I'll have a look around.
- What about this?
- That's it.
Better put these on.
- I forgot the gloves.
- I'll put this in the car.
David!
- Brian, I...
- You must, you must!
Can you hold that?
Keys, in the boot.
Try and hang on
until we get back.
- Thank you, nurse.
- How are you feeling?
- As well as can be expected.
- He's had a lot of pain.
- Not much.
- I'll give you another morphine.
First a sloppy bit of surgery and now
you're turning me into a drug addict.
- It's your choice.
- I don't need it.
All right, but we'll give you
another transfusion.
One more, and I'll be
a full-blooded Irishman.
I think he's feeling better.
- Is that all the cattle?
- That's all.
Most of them.
Very few escaped the round-up.
Let's hope
we've got enough Strontium 90.
Herd them through one at a time.
That's the lot.
I had to cut down the shots
on the last few.
- Do you think it'll be enough?
- I don't know.
Let's get back,
and get those lights strung up.
You've done it.
- Give us a bulb.
- Here, take this.
Yeah, that's it.
What if it doesn't work?
Then we'll just have to
wait for help.
Our biggest worry is that they'll
panic. They must understand.
They're scared to death...
So am I.
We're all scared. If they go
outside, it's certain death.
Those things will be
all over the building.
Probably.
Now, look,
you must keep the people
calm, they trust you.
I'll do my best.
The lights are a strain
on the generator.
- That'd really cause a panic.
- I've got torches and candles.
- I hope we don't need them.
- We've food for a week.
You must convince the villagers.
Our one hope is that they'll starve
if the Strontium doesn't work,
or at least the lack of food
may cut down the multiplication.
- Are you going to have a look?
- Yes, but first I'll see Stanley.
I'll talk to the people.
You move around amongst them
and keep them occupied.
Get help from Dunley
and some of the others.
Good.
I've injected the cattle but
we ran short of the Strontium 90.
I had to cut down
on the last few.
If it doesn't work, we'll wait until
the helicopter or boat arrives.
- When will the Silicates get here?
- It's a little after ten.
According to the last positions,
in about an hour and a half.
What about the division time?
That may take some time
and there aren't that many cattle.
You get some rest.
A perfect time for a nap.
You will let me know if anything
unusual happens, won't you?
We've got to get out of here.
Where can we go?
We can't reach the mainland.
If you'd seen what it did to Archie,
you'd swim.
Halsey!
Shut up.
Listen all of you,
if anyone leaves this building,
they'll be killed for sure.
We're safe enough in here, we've got
enough food and water to wait.
I'm so frightened, Mr. Campbell.
If you do as we say,
you've nothing to fear.
- Will you trust me?
- Yes.
Now, listen, Halsey,
and listen well.
If I hear another sound out of you,
I'll throw you out for those things.
I'm talking straight,
understand?
- Mr. Campbell, I can't stand it...
- Do you understand?
Mind that you do.
There's nothing to fear. We'll be
all right as long as we stay here.
- Are you sure?
- Sure.
Why, I've stuffed this place
with supplies on credit.
He's a much better colour,
he'll rest now.
Now what?
- I think you could use some rest too.
- I suppose we all could.
- Why don't you go and lie down?
- I'd rather not, not now.
- David?
- Hm?
Do you really think
we'll get out of this?
Well, I think we stand
a very good chance, yes.
But you don't believe that, do you?
Not 100%, no,
but I'd like to believe it.
Toni?
I've never been...
I've never been much good at...
At being serious with a woman
before now, but...
If we get out of this, I will...
Don't say anything more.
Not here, not now.
Yes, I'd better get outside,
it's nearly midnight.
David, be careful,
I love you.
The cattle are getting restless.
Aye, they're moving around a lot.
- How are the people taking things?
- I think it'll be all right.
- The boys are keeping the talk going.
- Good.
How many, do you think?
Hard to tell. About 100.
- So they didn't divide.
- It doesn't look like it.
Well, this is it.
It's a nightmare.
It's all over.
They're coming this way!
- Not stopping.
- No.
- Good Lord, look!
- They're dividing.
That means the effect
of the Strontium will be halved.
- I'd hoped it'd work before then.
- Let's get inside.
Tell them it may take time
to work.
- Will it work?
- I wish I knew.
- Brian, they've divided.
- What does that mean?
That the power and effect of
the Strontium is cut in half.
Did they divide before
or after they ate the cattle?
- After.
- That's something.
- Not much, but it's something.
- How's your arm?
I'm trying not to think about it.
It may take time
for the Strontium to work.
If it works.
- I don't like this.
- The generator's had it.
- They're coming.
- I can hear.
I'd better talk to them.
- Quiet everyone!
- Hold it!
- Please try and be quiet!
- Now don't panic.
We expected them here.
We must give it time to work.
Light the candles and lanterns.
Take it easy! Take it easy!
Quiet, please. Quiet.
They're frightened without the light.
- If they start breaking out.
- I know.
Come on, we've got a job to do.
- What's happened to the lights?
- Quiet!
Be careful,
they're panicking as it is.
- I'm sorry.
- We've got to set an example.
I'm not staying here.
I'll shoot anyone that moves,
I mean it.
I'll shoot anyone that moves.
Get back to your places,
away from the windows and the door.
Look out!
Get to the clinic,
as many as you can!
Open the door!
They're breaking in.
Take care of her, I'll be back.
Wait!
Come on,
quickly, block it!
Quick, bring anything you can!
Quickly, bring it over here!
- Hold on.
- I'm trying, but I'm so frightened.
I'm frightened.
No place else to go.
Hold it,
they're getting weaker.
Careful.
Give me a hand with this.
They're dead.
- Oh, David!
- Darling, it's all over.
We're all right now.
- And now my hand itches.
- Oh, shut up, Brian.
Watch it, or I'll sue you
for malpractice.
As soon as we get on,
we'll radio ahead for aid.
We'll need a lot of help to clean up
the island, bury the dead.
They'll send everything,
this afternoon.
I wish Philips'
had never started this.
No, he was just trying
to help humanity.
Science has its risks, but they
aren't enough to hinder progress.
- Have you searched the island?
- Yes, several times.
We killed them all, I'm certain.
I shudder to think of them.
Don't think about them, just try
to get them out of your mind.
- It's easier said than done.
- I know.
- What'll happen to the villagers?
- We'll send back help.
You know, we were lucky
this is an island.
If it had happened anywhere else,
I doubt we would've destroyed them.