Friends, we last left Jane and Rafael
dealing with an unexpected development.
I believe Mateo does have ADHD.
How can we help him?
Well, there are treatment options
that range from behavior
interventions to medication.
But at least the two of them
were back in a good place.
Not in such a good place?
Our Petra.
See, she was going to propose to J.R.,
but then J.R. broke up with her
and moved to Houston.
But at least Petra had a
shoulder to ugly-cry on.
I was gonna propose.
Also feeling vulnerable? Xiomara.
See, she was waiting to find
out if her chemotherapy worked.
I'm not out of the woods yet,
until after the PET scan.
And so, yeah,
everything was on pause for now,
including her sex life, unlike Alba,
who just got hitched!
That's right.
Alba and Jorge went from
first base to a home run.
And speaking of home runs,
Rogelio had a brand-new TV show.
What if our young lead's story
is in present day
and you and River
are living in the future?
On Mars!
We can call it
This Is Mars.
I know, pretty out there, right?
But hey, it's a telenovela.
So let's blast off into ours.
When Jane Gloriana Villanueva was...
well, actually, for all of Jane's life,
there was no man of the
house, just three women.
And they didn't need a man,
because they took care of it all.
Electricity went up.
Mom, remember not to leave
your curling iron plugged in all day.
My curling iron doesn't use
half as much electricity
as the fans your abuela
keeps running all day.
There, no more wobble.
Ooh, I like that nail polish.
Thanks. it's called Breakfast in Red.
I'll loan it to you.
In fact, Jane had never heard
the term "man of the house"
used in real life until...
Mm.
Aww, looks like the man
and woman of the house
are in still in the honeymoon phase.
So what's on the agenda today? Huh?
Besides being totally adorable.
Now that our arrangement
is permanent,
I'm taking my things out of storage.
Oh, great.
Not at all. I'll do it right now.
Anything for my new step-abuelo.
And maybe you could move some
of your bathroom things into your room.
All the hair stuff.
Of course.
Sync and correction by LittleDuck
www.addic7ed.com
Hey, uh,
how you feeling?
Itchy.
Your sheets are awful.
What thread count are they?
I don't know. They were on sale.
I'll have Temp send you
a set from the hotel.
They're Egyptian cotton.
I...
I meant how are you feeling about J.R.?
I had a good cry and now
I'm going to move forward.
It's okay to give yourself
some time to wallow.
No, I wallowed last night,
now I'm moving on.
Fresh start.
Ugh. I'm supposed to be
in a meeting right now,
but Temp didn't remind me.
You know what?
Today I'm about fresh starts all around.
She's fired.
Oh, no. Uh... Poor Temp.
When you reward
incompetence, we all lose.
Wait. Uh, I'll walk you out.
I have to get to
Rafael's to talk about...
Mateo! Five more minutes, okay?
So what do you think about
putting him on ADHD medication?
I really don't want to
go to that right away.
Because medication is
a lifelong decision,
and he is so young and I just,
- I don't feel comfortable...
- Jane.
I agree.
You do?
Yeah, 100%.
I'm obviously not anti-medication...
It's really helped a lot with my
depression...
but I'm an adult, and he's a kid,
so we should try other options first.
Exactly. So let's dive
- into behavior modification.
- Sounds good.
Now hand over whatever ten-step list
I know you've already made.
Actually, it's 15, with subcategories.
I've been researching and...
You know,
I'm the man of this telenovela,
and I say let's skip the boring stuff.
It all boils down to
three basic headlines...
In other words, "cut the crap"
Uh, sorry, I'm just picturing
Jane working out. Whew.
Okay.
And the most important
thing to remember is
it's not about the days,
it's about the patterns.
That's our mantra.
Look at us, with a mantra.
A mantra. And...
- a notebook.
- Ah.
So we can keep a log
of Mateo's activities.
We need everything to be
as consistent as possible
between our two places
so we can track Mateo's
patterns over time.
Per the mantra.
Remind me of the mantra again?
I'll write it in the notebook.
You've got this.
You're killing it, Dina.
Okay, bye.
Dina's been working like a
madwoman to finish the script
for This Is Mars. She's almost done.
Wow, that was fast.
Yeah. She's turning it in
tonight, yes, she is.
The pilot is brilliant.
Between that and this,
the network has to
give us a pilot order.
That's great, hon.
Hopefully, we'll both be
getting good news soon.
The doctor scheduled my final PET scan.
In three weeks,
we'll find out if the chemo worked.
Really?
How are you feeling?
I'm nervous,
but I'm trying to stay positive.
I keep picturing all of the
things I'll be able to do
once I know the cancer's gone.
Get back to work, dance again.
And maybe even get our sex life
back on track before we turn 50.
Well, no matter what happens,
we're in this together,
and that's the key.
Ah! Abuela!
Hmm?
What happened to the table by the door?
Don't. I-I want it.
Jane, door!
Yeah, so there's been
quite a bit of re-Jorganizing in here.
I've got it, don't worry.
Petra? What's wrong?
Oh, I was cleaning the penthouse
because my idiot temp messed
up the maid schedule again.
Maybe it's time to cut her loose.
Him.
Oh, sorry, it's been three weeks.
Let me catch you up.
As you'll recall, Petra had this temp.
But then she had this one,
then this one and this one.
And...
But that's not the point.
The point is when I was cleaning,
I found the engagement ring
I was going to give J.R.
and I know I shouldn't have looked at
it, but I did,
and now...
Aww.
How long is this going to last?
I'm so sick of crying.
I feel like a Villanueva.
I know, I know, but,
uh, it's like I told you
on the phone last night...
And the past 20 nights.
grieving is a process.
Maybe it's time to take the
next step in the process.
Showering?
Returning the engagement ring.
Will you come with me?
Of course. But tomorrow,
'cause we're about to have dinner.
Did Alba make arepas?
Yeah. Do you want to...
Yeah, thanks.
Geez, who died?
Uh, actually, my mom's getting
her final PET scan tomorrow,
to see if her cancer treatment worked.
Oh, my God, I'm so sorry.
- I'll go.
- It's okay.
Please stay.
You're just in time
to pray with us.
I will do it in English.
We ask you, Heavenly Father,
to guide Xiomara,
as you already have,
through her journey with cancer.
We pray that the treatments
have done their work,
that her suffering is at an end.
We pray that her life from now on
be blessed
and full of joy and good health.
In the name of the Father and the Son
and the Holy Spirit. Amen.
Amen.
You'll recall, we last left Jane
praying for her mother.
Her PET scan's later today.
Waiting is the hardest part.
Do you want to distract yourself
with some reading material?
It is a real page-turner.
Ooh.
I especially love the
part about the color
of the sunrise when you ran
Mateo to school last week.
Okay, maybe my entries
are a little too detailed,
but at least you can read
my handwriting. I...
I am sorry, but what is a "meldooper"?
Meltdown.
Oh. Oh, no, what happened?
He lost it at Ethan's birthday party.
It was hard to sell him on
a nitrate-free Fruit Roll-Up
when all the other kids got cake.
How bad?
"We owe Ethan's mom a new lamp" bad.
It's not about the days...
It's about the pattern. I know.
It's just a small setback.
Should we talk about it over dinner?
Oh, I, uh, can't tonight.
What, you got a hot date?
I mean, not a hot date.
Just a regular one?
Careful. Don't have a meldooper, Jane.
Oh. Okay. Hope it goes well.
Slow down, Mateo,
you know we don't run in the house.
It's important to note
that Jane wanted to talk
to her abuela about Rafael,
but unfortunately,
she had bigger fish to fry.
Do you?
Hmm...
Mm-hmm.
If he can catch a giant fish,
I think he can probably
make his own tuna sandwich.
I know. I'm... I just mean,
you're a strong, independent woman.
You don't have to let him
hang something on the wall
if you don't like it.
And yours.
Yeah, Jane. Ours.
It's like they're
living in the '50s.
He might as well have said,
"Woman, go make me a sandwich!"
- Woman, go easy on him.
- Ah...
I'm just worried this
will become a pattern.
He's her husband, not yours.
And I know you don't excel
at minding your own business,
but you should stay
out of their marriage.
You've got this.
Yeah! Mm-hmm.
And speaking of marriage...
How did the proposal go?
Would I be standing here
with a ring if it went well?
That was a rhetorical question.
She just wants her money back.
Right away.
Wow. Just
handing over that ring
makes me feel like a
weight has been lifted.
Well,
it was a three-carat diamond.
You were right.
Ooh, it feels good to get
rid of that reminder of J.R.
That's one
small step for Petra...
and one giant leap for
Rogelio de la Vega.
That's right. Dina really was on a roll.
And This is Mars got a pilot
order from the network!
How does that space suit feel?
Sleek, supple and slimming.
I can't wait to get in front
of the cameras tomorrow.
Rogelio, thank you for the
beautiful Martian bouquet.
Of course.
Uh-oh.
That's gonna be a problem.
They're not gonna be a problem.
Oh, ignore me!
We're so much more talented than them.
And you're so sexy.
And you're so gorgeous.
And our skin glows like the sun.
And theirs will only get worse.
Looks like
they have a mantra, too.
And so will your skin if
you keep frowning like that.
Do you know how much Botox
it takes to get rid of worry wrinkles?
Approximately eight to 20 units.
Exactly.
Forget them.
No, I was just thinking about Xiomara.
She had her PET scan this
morning, so now we're waiting.
It's just a telemarketer.
Look, I appreciate the support,
but you guys should really go home.
The doctor probably
won't even call today.
Yeah.
I thought I was headed in the
right direction, you know?
Getting used to us as friends.
But this feels like a real setback.
Yeah, remember,
Jane, you're gorgeous,
your skin looks amazing, and...
Oh, sorry. Wrong mantra.
"It's not about the days,
it's about the pattern."
It's the doctor's office.
We're right here with you, Mom.
Thank you.
But can I have one of my hands back
- so I can answer?
- Oh!
Hello?
Yes, this is Xiomara.
Okay.
Thank you. Bye.
I'm cancer-free.
Oh, yes!
Oh, I have to call your father.
Oh, thank God. I'm so happy.
I can't wait to see you
tonight and celebrate.
Okay. You too.
Xo's PET scan results came
back, and she is cancer-free!
Finally...
we can be together!
Mars, we have a problem.
Ms. Fields? They'd like to see you
for one more zero-gravity hair test.
To not having cancer.
I've been saying it
over and over all day,
but it's hard to believe it, you know?
It's hard to just click back to normal.
Give yourself time. It'll happen.
Agreed.
And maybe this will help.
Should we dance, Mr. De La Vega?
I would love to dance,
Mrs. De la Vega.
I'm so happy.
Me, too.
So happy.
I also have a piece of-of teeny, tiny,
totally unimportant, not-so-happy news.
News that won't even matter in light
of how great your news is.
What are you talking about?
River kissed me.
What?
Obviously, it wasn't reciprocated.
Because I'm happily, ecstatically
married to the most amazing
woman on the planet.
So I'm sure that after
your clear PET scan,
this little incident
will roll right off your back.
Oh, hell no!
I cannot believe that conniving
bitch made a pass at you!
What was she thinking?
Apparently she thought that our
love-hate relationship was mostly love.
Have you been flirting with her?
No! Of course not!
I've only been nice to her.
How nice?
People fall in love with
me all the time, Xiomara.
I usually see it coming.
But don't worry. I will clear it all up.
I just have to handle this delicately.
Because I don't want to jeopardize
our working relationship.
You better set her straight.
I promise. I will.
Still want to dance?
Are you kidding?
Another amazing meal.
Even when your abuela's at work!
I don't know
how she does it.
She cooks, she cleans...
She is the perfect woman.
Hmm.
I'm not sure their criteria
for that is the same...
Ooh.
Oh... Oh, uh, Mateo?
Take your plate to the sink.
Remember, we have
a dinner routine: set the table,
eat, clear the table.
Jorge didn't have to clear his plate.
Why should I have to?
I'm the man of the house, too.
Oof. This is not the pattern
Jane was trying to reinforce.
You might be a man,
but gender roles have evolved,
and boys and girls
do the same things now.
And frankly, "man of the house"
is not a term people even use anymore.
I don't care,
I just want to watch soccer.
Oh, uh...
Sorry, Mateo.
No screen time on weeknights.
Grab your dish and
we'll go pick out a book.
No!
This is not up for discussion.
Reading time.
- I don't want to read! I hate reading!
- Now.
Mateo...
No! No-no-no-no-no...
Do you have a minute?
Oh. You want to join me?
Um, no. But thank you.
Is my grandma here?
Grocery shopping.
That woman never gets tired.
Glad Mateo's calmed down.
Last night was a doozy.
Actually, um, maybe we can
talk for a minute about that.
So, I know living together
has been an adjustment.
For everyone. But since we are
living under the same roof,
there are a few things
that you could do that
would really help me out
with Mateo.
Oh, okay. Sure.
Well, for example, the television.
Uh, with Mateo's ADHD,
we're really trying to establish
patterns and healthy routines,
and it is hard for Mateo
to focus when the TV is on.
So, if you could maybe wait
until Mateo's asleep to watch TV?
Uh, just on the nights
when he's sleeping over, of course.
Okay.
And also, it would be really great
if, when Mateo's around,
you could pick up your dishes?
Just to help us reinforce
good behavioral routines.
Ah. Gotcha.
And obviously, if there's anything
I can help you with, I'm all ears.
Sounds good.
Thank you, Jorge!
I really appreciate that.
Uh... now I have to run.
Literally.
In case you forgot...
You're doing great, Mr. Sweetface!
More like Mr. Sweaty-face!
Ah! Come on, Mateo.
Only five more blocks. Huh?
And you'll be able to focus
so much better at school
if you get some of the energy out now.
I'm not going! I'm tired.
You've got this!
I hate running,
and you're the worst mommy ever!
You're gonna be late for school, Mateo.
So? I hate school, too!
I'm staying right here!
Would you move for a candy bar?
Technically, a gluten-free,
preservative-free protein bar.
You can have the whole
thing if you finish our run.
What do you say, Mateo?
Huh? Huh? Okay!
What? Nothing.
I just asked him to put his dishes away,
I can't believe he tattled on me.
I'm disrespectful?
I think the way he treats
you is disrespectful.
He's making you wait
on him hand and foot.
You're married, not indentured.
Abuela, don't you think
that's a little old-fashioned?
I'm just worried that you're
losing who you are, Abuela.
Establishing bad patterns
for your relationship.
Damn.
Jane got owned.
Yes, of course.
I would also like an apology.
And so Jane apologized to Jorge.
Even though what she
wanted to do was hit him
upside his head with his big, dumb fish.
And I know I overstepped...
and offended you.
I didn't mean any
disrespect and I'm so sorry.
Thank you, Jane.
And since we're talking about respect,
there are a few other
things we should discuss.
I-I notice you often park
by the footpath in front of the house.
I would appreciate it if you
leave that space for Alba,
so she doesn't have to walk as far
when she gets home from work.
- Got it, will do.
- Also...
- Hmm?
- it would be great
If you could be a little quicker
in the bathroom in the mornings.
Quicker in the bathroom, check.
And, also...
when you come home later than 9:00,
please try to keep it down.
We're both light sleepers.
No problem.
Is that it?
That's it.
Great. See you at home.
I hate this.
I hate everything about this.
Start over.
Hey, what's going on?
I'm redecorating the hotel and
looking at some terrible ideas.
But didn't you just redo it?
That was two years ago, Jane.
That's like a lifetime
in hotel years. Look,
I know what I'm doing, okay?
Okay, yeah. Great.
Yo, Mrs. S.
Here are those blueprints you asked for.
The task was to get
them signed by Milos.
Are these signed?
Nah, brah; couldn't make it
to the prison in time.
Traffic was gnarly.
I told you Tuesdays were
the only day Milos could get
visitors, now I have to wait
a week to get his signature.
You have to start planning
ahead and if you can't
do that,
maybe this isn't the job for you.
Yeah. I don't think it is.
Great. You're fired.
Sweet. Fun employment!
Who does she miss? J.R.?
Hi, Mrs. Solano.
Ah, yes.
You remember Krishna.
Hey, you.
How's life after prison?
- Uh, did you get my fruit basket?
- No.
Oh. O-One of my temps
was supposed to send you one.
Uh, which is exactly why I'm calling.
Look.
I feel so guilty about everything
that happened and, and I...
I miss us.
So what do you say?
Want to come back to work?
Get the gang back together?
Hard pass, Mrs. Solano.
Did you talk to River yet?
No, she's still in wardrobe
but as soon as she's out,
I'll straighten her out.
This set needs to be a place of honor,
respect and dignity.
Because I'm half-human, half-Martian.
I've started to evolve.
Didn't you read the script?
Hello.
I'm calm.
But he better set her straight.
And I'm listening in.
Oh. Your wife is here.
Yes, and I've told her what happened.
And I'm flattered.
That someone
as spectacularly beautiful
as the incomparable River Fields
would be interested in me.
But alas,
I must make clear
I'm very happily married.
And I'm sorry if I misled you
in any way.
Let's just keep this
relationship professional.
I completely agree.
This show is too important
to both of us to jeopardize it.
I apologize for overstepping.
It won't happen again.
Professional it is.
All right.
Time for you two to have sex.
Should I be worried about this?
Petra?
Worried about my personal living space?
Which is none of your business?
You are my business.
And I knew you were doing
some work in the lobby,
but I didn't realize it
was a whole hotel remodel.
It's gonna be expensive.
You want to maybe talk it through?
The girls are waiting
for you in their room.
I am just worried that you're
getting in over your head.
Permits alone are gonna
be a huge expense.
Would that be worth it
for maybe 10% growth?
I know it's a big investment, Rafael.
I don't need you to mansplain
hotel finance to me.
And from mansplaining...
to Marsplaining.
Our scientists have
finally figured out
how to support all forms of life
in the Martian atmosphere.
The first Martian
flower was just the beginning.
In our man-made lake,
we have the first Martian shark.
And I've saved the best news for last.
We will name it Lake Brenda.
After the first co-president of Mars.
I think we should properly christen
this lake by making love in it.
Cut.
Hmm!
That's definitely
not in the script.
Get your hands off my man,
you horny Martian bitch!
Cut!
Somebody stop them. Stop, stop!
No! Stop.
Somebody stop them.
No, Xiomara.
No!
Watch out, Xo.
Jump over that shark.
Stop! Stop, stop.
Xiomara, stop. Please stop.
No, no, no, no.
What were you thinking?
Why don't you ask that
woman who was groping you?
It's called acting!
Yeah, right. They called "cut."
I didn't hear it.
Maybe that's because
you were too busy trying
to get a piece of
tail, you home wrecker.
Okay. Come here.
Come here, come here. Come on, let's go.
Xiomara, this is my place of work.
Exactly.
So why is your costar dry humping you
in front of everyone?
We have a lot of
material to shoot today.
- We'll talk later.
- Excuse me?
Why don't you go cool
off in my dressing room?
Inhala, exhala.
Uh, Mateo.
This is important.
These breathing exercises
will make it easier for
you to pay attention
to your school work,
but you need to focus.
I can't.
I'm too bored.
Sounds like you need to
burn off a little energy.
What do you say we run
around the block a few times
- while Daddy finishes cooking?
- I'm sick of running
And I don't want Daddy's gross food.
If you finish your
exercises and eat dinner,
you can have a chocolate bar.
How's that?
I don't want a disgusting
fake candy bar.
Uh-oh, looks like
he's having another "meldooper."
I never get real dessert.
- Or even chicken nuggets...
- Try to calm down.
- or anything good.
- Please, Mateo.
If you make me run to school again,
- I'm running away from home!
- Just take a deep breath.
No, I don't want to do this anymore.
Well, neither do I.
I need a time out.
You know what?
I think we all need a break.
Here, play with this.
Oh, yes. Yes, yes, yes.
I need some air.
He's right.
I can't do this.
I can't run with him to school anymore.
I'm exhausted and we're always late.
Then there's the logs, his diet;
I just feel like I'm always
studying him and disciplining him.
So let's stop.
- We can't.
- Why not?
Because we have to help
him however we can.
Yeah, agreed.
However we can.
And we can't evaluate
If the behavior therapy
is actually working
unless it's something that
we can sustain long term.
And we can't sustain this.
I just want to do everything possible.
Don't we owe him that?
We are.
And we will.
But we also have to enjoy our son.
And live our lives.
Let's just relax the food rules
on the weekends.
Let him have cake at birthday parties.
Yeah.
Okay.
- No more running to school.
- Oh, thank God.
Mm. Let's throw out
that stupid notebook.
I love the notebook.
Can't we just keep the notebook?
This is nice out here.
Yeah, I needed this.
So? How'd your date go?
Not bad.
Cool.
What does "not bad" mean?
- That I don't want to get into it.
- Gotcha. Understood.
I will tell you if there's
something worth telling.
Perfect.
Aw.
Look at them. So mature.
Less mature...
I'm sorry for my outburst.
But River Fields is after you.
You have to believe me.
Xiomara, she just got
caught up with the scene.
Please, let this go.
Can we talk?
I want to apologize.
I honestly did not hear
the director call "cut."
But beyond that,
I should never have kissed your husband.
And even though what I did
is totally unforgivable,
I still wanted to apologize to you.
Sometimes I get caught up
in the fantasy.
I lose myself in the role
and... as pathetic
as it sounds,
I start to believe what I'm feeling.
It's a combination of... being method
and... and, well,
being a little lonely,
if I'm... if I'm being honest.
But it's no excuse.
And nothing like that
will ever happen again.
You have my word.
Okay, then thank you for saying that.
I'll-I'll get out of your hair.
- I'll see you at home?
- Yes.
Thank you for doing that.
No problem.
Oh!
You slapped me?
Uh!
Well, you kissed me!
Because your wife
bought our cover story.
Our what?
There is no cover story.
Let me make this perfectly clear.
I love my wife.
I don't want to have sex with you,
I have never wanted
to have sex with you,
and if you keep trying
to have sex with me,
I'm going to HR,
and if they don't pay attention,
I'll go to Alyssa Milano.
Jorge...
Hey. I need a place to stay.
Yeah, sure. Come in.
I just need to make a call.
My last temp screwed up my injunction,
and now Milos is blocking
the hotel renovation.
Well, maybe that's for the best.
It'll give you time to think
about whether you really
want to go ahead with it.
Rafael talked to you.
He may have mentioned it,
but that's not the point. I...
I'm worried that this renovation
is just one big,
old distraction from J.R.
Yeah, of course it is.
Everywhere I look,
I see reminders of her.
I can't take it.
So you're gonna...
- redecorate her out of your memory?
- Exactly.
As soon as I get that injunction.
Judge Judy stayed here last
month with her grand kids.
I'll give her a call.
Eh... It's 11:00 on a weeknight.
You cannot call Judge Judy right now.
Of course I can! Give it to me.
Not a chance. I am your friend,
and I am not giving this
phone back until you agree
to stop bankrupting yourself
to erase J.R.
It's not just about erasing her.
I want her back.
But I can't have her.
And I feel totally out
of control and powerless,
and I don't know what to do with myself
and I have to do something
or I'm going to explode.
Get your sneakers.
Why are we doing this again?
When your emotions and
energy levels are too high,
heavy exercise can help.
It's not.
Yeah. Keep running.
I don't know if you've ever
been heartbroken before.
Have you?
Not like this.
Not even close. I blame you.
Of course you do.
For what, exactly?
Well, I never believed in
this sappy destiny stuff before.
And for a while there, because of you,
I actually thought J.R. was my...
happily ever after.
Well, if it helps,
I'm over that now.
I thought Rafael and I would make it,
but I might change the end of my book
so the heroine ends up
living with her abuela.
Okay.
That makes no sense.
And I'm done.
Why would the heroine
live with her grandmother?
She's a grown-ass woman.
Can't she move out even if
she doesn't get the guy?
Yeah, I guess she can.
So why hasn't she?
I don't know.
Maybe she was waiting
for things to change.
Is she done waiting?
Yeah, she is.
And is she ready to not renovate?
No, I'm-I'm not she. You're she.
Fine, fine.
Are you?
Bankrupting myself probably isn't the...
healthiest way to get over J.R.
Well, you were right. Uh...
River kissed me again.
I knew it.
I'm sorry. I told her off...
In no uncertain terms, this time.
Good!
And you're not allowed to do
any sex scenes with her anymore.
Xiomara, she plays my wife.
Sex scenes are involved.
Then I'm gonna be there,
watching like a hawk.
I told her to back off.
She got the message this time.
- I'm still coming.
- You can't.
- Why not?
- Because you being there
will make the situation worse.
Well, it's gonna be worse, then,
- because I'll be there.
- You are not.
I forbid it.
You forbid it?
Oh, excuse me,
I didn't realize we
were back in the cave!
My work pays for this cave.
And I will not let you jeopardize my job
because you're jealous and insecure.
Go to hell, Rogelio!
Uh-oh. Looks like someone's
the man of the doghouse.
Okay, I'm sorry. Come back.
Xiomara, don't leave!
Wh-What is wrong? Why are you smiling?
You called me jealous and insecure.
And it hit me that...
that's true!
I am jealous and insecure!
And even though that's
a crappy feeling...
that's a normal feeling.
Normal like before I had cancer.
You're right.
And I yelled at you for
being jealous and insecure!
I know!
You never would have yelled
at me before the PET scan.
Oh...
We're getting back to normal.
Unlike Rogelio's last kiss,
this is a very wanted advance.
Thank you for yelling at me.
I'm prepared to yell
at you all night long.
And after a five-year rest period,
I'll be ready to yell at you some more.
Oh, I plan to yell, too.
And yes, friends, that's how Xo and Ro
got their groove back.
Not feeling so groovy...
Don't call her, Petra.
You're moving forward, remember?
P-Please. No... It's been torture,
not having you here.
Look, I-I... I need you back.
What we have doesn't
come around every day.
So much for Petra's fresh start.
And you picked up the phone.
Look, you wouldn't have done that
if a small part of you
didn't miss me, too.
So what will it take for
you to come back to me?
I'd consider it
for triple my salary.
Done. You're worth every penny.
And way cheaper than
renovating the entire hotel.
And I want a lunch hour every day.
Every day?
Good-bye, Mrs. Solano.
It's a deal.
But you start tomorrow.
See you then.
Well, at least she got
one of her exes back.
And continuing our apology tour...
And, again, I'm just so sorry.
It's your life,
and I had no right to criticize it.
Oh, you don't have to explain anything.
I'm glad.
Yeah, but it's a good one.
And it made me realize
it's time for a change for me, too.
So... I'm moving out.
I know.
But what am I waiting for?
Mateo and I will get a studio,
which is what I can afford right now.
Down the road,
hopefully something bigger.
I don't.
I just think it's time for
the next phase in my life.
For what it's worth,
I totally agree.
And speaking of
moving forward with life...
So... last night was nice.
So was this morning.
It was.
But it didn't exactly solve
all my insecurity and jealousy.
I know.
And you can come to set if you want to.
I don't want to.
But that's the thing.
I want to get my own life back on track.
Figure out what comes next.
And I want to trust you.
I should trust you.
Well, I should have trusted you
when you said you felt like
River didn't get the message.
But I promise you, Xiomara,
she got it this time.
True, for the record.
But while Rogelio's home life
might be back to normal...
his work life is about
to get very uncomfortable.
He loves me not.
He will pay.
Sync and correction by LittleDuck
www.addic7ed.com