How are you?
Hello?
Yes, this is Harold Angel.
Yep, middle initial "R" just
like in the phone book.
Excuse me? Winesap.
Herman Winesap of
Winesap and Mackintosh.
Hold on a second.
Okay, Winesap.. of
Winesap and Mackintosh.
Okay, I got it.
Of course I know
what an attorney is.
Yeah, it's like a lawyer,
only the bills are bigger.
Sure, I'll hold. Asshole.
Mr. Winesap, yeah, Harold Angel.
Well, yeah, I could be free.
Would this be with your firm?
Okay, give me that again.
Louis.
How do you spell that?
Cyphre. Okay. What
is it, foreign?
A foreigner? Is your client
a foreign gentleman?
Okay.
Mr. Winesap, could you give
me a few more details?
Okay. No, I know the place.
It's a long way up,
but I can be there.
Hallelujah!
Permit me to be
transmittable, hallelujah.
reincarnatable, hallelujah.
Permit me to be
reproducible, hallelujah.
For His kingdom is
yours, today, right now.
Hallelujah. Follow me.
Follow me through his paths.
Hallelujah. I want you to show
right now how much you love God.
I want you to show
as your tithe.
I want you to open up your
hearts and open up your wallets.
And open up your purses.
And open up your pockets.
And give it up. Praise the Lord.
Somebody's been talkin' about me, about
I've been riding around in a Cadillac.
If you love me, and you
wanna give to me..
then I should be
in a Rolls Royce.
Let's hear it, Brother.
Let's go. Yes!
Hey! Hey! Come on.
- Mr. Angel?
- Yeah.
Herman Winesap.
Would you come with me, please?
An unfortunate husband..
of one of Pastor John's flock
took a gun to his head.
Most unpleasant.
Mr. Angel? Please?
Mr. Angel.
Allow me to introduce my
client, Monsieur Louis Cyphre.
Hiya. Harry Angel.
Pleased to meet you, Mr. Angel.
I don't want to appear rude or impolite,
but do you have any I.D., before we begin?
Sure. Yeah. Here.
Let me see what I got here.
How's that?
Nothing personal. It's just
that I'm a little overcautious.
- You know how these things are.
- Oh, I know.
So, how did you hear about me?
I guess you guys just looked
in the phone book, huh?
Usually that's what happens.
Because my name is Angel.
It's under A's.
People..You know,
people are lazy.
They flick through. They see
the first name in the book.
- Johnny Favorite.
- Excuse me?
Do you by chance remember
the name Johnny Favorite?
Remember the name Johnny?
No, I don't think so.
- You never knew him?
- Am I supposed to know him?
He was a crooner before the war.
Quite famous in his way.
I'll tell ya, Mr. "Cyphre,"
you know, I..
Mr. Cyphre.
I'm sorry, beg.. I'm sorry.
Mr. Cyphres. I usually don't get
involved in anything really heavy.
I usually handle
small-time stuff:
insurance jobs, divorces,
things of that nature.
I get lucky, sometimes
I handle people.
But I don't know no,
you know, crooners..
or anybody famous, you know?
- His real name was Liebling.
- I don't..
I don't know any
Liebling either.
So what is it you
guys want from me?
- Does this man owe you money?
- Not quite.
I gaveJohnny some help at the
beginning of his career.
So were you, like, his agent?
No, no, no. Nothing so..
Monsieur Cyphre has a contract.
Certain collateral was involved, to be
forfeited in the event of his death.
You're losin' me a little bit. Are
we talkin' about a guy who's dead?
No, he was drafted in '43.
North Africa.
Special Entertainment Services.
There was an attack.
He was badly injured
about the head and face.
- He had..
- Amnesia, I think you call it.
- Shell shock?
- Shell shock. Yes.
- I know how that feels.
- Why? Were you in the services?
Yes, I was in for a
short period of time.
But I got a little fucked up real quick.
Excuse my language.
And they shipped me back home..
and I sort of missed
the whole shebang.
You know, the war, the medals,
the whole nine yards.
And I guess you could
say I was lucky.
Johnny wasn't so lucky. He
returned home a virtual zombie.
Favorite's friends had him transferred
to a private hospital upstate.
There was some sort of radical
psychiatric treatment involved.
Favorite's lawyers had the
power of attorney to..
Pay the bills, things like that.
But you know how these things are.
He remained a vegetable, and
my contract was never honored.
I see.
I don't want to sound mercenary or
anything, but you must understand..
that my interest in Johnny is only
in finding out if he's alive..
or if he's dead.
Each year my office receives a
signed affidavit confirming..
that Johnny Liebling is
indeed among the living.
Until this last weekend,
when quite by chance..
Monsieur Cyphre and I were in the vicinity
of the hospital just outside Poughkeepsie.
We decided to check for ourselves but
were given misleading information.
- Yeah, the runaround.
- Yes. I didn't want to cause a scene.
I hate to have any
sort of a fuss.
So I thought perhaps you could..
subtly, in a more quiet manner..
- You want me to check it out.
- Check it out.
Okay. Yeah.
It's funny. I have a feeling
I've met you before.
I don't know. I don't think so.
Do you by chance remember
the name Johnny Favorite?
His real name was Liebling.
My interest in Johnny is only in finding
out if he's alive or if he's dead.
- May I help you?
- Yes.
My name is Harry Conroy, and I'm with
the National Institute of Health.
Is there anyone in particular
you'd like to see, Mr. Conroy?
The Institute is conducting a
survey of incurable trauma cases..
and I understand you have a patient
here fitting that description.
I'm afraid we can't let you see
anyone without an appointment, sir.
Oh, sure. I appreciate that.
But maybe, you know..
you could check the files and
make sure I'm on the right track.
I don't want to bother
anybody unnecessarily.
Okay? Thank you.
- What's the name of the patient?
- Liebling.Jonathan Liebling.
One moment please. I will check.
So, was you workin'
here last weekend?
No. Day off.
- Did you do anything nice?
- My sister's wedding.
We did have a Mr. Liebling..
but it says here he
was transferred.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, that's what it says here.
- When was that?
- Years ago. December '43.
May I take a look at this?
Thank you.
- Is this recent?
- It's an old file.
It's in ballpoint. You know, they
weren't too big on ballpoint in '43.
- Is that ballpoint?
- Yeah.
Well, I'll be. They didn't
have ballpoints back then?
This here Dr. Fowler..
does he still work here?
Just part-time. He's old.
Thank you.
About time for your evening fix?
Who are you? How'd
you get in here?
Through the mail slot.
I'm a private detective.
Breaking and entering is a serious
crime, whoever or whatever you are.
Hey, man, call the police.
Which you won't do in case they
discover your little opium den..
you got in the icebox there.
I'm a doctor. I'm perfectly entitled
to keep pharmaceuticals at home.
Hey, look, Doc, tell it to
somebody else, all right?
We're not talkin' about a
Band-Aid and two Bongateen.
- How long you been hooked?
- What do you want of me?
Information about
Johnny Liebling.
I vaguely remember treating a patient
of that name many years ago.
Hey, look, Doc, I'm not
foolin' around here.
Either you start giving me some straight
answers, or I'll call the police myself.
I've seen the works cookin' upstairs,
pal, and it ain't Mr. Salk's vaccine.
I remember. He was in detainer
during the war. Neuro case.
No chance of recovery. So we transferred
him to a V.A. hospital in Albany.
Hey, Doc, I hate to shake you
up, but I checked with Albany.
He's not there. You
faked the transfer.
I did that quickly because
he had a visitor recently.
In 12 years, he
hadn't had a visitor.
Popular guy, huh?
- Where is he now?
- I honestly don't know.
Look. Come here.
I haven't seen him since he
was a patient in the war.
Look, Doc, you're in a cold sweat.
Look at you.
You can't wait for me to leave here so
you can raid the goodies in the icebox.
Now, the sooner you
get out with it..
the sooner you can shoot
yourself to Palookaville, okay?
I'm gonna ask you again.
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
Some people came one
night many years ago.
He got in the car with him & drove away.
I never saw him again.
He got into a car? I thought
this guy was a vegetable.
When he first came here, he was
in a coma, but he soon recovered.
But he still suffered
from acute amnesia.
The friends? Who
were the friends?
The gentleman's name was Kelly.
Edward Kelly.
The young lady, I
don't know her.
- She stayed in the car.
- Where were they taking him?
I think down south. The man
said, "We're taking him home."
- What was the deal?
- $25,000.
For what?
To maintain the pretense that he was
still a patient in the hospital.
Didn't the
administration suspect?
But why should they? I kept
the charts up to date..
and no one asks questions
when the bills get paid.
I want you to tell me
about Johnny Liebling.
- What did he look like?
- I have no idea what he looked like.
His face was damaged. He had
extensive facial reconstruction.
He was still in bandages
the day he left.
Tell me about this guy Kelly.
- It's so long. I have only a vague memory.
- Come on.
I can't remember. He was well-dressed.
He had a southern accent.
- I..
- What?
- Truly can't remember.
- All right, Doc. All right.
Hey. We're gonna have a
little lie-down, all right?
I'm gonna go out, and I'm
gonna grab a cheeseburger.
Maybe a few hours cold turkey will
refresh your memory. All right?
Come on.
Watch yourself there.
Okay, Doc. We're gonna
take a little nap now.
Sit your ass down.
I'm gonna clear your
mind a little bit.
I'm gonna go out. Maybe
when I get back..
I'll fix you some goodies
from the icebox, all right?
Listen, you tell me what I want to
know, I'll be out ofyour hair forever.
Johnny.
Harry. Harry.
Harry.
Hey, I'm back, Doc. I brought
you a little somethin'.
I didn't think you'd want a
cheeseburger and a shake.
- I won't. Bye.
- Bye.
- Hey, Allie.
- Hey, Harry.
That your boyfriend?
- He got a car and everything?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- Bye.
- See you later.
- Did you see him?
- No.
- Why not?
- 'Cause it would have been difficult.
- Why?
- Why? 'Cause he's not there.
Your Johnny Favorite walked out of
Sarah Harvest Dodd's 12 years ago..
wearin' his best suit and a
new face wrapped in bandages.
With a headache.
He took off with some guy
called Kelly and a girl.
Do you know this Kelly?
It seems that this
guy Kelly paid off..
some bent doctor called Fowler to
pinch-hit for your guy all these years.
He's been coverin' up
for him ever since.
It looks like ourJohnny has found
himself a perfect disappearing act.
It seems so.
You know what they
say about slugs.
No, what do they
say about slugs?
They always leave slime
in their tracks.
- You'll find him.
- No, I won't find him.
'Cause I left out
one little detail.
This Dr. Fowler guy ended up dead with
his fuckin' brains blown out all over.
- Fowler?
- Yeah, Fowler.
- Did you kill him?
- No, I didn't kill him.
But the cops might think I did.
Hey, look. I took on $125 a day
missing persons job with you.
Now I'm a murder suspect.
That's it. I'm out.
Such are the hazards of
your profession, Mr. Angel.
If the fee bothers you,
we can have it adjusted.
No, Cyphre, you bother me. Listen,
the closest I ever come..
to death is standin' on the corner on
2nd Avenue watching the stiffs go by..
in the hearse, all right,
that's the way I like it.
Are you afraid?
Yeah, I'm afraid.
I'll instruct my lawyer immediately
to send you a check for $5,000.
If you don't want the job,
I'll engage someone else.
- $5,000?
- $5,000.
You must want this
Johnny pretty bad.
I don't like messy accounts.
You know, some religions think that
the egg is the symbol of the soul.
- Did you know that?
- No, I didn't know that.
Would you like an egg?
No, thank you. I got a
thing about chickens.
Gavilan weighs 146 pounds
tonight, just a pound..
under the welterweight limit.
Turner weighs 144 1|2.
I t's a $270,000 gate, an all-time
record for the welterweight title.
It's after 11:00, Harry.
You're late.
I'm sorry. Did you get it?
If I lose my job, I'll come
and be your secretary.
Hey, I couldn't pay you what the Times
pays. Besides, they're not gonna miss it.
They must be digging up stuff
like this all the time.
Hiya, Johnny. Where
the fuck are you?
Johnny Favorite was a
crooner, like you said.
I didn't realize he was so big.
He used to be in a band called
the Spider Simpson orchestra.
- All dead. Only Spider's here in town.
- Oh, yeah? Where is he?
I wrote it all down.
The dyke in Archiving's library
is getting suspicious.
My boss hasn't researched
a story in years.
You can get the files.
Spider's in an old people's
home on 138th Street.
Oh, wonderful. I get
to go to Harlem again.
There was a picture of Johnny
with a guy called Toots Sweet.
- A guitar player.
- And?
No one's heard of him for years.
Now here's the juicy bit.
He was engaged to a rich broad,
name of Margaret Krusemark.
Dad Ethan owns
half of Louisiana.
Met Johnny at a high school
prom in New Orleans.
Johnny shit on her, and she
went back home to Daddy.
- Oh, yeah, there's lots on her spells.
- Spells?
What do you mean, spells?
You mean like eye of a newt and
toe of a frog, that kind of shit?
Seems she's a bit of a crackpot.
Casting spells at
society dos and stuff.
Didn't go down too well with
the lvy League stiffos.
Oh, yeah, she was known as
the Witch of Wellesley.
The Witch of Wellesley.
- Did I do good?
- Yeah, you did great.
So, what do I got? I got some kind
of religious loony for a client.
I gotta find Johnny
Golden Tonsils.
We don't know where he is. He
probably doesn't know who he is.
I got a geriatric bandleader
at a home in Harlem.
I got a guitar player
called Toots Sweet.
- What else I got?
- A hard-on.
Are you okay?
January 3, 1955.
Louis Cyphre.
Winesap and Mackintosh,
attorneys.
As reported, Johnny
Favorite has not been..
in the Sarah Dodd Nursing Home of
Poughkeepsie for the last 12 years.
He was taken away by a man
called Edward Kelly and a girl.
The girl is unidentified.
Kelly paid a Dr. Fowler
$25,000 to falsify reports..
stating Favorite was
still at the hospital.
The doctor is now deceased.
Before Johnny's accident, it seemed
his career was goin' great..
till he started to dump
on everyone around him.
I tracked down Spider Simpson,
Johnny's old bandleader.
Spider now resides at the
Lincoln Presbyterian Hospice..
for the Elderly,
on 138th Street.
Johnny also had a close buddy, a
guitarplayer called Toots Sweet.
Toots went back to Algiers.
That ain't Algiers in Africa.
That's Algiers in New Orleans.
I think maybe Margaret went back
there too, and maybe Johnny.
Oh, yeah. According to Spider,
Johnny had a secret love.
A black lady called
Evangeline Proudfoot.
Evangeline ran some kind of
spooky store in Harlem..
called Mammy Carter's.
You don't need to
know that, Cyphre.
I think secret loves
should stay secret.
And the only other person
Johnny was seeing regularly..
was a palm reader out in Coney
Island called Madame Zora.
Hey, you Izzy?
Yeah.
- It looks like the last of the sun, huh?
- Yep.
Hey, listen. The guy in the arcade over
there told me you might be able to help.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
I'm lookin' for a Madame Zora.
Yeah, sure, I know her. A friend
of the wife before the war.
- It's the fortune teller, right?
- Yeah, and then some.
Real creepy. I hate those
hocus-pocus bitches. Fuckin' witch.
Her and the wife got
along real well.
The wife's a Baptist. Oh, here.
Have a nose shield.
Go on. Take one.
I found a whole box fell
under the boardwalk.
There's not much sun
in the city right now.
Yeah, but it keeps
the rain off too.
Hey, listen. You ever hear
of a Johnny Favorite?
- The singer?
- The crooner.
Used to visit Madame
Zora all the time?
I heard of him, but I don't
know nothin' about him.
Ask the wife. She'll know. She's always
singin' stupid tunes off the radio.
She knows all that kind of shit.
- She likes the water, huh?
- Nope. Hates it.
She's gettin' on the heavy side. She
thinks it's good for varicose veins.
All right. Thanks.
Listen. What do you do around
here in the summertime?
- I bite the heads off of rats.
- What do you do in the winter?
Same.
Excuse me!
I was just talkin' to
your husband over there!
I was inquiring about
a Madame Zora!
Yeah, I knew her before the war.
Madame Zora, you say?
Yeah, she was some kind
of gypsy fortune-teller.
Yeah, she used to have the booth
across the boardwalk from me.
She weren't no gypsy.
She was a debutante.
She was messin' with more
than readin' tea leaves.
Did you ever see her with a
guy called Johnny Favorite?
Yeah, he was cute. Used to visit her
all the time. She was real stuck on him.
The guy with the golden tonsils, they
used to call him. I knew all his tunes.
Hey, did you ever hear of a..
of a Margaret Krusemark?
Don't be a gazoony, fella. Madame
Zora was Margaret Krusemark.
What happened to her?
Packed up her stuff one day & closed up
for good. Went back home. Down south.
Do you have any idea where I
could find Johnny Favorite?
Nope. Maybe the cemetery.
Wanna hear one of his tunes?
I cried for you
Now it's your turn to cry over..
Hey, thanks for the nose shield.
- Okay.
- I'm gonna need it where I'm goin'.
- In Brooklyn?
- Nah. Louisiana.
Nice.
Where'd he go?
Mr. Angel.
Sorry to keep you waitin'.
You're a little early.
I had a bad line. I didn't
know if it was 4:00 or 4:30.
Wow, this is really a
wild place you got here.
Yes, I've been very happy here.
Hey, you know, I never had
my fortune read before.
- Does this take long?
- I'll just take the details now.
It usually takes me a couple
of days to do a chart.
Tea?
- Do you want some tea?
- Oh, yes. Thank you.
Darjeeling, jasmine or oolong?
- Oolong.
- Not many people like oolong.
You play the piano?
No, not exactly.
Sing?
I can carry a tune,
but not really.
So, who's this mean-looking guy?
It's my father.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry. He hates it too.
You know, he really looks like one of
those guys in an old pirate movie.
What's his name?
- Ethan.
- Ethan. Ethan Krusemark.
I'll tell ya, you know, I never
saw any of Ethan's movies.
Do you speak French, Mr. Angel?
- I'm from Brooklyn.
- I'd prefer it if you didn't smoke.
Oh, that's okay.
- Cream or sugar?
- No. Straight up is fine, thank you.
Now. I'm gonna need your
exact date of birth.
Sure.
Okay, I was..
born February 14.
1918. That's Valentine's Day.
How curious.
I used to know a boy who was
born on that exact same date.
Really?
You know how it is. All the
soldiers home on leave and all.
Hey, maybe we could pull your friend's
chart and save ourselves some time.
I don't think so, Mr. Angel.
Every person's very different. I
don't think you'd like his chart.
- Place of birth?
- Brooklyn, New York.
Why, was he a jerk or
something, your friend?
Yeah, you could say that.
So, I guess you just didn't get along.
You and Johnny.
You and Johnny Favorite?
Who are you?
I was an old army buddy.
I thought that you two
were kind of a..You know.
All right. Look. I
ain't no army buddy.
I'm just a guy who was
paid to snoop around.
But to tell you the truth, I
wasn't born on Valentine's Day.
lt'sJohnny's future
that I'm interested in.
Johnny has no future. He's dead.
He died 12 years ago, and
Mr. Angel, I'd like you to leave.
Look, I know you're probably thinking
who's this creep lookin' to snitch around.
I don't want to sound
nosy or nothin', but..
He's dead, Mr. Angel. And
if he isn't, he is to me.
Wow. He must've hurt
you pretty bad.
We all have our
scars, Mr. Angel.
Look. You know, I don't know
too much about this guy..
but he must've been really
stupid if he let you go.
Lies and cruelty come very easy to
some people. Good-bye, Mr. Angel.
It's a pity. You know, I really would've
liked to have gotten my palm read.
Could've held your hand
a little while longer.
I don't think you'd
like what I see.
That's a very pretty
necklace you got there.
- Hi.
You got any Hygeia
the Conqueror root?
- Powdered or hanging?
- I don't know. I'm not really sure.
- Caught in the rain, huh?
- Yeah.
Two roots. $1.20.
Listen, I have a question
I wanna ask you.
I have an acquaintance
back in Harlem..
who used to deal in Hygeia
the Conqueror root.
And her name was Evangeline.
Did you ever hear of her?
Practically everyone around here
is called Evangeline, mister.
After the poem. You
know the poem?
Yeah, I know the poem. This..
This acquaintance of mine had a store
in Harlem. It was the same name. Carter.
Everybody uses the name, mister. Like
Howard Johnson? This is the real place.
Her name was Proudfoot,
Evangeline Proudfoot.
Yeah, I knew her.
She used to come back here all the
time when she was livin' in New York.
Do you know where she is now?
She got sick. Died. Went
back to Holy Shelter Swamp.
They buried her in Almondville.
She was waitin' on some fella.
- Just like in the poem, huh?
- Just like the poem.
$1.20.
Who was the guy?
She never told.
Okay, thanks.
- A week, you say?
- Yeah, at most.
What you crying for? What? What?
What you crying for?
Let's go see Grandma.
Who's over there?
It's Grandma. Grandma.
Let's go.
Give me your hand.
Soap.
Excuse me?
- Miss Proudfoot?
- Yeah.
Oh, I'm sorry. I got
these from some guy..
and it's funny how some
babies react to 'em.
- I'm sorry.
- Stop crying.
Listen, I was hoping maybe I
could talk with your mama.
Yeah? You're a little late for that.
Did you know her?
No, I've never met her,
but I was hoping..
maybe she could answer a
few questions for me.
- What are you? Some kind of cop?
- No. My name's Harry Angel.
How are you? I'm a
private detective.
- So what's..
- Epiphany.
- Epiphany?
- Yeah.
Your mama left you with a very
beautiful name, Epiphany.
Not much else.
Actually, to be quite frank,
I'm looking for a friend..
of your mama's, a guy
called Johnny Favorite.
Yeah? I met all of
mama's friends.
I never met anyone
called Favorite.
Jesus. Oh, shit! I got a
thing about chickens.
Yeah. This guy Favorite..
he was friends with your mama, back
in New York City, before the war.
Yeah? She never told me.
My mama had a lot of guys.
She liked men.
How 'bout a guy
named Toots Sweet?
He was a friend of Favorite's.
Did you ever meet him?
He was supposed to be a
pretty good guitar player.
I was gonna go try to
catch his act tonight.
Listen, I'm gonna be stayin'
here in town, in a hotel.
And I figured if maybe, if you could
remember anything that might help me..
maybe you could give me a call.
You're a very pretty girl, Epiphany.
Your name suits you.
Chickens.
Hey, what are you after him for?
Johnny Favorite?
I'm not really after him. I'm just
being paid to find out where he is.
He could be six feet under.
Then I'll have to buy a shovel.
She had two cups of coffee
And I had one small cup of tea
She just walked out of my life
Left them low-down
dirty blues with me
it was on
Oh, Lord, it was on
On a rainy day
One time for Toots
I t was on
- Oh, Lord it was on
- How's it hangin', sugar?
On a rainy day
Go ahead.
Hey, that was some beautiful tune you
were singing in there, Mr. Sweet.
- Toots, son. Thank you.
- Yeah, listen. Can I buy you a drink?
No, I get mine on the house.
Two Sisters cocktails.
Don't know what's in 'em, but I get a bigger
kick out of 'em than I do six stingers.
Listen. You know that I heard
you play years ago in New York?
Yeah, it was before the war
at the old Dicky Wells bar.
- Yeah.
You was hammin' it up pretty good
with some cat called Johnny Favorite.
Yeah, I vaguely remember
playin' with that guy once.
Yeah, you and him was
buddies, weren't you?
No. He made a record of one of my
songs, but that don't make us buddies.
Say, are you a dick
or book writer?
I'm neither. What I
am, I'm a journalist.
You see, what I'm doing
is, I'm doing this piece.
The piece is on Johnny and the
old Spider Simpson Orchestra.
I remember Spider. He used to play them
drums like two jack rabbits fuckin'.
Got to go, son. Ain't
got much time.
A piss and a spit and back to work. Try
one of them Two Sisters cocktails..
and then you can make the whole
thing up, any way you want to.
That's what you newspaper
people do anyway, don't you?
He starts his lovin'
when you get through
Can't even take a piss.
Hey, look, pal. I just wanted
to have a little talk..
with you about Johnny Favorite
and Evangeline Proud..
I'm too big to go hidin' under beds.
I don't know nothin'.
Two Sisters cocktails are the only thing
I'm interested in nowadays. Fuck!
- What's going on, Toots?
- Nothing.
Mind your own business.
I wanna piss.
Ifyou don't get the hell out of here,
I mean clean out on the sidewalk..
you gonna wish your little
white ass never was born.
Please. I got a thing
about chickens.
So take a tip, honey
and just leave my door
Because your key don't
fit in my lock no more
You got the right key
You're knockin '
on the wrong door
All right, now. Hey.
This is the end of
bullshit time, pal, okay?
I got a good look at
you and Epiphany..
doin' your hot-shoe
number with the chicken.
And listen.
I ain't up on all this voodoo shit.
I'm from Brooklyn.
We ain't all Baptists
down here, sonny.
What's the story with
this Proudfoot girl?
She's a mambo priestess, like her mom.
Has been since she was 13.
When's the last time you saw Johnny
Favorite at one of those chicken stuffings?
He used to run around with
Mom Mambo, didn't he?
I told you, I ain't seen
him since before the war.
What about the chicken
foot in the john, huh?
- Means I got a big mouth.
- Not big enough, Toots.
What's this fuckin' star you wear in
your mouth? I'll tell you what.
I'm gonna give you my hotel
number, and you give me a call..
in case you hear anything.
You never know, the
next time you get..
a special delivery chicken foot,
you may need a little help.
I'll tell you, as far
as I'm concerned..
any dead chicken's a
good chicken to me.
Hey, only cops and bad
news don't knock.
Only private dicks
sleep so late.
That's quite a dream
you were having.
I was on my way to
Mandalay again.
Shit. That's some leak
you got up there.
Here. This your name?
- Yeah.
- That your hotel?
- You're standin' in it, ain't you?
- Your handwritin'?
I think so.
Then perhaps you'd
like to tell us why..
we found that in the hand
of a dead guitar player?
- Toots Sweet is dead?
- Yeah. Toots Sweet.
Only this one weren't so quick.
This one took time.
How did he die?
Technically, asphyxiation
by his own genitalia.
But not so technically.
Somebody cut his dick off, stuffed it
in his mouth and choked him to death.
Took to redecoratin' his apartment
with the poorjerk's blood.
So, when'd you see him, Angel?
- I interviewed him yesterday around 1:00.
- In connection with what?
Missing person.
Who?
Some cat took a walk 12 years ago. I saw
Toots in an old photograph with him.
What's the name of this
party you're lookin' for?
Sorry, friend. Can't say.
That's right of privacy.
- I'm workin' for a New York lawyer.
- Name?
Oh, come on, man.
Winesap. You want his number,
you want his address?
Ask Tess Trueheart over there. It's
in the book he's flickin' through.
It's under "W," genius.
You know Ted Williams,
the baseball player?
Yeah.
Herman Winesap.
All right, is that it, guys?
That's it.
You and your "right to
privacy" can go eat lunch.
But don't stroll too far, Angel.
Not till we talk to
this lawyer of yours.
You ever watch the
Mickey Mouse Club?
'Cause you know what today is?
Today is Wednesday. It's
"anything can happen" day.
Hey, man, you want a tune?
Yeah, I got a tune for you.
Hiya, boys.
Oh, yeah, same to you.
Hey, I'm gettin' kind of hungry. You
wanna sell some of those things?
Hey, Pop.
- Ten cents a sack.
- Sure, man, give me a sack.
Oh, shit! Get..
You listen good, mister.
Margaret Krusemark's old man wants
you on that first train home.
Get that fuckin'
thing away from me!
If you don't, my dog here's gonna
bite your fuckin' face clean off.
Fuck!
What happened to you?
A dog bit me.
Yeah, so? What do you want?
Right now, I need a laundry.
- Listen, Epithany.
- Epiphany.
Epiphany. I got something
on my mind I wanna ask you.
Yeah. The other night I
saw you and Toots Sweet..
boogyin' with the cock-a-doodle-doo
out in the woods.
Looked like you all
were havin' some party.
Yeah, so what's your problem?
It's a free country.
Not for chickens it ain't.
Oh, yeah, you got a thing about chickens.
I remember.
Listen, Epiphany, Toots
is..Toots is dead.
I know. I heard.
- And you set him up.
- No, I didn't.
You were the only one that
knew I was seein' Toots.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
You're the one that sent the gift-wrapped
chicken for two, aren't you?
Yeah, well, Toots
had a big mouth.
I guess he did, judgin' by
what the cops found in it.
Quite a cute religion you got.
Nailing a man to a cross
ain't so cute, either.
Yeah, I know. You got to kill
a chicken to make the soup.
We don't go around murdering people,
all right? What about Johnny Favorite?
So now you remember
him after all, huh?
Yeah, he was my father.
Mince?
Mince, I'm gonna pick the
baby up later, okay?
He's gonna be all right.
Hey, look, if you got anything you're
holding out, now's a good time to tell.
Nothing to tell.
Johnny never came
back from the war.
Mama waited. Mama died.
It's sad and simple.
Epiphany, there's too many
dead bodies floatin' around..
even for Louisiana.
I'd tell your old man
to look out for you.
- You do have a husband.
- No. No husband.
Jesus, you got beautiful
eyes, Epiphany.
You really do. They're
truly beautiful.
They're the kind of eyes you can
tell just what's goin' on inside.
- Right now you're scared.
- I manage.
- Hey, well, listen..
- Yeah. I'll call you if I hear anything.
Hey.
Call me ifyou don't.
All right?
I have a message for you.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I'm so glad you could come.
Yeah. I didn't know you
were comin' to town.
I have a speaking
engagement in Baton Rouge..
and I thought it would be opportune
to catch up with your progress.
I'm tellin' ya..
Progress ain't too good.
I found out a lot of stuff.
But so far, no Johnny Favorite.
How unfortunate.
All I got is a bellyful
of hocus-pocus..
and three stiffs.
- Stiffs?
- Yeah.
Dead bodies, Mr. Cyphre.
Murders.
- Murders.
- Yeah.
I got Fowler..Johnny's
doctor bumped himself off.
I got this old voodoo
guy, Toots Sweet.
He got choked to death with a part
of the body meant for pissing with.
This is a church, Mr. Angel.
I'll tell you something.
I know it's a church..
but there's a lot of religion
going around with this thing.
It's very weird, and I don't
understand it. It's ugly.
They say there's just enough
religion in the world..
to make men hate one another, but
not enough to make them love.
Oh, is that what they say?
I'll tell you something,
Mr. Cyphre, there..
wasn't too much love around
for Johnny Favorite.
All right, that guy was bad luck and
it's starting to rub off on me.
I'm a murder suspect
already in two cases.
The police found my name and my
address in Toots Sweet's hand.
I know. Winesap told me.
You must be careful, Mr. Angel.
And a third? You said
there were three murders.
I checked out Johnny's old society
girlfriend.. Margaret Krusemark.
- Do you know her?
- Vaguely.
Vaguely? Let me tell you, I'm a
little fed up with fuckin' "vaguely."
"Vaguely" is puttin' a noose around
my neck, and I'm startin' to choke.
So, Mr. Cyphre, did
you know her or not?
I knew about her, but I
never actually knew her.
All right. I'll tell you what.
She was doin' my chart. I gave her
Johnny's birth date.. February 14..
Except someone got to her and took
out their own Valentine's card.
They split her open and
they cut out her heart.
I guess she couldn't predict
the future for herself.
The future isn't what it
used to be, Mr. Angel.
- And your conclusions?
- I haven't any.
All I know is Johnny's runnin' around
bumpin' off everyone he used to know.
And more and more it's me
who's on the line for it.
I'm bein' set up, and it's scarin'
the shit out of me, all right?
So why don't you just tell me and level
with me what the fuck is goin' on here?
Just Johnny Favorite and the debt
that's owed to me, Mr. Angel.
I have old-fashioned
ideas about honor.
You know, an eye for an
eye, things like that.
Who the fuck are you, Cyphre?
Watch your language.
Hey, I don't give a fuck
if this is a church, okay?
Churches give me the creeps.
I don't like churches.
- Are you an atheist?
- Yes, I am.
I'm from Brooklyn.
I'll be in town
for a day or two.
Let me know what else you
find, and if you need money..
No, no, the money's fine.
But if I ain't careful, that
5,000 bucks you gave me..
could just buy me a seat
on the electric chair.
Hi.
Frightened eyes never lie.
Come on. Come on inside.
- Where's your child?
- He's with Mincy.
She's bringing him over later.
She's got 14 of her own,
so he'll be okay there.
Look, Epiphany, you're very welcome
to stay here or I'll get you a room.
No, I'm okay.
I'll tell you what, I'm gonna have a drink.
You want a drink?
You're gonna have one anyway.
- I've been thinkin', Epiphany.
- Yeah?
I was wondering what the hell your mama
ever saw in a guy like Johnny Favorite?
I don't know. Whatever he had,
he sure stole her heart away.
To tell you the truth,
the guy was a creep.
She sure missed him.
I mean, I'll tell ya.
What does a lady see in a guy that runs
around choppin' up pigeons, you know?
You know what they say.
It's always the badass that makes
a girl's heart beat faster.
Did she ever say
anything about him?
- Johnny?
- Yeah.
- Just two things.
- Yeah, like what?
She once said that Johnny Favorite
was as close to true evil..
as she ever wanted to come.
- What else did she say?
- He was a terrific lover.
How old are you, Epiphany?
- Seventeen.
That's kind ofyoung to
have a kid, isn't it?
It's old enough.
- So, where'd the father go?
- I never knew him.
I'm sorry. To tell
you the truth..
I don't know why I
took this room.
It was at Bamboucher.
When the spirits possess
you, it's called chevalier.
Oh, yes, I'm familiar with that..
Chevrolet.
- Chevalier.
- That's what I said: Chevrolet.
Mounted by the gods.
- Oh, so the gods got you pregnant?
- Yeah.
I understand that. Sorry.
I'm not. It was the
best fuck I ever had.
Want to dance?
In here?
Yeah, here.
I got bit by a dog this mornin'.
I can't move around.
You won't feel a thing.
- I'll dance with you.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. But you gotta promise.
- What's that?
No chickens.
- Okay.
- Come on.Jump on.
I should've
recognized the knock.
At least you got reason for
sleepin' late this time.
Down here, Angel, we don't
mix with the jigaboos.
The colored folks
keep to themselves.
Hey, I ain't from down here.
- You cut yourself?
- A dog bit me.
Somebody named Margaret Krusemark
figure in this missing persons case?
- No. Why?
- She's dead.
That nigger guitar player of
yours, he don't matter a shit.
He was into voodoo. They
86 one another two a week.
This Krusemark dame, she comes from a
Louisiana money family..white money.
So two people get bumped off in the
same week. What's the connection?
- Similar circumstances.
- Like what?
Did she get her
dick cut off too?
No. Some fucker cut her heart out,
neat as a butcher on Decatur Street.
Look, mine's a missing persons. It's not
a murder, okay? Why you telling me this?
I want to know the name of the
party you're lookin' for.
I already told you. Call New York.
Talk to the lawyer.
I did. That fancy mouthpiece, he gave
me the same big-city shit as you.
What do you want me to say? Hey,
you and Effie Klinker over there..
why don't you just fuck
off and leave me alone?
This ain't jigaboo town, ass wipe! You
play jump rope with Louisiana law..
and I'm gonna stuff your big-city
smarts right up your New York ass!
This Krusemark broad, she was into
stargazing, black magic, all kinds of shit.
There ain't nothin' worse for a cop than
people who get killed for nutso reasons.
Sorry if I made a mess. Maybe you
can get your nigger to clean it up.
Girl of my dreams
I I love you
Honest I do
You are so sweet
If I could just hold your charms
Again in my arms
Life..
What's that tune you're singin'?
You don't know it? It's
one by Johnny Favorite.
My mom used to sing it
to me all the time.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
If I could just
Hold your charms
Again in my arms
Life would be complete
Shit!
Thanks.
What do you want, Mr. Angel?
I guess you already knew that.
Why should I?
A couple of your morons
with a matching poodle..
have been chasing my
balls around for days.
I'm looking for Johnny Favorite.
As far as I know, that dance
band scumbag is dead.
That dance band scumbag may be the
one that killed your daughter.
Who's employing you?
I can't say.
I'll pay.
So do they.
Twelve years ago you and your
daughter snatched Favorite..
out of some nuthatch
up in Poughkeepsie.
You paid a junkie doctor 25 grand to
pretend Johnny was still a turniphead.
You did a pretty good
job until a week ago.
You used the name Edward Kelly.
Let's walk over here. It's a little
private, and you can sample our gumbo.
That's all right. I
got an acid stomach.
Besides, Cajun cooking kills me.
It's a pity about your stomach.
You'd have enjoyed our gumbo.
I was Edward Kelly. It was me
who paid Fowler the 25 G's.
- Did Favorite know you?
- No.
He acted like a sleepwalker.
He just stared out the window
and watched the lights go by.
Where were you takin' him?
Times Square. It was New Year's Eve,
1943. I just dropped him off..
in the crowd and he walked out of our
lives forever, or so we thought.
You're tellin' me that you paid 25 grand
for a guy and you lost him in a crowd?
I did it for my daughter.
It was some sort of hocus-pocus she
and Johnny were foolin' around with.
- My daughter was obsessed.
- I know.
I found a mummified
hand in her room.
The "hand of glory." It was supposed
to be able to open any lock.
It was the right hand of
a convicted murderer..
cut off while his neck
was still in the noose.
Or so Margaret believed.
- Black magic.
- Black, white, what difference
does it make?
- Margaret was always..
- Evil.
Evil is a dunghill, Mr. Angel.
Everyone gets on his own and
speaks out about someone else's.
Margaret wasn't evil. She
was a strange kid, though.
She was into tarot cards
before she could read.
Who got her started?
Some maid, governess..who knows?
Some maid, some governess.. Everything
you tell me is a crock of shit!
You're the one that got her started!
You're the fuckin' devil worshipper!
The prince of darkness
protects the powerful.
- That's a crock of shit!
- I can't help it if you don't believe.
You come straight with me, you slimebag,
or I'll save this state an execution.
I introduced Johnny Favorite to my
daughter. He was very powerful.
I once watched him conjure up
"Lucifuge" in my living room.
He was in it much
deeper than me.
He made a pact with Satan.
He sold his soul.
You expect me to swallow that?
Swallow it. Spit it out.
I don't give a damn.
That's a crock of shit, you
lying, old, fucking motherfucker!
- He sold his soul for stardom.
- For stardom? Are you..
- That's a crock of shit!
- Satan rose from the depth.
It was magnificent, except he thought
he could outwit the prince of darkness.
Johnny sold his soul. Then when he made
it big, he tried to duck out of it.
That's a crock of shit!
Johnny came across an obscure
rite in an ancient manuscript.
- He needed a victim his own age.
- Why?
To steal their soul. So Toots and
Johnny picked up a young soldier.
Who?
Just a soldier celebrating New
Year's Eve in Times Square.
- Who was this soldier?
- They took him back to Johnny's hotel.
- That's where the ceremony took place.
- What ceremony?
The boy was bound naked
on a rubber mat.
There were complicated incantations
and stuff in Latin and Greek.
A pentacle was branded
on his chest.
Margaret handed Johnny a virgin dagger
and he sliced the boy clean open.
And he ate his heart.
He cut it out so quickly the heart was
still beating when he wolfed it down.
Johnny's plan was to drop out
and resurface as the soldier.
But before he could work
things out, he was drafted.
Then Johnny was injured, sent home
without even knowing who he was.
Who was that boy?
Only Johnny knew. He sealed the dog
tags in a vase and gave it to Margaret.
It was Margaret's plan to
drop him off in Times Square.
That would be the last place that
he'd remember before it happened.
He needed a victim..
someone his own age..
to steal their soul.
And he sliced the boy clean
open and he ate his heart.
Who was the boy?
Johnny's plan was to drop out
and resurface as the soldier.
Or maybe he gained possession
of the guy's soul.
He still looked
Iike Johnny to me.
Oh, shit!
I know who I am!
Alas.
How terrible is wisdom when it brings
no profit to the wise, Johnny.
Louis Cyphre.
Lucifer.
Even your name is a
dime-store joke.
Mephistopheles is such a
mouthful in Manhattan, Johnny.
You think posing as the devil..
just 'cause it scared some
superstitious old guitar player..
and that witch and
that nutty old man..
You think it's gonna scare me?
It ain't, 'cause
I know who I am.
And you killed them, and
you're tryin' to pin it on me.
And I know who I am.
If I had cloven hoofs and a pointed
tail, would you be more convinced?
You're crazy.
I know who I am. You're
trying to frame me.
You're trying to frame me.
Cyphre, I know who I am.
You murdered them people.
I never killed nobody.
I didn't kill Fowler..
and..
and I didn't kill Toots..
and I didn't kill Margaret
and I didn't kill Krusemark.
I didn't kill no one.
- I'm afraid you did, Johnny.
- My name's not Johnny.
All killed by your own hand.
Guided by me, naturally.
Frankly, you were doomed from the
moment you slit that young boy in half.
And Johnny..
for 12 years you've been living on
borrowed time & another man's memories.
Hey, I'm gonna tell
Winesap, 'cause he knows.
Winesap? He's dead.
Nasty accident.
Don't worry. No one will mourn
one less lawyer in the world.
There's death everywhere
these days, Johnny.
But what gives human
life its worth anyway?
Because someone loves
it or hates it?
The flesh is weak, Johnny.
Only the soul is immortal.
And yours belongs to me.
I know who I am.
That's it, Johnny.
Take a good look.
However cleverly you
sneak up on a mirror..
your reflection always looks
you straight in the eye.
I know who I am!
Why'd you come back?
I live here.
Who is she?
She ain't "Angel, Harold."
She's my daughter.
Bullshit. Who is she?
She's Epiphany Proudfoot.
She stayed here for
a little while.
Long enough for you
to kill her, right?
Unless that ain't your
gun up her snatch.
You're gonna burn
for this, Angel.
I know.
In hell.
SubText:
NoRMITA.326
Harry.
Johnny.