Adam and Eve just had sex, right.
And God says to Adam,
"Where's Eve?"
So Adam says, "She's down
at the stream, washing off."
God says, "Damn, now I'll never get
that smell out of those fish."
You really think
that's funny, don't you?
I bet every man here
thinks that's funny.
Ease up, huh?
All of you. Women, Christ!
Getting to be a real pain in the ass.
You know that?
I don't know what's wrong
with the way it used be
when you just did what you were told?
Fuck you, Hopper.
I do, every night.
Me and my jar of Vaseline.
I can fuck any woman I want.
I don't even have to make her cum.
Really? I'd rather get fucked
by a vibrator than your cock any day.
It's honest, loving and I don't have
to make breakfast for it in the morning.
You remind me of my ex-wife.
She had an answer for everything.
Like whenever people
would ask her what I did.
She'd say, "He struggles."
You guys,
you all think you are the victim.
Hey, wait a minute.
I think we're taking a bum rap here.
I happen to be a very giving lover.
Yeah, you're giving alright.
You gave half the city the clap.
Alright, enough.
Mr Grady.
You've been awfully quiet.
I know it's your first night with the group
but is there anything you'd like to say.
No, I just came as a guest.
My buddy Hopper over here brought me.
I know. But surely you must
have something to say about all this.
I mean, you are planning
to stay with us?
Me? Why, me, I'm happy.
Been married to the same woman
for 11 years.
Been together since high school.
We have two kids.
Cut the crap. You wouldn't be
here if something wasn't bugging you.
I told you, I'm here with Hopper.
I have a great marriage.
I don't understand all these...
hang-ups with you people.
I've never cheated on my wife
in ten years.
I thought it was 11?
I've never met a man
yet who'd admit he was a lousy lay.
What's that supposed to mean?
You think everything has to do with sex?
Admit it. You're a lousy lay
and she's learnt to accept it.
- Like we all had to.
- Wait a minute!
- You think I'm a lousy lay?
- You got it.
I'm not the one who complains
how tired I am every night.
Getting her to make love...
It's like asking her to run
the Boston Marathon.
And then when we actually
go through with it,
I don't know whether
to embrace her or embalm her.
So don't tell me that I'm a lousy lay.
What am I saying?
What the hell am I doing here?
Oh, thank you, ladies and gentleman.
I'm grateful
from the bottom of my heart.
It is truly an honour
to be named Miss Liberty 1984.
I have dreamed
of this moment all my life.
And I promise I shall carry the name
with dignity and with pride.
I will always serve my country
and be a shining beacon of hope
to nations the world over.
Spreading the true spirit
of freedom and liberty that is America.
Oh, we're proud of you, Miss Liberty.
What do you plan to do
with your scholarship money?
Well. I plan to study music, sir.
Music, do you say?
What kind of instrument do you play?
I play the flute, sir.
In honour of our forefathers
who died at Concord and Lexington.
Would you like to see
how Miss Liberty plays the flute?
Oh, yes. Yes, very much.
First, I unzip the case.
And then I take out the instrument
very carefully. I'm very gentle.
And then I run my little hand all over it.
Up and down. Then up and down.
And then I fondle it so softly.
So softly.
I love the look of it.
Oh, I love the feel of it.
So smooth and firm.
I like to wrap my fingers around it
and tenderly caress it.
Then I like to lift it to my mouth.
And wrap my lips around it.
And then I just wait for that sweet,
sweet music to come pouring out.
Fucking incredible. Oh!
Fucking incredible!
I knew it would be.
You knew it would be too, didn't you?
Ha-ha.
We know each other so well.
You know what I mean?
What did you say your name was?
China Blue.
No, I mean your real name.
Miss Liberty.
Well, that was some game of yours,
Miss Liberty!
You wanted romance.
My name is Carl
and I just split up with my wife.
It's gettin' late babe. Got to move.
Can I see you again?
I work the street. Keep an eye out.
It's just that it's been so long
since I got a hard-on just...
...looking at someone.
We were married 12 years.
She just walked out on me.
Just like that.
I don't know what it was I did wrong.
I know what you mean.
My ex beat it out the door
when he was tired of beating me.
Is that true?
Does it matter?
Yeah, well.
I'll see you around, China Blue.
Oh, put the cash on the dresser.
Hey! Shit!
"Dear God! The heathen are come
unto thine inheritance.
"Thy holy temple, have they defiled.
"They have laid Jerusalem on heaps.
"Their blood have they shed
like water round Jerusalem."
- Like, like, like...
- This guy is crazy.
They fuck and they piss and they shit
like the fucking scum they are.
Dear God, hallowed is Thy name...
In the spirit of Lucifer.
Forgive me Lord. Forgive me.
How long, Lord,
shalt thou be angry forever?
Shall they jealously burn like fire?
Shall we keep on
fucking and pissing into this.
Forgive me, Lord.
That was... that was not me.
You child, victim of the night.
I am the Reverend Peter Shayne
and I know the plague that cripples you.
I've been sent by the Lord to save you
and to rid the earth of that plague.
I am His holy messenger.
Do you recognise me, child?
Sorry, I never forget a face.
Especially when I've sat on it.
- Save your soul, whore.
- Save your money, shithead.
I'm sorry, man. I didn't think
they'd come down on you so hard.
Forget it. Come on in and see the shop.
You haven't seen it for a while.
- Hey, Jerry!
- Good to see you, Grady.
How come you're still here?
I thought Mollie was sick.
They're coming
to pick this up tomorrow.
Can't afford to lose customers,
you know.
Well, don't worry about it.
I'll finish it up. Now, get out of here.
- Your wife is sick. You should be home.
- Well, thanks, Grady.
You know, you're the only one left
who gives a damn.
' What do
- erry!
Step on it.
What you afraid of? Step on it!
Got you surrounded.
- Still playing games?
- It'll scare the hell out of any thief.
Do not attempt to escape.
Keep your hands up.
Bobby, about that session.
Things must be pretty rough at home.
Things are great.
Just got a little wound up, that's all.
Like I said, still playing games.
You should talk. All the bodies
floating in and out of that bed.
That's some kind of life, pal.
Spend half of it changing sheets.
Sheila called me yesterday
for the first time since the divorce.
Still can't let her go, Bobby.
Well, I got a great idea.
Amy invited Sheila to the barbecue
on Sunday with Tommy and Patty.
So why don't you come?
It'll just be like old times.
Who's there?
I didn't hurt you, did I?
A little rougher this time
than usual.
Don't worry, 'sweet dick'. I'm tough.
"Sweet dick"?
Do me a favour next time.
Don't walk so fast. Hard to keep up.
Maybe I should rape you, huh?
One way to get back at your old man.
- Sorry?
- Your father.
I know he raped you
when you were a kid.
You told me the first time
we were at it together.
Oh, yeah. I forgot.
- You said you trusted me.
- I do. You're the only one I told.
It is true, isn't it?
- Sure it's true.
- Well, you don't seem too upset.
You were almost in tears
when you told me.
I'm trying to block it out of my mind.
Can't you understand?
I'm sorry. I didn't know
it was still a sore spot.
Not as sore as it was then.
Maybe, if you're real nice to me
I'll tell you all about the time
he tied my arms to the bed
with black twine.
Did he really do that?
He did that
to a sweet little thing like you?
See the scars.
- Where?
- Look closer.
Oh, yeah. I see.
How low can you get?
As low as you can afford.
And your meter's up pal.
That's the bitter truth.
Can I keep these?
For ten bucks.
Keep the trust.
I'm sorry I'm late honey.
I had to finish up.
- I ate with the kids.
- Well, I brought dessert.
- Thanks. You know I'm on a diet.
- Open it.
Da-da!
Have you eaten?
I'm not hungry.
I'll fix something later.
Dinner's still warm.
Listen, I invited Donny
to the party on Sunday.
You know, he and Sheila
have been speaking.
- Or at least she called him.
- Are you crazy?
She only called him
'cause he was late with the alimony.
So how are the kids?
Jimmy needs braces. The dentist
says he has an overlapping bite.
Will they hurt?
I'm not concerned
whether it will hurt or not.
Well, if he needs braces, honey,
give him the braces.
- Just like that.
- Yeah, just like that.
So we'll go another year without
a hot tub. We can use Larson's.
Sure, and when we need a new car
we can just borrow the Murphys'.
I can borrow my sister's Cuisinart
and Sally's microwave.
And Kathy just got a new video recorder.
It cost 1,000 bucks.
She says it'll do anything she wants.
Well, for that price,
she should go down on him.
Very funny.
Did you talk to Jerry?
So where's the salt?
- You didn't, did you?
- Don't we have any salt?
- Bobby!
' Amy, I told you!
I am not letting the guy go.
I don't care how slow things are.
He's got a wife and kids.
And what do you have?
Maybe if you'd gone into a real business
like a normal person...
It's on the stove.
No wonder we never have any money!
Amy, look, I love that business.
I'm proud of it.
I work damn hard at it.
We'll make out OK.
Haven't let you down yet, have I?
So, who the hell needs a hot tub?
Who needs a bathtub?
Thinking of which,
why don't you and I...
...go upstairs
and take a bath together?
We could certainly use a bit
of adventure in our lives.
I'm really not in the mood
for a little adventure.
So what kind of lousy mood are you in?
Did you get your period today?!
No, I did not get my period today.
Every time I'm in a lousy mood,
you think I've got my period.
I wish.
By stocking Tampax I'll retire.
There is nothing
that means more to me...
...than this family.
Not even some stupid hot tub.
I have to clean up.
Hey! What are you guys still doing up?
Do you know what time it is?
Mum said we can stay up
till the next commercial.
No, you can't,
'cause you're under attack.
It's bombs away!
Watch out, here it comes!
Why don't you give your sister
time on it, cowboy?
Come on, you too. March, up!
Did you hear the joke about...?
Yeah, well don't worry about it,
because it's bedtime. Isn't it, Daddy?
- Come on. Let's go!
- Give Daddy a big hug.
- Goodnight.
- Hello?
- Walt Pierson here.
- Bobby Grady! How are you doin'?
- Great. You?
Yeah, I'm just fine, thanks.
Urn, listen. You asked me about doing
some night time surveillance for you.
Yes. Do you think
you might still be interested?
Yeah. Well, I was wondering
is the offer still good?
You got to work nights, though.
No problem. I could use the money.
- I think I've got something for you.
- You do? Terrific.
- You got to work nights, though.
- No, no, that's great.
- You didn't think I had the nerve!
- No, I didn't.
Neither did I.
I guess it just comes with poverty.
Come on in and we'll talk about it.
Yeah, well, thank you very much
and you take it easy.
- Yeah, right. See you tomorrow.
- Fine. Bye.
You tell them jokes and I'm the wicked
witch who sends them to bed.
Well, I'll put them to bed.
What, and keep them up
half the night with your stories?
It's good for the imagination.
Theirs or yours?
I'm going to be doing
some tracking for Walt Pierson,
so it means you can make room
for that hot tub.
You act like I've... forced you.
I don't even want it anymore.
Well, what do you want?
Do you know?
And you didn't force me.
Maybe I'll do the magic act at the party.
You know, for laughs.
What do you think?
Whatever you want.
Oh, Bobby, come on. Stop it.
We just got the cable.
Walt Pierson speaks very highly of you.
I've a lot of respect for Walt.
His word's good enough for me.
I'm damn good at what I do, Mr Bateman, but
I'll only take a job if I can do it right.
As long as you keep it quiet. I don't
want to turn this into a major event.
I've always been a pushover
for industrial espionage.
I'd like to help you.
Just tell me what the facts are.
I'm one of the largest manufacturers of
ladies' sportswear outside of New York,
but I'm falling behind
for the first time in 20 years.
Last week's orders
were at an all-time low.
I believe someone
in my organisation is selling patterns
to one of my competitors.
- I want you to follow her.
- Who is she?
The young woman's
been with me about two years.
Very talented designer.
Hell of a future, if she hasn't blown it.
- What makes you think it's her?
- I don't know. Gut feeling.
There's something about her.
I'll point her out to you.
Try and save some yardage
in the sleeve, OK?
That's her, in the grey suit.
How could someone
that looks like that be a criminal?
That's what I'm paying you to find out.
Follow her, where she goes at night,
what she does.
- Morning, Lou.
- Phil.
What do you mean,
"there's something about her"?
She's a mystery. Divorced.
Lives alone.
No boyfriends I know of. A real loner.
- What's she like in here?
- Impulsive, ambitious.
Never stops working,
never satisfied.
You know the type.
Always proving themselves.
- Perfection or bust.
- Any friends?
She gets along fine
with the other women.
But if you've got a penis,
you're in trouble. She turns to ice.
- That still doesn't make her a criminal.
- It makes her a suspect.
I don't trust anyone that works that hard.
She must be hiding something.
- I want you to nail her lily white ass.
- What the hell is this?
- You think she's that dangerous?
- It depends on what you discover.
Paradise Hotel. 4th and Main.
Hey, this is a fucking pain
in my ass.
- Do you recognise me tonight, child?
- Ha! Well, if it isn't my saviour!
The Reverend Peter Shayne requests
a few moments of repose upstairs,
in your holy of holies.
A reverend, no less.
You know, the last reverend who tried
to, er, save me... lived to regret it.
I chased him all around the church
until I caught him by the organ.
Come on.
I make a great Joan of Arc.
Can't you tell?
I imagine you do spend a good deal
of your time on your knees, my child.
Excuse us.
We've got business to conduct here.
Hi, baby! How about a shot
of the Grand Canyon, huh?
Holy shit!
Stick it there, Rev.
What do you want?
I want to help you.
Admit you need it.
I need it.
With conviction.
Make me believe.
Oh, please, Reverend.
You're so good and wise and strong.
Please help this sick,
disgusting degenerate.
I deal in truth. I'm bringing you
something greater than a hard-on,
assuming you consider truth
to be greater than a hard-on.
- Depends on the hard-on.
- Try it again, sinner.
First month I was married, I tried to
make my husband's favourite casserole.
I made a mess.
So I cried to my best friend Peggy
all week about it,
till I found out that
when I was in the kitchen making it,
he was in the bedroom
making Peggy.
Don't stare at me.
You're wearing your anguish
like a breakaway chastity belt.
You wanted the truth.
What else are you selling?
This is a fantasy business, Reverend.
You can have any truth you want.
And so can you.
Isn't that why you're here?
- Isn't that why you are?
- I'm here to save you.
Why don't you fuck me?
That'll save me.
Not from your disease.
What disease?
I'm healthy as a horse.
I'm fit as a fiddle and ready for cock.
Whores and metaphors don't mix.
Who are you?
I'm Cinderella, Cleopatra,
Goldie Hawn, Eva Braun.
I'm Little Miss Muffin, Pocahontas.
I'm whoever you want me to be,
Reverend.
But what are you doing here?
- Satisfying.
- Who?
- I think the confessional is about over.
- Don't you want to be saved?
- Do you get that much out of this?
- I get paid.
I'm not interested in what you're selling,
only what you're buying.
Why don't you assume
the missionary position, Reverend?
My purpose here is totally humanitarian.
- To make me see the light?
- To make you see through the bullshit.
You want truth, Father?
I give the best truth in town.
So good, you wouldn't
know it from make believe.
- Is it?
- If you believe it is.
Everybody needs something
to believe in, don't they, Reverend?
Bow down, 0 Lord, and hear me
for I am poor and needy.
Preserve my soul, for I am holy.
O Thou, my God.
Save thy servant, that trusteth in Thee.
Save him from this bigmouth cooze
with a motor driven ass.
Forgive me, Lord. I speak not in vain
but this little bitch provokes me so.
Oh, Jesus!
At least I can stay in character.
You couldn't even get a walk-on, unless
it was you that was being walked on.
I am a messenger of God,
you little cocksucker!
What's this, your mail bag?
Let's see what's in it
No!
- What is this, top secret?
- No.
Let Mama have a little peak.
What have you got in here,
the Holy Grail?
Oh, my God! Oh, excuse me, oh God!
Need I remind you, Jezebel,
that curiosity killed the cat.
Not until it got out of the bag.
These are the Devil's playthings.
Those who touch them will burn.
Put another log on the fire, Reverend.
Let's see a sample.
- It's a disgusting array.
- Disgusting's my middle name, honey.
- What have you got in the bag?
- God, forgive me.
A tit pacifier.
That milk of human kindness,
remedial, even in simulation.
A foam rubber pretty kitty, already house
broken. You can teach it new tricks.
It comes with a battery pack.
It's in here somewhere.
An auto-suck.
Modern technology at its most
compassionate, and it swallows.
This one is a little on the blink.
Oh, are you hungry? How about
a beat-me-eat-me liquorice whip?
The taste that leaves its mark forever.
Hey, no. Wait a minute.
I'm not through here. What else you got?
What?
What the hell?
Is this a cruise missile or a Pershing?
What are you gonna do?
Fuck someone to death?
You'd like to, wouldn't you?
Only the right woman.
I've got to go.
Just when we're making progress.
I can only handle
one revelation a night.
Enough of them
and you might be able to handle real life.
Real life, Reverend?
Tell me your name,
or is that a tough one?
China Blue.
I like it. It's rather exotic,
like something out of Charlie Chan.
B-movies have always
been my inspiration.
What's yours'?
Going My Way?
All you need to know about me
is that I intend to save you.
And all you need to do is... be there.
Stay with me, China Blue.
Trust me. I'll free you.
Who are you?
You're not a Reverend. Who are you?
I'm you.
I will sing of mercy and judgment.
Unto thee, o Lord, will I sing.
I will behave myself wisely
in a perfect way.
I will walk within my house
with a perfect heart
and I will set no wicked thing
before mine eyes.
Not even the stupid douchebag
who's luring me into her rotten spell.
The snatch can't fool me, Lord.
I'm not like the others.
I know her cowardly game.
A fear of men so great, she can
only feel strength behind her facade.
"Who so slandereth his neighbour,
will I cut off."
I'll cut off, alright.
I'll cut off... her little tits.
Why didn't you come to me, Phil?
I would have loaned you the money.
- Hell, I would have given you the money.
- Goddamn pride.
What about jail? No pride in there.
Who thinks? Cooper offered me
a fortune for the patterns.
I lost control!
Please, Lou.
I'll work for nothing.
Anything you want.
What this would do
to Sarah and my boy...
I'll have to think about it, Phil.
I had to have someone around here
to talk to about this whole damn thing.
The man's been with me 18 years.
I trusted him.
He was so moved that I did
that he broke down and confessed.
That's gratitude for you.
I didn't know my trust meant that much.
What do I do now?
- Give him another chance.
- The man is a criminal.
Come on. You heard his motive.
The guy's only human.
He knows he was wrong.
God knows we've all made mistakes.
Why ruin his life over one mistake?
- What about the law?
- Screw the law.
What good is he in jail?
Beside, he'll work twice
as hard for you here.
And you can feel like the king of hearts.
I don't know
what's right or wrong anymore.
- Did you really believe it was her?
- So I'm a lousy guesser.
What did you get on her?
Not much. She stayed home all night.
- Is that you, Joe?
- Are you free?
No, but I'm one hell of a bargain.
I meant, are you available.
You know... for action.
Action? Soldier, for 50 bucks,
you can name your own battlefield.
I'm sorry! I'm not too good at this.
It's my first time.
Oh? Are you that desperate
or that horny?
- I'm married.
- Oh, that desperate and that horny.
Go slow! I'm just... a boy scout.
Well, baby,
you are about to become an explorer.
Oh, hot body!
- Are you an athlete?
- Yeah.
Played varsity football, high school.
- Quarterback.
- Mm.
Well, Quarterback,
you can have the ride of your life,
if you trust me at the wheel.
Sit down.
How, er, good a driver are you?
Who said anything about driving?
Driving's what you do with your wife.
Here, we fly.
Sound good, lover?
Bet you and your wife
haven't done much flying, right?
Shit, me and my wife haven't
been doing much driving lately.
I'm ready for take-off.
You're on standby, babe.
I got a full load.
OK, but next week it's first class.
Who are you?
It's not a prom date, sweetie.
I'm a hooker, you're a trick.
Why ruin a perfect relationship?
Here, have a Quaalude.
To float. You'll love it, I promise.
Flyer never lies.
Fasten your seatbelt, honey,
and say hello to freedom.
Good evening.
Welcome to China Blue Airlines flight 69,
non-stop service to paradise.
We'll be taking off shortly.
I'll be unbuckling your belt
and seeing that big bird rise and rise,
finally settling into the comfort
only this wide body can provide.
We're here to serve you.
Please remember that although
we may run out of Panam coffee,
we'll never run out of TWA tea.
Hey, Ivory soap.
99 and 44/100% pure.
Kind of funny, isn't it?
- That guy...
- Don't say it.
You don't even know
what I was going to say.
Do you?
- Why are you in a hurry?
- Me?
You raced for that shower
like it was the Indy 500.
You couldn't wait to wash it off,
could you?
- Now wait a minute...
- No problem.
Hey, I know the boy scout oath.
"Cleanliness is next to godliness."
How the hell would you know?
You haven't been
next to one in years.
What I do in this room
might not win me a Purple Heart
but it sure as shit
beats the PTA meeting.
Why are we acting like this?
I thought fucking was supposed
to bring people closer together,
- not drive them apart.
- Is that what it did for your marriage?
What we did tonight...
You felt it too, didn't you?
You weren't just acting.
You felt what I did.
Tell me, please. I have to know.
Would you, um...?
Would you maybe
like to see me again?
Yes.
But I can't.
Well, you know there are three things
you have to know to be able
to make it as 50 buck hooker.
You have to act, fuck
and know how to count to 50.
You're lucky, you've seen all three.
Close the door on your way out.
There are a lot of creeps around here.
Ready when you are, CB.
Not tonight, OK.
Freedom requires treatment.
Just leave me alone.
I would if I thought you wanted me to.
Get out.
Women, you mystify me.
The extremes you go to for a little
validation, but you still go home alone.
What's your mystery, Reverend?
Authority never reveals itself.
Huh. Why?
Are you afraid I'll stop believing,
or afraid you will?
Those are the rules.
My 50, my game, my rules.
Game's over, fraud.
The game's never over.
That's what you're here for, isn't it?
- I don't feel like playing games.
- I think you do.
Consider the alternative.
You want a game? Go sit down!
♪ Onward, Christian soldiers!
♪ Marching as to war
♪ With the cross of Jesus... ♪
Stop it!
♪ Going on before ♪
Come on, stud!
Give it to me. It's all a game.
Fly! Do what you want!
You want freedom?
You need to manipulate
women to feel like a man?
Do it! That's what we're here for.
Like you manipulate men
to feel like a woman?
- Let go, damn you.
- Why, it's only a game.
- Let go, I said.
- It hurts, doesn't it?
- Let go, you fuck!
- Tell me it hurts.
Yes, it hurts!
You see, you can feel.
I'm sorry...
How was it, huh? Not bad?
PhD in emotionalism, huh?
I have accepted reality.
I'm cured.
Free at last!
Shit!
You self-righteous son of a bitch!
I can play your goddamn game
as well as you can
and I don't use religion
to pump myself up.
If you're a minister, I'm Snow White.
Yes, but, what fun
it is playing the part.
- Would you leave now, please?
- That was quite a performance.
There's no limit to my talents.
You're the head of your class,
or is it the...
- ...class of your head?
- Oh, a man of words.
He makes up in diction
what he lacks in click.
Lesson for today.
I've written you a poem.
Would you like to hear it?
Behold this wicked woman
She falls, she mends,
she crawls, she bends
She sucks it, fucks it,
picks it up and licks it
You can whip her, beat her,
maul her, mistreat her
Anything you want
as long as you don't touch her
Get out of here. Take your
goddamn truth and get out of here!
Show her affection, she turns to stone.
You haven't had
your 50 dollars worth yet!
- Come back her, listen to me!
- Get away from me!
- Urgh! You...!
- Do you know what you are?
A cheap painted slut
who makes a fortune selling illusions.
Ah!
One of your regulars, my dear?
Rather eager tonight, isn't he?
I guess I taught that guy a lesson.
That was no guy.
That was my saviour.
I've never been fought over before.
Only been fought.
Yeah, well, it's tough work.
You can't please everyone.
Oh, I didn't mean this work.
In this work, I can please everyone.
Come on. What are you still doing
hanging around here anyway?
It's OK. I'm not helpless.
I guess I could use some help.
Thanks for the help just then.
Or the attempt anyway.
Yeah, we're not all out to get you.
Now go on home to your wife.
I wish I could tell her,
the way you made me feel.
She'll say it's part of my imagination.
It was.
- The kids hate this salad.
- Where are they?
They're at my mom's.
Guess who we just saw.
Janey Durant.
Remember, Amy? She beat you out
for head cheerleader.
- What a slut.
- She's not a slut.
She went to Ohio State.
Every two years they let a slut
into Ohio State.
Her timing was good.
I sat next to her in Biology.
She was always dropping her frog.
- What's she doing now?
- She's a waitress at Seafood Heaven.
- Didn't she marry Lenny Harris?
- That nerd?
He sat behind me in English
and tied mirrors to his shoes
so he could look up my dress.
Shit! What are you talking about?
That was me!
I knew it was some nerd.
It's OK. I've got one.
- Isn't it flat?
- I like it flat.
You never liked it flat
when we were married.
I never liked anything
OK, team. Get it while it's hot.
He thinks he's still in high school.
Alright!
You've got mustard all over!
OK, everybody.
Look at me and smile.
One or the other. We can't do both.
One more for posterity.
200 for a three-way.
- You got a radio?
- We've got whatever you want.
Health insurance?
Want to get to heaven early?
Maybe we should make him
an offer at 14.
He's got so much stock already,
he might cooperate.
We can't go lower than 18.
It's an insult.
I refuse to pay that opportunistic
bastard more than he deserves.
It's a matter of principle.
I'm still worried
about Fenley coming through, though.
The man has absolutely no sense
of morality. Don't you agree, dear?
Mmhm.
I'd like to finalise this
before Laurie comes home for vacation.
Hope she isn't bringing that boy
she's seeing. You know, the Jew.
Not that I'm a bigot or anything.
You know the work
I've done for crippled children.
If he's Jewish,
what are we gonna do with him?
God knows we can't take him
to the country club.
Claudia, have you ever heard
of a Jew who didn't play golf?
Arthur, don't stick your tongue in her ear.
You have to be careful
with these people.
You don't know what kind of germs
they could be carrying.
Stop this crate!
Close the deal quick
before your tongue drops off.
Promise me
you won't do the magic act.
- What? You told me you liked it.
- I lied.
Donny... Donny!
I think it's time for the old HP.
A little nostalgia for the gang.
You rat porker!
- Does Amy know?
- I thought I'd surprise her.
Ladies and gentlemen, your attention
please. We have a treat in store.
That dumb magic act.
It's no magic act.
Live on our stage,
direct from the wild jungles of Borneo...
Ah, damn! It's the old ace pick.
Skill and daring,
ladies and gentlemen,
prepare yourselves,
you're about to experience...
the human penis.
Bobby, don't. I mean it!
Bravo, bravo!
Did your mother teach you
to wash your hands
after you go to the bathroom?
She taught me not to piss on my fingers.
- Did it feel good to get even?
- Did it feel good to lie?
I thought you liked the magic act.
I just didn't want to hurt your feelings.
I guess you can't win.
You can win by being honest with me
instead of humouring me.
What do we have
if we can't be honest with each other?
I don't know, Bobby. What do we have?
I don't know, Amy.
What else have you
been humouring me about?
Go to sleep.
No, I want to know what else
you've been sparing me from.
I'm really not in the mood for this.
Are you ever in the mood for anything?
Don't turn away from me.
I want to know what's bugging you.
Is it the way I eat?
Why did you pour
all that maple syrup on my pancakes?
It was a mistake, alright?
- Was it?
- What do you think?
I'm trying to poison you
with maple syrup?
If you're unhappy about something,
just tell me.
Don't take it out on me.
I'm really tired.
No, damn it! Stop avoiding this.
You've been acting like
I have the plague or something.
I want to know
what the hell is bothering you.
Is it money again?
Nuclear war?
What about the way we make love,
if you can remember back that far?
All your ooh-ing and ah-ing.
Is that so you just
don't hurt my feelings?
- Stop!
- Come on, I want to know. Tell me.
- Bobby, don't do this.
- Tell me, damn it!
Be honest for once. I can take it.
Have you been getting off too?
- You've just been humouring me.
- I really hate this kind of talk.
It's not the HP
and it's not the magic act.
It's just us.
I want the truth.
You wanted the truth.
I'm sorry.
You're sorry.
What do you want me to say?
Why couldn't you just tell me this before?
All this time
it hasn't been good for you.
Why did you have to lie about it?
I am your husband. Don't you think
I would care about something like that?
That I'd want to do something about it?
Didn't you trust me enough
to believe that?
I didn't say it wasn't good for me.
I just don't need the same thing
from it that you do.
It's never been important to me.
And you know
I feel funny talking about it.
Do you feel better faking it?
You were satisfied.
Satisfied?!
What do you think I am?
Some kind of machine?
That I just need a hole to cum in?
I mean, what do you think
makes me cum?
- Stop!
- No.
- What do you think makes me cum?
- I don't care!
I'll tell you. I thought it was
being inside the woman that I love.
And giving her as much pleasure
as she was giving to me.
You know, the two of us, together.
Some kind of magician I turned out to be.
So good, I conned myself.
Maybe it's time
we both stopped the conning.
Started learning again.
On our own.
I know you're pissed, but before
you go crazy, just let me explain.
You followed me!
I don't fucking believe this.
I just want to talk to you.
I don't to make any trouble. I promise.
- I have to go to work.
- It won't take long. Please.
Thank you.
- Well?
- It's a great apartment.
What are you, a real estate agent?
I saw these in a book once.
They say that in the East,
it's forbidden to have sex with someone
who knows your secrets,
or shortcomings.
You'd never be horny there.
I'm never horny here.
I guess not.
Cut the crap.
What do you want from me?
What makes you think
I want something?
Everybody wants something.
Why did you come here?
I wanted to see you again.
Look, if you think you're gonna
get back in my panties forget it.
There's one asshole
in there already.
Maybe I just want to know you.
I mean, I've never met anyone like you.
Who has?
I just thought after last week
maybe we could be friends.
You really think we could be friends
after last week?
Yeah, I can't think of a better way
to start a friendship.
We haven't met. I'm Bobby Grady.
Joanna Crane, I saw it on the mailbox.
What are you, about 30?
Still call yourself Bobby?
- I'll grow up when I'm ready.
- Oh, I think you're ready.
Are you alone?
Aren't we all?
You remind me of this hamster I had
when I was a kid.
- I remind you of a hamster?
- Yep.
He ran away
whenever you tried to touch him.
So I wanted to show him
there's nothing to be afraid of.
So one day, I just picked him
real fast and I held him.
- And he turned tender and loving?
- No, he shit in my hand.
Well, I'd better get going
'cause you're gonna be late for work.
It's OK. I'm used to breaking rules.
I'm a criminal at heart.
You meant you had one.
Thanks a lot, and I'm sorry
for busting in on you like this.
I really appreciate you listening
and I won't bother you again.
Oh, Bobby, if you, um...
If you ever really need me...
- ...to talk or whatever, I'm here.
- I know.
Joanna Crane.
Hello?
Hey, cowboy.
- Hi.
Dad, Morn said you've moved out.
Well, your mom and I,
we have to be on our own for a while.
I swear, that doesn't mean we've
stopped caring about you and Lisa.
Dad, if Mom gets married again, I don't
have to call the other guy Dad, do I?
Oh, Jimmy. No matter what happens,
I'm always gonna be your dad.
Why do you have to go?
Promise you won't be
any trouble to your mother.
- You watch out for your sister.
- Jimmy, come on!
- I will, don't worry.
- I'm not worried.
Hello, Joanna.
What are you doing here?
You have no right to be here.
I had to.
For both of us.
Get away from me.
I don't even want to know you.
No more deceptions, Joanna.
I know who you are.
We're the same, don't you see?
The same rage, the same fear.
We hurt the same,
we escape the same.
But we don't have to any more.
We have a chance. Both of us, together.
- No more disguises.
- I don't need you!
I'm crying out to you, for God's sake.
Is everything a negotiation here too?
- Stop it. Just shut up!
- Listen to me. Help me.
I'm tired of standing at street corners.
I want to love and care and need,
just like you do.
We can help each other.
We don't have to grow old...
It's alright. Joanna?
Run away. Turn on me.
I was only trying to save you.
Well... the game's not over.
The messenger of God will return.
And this time...
he'll bring the final word.
There's Ivory soap in the shower.
It's... 99 and 44/100% pure.
Isn't that funny?
Yeah?
I don't know how to do this sort of thing.
I've been driving around for an hour.
Drive on, lady.
Please, it's not for me,
it's for my husband.
Just the two of you.
I want to buy you for an hour,
if that's what you call it.
- Is this some kind of freak trick?
- Nothing like that, I swear.
You know what it'll cost? I'm the
hottest piece of life on this street.
It'll cost you 100 bucks.
Have you got 100 bucks?!
I'll drive you there and bring you back.
Ten minutes on the expressway.
I just need someone to be with him.
My husband is dying.
Maybe another three months.
He's still functioning.
In fact, you'd hardly know he was sick.
We've been married for 28 years.
But since I found out,
I haven't been able to go near him.
He needs me so badly.
I just can't do it.
I want you to make him
feel like a man again.
His name is Ben.
My wife takes her guilt very seriously.
- I'm sure she told you I'm sick.
- Yes.
I didn't want her to do this.
I haven't been with another woman
in 28 years.
But she insisted.
Yes, ma'am. She insisted.
Charity really does begin at home.
My God, you're lovely.
What's your name?
China Blue.
I see. Image and all, eh?
Well... China Blue.
My body's not in the greatest shape,
as you know.
I'll try and not make
it too painful for you.
No, don't say that.
I want to make it good for you.
Oh, I want you so.
You're my master, my king.
Please let me have it. I wanna feel
that big strong man inside me.
- Please, I want you so bad.
- Don't.
Alright.
Well, your wife got you the best.
I'm the best there is.
I'm gonna give you
the hottest night of your life.
Do you think you can raise the dead?
Oh no, Ben, don't.
Don't be afraid.
It was only a game.
I'm sorry... I'm so sorry
you have to see me like this.
Don't be sorry.
You have a lot more courage
than I have.
At least you've stopped pretending.
Well, so long, China Blue.
Joanna.
- Yeah'?
- It's Bobby.
Look, I'm sorry. I know it's late.
Remember when you said,
"if you need me, I'm here."
Well, I need you.
Come on in.
God, I don't believe
that you're still working.
When do you sleep?
Valentine's Day.
- Is it your wife?
- Is it my wife?
The first time Amy and I made love,
she asked me if I still respected her.
Hell, I thought
that's the reason we did it.
Well, it's all over.
Go and sit down.
Do you want some coffee?
No, I could use a shot of morphine,
if you've got it!
I'd love to kill the last 12 years.
You'll survive.
I'm a goddamn fool.
Why did I believe so hard?
Now what do I have to believe in?
Bobby, come on. it really is late
and I have a lot that I have to do.
Don't judge me, Grady, huh?
- We both live our fantasies.
- Only mine's over!
And you're just still hanging around.
Come on.
What the hell is the point, Joanna?
You work so hard
at getting these people who want you
when it's not even you that they want!
Well, I do!
You're the one that said,
"When are you gonna grow up?"
Well, I think it's about time
that we both did.
It's so hard, Bobby.
No man's ever given me that kind
of faith before, that kind of respect.
But that hotel
is the safest place in the world.
I can do anything there,
I can be anything I can dream of
because it's not me.
Don't you see?
- I'd only end up disappointing you.
- I can chance it.
I'm tough.
- I'm not.
- Wait a second.
Just remember one thing.
We're friends.
What we did in that hotel room
we can do here.
We're the same people.
We've done as much as two people can.
Only now it'll be for each other
instead of to each other.
And you can't buy any higher than that.
O God, to whom vengeance belongs.
How long shall the wicked triumph?
How long shall the utterance speak
hard things?
How long shall they turn 50 buck tricks
and strut their evil bodies
in smelly silk underwear?
Tear off that dress
and she's as helpless as I am.
China Blue,
alias Joanna Crane.
Alias Peter Shayne.
They'll all be saved.
I have to talk to you.
What is it? Is it the kids?
What's wrong?
Nothing's wrong.
I wanna talk to you.
About what?
Didn't you used to have
a funny painting on that wall?
Yeah. I took it down two years ago.
Now what's up?
I've been doing a lot of thinking,
and I think I made a mistake.
I'd like us to give it another try.
Women! I give up.
What do you mean, "women"?
Who else?
Amy, Why?
You love me so much
you can't stand being apart,
or you're having trouble
getting a plumber?
It's hard being alone, Bobby.
Me in that big bed.
Last night I thought
I heard somebody trying to break in.
I'll rig up another alarm system.
I don't want another alarm system.
I don't want that damn hot tub. Really...
...all I want is my husband.
I understand, Bobby. It's your family.
If you can't stay, you can't stay.
I'm going to dinner, that's all.
It doesn't mean I'm not gonna be back.
No matter what Amy says,
I can't go back to that life.
Maybe you'd better
not come back here either.
What's that supposed to mean?
Maybe in a month or so, you'll start
feeling guilty about leaving the kids.
Maybe I'll start feeling
crowded and trapped.
Maybe you'll start resenting my past,
the time I put in on my work.
You'll want a good meal, I can't cook.
Why don't you just go, goddamn it?!
You don't know what it took, Bobby.
How long I wanted and hoped
for somebody to care for.
- To let somebody care for me.
- I'll be back.
Oh yeah, you say that. I know that.
But you're just so fucking honourable.
Sheila told me a good one
the other day.
She says, er,
the secretary says to the boss,
"So, could I use your dictaphone?"
And he says, "No. Use your finger,
like everybody else."
I made a new recipe tonight...
It has all your favourite vegetables in it.
It looks pretty good.
Oh, you know, listen, don't er...
Don't forget it's Parents' Night
at Lisa's school next week.
Well, I was gonna save this
until later, but...
Here.
Why don't you go on, open it?
I found it in the garage.
I bet you forgot that was still around.
I washed it up and had to sew up
a couple of places on it...
Put it on.
Oh, I used to get
so turned on with you... in this.
Bobby?
Last rites.
Lovely apartment.
What do you call it, Paradise Lost?
The Reverend's
gonna save you tonight.
Who are you? You son of a bitch!
Don't fight me, child. I'm the messenger
of God. I only want to heal you.
Heal thyself, pimp shit!
You're opposing me, Joanna.
You have to trust me.
One more game. The final one
that will free you forever.
Do I have your trust?
Because we can only play
if I have your trust.
Do I have it?
You are out of your fucking...
Now listen to me. I want your trust
and I'm gonna have it any way I can.
Now, you will follow
the Reverend's orders.
Is that clear?
Good.
I believe you'll find this game unique.
It's one you've never played before and
never will again, so make the most of it.
It's known as 'exorcising the demons'.
In my calling,
it's the ultimate salvation.
And its ends are sacrosanct.
With my ecclesiastic gift,
plus the grace of God,
and a little help from... Superman here,
I shall bestow upon you
the supreme humanitarian blessing
and give you your freedom.
You, er, do want that, don't you?
I knew you would.
What's the game... Reverend?
Sudden death. Now smile.
Smile, pig!
- ~ Ah!
- ~
- Why are you doing this?
- Why?
My mission
has always been your salvation,
but you never trusted me.
You refused to see.
But I saw.
I looked at you and I saw myself.
I saw the same escape,
the same malignancy.
But I know the cure and I know
how desperately you need it.
And only I can give it to you.
- I want to, Joanna.
- Why?
Because it's my gift to you.
Freedom.
The only thing I have left to give.
You refused it once
but this time you have no choice.
Getting into the part, my love?
I know I am.
Go fuck yourself.
"Go fuck yourself“?
Not a very nice thing
to say to a man of the cloth.
Remember, scumbag,
I'm here for your benefit. Got that?!
Healthy looking plants.
You must water them diligently.
I've always preferred
plastic flowers myself.
I could never bear
to watch the real ones die.
But that's the trouble with living things,
I suppose.
Inevitably they die.
You've never seen anyone die,
have you?
Certainly not up close.
The swift final gasp and then...
...absolute silence.
The stillness of the body
as the flesh turns white.
You're terrified right now
because you think of it as death.
But, er, think of it as...
...freedom.
♪ Forget your troubles,
come on get happy
♪ You better chase all your cares away
Sing Hallelujah, come on get happy
♪ You're heading for the judgment day
The sun is shinin', come on get happy
♪ The Lord is waitin' to take your hand
♪ Shout Hallelujah, come on get happy
♪ You're heading for the promised land ♪
There's somebody
coming by here any minute.
Then let's not waste any time.
Kill me, Joanna!
Give my life value.
Give me something to die for!
Save me. You are me!
One of us has to die
so the other can live.
Kill me, you worthless cunt.
I'm all the men who ever hurt you,
who made you feel like shit.
Who stole your self-respect
and turned you into China Blue. Kill me!
Release the rage.
Get it out. Get even!
Too late.
Take it out.
China Blue lives.
Strip, bitch.
- No!
- Come on.
- I can't.
- Joanna?
Do it, you bitch!
What are you waiting for?
Joanna?
Jo, are you OK? You OK?
No!
Goodbye, China Blue.
I'm here tonight...
...because I wanted
to finally start telling the truth.
My wife and I,
we've split up for good.
That's right. Me, the boy scout.
I just never had the guts
to admit the truth,
that Amy and I
had just stopped loving each other.
There's nobody to blame.
That's just what happened.
Then...
...I met this woman,
Joanna.
She saved my life.
We're together now.
I'm not sure if it's gonna work out.
We don't have
a whole hell of a lot in common
other than the fact that...
...we both need help and each other.
The thing that scared me the most
during my marriage
was just admitting that I was scared,
and letting Amy down.
Well, I can't pretend anymore.
I was scared shitless
to come back here.
I told Joanna.
And she took me in her arms
and she said,
"it's OK to be scared."
I felt... stronger.
And freer.
And more like a man
than I've ever felt before in my life.
Then we fucked our brains out.