♪ It seems today that all you see ♪
♪ Is violence in movies and sex on TV ♪
♪ But where are those good old-fashioned values ♪
♪ On which we used to rely? ♪
♪ Lucky there's a family guy ♪
♪ Lucky there's a man who positively can do ♪
♪ All the things that make us ♪
♪ Laugh and cry ♪
♪ He's... a... Fam... ily... Guy! ♪
♪ Family Guy 10x22 ♪ Viewer Mail 2
Original Air Date on May 20, 2012
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
- 大家好 我是Brian Griffin - 我是Stewie Griffin
- Hello, I'm Brian Griffin. - And I'm Stewie Griffin.
几年前 我们制作了一集"观众来信"
A few years ago, we did an episode called "Viewer Mail"
你们 我们的粉丝 写信来给我们提出了
where you, our fans, wrote in and suggested ideas
剧集的新创意
for new episodes.
现在已经10年了 然你们还是在寄给我们各种创意
Well, it's ten years later, but you're still sending in ideas.
呃 至小石城的Rashad 我们想告诉你
Uh, to Rashad in Little Rock, we wanna let you know
我们讨论了这个"让婴儿放纵一把"的创意很久
we kicked around idea, "Make the Baby Go Wild" for a while,
但是没有找到一个很合适的角度
couldn't really find an angle on it.
这一个是来自爱荷华州的Lee Mills
Here's one from Lee Mills of Iowa.
他写道:"亲爱的恶搞之家 你们的剧集是根据什么改变的么"
Lee writes: "Dear Family Guy, was your show based on anything?"
这是个好问题 Lee
That's a great question, Lee.
事实上 恶搞之家是源于美国电视剧
In fact, Family Guy is based on an American television series
名叫《辛普森一家》
called The Simpsons.
其实 《恶搞之家》更像《办公室》
Actually, Family Guy, much like The Office,
是取材于一部英国电视剧《庄园小伙》
is based on a British series called Chap of the Manor.
这个名字也是恶搞了family guy
我们一起欣赏吧
Let's watch.
(farting)
现在我们继续播放英国
ANNOUNCER:We now return to Britain's
最受欢迎的游戏节目
most popular game show...
优雅…之…轮
BRITISH AUDIENCE:Wheel... of... Politeness!
恶搞了美国的游戏节目幸运之轮
- 请开始吧 - 噢 不 您先请
- Do go ahead, then. - Oh, no, you first.
- 我从来就没这么想过 - 你真是太好了 但我坚持您先来
- Wouldn't dream of it. - Too kind, really, I insist.
- 这对我来说是不正确的 - 我很感激您的好意
- Wouldn't be proper of me. - I appreciate your courtesy.
- 您也是 - 好吧 时间到
- Likewise. - Well, we're all out of time.
请于明天同一时间继续收看
Join us same time tomorrow
如果没有完全为您带来不便的话
if it's not entirely inconvenient for you.
如果有的话 我们当然也理解
If so, of course, we do understand
并提前致歉
and we do apologize in advance.
这完全就是强加于您的 我感到非常抱歉
This has all been an imposition. I'm so dreadfully sorry.
- 抱歉 - 抱歉 - 抱歉
- Sorry! - Sorry. - Sorry.
抱歉了 大家
Sorry, everyone!
好了 孩子们 今天的电视到此为止了
All right, kids, enough telly.
我希望大家都想来吃点煮羊腿
I hope everyone's peckish for some boiled lamb shank.
我就不要了 Lydia
None for me, Lydia.
我要去酒吧见我的朋友们了
I'm meeting me mates down at the pub.
又去? 但是 Neville 你的所有时间
Again? But Neville, you spend all your time
都花在了 狐狸与猪与狗与狼与猫
down at the Fox and Pig and Dog and Wolf and Cat
与小提琴与口哨与鸡巴吧了
and Fiddle and Whistle and Cock.
你这么说就错了
And that's where you're wrong.
狐狸与猪与狗与狼与猫
The Fox and Pig and Dog and Wolf and Cat
与小提琴与口哨与鸡巴吧是废物去的地方
and Fiddle and Whistle and Cock is for tossers.
我们要去的是 狗与猫与公牛与口哨
We're meetin' at the Dog and Cat and Bull and Whistle
与小提琴与鸡巴与猪与狼与马车
and Fiddle and Cock and Pig and Wolf and Carriage
与火与另一只狼吧
and Fife and Other Wolf!
但我想让你留在家和Collingsworth谈谈
But I need you to stay and have a chat with Collingsworth.
我今天早上发现他又在抽烟了
I found him with another fag in his mouth this morning.
噢 这样做对么
Oh, is that right?
这么说你喜欢香烟 对么
So you fancy fags, do you?
那好吧 给你一整条烟
Well, here. Have a whole carton of fags!
恶搞了S09E13与S10E03中Peter为了惩罚Chris而给了他一整条烟
我只是想得到一位清秀姑娘的垂青
I just want a comely lass to look upon me with favour.
我看上你了哦
I look on you with favour.
你整个人我都看上了
I look on all of you with favour.
闭嘴 英国的Meg
Shut up, British Meg.
(德州口音)看看Lydia啊
Look at Lydia.
真是个下贱的威奇托婊子
What a two-bit Wichita whore.
美国堪萨斯州南部城市
总有一天 她会死在床上
One of these days, she's gonna wake up killt.
啊 弑母者
Ah, matricide.
又是个你儿时的古怪念头
Yet another of your childhood whims.
恶搞了S05E08中关于Cool Whip的发音段子
不 不是的 我只是要遵循…
No, it ain't. I'm gonna follow through with...
等等 你为什么那样说
Wait, why'd you say it like that?
要嵌入了么 先生?
Cutaway, sir?
是的 现在是个好时机
Yes, that's good then.
朋友们 家人们 还有跑龙套的们
Friends, family, and characters random
为了连续地为您带来欢乐和笑声
To bring you joy and laughter in tandem
为了转移视线和让你眼花缭乱是我们的目的
To divert and dazzle is our intention
那么做好了 放轻松 然后欣赏我们的故事
So sit back, relax, and enjoy our invention.
啊 我喜欢夏天
Ah, I love summer.
晚上好 Billingsbury 我是Clive Crowley
Good evening, Billingsbury. I'm Clive Crowley.
接下来的新闻:带着一杆枪2发子弹的男人
Coming up: a man with a gun and two bullets
已经接管了曼彻斯特市
has taken over the city of Manchester.
但首先是我们今晚的头条新闻: 女王陛下
But first, our top story tonight: Her Majesty, the Queen,
明天将会经过我们的小镇
will be passing through our very town tomorrow.
详细内容 我们现场连线到
With details, we now go live
印度记者 Tricia Dasgupta
to Indian reporter, Tricia Dasgupta.
神啊 引起这里不少骚动呢
Oh, my golly, there is much commotion.
谢谢 Tricia 广告之后
Thank you, Tricia. After the interval,
我们将会揭晓哪12支球队今晚打成平局
find out which 12 football teams tied tonight.
女王要来Billingsbury?
The Queen's comin' to Billingsbury?
这太他娘的棒了
That's bloody sweet!
知道么 我其实是王室的亲戚
You know, I'm actually a relation of the royal family.
你肯定不是
You most certainly are not.
你这想法是从哪冒出来的
Where would you get that idea?
我妈过去常抱怨她是个温莎家的人
Me mum used to claim she was a Windsor.
温莎甲组由1917年后开始统治大不列颠
而且我老听我奶奶说她是怎么傍上公爵的
And I always heard my Nana talk about how she took a duke.
duke也指体积比较大的屎
这也一定是场艰难的婚姻啊
Must've been a difficult marriage, too,
因为每天下午她都会因为
'cause every afternoon she'd be belly-achin'
她那该死的公爵(巨屎)肚子疼
about her bloody duke.
我想你只是有个恶心的奶奶罢了
I think you just had a gross grandmother.
不 我很肯定 为了证实这一切
No, I'm quite sure of it. And to prove it,
我要偷来一些女王的头发
I'm gonna nick one of the Queen's hairs
在她明天到来的时候
during her visit tomorrow.
然后等DNA匹配时 你们就会知道我是皇亲国戚了
And when the DNA proves a match, you'll see I'm royalty.
女王吗
The Queen, eh?
我更喜欢用我的香肠去捣烂她该死的布丁
I'd like to mash my banger in her blood pudding.
Googity. Googity. Glop.
- 好啊 伙计们 - 噢 你好 Seamus
- Hello, lads. - Oh, hello, Seamus.
今天的板球比赛表现十分良好
Right fine performance at the cricket match today.
是的 我很高兴你们去了现场看我比赛
Aye. I was spirited to have you down there watching me.
啊 真是个打一场冗长且
Well, it's a brilliant day
莫名其妙的板球的好天气
for a long and confusing game of cricket.
场地上满满的都是戴头盔的人
The field is teeming with men in helmets
但看上去其实完全不需要带
who don't seem like they need helmets,
而那些没戴头盔的人
and men not in helmets
看上去其实更应该带
who seem like they probably should be wearing helmets.
噢 他一板就把球直接打出了体育场
Oh, he's batted it clear out of the stadium.
那很厉害么 我们不清楚 但我们就是这样的
Is that good? We don't know, but it's what we do!
耶-耶
Y-Yay!
呸 呸
Boo!Boo!
呸
Boo!
Oh my goodness, the Queen is
going to be here presently.
This is oh-so-exciting!
My favorite part
before the Queen arrives
is yelling "wanker"
at Prince Charles as he passes.
Wanker!
I know, I know.
Yes, I know. Yes.
Wanker!
You're a wanker!
Right, quite right.
Spot on. He's got it.
I say, a lot of people have
turned out to see the Queen.
Should make for a grand day.
Hey, watch it there!
Good show, old chap.
Well played.
Here she comes!
(crowd cheering)
Very well.
Time for action.
A lock of the Queen's hair
shall soon be mine.
Here she comes.
Have at it then.
Crikey! This is a haircut
fit for a queen!
Oh, bloody hell!
All right, time for Plan B.
Let's go!
I'm not going any lower.
Well, Father,
you gave it a good go.
Oh, we're not done yet.
Come on!
(tires squeal)
Queen! Queen! Give me
some of your hair!
Come on, Queen!
Don't be a bitch!
Get us away
from that lunatic!
(tires squeal)
She's heading into that tunnel!
(crashing, horse neighs)
GUARD (screaming):
Dear God! The Queen's dead!
(both whistling)
All right, Collingsworth,
I got a hair.
Now, just walk away casual-like
and we're in the clear.
Oh, no!
Here come the coppers!
("Yakkity Sax" playing)
(inhales deeply)
Bugger.
Well, it turns out
I'm not royalty.
Shame about the Queen, though.
Yeah, I reckon she's with
Jesus Christ in heaven now.
(spits)
(metallic ding)
Well, I'm just happy our
family is safe and sound
back in our cozy row house.
Row house.
(thunder rumbling)
TV ANNOUNCER:
We now return
to The Comedy Central Roast
of Robin Williams.
Aw, man, Robin Williams
is my favorite!
He must be getting recognized
for all his contributions
to show business.
I don't think
that's what a roast is.
Robin, as a comic, it's an honor
to be up here roasting you.
As a moviegoer, I want
to punch you in the face.
(laughter)
Oh, that's funny.
Advocate violence.
And let's face it, Mork.
You're getting Nanu-Na-old!
(laughs)
(laughter)
Stop it! You stop it!
Robin Williams has a manic gift
that gladdens a sad world
and all he asks in return
is our unceasing attention!
How can you allow this?!
Robin Williams has given us
nothing but joy!
I wish everyone
was Robin Williams!
(thunder rumbling)
(electric sizzling)
Boy, that looks enticing.
(thunder rumbling)
(electric sizzling)
Yeah, this is nice.
Oh, my God.
What happened?
You were in a coma, and then I
kissed you, and you woke up.
(mumbles)
Like two days later.
Anyway, all your
numbers are normal.
What numbers?
No idea.
Well, congratulations.
You're gonna be just fine.
(electric buzzing)
Oh, my God!
You're...
You're Robin Williams!
Ding! Thank you for playing
"That's Obvious!"
Tell him what he's won, Cletus!
(hick accent): Money!
(normal): Ho-ho! Money.
Or as the Republicans
call it,
(imitating witch):
Mine!
(laughs)
I hope this is covered
by your HMO.
I was covered once by
an HMO in San Francisco.
I Haight my Ashbury
in these jeans!
Ding-ding, Rice-A-Roni!
Ah! You got all those
references in there!
Of course now everyone
can afford health care
because of Obama.
Yeah, you want a Band-Aid?
No problem, turkey.
Come on down to Obama-Mart!
The price is free,
but yo ass better vote for me.
Ha! Political
with a twist.
It's funny from the news!
What's going on in here?
You gotta check this out!
It's Robin Williams!
Ho-ho! A nurse
is a nurse, of curse.
Up yours, Wilbur.
Oh, my God!
Everyone I touch
turns into Robin Williams!
Yess! Peter Sweet Cheeks
Griffin-uh!
You have been given
the power from god-uh!
Ho-ho! Ho-ho!
Ho-ho!
(laughing)
I will be so responsible
with this.
Thanks, guys!
Ho-ho!
Bye!
See you, Peter!
Y'all come back now, y'hear?
(chuckles)
It's Patch Adams Robin.
He cures stuff the fun way,
not the medicine way.
So, somehow the lightning
gave your dad
the power to turn anyone
I touch into Robin Williams.
Peter, did Dr. Hartman say
how long this was gonna last?
There is no more
Dr. Hartman, Lois.
He's Robin Williams now.
Bet you kids never thought
your dad
would have superpowers, huh?
Peter!
Ho-ho! You pat my back, I pat yours,
and Pat Robertson
pats Mr. Happy.
(Southern accent): Yayuss! Praise
Jesus with your Visa card!
Max it out
on the Lord, people!
Oh, boy!
And that's the second
Southern preacher one.
Look, Brian! Meg is
one of the sensitive,
bearded Robin Williams
characters.
Ha!
You think that's funny, chief?
Well, I...
My wife is dead.
Oh, I'm... I'm sorry.
She's dead, chief.
Ho-ho! Dead.
The Grateful Dead. Please
do not take the brown acid.
It will turn you
into a Martian.
Take me to your wiener.
Ho-ho!
We're (bleep).
("Rockin' Robin"
by Bobby Day playing)
♪ ♪
♪ He rocks in the treetop
all a day long ♪
♪ Hoppin' and a-boppin'
and a-singin' the song ♪
♪ All the little birds
on Jaybird Street ♪
♪ Love to hear the robin
goin' tweet-tweet-tweet ♪
♪ Rockin' robin,
tweet-tweet-tweet. ♪
I don't know, Peter.
This all seems kind of creepy.
What do you mean?
This is great!
Everyone's hilarious now!
What do you think, Quagmire?
What? I can't hear a thing
over this noise.
What?!
This is unbearable!
I think I got just the thing
to cheer you up, Joe.
I know I said I was a leg man,
but this is ridiculous. Ho!
I feel like a testicle
on steroids.
Honey, I shrunk my nuts!
Ho! Ha!
Ho-ho! I'm a
San Francisco pirate.
I Haight my Ashbury
in these jeans!
A lot of the material
is repeated.
Mmm, Lois,
your torso is
so broad and solid.
(spits, coughs)
Ah! You're not Lois!
I can hear you!
I'm not deaf!
I don't believe that's
real sign language!
Brian, this is
a disaster!
I turned everyone
into Robin Williams!
You gotta help me!
Yo-yo-yo! Peter G.
What's happening,
dawg?
Oh, Sideways Hat Robin.
Dear God, no!
(kettle whistles)
♪ Gonna have some hot tea,
baby, this morning! ♪
(yells)
Run, Forrest, run!
All right, Rupert,
all we have to do
is act like Robin Williams,
and he'll think
we've already changed.
Ho-ho! Scattered
stream of references!
Lots of energy! One good one
for every ten! Ho-ho!
Damn these hands!
Mwah!
Vell, I haven't been
to temple in a while!
Ah!
Ladies and gentleman,
The Doors!
(screaming)
Ho-ho! Jogging!
Running on empty! Ho-ho!
Run, Forrest, run!
ALL:
Ho-ho! Ho-ho! Ho-ho!
Ho-ho! I'm a Mercedes!
Und vere are your papers?
Are you from
East or Vest Berlin?
(a la John Wayne):
Vell, I'm from Vest Berlin, pilgrim.
(sobbing)
Shut up!
(yelling)
(sobbing)
Ho-ho! Ho-ho!
Stop riffing!
Jump, Forest, jump!
Must be a leap
year, ho-ho!
Time to lose
some weight, dearie?
No... more... comedy.
Guys, will you please
settle down?
Can we, can we settle down,
please?
Every... everyone.
Everyone, can I have
your attention?
Oh, Captains! My Captains!
I have an announcement to make:
You are all free!
You have been fired
from the school.
Vietnam is over.
The hospital is closing.
Will Hunting is all better.
It's not your fault.
Shut up. Seriously, shut up.
Please, you are done here.
Go and spread your comedy
to all corners of this country.
Wait, not you five.
I'm gonna keep you for...
an experiment.
Ho-ho! Eggs!
Who came first, the chicken
or the porn star?
Ho-ho!
The Porn Identity!
Who am I? Oh, yeah!
The pizza man!
Baka-chikka-bwow-bwow!
Ho-ho! Ho-ho!
Peter, can you pass
the coffee?
Sure, Brian the dog.
Anything for my family.
Coffee now.
Here we go, here we go.
I guess Disney wouldn't let us
do the Aladdin one.
LOIS:
Stewie, rise and shine.
Good morning, Stewie.
(bleep) you.
You ready for the day, sweetie?
Oh, someone needs
a diaper change.
Are you proud
of yourself?
That this
is what you do?
Is this a dime?
Did you swallow a dime?
Yeah, wipe it off
and put it back in your purse,
you white trash hen.
There we go.
Who's my clean little boy?
(Stewie laughing)
Ugh! Your roots
are ridiculous.
I'm gonna grab
your hair 'cause
I like grabbing stuff.
Okay. Okay, Stewie, let go.
Let, let go, Stewie.
Let go of Mommy's hair.
When I grow up, I'm
never gonna call you.
I'm gonna be busy
with my job and my family.
You'll be nothing.
Stewie, I want you
to have my ring.
It's one of my most
important possessions,
and I want you to have it.
Okay, red flag.
Red flag, everybody!
Hey, Stewie,
wanna go down the slide?
STEWIE:
Um...
What's the matter?
Ya never been down
the slide before?
(scoffs) Yeah, like,
like a thousand times.
Just done it so much
I'm bored with it, that's all.
All right, I guess
we're doing this.
Whoa.
Come on down,
Stewie!
(hawks screeching)
This is crazy. This is crazy.
This is crazy.
All right, you can do this,
Stewie. Here we go.
(screams)
(thud)
Are you okay?
Yeah, that wasn't so bad.
You might wanna move.
That farting Polish kid
is coming down the slide.
(Stewie grunts)
(kid farts)
Ah, Pavel!
Hey, kid, come here.
I wanna see
if I can still smell
your mom's boobs on your mouth.
Why don't you go hump
a pile of garbage?
All right, here we go.
Classic.
(engine starts)
Uh-oh. (grunts)
Oh, God! Brian! Brian!
Guess I'm going for a ride.
Why are we stopping?
(squirrel chitters)
Oh, come on.
For God's sake, Brian.
It's just a squirrel.
BRIAN:
Yeah!
Oh, God!
(Stewie groans)
He can't hurt you anymore.
Hey there, little fella.
We sure got a lovely day for it,
don't we?
Stay away from
my brother's butt.
Okay, Stewie, let's get
that little face washed off.
Then you can play
with your bath toys, huh?
No, I hate getting
my face washed!
Oh, look!
It's just Mr. Frog!
Hello, Mr. Frog...
(spluttering)
My God, how the hell
do I keep falling for that?
Now you play with your toys
and I'll go get yo
a nice, fluffy towel.
Stewart Griffin, explorer,
adventurer,
skin-diving
international playboy.
(takes deep breath)
(Stewie growls, screams)
I'm swimming at night
'cause I'm a slut
and now I'm paying
the price for it.
(panting)
Hey, Stewie!
Wow, looks like you got
some cool bath toys in there.
Is it okay if I join ya?
No! (screams)
Hey, is that
my froggie butt cloth?
Okay, Stewie, bedtime's
in ten minutes.
I'll be right back.
Hmm. I think I have time
for a quickie.
Excuse me, Mr. Cobain.
Look, I know
you're depressed.
Made some bad choices
with women,
but there's another way.
Haagen-Dazs,
lots of Haagen-Dazs.
(whooshing)
Well, let's see if it worked.
Here we go.
Ha! You're still alive,
you fat (bleep).
Okay, Stewie, time for bed.
You want Mommy to read you
a night-night story?
Oh, how 'bout this one?
"Good Night, Town
from Footloose"?
LOIS:
Who is this book for?
(slurring): Hey, Lois.
I'm home from the Clam.
You know what that means.
STEWIE: You spent the last ten minutes
parked in front of the house
crying in your car?
Not now, Peter. I'm doing
story time with Stewie.
Yeah, scram, Drinky.
I got a story.
It's about the little penis
that could.
It thinks it can, it thinks...
In fact, it's pretty sure
it can.
It-It, it's gonna.
Hey, am I gonna have
to handle this?
Do you want me
Peter, just go wait
in the bedroom.
I'll be right there.
Fine, but if I gotta pee first,
this night's gonna be ruined.
Ruined.
Good night, sweetie.
Mommy loves you.
(Stewie yawns)
(rhythmic thudding)
Huh?
(both grunting)
It's big, isn't it?
Yes, Peter.
It's very big.
Yeah, it's big.
Oh, God, yes!
Ah, yes...
Ah, yeah.
Oh, you're gonna use that thing,
good. I love you so much.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==