You know, I smoked a lot of grass
Oh, Lord, I popped a lot of pills
But I've never touched nothin'
That my spirit could kill
You know, I've seen a lot of people walkin' 'round
With tombstones in their eyes
But the pusher don't care
If you live or if you die
God damn
The pusher
Hey, hey, I say the pusher
I said, God damn
God damn the pusher man
Get your motor runnin'
Head out on the highway
Lookin' for adventure
And whatever comes our way
Yeah, darlin' Gonna make it happen
Take the world in a love embrace
Fire all of the guns at once and
Explode info space
I like smoke and lightnin'
Heavy metal thunder
Racin' with the wind
And the feelin' that I'm under
Yeah, darlin' Gonna make it happen
Take the world in a love embrace
Fire all of the guns at once and
Explode info space
Like a true nature's child
We were born, born to be wild
We can climb so high
And never wanna die
Born to be wild
Hey, you got a room?
Hey, man!
You got a room?
You asshole!
I'm goin' down to Mardi Gras I'm gonna get me a Mardi Gras queen
Oh, man. Wow, Mardi Gras, man.
That's gonna be the weirdest, man.
You know what we ought to do first thing, man?
Go and get us a groovy dinner.
Break out some of that cash, man.
Out here in the wilderness, fighting Indians and cowboys on every side.
What's the matter? You zonked? You really zoaned?
No, I'm just kinda tired, man.
Oh, man, you're pulling inside.
You're getting a little distance tonight.
You're getting a little distance, baby.
Yeah.
Well, I'm just getting my thing together.
Yeah, right.
Come on. It's check-out time.
Hey. Billy.
Oh, man, don't do that.
Howdy.
What can I do for you?
I'd like to fix my flat, if you don't mind.
No, I don't mind.
Just get in the barn. You'll find the tools you'll need.
Whoa, baby. Whoa, honey.
Turn that thing off. You're making my horse skittish.
That sure is a good-looking machine.
Yeah.
There you go.
You fellas can sit down here.
Would you mind taking off your hat?
We thank Thee, O Lord, for these, Thy gifts...
received from Thy bounty...
in the name of Thy only begotten son, Jesus Christ, our Lord.
Amen.
Where you fellas from?
L.A.
Los Angeles.
Los Angeles. Is that a fact?
When I was young...
I was headed for California, but...
Well, you know how it is.
Well, you sure got a nice spread here.
Sure got a lot of 'em.
My wife is Catholic, you know.
Honey, could we have some more coffee?
No, I mean it. You've got a nice place.
It's not every man that can live off the land.
You do your own thing in your own time. You should be proud.
Well, I'd rather go and journey
Where the diamond crescent's glowing
And run across the valley
Beneath the sacred mountain
And wander through the forest
Where the frees have leaves of prisms
And break the light in colors
That no one knows the names of
And when if's time I'll go and waif
Beside a legendary fountain
Till I see the form reflected
In its clear and jeweled waters
And if you think I'm ready
You may lead me to the chasm
Where the rivers of our vision
Flow info one another
I will want to dive beneath
The white cascading waters
She may beg, she may plead
She may argue with her logic
And mention all the things I learned
That really have no value
In the end she will surely know
I wasn't born to follow
Hey, man, what are you doing?
I gotta talk to you, man.
Everything we ever dreamed of is in that teardrop gas tank...
and you got a stranger over there pouring gasoline all over it.
All he's gotta do is look into it and he can see that...
He won't know what it is, man.
Don't worry, Billy. Everything's all right.
All right, all right. I don't know, man.
I do.
Everything's fine, Billy.
- Well... - That's all taken care of.
I like that.
I pulled in to Nazareth
Was feelin' 'bout half past dead
I just need some place
Where I can lay my head
Hey, mister, can you tell me
Where a man might find a bed
He just grinned and shook my hand
"No" was all he said
Take a load off, Fanny
Take a load for free
And
You put the load right on me
I picked up my bag
I went lookin' for a place to hide
Then I saw old Carmen and the devil
Walkin' side by side
I said, Hey, Carmen
Come on, let's go downtown
She said, I gotta go
But my friend can stick around
Take a load off, Fanny
Take a load for free
And
You put the load right on me
Yeah
Take a load off, Fanny
Take a load for free
And
You put the load right on me
- How much further we gotta go, man? - I don't know.
Not much further.
That's what you said this morning.
I sometimes say it all day.
Really? You say it all day, huh?
We don't have much longer. We'll be there soon.
We gotta get to Mardi Gras, man. We're going to Mardi Gras.
Little heart is set on that, huh?
We got a week.
That's a week away, man.
It's a long way to Mardi Gras, baby.
It won't take us a week to get to New Orleans.
Wow.
I think I'm gonna crash.
I think you have crashed, man.
I keep seeing things jumping all over the place.
- Really? - Yeah, look.
- What is it? - It's a moth.
- A what? - Moth.
Bug.
It's a weird place, man.
Oh, man. That smoke's getting to me.
But I notice you're not moving.
Where you from, man?
Can I have a light?
Hard to say.
"Hard to say"? Where you from, man?
It's hard to say because it's a very long word, you know.
I just wanna know where you're from, man.
A city.
What city?
Doesn't make any difference what city. All cities are alike.
That's why I'm out here now.
Why you're out here now? Why?
'Cause I'm a long way from the city, and that's where I wanna be right now.
They know you in this place?
This place we're coming to?
Or the place we're at now?
This place.
You're right on top of 'em.
- I'm right on top of 'em? - Yeah.
The people this place belongs to are buried right under you.
You could be a trifle polite.
"A trifle polite"?
A small thing to ask.
You ever want to be somebody else?
I'd like to try Porky Pig.
I never wanted to be anybody else.
You can't hit me! I'm invisible! I'm invisible!
Hey, Sarah.
How's it going?
Rudolph, what are you eating?
- Thanks for the stuff you brought. - How's it going?
We just can't take any more strangers. Just too many people dropping in.
I'm not talking about you and your friends... you know that.
The week before, Susan dropped in with 12 people from Easter City.
She wanted to take ten pounds of rice with her.
Naturally we had to say no...
so she gets all uptight, breaks out some hash and won't give us any.
That's not all. The next morning they couldn't get their bus started.
Sarah, I bet you haven't had anybody like me around to rap to, have you?
I don't have to tell you how it is, Sarah.
I love you, and I want you to rap.
- Oh, God, I want you to rap, rap, rap. - Cut that out!
I guess nobody else here is interested, but I'd sure like to meet your friend.
I bet you'd like to do more than that.
I think he's beautiful.
He's beautiful.
What is that weird thing up there on the hill, man?
It looks like a stage. You got light opera coming here or something?
That's the mime troupe's stage.
They've gone down to the hot springs to bathe.
Mime troupe?
Hey, Lisa. What does this mean?
"Starting brings misfortune.
Perseverance brings danger.
Not every demand for change in the existing order should be heeded.
On the other hand, repeated and well-founded complaints...
should not fail to a hearing."
Hear ye, hear ye, hear ye!
We've come to play for our dinner.
Or should I say, stay for our dinner?
Or even...
slay for our dinner!
Oh! Men at war. How ghastly.
We've come to drink your wine...
taste your food and take pleasure in your women.
The water in that river is about 80 degrees.
You put your hand in about a foot away, it's below freezing.
- Come on! I've got to get dinner on! - What's this I hear?
Who said "out" to me?
Pardon me! I've played communes all...
Out! Out! Out!
The evil eye on this place! A double whammy for all of you!
- When you lie with dogs, you get fleas. - Come, my dear.
We won't play here.
Wow. Wow. Wow.
Get out.
I like you.
What happened here is, these people got here late in the summer.
Too late to plant.
But the weather was beautiful, it was easy living, everything was fine.
Then came that winter.
Forty or fifty of them living in this one-room place down here.
Nothing to eat. Starving. Out by the road looking for dead horses.
Anything they could get ahold of.
There's 18 or 20 of them left, and they're city kids... look at them.
But they're getting this crop in...
and they're gonna stay here till it's harvested.
Do you get much rain here, man?
I guess we're gonna have to dance for that.
Look at this, man. A seashell, man.
See that?
This is nothing but sand. They ain't gonna grow anything here.
They're gonna make it.
Dig, man.
We have planted our seeds.
We ask...
that our efforts be worthy...
to produce simple food...
for our simple taste.
We ask that our efforts...
be rewarded.
We thank You for the food we eat from other hands...
that we may share it with our fellow man...
and be even more generous...
when it is from our own.
Thank You for a place...
to make a stand.
Amen.
Let's eat.
Ah, hark, ye gentles! Hark, ye all!
The time has come for a curtain call.
How do you wear your hair Does your hair hang low
Do you tie if in a ribbon Do you tie if in a bow
Do you wear it over your shoulder like a Continental soldier
Does your hair hang low
Are you an Aquarius?
Pisces?
I guessed right.
Do you like our place here?
Yeah.
We will kill the old red rooster
We will kill the old red rooster when she comes
We'll all go to greet her when she comes
We will all have chicken and dumplings when she comes
Who sent you?
Does your hair hang low
Do you tie if in a ribbon Do you tie if in a bow
Do you throw it over your shoulder like a Continental soldier
Does your hair hang low
Look, I gotta get out of here, man.
We got things we wanna do, man.
I gotta get out of here, man.
Could you take me and my friend over across the canyon?
Yeah, anything.
It won't be out of your way. Honest.
It's all right.
We're not no travelin' bureau. Why don't they get their own ride?
We're eating their food.
All right.
- Get 'em together, though, man. - Right.
More water! More water!
Well, I'd rather go and journey
Where the diamond crescent's glowing
And run across the valley
Beneath the sacred mountain
And wander through the forest
Where the frees have leaves of prisms
And break the light in colors
That no one knows the names of
And when if's time I'll go and waif
Beside a legendary fountain
Till I see the form reflected
In its clear and jeweled waters
And if you think I'm ready
You may lead me to the chasm
Where the rivers of our vision
Flow info one another
I will want to dive beneath
The white cascading wafers
She may beg, she may plead
She may argue with her logic
And mention all the things I learned
That really have no value
In the end, she will surely know
I wasn't born to follow
When you get to the right place with the right people...
quarter this.
You know, this could be the right place.
Your time's running out.
If we're going, let's go!
Yeah.
I'm hip about time.
But I gotta go.
"Parading without a permit"? You gotta be kidding!
Do you know who this is? This is Captain America! I'm Billy!
Hey, we're headliners, baby!
We played every fair in this part of the country, and for top dollar too!
Weirdo hicks, man. A bunch of weirdo hicks.
"Parading without a permit"! Man!
Oh, no. What did I do now?
Oh, what am I gonna do now?
Oh, my head.
All right, George, what are you gonna do now?
I mean, you promised these people.
You promised these people.
They ain't gonna believe you, George.
Hey, man, would you mind? You just woke my friend up.
Oh. Yeah, well...
I'm real sorry. I didn't realize.
I didn't realize.
My head.
If you don't shut your mouth, you ain't gonna have a head.
I see you're up, Mr. Hanson. You'll feel a lot better after this.
Oh.
Thank you, Bob.
I guess I really tied one on last night.
Must have had a hell of a good time.
Wish I could remember it.
Hey, man, you don't think you could get me a cigarette, do you?
You animals ain't smart enough to play with fire.
Oh, no, that's all right, Bob. They're good boys.
You can give them a cigarette.
Thanks, mister.
- You got a match? - Yeah.
Thank you, Bob.
I'm sorry about, you know, the misunderstanding.
Oh, that's all right. There was no misunderstanding.
We're all in the same cage here.
You must be some important dude, man, to get that treatment.
"Dude"?
What does he mean, "dude"? Dude ranch?
"Dude" means...
a nice guy.
A regular sort of person.
Well, you boys don't look like you're from this part of the country.
You're lucky I'm here to see that you don't get into anything.
"Anything"?
They got this here...
scissor-happy, "beautify America" thing going on around here.
They're trying to make everybody look like Yul Brynner.
They used rusty razor blades...
on the last two longhairs they brought in here...
and I wasn't here to protect 'em.
I'm a lawyer. Done a lot of work for the ACLU.
"George Hanson."
You think you can help us get out of here with no sweat?
I imagine that I can, if you haven't killed anybody.
At least nobody white.
See there? Twenty-five dollars. And no razor blades.
Very groovy, George. Thank you.
"Very groovy." See there? I'll bet nobody ever said that to you.
Oh, by the way, Bob, thanks for the aspirin before.
George, I'm gettin' to think you're a regular regular around here.
I'm not gonna tell your dad.
You just gotta be more careful.
Well, Pat, that'd be real good if the powers that be wouldn't hear about this.
I mean, the old man hasn't been feeling too good. You know what I mean?
Well, now, George, you know we won't tell your dad about that.
- Isn't that right, Bob? - Right.
Well...
what do you say we take a look at these super machines...
we've been hearing so much about?
Let's get it on.
- Thanks a lot, Bob. - Sure. See you later.
I'll take care of it later.
All right, Carl.
Thanks a million. Say hello to the missus for me.
Here's the first of the day, fellas.
To old D.H. Lawrence.
Indians!
Thank you.
You know...
I must have started off to Mardi Gras...
six or seven times.
Never got further than the state line.
Governor of Louisiana give me this.
"Madame Tinkertoy's House of Blue Lights.
Corner of Bourbon and Toulouse, New Orleans, Louisiana."
Now, this is supposed to be the finest whorehouse in the South.
These ain't no pork chops. These are U.S. Prime.
Out of sight, man.
Oh, I'd like to get over there.
How long did you boys say it was gonna take you to get down there?
- About two or three days. - Two or three days? Is that right?
Oh, boy, I sure wish I was going with you.
Yeah?
You got a helmet?
Oh, I've got a helmet.
I got a beauty!
Well, old buddy, I never thought I'd ever see you again.
You know I threw this thing away one week ago.
My mother, of all people, retrieved it. I can't understand that.
She didn't even want me to play football.
Always afraid I was gonna get hurt.
And 12 years later, I find it on my pillow...
with a note pinned next to it saying...
"Save this for your son."
Fire.
Do this instead.
Oh, no, thanks. I got some store-bought right over here of my own.
No, man, this is grass.
You mean marijuana?
Yeah.
Lord, have mercy. Is that what that is?
Let me see that.
Marijuana, hmm.
Light it up.
Oh, no, no. I couldn't do that.
I mean, I've got enough problems with the booze and all.
I mean, I can't afford to get hooked.
You won't get hooked.
Yeah, well, I know, but it leads to harder stuff.
Except y-you say it's all right?
Well, all right, then.
H-How do I do it?
Here.
That's got a real nice taste to it.
Though I don't suppose it'll do me much good.
I mean, I'm so used to the booze and everything.
You've got to hold it in your lungs longer, George.
Oh, wow!
What... was that, man?
What the hell was that, man?
Huh?
No... Hey, man, wow. I was watching this object.
Like the satellite that we saw the other night.
It was going right across the sky, and then...
I mean, it just suddenly...
It just changed direction and went whizzing right off, man.
- It flashed... - You're stoned out of your mind.
Yeah, like, I'm stoned, you know, man...
but I saw a satellite, man...
and it was going across the sky...
and it flashed three times at me...
and zigzagged and whizzed off, man.
And I saw it.
That was a UFO beamin' back at you.
Me and Eric was down in Mexico two weeks ago.
We seen 40 of 'em flyin' in formation.
They have got bases all over the world now.
They been comin' here ever since 1946...
when the scientists first started bouncin' radar beams off of the moon...
and they have been livin' and workin' among us in vast quantities ever since.
The government knows all about 'em.
What are you talkin', man?
You just seen one of 'em, didn't you?
Hey, man, I saw something, man...
but I didn't see it working here, you know what I mean?
Well, they are people just like us...
from within our own solar system...
except that their society is more highly evolved.
They don't have no wars. They got no monetary system.
They don't have any leaders because each man is a leader.
I mean, each man... Because of their technology...
they are able to feed, clothe, house and transport themselves...
equally and with no effort.
Wow.
Well, you know something, man?
You wanna know what I think?
I think this is a crackpot idea! That's what I think.
How 'bout that? How 'bout a little of that?
I think it's a crackpot idea!
If they're so smart...
why don't they reveal themselves to us and get it over with?
"Why don't they reveal themselves to us?" is because if they did...
it would cause a general panic.
Now, we still have leaders...
upon whom we rely for the release of this information.
These leaders have decided...
to repress this information because of the tremendous shock...
that it would cause to our antiquated systems.
Now, the result of this has been that the Venusians...
have contacted people at all walks of life.
All walks of life.
Yes.
It would be a devastatin' blow to our antiquated systems.
So now Venusians are meeting with people in all walks of life...
in an advisory capacity.
For once, man will have a godlike control...
over his own destiny.
He will have a chance to transcend and to evolve...
with some equality for all.
How's your joint, George?
Oh, my, I believe it went out.
I got to talkin' so much I clean forgot about it.
Went out.
Save it. We'll do it tomorrow morning, first thing, all right?
Gives you a whole new way of looking at the day.
I sure could use that.
Yes, I sure could use a little of that.
Don’t Bogart that joint, my friend
Pass it over to me
Roll another one
Just like the other one
You've been hanging on to it
And I sure would like a hit
Yeah
Sing a song, brother
If the sun refused to shine
I don’t mind
If the mountains fell in the sea
Let it be
It ain’t me
Got my own world to live through
And I ain’t gonna copy you
Now if a 6 turned out to be 9
Oh, I don’t mind
I don’t mind
If all the hippies
Cut off all their hair
I don’t care
Oh, I don’t care
Dig, 'cause I got my own world to live through and I...
What the hell is this? Troublemakers?
You name it, and I'll throw rocks at it, Sheriff.
Y'all, check what just walked in.
Ooh, I like the one in the red shirt with the suspenders.
The white shirt's for me.
Look how tuff those black pants are.
We're in the establishment now, aren't we, gentlemen?
- What did you say? - I said...
I just can't believe it. What are they doin' here?
- Look at the teeth around his neck. - Did they drive up on motorcycles?
They know we're talkin' about 'em. They're lookin' over here.
Hot damn. I'll tell you.
I'll order kidneys, 'cause I left mine out on the road somewhere.
I don't know, but I like his hair.
I like his eyes.
See that little girl right over there in the corner?
Don't look too close at her...
because the sheriff's right over there.
Check that one with the long hair.
I checked him. Might have to bring him up to the Hilton before it's over with.
I think she's cute.
Isn't she? Guess we'll put 'em in a woman's cell, don't you reckon?
I think we oughta put 'em in a cage and charge admission to see 'em.
Those are what is known as "country witticisms."
What are they doin' here?
- I don't know. - I'm gonna ask for a ride.
Don't be foolish. No.
- They'll laugh in your face. - Yeah.
I'm gonna ask 'em.
Not when I'm around you're not gonna ask 'em.
- I don't think you're gonna. - Go ahead.
Go ahead.
You know, I thought at first that bunch over there...
their mothers may have been frightened by a bunch of gorillas...
but now I think they're a cult.
One of 'em is Alley Oop, I think, from the beads on him.
One of 'em, darn sure, is not Oola.
Look like a bunch of refugees from a gorilla love-in.
- A gorilla couldn't love that. - Nor could a mother.
I wouldn't even mate him up with one of those black wenches out there.
Oh, now, I don't know about that.
That's about as low as they come, I'll tell you.
- Oh, he's a biggie. - Man, they're green.
No, they're not green. They're white.
White?
You're color-blind. I just got to say that.
I'd like to get some food.
I thought most jails were built for humanity...
and that won't quite qualify.
- Wonder where they got those wigs from? - They probably grew 'em.
Look like they're standin' in fertilizer.
- Nothin' else would grow on 'em. - I'm not real hungry at the moment.
- You know what I mean? - I saw two of 'em one time.
They were just kissin' away. Two males! Just think of it.
What you think we oughta do with 'em?
I don't know, but I don't think they'll make the parish line.
Let's split.
- Split? - Yeah.
Yes, sir, it certainly has been nice.
They got some fancy bikes out there. That's some Yankee queers.
Check the flag on that bike.
It sure is.
I still say they're not gonna make the parish line.
Here come the poontang.
Hey, y'all, could we have a ride?
- You want a ride? - Yeah. Please?
You got a note from your moms?
- My old lady won't mind. - Please let us have a ride.
I wouldn't mind giving you a ride.
Uh-oh. The Man is at the window.
The Man is at the window.
Oh, come on.
The Man is at the window!
I'd love to take you girls for a ride.
You know, this used to be a hell of a good country.
I can't understand what's gone wrong with it.
Everybody got chicken, that's what happened.
Hey, we can't even get into a second-rate hotel.
I mean, a second-rate motel, you dig?
They think we're gonna cut their throat.
- They're scared, man. - They're not scared of you.
They're scared of what you represent to 'em.
Hey, man, all we represent to them is somebody who needs a haircut.
Oh, no.
What you represent to them is freedom.
What's wrong with freedom? That's what it's all about.
That's right. That's what it's all about.
But talkin' about it and bein' it...
that's two different things.
It's real hard to be free...
when you are bought and sold in the marketplace.
'Course, don't ever tell anybody that they're not free...
'cause then they gonna get real busy killin' and maimin'...
to prove to you that they are.
Oh, yeah, they gonna talk to you and talk to you and talk to you...
about individual freedom.
But they see a free individual, it's gonna scare 'em.
Well, it don't make 'em runnin' scared.
No. It makes 'em dangerous.
Swamp.
Yeah, right, man.
- Swamp. - Swamp!
You ever...
You ever talk to bullfrogs in the middle of the night?
Not generally.
You know what I used to do?
What did you used to do?
I'll tell you one thing I didn't used to do...
is talk to bullfrogs in the middle of the night, fool.
Shit! You're out of your mind!
That's right.
Hey, man.
You okay?
Oh, God, man. Oh, God.
What are we gonna do with his stuff, man?
Get it to his folks.
There's not much here.
There's some money and his driver's license.
There's a... Oh, man, here's his card, man.
He ain't gonna be using that.
We'll go there for one drink. Just one drink.
No, man. Hey, listen. Seriously. He would have wanted us to.
"If God did not exist, it would be necessary to invent him."
That's a humdinger.
I'm getting a little smashed, man. A little smashed.
Wow, it's hot in here, man.
Chicks, man.
Where are those chicks, man?
Look at this one.
- It's okay. - Good-bye, girls.
- Howdy. - Hello.
My name is Billy...
and this here is Captain America.
Excuse me one minute, ladies.
Do you mind if I take the tall one, man?
- No, that's all right. - Oh, thank you, man.
Come on, you little hoofer, you. Get yourself over here.
You ol' thing, you. I'm really from New York.
This is all just a weird act.
You're a freak, aren't you?
My name is Mary.
- You want a drink, Mary? - No, thanks.
What's this?
- Is this really your hair? - What is this?
Is this really your hair? Are you kidding me?
- What are these things? - Well, what are these things?
I'm kind of a freak myself.
I never really thought of myself as a freak...
but I love to freak.
- What's happening outside? - What?
In the street. What's happening? Mardi Gras.
Oh, well, it's crowded and all that.
Yeah.
Want a drink?
- Here's to you. - Thank you.
What's the matter? Don't you like me?
- What? - You paid for me, right?
Well, that was for my friend.
I don't...
- Why don't I buy you a drink. - I don't drink.
I've got an idea. Let's go outside.
We'll all go outside to Mardi Gras.
Okay?
When the saints go marching in
You know I want to be in that number
Now when the saints go marching in
Oh, when the saints go marching in
I want to be in that number
When the saints go marching in
Oh, when the saints go marching on in
Oh, when the saints go marching in
You know I want to be in thaf number
When the saints go marching in
What's that?
Never mind. Just shut up and take it.
Yeah, right.
What do you do with it?
- Give it to me. - Just shut up and take it, man.
Put it under your tongue.
I believe in God...
the Father Almighty...
Creator of heaven and earth...
Going up for the last time. The last time. The last time.
...was crucified, died and was buried.
He descended into hell. The third day, He arose again from the dead.
He ascended into heaven and sitteth at the right hand of God...
the Father Almighty, Creator of heaven and earth.
I believe in God, Father Almighty, Creator of heaven and earth...
and in Jesus Christ, his only Son, our Lord.
Shut up.
Who was conceived by the Holy Ghost, born of the Virgin Mary...
suffered under Pontius Pilate, was crucified, died and was buried.
He descended into hell. The third day, He arose again from the dead.
He ascended into heaven...
and sitteth at the right hand of God, the Father Almighty.
From thence He shall come to judge the living and the dead.
I believe in the Holy Ghost, the holy Catholic Church...
the Communion of Saints, the Forgiveness of sins...
the Resurrection of the body and Life everlasting.
Amen.
Glory be to the Father and to the Son...
- and to the Holy Ghost... - How could you make me hate you so much?
As it was in the beginning, is now and ever shall be...
- I hate you so much. - World without end. Amen.
- Look at me. - I want you to be beautiful.
I always wanted to be pretty.
Listen to me. I want you to be beautiful.
- I want you to be beautiful. - No.
You know me.
I know you.
- Baby... - You did something bad.
Hail Mary, full of grace, the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God, pray for us sinners...
- now and at the hour of... - I know it. I know you.
I know you. I know you.
Oh, wow.
Glory be to the Father and to the Son...
We're all aglow, man! Look at this! We're all aglow!
Glow! Glow! We're all aglow!
Where's your junk?
- I don't know if I like you. - I like you.
But I like you.
Don't you dare. Don't you dare!
I can feel the outside.
I can feel the outside, but I can't...
I can't feel the inside.
Okay?
Don't stop!
I'm dying! I'm gonna die!
I'm gonna die!
I'm dead. I'm dead. Do you understand?
Mary love the lamb...
Mary love the...
Oh, dear God! Please help me!
Please help me to conceive a child!
I'm right out here.
I'm right out here! I'm right out here.
I'm out here, out of my head.
Please, God, let me out of here!
I want to get out of here!
Please help me.
Do you know what I mean?
You wanted me ugly, didn't you? I know you johns.
In the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit. Amen.
- You never thought about me. - I believe in God, the Father Almighty...
Why did you leave like that?
- Everybody else, but not you. - He descended into hell.
- And not me. - The third day, He arose again...
...hallowed be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come, Thy will be done...
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread, and forgive us our trespasses...
as we forgive...
You're such a fool, mother, and I hate you so much.
We've done it. We've done it.
We're rich, Wyatt.
Yeah, man.
We did it, man. We did it. We did it.
We're rich, man.
We're retired in Florida now, mister.
You know, Billy...
we blew it.
What?
That's what it's all about. I mean, like, you know.
You go for the big money, man, and then you're free.
You dig?
We blew it.
Good night, man.
Darkness at the break of noon Shadows even the silver spoon
The handmade blade, the child's balloon Eclipses both the sun and moon
To understand you know too soon There is no sense in tryin'
Pointed threats, they bluff with scorn Suicide remarks are torn
From the fool's gold mouthpiece The hollow horn plays wasted words
Prove to warn That he not busy bein' born
Is busy dyin'
Temptation's page flies out the door You follow, find yourself at war
Watch waterfalls of pity roar You feel to moan but unlike before
You discover that you'd just be one more person cryin'
So don't fear
When you hear
A foreign sound to your ear
It's all right, Ma
I'm only sighin'
Hey, Arnold, look at them two.
Pull alongside. We'll scare the hell out of 'em.
Want me to blow your brains out?
Why don't you get a haircut?
What happened?
Billy!
Oh, my God.
- I'm going for help. - I'm gonna get 'em.
We better go back.
I'm gonna get 'em.
We're ready now.
The river flows
It flows to the sea
Wherever that river goes That’s where I want to be
Flow, river, flow
Let your waters wash down
Take me from this road
To some other town
All he wanted was to be free
And that’s the way it turned out to be
Flow, river, flow
Let your waters wash down
Take me from this road
To some other town
Go, river, go
Past the shaded free
Flow, river, flow
Flow to the sea
Flow
To the sea