[singing]
♪
♪ Ooh yeah
[alcohol being poured]
♪
Oh shit. Hey man,
I gotta get to Brooklyn,
I gotta get to work,
open the bar,
I gotta work
on this audition
for the morning.
What're you
going in on?
Now is this scene
before or after
you saw your
own leg off?
I've seen slaves breaking
their backs in the fields.
Have you?
[indistinct chatter]
Pardon me, pardon me,
I'm very sorry. No, we
should head out. We
gotta be there at four.
That's enough, from both of you.
And you...wait. That's enough.
We need you
up there, kid.
I'll be right up.
Brother, prepping an audition
or doing an audition, or
resting from an audition.
You can never commit,
because you never know,
you might get a job, but
you never do get a job.
Sorry, but you don't.
♪
Okay, who needs what?
These three here,
we need two Ripostos
one Fellini.
I don't know what
he wants, and that
freak down there,
I'm not certain.
Oh shit, is that Raphael?
I was a gay on
the Woody Allen
movie you did.
I'm gonna be right
with you.
Just kidding.
I knew you had a small part
but you were great. Thought
you were gonna be huge!
What happened?
[indistinct yelling]
When I headed
for that door
I realized
if I went out,
I would never
come back.
I didn't want to
never come back
but I couldn't come
back out onto the stage, so
there wasn't anything left
so I went up the ladder.
[laughing and applause]
You're The King.
The King. You're
Joe Strummer.
- I'm Joe Strummer.
- You're a sonic producer.
I'm a sonic producer!
I think I liked it.
If you don't mind
I wanna sit for
the second scene.
Sure, no.
What you did,
really good.
Really good.
Very good, thanks.
I don't know what else
to tell you. You're in
an age void.
Would you like
a Peroni?
I want you to change
your attitude, chief.
I want you to ask
me again, and this
time, with a smile.
Go fuck yourself!
Get the fuck out!
[screams]
Yeah, we will get
the fuck out of here!
- Look at me, look at me.
- Dude I can't do this anymore.
I'm gonna fucking kill someone.
♪
- In an age void.
- What?
They don't know what
to do with me. That's
the problem.
Look, it's Lincoln Center.
It's a cultural superstore.
It's white boy business,
I mean, you getting that
part is a long shot,
come on!
Well what's the point
then, Raph?
Please, tell me,
I mean it's the same
five directors,
the same 10 writers,
the same 20 actors,
they just do everything!
It's not good for theaters,
it's fucking boring.
Look, it's a tight circle,
we're not part of it.
You know the days
of Joe Papp, off
the street, the living
theater, that's done!
Who's off the street?
I'm trained, well trained.
- I know you're trained.
- I went to conservatory!
Yeah but you didn't go
to Juilliard, and that's
what this is all about, right?
What big shows you were in,
who saw you do it, my dad
is Edward Albee, all that kind
of stuff.
- Edward Albee doesn't
have kids.
- I know.
- He's gay.
- Doesn't mean he
doesn't have kids.
- But he doesn't.
- [Kaplan] Hey, Dom!
Who's this, your pimp?
Hey, how you doing,
what a sight!
You look fantastic. Look who
it is, Kaplan!
Hey don't mind us.
We were running
a scene right now...
I can't believe I'm running
into you maniacs, you guys
have been on my mind all week!
- Was it in a naughty way?
- Take it easy.
It's always a little
naughty with you, Raphael.
Tell us the less naughty
parts for now.
All right. That was an amazing
night at your bar last month.
We've had so many amazing nights
at the bar with you, Kaplan.
No, we were talking movies
with your writer friend,
Jonathan.
- You had those leather
pants on!
- We love those pants.
Wasn't Jonathan talking about
doing some low budget Raymond
Chandler detective story thing?
- No.
- That was our idea.
Who was mentioning
the Sweet Smell of Success?
- "Match me, Sidney"
- Match me.
I love that movie.
What's Jonathan up to?
I love his show.
Can you get me in touch?
I promised my boss I'd
find something interesting
for him to produce
for under 300 grand,
he's looking to shuffle
some money around
on a tax credit thing.
I don't know what
Jonathan' up to, but
we wrote that script.
- It's written, it's done.
- What script?
- The Raymond Chandler thing.
- We're burning down
the cultural superstar rasta.
Wow, look at you guys,
that's great. Did you write
parts for yourselves?
- Of course.
- Yeah, we're the leads.
We play brothers.
Okay, well what's
it about?
Don't be shy, Dominic.
Tell Kaplan what it's about.
It's, uh, well,
basically, um...
- Well, we play brothers.
- Yeah, I got that.
[laughing]
And, you know, we own
a detective agency.
- And it's a noir.
- Absolutely.
Uh, you know,
basically...
Well, it's an elevated
genre film. At least
that's how aunt
Carrie described it.
- Aunt Carrie read it?
- Yeah, she loved it.
How the hell did
you get aunt Carrie
to read it?
- No offense.
- None taken.
- We know some people.
- Yeah, we're tapped in.
Well, what'd she say?
She said, er, what did
she say, Raph?
- Said it was raw.
- Yeah, oh yeah.
She said it was really
raw and original,
and that she'd love
to get her hands on it.
It's called
"The Blackmailers
Don't Shoot."
- Or maybe "The Black Mask."
- Yeah, I like that one.
What the fuck, is it low
budget? You guys think
you can make it for under
300 k?
- Oh, yeah.
- Super low. Really low.
- Less than that.
- This sounds perfect.
My boss is looking
for something new.
I get to produce
this project.
Show me the script,
let's do this.
No wait, hold on
a minute, you know...
We're doing rewrites,
we're swamped, you know,
we can't.
This money goes away in two
weeks, we don't have to jump
through any hoops with them.
- I just need to see the script.
- I'm gonna be honest with you.
Look I get you guys,
I always have.
I can give you ten days,
that's it. But we're meeting
with other writers, so get
it to me.
How you gonna get out
of this. We don't even
know aunt Carrie.
I auditioned for her once.
- You can't write a script
in ten days.
- Yes, but we can.
We, together.
Come on, we've been talking
about doing this for years.
I have an idea.
What do writers do?
They go to the country.
We'll go to the country.
To my sister's house.
We'll have it all to ourselves.
Peace, quiet,
no distractions...
Let's just get there,
get down, and do it.
♪
[engine spluttering]
[engine revs]
♪
[engine shuts off]
Photosynthesis baby.
Oh, I forgot how
peaceful it is in
the country.
Nature will flip
you, Dominic.
Flip you for real,
remember that.
Yeah!
[grunts] Police activity,
people. stay back.
- Dominic, grab the bags.
- Oh, yeah.
That's very cute.
Very cute.
[wind chimes ringing]
To Gigi's country manor.
- Starting tomorrow, I think
we should cleanse it out.
- No booze.
I saw this documentary
on Ingmar Bergman
- at the Film Forum.
- I love the Film Forum.
He said the demons
want you to stay in
bed with cold feet.
So the first thing he does
is he gets up in the morning
and he takes a walk.
And then he writes.
[laughs]
♪
You want some gross
character of a woman!
That means power makes you
more masculine, and masculine
means you're ugly.
Well shame on you,
you macho shithead!
All right, fuck this.
Eureka!
Yes, that's it!
It's a simple
missing persons case.
Gets more evolved
when we find the girl.
[groans]
- Recognize!
- It's a character piece,
- masked as a noir,
- wonderful.
Wonderful, wonderful!
Maybe a dubonnet with a twist.
It's a secret!
Corruption that echoes
the world in which they live.
Yes, uh,
dark shame.
[grunts]
It could be
a double cross.
Could be,
- Genius!
- Yeah!
♪
[rooster crows]
[birds chirping]
Maybe she joins a group, a cult, like the Source Family.
A cult could be fun.
It's a period piece,
but maybe we
make it a mash up.
Set in Los Angeles over
a 24 hour sequence.
Some dialog,
dancing but heavy,
like The Umbrellas
of Cherbourg.
- I love that movie.
- Okay, so, dancing...
[Raphael] Mm hm.
- In a noir.
- Yep.
That's good, right,
we haven't seen that!
That's good.
Okay, so, she--
Who's...who's that?
[operatic music on radio]
That's what I
wanna know.
[operatic music continues]
♪
- Hello.
- Hi.
How you doing?
- You must be Dominic.
- How do you know
who I am?
I've seen
pictures of you.
Er...Where?
In Gigi's store. I used
to work there, I'm Ava.
Oh, yeah. How is it
we've never met?
- I guess we've just never
seen each other.
- You don't look like an Ava.
- What does an Ava look like.
- You change your name? Let me
see your ID. Got your passport?
Some outfit you have on.
Is your name Lawrence
by any chance?
Of Arabia? Close,
Raphael, of Brooklyn.
You wanna borrow this?
I got this one in Marrakesh,
Okay, Ava, Ava,
here's the, um...
Raphael, Brooklyn and I,
we really need to be alone.
So, um...
What you doing here?
Planting flowers.
I'm doing Gigi a favor.
My friend Carl is going
to do a shoot here in
a couple of weeks.
Okay, Gigi, she didn't
tell me anything about this.
- Don't worry about it.
We're the king of this castle.
- Something wrong?
Here's the thing, Ava.
We're up here to write.
- We've been contracted
to write a screenplay.
- We have nine days to finish.
I'll be very quiet.
Like a mouse.
[whispers] Like a mouse.
I'm staying out
in the trailer.
Well, why you
doing that?
- Why not?
- Okay, see. I just wanna
set the right tone.
The tone is set.
[operatic music on radio]
♪
[whispers]
Now look.
That girl is very hot.
[both whispering]
- I can see that.
- Just stay calm.
I can't control
the bitches worldwide.
Yeah, okay, this...
This is gonna be a problem.
- It's probably Karl Lagerfeld.
- What?
[loudly] Why are
we whispering?
[continues whispering]
- What, what?
- Her friend who's gonna shoot
here in a couple of weeks.
- It's probably Karl Lagerfeld,
the famous designer.
- Yes, I know who he is, bitch.
What are you guys
whispering about?
[clears throat]
Ingmar Bergman.
[whispering]
I told you.
We don't trust something
about her, correct?
about anyone.
We're detectives.
Why hasn't she gone
to the police?
She wants to keep it
out of the paper.
Wants to use discretion
doesn't want anything
to go on record.
She's got an aversion
to celebrity culture.
Are you guys
going somewhere?
- Yeah.
- No.
Why?
You're sitting in your car.
I was hoping you could
give me a lift to the store.
- We can't.
- Absolutely. Why not?
Okay, I'm gonna walk then.
Do you guys need anything?
- No, no thank you. We're cool.
- Do you want some Red Bull?
- Are you kidding?
- For the writing.
No we're keeping it clean.
Okay.
[Ava] Bye.
[honks horn]
Ava, can you get me some
bittersweet chocolate,
some vanilla ice cream,
some cookies and maybe
some beef jerky.
- Don't go crazy. Just get
one or the other.
- Worry about yourself, damn!
[honks again] Ava!
Just make it vanilla
swiss almond!
- Okay.
- And some condoms.
[laughs]
- I think you should fuck her.
- I'm absolutely not going
to fuck her!
- It'll open you wide up.
- I'm here to write.
- I'm writing!
- You can do both.
- Are you drinking a Red Bull?
- It's Prosecco.
Mm, ugh.
That's Red Bull.
Why would you
drink that?
You wanna work
all night? You wanna
be a big time writer?
Try something before
you dismiss it!
Put down the hand sanitizer
and get a little messy.
Gonna feel like
a tarantula.
[sound of car crashing outside]
What the fuck was that?
♪
[sighs in exasperation]
Whoa! Gigi!
Oh, my God, what are you
doing here? Are you okay?
Are you all right?
Gigi, what're you...
Have you been drinking?
Have you...
You're wasted!
Gi--
[Gigi laughing] Raphael!
Raphael.
- Raphael.
- Gigi!
[Raphael screaming excitedly]
[both screaming excitedly]
[laughs]
What are you doing
for fun these days?
I don't know, stranger,
what have you been doing
for fun these days.
Think we owe
each other
about three
happy new years.
- She drove here drunk.
- Oh, give it a rest!
I didn't drive anywhere.
I stopped for a second
or something.
Can't you see she needs
taking care of, Dominic?
Aw you!
You are in tune.
You simply tune in.
You always have.
Gigi!
[shrieking in excitement]
[continues shrieking]
[Gigi] My little darling!
Bring 'em more water please.
The last thing I want...
Okay, wow.
[Raphael] Splish, splash,
I feel fantastic!
Dom, you wanna get in there
and make it a family affair?
[laughs]
I'm so happy we're all
here. It's wide open.
- You guys have known each
other a while, right?
- Yeah.
- Raphael was
her boyfriend, sort of.
- What do you mean,
sort of?
Whatever they were.
That was way back.
[Raphael] Hey!
Yes, it's true. Raph was
my boyfriend, sort of.
[Gigi chuckles]
- Speaking of, where's Wayne?
- Don't mention Wayne, no no,
don't mention Wayne.
Why not, why?
What happened now?
He has some nerve.
That's all I'll say.
Raph and I have a lotta work
to do tonight so we might have--
Not a bubble bath
without some bubbly.
Yes!
[laughs]
Please man.
[indistinct chatter]
Why are you people
ruining my life?
Because I love it when a man
brings me champagne!
The honey is flowing
in all directions!
[laughs raucously]
[birds chirping]
Yeah, get up.
Let's go.
We're leaving.
♪
- What are you doing?
- I'm leaving.
- Why?
- Why do you think?
♪
Dominic. Dominic!
- What?
- I was losing my mind!
You can't leave, I practically
crashed the car into the house
last night. I drove drunk.
I don't have time for this.
I don't have time.
Get off!
[grunts]
I don't wanna be
alone right now.
Well I do!
[grunts]
- G, stop it.
- Why can't you stay?
- Because, I need to focus!
- So focus!
It's a really big house.
[screams]
- Do you like that?
- I need you! I might
be at the end of a rope.
Fine, all right,
I'll stay!
Savage!
♪
[grunts]
- Gorilla.
- Pussy!
What's up with my brother,
what are you feeding him?
Roast turkey and Miles
Davis of course.
[chuckles]
Had a dream about
you last night, G.
That sounds
promising.
You were telling me
you wanted to sell
your shadow for 60
dollars.
- I could get more
than 60 bucks.
- I bet you could.
Hey would you mind
reading this with me?
I'm tired of my shadow
pinpointing exactly
where I am.
I'm not sure
that I follow.
I want to be rid of it.
It's not that simple, lady.
Neither am I.
There's no turning back,
you understand?
Someone else could find
a better use for it.
It got a little complicated...
[radio in the background]
Missed you.
[Dominic] Change of plans.
We're not leaving.
So, upstairs in five,
back to work.
Is this hot?
G, just so you know,
you fucked up my rib,
really bad.
It's killing me.
- Let's go. Back to work.
- So...
...you write and then
you dream, or you dream
and then you write?
- Which comes first?
- I dunno, that's
a good question.
Sometimes I think
the dream is writing me.
- So if we find her,
why don't we bring her back?
- I'm not sure, I'm not sure.
Because if we bring
her back,
the movie ends.
I'm not so sure
about that,
I'm not sure at all.
What's so special
about this cult?
Primary colors, Stanley
the dog, abandoned peers.
Keep that close,
abandoned peers.
Snails. A quote:
trans-cranial
magnetic stimulation.
Grapefruit the size
of cannonballs.
The realism of nature combined
with the serial-ism of nature,
aka, whimsy. Aha!
[Dominic] What?
Carlos Puyol beats
Real Madrid
with his head.
With his head!
Raph, Raph, Raph.
What? Okay, what
is all that? Where
you going with all this?
You see how quickly
young Ava dropped her robe?
You gotta love a girl
who can think on her
feet, huh?
If you're a man with sight,
you'll notice she had a little
fur down there.
I've been wondering for some
time now if the kids have been
bringing bush back.
Kojakhas been ruling
the area for a long time now.
Back in the day,
your sister
had a full on Joan Baez.
- Okay, stop, stop.
Please, stop!
- What? What?
These are my notes.
These are things
that can
spark my vision.
We have to stick with it
to get somewhere.
I need to circle the muse.
I need to let the character
emerge. I'm not a machine!
You need to circle.
You seem to circle
a lotta things.
Oh, I see what's
happening here.
I'm just saying man,
sometimes, you gotta push.
Man, you gotta jump!
[Raphael imitates Tarzan]
[Dominic] All right!
Okay! All right!
Just forget it, forget it!
Back to the story, okay?
Back to the story.
Just give me something
real man, something deep,
something truthful!
Oh, it rubs me the wrong way
when you say deep, and truth.
It just rubs me the wrong way!
The guy who wants success
in ten days. The guy who
wants everything now.
That guy's gonna talk to me
about truth, about death?
- You don't wanna get in there.
- Get in where, get in where?
You're just saying words,
I dunno what you're
talking about!
This is the omphalos
of the entire story.
- The omphalos?
- The navel, the central point?
Fuck you,
word of the day.
[Gigi and Raphael laughing]
[laughing continues]
[Dominic] You gotta be kidding.
Dark, Mediterranean man
sits at his computer,
a pensive look
on his face.
- Hi, Ava.
- The curious girl
enters the room.
Hey, look, Ava, you're a really
nice girl, but I thought you
were gonna be quiet as a mouse.
His brow tightens,
she offers him a drink.
This is for you.
[Gigi] No, I wasn't. I was
just waving to you and I was...
[Ava] Look at those two.
They can't resist.
- How's the writing?
- I'm stuck.
On what?
Um, in...
In the story, my
character's hired to
find this girl who's
wrapped up in a cult.
I find her, I don't know
what happens next.
She's in some kind
of trouble.
Well, I know all
about trouble.
- What do you mean?
Well, what kind of trouble
have you been wrapped up in?
It depends how
you define trouble.
Sometimes trouble
give you the answers.
Maybe your character
is conflicted.
This girl is drawn to you.
She's involved in something
that intrigues you.
Question is,
do you explore it?
Or maybe he's
falling for her.
Anyway, if you get stuck
again, give me a holler.
♪
So he buys me this
'66 Barracuda Fastback.
Pearl white, burgundy bucket
seats, I love it.
- And Wayne loves it.
- I love it.
For about a week. And then
the next week he's just
in his shell.
He's curled up, he won't get
out of bed, and he's angry.
So angry about everything!
Then suddenly decides he
wants to get rid of it.
- What!
- Not just the car.
He's suddenly obsessed
with the Ramapough Indians.
- To what end, I have no idea!
- Is that a new thing?
He's riding the Staten Island
ferry back and forth. He's not
going to Staten Island, he's
just riding the ferry.
Says he needs
to stay on the water.
I don't know what's
going on with him.
Maybe it's everything going on
in the world right now. Maybe
that's what's setting him off.
- Yeah.
- I dunno.
We were so good for so long.
- And now, we're not connected.
- Not working.
I feel like he's
bamboozling me,
unless maybe it's me.
- No it's not.
- No, my man is fucked up.
I'm sorry, G. I love you, but
he's got some serious issues.
He was in a war.
Then he was
fucking Team Six.
- What's Team Six?
- It means he was elite.
Okay, the best at
what he did.
Anything after that,
it has to feel like a
let down to some degree.
- She's no let down!
- Yeah man.
No, you know what I mean.
I don't mean that. It's just
that now he's a...
he's a glorified handyman.
Let's not glorify the fact
that Wayne is a product
of the military industrial
complex.
It's sad, but he
made choices.
What I know,
is Gigi here is a radiant
sunflower. And one who
appreciates the sun,
certainly loves
sunflowers.
[laughing]
You're in love with him.
It's really simple.
Battle of the sexes,
people. Men in the lead.
All right, let's do it.
Let's go. I'll play around.
- On the case.
- I'll play around, here.
[Dominic] Get this going.
- Billie Jean gonna go down.
- I remember how to do this.
Oh, yeah.
Dominic is on fire.
[Dominic] Winning does
make you feel good.
I haven't won in a while.
[Raphael] Wait a second.
Winning is all.
Chiang Kai-shek,
remember that.
This is it.
This is how
it should be.
Friendship is as important
as romantic love,
remember that.
The cards are life.
Minnesota Fats,
remember that.
[Ava singing]
It's all in the sauce.
Listen, Raph, here it is.
I've got pages man, exciting
stuff. This is what
happens, okay?
Our girl, she's running
from everything, you know?
Her family, society, the status
quo's, all getting ripped out.
She's found a new life with
this cult, and I'll tell you
this much. It is beautiful
and I am wide open to it.
- Now what do you think?
[yells]
- I think you're out.
I'm out.
[yelling]
I won.
[celebratory noises]
[indistinct chatter]
You're mine.
[laughs]
Hey, hey, watch out.
Okay, come on you two,
let's do it.
[indistinct chatter]
[laughing]
♪
[printer buzzing]
[Raphael] Don't be
a sap, Renee.
You dummy up
on me now, you're
looking at 99 years
in Cincy.
Where'd you stash
the dame?
I'm not telling you
where she is.
[seagulls chirping]
I don't see that you have
much of a choice, bucko.
You wouldn't understand.
Try me.
[boat's horn blaring]
She told me about
the light.
[laughing]
[continues laughing]
- I'm not talking
about a street lamp.
- Yeah.
A light? You getting
sucked into her cult.
I'll be lookin'
for you next.
- You may not find me.
- Wonderful, wonderful!
- Wonderful scenes you've
written. I love it
- It's good right?
I can't see him right now.
You gotta... You gotta stall
him. Make him go away.
Something! Okay?
Yo, dude! What's up, man?
Come down!
Yeah, I'll be right down.
[Devon] How you gonna act, man?
- I dunno.
- Oh, cool.
- What does Gigi want?
- She wants me to be cool.
[Devon]Cool, man,
so just stay here,
cool spirit.
Smoke this, dude.
Chill out, when you're done
you go inside. Cool?
[Wayne] Yeah, okay, you
want me to stay here?
[Devon] Yeah, stay here,
I gotta piss.
- Wait...
- Dude I gotta piss!
[wind chimes ringing]
[birds chirping]
Gigi!
Hey, killer.
Look who it is. Holy shit.
I didn't know you were going
to fucking be here. What're
you doing?
I'm up here with Dominic,
yeah, I'm writing with Dom.
- Work.
- Yeah, work.
- You still acting?
- Yeah, I still got the curse.
Well, you still look like
a movie star. You get
botox yet?
[laughs]
These are new.
Saw Dom on
Law and Order.
Got his ear cut off.
He was being such
a pussy about it.
You still working
at the bar?
Yeah, I'm still working
at the bar.
I gotta take care of some stuff
with G, so, um... maybe we
have a barbecue later.
Yeah?
She mentioned
you guys had
a little blow off.
She did?
You know,
just in passing.
Thought maybe you'd
wanna go get some flowers,
bring them up there,
Clark Gable style.
Oh, is that
what you think?
Well, all we have up
here is flowers.
I guess I'm
the flowers.
Yeah, I'm
just saying.
- She's still in bed.
- She's in bed?
You know that? You know
that she's in bed? How do
you know that she's in bed?
[chuckles nervously]
How do you know
she's still in bed?
[laughing]
You got a lotta
information.
Just up here riding with Dom,
you know? [nervous chuckle]
You said that.
[whistles]
- Runs good, don't it.
- [laughing] Yeah.
Hey, man, you haven't
changed a bit. Look out!
G. Hey, G.
[knocking on door]
G?
- Hey, man, nice haircut, dude.
Like the way you're wearing it.
- Thanks, man, thanks.
You know, what's going on?
I thought you were driving
to L.A?
Dude, so did I. We got
to Ohio and Wayne
pulled a 180.
- Wants to work it out with Gigi
- How long you gonna stay,
you think?
Dude, I dunno. Could be a while.
Hey can you do me a favor?
There's a black bag in there,
it's Wayne's. Can you grab it?
- Just in the back, dude.
- Yeah, no I got it.
- What is this?
- Oh, bro, that's my
head shot man.
- What do you
need a head shot for?
- Oh, it's for my show.
What show?
You didn't hear it, dude?
I got my own show.
Wayne's such a dick!
- I don't get it.
- Dude, I don't get
it either, bro.
I'm just teaching my class
at Point Pleasant one day,
surfing
It's like the best
day of my life
everyday.
Then getting changed
on the beach, right?
This guy comes up to me.
He's like "Hey, bro, I've been
watching you."
And I'm like "Hey, bro,
what the fuck, man?"
Because I thought he was
trying to pick me up, dude.
- Yeah.
Happens that this guy works
for Jerry Bruckenheimer dude.
- Jerry Bruckheimer?
- Jerry Bruck-heemer.
- Bruckheimer.
- Yeah, dude,
he did Armageddon.
He does The Amazing Race,
all these huge things!
- Jerr...Jerry Bruckheimer.
- Jerry Bruckheimer, yeah, dude!
He called me on my cellphone,
I pick up. I'm like "Hello"...
I'm like "Okay, dude, yeah,
go fuck yourself'", because I
thought it was Vasper calling.
Dude, it was really Jerry
Bruckheimer, he called
me up, he was like
"Hey, man, I want you
to come in, I want to
talk about your show."
So I go in and sit
down with him, dude.
You know what?
Great guy, man,
he's wearing
these tight jeans,
he's kinda staring.
He's got these beady
eyes, so I'm like
"Hey man", you know?
"Is everything cool here?"
and he's like "Yeah,
everything is cool here."
- So then, we start talking
and we just get each other dude.
- Yeah.
He's like my other brother
from another mother, dude.
We're just mano e mano,
really vibing out,
and then he turns to me
he's like "You're my guy."
- Guy for what?
- Dude, for my show I just
told you about!
It's a reality show about
my life, bro, I'm gonna teach
guest celebrities how to surf
and they're gonna compete.
Dude, it's like Dancing
With the Stars. I mean
meets The It Factor,
meets, like, American Idol,
meets, like, we're gonna party.
- Sick!
- How much is he paying
you for this?
Dude, can't tell ya.
Signed a confidentiality
agreement.
- [laughing]
- It's a lot of money, dude.
Hey, man, dude
hang on a sec, man.
My new agents are working out
the contract, fucking UTA.
- Ooda?
- Yeah, dude, United
Talent Agency.
- U-T-A?
- Yeah I call 'em "Uta"
to fuck with them.
UTA, man,
that's top ten.
- Hey man, what are you up to,
dude? What're you doing here?
- I'm just, you know man...
- I was, uh...
- Wayne said you were
on L.A Law.
You got your ear
cut off or something?
That was a while
ago, but, yeah.
That's great news,
that's awesome news.
Awesome. The door's that way.
Look at all the chimes, man!
Everywhere, just chimes.
Okay, man, I'll see
you inside.
[tires screeching]
G. G, wait, G!
God dammit!
- Gigi just pull out?
- She did.
- What she do that for?
Did she know I was here?
- I don't know.
- Come inside. Ah. Ow, Wayne!
- I'm here.
Aah, fuck.
- You all right?
- Yeah, I'm all right. Um...
I really don't know if she
knew you were here.
I'm sorry, man, I didn't mean
to do that. I was just...
- It's good, see, I'm cool.
- You okay?
I'm okay, yeah.
What about you?
You okay?
Yeah, man, I'm good,
man, I'm good.
- That's good.
- You know...
Gigi hasn't been picking up
my calls for a few days, so...
- But I'm good, you know.
- You guys gonna...
- have it out or something?
I mean...
- Absolutely not.
Negative.
- Because I'm up here--
- [whispers] Is she gonna break
up with me?
Wayne, I dunno what
she's gonna do. I
really don't know.
It's just, I'm up here,
I'm trying to work
Yeah, that's what
Raph said.
You guys are
working up here.
I didn't know you
were gonna be up here
you know, so it was a
little bit of a surprise.
- Well, I told G, you know.
- What are you guys doing
here, what's Raph doing here?
He's writing a script
with me. We're trying
to write a screenplay.
About what?
It's about some
fucked up, you know,
like some noir stuff. Some...
- missing people, and things--
- That's cool, man, I'm not
gonna get in the way.
I just wanted to see G man.
I don't know if she's been
picking up my calls...
But I'm here to make it cool,
you know. It's cool, I mean
is she cool? You think
she's cool?
- What do you think?
- You think she's
being uncool?
- I'm asking you a question.
Can you focus?
- Okay.
I'm saying that
I'm cool, and I'm
wondering if she's cool.
- Is she cool?
- She's gonna come back.
I'm just asking
if she's cool.
She's been normal.
Are you not hearing what
I'm saying? I'm just asking
is she cool.
I dunno, I mean,
I'm not sure what
we're talking about.
Don't worry
about it.
Where's my bag?
- Huh?
- Where's my bag?
I dunno... Maybe...
- Maybe that's it there.
- What's it doing over there?
- What's it doing over here?
- I have no idea.
[Wayne] Hey, man, I'm really
sorry about that. I didn't
mean to...You okay?
Yeah, I'm good.
All right, see you
later, Wayne.
♪
[Dominic] It's just we're
being pushed out!
- It's a reality surfer
show, so what?
- So what?
It starts with
a stupid
surfer show,
or Idol, Top Model,
then your Jennifer Hudson
winning a fucking oscar!
Do you wanna work?
- But you act like
you don't care!
- I don't care?
I don't know, just...
What are we missing?
What?
- Maybe, Devon...maybe
he just has 'it'.
- Definitely has 'Id'.
- So you agree, he has 'it'?
- He's a beach bum,
he's a pleasure seeker.
What does that have
to do with having 'it'?
Having 'it'?
- That's what the fuck
I'm talking about!
- Thought you meant 'Id'.
Do you think he has
that something special?
Jesus Christ, Raph.
I wouldn't go so far
as to say Endless Summer,
has 'it', whatever
that is exactly.
Maybe people are seeing
something in him, that they
just don't see in us, and that
something is 'it'.
- I don't know what
you're talking about.
- He's on TV, we're not!
He's got a big
agent, we don't.
I bet you, in a year,
he's doing a war film
with Ed Harris,
and you and I are still
shaking Cosmos in Brooklyn,
talking about Bertolt Brecht.
I'm not gonna change my
philosophy for living
because Devon got
a reality TV show.
[Dominic makes
frustrated noises]
Come on! Okay, so what
is this so called philosophy
for living, Raph?
Because the last I looked,
you were a 40 year old
bartender.
I don't give
a motherfuck
about Idol!
I don't give
a motherfuck
about Jennifer Hudson,
surfing, 'it',
or whatever
you're talking about!
Now I wanna end
this conversation.
Either you're doing
something wrong,
or you're doing everything
right. That could mean that
you just don't have 'it'.
If you have talent,
if you have real talent,
you don't question it,
and people that constantly
question it, are the mediocre
ones, and that's what you are.
Mediocre.
Is that how you
really feel about me?
I mean, is that
how you really feel?
- You're doing it right now!
- What? I'm doing what?
You're begging approval.
You have this pathetic need
for validation, look at you.
Even from me.
Even from me,
the 40 year
old bartender.
Well, at least I'm
putting myself
out there.
At least I'm going for
something. You know what,
that takes courage.
You're doing nothing!
You've become a novelty act,
and I'll tell you something,
you're kidding yourself
if you think my sister would
ever have a serious
relationship with you.
You're an entertainment.
No one we know takes
you seriously. No one.
You're a fucking joke.
[grunts]
[choking]
[gasping]
[continues breathing heavily]
♪
Should take a blowtorch
to this fucking place.
Dude, there's some chick
out here, bro, it's like
a mirage. She's so fucking
hot, dude.
- You know her?
- That's Ava. She used
to work for Gigi.
You're not gonna land her
the way you do those
L.A skanks.
Couple of tiki drinks
with some coke.
Dude, nobody drinks
tiki drinks.
[scoffing]
Do you think
I can fuck her, bro?
- See all this stuff out here?
See all this?
- Yeah.
- It's my stuff. Gigi put
all my stuff out here.
- Wanna bring it back in?
She thinks it's over,
she's wrong.
Well, do you think,
there's a chance
it might be?
Might be what?
- Over, dude.
- Come here.
- What?
- Come on, man. What did I
do, dude?
- Come here.
- What? What are
you doing?
- Nothing man.
- Nothing? What are
you doing? Hey.
- Hey.
- Why?
- What are you doing, man?
What are you doing, stop.
- What are you prepared to do?
- No, Wayne, don't get yourself
worked up.
- Is God big and white?
- Don't get yourself worked up.
- Do you believe in the Pope?
- Chill out, stay in the pocket.
I'm in the pocket.
You in the pocket?
You want the same shit to happen
that happened in the city? You
want that to happen here?
Do you?
Do you, man?
- Okay, okay.
- Okay.
- I'm glad you're here.
- Yeah, me too, man.
Hey, tell me
this. She 18?
[thunder rumbling]
[rain pattering]
- Hey.
- Hi.
What's happening?
- You look nice and comfy.
- I feel comfy.
- You know Wayne?
- I do.
I'm his brother, Devon.
- You're Ava.
- I am.
Hey.
Welcome to our illustrious
country home, Wayne's
brother, Devon.
[chuckles]
I surf.
Cool. Professionally?
Yeah, but that's not all I do.
I'm a philanthropist. Got my
own clothing line.
[Wayne] Devon, Devon!
I gotta get in the pocket man.
Gimme your car keys.
Oh, they're in the visor.
He's fine. So, like,
what do you do?
What are you
a professional at?
Wayne said you're
en entrepreneur?
Did I just see Wayne
drive down the road?
Yeah, he just took a drive
to get his head straight.
- Hi, Dev.
- Hey, G.
Just met Ava.
She's very pretty.
[Devon] You know...
Wayne really wants
to work it out with you.
- He's trying, you know,
he's really trying.
- He's crazy.
Izzy, I didn't get your
messages. The service
is in and out up here.
I had to go to the emergency
animal hospital, all night
with him.
- All night and--
- The service is bad.
If I knew...
Of course I would have called
you if I knew Benny hurt his
eye, I mean, what...
Just tell me what's...
What happened? Tell me
what happened? Is he okay?
I don't wanna talk to you until you're done writing this screenplay, or whatever it is.
Are you serious? Are you
seriously doing this to me
right now?
- Can you put Benny on speaker
phone? I wanna talk to him.
- No, no,, no.
That's ridiculous. I'm not
putting your dog on speaker
phone.
Izz? Izzy,
are you there?
- You okay?
- Jesus!
- Devon, you just scared
the shit out of me.
- All right, dude, chill out.
We're in a country.
It's illustrious here.
- How you doing, babe?
- What the hell?
- What happened to you?
- Me and your brother getting
down at the deeper truths.
How's it going
with you and Wayne?
- I haven't seen him yet.
- Yeah?
Well, if you need me,
you shoot up a flare, okay?
You still got it![laughing]
Look, I'm throwing a goddamn
party here tonight, lighting
this place up.
- You got an old suit in that
collection for me?
- A party? Yeah, sure.
- I have a suit, of course.
- Okay, good.
[sighs]
- You smell that
night jasmine, do you?
- Yeah, I smell it.
Be cool, Raph. Okay?
Just be cool.
Hold up, broheim.
What's up superstar, I heard
about your show. Congrats.
Thanks, friend.
Nice ride.
What do you want, Dev?
- Where you going?
- I'm going to the store.
Are you gonna
get something
for Gigi?
I'm gonna get something for
everybody you want me to
pick you up a nice Rose
there, Venice?
Your eyes, my eyes.
Your eyes, my eyes, bro.
I'm watching you. All day.
[starts engine]
Hi.
Hi, Devon.
♪
[phone vibrating]
- Hello?
- What're you doing?
[clearing throat]
I'm thinking.
What's all that noise?
- Cooking.
- Mm, what're you cooking?
Everything.
- Sauce?
-Yeah.
Polenta?
- Mm hm.
- Nice.
Lamb?
- What do you want?
- Come around the corner,
by the pond.
[man speaks on radio]
Hey, how's the sauce?
- Good. What're those?
- Would you like to have a seat?
Where'd you get 'em?
Did you take them?
Don't worry about
where I got 'em.
Just sit down, please?
I wanna talk.
- Did you take those chairs
from somebody's porch?
- I borrowed them.
Just bring 'em back, Jesus.
I thought we could sit down
and talk and be nice. What you
being so uptight about?
- You asked me to marry you!
- How is that a bad thing?
I don't see how this is a bad--
How and when you did
it is the bad thing.
And then you just took off?
That's a bad thing!
- I mean what were you thinking?
- I don't know.
My head was fucked up, okay,
but I've been thinking about
this for a long time.
- Jesus Christ, Wayne.
- Jesus Christ what? What do you
want from me? I love you.
I wanna marry you.
[scoffs]
Where are you going?
Don't you think I know
what's wrong with me?
Please, come back.
Please, come back here.
I got something for you. It's an
anger card, just for you to...
Sit down.
- Babe, sit down.
- Hey, I don't wanna sit.
"There's nothing really worth
getting angry about. What're
you angry about this time?"
- Are you asking me this?
I don't get it.
- No that's to myself.
I've been carrying that around
for a few weeks now. I write
stuff down that...
- Triggers?
- Yeah! More I write it out,
more I can start to see the...
- Patterns?
- Patterns.
And then I can start to figure
some of that shit out.
Okay. This is very
evolved for you.
Is this some
kind of trick?
What do you think?
No, it's not a trick.
Okay, it's a trick.
You're being tricked.
[reading]
"Lights."
Yeah? Okay, I know that one.
[reading]
"Bruni the super?"
- Yeah, that fucking guy.
- Well, I know. Me too,
for that matter.
Rain...
Rain gets you mad?
No, not the rain. Umbrellas.
People aren't careful you could
get your eye poked out.
They could easily lift it up,
or tilt it. They don't fucking
do that.
Get poked with
a fucking umbrella.
I don't see anything on here
about the Barracuda.
Are you listening, are you
really reading this? I'm
working my way up
to the big one.
Why would you wait till now
to give me this? After you've
caused all these problems...
[sighs]
You do something like this,
and then you propose, that's
reasonable.
But, not on the heels
of a huge argument.
And then you--
♪ Did you ever see a dream walking? ♪
♪ Well, I did
♪ Did you ever see a dream
talking? ♪
♪ Well, I did
♪ Did you ever see heaven
right in your arms? ♪
♪ Saying I love you, I do
Stop it!
Well the dream that
was walking, I --
[clears throat]
That was a little high.
- Stop. Stop!
[continues singing]
I love you--
I didn't want you
to leave. I never
want you to leave.
But you're always
fucking leaving.
I'm working on it, baby.
What do you think the card's
all about?
I don't wanna leave. I don't
want you to leave either.
Let's get married.
- Oh, my God!
- What, oh, my God?
I can't believe
you did it again!
- What am I doing?
- You're not getting it.
[cell phone chimes]
Dominic! Hey, it's me, Kaplan. Listen, bad news, the money went away for a little project.
So, I won't be
needing your script.
But hey, these things happen, you know, so, you gotta stick it out. The money was there,
now it's not. It's very
frustrating, but what can
you do?
Okay, take care, babe.
I gotta go. Bye.
Fuck.
♪
You were crying.
Why were you crying?
Because they sliced
my ear off, dude.
But that's not what would
happen. That's blunt trauma.
You would go into shock
or something.
You've never had your ear
cut off. How the fuck do
you know?
No, but I've been shot.
Got a piece of shrapnel
on my thigh,
seen my buddies get their
fingers blown off. That's not
what happens. You go into shock.
This guy, it was very close
to my head, man.
- It hit nerves and shit.
- What about playing like
an interior decorator?
Or maybe like
a hairdresser?
Stop it.
Come on, Wayne.
- Wanna do a shot?
- Yes.
[pours drinks]
[indistinct chatter]
Let's go out.
♪
Cheers, bro!
[together] Cheers!
I want you, right there.
You, give me...
[indistinct chatter]
♪
[Raphael] Check, check, check!
DJ Fluxus is gonna juxt your whole position, people.
Everyone back down on the dance floor.
Let's do it.
♪
Listen to me, you're
my everything. You're
all that means
anything to me.
You're my ice cream sundae,
you understand. You get me?
Why don't we go
to Niagara Falls and
have a honeymoon?
- Hey.
Hi! Those were seriously
some good dance moves.
- You too!
- Thanks.
Cold water doesn't bother
me. I can keep my hand
in there all night.
Maybe you should
do that.
Ah. No.
[whispers] Sorry.
Whoa, what the fuck?
You're not into this?
♪
- Come here.
- What? Oh.
♪
Everybody on the dance
floor. Everybody, come down.
We do the honeymoon now,
and if that goes well, we
can get married later.
- Know what I mean?
- I like that.
And if we get really crazy,
we could drive to Canada.
Keep on driving
to Montreal.
Is that something you wanna do?
Don't you wanna do that?
Do you wanna
do that?
What?
Look I'm sorry,
it's just, you know, I...
Have a girlfriend.
That's not what
I'm talking about.
♪
[applauding]
[Raphael] All right,
okay, okay, next.
You know what
the main ingredient
of the marshmallow is?
- Sugar!
- No.
- Horse?
- Cocaine?
- No. What?
- Horse...horse hoof.
- Hooves, hooves!
- Oh, my God.
[more applauding]
Politics. Politics
people, politics.
All right, last one.
Who's on the 500
dollar bill?
William McKinley.
- Bitches.
- Who the fuck knows that?
No one. That's the point.
William McKinley was a fucking
president of the United States
and no one knows who he is.
Everybody knows who Washington
is. Lincoln, fucking Ben
Franklin wasn't even president
and he's on some money.
But what the fuck did
William McKinley do?
- He got assassinated.
- He did get assassinated.
- Does anybody know?
- He was President?
- I've never even heard of him.
- They don't even make 500
dollar bills any more.
[Wayne] What's your point?
My point is, McKinley
never made his mark.
Oh.
- So you're a man on a mission.
- Yeah, I'm a man on a mission.
You know, I wanna
make a mark.
[Wayne] What then?
I don't know. That's it.
I get to live my life
doing what I love.
Again, and again and again,
and again.
And then we die,
and then it's over
and who cares?
We're all fucking
just bacteria, dude.
[laughing]
Why are you so caught
up in making a mark for?
I wake up every
morning with this...
pain in my stomach like I did
something wrong. I don't
wanna feel that shit any more.
Shame.
I don't know what
it is but I don't
wanna feel it.
Was talking about
self-loathing. Shame.
You gotta look
to it man.
[Wayne] Everything else
will come.
I don't know...
But you do know.
It's exactly that. The weight
of all this stuff gets lifted
when you embrace love.
All of this other
stuff is real.
But it's good to align
yourself with love.
It helps.
What's the point,
if we don't have love?
Yeah.
Why are we here?
Yeah, dude, love.
Riding high energy.
When I surf, I feel love.
A wave is like a wavelength
of energy. It's moving water
and I'm riding the surface.
Dude, think about that!
I'm in perfect harmony
with mother nature
when I'm surfing.
- That's amazing!
- That is amazing.
[excited squeal]
I love Gigi.
[Devon] I love Gigi too.
[laughing]
I love you.
[Wayne] Take it easy, tiger.
She loves you too.
I'm serious.
- I love you too.
[laughing]
- Here have a marshmallow.
[indistinct chatter]
Love is a giant pickle.
I'm in love with you.
These people, they don't know
what we're talking about.
I'm in love with you.
Wayne, I'm sorry you have
to hear this. I got nothing
against you.
There's something alive
here between Gigi and me.
Right.
Remember back in the day,
you wanted to drive down
the Pan-American highway
with me?
Remember that?
You wanted to drive
all the way down
there with me?
But I wasn't ready.
- These last few days
have been so--
- Let's hear him out.
Gigi, I can love you
like you never, ever,
ever...
Like earth, like magic.
Just meet me in my car
at 4:00 a.m..
You don't bring anything.
We gonna make that drive.
[fire crackling]
[rain pattering]
[thunder rumbling]
[footsteps approaching]
Hey, Dev, you're
in the wrong car.
[car door shuts]
Sorry.
Good night.
[coughing]
♪
[wind chimes ringing]
[door shuts]
What's up big boy?
[exhales slowly]
[chuckles]
You know, I like
what you guys have
written so far.
Yeah, what do you
like about it?
I like that they
fall in love.
Does she fall through
with the double cross?
Because that would be
heart breaking.
Would.
[wind chimes ringing]
[bottle cap rattles]
Think she goes through
with the double cross?
I absolutely do.
♪