Oopsy-daisy.
So, then Jeremy said–
Ugh!
Stacy?
Phineas and Ferb, that was important!
You guys are so gonna get it!!
Mom!
Elsewhere, in space.
I think the boys are shooting green lasers in the backyard.
Look!
Hey, Ferb.
I can totally see up your nose.
Hey, kids, how's the over-nighter going?
Great, Mom!
Everyone's helping, even Perry.
Candace, do you remember two weeks ago, when we wrote up this contract?
The Bust Accord?
And do you recall article twelve?
Yes.
"I will not attempt to bust my brothers more than once a day."
I remember.
But–
And what happened earlier today?
I tried to show you a giant ant farm.
Excellent, we have an understanding.
Now go to bed.
You can try again tomorrow.
Fine!
I'll just wait till tomorrow.
Wait a minute.
At midnight, it'll be tomorrow.
I can just stay up and bust them.
This sleepover is a good idea.
How are we all supposed to see through that puny telescope?
The telescope is just to find the probe we launched seventeen months ago.
Then we can tap into the signal from deep space.
And using Dad's old projection screen and some fiber optics to relay the images from the probe, we can view the galaxy in comfort from these lawn chairs.
Space probe?
Fiber optics?
Ooh, I can smell a bust comin' tonight.
These joysticks should control the space probe remotely.
Come on, already!
Let's start lookin' for stuff.
Buford, I've never seen you so enthusiastic.
I have my reasons.
Oh, here we go again.
He's going to tell the story of when he was abducted by aliens.
It wasn't an abduction, it was an encounter.
Encounter?
Yeah, I was walkin' out in the woods one night with my lucky tambourine.
(Song: Whalemingo)
? Float by ?
? Drift through my dreams! ?
? Whalemingo! ?
? (Whalemingo!) ?
? In the sky ?
? Like strawberry cream! ?
? Whalemingo! ?
? (Whalemingo!) ?
? You take a whale ?
? You drop the fla ?
? You keep the mingo, that's how I named it whalemingo! ?
? (Whalemingo!) ?
? If you see a big, pink whale ?
? With feathers and a beak and skinny little legs, then bingo ?
? That's a whalemingo! ?
? (Whalemingo!) ?
I think about you often, whalemingo.
And that's my story!
I didn't know you had a lucky tambourine.
This whole story is ridiculous.
No, it's not!
I have proof.
Ugh, here comes the picture.
See?
I named him Tristan.
That is just a flamingo.
Tristan is not a flamingo, he's from outer space, and he's a whalemingo.
But then he had to go home, and I never saw him again.
Hey, what are you doin' with your hands?
Mocking you.
All right.
I'd be angry, but I admire your honesty.
There you are, Agent P.
Sorry to call you in for a second time today but...
Oh, this?
It's–
It's just an exfoliating mask.
I have another ten minutes before I can peel it off, or I get zero of the benefits.
Agent P, we just got word that Doof may have fired tomorrow's inator, today.
This is a major breach in protocol.
So, give yourself a good slap in the face, and get over there.
? Perry! ?
Okay, gang, let's fire this thing up.
Zoom in on the swirly thing.
My gut tells me, that's where the whalemingos are.
Roger that.
Hey, it's our milkshake bar!
And business seems to be booming.
What about over to the left?
Okay.
Wow.
Yeah, wow.
It's a whole planet of...
...whalemingos.
I do not believe it.
Buford was right.
They're all so beautiful.
Tristan.
? Volgen nu! ?
(Song: Double Dutch)
? One dutch, two dutch ?
? Queens of the double dutch ?
? We skip better than you by that much ?
? Watch our feet, our moves are sweet ?
? Our double dutchin' won't be beat... ?
Perry the Platypus?
How did you get stuck in my double dutch machine?
That's not even a trap.
Anyway, what are you doing here?
Oh, that.
T-The beam that I shot through my roof?
Well, that was just an accidental misfire from my Sphere-attract-inator.
Luckily it was pointed up, so it didn't hit anything.
Anyway, I started thinking and realized the true measure of a man is having a world famous roadside attraction.
But which one to choose?
Which one would be the most spectacular?
Then it hit me, nothing brings them in like a big ball of twine.
So that's why I built the Sphere-Attract-inator.
To steal the world's largest ball of twine!
Then all I need is some sort of road to put it beside.
Right?
I gotta admit Buford, I had my doubts, but whalemingos are truly amazing.
Told ya.
Hey!
Why's everything all fuzzy?
I'm not sure.
Let me back it up and we'll take a look.
It looks like the planet's growing.
Planets do that, right?
It is not growing, it is getting closer!
This sounds serious.
Ah!
This is catastrophic!
Should we not do something?
Should no one inform the populous of the impending impact?
Calm down, Baljeet.
I'm sure the government scientists are already doing something.
Duck and cover!
My watermelon!
Based on my calculations, the planet will be here by midnight!
That's great news!
Our planets are going to collide!
You do know what that means?
Sure, it's like when you have two sets of keys.
And you keep one in the car.
No, it means...
NO!
It means all life is going to be wiped out on both planets!
Guys, we've gotta save Tristan!
Anything else, Buford?
And the Earth.
Oh, Perry the Platypus, what do you say we open up the roof and activate the Sphere-Attract-inator?
Then I can get a good night's rest before all the crowds arrive to see the world's biggest ball of–
? Nu! ?
? One dutch, two dutch ?
? Queens of the double dutch ?
? We skip better than you by that much ?
? Watch our feet, our moves are sweet ?
? Our double dutchin' won't be beat ?
? Touwtje springen ?
? Fast feud ?
? Touwtje ?
What are we gonna do?
We could use electro magnets, if only we knew the planet's molecular density.
I got a pail of water and a nest to make Tristan comfortable.
I figure I can keep him in my garage 'till spring.
Spring.
Spring!
That's it.
Guys, I know what we're gonna do tonight!
? One dutch, two dutch ?
? Queens of the double dutch ?
Oh, you sassy.
? We ski– ?
I knew they'd practically bust themselves, by just waited long enough.
You guys are so busted, in like... nine minutes.
Oh, hey Candace, glad you're still up.
You'll get to see the cool planet coming directly at us.
But don't worry, we're building a giant spring to bounce it back into space where it came from.
A spring?
That's not very scientific.
But it is still bustable.
Here comes the planet now.
I can't wait 'till they get here.
Tristan!
Finally!
It's tomorrow!
Mom! Mom!
What are you guys doing?
Oh, hi, honey.
We were just listening to some records. It's what we used to use for music when we were kids.
Candace, I thought we had an understanding.
Yeah, it's midnight.
Tomorrow.
Don't worry, it'll be all right.
The world's largest ball of twine is on its way!
Y-You'd better stand back, i-it's supposed to be huge! It's supposed–
What?
That's it?
Goodbye, Tristan!
Remember me!
I got a twine ball bigger than this in my junk drawer.
Help me, Perry the Platypus!
I'm slipping!
Oh, thank you, Perry the Pla–
? Nu! ?
I mean, curse you, Perry the Platypus!!!
? One dutch, two dutch ?
? Queens of the double dutch ?
? We skip better than you by– ?
Hurry, let's go!
Let's go!
Clearly we need a thirteenth amendment to The Bust Accord.
Mom?!
You kids okay out here?
Yeah, we're great!
We saw a giant planet filled with whalemingos!
Whalemingos, huh?
Why don't you all come on in for midnight snack?
Wash your hands.
Especially you, Buford.
Hey, sleepyhead, do you want a snack too?