What are you doing here?
Who has touched you?
My Priest!
Pharoah's bodyguards
You must go! Save yourself!
-No.
-Only you can resurrect me!
I won't leave you!
Get away from me!
You shall live again!
I will resurrect you!
My body is no longer his temple!
HAMUNAPTRA - 1923
The Creature remains undiscovered.
And what of this one?
-Should we kill him?
-No.
The desert will kill him.
CAIRO, EGYPT  - 3 YEARS LATER
GIZA PORT - CAIRO
Come with me my Princess Anck-su-namum.
The language of the slaves...
...I may have use for you.
And the rewards...
...will be great.
Where are the other sacred jars...
FORT BRYDON - CAIRO
You saved me from the undead.
I thank you.
Kill them all!
Kill them ... and wake the others.
With your death,
Anck-su-namun shall live!
And I shall be invincible!
The Book of Amun-Ra.
Destroy him!
I command you to destroy him!
Give me that book!
Now you die!
Now it's your turn.