Yeah, he treats me like that.
You really don’t want to go together
The subway is very fast.
I’ll take the subway
You must be tired too. Go on now
Oh yes
It’s my mother’s birthday next
week. Please pass this on to her for me
Why don’t you give it to her yourself?
Go on now, quickly
7pm at Susi Hotel. Come
over if you change your mind
Go on
Let’s go
Ok, see you
Looks like it’s going to
rain soon. Better get going
Ok
Looks like you’ve
become closer with Min-ho
Huh?
How fortunate. The two of
you are getting along better
All right. Why don’t I say it first
About yesterday, it’s ok with me
Anybody, when stuck with a man…
…in a house overnight and
not in her usual frame of mind
That is my slippage
Soo-hee
In that kind of a situation, it
is still best to not say anything
I’m sorry. It’s a mistake.
It won’t happen again
Other than these there’s
really nothing else to say
Just take it as an emotion
of the fleeting moment
What else can we do?
Things are already like that
Let’s not tell Ji-ahn about this
Sometimes being too honest can be
hurtful. He doesn’t need to know about this
What are your thoughts?
You’re not the only one
feeling awkward. I am too
Rascal. If I weren’t there then,
you would have been dead, rascal!
How frightened you were
when you saw those gangsters
Frightened? Who was frightened?
It was you who was frightened
Me? “You said me? Brother…we are…”
You were frightened first…who was that?
You saw?
Weren’t you like that?
So sorry. So sorry
Why are they blocking others’ path?
Kim Min-ho. It was your fault
Sorry. Please hold on for a while. Sorry
An apology would have sufficed. Why
did you buy the toothpicks as well?
Just leave them around. Leave
them around. I’ll use them anyway
I can’t even pass him
a word of my pining
The years have pass, but no matter
how I try, I simply cannot forget
Holding the liquor glass,
I dedicate this song to love
Men, men, I hate the
tears I leave for the men
What is this?! In the middle of
the night! This is really too much
Hello? Hello!
Open the door now! This is too much!
Mi-ri, what’s going on?
Are you deaf? Can’t you hear?
I want to leave with you, yet I cannot
No matter how long it takes,
I will find you, right?
Over the mountains, pass the ocean
It’s the middle of the night! Why is
she not sleeping? What is this? Really!
Why is she not coming out?
What is she trying to do?
Oh…it stopped. She’s
not singing anymore
It’s quiet now. Go away
I can’t believe this!
Is this woman crazy?
I can’t believe this! This is really!
She started singing at 4am.
At first I thought it would stop soon
But she continued on for two
hours plus. She wouldn't stop!
After the entire building was at her
doorsteps, her voice finally became tired
There were no songs she didn’t know
Fast songs; dance numbers; pop songs
She’s driving everybody crazy.
You heard what she said just now
“It’s quiet now. Go away”.
A complete scoundrel. Scoundrel!
All my life I’ve seen
all kinds of crazy women
Hey, your house is just ahead.
Why are you showering here instead?
There’s no warm water at my place
This belongs to the uncle.
Why are you using it?
Can’t I even borrow it?
No
Want some coffee?
Nope
Right, how was the trip to Jeju island
with Soo-hee? I haven’t asked yet.
Was it good?
Not good?
It wasn’t much?
You’re just going to give me
all these vague answers huh?
Do you think I don’t know you?
Didn’t you fall for her the first
time you laid eyes on Soo-hee?
Dare you deny it? Why is your
drawer full of her photos?
I peeped. You can report
me to the police if you want
Your heart will collapse if
you keep cooping it all up
That’s my business
That’s my friend’s business
If you’re miserable,
I will be miserable too
When my father was cleaning up,
when he was knocked down by the truck
I helped you, so you’re very grateful
You said you liked Ho-chul,
and you want to break up with me
You didn’t two-time me, but told me
honestly. I’m very grateful for that
I said to continue as friends
You agreed. I’m also very grateful
About Soo-hee, you knew but didn’t
say a thing. I’m also very grateful
So, help me one more time, Mi-ri
Just ignore me now
The coffee is really good. Have a cup?
Ok. Oh yes. Can I borrow your car today?
For what?
Don’t ask? Ok, got it
Who’s that? Who’s there?
Tell me which is a good
restaurant around here
Not operating? Anybody around?
This is really good.
Do you do delivery?
I said, do you do delivery?
[No]
You can’t talk?
Can you hear?
Then how do you know what I’m saying?
Oh, you read people’s lips
You’ve dyed them with peach water
How pretty
Ah. You store the peaches in the
freezer so you can dye even in winter
I didn’t know
My mother loved peach water too
Granny
This is really infuriating
Granny, we’re hungry
The two over there. What’re your names?
Neighbours should
know each others’ names
I’m Kim Min-ho.
She’s Choi Mi-ri
Hey, who allowed you to tell
my name to strangers, now?
Are the two of you friends?
I don’t feel like talking to you
Come over to my place tonight for a
house-warming party! Come, both of you
I’m preparing to order Chinese food
“Miracle” is the most
well-known in Korea
They do it the authentic way. The best
Auntie
I prefer “sister” better
Forget it.
You have such an outstanding professor
as a husband and you have your children
Just ask your family over to eat instead
Also, please. I really don’t
want to talk to you, Auntie.
So please don’t talk to me
You talk so much. Just
say you don’t want to come
Completely defeated by her
Agree
Continue your surgical studies
I can’t
You’ve got such a good
mind, why can’t you continue?
I’ll pay for everything
Rascal. I was so happy when he
said he wants to become a doctor
Behind my back, specialise
in animal nerves. Crazy
One didn’t complete his high school.
One went to a third-grade university
The other becomes a useless doctor
Only dad thinks that animal nerves
study is useless. Others don’t think so
Are you looking down on me now?
Ji-ahn, the food here
is pretty good. Have more
Little rascal
Uncle
So-hee’s handphone may be out of
battery. I called but she won’t pick up
Can you go over to Soo-hee’s
place and have a look?
I can’t because I can’t
leave uncle here alone
I can’t go over now
Please. We agreed to
meet at 9pm. Please go now
All right. I’ll go. Hanging up
Was it me being stubborn
today again, losing my temper?
I especially hated it when my
father flared at the dining table
But I’m completely like him now
I’m getting old. I should
control my temper a little
Hello
When did you start following?
You got me
From the hotel?
Let me have a look at you
Pull over
Nope. I got caught. Going
off. It’s no fun anymore
The brooch. It’s very pretty
Haven’t I got the eyes?
Let me have a look at you
Let’s have another surprise
meeting like that next month
Hanging up
Why are you here?
Didn’t you arrange to meet Ji-ahn at the café?
Why are you here instead of waiting there?
It’s past the agreed time.
I thought he’s not turning up
Why didn’t you pick up your calls?
I don’t know. It got shut off on its own
Ji-ahn was worrying for nothing.
You’re having fun on your own here
My job is done. I’m off
I have to go over to Mi-ri’s place
Mi-ri’s drawing is done.
I have to show it to her
Follow me. My car is at the parking lot
Gone anywhere?
I went to see my mum
Your mum?
Meet?
I heard from Ji-ahn you
don’t meet each other
Loud-mouth
It’s hot in the car
Soo-hee! It’s so beautiful!
This drawing is so beautiful
Draw for our café customers too!
If you do, it’ll definitely
draw a lot of customers there!
I’m not a professional at sketching
What professional. As long as
you get the drawing out it’ll do
Do it!
I’ll pay you. I’ll pay you
I’ll consider
It’s a deal
Uncle! This is me!
What?
I said it’s me in the drawing
What did she say?
Really! Is this woman crazy? What is
she doing in the middle of the night?
Having a birthday party I suppose
I really can’t take it anymore
Don’t interfere
What don’t interfere?
Weren’t you the one who asked the woman
to call her family over and have fun?
So people are having fun now.
Why are you looking for trouble?
I asked them to have fun. Who
asked them to make so much noise?
You’re even louder now, damn it!
Why are you always doing as you please?
Today as well. If you’ve invited
your friend, why did you ask me over?
Are you that unwilling
to meet my friends?
Yes. Unwilling
Am I dating a shadow?
Can’t I show my lover off to
my friends, is that so wrong?
Is it me who is
unwilling now, you rascal?
Then go
Do you think I won’t
go if you ask me to?
Hyung! Hyung!
You’re really great
Am I the one with a weird
temper? It’s him who is weird
Until now. Even till now…
Mi-ri, go get uncle back
Then apologise. Just say you’re sorry you asked
your friends over without informing him. Sorry
Why should I apologise?
What did I do wrong?
What? You’re leaving too?
Give uncle a call and
ask him to come back.
I’m off
Really. I’m going crazy
Hello! Hello!
Why, the door is opened.
“Have more. Congratulations! Thank you!”
What? There are so many voices
in there. Why are there no shoes?
“So happy you made it!
Is work going well?”
Hello?
“Come, let’s make a toast”
“Happy birthday to you, happy birthday to you,
we love our birthday star, happy birthday to you!”
“Congratulations, congratulations!”
“Congratulations!”
“Thank you”
“A toast to health!”
“Let’s sing a song”
I’m dying of hunger. Hurry up
So. What about last night?
What about what? I went
out without saying anything
So that auntie doesn’t even
know you were in the house?
No, I said goodbye when I left
Be careful. If that auntie sues you for
trespassing, you would have nothing to say
Trespassing? Go ahead. And I’ll
sue her for disturbing the peace
Hello!
Going for breakfast?
Yeah
Sorry I disturbed you last night
Sometimes life will
have moments like that
Say something
Sorry. We had a small gathering last night. Because
it was quite noisy, so we felt a little disturbed
That’s why Mi-ri…
It’s not Mi-ri’s
fault. The fault is mine
Will you accept my apology?
Certainly
Then as an acceptance of my apology, come to
my place tonight for a red wine party, will you?
Party?
We’ll be very grateful if
you would take us in as guests
Thank you. I really want to make some friends, so I’m
really honoured that you’re accepting my invitation
Then, I’ll see you tonight!
Hey! I don’t want to talk to
that woman, don’t want to go!
Come on. We’re all neighbours. It’ll be awkward
when you meet. And she goes to the café so often
I don’t want to. I don’t want to!
Come along
I can’t get along with that woman
Let’s go eat
Sorry. I also need to use money urgently
Last year as well. There were some
uncollected rent too, as you know
Yes. I’ll try my best
Ok, I’ll trouble you to, then
Delicious food prepared by granny!
Soo-hee…
Yesterday, I…
…You were so busy and I
still asked you to come over
And I didn’t discuss with you before
asking uncle to come over. And then…
So both uncle and your moods were ruined
And also the neighbour auntie
That’ll do
I still prefer you thick-skinned.
This is so unfamiliar
You just have to put it that way?
Like it’s really your bad luck
Mi-ri, can you lend me
some money? 5 million won
Do I have to supply a reason?
With our kind of relationship, it will
be a big deal if you still need to do that
You cannot do that
Why not? I don’t have a need
to go through treatment anymore
I’ll leave it to you
to convince my husband
In other words, to write a letter of proof
saying I have no need for further treatments
Then I’ll be able to go home.
So please write the letter
Stubbornness is your strength, isn’t it?
The same goes for you, I think
Recorded, but say you didn’t do
recording. Wasn’t that you, doctor?
I recorded?
Denying?
To believe all that you understand as the
only truth, that is also a kind of illness
Let’s talk about Oh Young-sook’s mother
Don’t we have to treat my illness?
Are you avoiding the
subject of your mother?
Yes
Also, it’s really tiring. There’s no need
to walk all the way to my stall to buy stuff
For a change, just buy
somewhere near your place
Did I give you a mission, or…
I don’t wish to see
you. This one is free
Granny, go on a date with me today
The napkin beside you…
…arrange it this way
Well done
Then, hold the spoon, that is
placed outside, like what I’m doing
Dip into the soup from outside to inside
Not used to it? Then just
drink in any way as you please
After you have cut your meat
Pick it up firmly with your fork
And eat it with the sauce, like this
This is only me. You
don’t have to follow me
Let’s measure our hands
Put your hand with mine for a while
Such big hands
Hands which have done so
much work, beautiful hands
My short and small hand, ugly hand
Are you curious about
what kind of a person I am?
I am a bad woman
I’m sorry. Please do not move
Why haven’t you been
coming often lately?
I’m a little busy at work
But you should still try to
come a little. Kinda miss you
Really?
If you’re so nervous, it will
be difficult for me to manage
I’m off
Is business good today?
What?
We’re receiving very good customer feedbacks.
Soo-hee earns money, I get more business
You get to see the Soo-hee you miss so much.
Isn’t this killing three birds with one stone?
Today after you’re done with this
customer, could you make some time tonight?
Why?
I’m forced to go to a place which I’m
reluctant to go to. Let’s go together
New-Comer Cultural Nomination Prize
Branded University
New York University.
This is so disheartening
Come get it!
I don’t quite understand auntie
You’ve gotten many great awards
Oh yes. Soo-hee is also
in the arts profession
They’re all fake. All the graduation
certificates and trophies over there are all fake
I didn’t learn anything.
Just a child with parents
Wanted to marry a well-educated,
kind and good-looking man
I didn’t have a choice
My career was developing
smoothly and I had some money
The man I love is too
good, and I am too shabby
So I lied to my husband
Everything was going quite well,
but I got found out recently
The price is, I’m now
separated from my husband
Under such circumstances, what
do you think we should say?
Do you have children?
They didn’t know, but recently my
husband told them everything in detail
So now, I’m not on speaking terms
with my children either
All of you have this “I don’t know
what to do” expression on your faces
Be more casual. Leave if you want to
After this incident, during this period
of time, close neighbours, friends…
…parents of my children’s
classmates, they have all abandoned me
After I got abandoned, I
grew stronger during then
The door is opened. Don’t worry
about me. Leave if you want to
Sister, do you think
everybody is like that?
Are we children? Leaving
because of something so small?
Drink up
Cheers!
I’ll pour you another drink
Come! Let us raise our glasses. Cheers!
Bottoms up!
Don’t talk so much. Come on. Bottoms up!
Soo-hee, so sorry. It’s so late
and I’m asking you to go home
If it’s normally, I would
have asked that rascal to leave
Today because…there was the
thing yesterday. So sorry
It’s ok, no problem
Min-ho, see
Soo-hee back home
Otherwise, let her
sleep over at your place
Shut up and close the door
Go on
Ok, keep in contact
I’m going
Ok
About that issue, I’ll settle it
You keep a close eye on
them. Don’t lose track of them
That’s it. And yes
Ask Muda to brush his teeth. That smell in his
mouth, it’s impossible to have a dialogue with him
Ok, watch the door. Don’t
tell them I’ve come here
Why would gangsters need to
watch the door? It’s no big deal
Ok, that’s it. Hanging up
[The season is changing. Watch your health.
Drink more tea or water. Jeju Island]
What is he looking at? Smiling like that
You have a woman?
You have a family?
Mother, elder sister, younger sister?
That’s enough
Exactly how old are you?
Born in year 1960, right?
Where is your hometown?
Kang Ho-chul, is that your real name?
Angry and you’re leaving.
You’ve got such a bad temper
Get angry easily. Give cold shoulders at
the drop of a hat. Leaving without a word
Are you all done now?
I’ve been dating you for three years.
What do we know about each other?
Is this love? When you’re in the mood,
you drop by. Leave some cash behind
Who do you have in your family? Where
have you lived before? Who do you know?
Do you have any friends? I
know nothing about you, uncle
You refuse to meet my father,
mother, brother and friends
And you refuse to let me tell people
about the places we have been to
When I’m tired you won’t let me complain,
and leave me to handle it all by myself
I want a shoulder to lean on too
You’ve got it wrong
Life is like that. Who do
you think you want to lean on?
If you want to lean, lean against a wall. Don’t
even think of leaning on somebody’s shoulders
Just because you’re a woman you’re privileged,
leaning onto men as and when you want to?
Men are leading a
tiring life too, rascal
If uncle is tired, you
can lean upon my shoulders
You complain of being tired even when I lean my
head over when we’re sleeping! Talk about leaning
Don’t think you’re so smart. Don’t just say pretty
words. Lead your life well, and I lead my life well
What a joke
I’m asking you again.
Do you have a woman?
I have plenty! Will that do?
Ji-sook, looks like I
have to go look for you
[Little nothing (Mi-ri)]
Speak
Speak up. If you’re calling why
aren’t you talking? I’m hanging up
It’s little nothing
I know it’s little nothing
Sorry we quarreled. Come back
Coming back?
I’ll be back after I get you your
favourite fried sticky cake at Sindangdong
So adorable. I just wanted to have some fun.
Now I’m really starting to like her. What to do?
This will not do
Stop looking at me like that, granny.
I know I cannot go on like this
Soo-hee is
Ji-ahn’s girlfriend
And it’s not like Soo-hee likes me
As long as I don’t say
anything, everything is aye ok.
Granny should know
I’ve got super endurance power. I should
be able to endure it this time too, right?
Say something
[Let’s eat]
All right, granny. Let’s eat
And yes. I need to see Ji-ahn
Then I’ll be able to catch my heart
which has gone to Soo-hee, right?
[But how did he start lying?]
Once I’m about to forget it appears. Once
I’m about to forget it appears. What is it?
Children are really so gullible
I deliberately turned the volume up loud
And I even left the door open for
her…But they all, all didn’t know
And it was last night. I think
my judgment was very accurate
Mi-ri said that Soo-hee is also in the arts
profession, so let’s start the truth rolling here
Or else I have to play all by my
lonely self again. This idea popped up
So I told them. It’s all
fake. Told them all the truth
Interesting, huh?
If there’s no interesting elements,
I think I would have died laughing
Really, the feeling of
being honest is the best
They didn’t think my real
identity would be like that as well
What I finally understood
yesterday is this:
There’s really nothing other than
honesty that can move people’s hearts
Miss Oh Young-sook
Yes?
It may be a little abrupt to say this
Miss Oh Young-sook is somebody who doesn’t
know the true meaning of being honest
You know how to make use of
other people. And you're very good at it
Time’s up. Go on
Woah! Not bad!
Is this your seat?
Come back to the company
I don’t want to. Sitting in front of the
desk, just moving my mouth. That doesn’t suit me
I’m making a move first.
Shall we go together?
All right, you stay here a bit
longer on your own. See you later
My impressions of Ji-ahn’s parents are very good
Want to grow old just like that
Stop!
Let go!
Dad don’t beg him! Dad don’t beg him!
We’re not in the wrong! Don’t beg him!
Dad
[It’s enough that I saw you.
I’m making a move first, friend]
You’ve had a hard
time! See you tomorrow!
Ok, you’ve had a hard time
I’m going
You’re carrying so much stuff
I bought a lot of
sketch books. I’m going
Soo-hee!
Will you see Soo-hee back in my
car? She’s carrying too much stuff
I don’t want to. Here you go
Listen to me
Said I don’t want to
Don’t know my temper? Don’t
want to live past tonight?
Mi-ri wants me to see you home. Get in!
No need
I won’t leave like that. Get in
Look after your stuff well
Kim Min-ho
What are you?
What does that mean?
At Jeju Island, why
did you do that to me?
This became our secret,
it’s not what I want too
I’m curious. Why did you…
Do that?
Yes
Think of it whichever way that
will make you more comfortable
Lunatic? Lecher?
Whichever way you prefer.
One of the two. It’s up to you
It’s none of my concern
which one you choose
What happened at Jeju
You can pretend nothing
has ever happened
I thought I can pretend it all
never happened before as well
Kim Min-ho
It seems like things are not that way
I’ve fallen. What should I do?
[Preview]
I have nothing to say. No, I have
a lot to say, but I can’t say them
*Translator: Rayndrop
If we leave it like this for a month,
Soo-hee and I will naturally become friends
*Timer: ltrang
Right, Granny
I can endure it
Did you quarrel with Min-ho?
It’s nothing
Something happened the last time
you went to Jeju Island, right?
*Editor/QC: Pinklily
Min-ho, I’m planning
to propose to Soo-hee
*Coordinator: Mily2
Maybe I’m becoming old. I’m
afraid of beating people up
Nobody understands me. I’ve
been wronged. I’ve been wronged