Although I'm really gratefully, I'll act as if I didn't hear this.
Alright, I won't request much of Manager Ryu.
Where exactly will Saelim Contruction's next project be located?
You will only need to tell me this, the construction site.
I won't know untill the public annoucements are made.
Why are you like this?
We have lots of fundings on our side.
If you can give us the information, then Manager Ryu..
Saelim will be finished if I were to say anything.
Then of course, I'll be finished as well.
I won't do such a dangerous thing.
Then..
That person is very unyielding..
Manager Ryu has met Jung Do-young.
For how long?
I got it.
Be careful, don't let Manager Ryu discover you.
I'm sorry, have you waited long?
Just a while..
Why were you late?
I met Jung Do-young.
Jung Do-young? Why?
What else can someone like him want?
There's no need to think too much about such things.
Episode 8
Min-ho, go meet with your mom for a while.
I don't want.
Let's leave after I take a look at her.
If my mom knew that I followed her to the Gallery to have a look at her..
she will be looking out the next time she comes to the Gallery..
to see if I am around or not.
She will be disappointed if I'm not around.
Let's go.
She looks pitiful from her back-view, doesn't she?
It'll be better if I let her go, right?
Looks like I'll have to divorce Min-ho's mom.
What do you think?
Things can only go this way.
Hide up well, your hair can be seen .....
I found you...
Oh my, Mom is found.
Mi-ja..
You are so cute.
Our Mi-ja, how did you find mom?
You are really smart.
So cute.
Mom, you must live together with Mi-ja forever.
If mom were to go anywhere, don't ever leave Mi-ja behind.
You must bring me along with you.
Ok, I know.
Oh, cute Mi-ja..
Why can't I even contact her?
Is it that Ji-soo, who lives in Jeju Do?
Boss, you don't have to say anything if you don't feel like it.
I'm really curious about the relationship between Boss and that person in Jeju Do.
You rarely meet and you also made a marriage registration.
Boss said that a gangster have to live on his own.
You will be soft hearted once you have a woman, and that's unacceptable.
Didn't you often say these things?
That's right.
But what can I do when I did something that I have to be responsible for?
That night when I slept with her.
An accident occured and her legs were crippled.
I must really be a lunatic.
She came to find me because she was genuinely in love with me.
But I treated it as a game and slept with her for a night.
So how would she feel when she was returning home?
At the cross road..
This is all my fault and I have to be responsible.
She's a younger sister that I know from the orphanage.
I should have sent her away when she started to become attached to me.
That woman, doesn't she have any family?
If she did, would she have been in the orphanage?
Shin-ji..
Yes, Boss..
Do you know Ma Ki No defense line?
I've heard it before.
To me, Ji-soo is Ma Ki No.
Ma is the last.
Ki, actually I have already reached hell.
No, I'm feeling angry.
I just can't abandon her, no matter how bad a person I am.
This is what I'm thinking.
Then, what about Miss Mi-ri?
Yes!
I suddenly wanted to hear your voice in the middle of work.
Stop playing, end of call.
I got it, I won't play anymore.
Hey!  Can't you use more strength?
Make it cleaner.
Rascal, why aren't you doing it seriously?
I'll go cook the noodles.
Flowers!
They are really pretty.
Min-ho, let's buy a few pots of flowers to decorate the front door.
They're not that great from what I see.
Why? Are they not pretty?
You are even prettier.
I know, but the flowers are pretty as well.
So let's still buy them.
I'm buying this. That one isn't bad either.
It'll sure be pretty if we place them all mixed together.
How about buying two?
That camera looks really great.
Do you want a camera?
Just a little.
Then, I'll buy it for you.
Since when does women buy gifts for men?
I'm not willing to accept gifts from a woman.
Honestly, shouldn't it feel strange when a man accepts gifts from a woman?
It'll seem like he's not very sensiblel.
Don't you know not to say something like that so directly?
Yes.
Noona will buy it for you.
I'm helping out my Senior with his work this time.
Wait untill I get my paid, understood?
Noona?
Soo-hee..
You.. Hey.. Come here..
Got it... Got it...
It's like drinking herb medicine when you use this to drink coffee.
I didn't scrub the bowl.
Really pretty.
Soo-hee..
We.. Let's go to a warm southern island and live there.
Let's decorate our house beautifully just like now.
I'll take pictures of the natives there for the children.
And you can do your art work.
Then when do we earn money?
Am I not hardworking?
We can plough the land together. We can go out at night to do some work.
If that's the case, meals aren't going to be any problems.
Your dream is too small.
Your's isn't anything special either.
People all think that dreams of earning big money are the right dreams.
The ones that will show your ambition. But I don't think that way.
And it's a small dream to be living life with the person you love in a simple and happy way.
I can never understand that.
Kim Min-ho, that warm southern island..
let's go there together.
We don't have to think of earning lots of money over there.
We only have to think of living our beautiful and simple lives.
Until now how many women have you seduced?
Two other women besides you.
But their answers were all "No".
If your anwer is "No" as well, I won't mention about living on a southern island again.
If that's the case.
My answer is OK.
Now, I think that you aren't that bad at all.
Please don't change.
You will die at my hands if you change.
Chung Soo-hee..
You are now saying "OK" to my proposal, do you know?
Yes, I know.
You asked me to come here saying that you have something to say.
I feel uncomfortable just sitting like this.
Just wait a while.
To satisfy your request, let's divorce.
But you must give me a month's time.
The problem about the company's share of power isn't that easy to solve.
It'll take some time to organize a shareholders' meeting.
Leave.
Thank you.
It's my first time hearing thanks from you.
But why is your vioce like that?
It's like you have no strength.
Are you so relieved?
Leave..
You are not comfortable being with me either.
Driver Lee, let's go to the construction site.
I have always wished to do this.
Supervisor Kim, you will be responsible for it.
So please pay more attention.
Yes, I know.
That.. 318 building, why is it taking so long to set up the electrical power there?
Yes.. because of extensions to the building, we are now redesigning it.
There's one part that needs to be extended.
I'll be responsible for it.
You must make sure that it tallies with the standard set.
Yes..
Let's go look at the 303 Building
I decided to divorce your dad.
When I think about the divorce..
the first person that I felt sorry towards was you.
Always.
You are always saying that you are sorry towards me.
I have already grown warts in my ears from hearing mom saying sorry to me.
So there's no need to say that again.
Min-jae..
That's your selfishness to want understanding from everyone.
Mom, just live your own life the way you want.
And I'll live mines. Let's just go on with our lives like this.
I'll come again.
I've finished, you can come down now.
Have I completed all the tests?
Yes..
When will the results be out?
Just come again three days from now.
You've worked hard.
It was hard on you too.
It's still not painful yet.
But there maybe pain later.
It's still not the conditions to be worrying about yet.
Eun-mi, if... if Mom get sick..
will you come to Seoul to visit me?
Daughters are still best.
You said " Of course" right away, eventhough you're so far away.
I'm sorry for not discussing about the divorce from your dad with you guys.
So you said it's alright.
You must be living well in America, you are so cool.
So it's like that, ok.
Go to sleep, ok.
Mom loves you too.
Yes.. Yes..
Mr. Kim Min-jae!
I might have gotten ill.
Let's meet again next time.
That kid..
She's walking everywhere again looking so dirty.
Who's her mom anyway?
No.. I won't give.
So as to say, these buildings are all built by me?
The market seller's son..
has become the nation's best contruction company chairman.
I'm considered successful, aren't I?
My dad was in the dairy business, and my mother sold soup rice in the market place.
My two younger sisters never even set foot beyond the school's gates.
They helped my mother deliver the soup rice.
But because I am a son, they allowed me to graduate from middle school.
And later, I started to earn money, fighting with my life.
I was lucky to be promoted to a manager.
And even became the son in-law of a good family.
I built sea water buildings and sold them at high prices.
I bought houses from the poor at low prices, demolished them and built high rise buildings.
I have suffered lots of scoldings but I never bothered about them either.
The younger brothers are suffering hunger.
The aged parents are still going around to earn a living.
The feelings of guilt, what a joke.
Let's go somewhere for a drink.
Drink it slowly.
It's alright.
Uncle, how did you and Aunty meet?
Because my company was developing very fast, and that became a threat to my in-law's company..
my in-law suggested that we merge together.
He didn't want any betrayal between us, so he married Min-ho's mom to me.
I, who never received a good education, married a woman both beautiful and university educated.
I never thought I was a success until that point in my life.
My wife was crying every night because she didn't love me.
But I felt that it was better that way.
I should have treated her better.
Perhaps it was my pride.
I get angry when I see her.
That's why we get angry everyday and fight.
I scream loudly because I thought I was great.
I told Min-ho's mom that we are going to end it.
I have never done anything for her after living together for so long.
She wants a separation.
I should at least give in to that request.
Bring more wine over here.
I suddenly miss Min-ho... that fellow.
You are already tired from painting the house. Aren't you too tired to still come to work?
I have nothing, but my physical strength is still conisidered pretty good, right?
Wait..
Hello..
Ji-ahn, it's you.
My dad?
Why?
I'm not going.
He is very drunk?
I got it, I'll go.
Yes..
My dad said that he wants to see me after he got drunk.
I'll come back after a while.
Just go inside and I'll see you later.
Ok, just go.
[Ba Ju City.. Ju Ahn Ri.. No.118]
Dad, I'm leaving.
Dad, I'm leaving now.
Please stay healthy, and please tell mom I will contact her.
Crazy fellow.
He asked for a busy person to come over just so he can leave like that?
He always does as he pleases. He hasn't changed that habit at all.
Uncle..., he really misses you.
Then, why did he leave?
He doesn't have the courage.
He hates me and is not willing to see me.
You may not know it, but Uncle really loves you a lot.
He's been mentioning about you lately, and he has said he's sorry.
There's nothing to be sorry about.
He's has been very good towards someone else's son.
You've already learned the truth, right?
I'm not my dad's son.
I'm not saying as it's difficult for me to explain.
But, Min-ho..
You are not someone else's son to Uncle.
I'm grateful to you for saying these things.
I understand my own dad.
He can't be bothered about anyone besides himself.
Sorry, I shouldn't have thrown my temper at you.
Let's go to the roadside stalls for a drink.
Until now, I still don't feel comfortable around you.
Do you really feel bad?
Isn't Soo-hee a really good woman?
I'm leaving.
How many pairs of fathers and sons are able to get along well in this world?
I think that there are lots of sons who also love their dads.
But there aren't too many sons who can get along well with their dads.
Ever since I was a child, I've only heard three words come out of my dad..
idiot, crazy, and no prospects.
I'm an idiot because I'm not good at studying.
I'm quite good in worthless things like sports, so I'm crazy.
I have no prospects because I can only smile with embarrassment when I'm scolded.
And so..
whenever my dad wasn't home, I would be so happy like it was my birthday.
Even so, didn't he say that he wanted to see you today?
I don't believe those words.
Wouldn't it still be the same after he wakes up from his drunkeness?
You've become really jaded.
Why? Are you disappointed because I'm a little jaded?
You didn't have a good relationship with your dad for a long time.
Then one day, he suddenly says that he wanted to see you.
Don't you think that in his heart he doesn't really hate you?
Me, too.. Even if my mom comes to visit me smilingly.
I'll get really nervous, thinking that something must have happened.
But you never really know, right?
I think I'm fighting out a battle with someone here.  Are you wanting to fight?
You are like a bad child.
But because you are a little jaded, I feel much better.
I'll be by your side to correct you whenever you get jaded like this.
I don't want to be like when I was young, fighting everyday in the house.
So, let's not fight when we are together.
It won't be the end even if we fight.
Just tell each other the truth.
We'll understand one another after we've talked about it.
Why aren't you replying?
Are we going to be able to keep all the promises we made?
I suddenly feel that we've made too many promises.
Is it because of me that you can't sleep well?
Sorry..
I can't sleep because I proposed to Soo-hee yesterday.
The answer was "Yes".  I'm even more sleepless because of that.
But Granny, I still feel really bad.
No one has ever kept all their promises to me.
I thought that it will ease the hearts of my father and brother when I left home.
But it hasn't worked out that way.
And my mother who says it's enough just to be with me, still feels lonely when she's around me.
My first love, Mi-ri too.
She said that she would come to me after leaving Ji-ahn, but she went to Ho-chul instead.
I'm afraid that Soo-hee will be like that too.
My proposal to Soo-hee is already accepted.
Really... can she really come with me to live in a warm southern island?
I wanted to ask her 10 times.. 20 times.. without stopping.
But I didn't do it because I was scared that she might regret her answer.
Did I do well?
It's not good?
That's right, it doesn't seem good either.
I shouldn't have asked.  I should have gone home to think whether or not it was true, right?
I can only do things that way, right?
But I have no other way to be with her.
It's putting off my own determination.
You think that I'm a coward, right?
Granny..
It's enough for you to know that I'm a coward, understand?
We often slept together like this when I first left home.
We haven't slept like this for a very long time.
Granny, if Soo-hee isn't going to go with me..
Granny, let's go there together.
I'm tired now, I'll sleep if you keep patting me.
When can we start working?
It will be better for me if we can start sooner.
I still need more time as I still have other work at hand.
Over at the Cafe too.
I have other things that I need some time to settle as well.
I have no problem waiting either 3 or 4 days for.
Here is the money for your hardwork.
Thanks.
Right, where is that cafe located?
At Ba Ju's side.
You are saying Ba Ju, right?
[Ba Ju City.. Ju Ahn Ri.. No.118]
Yes..
You sound really well from your voice.
You must be feeling really good.
Have you been living well?
Quite good, besides thinking of you sometimes and some heartaches.
I transferred some money to you.
Isn't today the day to pay your rent?
Ji-ahn, please don't be like this.
It'll burden me to you.
Don't feel burdened. I did it willingly.
Even if you say that, I will still feel burdened to you.
I won't accept it.
Soo-hee, why are you so cold towards me?
Sorry..
Just accept it if you feel sorry. I'm hanging up now.
Ji-ahn..
[Soo-hee, he is very good at lying. Sometimes, the lies that he spoke..]
[He can even believe them to be truths.]
[Soo-hee, he's going to let out the truth right now.]
[Soo-hee, why must he start to tell lies?]
[Soo-hee, he doesn't want to end it here.]
[Ba Ju City.. Ju Ahn Ri.. No.118]
Thank you.
You are really pretty.
Isn't this that little girl?
Hey, don't speak any more nonsense and teach this girl a lesson!
Hey, girl! You really have no upbringings?
How dare you play around with us?!
You are looking to die, right?!
Hey, thief! Just speak if you have a mouth!
I'm asking you to speak!
Are you thinking of not speaking till the end?!
Why are you falling down?!
Those students..
What are you doing?
Ahjuma, what are you doing?
You just wait a while, Girl. I'll deal with you after I've dealt with her.
You will all die if you dare to touch her again.
Where do you live? Are you a gangster?
Girl, you are a student so you should behave like one.
How can you be hitting your friend at the roadside in broad daylight?
Where are your parents?! Where?!
You, Ahjuma!
Where do you think you're going?!
That girl, she stole our money.
Because she's from a poor family and none of us really wanted to play with her!
We took her out to play, but she still betrayed us and stole our money!
What?
Tell me, is she telling the truth?
You, nasty girl.
And you all... no matter what the reason, how can you be hitting your friend?
If my friend doesn't have any money, I'll give it to her immediately.
So why must you hit her? Bad children..
Violence, regardless of any reason, is a bad thing.
How much has she stolen from you?
It's 8000 won from me and my friends.
It's only because of 8000 won.
You are really shameless.
Here..
8000 won I'm returning for her. Use the rest of the money to buy rice cakes for yourselves.
You, too.. return home quickly.
Why are you still crying?
Oh my, why are kids these days like this?
Unni! Where did you say the Kimchi was?!
It's in the white container on the bottom right side of the fridge.
There are a few white containers here!
You really like to make my head hurt don't you?
Isn't it there on the right? The white container.
There are two of them.
I said it, right? It's the one below.
Come out..
Isn't it here?
Oh, below..
Sorry.
Unni, what's this?
My wedding dress..
I brought it over when I moved house.
I was just thinking of throwing it away or..
Unni, throw it to me if you want to throw it away.
Really..
The real wedding is already so troublesome, so why must you think of going through with a fake one?
Stop thinking of those nonsense and get out quickly.
I couldn't get anything out because I wasted my attentions on you.
Quickly, why aren't you leaving?
It's my dream. Didn't you say that you will fulfill any of my dreams?
After a gentleman says something, there's nothing he can do to take it back.
Stop it..
Nothing he can do to take it back.
You are using that look again. Your eye balls are coming out.
Carry on doing your business!
Aren't you buying too much?
Although it's a small wedding ceremony, I have to get these.
What do you mean by ceremony?
There's such a thing.
You like this, right?
Oh, what's that?
Why does that look like Ji-ahn's back view?
Let's go.
Are you still contacting Ji-ahn sometimes?
Sometimes..
Are you now in love with Min-ho and Ji-ahn, both of them?
You are thinking of holding on to two rabbits with both hands, right?
But you can't think that way. You must cut away completely from Ji-ahn.
Don't pretend to be kind, you will make people confused that way.
Choi Mi-ri, I know that you are very smart.
But don't pretend to be kind, friendships are supposed to be like that.
I have already given Ji-ahn a really big, painful blow.
So do you want me to give him another?
Will I be able to endure it if that's the case?
I have no confident.
We met because of fate.
And we broke up because I had a change of heart.
From Min-ho's point of view, I was like a married woman.
But Mi-ri, because you're my friend, I felt a bit wronged right now.
Don't you think that I still need some time? Can't you understand me?
I'm always so thickheaded. I really should die.
You are really pretty, and the dress really suits you too.
I'm finally realizing my dream.
I have always wanted to wear a wedding dress since I was young.
And so, aren't you wearing it now?
I want to be good to Mister.
My mom once asked me,
"Will a gangster like him be able to let you wear the wedding dress like you've always wanted?"
"It's alright, even if I don't get to wear it."
"And so.. don't bother about me, ok.."
At that time, I thought that it didn't matter.
But I feel really happy wearing this right now.
Yes, Min-ho.
I see.
Ok, I'm hanging up now.
That gangster isn't coming?
Yes..
Let's drink some wine.
Why are you following me?
Why are you staring at me?
Is there something you want to hear from me?
What are you going to do about Mi-ri?
Ahjuma, bring me another bowl.
Although I'm the type of person who can't be bothered with other people's business,
I have to stick my nose in this this time.
If you've only been playing around with Mi-ri, this is your chance to break up with her.
Your current girlfriend now is called Soo-hee.
I heard that you've already liked her long before.
Why? Is it funny?
For me to be a single hearted man?
Rascal, why must you be so rash when you haven't heard all I wanted to say yet?
You want to fight?
You should finish listening to my good words. I wanted to say that I envy you.
Rascal, you are a real man.
It's not the actions of a real man to be playing around. That's really improper.
Don't learn to be like me, got it?
Stay loyal to one woman. You're alright in my point of view.
Hyung, then you must also treat Mi-ri..
Ahjuma!
Yes!
I'm cancelling the Wu Dong.
I'm a bad person. I'm bad from the core.
So I just can't do it, understand?
Why can't you?
How can you say that you can't when you haven't tried it?
A guy like him is as cute as a girl.
Ahjuma, I want some Soju over here.
Min-ho doesn't want to see me like this, so he made an excuse to go to the cafe.
That's right, my looks are still not bad.
He has always been pitying me.
Speaking of friendship, he's really great.
There's something that I really want to ask.
I know that you really want to have kids and a wedding.
But that Mister doesn't take any of it to heart.
I'm really angry about it as a friend.
But why are you so tolerant to Mister?
You think that I'm really pitiful, right?
Seeing me stick to a gangster who doesn't even have a good temper..
makes you really unhappy, right?
Really, even if you give him away people wouldn't take him. So why are you like this, Girl?
What you don't know is..
if that gangster is the monkey king, then I'll be the palm of the Ru Lai Buddha.
Does it look like I'm really afraid that he will leave me?
Does he have anywhere else to go if he leaves me?
To be honest, no one else in this world will like that gangster besides me.
I, too.. have been seeing this and that guy.
But who can understand it, if it's not him?
I really want to have children.
I really want to be married, too.
But, my friend and Unni..
it's not love to be doing only things I like.
To be doing things that he likes, that's love.
Isn't that so?
Yes, that's right.
Hey, don't talk about those useless things.
I did everything that the man in my house liked, but we still ended up divorcing.
Unni's ex husband wanted nothing esle but a divorce.
This kid is still rather smart.
Right, how are you getting along with Min-ho?
You don't think of Ji-ahn or anything esle, right?
I still think.. Sometimes..
When?
It's only sometimes, when I'm together with Min-ho.
That I had good times like this with Ji-ahn, that's all.
He doesn't have many friends either.
And I'm also a little worried about how has he been doing lately.
I can't do anything either since things are already this way.
Ji-ahn is a strong person.
Your concern is unnecessary.
I know all about Ji-ahn and what an evil person he really is.
That's why I said, not to worry about him.
Chung Soo-hee, it's enough for you to live well yourself.
I really want it to be like that.
That's really good.
Red wine.. Candles.. It's really like the American movies.
It makes me remember the past.
You also had times that you lit up candles like this in the past?
Yes, during the newly married period, when my husband and I loved each other more than anything else.
The room... Everywhere... We had more candles lit up than even in this room.
Even more then here?
It must have been really romantic.
It was still alright after an hour.
But I thought we would die when we ran out of oxygen.
Hey, You!
It's so funny! It's really funny!
Unni, that's really funny!
Nasty girl, you!
These things haven't been eaten yet, what are we to do?
Take your heavy arms away.
Hey, what are you doing?
Why are you so bad when you sleep?
Mister, there's a picture of me wearing the wedding dress in my handphone.
It's really pretty. Please take a look for once.
And also..
I'll promise to not do things that Mister doesn't like me to do.
Because I love you, very much.
Is there a princess that is so beautiful?
Like a fairy, right?
And an angel, too.
I'm so embarrassed.
Why must you always finish what I have to say for me?
That's so true.
Just sleep, sleep..
Teacher Kim?
Hello, Mister is not here at the moment..
Where are you calling from?
Je Ju Do? What's the matter?
You're saying Ji-soo is ill?
Hello.. Hello..
Why is she so anxious?
Je Ju Do.. Ji-soo..
It seems like it's time for us to finally fight it out for once.
Why do you live like this?
Pretending to be a deaf and dumb person.
You even changed your name from Bok-hee to Lee Mi-young.
The people around you and at the market all call you by this new name.
You are scared that I'll let out the truth, right?
Although we are a pair of mother and daughter without any blood relations,
but aren't we as bound to one another as life and death?
You seem so scared of me now.
Just talk, New Mother..
Just answer my questions.
I heard the people around here saying that you are quite rich.
Is it really a lot?
I need money.
Give me money.
You are still not going to speak?
But, it doesn't mean that I won't take it if you won't give it to me.
I became tough and poisonous after you left.
I became like this all because of you.
You are even worse than dad, you are even worse.
Right, did you know?
Dad died after you left.
Although I hated dad.
But as his child, I feel that I should take revenge.
Isn't that so?
I'm sorry, Ji-ahn. I didn't think of contacting you orginally.
But the situation is too urgent..
Seong-yi's kid is in danger, please come over quickly.
I just got off the bus, so just tell me.
I bought everything needed from the hardware shop this morning.
So where are you now?
What? Messages?
I think that it's a joke as well, but I just can't stop thinking about it.
And this is the address in the messages.
So I decided to take a look, to confirm everything.
There's no need to come. I can handle things here myself.
I know, I'll contact you if I find anything fishy.
I'll go back immediately. I'm hanging up now.
[Ba Ju City.. Ju Ahn Ri.. No.118]
Excuse me, can you tell me where No.118 is?
Chung Soo-hee, this kid really doesn't listen.
But why is she thinking of it?
Hello!
[Ba Ju City.. Ju Ahn Ri.. No.118.. Ryu Jae-hyun]
Excuse me, are you the people living here?
Translator: Yeohweping
Timer: Victory
Editor/QC: Pinklily
Coordinator : Mily2
~ TEAM W.I.T.H. S2 Fansubbers ~
- Get these subs free @ d-addicts! -