Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.5
Created time 11.05.20 15:36:45
很无聊啊 I get so bored
6点到10点 From 6.00 to 10.00
10点到6点 From 10.00 to 6.00
做6点到6点 From 6.00 to 6.00
这就是我的生活 All my life
我的白天和晚上的生活 Both day and night
我觉得无聊 I get so bored
真的想 If only
我可以找到 I could find
无论是活的还是死的 alive or dead
一个男人或者一具尸体 A man, a body
或者是动物 An animal
我不介意 I don't mind
这是做梦 Just to dream
因为我太无聊 For I get so bored
从6点到10点 From 6.00 to 10.00
肥妹/姐妹情色 FAT GIRL
我生活的全部 All my life
白天和黑夜 Both day and night
我真是无聊 I get so bored
我真的想 If only
可以找到 I could find
一个男人或女人 Man or woman
一个小孩一个灵魂 A body, a soul
一个凶手 A werewolf
我也不介意 I couldn't care less
只是在做梦 Just to dream.
当你爱上一个男孩你会 想方设法尽快得到他 When you fall for a boy, you try to pin him down too soon.
三天之后他就想溜走想自由 After three days, he wants to kick his way free
有多远走多远 and get as far away as he can.
哦 真的吗 那我们看看谁能 先找到一个正派的男孩吧 Oh, yeah? So let's see who can pick up a decent boy first.
我很大方，甚至不必 一定要是正派的男孩 I'll be generous. Doesn't even have to be decent.
任何男孩 Any boy.
即使像你一样的肥胖懒汉 Even a fat slob like you.
好像哑巴一样 That shows how dumb you are.
你身体强壮 You're great physically,
但当他们了解你了 他们会跑得老远的 but once they get to know you, they run a mile.
甚至还没了解你就跑了 They run before even getting to know you!
我只是还太年轻 I'm just too young.
他们怕跟我睡 They'd be scared to sleep with me.
但你道德沦丧 But you reek of loose morals.
我不会在外过夜的 I don't sleep around.
这个是你唯一不做的事 That's the only thing you don't do.
你对不在外面过夜 的理解很怪诞 You have a weird notion of what "not sleeping around" means.
这是事实你知道吗 That's what matters, you know.
我不这样认为 I don't think so.
如果我找到我爱的人 我就会打破这个原则 If I meet a man I love, I'd want to be broken in.
他不会在意我的第一次 He won't think my first time counts.
第一次不应该给任何人 The first time should be with nobody.
我不想那个男的说 得到了我的第一次 I don't want a guy bragging he had me first.
男人都有病 Guys are all sick.
我累了 I'm wiped out.
来吧 我想你是渴了 - Oh, come on! - I thought you wanted a drink.
哪里简直就是垃圾堆 That place is a dump.
你愿意就坐这里吧 You can sit here if you like.
告诉你的朋友 我的姐妹 Tell your friend -- - My sister.
你不能只是坐下 还要问别人是否介意 You can't just sit down. You ask if people mind.
我不介意 我也问过你的 I don't mind. I asked you to.
来吧 Go ahead.
你真好 It's very kind of you.
当没有座位 你感到渴和累的时候 When there's no seats free and you're thirsty and tired,
有一个这么友好的人真是太好了 It's nice to find someone friendly.
佛兰多 埃琳娜 - Fernando. - Elena.
这是我的妹妹安娜福斯 My little sister, Anais.
别站在这里 你都冻坏了 Don't just stand there, you lump.
想喝什么 What would you like?
咖啡 Coffee.
你是意大利人吗 是的 家在罗马 Are you Italian? - Yes, from Rome.
香蕉半剖条我最喜欢的 A banana split -- my favorite.
我们来这里度假 住在当地人家里 We're on vacation here, staying at the Residence.
很安静 但 It's nice because it's quiet but.
我们出入不方便 we can't get out easily.
我们觉得 We're not allowed.
不自然 Speak for yourself.
别担心 Don't worry.
他不明白你刚才说的那个词 He can't understand a word you're saying.
他只是很有礼貌 He's just being polite.
不这样不错 No, it's okay.
但你能不能说话慢点呢 But can you speak more slowly?
我需要提高我的法语水平 I need to improve my French.
我在上高中 I'm in high school.
我刚读完大二明年就大三了 I just finished sophomore year. I'll be a junlor next year.
我也不知道以后要做什么 但很快就会看到的了 I don't know what I'm gonna do later, but it's handy, see.
要有文学和科学 It's part literature, and part science.
高中 High school.
那是很久以前的事了我在上大学 That was long ago. I'm in college.
学法律 I study law. Avvocato.
你在上大学吗那应该是难得空闲了 You're in college? That must be different. You're free.
这是个问题 That's the problem.
你可以不去上课 You're not required to attend classes,
但必须参加期末考试 but you have to take final exams.
你经常要在6月参加补考 如果老不及格 You can always retake them in June, but if you keep falling behind.
还有我爸爸就是不理解 Besides, my father wouldn't understand.
他做什么的 我爸爸吗 - What does he do? - My father?
他是一间煤矿公司的 He's an avvocato international.
全球化主管 mine's a company director.
不好意思我刚下班 Excuse me. I'm finishing my shift.
看到你在门外的身影 See you back at the gate.
等了很久吗 Been waiting long?
我正要回家呢 I almost went home.
你真好 You're sweet.
我不信有龙卷风 这里是法国 - I couldn't believe there was a tornado. - This is France.
我们这里没有龙卷风 Precisely. We don't have tornadoes here.
这床会摇动的 我很怕 The bed was shaking. I was terrified.
但我没有下楼找安全地方 But I didn't come downstairs to safety.
我用被单蒙头 I pulled the sheets over my head
我决心 and decided
要忘记那些声音继续入睡 to ignore the noise and go back to sleep.
我一定是疯了 睡觉救不了我 I must have been crazy. Sleeping wouldn't save me.
什么 你是学什么的 - What? - What are you studying?
我学法律 明年就大三了 I'm studying law. Next year I'll be in my third year.
刑法吗 Criminal law?
是的 我对刑法很感兴趣 Yes, that's what interests me.
我想它会更有用 I think it's much more useful.
当然我也是学国际法的 Of course, I'll study international law too
要做个商业律师 to be a business lawyer.
但是我工作是想过好日子 But I'd like to start out working for good causes.
那你是学国际法 So you'll be in international law.
我父亲也很看重的 My father insists on it.
我父亲也是国际法律师当然 He's an international lawyer and so, of course,
他也想我学国际法 he'd like me to follow in his footsteps.
你了解国际法吗 Have you gotten acquainted?
能应付得来吗是的 我学得很好 Is this okay for you? - Yes, perfect.
我叫他节食 I'm putting him on a diet.
你觉得我肥 You think I'm fat.
不是 但在你这个年龄你的身材不是苗条 No, but you're not thin for your age.
你真的吃饱了吗 我看都吃光了 - Sure you've got enough? - I was worried it'd all be gone.
别人还说她怎么会肥 And people wonder why she's fat.
其实很简单她吃得像头猪 这都是她自己造成的 It's simple: She eats like a pig. It's all she does.
不是她的错是激素的错 It's not her fault -- it's hormonal. She can't help it.
也许是这样 但她不停地塞东西入口 Maybe so, but she keeps stuffing herself.
让我没有食欲 哦得了 It ruins my appetite. - Oh, come on.
那你是怎么认识我女儿的 So, how did you meet my daughters?
聚会 Franois!
年青人的聚会 Young people meet.
我们认识没多久 It just happens these days.
我觉得非常无聊 且无休无止 I get so bored It's not over yet
在我的生活和声明之后 After my life and my survival
在我死了之后我仍觉得无聊 After my death I'll still be bored
比以前更甚 More than ever before
只要我能找到 If only I could find
无论是神灵还是鬼怪 是男人还是女人 A specter or a ghost Woman or man
甚至是动物我都不介意 An animal I don't mind
来做梦 To dream.
我的嘴唇很柔软是吧我是个接吻好手 My lips are soft, huh? I'm a good kisser.
是的你是我的爱人 Yes, you're my love,
但是我不想和你结婚 but I don't want to marry you yet.
既然我了解我这样的男人 Now that I know men like me,
我想要些其他经历 I want other experiences.
我吻得好不好啊我以前只是吻过一次而已 Don't I kiss well? I've only been kissed once before.
你妒忌吗我没有骗你 Are you jealous? I didn't really cheat on you.
你知道女人不是肥皂泡 Women aren't like bars of soap, you know.
她们不会破灭 They don't wear away.
相反每个爱人会让她更丰富 On the contrary, each lover brings them more,
你会得到所有的好处 and you get all the benefit.
你让我觉得很恶心啊你怎么能让 我那么讨厌你又那么吸引我啊 You make me sick. How can you disgust me and attract me so much?
你是我付出所有的一个 You're the one I'll give it all to.
不我以前从来没有跟人睡过 No, I've never slept with anyone before.
你在做什么啊 What are you doing? Can't you ask?
你在做什么啊忘记 - What are you doing? - Get lost.
出去吗 不不是我怎么可以呢 - Going out? - No, I'm not. How the hell can I?
你没有请他来这里是吗 You didn't invite him here, did you?
去睡觉 Go to sleep.
你什么都没听到什么都 没看到什么都不知道 You hear nothing, see nothing and know nothing.
如果你要睡觉就不用化妆 No need for makeup If you're going to sleep.
睡觉吧好吗 Go to sleep, okay?
记住别多管闲事 And remember, mind your own business.
你找对地方了 You got the right place.
你说是左边第一道门 You said the first door on the left.
我妹妹睡了 My little sister's asleep.
门卫差点不让我进来 The gateman almost didn't let me in.
那你怎么进来的我给他小费了 - How did you manage? - I gave him a tip.
来点音乐吧 Let's put on some music.
不行 We can't.
又不是什么大事 那什么是大事啊 It's no big deal. - What's a big deal?
那就是好像 It's as if.
音乐比我更重要一样 the music counted more than I do.
对你来说 As if it meant more to you.
我会被侵犯 I could get offended.
什么没什么 - What? - Nothing.
对不起我的法语说得不好 I'm sorry I don't speak French well.
我不想告诉你 I'd like to tell you all kinds of things.
你是那么的动人 That you're so pretty.
我知道双方不理解是很辛苦的 I know. It's hard not being able to understand each other.
好像我说意大利语的 却说西班牙语一样 To think I could have taken Italian but chose Spanish instead.
他们很有男子气概 They're machos.
我明年要苦修意大利语 I can try to learn Italian next year.
不应该是我去学法语 No, I have to learn French.
我不知道为什么 I don't see why.
当我到巴黎看你时 我的法语一定学得更好 When I come to see you in Paris, I'll have learnt French better.
你会来巴黎看我吗 我会 - You'll come to see me in Paris? - Yes.
其实我不是住在巴黎 I don't actually live in Paris.
我住在巴黎外面 I live just outside.
虽然我有很大的房子 I have a great house, though.
那行我会去的 That's okay, I'll be coming anyway.
你上床也带乳罩的吗 You wear your bra to bed?
不是我忘了脱而已 No, I forgot to take it off.
你能帮我吗 Can't you help me?
男孩总要干活 A boy has to work.
如果太容易得到了那就没意思了 If it's too easy, there's no pleasure.
别担心这些不是那么简单的 Don't worry. These things are always so complicated.
真的吗 Is that true?
你以前有很多女孩子吗 我不是第一个 You've loved a lot of girls before? I'm not the first.
当然你不是 Of course, you're not the first.
我知道我只是问问你 有很多很多的女人 I realize that. I'm just asking If you've had lots and lots of girls.
那又有什么关系 What does it matter?
重要的是我现在和你一起 I'm here with you now.
但是有多少个啊 But how many have you had?
不是很多 那有多少啊 - Not that many. - How many?
我不知道 I don't know.
如果你不知道那就是非常多了 If you don't know, that means loads.
你妒忌了 You're jealous.
我从来没遇到像你一样的 I've never had one like you.
真的吗 Are you sure?
即使不是我和你睡 也会有其他的人吧 Even if I don't sleep with you and others do?
那可不一样 That makes a big difference.
我对处女没兴趣 I haven't been interested in a virgin since.
什么时候开始 Since?
我15岁时 Since I was 15.
其他的女孩都是第一次见面 就跟你睡的吗 The other girls all slept with you on the first date?
第一次或第二次都一样 first or second, it's the same.
不不一样 No, it's not the same.
你可以说都是他们自愿的 You can tell it's all they want.
有时候吧 这让我很不舒服 Sometimes, it's so obvious It makes me sick.
就是自从那次 There was this one once.
她约我吃饭然后带我到她的房间 She asked me to dinner and took me to her bedroom.
你进入我身体了 You're in mine now.
这很不同 This is different.
而且我们没有选择 We have no choice. Anyway.
有人告诉我她想跟我出去 someone told me that this girl had wanted to go out with me
从那年年初就想了我没有注意到 Since the start of the year, but I hadn't noticed.
所以她就约我吃饭 然后去了她的房间 So she asks me to dinner, and we go to her room.
开始喝酒喝了四瓶 And there we start drinking. There were four bottles of wine,
就是这样好像刚好四瓶 just like that, as if by chance. Four of them.
我们就开始喝酒什么都没吃 So we start drinking and eat nothing.
我在想你不可能赢我的母狗 I'm thinking, "You won't get me, bitch."
我的意思是说女的喝酒 绝对没有男的厉害 I mean, a girl can't take as much drink as a guy.
所以我喝酒速度就减慢了 So I slow down on my drinking
不停的给她倒酒 and keep on filling her glass.
到了半夜我跟她说对不起 At half past midnight, I tell her, "Sorry.
我就要赶不上末班火车了晚安 Got to go. I'll miss the last tram. Good night."
我扔下烂醉如泥的她 她对我非常生气 I left her blind drunk and mad at me.
再也没有跟我说话 She hasn't spoken to me since.
你不喜欢她吗 You didn't like her?
她是很可爱的那种女孩子 She was kind of cute.
但我就是这样踢走她的 But I got a kick out of dumping her like that.
还有她不是唯一一个 Besides, she wasn't the only one.
我这样对待的人 I've done it loads of times.
跟女孩子在一起是那么的容易 It's so easy with girls.
你喜欢过跟你睡过的女孩子吗 Were you in love with the others you've slept with?
我知道你想什么你在妒忌 I know what you're getting at. You're jealous.
其它的不算 The others don't count.
我跟他们睡只是因为我是男人 I only sleep with them because I'm a guy. That's all.
所以如果你跟我睡 So if you slept with me,
我会跟其他的女孩子一样嘛 I'd be like all the other girls?
不会 No.
我尊重你 I'd respect you.
甚至你和我睡觉嘛 Even if you slept with me?
是的 Yes.
发誓你不想做 Promise you won't do it.
我不想你做 I don't want you to.
我以我妈妈的头发誓 I swear on my mother's head
我会适可而止的 I'll stay on the edge.
在不介意的边缘 On the edge doesn't count.
真的吗 不会的 - It does. - It doesn't.
会的 It does.
因为我介意 Because I count.
你是唯一一个介意的人 You're the only one who counts.
我怕到时候你控制不住 I'm scared you won't be able to hold back.
别担心这个这是我的问题 Don't worry about that. That's my problem.
我是个男人我知道是 否能做到 我可以的 I'm a man. I know if I can hold back or not. And I can.
但我像完全的拥有你 But I'd like to have you properly.
这不可能 That's not possible.
如果我跟其他我不爱的女人 一起那真的是无法忍受的 It's dumb if I have to go with another girl, a girl I don't love.
你想吗 Will you need to?
你看我不想 Look, I don't want
但我不能 to bring myself off on my own in the can. That's sick.
我爱你 I love you.
我真的爱你 但请你给我时间 I really love you. But give me time.
我说了我不想 I said I don't want to.
我什么都不做 I didn't do anything.
我还以为你也想的我什么都没做 I thought you wanted it too. I didn't do anything.
你把这一切都破坏了知道吗 You're spoiling everything, understand?
是你破坏的 You're spoiling it.
这很好啊 It was fine.
是的是很好 你不觉得很好吗 Yes, it was fine. Don't you realize it was fine?
我不觉得 I can't.
这是我的错我不能这样太快了 It's not my fault. I can't. Not like this, straight off.
我不是骗你 I didn't trick you.
我警告你 I warned you.
我不是快餐饼干 I'm not a cocktease.
你是不是疯了 Are you crazy?
你这样逼我 我又怎么能不反对呢 How can I resist if you press up against me like that?
你以为我是圣人啊 You think I'm some kind of saint?
你看不到你对我做了什么吗 You can't see what you're doing to me, huh?
你觉得这是对我好吗 You think it's good for me?
不 No.
但是 But.
你不觉得和爱你的人 Don't you think it's best to do it for the first time
第一次就做是最好的吗 with someone who loves you?
是的 Yes.
这是爱的证明 That would be a proof of love,
真爱的证明 a real proof of love,
你对我的爱和我对你的爱 from you to me, and from me to you too.
我是说很多的男人 I mean, there are loads of guys
看到处女都会脱光她的 who take off when they see a girl's a virgin.
这有太多的争论 有太多的责任你知道吗 It's too much hassle, too much responsibility, see.
事后他们回来 They come back once the job's been done.
真的吗是的 - Really? - Yes.
真恶心 That's sick.
如果不是我希望你找 个比你大的女人 If not, I'll need to find another girl older than you.
那也是恶心我不想做 That's sick too, and I don't want to do that.
我不想 I don't want to.
你是个小女孩 You're a little girl.
很像女人的小女孩 A little girl who looks like a woman.
你必须忘记男人 You have to forgive men.
你不是生我气吧 You're not mad at me?
你疯了啊 Are you crazy?
我是生你气 I'm mad about you.
如果你够好心 If you were kind.
如果我够好心 If I was kind?
所有女的都反过来 All the girls take it the back way.
所有女的是的 - All the girls? - Yes.
那样不重要 That way, it doesn't count.
她们可以说从来没有跟人睡过 They can say that they've never slept with anyone.
真恶心 不是的 - That's sick. - It isn't.
这不恶心 这是爱的证明 It's not sick. It's a proof of love.
如果你对我的爱是 跟我对你的爱一样 If you love me the way I love you.
我想哭 I feel like crying.
不你不能哭 No, you mustn't.
你不能 你是个很好的女孩子 You mustn't. That was a wonderful gift.
你不知道这对我的感觉吗 Didn't you feel what it did for me?
知道但我感到羞耻 Yes, but I'm ashamed.
你已经证明了对 我的爱那是爱的证明 You've shown your love for me. It was a proof of love.
爱的证明知道吗 A proof of love, see.
是你对我的爱和我对你的爱 From me to you and from you to me.
你也一样爱我吗 Do you love me all the same?
是的 Yes.
别担心 Don't worry.
你是那种 You're the kind of girl
男人梦想结婚的女孩子 that men dream of marrying.
你想和我结婚吗 You'd like to marry me?
如果你不是那么年轻我想 If you weren't so young, yeah.
我必须先参加考试 I have to take my exams first.
你会等我吗 Would you wait for me?
除了等你我还能做什么 What else am I doing but waiting for you?
停 Stay.
好 Yes.
已经是早上了 It's morning.
我必须回去了 I have to get back.
你知道我走之前想做什么吗 You know what I'd like before I go?
我想你带我进入你的嘴 I'd like you to take me in your mouth.
不是和我的妹妹在这里 Not with my little sister here.
她睡了 She's asleep.
她可能是假睡你不了解她 She might be pretending. You don't know her.
她妒忌 She's jealous.
你接受不了我比她大 She won't accept that I'm older than her.
她睡着了可以了吗 She's sleeping, okay?
如果给她看到我就真的麻烦了 It would really bother me If she saw me.
我也想睡一会 I want to get some sleep!
你喋喋不休的真讨厌 你醒了 I'm sick of you rattling on. - You're awake?
你整晚在偷听我们说话吗 You've been spying on us all night?
不是 我尽力睡了 懒得理你的声音 No, I've been trying to sleep. I don't care about you screwing.
你这条小母狗 You little bitch!
你叫我母狗 You're calling me a bitch?
这个称呼好啊 That's a good one!
我姐姐让个男人整个晚上摸她 My sister lets some guy fondle her all night long,
完全没有考虑我还叫我是母狗 Never thinking about me, and I'm the bitch!
你生我气啊 Are you mad at me?
我觉得很肮脏我觉得不舒服 I feel dirty. I don't feel comfortable.
是以为我的姐姐吗 不不是她 - Because of my sister? - No, it's not her.
相爱中的人都是这样 What should be natural between two people in love is so --
真恐怖 Well, it's sinister.
我不想你造次知道吗 I don't want it to happen again, see?
你想分开吗 You want to split up?
我想爱你 I want to love you.
下次 Next time.
下次我们就做了 你想做吗 你还是想做吗 Next time we'll do it. You want to? You still want to?
回答我啊 Answer me!
当然啦 Of course.
如果你说不想 我就去死 If you'd said no, I'd have died.
我将是你第一个爱人 I'll be your first lover.
那个带你今日爱河的第一个人 The very first. The one who introduces you to love.
你会一直想着我 You'll always remember me.
即使你以后和其他男生在一起 Even with other guys later,
我就是第一个 I'll always be the first.
你会忘记我吗 Won't you remember me?
男生不像女生 Guys aren't like girls.
你永远不会离开我的 You'll never leave me, then.
住手 Stop.
住手 Stop it.
你会着凉的 住手 You'll catch cold. Stop it.
不 我不冷 No, I'm not cold.
如果我们在一起的事被人知道了 你知道我回家会有多惨吗 You know what I risk back home If we're found together?
告诉我 Tell me.
我会进监狱的 I'll go to prison.
你还不到16岁这太危险了 It's too dangerous. You're not 16.
这不公平 是我想要的 That's not fair. It's me who wants it.
看 不是我想住手的 See, it wasn't me who stopped first.
下次 Next time,
我会告诉你什么是爱 I'll teach you all about love.
完璧归赵吗 Returned goods? In the returned goods column!
太多了没有什么区别 There's a lot? No difference.
你究竟在做什么啊变得更平滑了 What the hell have you done? It was going smoothly,
我一转身 and once I turn my back.
你会想我回来的是不是 You want me to come back, huh?
告诉你那个怪东西会让我回来的 I'm telling you, that jerk will make me go back.
不 顺其自然吧 No, let them get by on their own for once.
现在好好度假吧 Enjoy your vacation for now.
你觉得开公司容易吗 You think it's easy to start up a company?
万事开头难 Everything's so sluggish at first before it takes off.
如果你走错一步 If you pick the wrong path,
事情变得会很快 things happen fast.
放个屁的时间你就破产了 One asshole and you can go broke.
哦得了这是老调重弹了 - Oh, come on. - It's the old idol with feet of clay.
面对竞争你会更强 You're way ahead of the competition. You feel strong.
你就有了现金流 And you get done in by cash flow problems.
吃 让你分心 Eat. it'll take your mind off things.
安娜福斯在做什么啊她在炫耀 - What's Anais doing? - Showing off.
安娜福斯别叫了我会得到她的 - Anais! - Don't shout. I'll get her.
我对你是有点过分但是我有理由 Okay, I was a bit hard on you, but I had my reasons.
我刚才生气了不是你的错 I've just got a temper. It's not your fault.
我不想做你的妻子 I'm sick of being your ball and chain.
你不是我的妻子 You're not my ball and chain.
但是你不和我一起 他们就不会让我出去 But if you're not with me, they'll never let me out.
他们想我和你一起 They like me to drag you along.
是的你和我 See? You "drag me along."
是的 明天 Yes, tomorrow.
不 早上最好 没关系的 No, the morning's best. Ah, well, never mind.
八点过十分钟 Ten past 8:00.
时间差不多 About time!
如果我们没有一起吃饭 那又有什么意义呢 What's the sense in being here If we don't eat together?
她有什么问题吗 没有 - What's wrong with her? - Nothing.
我应该失望了 I should hope not!
度假看到这样的脸孔 我不是跟自己过不去吗 I'm not working myself to death to see a face like that on vacation!
事实上我没有度假 我是唯一不会生气的人 In fact, I can't take a vacation, and I'm the only one not sulking!
看看你说的 Look at you all!
很希望你高兴 谢谢主 我明天要走了 I'm glad you're so happy. Thank God I'm leaving tomorrow.
你怎么啦 她怎么啦 What's wrong with you? What's wrong with her?
她还是个少女可以 克服这一关的 It's adolescence. She'll get over it.
她最好快点克服 She'd better get over it fast.
不会那么严重的 你还没失去胃口 It can't be serious. You haven't lost your appetite.
来吧吃吧 Come on, eat.
吃对你有好处 It'll do you good.
吃可以让你不去想起什么事 Eating takes your mind off things.
聚会你差点忘记了 Franeois, you almost forgot this.
如果他回来 If he's flying back --
那是什么我们会坐车回家的 What of it? We'll go home by car.
我会开车 I'll drive.
累的时候就用高速路休息站 We'll use highway rest stops when I'm tired.
这样会更花更多时间 It'll just take longer.
你会开车吗 You'll be driving?
哦我可以的我只是不想 Oh, come on. I can do it. I just don't like to.
每年我都想 你爸爸还能坚持多久 Every year, I wonder how long your dad will last.
他这次破了自己的纪录 He broke his record this time.
他不能度假 He can't stand vacations.
他也不能接受同伙度假 And he can't stand his partners being on vacation either.
他会马上叫他们回来工作的 You'll see. He'll have them back at work in no time.
我想我跟他不一样 I guess I'm not like him.
我可以理解他 I understand him.
度假充电 Vacations suck.
不会再有了 Not again!
你的衣服不一样的 You're not getting the exact same dress as me.
你是不是不想和我搭配啊 Aren't you sick of copying me?
想恢复到以前啊 Try to be original for once.
态度完全不同的 It's a different color.
是一样的衣服 It's the same dress.
我一直都跟着你的 风格的现在是你学我的 I'm stuck with you all the time, and now you copy me.
我不知道你穿了同一件 I didn't know you chose the same one.
我觉得那是最好的一件 I think it's the best one too.
你也可以拿走我的男朋友 You could take my boyfriend too
再说 我根本不知道他就是你的 and say, "I didn't see he was already yours."
他不是你的 他不是狗 He's not yours. He's not a dog.
他是我的你 只是条母狗想要学我 He is mine. And you're just a bitch, trying to copy me.
你没有机会了 永远都不会像我 You don't stand a chance. You'll never be like me.
你一定是开玩笑 我不想跟你一样 You must be joking! I don't want to be like you.
那好你最好什么都别学我的 Well you'd better not copy me in any case.
我不觉得这是同一件 I didn't realize it was the same one.
这个更短了 Shorter.
我想要短些 I want it shorter.
刚过膝盖 It's prettier below the knee.
是我穿的我想要短些 I'm the one wearing it, and I want it shorter.
让我来 Let me do it.
真是个倔强的人 我跟她做不了什么 A real mule. I can't do a thing with her.
我该离开这里 It's pretty creepy out here.
我也觉得是最少 我觉得很不舒服 I think so, at least. I feel really uneasy.
你错了外面很美好 You're wrong. It's great out here.
你甚至看不到马路 You can't even see the road.
我希望我们迷路了永远走不出来 I hope we lose our way and never get out,
好像走进远古一样 like in an ancient legend.
这个主意不错 Good idea.
我决心要忘记路 I've set my heart to rot away
在窗边 On the windowsill
我相信将来 I trust in a future day
乌鸦会过来 我相信它们会的 The crows may come I hope they will
看到他们的嘴从天空飞过 with their beaks so fleet
他们会 They will peck away
吃掉一对生肉 At this lump of raw meat
这就是你担心的 Over which you thought you held sway
我决定要离去 I've set my heart to rot away
窗台边 On the windowsill
因为很不愉快的日子 For the joyless joy of the day
我的担忧来了 My worries fall still
如果你看到羊群 If you see the flock
羊群跑过 Of crows fighting over it
别用石头扔他们 Throw them not a rock
因为我跟他们差不多 For I am worth not a bit
我决心要离去 I've set my heart to rot away
在窗台边 On the windowsill
我相信在未来的日子里 I trust in a future day
乌鸦来的时候如果它们能来到 When the crows come, if they will
它们的嘴是那么的灵活 with their beaks so fleet
它们会吃掉 They will peck away
这一堆生肉 At this lump of raw meat
这就是你担心的 Over which you thought you held sway
荡妇 Slut.
没人会相信我们是姐妹 No one would think we're sisters.
真的我们根本不像的 It's true. We don't take after anyone.
好像是不同的人的孩子 It's like we're born of ourselves.
有趣的是 我们真的 没什么共同点 看你 It's funny. We really have nothing in common. Look at you.
一双小的坚强的眼睛 You have small, hard eyes,
而我的眼睛很朦胧 while mine are hazy.
但我仔细看你的眼睛 But when I look deep into your eyes,
让我觉得那是我属于我的 it makes me feel like I belong,
好像是我的眼睛 as if they were my eyes.
我也这样想 I feel the same thing.
所以我们是姐妹 That's why we're sisters.
当我恨你的时候我看这了 我就恨不起来 When I hate you, I look at you and then I can't.
就好像要恨我自己一样 It's like hating part of myself.
所以才那么讨厌你 That's why I loathe you so violently,
因为你本来应该跟我一样的 because you ought to be like me.
但现在我觉得你跟我完全相反 But at times I have the feeling you're the exact opposite.
我也这样想的 I feel that too.
这也是你比其他人更让我生气的原因 That's why you make me angrier than anyone else.
我不想让你错过什么 I don't let you get away with anything.
你这样是错的而我对你的生活有说法 You have no rights, whereas I have a say in your life.
我们都讨厌对方因为 我们一直都是竞争者 We hate each other because we're raised as rivals.
这是爸爸妈妈的错 It's Dad and Mom's fault.
这也不是他们的错 And yet it's not their fault.
他们认为这样好可以刺激我们 They think it's good, that it stimulates us.
当跟我在一起时我想你 会觉得他们是错的 I think you hated it when I came along.
我是说 I mean,
当我是个婴儿的时候 你做我的妈妈 when I was a baby, you played mommy with me.
但我长大之后 But when I got bigger --
你的意思是父亲了 Fatter, you mean!
母狗 bitch.
当我跟着你到处走时 When I could start belting you for bossing me around,
当你不能再扮演妈妈时 when you couldn't play mommy anymore,
当我能说话时 and when I caught up with you language-wise too.
真的吗我都不记得了 Really? I don't remember that.
你确定你不想讲和吗 Are you sure you aren't making it up?
不 我记得很清楚 No, I remember it really well.
你教育我的激情没有了 The day your passion for educating me ended
是我们在床上那晚在我们的双人床上 was when we were in bed one evening, in our pink twin beds,
因为些什么事你说了 一大堆对我指指点点 and for some reason you launched into a speech, bossing me around.
而我反驳你 And wham, I pounced on you.
你向妈妈抱怨使我很高兴 I was pleased because you called Mom to complain
我应该狠狠的反驳你 你有两个地方被打伤 that I'd pinched you really hard, and you had two big bruises.
从那天开始 since that day,
你就变了 the wind's gone out of your sails.
你不在指挥我 You've never bossed me around again.
我一点都不记得了 I don't remember that at all.
我记得很清楚 I remember it perfectly.
我对你很好我会开车带你去散步 I was nice with you. I'd wheel you in your stroller
叫自己是妈妈 and call myself Mommy Lélaine.
我讨厌那样 真的吗 - I hated that. - You did?
你必须接受这太不公平了 You have to admit, it's pretty unfair.
你做什么都可以比我早两年 You're allowed to do things two years sooner than I could.
是的 我不否认那不公平 Yes, I'm not denying that's unfair.
如果不是就没有好处了 If not, there's no advantage in being second.
另外很多人都想分清你和我 Besides, so many people don't bother to remember which one's which
因为我们的昵称一样 我的意思是我们不像 since we have the same surname. I mean, we're not alike.
那是真的我们不像 That's for sure, we're not alike!
母狗 bitch!
我变成那么卑鄙了 I wasn't being mean.
要不要我告诉你一个秘密 Want me to tell you a secret?
佛兰多给我的 Fernando gave me this.
是订婚戒指 It's an engagement ring.
是紫色的猫眼石 他不会给你的 A mauve opal. - He can't have given you that.
你丧失理智了 You're out of your mind.
一定是被俘虏了 There must be a catch.
不是的 我们订婚了 No. This way, we're engaged now.
这是个约定 It's a pact.
我要定做的 I need to get it fitted.
他什么时候给这个你的 在山丘上 - When did he glve you that? - In the dunes.
像鱼腥一样我不信你会接受 Something's fishy. I don't think you should have accepted.
我不知道这太贵重了 It's not right. it's too valuable.
拿着 我才不要什么戒指 Hold on. I didn't want some shitty ring!
他到底在哪得到这个的 Where the hell did he get it?
他祖母给他的 His grandmother left it to him.
我想我今晚就要献身给他了 I think I'm going to give myself to him tonight.
你的说话很荒谬啊 You use some really weird expressions.
如果他用避孕套 我就随他怎么来 If he uses a condom, I'll let him go all the way.
得了别讲那些细节 Spare me the details, please.
你不知道我有多怕 You have no idea how scared I am.
总有一天我还是要经历的 Still, I have to go through it one day.
所以更我爱的人做最好 So it may as well be with someone I love.
你怎么想有什么建议 What do you think? What do you suggest?
无论如何你已经做了的和那个 In any case, between what you've already done and that,
已经没有什么区别了 我觉得 there's no moral difference in my opinion.
这个完全不同 There's a world of difference!
我要把自己第一次 Personally, I want my first time
给一个我不爱的人 to be with a boy I don't love.
因为之后 Because afterwards
你知道他不再爱你或你 不再爱他你就无话可说 you realize he doesn't love you or you don't love him, and you feel dumb.
等你恋爱了你就会了解 You'll see when you fall in love.
我怀疑 I doubt it.
无论如何别怪我 In any case, don't mind me.
你别怕吵着我可以整晚的做 Do not be afraid you are disturbing with me Could be to do all night
吻我吧 Kiss me.
我怕 I'm scared.
大方点 不 Be gentle. - No.
最好前进一步 那就完事了 One hard push is best, then it's over.
不 轻轻的 相信我 - No, gently. - Trust me.
听众来见过你了吗 Do audiences come to see you
因为踢还是因为什么 for kicks or what?
不是根本不是 No, not at all.
为什么不呢为什么 Why not? Why?
我在做性杂志 True, my show tackies sexual issues.
没有性完全不同的 There's no sex, that's different.
也许我不清楚性别和性的区别吧 Maybe I confuse sex and sexual issues.
这是个性问题的调查 就这样 It's an investigation of sexual issues. That's all.
这在法国很困难 Its a big problem in France.
已经有了巴多特这样的性杂志 You have Bardot, who is a sexual issue.
不 她是个案例不是杂志 No, she's a case, not an issue.
她是个案例所以可以上杂志 She's a case, so she's an issue.
你应该看看德贝未诺的文章 You should read what De Beauvoir wrote.
她的文章写的很好我喜欢巴多特 She wrote some great things. I love Bardot,
但是个性杂志 but she's a sexual issue.
你为什么要研究性问题啊 So why do you investigate this issue?
这是个简单而明显的 问题每个人都理解 It's a simple and obvious issue that everyone can understand.
这是个人类简单的问题 It's a very simple human issue.
但是没有人做得完美 And no one is perfect on that level.
其他的问题更复杂 things are more complicated with other issues,
让世界很混乱 given the confusion in the world.
那你呢你觉得自己的水平还不够吗 How about you? How do you fall short on that level?
我没有说 I'm not saying.
她很好是不是 She's great, isn't she?
我从来不了解人我很想知道 可是我出生太迟了 I'll never know the people I'd like to know. I was born too late.
叨扰下这是平高特家吗 Excuse me. Is this the Pingot home?
说吧这不是什么难回答的问题 Come now, It's not a difficult question.
我仍觉得等这样的答案很愚蠢 Still, I suppose it's stupid to expect an answer.
那样的话我还是进来吧 In that case, I'll come in.
我是佛兰多的妈妈 I'm Fernando's mother.
很抱歉我只是走路过来 I'm sorry. I just walked right in.
你是埃琳娜的妈妈吗 Are you Elena's mother?
我烦着你了吧 没有 Am I disturbing you. - Not at all!
这些苔藓和水草长得真快啊 The moss grows so fast with all this wet grass.
这里很乱 This is very awkward, you see. Very awkward indeed.
没有不是的 No, not at all. Really.
这里太乱了 It's an awkward situation.
真的不是 我打扰你了 - Not at all. - I'm bothering you.
不 我真得要感谢你 你儿子是 No. I really must compliment you. Your son is  --
这太混乱了 It's an awkward situation.
我不知道该怎么开始 I don't know where to begin.
你知道每个暑假 You know, every summer,
我都带些珠宝 I always bring a few valuable jewels along.
有些很昂贵的 其他的都是 普通的珠宝 你也知道 Some precious, others just costume jewelry, you see.
我不是每天都检查的 I don't check on them every day.
问题是他们都带着记忆 Trouble is, they're memories.
戒指代表你将要结婚的男人 Rings represent the men
你也知道的 whom you managed to make understand
他才会给戒指你 that they should offer them to you, you see?
我不明白 I don't understand.
而且这完全是荒谬 Besides, it's totally ridiculous
把那么贵重的戒指给年轻的姑娘 to give such a valuable ring to some young girl
你刚才遇到谁了 whom you just happen to meet
我在度假 on vacation.
这这是荒谬 It's totally absurd!
什么戒指你说什么 What ring? What do you mean?
我那紫红色的猫眼石 My mauve opal.
我不知道她为什么这样就接受 I don't understand how she could have accepted it just like that.
我儿子还太年轻 不能 处理我的财产 我还没死 My son is too young to dispose of my property. I'm not dead yet!
我也不想死 And I don't intend to die!
我毫无头绪 但我的女儿不是这样的人 I don't understand any of this, but my daughter's not like that.
你在这里啊 你的姐姐在哪里 There you are. Where's your sister?
我又不是她的保姆 I'm not her keeper.
你疯了啊 You're crazy.
你是不是一直都要拖她后腿啊 You're always ready to back her up when she screws up, aren't you?
你疯了 别装作不知道 - You're crazy. - Don't pretend you don't know.
她有个属于这位女士的戒指 She has a ring that belongs to this lady.
你儿子不能亲自来吗 闭嘴 - Couldn't your son come himself? - Stop it.
你要走了吗 我们总要回家的 - You're leaving? - We have to go home one day.
不可能逗留太久 这就是生活 - You didn't stay long. - That's life.
听点音乐吧 Can we have some music on?
我什么都没做 I didn't do anything.
我因为她而大叫 I get yelled at because of her.
我的度假心情都给破坏了 And my vacation's been wrecked.
你爸爸想你考试 Your father wants to have you examined.
要不要来份警察的报告啊 How about a police report too?
发表在报纸上 Published in the papers?
是的他可以的 我的女儿 He c an't. - Oh, yes, he can, my girl.
你要先想清楚 You should have thought of that first!
我想你应该还没试过 I suppose you never had a first time?
有没有得到你爸爸的同意啊 did you ask your dad's permission?
那不是我 This isn't about me.
我讨厌这样 I'm sick of it.
别装蒜了我讨厌你痛哭流涕的样子 Stop this playacting! I'm sick of you sniveling!
我忍不住哭 I can't help crying.
好 那别哭出声音 Well, cry in silence, then.
妈妈 Mom.
停车吧 我觉得好难受 Stop the car, please. I feel sick.
看看这母狗 Look at the bitch.
她很自以为是 闭嘴 She's pleased with herself! - Shut up.
我讨厌她 I hate her.
我想她死 I wish she'd die.
我不管 我会和她一起死 I don't care. I'll die with her.
对你自己说 Speak for yourself.
我不想死 I don't want to die.
别冒这个险 No danger of that.
阎罗王还不想见你 You're not in the dead man's seat.
关掉它吧好恐怖 Turn that down! it's horrible!
我在开车需要有人陪我 I'm driving. I need to keep myself company.
人都是猪 People are pigs.
典型的法国人 Typical French.
我们够羞耻的了 We have enough to be ashamed of.
你又开始吃了啊 You're eating again?
妈妈 这太恐怖了 Mom, that's terrible!
看谁在说话啊 Look who's talking!
我累死了 I'm worn out.
我要睡一会 I need to sleep a bit.
我要尿尿 I have to pee.
你以为她会把一切都告诉爸爸 You think she told dad everything
那他就要检查我了 and that he'll have me examined?
我不知道 I don't know.
他们认为这是他们的事 真讨厌 It's sick that people think it's their business.
做处女真麻烦 It's sick being a virgin.
我怕了 I'm scared.
他真是个畜生 He's a real bastard
让我以为我们订婚了 to have made me think we were getting engaged.
还用他妈妈的戒指 And with his mother's ring, too.
别想了 Stop thinking about it.
睡吧 Go to sleep.
我不能不想啊 I can't stop thinking about it.
他是第一个 He was the first.
还有很多其他的呢 There'll be plenty of others.
你不要这么难过 You won't give them such a hard time now.
可能但是我不能不想他 Maybe, but I can't stop thinking about him.
睡吧他早忘记你了 Go to sleep. He's already forgotten you.
你这母狗 You bitch.
我只是对你说实话 I'm just being honest with you.
你感觉好点了吧 You deserve better.
睡觉吧 Now go to sleep.
关好门 Lock your door.
你不会伤害我吧 You're not going to hurt me?
闭嘴 Shut up!
她在树林中 她说他没有强奸她 She was in the woods. She says he didn't rape her.
如果你不想 就别相信我 Don't believe me If you don't want to.