Come on, get up.
You need to buy gifts for your kids
before we leave.
I'll pick up something at the airport.
No way.
Airport gifts suck.
Marie, please let me sleep
another half hour.
Fine.
If you won't buy the gifts
for your kids, I will.
Can you ask the front desk
to prepare the bill...
...and have some breakfast sent up?
You know what?
The posters are up, all over Paris.
Apparently, you can't miss them.
How many have you seen?
Really?
They said there would be
120 across Paris.
Can you sum up the headlines for me?
I won't have time to go online.
That's good.
Big kisses, bye-bye.
I feel bad. I should've stayed on
to cover the story.
After what happened to you?
They've sent a crew
from the Hong Kong office.
I've never done that...
...run away from such a story.
-You okay?
-Yeah.
-Should I come up?
-No, I'll be fine.
I almost forgot...
...the gifts for your kids.
I love you.
The estimated figures are
at several billion dollars.
But of course, we're going to talk
about the survivors...
...because we hope there are survivors.
The number of victims is estimated
at several hundred thousand.
It is a horrific scene here,
as this tsunami...
...has devastated the population.
Good evening, everyone.
Marie, can you hear me?
Everybody, break a leg.
Ready and on the air in...
...five, four...
...three, two...
...and cue, Miss Lelay.
Good evening,
and welcome to a new edition...
...of Window on Events.
Tonight, our guest is
Guillaume Belcher...
...CEO of famous
clothing manufacturer Soucil.
We're going to present to you
a shocking investigation...
...on child labor in their factories
in Southeast Asia.
Cyril Guignard reporting.
Here in the West, it's easy to criticize
Third World labor practices.
But the truth is...
...these factories...
...play a vital role in
industrial development...
...and evolution of poorer countries.
And let's be clear about this,
the wages we are paying...
...are substantially higher
than local wages.
Marie, go at him!
Marie, do you hear me?
Pull this guy apart!
You hear me, get him!
But will this kind of justification satisfy
French customers...
...Mr. Belcher?
If they were aware of the conditions
under which the clothes are produced...
...do you think you would
still be profitable?
Go there and you'll see how much
these people need us.
Thank you for watching.
That's all for now, see you next week.
I'm sorry, that was unforgivable.
We'll fix it in the edit. No one will notice.
And it was my fault.
A defensive CEO was a tough start
for the new season.
Do you want to get something to eat?
I'll see you tomorrow.
I think something happened
to me out there.
You had a close call.
No, something really happened to me.
When I went underwater...
...I had visions.
I don't know.
You had a concussion.
You hit your head.
You're right.
Two right-wing newspapers claim Sikhs
were out in the streets...
...burning cars, looting shops.
Others say the unrest was triggered by
elements within the nationalist parties...
...10 cast negative suspicion
on racial minorities.
What do you think about
the story on the Sikhs?
What?
The story on the Sikhs,
what do you think?
It's very good.
Listen, I've got to work late
and finish some things.
See you tomorrow.
Can I say something...
...you might find difficult to hear?
I think you came back to work too soon.
Physically, you're fine.
But since the accident...
Take some time off
to get over what happened.
Just a couple of weeks.
N
To "get over"?
You've always said you wanted to write.
Your book idea, Michel would jump on it
and pay good money.
But that would take time.
This will all be here waiting for you.
What matters is that you feel better.
We need you too much.
I'll think about it.
Summing up France's postwar history,
only two statesmen counted:
De Gaulle and him.
On DE Gaulle, everything's been written.
On Mitterrand, I want to finish the job.
There are fascinating elements.
The abolition of the death penalty,
the European Union.
Coming from a right-wing family,
he seduced the left.
And what's more,
converted it to liberalism.
Amazing! It was a revolution, right?
Plus the darker sides of his character
that have never been explored.
He's been dead for 10 years.
The timing is right, we can dig deeper.
I want to dig into his past.
Vichy, the Elf scandal...
What part did he play?
The Taiwan frigates,
the Papon scandal...
...Mazarine, Marguerite Duras.
These stories were never really addressed.
They've all been buried.
I'm going to tell who knew,
who didn't talk.
Isn't that going to bring us
too much controversy?
I don't think so.
What I want is a book
that can be read by all.
Mitterrand was not just a politician.
Mitterrand was an icon.
He's "Tonton," our uncle!
Maybe that's what we should use
as the title!
Tonton.
I'm not sure we can keep that title.
Of course not. It was a joke.
I'll welcome your suggestions
for the title.
How about Chipping Away at the Myth
or The Vacillating Statue?
I look forward to your suggestions.
We'll make a list.
Congratulations.
The timing couldn't be better.
Politically, there's nothing going on
now anyway.
You'll write the book you've always
wanted to. You'll get some rest.
Come this summer,
you'll be back on the air...
...with a bestseller under your belt,
and a big renegotiated contract.
Stronger than ever.
Exactly.
Adapting and turning misfortune
to your advantage.
That's what I've always loved about you,
never a victim.
That's right.
Never a victim, never vulnerable,
never complains.
Excuse me. Your table is ready.
Great. I'm starving.
Can I ask you something?
What do you think happens
when we die?
That's a strange question!
Tell me.
When you die, you die.
The lights go out, that's it.
Why?
That's it? Just blackout?
Totally black, the plug's pulled out.
The eternal void.
Don't you think it's possible
that there is something?
Like what?
I don't know, something...
A hereafter.
No, I don't.
If that were the case, wouldn't someone
have discovered it by now?
And there would be proof.
I guess.
Do you have a lot of questions like that?
More champagne?
Good evening.
Following a joint statement by Vivendi
and electricity giant VFM...
...announcing higher than expected
quarterly profits...
...we wonder if evoking France's economic
downturn might be premature?
Sorry, we are running a little late.
Come in.
Everyone is upset by the events.
Sit down.
Marie, to be honest with you,
I'm a bit confused.
I thought we commissioned a book
about Francois Mitterrand.
Instead, you give us
the first three chapters of...
...Hereafter:
The Conspiracy of Silence.
I realize it's not
what you were expecting.
You always said there weren't
enough surprises in publishing.
Well, this is certainly a surprise!
I don't know where to begin.
Did you at least find it interesting?
Of course.
You've always had a nose for a good story.
But we're a political publisher--
This is political!
This kind of material, however fascinating,
is for a specialized market.
This morning, in London, six bombs
went off in the heart of the city.
Apparently coordinated, the bombs
exploded at the height of the rush hour.
Why are you all against this?
Why are you so afraid of this?
This is real!
This is scientific evidence...
...from well-known researchers
forced to work in secret.
A Nobel Prize winner, hounded
by the religious lobby. That's a story!
Better than a philandering,
dishonest old politician.
But a book like that would probably
have to be written in English...
...for the American market.
It happened to me, Michel.
I saw it with my own eyes.
Where we're going.
What we'll experience.
Each and every one of us.
That doesn't interest you?
Now listen, we commissioned a book
about Francois Mitterrand.
Either we agree on this
and you start writing it...
...or else I want my money back.
That's all I can say.
It was so humiliating.
They looked at me as if I'd lost my mind.
Six months ago they begged me
to write about anything.
Anything by the great Marie Lelay.
You'd better give me my job back.
I've had enough with being humiliated.
Today, they even took down my posters.
Why didn't you tell me?
And your book?
I'll finish it in my spare time.
It's caused me enough trouble as it is.
What's the matter?
Look...
...getting your job back...
...might not be as easy as you think.
Why?
It was a temporary break.
And on your advice.
I know, but--
What we couldn't have foreseen is...
...you'd be talking in public
about these experiences.
-That you'd lose your credibility.
-But I didn't want to write this book!
It was your idea!
It was my idea you should write
about Mitterrand.
So, what are you saying?
I'm saying take some more time.
Finish the book, get it out
of your system, then come back.
It's that girl, isn't it?
My replacement?
I've watched her a few times.
She's good.
Yes, she is.
But not as good as you.
You're sleeping with her?
How can you say such a thing?
You always told me to ask
the tough questions.
It's funny...
Who'd have thought it?
A few months ago I was famous.
Rich.
A success story.
I was happy.
Fulfilled by my work.
By you.
All this happened because
you didn't buy your kids their gifts.
Because of what?
What are you talking about?
I don't understand.
Forget it. It doesn't matter.
It's Michel.
Listen...
I feel terrible about our meeting
earlier today.
This book is obviously
very important to you.
I think everyone was a bit on edge
because of the events in London.
But I made a few calls. There are
two publishers who might be interested.
One American, one English.
Do you have a pen?
I'm listening.