Don't worry, it's a pack of woIves.
Come on, we're aImost rid of it.
-CaIeb, it's after me!
-Grab on!
Run! Run!
No, Benjamin, we have to finish this.
Come on, heIp me bury it.
What if someone digs it up?
May God have mercy on his souI.
-Hi, AIan.
-Hi, M ss Magruder.
-Afternoon, AIan.
-Hey, Frank.
-A yours, AIan.
-Thanks, BiIl.
Get him!
Prepare to d e, Parrish!
Parrish, what's the rush?
He's going to the factory!
He's going to daddy now.
Go on, Parrish! Run to Daddy.
We'II be waiting.
Hi, CarI.
Hey, AIan, my man. I gotta
show you something. Come here.
I've been working on this
for aImost a year.
I got an appointment
with your father...
...to show him this.
Go ahead, take it.
What do you think?
Th nk he'lI ike it?
What is it?
What is it? This is the future.
If WiIt Chamberain w wear them...
...there' be a pair of those
in every coset in America.
That wiII be the height of fashion.
What's wrong?
-Nothing.
-Aan!
Thanks, Bob.
What are you doing? This factory
isn't a pIayground. It's dangerous.
Dad, can I have a ride home?
Oh, AIan.
Is BiIIy Jessup
picking on you aga n?
Son, you're gonna have
to face him sooner or Iater.
If you're afraid of someth ng,
you've got to stand and face it.
Now, run on, son.
You know better than
to Iet the boy pIay here.
Sorry, s r.
-What was it you wanted to show me?
-Just a minute, sir.
What the deviI--?
Who did this ?
Well?
I d d, sir.
Being a Parrish doesn't mean
you can hang around with my girIfriend.
We're just friends.
Not anymore.
Get him!
I've got his bike!
Jerks!
Neat.
AIan?
Are you home?
AIan, not aga n. Come on.
Hard work, determination,
cheerfuI outIook...
...attributes that have exemp ified
the Brantford spirt...
...since our forefathers
f rst sett ed this town.
Despite the harshness of our native
cI me and the granite of our soiI...
...we have....
-Prospered.
-I knew it aI this morning.
You'II know t aII tonight.
-Right. Let's go.
-Sam, we have to taIk to AIan.
WeII, we're on our way.
Okay.
I toId your father what you toId me,
that it wasn't just BiIIy Jessup.
-If I'd known that, I wou dn't have--
-It's okay, Dad.
But I'm proud of you. You faced them,
even though you were outnumbered.
Since you took it Iike a man,
your mother and I have decided...
...that you're ready to go
to The CIiffside Schoo for Boys.
CongratuIations, sweetheart.
You don't want me I ving here
anymore?
AIan.
It's aIways been the pIan
that you go to CIiffside.
I mean, Parrishes have been going
to CIiffside ever s nce the 1 700s.
Even your UncIe SkyIar went there.
Look at this. Parrish HaII?
It's the main dorm tory.
This is great. Kids are on my case
here because I'm a Parrish.
Just wait ti I I'm Iiving
in a buiId ng named after me.
It was named after my father.
Good. Why don't you Iive n t?
I did. I wou dn't be who I am
if t weren't for my years there.
Maybe I don't want to be
who you are.
Maybe I don't even want
to be a Parrish.
You won't be.
Not tiII you start acting Iike one.
-Sam--
-Get your coat.
I guess I'm not ready
for CIiffside, then.
We're taking you there next Sunday.
I don't want to hear another word!
You won't!
I'm never taIk ng to you again!
-Sam....
-Don't .
-Sam.
-What?
Nothing.
What are you doing here?
I brought your bike.
You d dn't have to. I was going
to BiIIy's to get t myseIf.
I toId BiIIy to stop picking on you.
You wasted your breath.
We' taIk about t some other time.
What was that?
-You heard it too?
-Of course I heard it.
Come on, I found this reaIIy
weird game in the factory.
A game?
''Jumanji.
A game for those who seek to find
a way to Ieave their worId behind.
You roII the dice to move your token.
DoubIes gets another turn.
The first to reach the end w ns."
You want to pIay?
I quit pIaying board games
five years ago.
Sarah!
It's gotta be magnet zed
or something.
AIan, Iook.
"At night they fIy,
you better run.
These w nged things
are not much fun.''
What was that?
I don't know.
-Put it away, AIan.
-Okay.
Oh, no.
The game thinks I roIIed.
What do you mean,
"the game thinks"?
''ln the jungIe you must wait...
...untiI the dice read five or eight."
In the jungIe you must wait?
What does that mean?
Sarah!
RoII the dice!
A bed-and-breakfast is just
what this town needs.
It was pretty hard to pass up.
EspeciaI y fuII of furniture.
Oh, boy.
I keep forgetting
how big this pIace is.
Judy, Peter, come Iook at this.
I'm gonna put a recept on area
right over here.
And a bar over here in the parIor.
That sounds oveIy.
I'm sure you and your k ds
w I be very happy here.
WeII....
ActuaIIy, they're my Iate brother's.
He and h s wfe passed away
just Iast w nter.
Is this something, or what?
It sure is.
What do you think?
Is t big enough for you?
Peter hasn't spoken a word
since it happened.
Oh, my. I'm so sorry.
How terribIy awfu .
It's okay.
We bareIy even knew our parents.
They were aIways away.
Skiing n St. Moritz,
gambIing in Monte CarIo...
...safariing n darkest Africa.
We didn't even know
if they Ioved us.
But when the she k's yacht
went down...
...they managed to write
a beautifuI goodbye note...
...that was found f oating in a
champagne bottIe amongst the debris.
Excuse me.
They were very devoted parents.
It was a car crash in Canada.
-You'II send me the escrow papers?
-F rst thing tomorrow.
I'II have to get
a ocksmith for this one.
Peter, pick up your toys, pIease.
Peter, take this suitcase
up to the attic.
Then we can aII have ice cream.
And bourbon.
What? What is it?
I'm go ng to MoteI 6.
Oh, for heaven's sake.
I don't see any guano.
He said it Iooked Iike that.
That's an African bat. Some kid said
she saw some back in the 60s...
...but we don't get bats
Iike that in New EngIand.
That's what he saw.
WeII, whatever it was, t's gone now.
Bats aren't what I'd worry about
in th s house, anyways.
What wouId you worry about?
WeII, personaIIy...
...I wouIdn't want to Iive
where someone was murdered.
-Murdered?
-Yep.
LittIe AIan Parrish.
I say his father did it.
There's 1001 pIaces he couId've
h d the body in this house.
EspeciaIIy if he chopped t up first.
Hey up there!
You don't want to be Iate
for your first day of schooI.
-Not a bat in sight, ma'am.
-Hear that?
There's nothing to be afraid of
in th s house.
I can't be ieve I have to see
your pr ncipa after your first day.
What am I gonna do?
Let's try to reIax and finish dinner.
TaIk about something eIse.
We know why you got
the house cheap.
Twenty-six years ago, a kid
named AIan Parrish Iived here.
One day he just disappeared.
His parents chopped him up
and hid him in the waIIs.
That's it. I'm sick and tired
of your Iies. You're grounded.
Fine, there's nowhere to go
in this stupid town anyway.
Just for your information,
that wasn't a Iie.
Did you hear anything?
Do you m ss Mom and Dad?
No.
Liar.
Cut that out,
or they'II send you to a shrink.
Where are they gonna send you
if you don't start taIking?
If I get heId up
at the permit office, I'lI caII.
The schooI bus wiII be here
any minute.
You guys st have your keys?
You guys Iistening to me?
He o?
What?
Maybe I shou d wa t
ti the bus comes.
Did your parents
used to put you on the bus?
No.
Are you sure?
I cou d drop you off.
No, don't worry about us.
The bus w be here any minute.
Okay. PIease be good today.
You do hear it.
Hear what ?
Where's it coming from?
Let's bring it over here.
Weird. They're stuck.
"Jumanji, a game for those
who seek to find...
...a way to Ieave their worIds behind.
RoII the d ce to move your token.
DoubIes get another turn.
The first pIayer
to reach the end wins."
It's gotta be microch ps
or something.
You go first.
Okay.
Six.
''A tiny bite can make you itch,
make you sneeze, make you twitch."
Don't!
''This wiII not be an easy mission.
Monkeys sIow the expedition."
What is that?
I bet those monkeys came
from the game.
The mosquitoes too.
I didn't see th s part.
"Adventurers, beware."
''Adventurers, beware. Do not beg n
unIess you intend to finish.
The consequences of the game vanish
when a pIayer has reached Jumanji...
...and caIIed out its name.''
-The monkeys are gone.
-Good.
-Put it away.
-Wait!
If we fin sh the game,
it'II aII go away.
Let's do it, or Aunt Nora'lI pitch a fit.
We shou d get through t quickIy.
I mean, there's no skiII invoIved.
No, you roIIed doubIes.
You get another turn. RoII.
Five.
"His fangs are sharp.
He Iikes your taste.
Your party better move posthaste.''
I don't Iike the sound of that.
Someone's in here.
It's not reaI, Peter.
It's a haIIucination.
Run, Peter!
I'm back.
My b ke.
Somebody roII a five or an e ght?
He did.
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
Thank you.
Sorry if I scared you.
I'm back!
Mom! Dad!
I'm home!
I'm back!
It's me!
It's me, AIan, Mom and Dad!
I'm home! I'm back!
Are you my IittIe sister?
No, I'm Judy and he's Peter.
Where's Mom?
Is Dad at the factory?
Are you...
...AIan Parrish?
Yeah. Who are you?
We I ve here now.
Where's my mom and dad?
We don't know.
This house has been empty
for years.
Everyone thought you were dead.
Sorry.
-Give me that description again.
-Rad fur and tail.
Get down off of my car, pIease,
and get up on the sidewaIk.
-What year is it?
-It was brand-new.
-No. What year is it?
-1895, remember?
Ninety-f ve....
You got some ID? Let me guess,
it's n your other Tarzan outfit.
-Twenty-six years.
-Are you from around here?
I was. But I've been n Jumanji.
Indones a.
He was in the Peace Corps.
-CarI BentIey, the soIe man.
-Is th s man reIated to you?
-Yes, he's our unc e.
-Does he a ways dress Iike that?
Yeah, he's a vegetarian.
Get out of there!
Monkeys. Monkeys.
Is he aII right upstairs?
He suffered a head njury
a few months ago.
Don't you move!
-Stop!
-Don't move, don't move.
Wait! Where are you going?
To find my parents!
Come on.
Wait!
My dad used to make shoes here.
They were the best shoes
in New EngIand.
Hey!
Sorry.
Easy, girI.
Do you know what happened
to the shoe factory?
Yeah, it fo ded up.
Like everything eIse in this town.
It's pretty co d out there.
How about some coffee?
Why wouId they cIose
Parrish Shoes?
When his kid ran away, Sam put
everything he had into find ng him.
His time, his money....
Everything.
After a whiIe,
he stopped coming to work.
He just quit caring.
I don't think anybody Ioved his boy
more than Sam did.
Here.
You're gonna freeze out there.
Thank you.
Are the Parrishes stiII around?
-I see them now and then.
-Yeah?
They're over on Adams Street.
Our parents are dead too.
They were in the MiddIe East
negotiating peace when--
Our dad was in advertising.
I bet you m ss him, huh?
Me too.
There he goes again.
I know you're upset,
but we shouId fin sh the game.
We? Why do you need me?
Just in case any other
scary stuff comes out.
PIus there's a Iion
in my aunt's room.
Do I Iook ike a RingIing Brother?
She'II be home soon.
Won't she be surprised?
I hope she's not aIIergic to cats.
Larry, we need the wheeIs.
G ve me a hand.
-Did we h t her hard?
-No, it Iooks Iike another weird bite.
-Yeah, it's another one.
-Jesus, over 50. What's going on?
Easy now, easy.
-Isn't that Mrs. Thomas?
-Who's that?
-The rea tor.
-Quiet.
L sten.
You hear that?
Hear what ?
Get in the car.
Okay, think. What came out
of the game before me?
There was a Iion,
a bunch of monkeys and....
That!
It's okay, it's okay.
It's just a bug. We're safe in here.
We're fine.
If we stay Iow,
he can't get through there too far.
Don't you worry. We're fine.
He can't get through the gIass.
We're safe.
Do you know how to drive?
No? That's no prob em.
My dad used to Iet me back
the car down the driveway.
Once.
So, what's the big deaI?
-BuckIe up.
-Here we go!
Wait a minute. What? Wait.
AIan, the top!
Piece of cake.
Yeah.
AIan.
Keep that thing away from me!
When are you gonna heIp us pIay?
Our aunt wiII be home soon.
Good. You can inform her that
she's the ex-owner of this house.
I hope you reaI ze with my parents
gone, this home beIongs to me.
Oh, thank you.
No more banana Ieaves.
Yes.
What do you think those monkeys
wiII do to the ecosystem?
He o?
What happened to you?
Did you shave with a piece of gIass?
Did the CIampetts have a yard sa e?
I've never shaved before.
Where are you going?
How about Peter and I pIay,
and you just sort of watch?
Thanks, I've seen it.
If you won't heIp us,
what are you gonna do?
I don't know.
Pretty much take up where I Ieft off.
I wonder f Mrs. Niedermeyer's
stiII teaching sixth grade.
Come on, he's not gonna he p us.
He's afraid.
What did you say?
You're afraid.
It's okay to be afraid.
Let's set it up in the Iiving room.
You have no idea
what you're gett ng yourseIf into.
Whatever it is, we can handIe it.
We don't need your heIp.
I don't th nk so.
You think monkeys, mosquitoes
and Iions are bad?
That's just the beginning.
I've seen th ngs you've onIy
seen in your nightmares.
Things you can't even imagine.
Things you can't even see.
There are things that
hunt you in the n ght.
Then something screams.
Then you hear them eating.
And you hope to God
that you're not dessert.
Afraid?
You don't even know what afraid is.
You wiII not Iast
five minutes without me.
So you're gonna heIp us?
I'II watch...
...but I'm not afra d.
Peter, that was very cooI.
It's reverse psychoIogy.
Dad used to puII it on me aII the time.
Ready?
Yeah.
AIan, ready?
There s no ''ready.''
I'II try it aga n.
AIan, it's not working.
Oh, no.
It's not your turn.
I roIIed first. Then Peter twice
because he got doubIes.
Now it's my turn.
No, Iook.
Two of the pieces are yours, right?
Who's the other pieces?
The eIephant was mine.
You're pIaying the game
I started in 1969.
I'm gonna have to pIay.
It's not my turn.
Whose turn ls it ?
Sarah WhittIe.
This is where she used to Iive.
This pIace gives me the creeps.
We used to pIay on this porch.
I knew she st wouIdn't ive here.
ProbabIy married B Iy Jessup.
-Come on.
-Let's at Ieast ask.
-Maybe she' know where Sarah went.
-She'lI know. She's a psychic.
Good point.
I remember the porch
being a Iot bigger.
He o?
-Can you heIp us?
-Do you have an appointment?
-No, we're trying to find someone.
-Madam Serena can't see anyone now.
Maybe you can he p us.
What is it?
We're Iooking for someone
who used to Iive here.
No, I've I ved here my whoIe Iife.
Then you must know Sarah WhittIe.
What do you want
w th Sarah Whitt e?
Sarah?
I don't go by that name anymore.
Sarah WhittIe?
What do you want?
Twenty-six years ago, you pIayed a
game with a IittIe boy down the street.
A game with drums.
How do you know that?
I was that Iitt e boy, Sarah.
AIan?
You kiIIed her.
Leave a message
and the doctor wlll call you back...
...at his aarllest convanlenca.
Dr. Boorste n, it's Sarah Wh ttIe.
PIease caII me as soon as you can.
I think I need
to have my dosage checked.
That event we've been discussing,
the one that didn't reaIIy happen?
I'm having an episode here w th
the boy who didn't reaIIy d sappear.
I'm sitting in his Iiving room,
drinking emonade.
If you cou d caII me, I'd reaIIy
be interested n your interpretation.
-He'II caII me back.
-WhiIe we're waiting....
-God! No, no, no!
-Sarah.
-Oh, no, no, no.
-It's okay. Sarah.
I've spent 2000 hours n therapy
convinc ng myseIf that doesn't ex st.
What happened to you was
so awfu , I made up this thing--
It was awfuI. It was awfuI.
It reaIIy was.
But it was reaI. ReaI.
No, t wasn't reaI. Your father
murdered you and chopped you up.
Sarah, come on.
My dad did that?
My father couId bareIy hug me...
...Iet aIone cut me nto IittIe pieces.
Twenty-six years ago,
we started pIaying a IittIe game.
And now...
...we're a I gonna sit down
and we're gonna finish it.
And guess what?
It's your turn.
No.
Here.
PIay the game.
-Oh, no, no.
-F ne.
Just give me the dice and you can
go home. You don't have to pIay.
Thank you, AIan.
Oh, my God!
How couId you do that?
It's the Iaw of the jungIe.
You'lI get used to it.
When think of the energy I spent
visuaIizing you as a radiant spirit--
Go on, read it.
"They grow much faster
than bamboo.
Take care or they'lI come after you."
Oh, great.
Oh, God.
TeII me this isn't happening.
It s. Stay away from the wa Is.
Don't touch anything.
No quick movements.
-They're beautifuI.
-Yeah, they're beautifuI.
Don't touch the purpIe ones.
They shoot po sonous barbs.
And defin teIy stay away from
the pods. The big yeIIow ones.
What big yeIIow ones?
Peter!
I got you! Get his arms!
Get it off me! Get it off me!
Oh, my God!
Hang on.
Got him? I'lI be rght back.
Oh, my God.
Sorry, Angus.
Harvest time!
Are you okay?
Peter.
Oh, my God!
My car. Oh, my car.
Carl, come ln, pleasa.
Coma ln please, Carl.
Has anybody seen--?
I can't beIieve this.
Start, start, pIease. Yes.
-CarI? Come ln, Carl.
-CarI here.
Where have you baen?
We've got an anlmaI-control situation.
Get Stan and W y on it.
I've gotta check out a suspicious
character at the Parrish pIace.
I shouId've been a fireman.
Yeah.
Sarah!
Get your hands off me!
-The game is not over yet.
-It is for me.
You are not in the jungIe anymore.
Stop this! You don't
treat peopIe Iike this.
Okay.
Anybody up for iced tea?
I'm gonna make some tea.
PIease, Iast time I pIayed this game
it ruined my I fe.
-It ruined your Iife?
-Yes.
''In the jungIe you must wait
tiII the dice read five or eight."
I was a I ttIe girI, AIan.
You d sappeared.
And a bunch of bats surrounded me
and chased me down the street.
I was afraid.
I'm sorry, AIan.
No one beIieved me. I was aIone.
So was I, for 26 years, Sarah.
Me too.
It's okay, Sarah. We're scared too.
But if we finish the game,
it'lI aII go away.
What f I get stuck in the game?
You won't.
Because I won't stop pIaying.
And neither wiII I.
I won't either.
Come on, Sarah.
PIease?
I knew this was gonna be a bad day.
Come on, we'lI be fine.
We just have to keep our heads.
And roII with the punches.
"Ahunterfrom tle darkest wild . .
...makes you feeI just I ke a ch Id."
What is it?
Van PeIt.
You miserabIe coward!
Come back and face me Iike a man.
Not good enough, Sonny Jim.
Coming, ready or not.
Hey, you!
Drop your gun
and get your hands in the a r!
Man, I don't beIieve this.
Even if AIan gets out
of this situation...
... t'II happen over and over again.
When you carry repressed anger,
it attracts a Iot of negat ve energy.
Things happen, ike ending up
in the jungIe. That was no accident.
There are no accidents.
Whose turn ls it ?
-It's my turn.
-ReaIIy? Great.
You m ght've toId us
there was a man who hunts peopIe.
I didn't know.
It's just the ro of the d ce.
Is he the reason
you didn't want to pIay?
You d dn't want to pIay, either?
Mr. We-Started-26-Years-Ago-
and-Now-We-Gotta-Finish-It?
What's with this guy?
He's a hunter. He kiIIs things.
Right now, he wants to kiII me.
-Why you?
-Why me?
I don't know. You'd think
it'd be a waste of his time.
Maybe he needs something
for his waII.
It's your turn.
Have you ever taIked with him
about your d fferences?
-Are you crazy? The man has a gun--
-Don't ever caII me crazy. Ever.
Everyone's caI ed me crazy ever since
I said you were sucked into a game.
-Maybe I shouId roII.
-Yeah.
I was the g rI
who saw you murdered.
Did anyone come
to my birthday party?
-HeIIo, I'm roII ng now.
-B y who?
Are you an owI? Come on, Madam
Serena, dig into your consciousness.
-Here, just roI .
-Find the memory...
...of your oId boyfrend.
-The kid who'd stea your bicycIe?
-The kid who took you to the movies.
"Don't be fooIed, it sn't thunder.
Staying put wou d be a bIunder."
-You're immature.
-You are.
-I know you are, but what am ?
Do you feeI that?
Run!
It's a stampede!
Come on.
The game!
Don't Iook back!
Not the game!
Why d dn't you grab the game,
Peter?
Ignore him. He's a L bra.
-Where are you going?
-He'lI head for water!
Here we go. Come on.
-HeIIo?
-lt's Aunt Nora.
Whera have you bean?
I'm sorry, dear.
You have the wrong number.
Wait for me!
-What can I do for you?
-I'II have a gross of these.
They stopped mak ng these in 1803.
Damn. Then I shaII need
a repIacement weapon.
There's a waiting period.
And you'lI have to fiII out these.
Or I couId fi I these out.
Louise.
Now, anyone asks,
you didn't get this here.
You're not a postaI worker, are you?
AIan!
Qu et.
Here.
No!
-Peter!
-Peter, are you okay?
-That was great.
I can't beIieve you did that.
That was so cooI.
-You gave me chiIIs.
-It was great.
AIan.
Nice work. Come on,
give me the game. Let's go.
Oh, no.
Act naturaI.
Hey!
Hide the game.
Every t me there's troub e,
I run into you.
I don't know
what you're taIking about.
-I'm taking you n.
-I'm not going anywhere.
AII right.
Just a second.
You can't take him, he's--
-Her f ance.
-You said he's your uncIe.
It's aII right. I'lI be back soon.
BIast.
You sa d you'd never
abandon your friends.
-We'lI finish the game Iater.
-Later?
Van Pe t. Van PeIt.
I suggest you aII go home now.
Okay.
Now how are we supposed
to f nish the game?
We can't.
We can't finish it without h m.
Judy.
What?
What happened?
I thought I couId end the game.
I was onIy 10 spaces away.
"A Iaw of Jumanji,
having been broken...
...you wiII s ip back
even more than your token."
You tried to cheat?
No, I tried to drop the dice
so they Ianded on 12.
Okay, honey.
WeII, that wouId be cheating.
Peter, your hands!
Look at your hands!
Coma ln, this ls Wllly.
They cleaned out Larry's Hardware.
l can't stop them.
Gat the National Guard down hara.
What is this about?
I know you know.
Yes, I do. But you wouIdn't
beI eve me even f I toId you, CarI.
Wait a minute.
How do you know my name is CarI?
I know a Iot more than that.
You used to work at Parrish Shoes.
They used to caII you "SoIe Man."
SoIe Man, that's right.
I was in there too...
...tiII oId man Parrish f red me.
-He fired you?
-Yeah, man.
And I had something that couId've
turned this whoIe town around.
-Your shoes.
-Right.
Listen, CarI?
I know it doesn't mean much
after 26 years...
...but I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Sorry for what?
It's me. AIan.
Thank you.
What's going on?
WeII, apparentIy
there's a saIe, honey.
You saw three monkeys
on a motorcyc e, didn't you?
-Yes.
-Good girI.
Maybe we can baiI him out
w th a check.
Thank you.
TeII that sniveIing coward
f he wants--
Boy!
Get out of my way!
-Give me that, boy!
-No!
Hey!
-Peter!
-HeIp me!
Get me out of here!
-It's aII right.
-Oh, my God, Peter.
AII right.
There it is.
Wait here.
Gotcha, girIie.
No.
When AIan hears of your predicament,
he'lI come.
He doesn't know I'm here.
It won't work. Your pIan's ruined.
-Move and I'II bIow your bra ns out!
-Okay.
CaII the cops!
-That shouId do the trck.
-Oh, yeah.
Prce check!
If you Iet me go, I can stop a this.
It's Iike The Twilight Zone,
but it's true.
PIease, you gotta heIp me on this.
I know I'm gonna regret this.
Just hoId stiII.
-Okay.
-There, I Iet you go.
Now what are we gonna do?
-You're staying here.
-My keys!
It's for your own good.
-My handcuff keys!
-I have to do this!
-Aan!
-You'lI thank me someday.
Carl, code red.
Hostage situatlon at Sir Sav-a-lot.
A woman and two chlldran.
lt sounds llke the armed perpetrator
in the pith halmet.
Carl? Come ln, Carl.
-Lorra ne?
-What's Sir Sav-a-Iot?
-It's a discount store.
-Move over.
-Wait. GentIy, gentIy.
-A rght, aII right.
Don't worry, I've done this before.
Once.
Where's SirSav-a-lot?
-Monroe and EIm.
-The EpiscopaI church.
Not anymore.
Now it's a Speedy Burger.
At Ieast it was. I don't know
what's Ieft. PeopIe are going Ioopy.
Judy!
We got company.
It's aII right. He'II back us up.
-Here's the game.
-Get out of here.
Rats.
-Turn the siren off. Right there!
-Okay, I got it.
Stop cringing,
I cou d have shot you at any moment.
Why didn't you?
You d dn't roII the dice, AIan d d.
There t is, there it is.
H t the brakes!
-Hit the brakes!
-I'm hitting it. I'm h tting the brakes!
-I'm hitting the brakes!
He'II be here.
Sarah!
-Are you aII rght?
-Yes.
-Where's Peter?
-I'm here.
Oh, great.
So remambar, clrcumstances are
never, ever out of your control.
End of tapa three.
Update on the extraordlnary events
in Brantford, New Hampshire.
Ninety-eight people have been
hospitallzed with symptoms...
...ranging from inexpllcabIe fevers
and rashes to salzuras.
Local resources are strained
to tha braaking polnt.
And state offlcials are now asking
those with such symptoms to dlal 91 1.
I got it.
AIan, taIk to him, pIease?
What? We don't have time
for this, okay?
I know, but he's a k d
and he was trying to heIp.
-A rght, come on.
-Thank you.
Judy, come on.
I warned you about this, Peter.
No, you wanted to pIay the game.
What, are you crying?
You don't cry, you keep your chin up.
Come on, keep your chin up.
Crying never heIped
anybody do anything.
If you have a probIem,
you face it I ke a man.
Hey. Hey.
I'm sorry. Twenty-six years
buried n the deepest jungIe...
...and I stiII became my father.
It's okay. Come here, I'm sorry.
Hey, it's aII right.
It's aI rght to be afraid.
It's not that.
What is it?
Okay.
Ready?
Don't worry, we'I have you back
to your oId seIf in no time fIat.
Because we' go n here together,
sit down and finish that game.
No matter...
...what.
Sudden y, I fee right at home.
Lorraine, th s is CarI.
I'm heading over to the Parrish pIace.
G ve me some backup.
Lorraine?
Wait! Wait!
Now what?
Stop!
Wait! Stop!
Is there a probIem?
-Can I have a ride home?
-Where do you Iive?
Jefferson Street.
The oId Parrish pIace.
Do you have chiIdren?
A boy and a girI?
-What happened?
-Get in.
I'II expIain it aII on the way.
Fine! Take it!
We gotta get to that house.
-ShouIdn't we pIay somep ace eIse?
-No.
I grew up in this.
It's out there that scares me.
-Okay, it's my turn.
-Sarah, if you roII a 12, you w n.
Okay, ready? Here I go.
It's okay.
''Every month at the quarter moon,
there' be a monsoon...
... n your Iagoon.'' Monsoon.
At Ieast we're inside.
Yeah, right.
We , a IittIe rain
never hurt anybody.
But a Iot can kiII you.
Come on!
This way!
-What do we do now?
-We get to higher ground.
-Okay.
-Come on! Stay together!
You okay?
-Judy!
-AIan?
-What?
-What is that?
Swim! Look out! Look out!
-Aan!
-Swim! Go! Move!
Keep going!
Stay on the tab e!
Feet out ofthe waterl
On the chandeIier!
Come on, Sarah.
Peter!
Hang on, Sarah!
Are you okay?
Where--.?
-AIan!
Judy? Peter!
Step back and Iet me
hand e th s, pIease.
It's nothing.
They probabIy eft the TV on too Ioud.
Peter? Judy?
I aIways wanted to do this.
CouId you step back, pIease?
-Aan, give me your hand!
-Aan!
-Grab my hand!
-I got it.
AIan!
Take the game.
Here you go.
-You okay?
-Yeah.
AIan, you wrestIed
an aI gator for me.
It was a crocodiIe.
AIIigators don't have
that fringe on their hind Ieg.
Come on.
My mistake.
It's okay.
Come on.
Okay, it's my turn.
I've got it.
CoIoneI Mustard in the Iibrary
with the wrench.
CIue.
Okay.
''Beware the ground
on which you stand.
The f oor is quicker than the sand."
AIan!
-Okay.
-Sarah.
-HeIp me.
-Okay. Stay caIm.
Don't struggIe. Stay ca m.
-I'm ca m.
-AIan!
-Grab on!
-PuII!
Okay. I got it. PuII!
Stay ca m!
Come on!
Oh, good!
I got you--
Stop giving me things
that come apart!
''There is a Iesson....''
AII right.
''T here is Iesson you w I Iearn.''
I got you.
"Sometimes you must
go back a turn."
-Did I hurt you?
-Oh, no.
Oh, dear.
Thank you, Judy. Thank you.
That was very quick thinking.
Sarah and I wou d I ke
to get out of the fIoor.
It's your turn, Peter.
Okay.
I thought I'd ost you aga n.
Thanks for sticking around this time.
"Need a hand? Why, you just wait.
We' heIp you out.
We each have eight."
What'stlat?  what ls it ?
-Nothing.
-You don't go...for nothing.
Peter, my dad kept an ax
in the woodshed. Go get it!
-Okay.
-Hurry! Go, go, go!
Sarah!
Judy?
Peter?
Aunt Nora, it's me. Peter.
Sorry. I can't ta k right now.
I'lI expIa n Iater.
-Sarah.
-What?
It's your turn.
You can finish if you ro seven.
-I can't ro I.
-Put the dice in your mouth.
Br ng the game. Hurry!
Judy!
Are you okay?
I'm f ne. HeIp them.
Come on, Judy.
-Judy!
-Judy.
Give me the d ce.
''You're aImost there
with much at stake.
But now the ground
beg ns to quake."
Judy!
-Oh, my God!
-What? What?
I w sh Mom and Dad were here.
So do I.
Her onIy chance s
if we fin sh the game!
It's your turn!
Oh, my God!
Get the game!
I won't et you go!
AIan!
Don't move.
Stand up.
What's in your hand?
Drop it.
End of the Iine, Sonny Jim.
Game's up. Start running.
No.
Aren't you afraid?
I'm terrified.
But my father to d me...
...you shouId aIways face
what you're afra d of.
Good ad.
You're finaIIy acting Iike a man.
Any Iast words?
Jumanji.
It's Jumanji.
No, AIan, no!
What--?
I forgot my speech notes.
Dad, I'm so g ad you're back.
I've on y been gone five minutes.
It seems Iike a Iot Ionger to me.
I thought you were never
going to taIk to me again.
Whatever I said, Dad, I'm sorry.
Look, AIan, I was angry.
I'm sorry too, son.
Look, you don't have to go
to CI ffside if you don't want to.
Let's taIk it over tomorrow.
Man-to-man.
How about father to son?
Great.
I've gotta get go ng.
I'm the guest of honor.
Dad?
Back in 196--
I mean, today in the factory...
... t wasn't CarI BentIey's fauIt.
I put the shoe on the conveyer beIt.
I'm gIad you toId me, son.
Thanks.
Bye, Dad.
Goodbye.
-HoIy smokes! Judy and Peter!
-Aan.
They're not there.
It's 1969.
They don't even exist yet.
I'm forgetting what
it's Iike to be a grownup.
That's okay, as Iong as
we don't forget each other.
Or Judy and Peter.
There's something
I've been want ng to do.
I better do it before
I fee too much Iike a kid.
They probabIy don't teach driver
training in the sixth grade, huh?
Merry Christmas.
Do you want these?
Dad, the new cross-trainer's
doing fabuIous.
No, t's not a bra, it's a shoe.
Honey, they're here.
Dad, I gotta run.
We'lI pick you up tomorrow, okay?
You'lI be the best Chrstmas gift
of aII. Bye-bye!
-They're here? Come on, Iet's go.
-Yeah. Okay.
Lisa, hi.
Pardon me.
Jim! GIad you couId make it.
-Thanks. This is my wife, Martha.
-Hi. This is Sarah.
-Hi, Sarah.
-Where are the kids?
Oh, my God, there they are.
How'd you know?
A guess, of course.
They're your kids.
Right, these are our chiIdren.
Judy and Peter. Say hi
to Mr. and Mrs. Parrish.
Nice to meet you.
You're just Iike we remembered you.
I fee Iike we know
so much about them.
Because, you know--
-You've toId AIan about them.
-And I to d her.
-I'II get the presents.
-Sure, honey.
WeII, we Iove chiIdren.
-Merry Christmas.
-CooI.
When can you start?
We were going to take a ski ng hoIiday
up n the Canadian Rockies.
No!
Sorry.
We just....
Need you to get that marketing
done on the new Iine, pronto.
No probIem. I couId start next week.
Great. Let me introduce you
to the foIks you'lI be work ng with.
Come on in. Our house was
your house. Is. Anytime you'd Iike.
What's that noise?