ADULT ADAM: Ah,
the phones of the '80s,
kitschy, colorful
and enormous.
And my dad hated
all of them.
Especially when he couldn't
get through to the house.
A busy signal?
Oh, what kind of
Chatty Charlie
is hogging the line?
Piece of crap
garbage children!
If you met them,
you'd know!
ADULT ADAM: But then we got
the cutting-edge tech
that would end
the busy signal forever...
Call waiting.
I love you more
than the Cookie Monster
loves cookies.
Whoa, (CHUCKLES)
that's a lot.
(LINE BEEPS)
Is that your call waiting?
Let me get rid of them.
Goldbergs.
And if this is for Barry,
he's instructed me to say
"Wassup, girl."
I've been calling
for ten minutes!
Didn't you hear the beep?
Oh, sorry, Dad.
Put your mom on.
Who knew there was more
than one kind of onion?
Mom, Dad's calling,
but make it fast
'cause I'm talking to Brea!
Just a sec,
Schmoopie Poops.
I'm adding some flavor
to my Swedish meatballs.
Dad, it's gonna be a while.
Let me get back to Brea.
No, no, no, don't you
do the click over.
Ooh, my finger's already
in motion.
Sorry, my love.
My dumb dad
was on the line.
It's still me, moron!
Whoops.
Brea?
Hey.
Where'd he go?
(BEEPING)
RECORDING: Please
deposit ten cents.
Fine! I'm gonna get
every onion there is!
I will take away
everything and everyone
you love forever!
Too much club,
sweetie.
Well, then, fine!
I'll throw your bedroom
into the ocean!
Moving closer,
but still a miss.
All right, I will remove
all of your precious phones!
Mom, talk to
your husband.
We need phones.
What if there's
a medical emergency?
There will be
if you don't move
out of my way!
Dad!
Okay, Murray,
there's too much slack.
** I'm twisted up inside
** But nonetheless
I feel the need to say
** I don't know the future
** But the past keeps getting
clearer every day **
ADULT ADAM: It was
November 18th, 1980-something,
and the Jenkintown Posse
was back in action.
Your lives
may begin again!
Your magnetic and
voluptuous leader
has returned!
JTP!
TOGETHER: JTP!
Hmm, the place
seems different.
Where's all the
sadness and stench
of a litter box
even though
there's no cat?
Oh, Erica's been helping them
spruce the place up.
Mostly, it's just cleaning.
Did you know that
there was a fireplace
behind the gum wall?
Okay, emergency
JTP announcements.
One, I am now single
and free to hang
around the clock.
Two, turn
this place back
into the filthy
hell I love.
Dude, they can't
live in a dump.
They have
girlfriends now.
Oh, please!
These loveless,
unlovable dummies
don't have love
in their love-
deprived lives.
But we do.
I met Beth
when she came
in The Gap
looking for
a fitted cable
knit sweater,
and she left
with my heart.
"Dear Penthouse letters,
"I have a story
you'll never use."
My special lady is Gwen.
Her purity ring says no,
but her anger at her father
says yes.
Gwen sounds like
a poor man's Beth.
I've recently begun
a dalliance with Laura.
She embraces
my nudist lifestyle
but asks that I put a towel
down on her couch.
Sounds like you guys got
a pretty good poker hand:
three fives.
Now let's go to the Wawa
and play some classic
JTP smash ball.
Is that where you smash
fruit with swords
and tennis racquets,
and the guy who works there
spends hours hosing it down?
Erica knows her sports.
Ah, we're gonna need
a rain check, man.
We have a quadruple date
at Bennigan's.
Our ladies like to day drink
in a funky atmosphere.
But article nine
of the JTP bylaws
states that all
members must
heed the wishes
of its most jacked
leader. Me.
I don't remember
signing off on that one.
That's because
it was just added.
The JTP Constitution
is a living document.
Yeah, these rules
seem to change
based on
your arbitrary whims.
Naked Rob gets it.
Now let's grab a weapon
and smash some stuff.
I call whatever this is!
Ooh, that's our decorative
river cane.
Let's...
Let's leave that be.
Now I'm angrier than Gwen
at her father.
Damn it! I learned her name.
Let's move!
ADULT ADAM: While Barry
forced the JTP to hang,
I was without a phone
and forced to connect
with Brea
the old-fashioned way...
Pen and paper.
"Brea, my light,
my heart..."
"...is laid bare
before you.
"I give you all of me,
"and in return
I require nothing
"but to see your smile,
"more glorious
than any sunrise."
ADULT ADAM: Okay,
Shakespeare we were not,
but these were
sweet nothings
shared between
just the two of us.
"My dearest sweet Adam..."
"...you are my sun
and my moon."
ADULT ADAM:
And apparently my mom.
"Until our lips meet again,
I am lost.
"I can't wait until we are
eternally bonded in marriage.
"Man and wife."
Oh, no!
(BLEEP) no!
Murray, turn off
your best friend!
We got a problem!
Is that the electric bill?
Because I told
those kids,
"Hey, you don't open
that refrigerator
"until you know
what you want!"
It's Adam and Brea's
love letters.
They're discussing
marriage!
They've only known
each other like a week.
They've been dating
for over a year.
She came to Miami
with us.
Ah! I know
who you're talking about.
Big girl, like six feet,
blonde hair, 200 pounds,
big wine-stain birthmark
on her face.
No! And who is that?
They're already tossing around
names for their children.
They want to name
their son Cameron.
My first instinct
is to do nothing.
I'm gonna go with that.
You're not shocked
by any of this?
Nah. My first girlfriend?
I told her
I would die for her.
We broke up a week later.
Just found out she died.
Nobody cares about
your old, dead trollops.
I'm worried about Adam.
My point is, young couples
say all sorts of dumb stuff.
Well, what if this
isn't just stuff?
This girl could be
our future daughter-in-law.
We barely know her.
We know her. Big girl
with the Gorbachev thing
on her face.
That's very specific.
Who are you thinking of?
I don't know.
But why are we on the hook
for all this?
Call up her parents
and let them destroy
young hearts.
That's a great idea,
Murray.
Except we don't have
a phone to call them!
So go down the street
and use the pay phone
like I do
to order calzones.
Why am I the only one
with good ideas?
ADULT ADAM: As my mom
thought of ways to reach out
to Brea's parents,
the JTP were returning
to their roots.
(CHEERING)
They sliced stuff.
Pina colada!
They crushed stuff.
ALL: Ohh!
Told ya!
Then they blew stuff up.
Whoo!
(LAUGHS)
That was bananas!
Firecrackers and wordplay!
This is the best!
Well. this seems like
a natural stopping point.
I gotta boogie.
You know how Erica
gets when I'm tardy.
Yeah, I should go too.
Same.
Me too.
But I have a long list
of other fun things
to destroy.
We love you, bud,
but our lovely ladies
are waiting for us.
Well, I'm afraid
you've given me
no choice
but to order you to break up
with your girlfriends.
(CHUCKLES)
You can't do that.
Oh, but I can.
Tell Linda, Essie
and Ginzy it's over.
Those aren't their names,
and we're not gonna do that.
We like them a lot.
More than me,
your best friend?
Well...
It's not the same.
Their hugs
are different.
Oh, get over here!
There's not a lady alive
I can't out-hug.
Bar, if anyone
should understand why
we wanna spend time
with our girlfriends,
it's you.
Yeah, you totally
disappeared
when you were dating
Ren and Lainey.
Hmm. This all
makes sense now.
As long as you have love
in your life,
you won't ever
have time for me.
Awesome.
Your tone is ominous,
but I'm glad
we could figure this out.
Oh, it's figured.
It's figured but good.
Hey, get back here
and clean this up!
ADULT ADAM: While Barry
cooked up a surprise
for the JTP,
I got a surprise visit
from my girlfriend's mom.
Hey, Adam.
Mrs. Bee?
What are you doing here
in my home
where my dubious family
resides?
You okay? You seem
a little startled to see me.
Oh, not too startled,
I hope.
(CHUCKLES)
Adam tends to get
a leaky fuel line
under the smallest
amount of pressure.
What?
We're talking
oil and gas.
Mom! It was one
Fourth of July!
I see. Uh, your mom
invited me over
to get to know each other,
and I already feel like
I know too much.
Excuse us for a sec.
Why is my girlfriend's
mom here?
Well, you've been dating
a long time,
and you are
her sun and moon.
You read my letters!
Those are private!
You should know that nothing
in this house is private.
That's why I took the doors
off the bathrooms.
You said the handyman
was painting them.
And to be clear:
no grandson of mine
is gonna be named Cameron.
We're also
considering Joshua.
I've already got
your kids' names picked out.
The boys will be Eli,
Jacob and Samuel.
And the twins will be named
Sasha and Lily.
Five kids?
Don't worry.
I'll be there the whole time
to help out.
MURRAY: I'm home!
Doesn't mean it's the start
of a conversation.
Dad! Put your pants
back on!
Vicki Bee is here!
The principal?
No, Murray,
I'm Brea's mom.
It's nice
to finally meet you.
I'm sorry. I wish
somebody would've called
and let me know
I'd be uncomfortable
in my own home.
We would have except Murray
got rid of all the phones.
Because this moron
was constantly
tying up the line,
talking to
his moron girlfriend!
Whose mom
is right here!
Great, we're
practically family.
Off they go.
ADULT ADAM: Yeah,
Mrs. Bee in my house
was bound to be bad.
But then the craziest thing
happened.
She and my mom
became fast friends.
I probably shouldn't
admit this but...
I took a teeny peek at one of
Adam and Brea's love letters.
I read 'em all.
Me too.
It was a little upsetting.
So tell me,
how do we pull the reins
on their stupid,
misguided, teenage love?
Maybe we talk to them
as adults?
Ooh, I got one.
We trick them into thinking
that marriage
is a faulty,
loveless institution
that yields no permanent joy
or happiness.
Oh, I've already
done that.
Oh?
Brea's dad and I
went through a nasty split.
Wasdatnow?
Yeah, we're divorced.
ADULT ADAM: Yep,
back in the day,
people were uncomfortable
with the "D" word.
Oh. Wow.
My mom was definitely
one of them.
Truthfully, it ended up
being the best thing
for everyone.
With that, my mom realized
Mrs. Bee's past
might affect my future.
So she did this.
Murray,
we've got to break up
Adam and Brea!
Damn right!
That lady's
way too old for him.
ADULT ADAM: My mom
was upset over the news
of Vicki's divorce,
and my dad wasn't helping.
So this doesn't
bother you?
She's divorced,
big deal.
So you don't care
about Adam
splitting with Brea
and only seeing his children
half the time?
So help me, if she takes those
little munchkins out of state,
I will kidnap them!
So you think Brea
will divorce Adam
just because her mom
is divorced?
Yes. Children repeat
the mistakes of their parents.
We have to stop Adam.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
Stop me from doing what?
Oh, baby, sit down.
We have some
upsetting news
about Brea.
Brea's mother, Vicki...
(WHISPERING)
...is divorced.
What are you saying?
(WHISPERING) Divorced.
Still can't hear you.
Dee. Vorced.
The Force?
From Star Wars?
(WHISPERING) Divorced.
What are you saying?
Divorced!
The woman is divorced!
Oh. Yeah, I know.
(IN NORMAL VOICE)
That harpy told you about
her broken marriage?
No, I kinda figured it out
when her dad lived
in a different house.
Without his family?
Is he ever not smiling?
Adam, let me tell you a story.
No. I don't wanna hear
how your aunt's handyman's
mom got divorced
and now she's living
in a giant soup can.
It was my manicurist's
roof guy
who lost so much
in his split
that they turned
his water off
and he had to bathe
in a lake.
Snapping turtles
took his toes, lips
and a nice chunk
of one buttock,
and now he's got to sit
crotch down.
None of that happened
to any person.
I only bring this up
because you and Brea
have been discussing
your futures,
and I don't think
that she has
the best role models.
And what do I have?
No boundaries
and no bottoms.
The kid's pretty clever.
When's he gonna
get a girlfriend?
Adam, you need to
listen to me!
Divorce is
no laughing matter!
I don't want you to be
one of those sad sacks
who has to go on dates
in his thirties!
In his thirties!
Stop!
Divorce isn't
some horrible thing!
Just because Brea's mom is
doesn't mean
it's inevitable for us.
Okay, so you're not
gonna listen to me.
Maybe you'll listen to one
of your esteemed heroes.
You think these bozos
are my heroes?
It's the best
I could do.
Thank you for agreeing
to speak with us.
We didn't agree.
This is a hostage situation.
Well, while we're
waiting for help,
let's find out more
about you people.
I'd prefer to keep
my private life private.
Oh, not me.
I talked about my gout
on a sports call-in show
this morning.
What do you want to know?
Dale, are you
currently married?
Nope, split
as the pea soup
I eat alone
in my bachelors-only building.
Your divorce
must have been difficult.
Actually,
it was the best.
What?
Yup. I was finally free
from the lies
about why our carpenter
was always wearing
my bathrobe
or coming with
me and Gretchen
on vacation.
Ignore him.
Ball, you're
a tragic divorcee, right?
Happily married
for thirty glorious years.
But you always seem
so bald and miserable.
This going how you thought
it was gonna go?
Fine. Surely you have
tragic tales of dating.
Au contraire.
The pool of unattached
older gals is deep.
Desperate, widowed bitties
want attention,
and I'm just the young buck
to give it to 'em.
Enough. No one cares
if Brea's mom is divorced.
Brea Bee's hot mom
is on the market?
Tell her I have
most of my original teeth.
Well, excuse me
for wanting
to protect you.
Protect him from what?
He's never gonna do better
than Brea Bee. Ever.
I mean, ever.
PRINCIPAL BALL:
It's true.
We spend hours
in the teachers' lounge
trying to figure out
how he landed her
in the first place.
My guess is she got hit
on the head
and it damaged
the part of her brain
that processes odd shapes.
This is starting
to feel personal.
It is. Ha!
ADULT ADAM: While my mom's
plan to break up
me and Brea broke down,
Barry was planning
a few breakups of his own,
one JTP member at a time.
Good afternoon,
it's Matt Bradley.
(HIGH-PITCHED VOICE)
Hi, Matt Bradley,
it's your girlfriend.
Beth?
You sound weird.
You sound weird!
Which is one of the reasons
why I'm breaking up with you.
Don't look for answers.
Bye!
(DIAL TONE)
One down...
(NORMAL VOICE)
Three to go.
ADULT ADAM: Yep,
he used every trick
in the breakup book,
like the Dear John letter.
"Dear Rob, it's over.
"Sincerely,
Naked Rob's girlfriend.
"Don't look for answers."
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
ADULT ADAM: The intimidating
home-wrecker.
Andy Cogan?
Yeah?
I'm your romantic rival,
and I have easily claimed
your girlfriend.
What? But you're
a turtlenecked child!
A turtlenecked child with
a fresh twenty in his pocket!
What?
Don't look for answers.
ADULT ADAM: And for Geoff,
he straight-up lied.
Oh, hey, Barry.
What's up?
Terrible news.
I just talked to my sister.
She said she doesn't
want to see you again.
Oh, my God! What?
Don't look for answers.
While Barry's lies
stunned the JTP,
my mom was about to face
a very angry Mrs. Bee.
Vicki! To what
do I owe this...
Cut the crap, Beverly.
Did you tell Dale Woodburn
that I was single
and ready to swingle?
(SCOFFS)
Not in those words.
He just called and asked me
to be his date
to his cousin's
sobriety anniversary.
Meeting the family!
Wow, you move fast!
I'm not going anywhere
with him!
Only one side
of his body sweats.
That's called
Harlequin syndrome.
It's a real
nervous disorder.
And I would think
you'd be more sympathetic
given your situation.
My situation?
Meaning I'm divorced?
Something you're clearly
not comfortable with.
I have no issue, zero,
with the fact that you are
(WHISPERING) divorced.
Then why can't you say it?
Please! (CHUCKLES)
Give me a soap box
and a megaphone!
You are
(WHISPERING) divorced.
Here's something I have
no problem saying:
you're crazy.
Your whole family
is crazy!
How dare you?
That is something
that you whisper!
Why? The whole world
should know.
Your husband
doesn't wear pants.
And?
And he threw out
all your phones.
And?
And you dragged
your son to school
to scare him with
the marital woes
of the faculty!
That's a good one.
(DOOR OPENS)
Mom?
What's going on?
Uh, what's going on
is we're leaving.
But... But...
Let's go!
(SIGHS)
What. Did. You. Do?
Nothing! (SCOFFS)
She called our family crazy
for some reason.
For all the reasons!
It's well established
you're a mentally
deranged crackpot!
Schmoo, don't be upset.
I'm just looking out
for your best interests.
Best interests?
I thought
you read my letters.
Brea is my everything.
No one who
really cared about me
would try to
take that away.
ADULT ADAM: While my mom
was divorced from reality,
Barry was ready to hang
with the newly-single JTP.
There they are.
I heard the news
about all four
of your lovers
leaving you
simultaneously.
But fear not,
I've come bearing gifts.
Yeah, Bar, how exactly
did you hear
about our girlfriends
dumping us?
You know,
the campus grapevine.
General scuttlebutt.
While I do like to gab,
I think of myself
as a listener.
Check it.
Used road flares, huh?
Dude, our ladies
didn't actually
break up with us.
Denial. People don't want
to hear the truth,
but it's best to accept it
and move on.
Cheggit:
Look Who's Talking.
It's a baby who's talking,
that's who.
Nice try, dumbass.
This is low
even for you.
Geoff, you took this strumpet
back after what she did?
Barry, I didn't
cheat on him!
Oh, don't play her games!
She knows what she did!
Barry, we know you're behind
this and we can prove it.
Sorry, Barry.
Even though this guy
wears sandals,
he's quick
like a rabbit.
I want my 20 dollars back.
Long gone, muchacho.
Like me.
Enjoy whatever this is.
Fine! You got me.
Another Barry prank
for the ages.
First we laugh, now we make up
over Hawaiian pizza.
No, thanks.
This time you went
too far, man.
Only because I wanted
to hang out with you guys.
And watch the romantic
ups and downs of a new mom
as seen through
the cynical eye
of a talking baby.
Why would
we want to hang out
with someone
who'd try to hurt us?
(SCOFFS)
We're gonna go be
with our ladies.
See ya around,
Big Tasty.
Come on.
Geoff, come on.
Wait!
ADULT ADAM: Barry's attempts
to free the JTP
from the bonds
of their girlfriends
had been fruitless.
The same could not be said
about the Wawa parking lot.
Uch. That tastes
nothing like Sprite.
Thought I'd find ya here.
You playin' some smash ball?
I tried, but I have
no one to play with,
so I'm just
eating the fruit.
Yeah, I see you munching
on that lime there.
How's that treating you?
Not so good.
Neither are
the three grapefruits,
basket of blackberries,
six mushy plums,
half a mango,
and something called
a jackfruit.
I'm starting to think
the seeds weren't edible.
Oh, no! Barry, that is
way too much fruit!
No, I deserve
the terrible gas,
bloating,
and pins-and-needles
feeling in my feet.
I'm a terrible friend.
I mean, it wasn't great.
Why can't you just
be happy for them?
I am.
I love those guys.
It's just they've
always been there
when I needed them.
And for the first time
they're not.
That's not true.
Bar, haven't I always
been there for you?
Yeah.
Look, you can still
be a good friend
while being
in a relationship.
What's the secret?
No secret.
You just got to
work hard at both.
And always make sure
no one forgets
how much they mean to you.
Are you saying
I should go to them?
They're on
a group date right now
at the mini golf course.
So maybe it can wait till...
I will go to them!
Thank you, Geoff.
ADULT ADAM: And so
Barry ran to his friends.
But my mom couldn't run
from how I really felt
about my girlfriend.
Whatcha doing?
Torturing myself.
Adam writes that
he will never love anyone
as much as he loves Brea.
You think he means it?
Yeah, right now
he does, sure.
Well, if he and Brea are in it
for the long haul,
we've got
some awkward holidays ahead.
I offended Vicki Bee.
Well, just call her
and apologize.
How? We have no phone.
I missed having
something to slam.
Thanks.
(HEAD OVER HEELS
BY THE GO-GO'S PLAYS)
But this is probably something
I should do in person.
ADULT ADAM: Sometimes
we get so caught up
in what's best
for the people we love,
we do crazy things.
Listen!
I need to say something,
but not to you guys.
To them,
the girlfriends.
Yeah, Bar...
You three
may not know it,
but you are
the luckiest ladies
on the planet.
All right? Let me
give you some advice.
Cherish these men
and all that
make them unique.
Like how irate Andy gets
when you use
his tiny back scrubber.
Do you mean
my toothbrush?
Accept them as they are.
Because if you don't...
You'll lose them.
And that's
a terrible feeling.
Um, Barry,
these girls aren't
their girlfriends.
What do you mean?
Okay.
Who remembers
what I just said?
NAKED ROB: We all do.
(LAUGHS)
JTP.
TOGETHER: JTP!
ADULT ADAM: Yeah,
there's lots of different ways
to say you're sorry.
But when it comes
from the heart,
that's all that matters.
Looking for Adam?
You, actually.
I want to apologize
for everything.
I have no right
to judge you.
I'm sorry.
Thanks.
Look, I have a lot of big,
sometimes-stupid ideas
about what
a traditional family
is supposed to be.
But you're a great mom.
You couldn't raise
a girl as amazing
as Brea if you weren't.
Well, Adam's
not too bad himself.
My body made his body.
That's something someone says
to another person.
It's just,
if our kids are gonna be
in each other's lives,
it would be nice
if we could
make it work, too.
For our kids,
we'd both do anything.
Come on in.
ADULT ADAM: That's the thing.
No family is perfect.
But it's our differences
that make us unique.
This makes me nervous.
I'm terrified.
And when you combine
those differences
with a whole lot of love,
it goes a long way.
(CHEERING)
In the end,
that's what strengthens
all the relationships
in our lives,
no matter what,
'cause when you got
people who love and care
and celebrate you,
it's a hole-in-one.
So, I'm here
with the real Brea,
who you saw playing
her own mother.
Is it just weird
to play your own mother?
It's super weird.
You and Adam really did date
in high school.
Did you guys actually
write those letters?
It is true.
We did date
during high school
and we wrote a lot of letters
to each other.
Now, I happen to have
an actual letter right here.
Oh, no.
"I feel like your soul
"and my soul
have become one.
"When I'm not with you,
I feel like I'm dying.
"It's almost like
I need you to live."
I mean,
that's normal, right?
(LAUGHTER)