- Hello, Mrs. MacGruder.
- Hello, Miss Daniels.
Have you ever seen so many gulls?
What do you suppose it is?
There must be a storm at sea.
That can drive them inland, you know.
I was hoping you'd be a little late.
He hasn't arrived yet.
- But you said 3:00.
- I know.
I know. I've been calling all morning.
Oh, Miss Daniels, you have no idea.
They are so difficult to get.
Really, they are.
We have to get them from India
when they're baby chicks, and then...
This one won't be a chick, will he?
Oh, no, certainly not.
This will be a full-grown mynah bird.
- And he'll talk?
- Well, yes, of course he'll...
Well, no, you'll have to teach him to talk.
I guess maybe I'd better phone.
They said 3:00.
Maybe it's the traffic. I'll call.
- Would you mind waiting?
- Well, maybe you'd better deliver him.
Let me give you my address.
Oh, well, all right,
but I'm sure they're on the way.
Would you mind if I called?
No. All right.
- I wonder if you could help me.
- What?
I said, I wonder if you could help me.
Yes. What is it you're looking for, sir?
Lovebirds
- Lovebirds, sir?
- Yes.
I understand there are different varieties.
- Is that true?
- Well, yes, there are.
Well, these are for my
sister for her birthday,
and as she's only gonna be 11,
I wouldn't want a pair of birds...
that were... too demonstrative.
- I understand completely.
- At the same time,...
I wouldn't want them to be too aloof.
No, of course not.
Do you happen to have a pair of
birds that are... just friendly?
Oh, I think so. Now, then, let me see.
Aren't those lovebirds?
No. Those are, uh... red birds.
I thought they were strawberry finches.
Yes. We call them that too.
Here we are. Lovebirds.
Those are canaries.
Doesn't this make you feel awful?
Doesn't what make me feel...
Having all these poor, innocent ...
...creatures caged up like this?
- Well, we can't just let them
fly around the shop.
- I suppose not.
Is there an ornithological reason
for keeping them in separate cages?
Certainly. It's to protect the species.
Yes, that's important,
especially during the molting season.
That's a particularly dangerous time.
- Are they molting now?
- Oh, some of them are.
How can you tell?
Well, they... get a
sort of hangdog expression.
Yes, I see. Well,
what about the lovebirds?
Are you sure you wouldn't
like to see a canary instead?
- We have some very nice
canaries this week.
- All right.
All right. May I see it, please?
Oh! Oh!
What is it? Oh! Oh!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Oh! Oh!
There we are.
Oh, there. Wonderful.
Back in your gilded cage, Melanie Daniels.
What did you say?
I was merely drawing a parallel,
Miss Daniels.
- How did you know my name?
- A little birdie told me.
Good day, Miss Daniels. Madam.
Hey, wait a minute. I don't know you.
- Ah, but I know you.
- How?
We met in court.
We never met in court or anyplace else.
- That's true. I'll rephrase it.
I saw you in court.
- When?
Don't you remember one of your practical...
...jokes that resulted in
the smashing of a window?
- I didn't break that window.
- Yes, but your little prank did.
The judge should've put you behind bars.
What are you, a policeman ?
I merely believe in the law.
And I'm not too keen on practical jokers.
What do you call your lovebird story...
I really wanted the lovebirds
You knew I didn't work here.
You deliberately...
I recognized you when I came in.
I thought you might like to know
what it's like to be
on the other end of a gag.
- What do you think of that?
- I think you're a louse.
I am. Good day, Miss Daniels. Madam.
And I'm glad you didn't get your lovebirds.
I'll find something else. See you in court.
- Who was that man?
- I have no idea.
They said the mynah bird would be here
later this afternoon,
if you care to come back.
- No, you'd better send him.
May I use this phone?
- Why, certainly.
Daily News? It's Melanie Daniels.
Could you get me the City Desk?
Just a minute, Mrs. MacGruder.
Hello, Charlie. Melanie.
I want you to do a favor for me.
No, this is a small one.
Pressure you? Why, Charlie,
darling, would I try to pressure you?
Would you call the
Department of Motor Vehicles for me?
Find out who owns this license plate:
W-J-H-0-0-3.
Yes, a California plate.
No. I'll stop off in a little while.
Is Daddy in his office?
No, I don't want to break in on a meeting.
Tell him I'll see him later.
Thank you, Charlie.
Do you have any lovebirds?
Well, no, not in the shop,
but I can order them for you.
- How soon?
- Well... Well, when would you want them?
- Immediately.
- Well, I could probably...
..have them here by tomorrow morning.
- Would that be all right?
- That would be just fine.
- Miss, is that for Mitch Brenner?
- Yes.
- He's not home.
- That's all right.
He won't be back until Monday...
I mean, if those birds are for him.
- Monday?
- Yes.
I don't think you should leave them in...
- ..the hall, do you?
- Well... Where did he go?
Bodega Bay. He goes there every weekend.
Bodega Bay. Where's that?
Up the coast, about 60 miles north of here.
Sixty mi... Oh!
It's an hour and a half by freeway, or
two hours if you take the Coast Highway.
I'd look after them myself,
but I'm going away too.
I'm awfully sorry.
- Good morning.
- I wonder if you could help me.
- I'll try my best.
- I'm looking for a man
named Mitchell Brenner.
- Yeah.
- Do you know him?
- Where does he live?
- Right here, Bodega Bay.
- Yes, I know, but where?
- Right across the bay there.
Where?
- Now, see where I'm pointing?
- Yes.
See them two big trees across there?
- On the other side of the bay? Yes.
- And the white house?
- Yes.
- That's where the Brenners live.
The Brenners? Mr. And Mrs. Brenner?
- No. Just Lydia and the two kids.
- The two kids?
Yeah, Mitch and the little girl.
Oh, I see. How do I get down there?
You follow the road around the bay,
and that'll take you to their front door.
The front door.
Is there a back road I can take?
- No. That's the only road.
- You see, I want to surprise them.
Oh.
- I don't want them to see me arrive.
- Oh.
It's a surprise, you see.
Well, you could get yourself a boat and
cut right across the bay to their dock.
Where would I get a boat?
Down by the Tides Restaurant.
- Did you ever handle an outboard boat?
- Of course.
- Want me to order one for you?
- Well, thank you.
- What name?
- Daniels.
Okay.
- I wonder if you could tell me...
- Yeah. Hold it a minute, please.
- The little girl's name?
- The little Brenner girl?
- Yes.
- Uh, Alice, I think.
Harry, what's the Brenner girl's name?
- Lois.
- Alice, isn't it?
- No, it's Lois.
- It's Alice.
- Are you sure?
- Well, I'm not positive,
if that's what you mean.
I need her exact name.
Oh, uh... Just hold on
one more minute, please.
In that case, I'll tell you what you do.
Go straight through town till
you see a little hotel on your left.
- Then you turn right there.
Now, you got that?
- Yes.
Near the top of the hill,
you'll see the school, and just beyond,
a little house with a red mailbox.
That's where Annie Hayworth,
the schoolteacher, lives.
- You ask her about the little Brenner girl.
- Well, thank you.
Save yourself a lot of trouble.
Name's Alice for sure.
Can I have the boat in about 20 minutes?
- How much for the phone calls?
- Oh, it's nothing.
Thank you.
- Who is it?
- Me.
Who's "me"?
- Miss Hayworth?
- Yes.
- I'm Melanie Daniels.
I'm sorry to bother you, but...
- Yes?
The man at the post office sent me.
He said you could tell me
the name of the Brenner girl.
Cathy? The one who lives in
the white house across the bay?
That's the one. Cathy Brenner. He
seemed sure it was either Alice or Lois.
Which is why the mail never gets
delivered to the right place in this town.
- I'm sorry. Smoke?
- Thank you.
Did, uh... you want to
see Cathy about something?
Well, not exactly.
Oh.
Are you a friend of Mitch's?
No, not really.
I've been wanting a
cigarette for the last 20 minutes.
I just couldn't convince myself to stop.
This tilling of the soil can become...
- ..compulsive, you know.
- It's a very pretty garden.
Oh, thank you. Well, it's
something to do in your spare time.
There's a lot of
spare time in Bodega Bay.
Are, uh, you planning on staying long?
- No, just a few hours.
- Then you're leaving after you see Cathy.
Well, something like that.
I'm sorry.
I don't mean to sound so mysterious.
Actually, it's none of my business.
Well, I better be on my way.
- Thank you very much.
- Not at all.
- Did you drive up from San
Francisco by the coast road?
- Yes.
- Nice drive.
- It's very beautiful.
Is that where you met Mitch?
Yes.
I guess that's where
everyone meets Mitch.
Now you sound a bit mysterious,
Miss Hayworth.
Do I?
I don't mean to. Actually,
I'm an open book, I'm afraid.
Or, rather, a closed one.
- Oh, pretty. What are they?
- Lovebirds.
I see. Good luck, Miss Daniels.
Thank you. Can I get out this way?
Go right around.
It'll take you back to the main road.
Thank you.
- Do you have a boat for Miss Daniels?
- Yes, ma'am.
It's the one right below.
- Are you all right?
- Yes, I think so.
- What made it do that?
- That's the damnedest thing I ever saw.
It seemed to swoop down at you
deliberately. Oh, you're bleeding too.
Let's take care of that. Okay?
That's a girl.
Come on.
What happened, Mitch?
- Gull hit her.
- A gull?
Oh. Let's try up at the restaurant,
all right?
- Might need a tetanus shot.
- I had a booster before I went abroad
last May.
- What happened?
- Hello, Deke. Young lady cut herself.
- Shall I call a doctor?
- I don't think it's that serious.
- Let's see.
Helen, get some cotton and antiseptic.
Um, you cut yourself outside, miss?
Don't worry, Deke. She did it in a boat.
I had a man trip and
fall in the parking lot
once. Sued me before
I could bat an eyelash.
- I don't think Miss Daniels
is gonna sue anybody.
- Here.
- Well, you're the lawyer.
- Thank you.
- What's that?
- Just some peroxide.
I'll clean out the cut.
So you're a lawyer.
That's right. Of course,
I usually defend people,
but if I were prosecuting...
- Do you practice here?
- Uh-uh, San Francisco.
What are you doing up here?
- What kind of law?
- Criminal.
- Is that why you want to see
everyone behind bars?
- Oh, not everyone.
- Only violators and practical jokers.
- That's right.
- Ow!
- Oh, sorry.
- What are you doing up here?
- Didn't you see the lovebirds?
You mean, you came all this
way to bring me those birds?
To bring your sister those birds.
You said it was her birthday.
- Besides, I was coming up anyway.
- What for?
To see a friend of mine. Careful.
Oh, sorry. Uh... who's your friend?
Annie Hayworth, the schoolteacher.
Annie Hayworth.
Well, small world.
Yes.
How do you know Annie?
We went to school together... college.
Did you? Imagine that.
How long are you staying up here?
The weekend.
Well, I think the bleeding's almost stopped.
Why don't you hold that on...
- So you came up to see Annie, huh?
- Yes.
- I think you came up to see me.
- No,
why would I want to see you of all people?
I don't know, but you
must've gone to a lot of trouble...
to find out who I was and where I lived.
It was no trouble at all.
I simply called my father's newspaper.
Besides, I was coming up anyway.
I've already told you that.
You really like me, huh?
I loathe you. You have no manners.
You're arrogant and conceited.
I wrote you a letter about it,
in fact, but I tore it up.
- What did it say?
- None of your business.
I can't say I like
your seagulls much, either.
- I come all the way up here to...
- You were coming up anyway, remember?
Mitch?
I thought I saw your car.
What are you doing in town?
- I had to acknowledge a delivery.
- A what?
Mother, I'd like you to meet
Melanie Daniels.
Miss Daniels, my mother.
How do you do?
How do you do, Miss Daniels?
Acknowledge a what?
A delivery. Miss Daniels brought
us some birds from San Francisco.
Oh. For Cathy for her birthday.
Where is she?
Across at Brinkmeyer's. Miss Daniels
is staying up here for the weekend.
So I've already
invited her for dinner tonight.
- Well, you did go to the trouble of
bringing those birds.
- Oh, I couldn't possibly.
- You did say birds?
- Yes, lovebirds.
Oh, I see.
So we couldn't let you get away
without thanking you in some small way.
And you haven't met Cathy,
and you are staying the weekend.
- Well, yes, but...
- You are, aren't you?
- Certainly, but...
- Then it's all settled.
- What time is dinner, Mother?
- 7:00, the same as usual.
I'll pick you up. Where are you staying?
With Annie, of course
Oh, of course. How stupid of me.
A quarter of 7:00?
Annie may have made other plans.
I'll have to see.
Besides, I can find my own way.
You're sure now?
You won't hire a boat or anything?
- I'm sure.
- 7:00, then.
Maybe.
We'll be waiting for you.
How's your head?
Much better, thank you.
A gull hit me, Mrs. Brenner, that's all.
- Oh, hi. Did you find her all right?
- Yes, I did.
I was wondering...
Uh, that sign there.
Do you suppose I could have
the room for just a single night?
- I was planning on renting it
for a longer time...
- I would appreciate it.
I've tried everywhere in town.
They're all full.
Well, all right. Got your bags in the car?
Well, it's utilitarian, I'll say that.
I just picked up some things
for the night at the general store.
I hadn't planned on staying very long.
Yes, I know.
Did something unexpected come up?
Yes. May I use your phone?
I'd like to call home.
I just put some coffee on the stove.
Don't they ever stop migrating?
Hi!
- Miss Daniels?
- Yes.
Oh, they're beautiful!
They're just what I wanted.
Is there a man and a woman?
- I can't tell which is which.
- Well, I suppose so.
- Hello there. Annie had no plans, huh?
- No.
We're very glad you could come.
Are you hungry?
- Reasonably.
- Dinner's just about ready.
We've been looking at the chickens.
Something seems to be wrong with them.
There's nothing wrong with those chickens.
- I'm going to call Fred Brinkmeyer
right now.
- What good's that gonna do?
The chickens won't eat.
He sold the feed to me, didn't he?
- Caveat emptor, Mother.
Let the buyer beware.
- Whose side are you on?
- Merely quoting the law, dear.
- Never mind the law.
This won't take long, Miss Dan...
Hello, Fred? Lydia Brenner.
I didn't interrupt your dinner, did I?
- How about a drink?
- I'd love one.
That feed you sold me is no good.
The chicken feed. Well, it's just no good.
The chickens won't eat it.
They're always hungry.
I opened a sack for them when I got home,
and they just wouldn't touch it.
You know chickens as well as I do,
and when they won't eat,
there's something wrong
with what they're being fed.
No, they're not fussy chickens.
Who? What's he got to do with it?
- Is that your father?
- Mm-hmm. Please sit down.
I don't care how many sacks of
feed you sold him. My chicken...
Oh, I see.
Dan Fawcett.
This afternoon? That proves what
I'm saying. The feed you sold us...
Oh.
Well, maybe I better go over and see him.
You don't think there's
something going around, do you?
No, never!
No, they don't seem sick at all.
They just won't eat.
Uh-huh.
Well, I'll try to go
over and see him. Maybe he...
Uh-huh. All right.
Thanks.
He had a call from Dan Fawcett a while ago.
His chickens won't eat either.
It's what you said, Mom.
Mr. Brinkmeyer's feed is no good.
No, Cathy.
He sold Mr. Fawcett a different brand.
You don't think they're
getting sick, do you, Mitch?
I still don't understand how you knew
I wanted lovebirds.
Your brother told me.
Then you knew Mitch in San Francisco?
Is that right?
No, not exactly.
Mitch knows a lot of people
in San Francisco.
Of course, they're mostly hoods.
- Cathy!
- Well, Mom, he's the first to admit it.
He's spends half his day in the
detention cells at the Hall of Justice.
In a democracy, Cathy,
everyone is entitled to a fair trial.
- Your brother's practice...
- Aw, Mom, please!
I know all that democracy jazz.
They're still hoods.
He has a client now who shot
his wife in the head six times.
Six times! Can you imagine it?
I mean, even twice would be overdoing it,
don't you think?
Why did he shoot her?
He was watching a ball game on television
- What?
- His wife changed the channel.
- Are you coming to my party tomorrow?
- I don't think so.
I have to get back to San Francisco.
Don't you like us?
Oh, darling, of course I do.
- Don't you like Bodega Bay?
- I don't know yet.
Mitch likes it very much.
He comes up every weekend, you know,
even though he has his
own apartment in the city.
He says San Francisco's like an
anthill at the foot of a bridge.
I suppose it does get hectic at times.
Well, if you do decide to come,
don't say I told you about it.
It's supposed to be a surprise party.
They've got this whole
complicated thing figured out...
where I'm going to
Michele's for the afternoon,
and Michele's mother will say that
she has a headache,
would I mind if she took me home.
Then when I get home here,
all the kids'll jump out!
Oh, won't you come?
Won't you please come?
I don't think so.
- She's a charming girl,
isn't she, Mitch? Hmm?
- Yes.
- Certainly pretty.
- Mm-hmm.
How long have you known her?
- Now, I told you, dear, we met yesterday
In a bird shop. In a bird shop.
She was selling birds?
No, no. I just led her into believing
that I believed she was, and then...
It's all very complicated. But she did buy
the lovebirds and then
drove all the way here.
- Mother.
- Yes?
Where did you go to law school?
Forgive me.
I suppose I'm just naturally
curious about a girl like that.
She's very rich, isn't she?
Yeah, I suppose so. Her father's
part owner of one of the big newspapers.
You'd think he could manage
to keep her name out of print.
- She's always mentioned in the columns,
Mitch.
- Yes, I know.
She is the one who jumped into a
fountain in Rome last summer, isn't she?
Yes.
I supposed I'm old-fashioned. I know it
was supposed to be very warm there, but...
- Well, actually the newspapers
said she was naked.
- Yes, I know, dear.
It's none of my business,
but when you bring a girl like that...
- Darling?
- Yes?
I think I can handle
Melanie Daniels by myself.
Well... as long as you
know what you want, Mitch.
I know exactly what I want.
- Be able to find your
way back all right?
- Oh, yes.
- Will I be seeing you again?
- San Francisco's a long way from here.
I'm in San Francisco five days a
week with a lot of time on my hands.
I'd like to see you.
Maybe we could go swimming or something.
Mother tells me you like to swim.
- How does Mother know what I like to do?
- We read the same gossip column.
- Oh, that... Rome.
- I really like to swim.
We might get along very well.
In case you're interested, I was pushed...
- ..into that fountain.
- Without any clothes on?
With all my clothes on.
The newspaper that ran that story...
happens to be a rival of my father's paper.
You were just a poor, innocent victim of circumstances?
I'm neither poor nor innocent.
- The truth of that particular...
- The truth is,
you're running around
with a pretty wild crowd.
Yes, that's the truth, but I was pushed
into that fountain,
and that's the truth too.
Uh-huh.
Do you really know Annie Hayworth?
No. At least I didn't
until I came up here.
- So you didn't go to school together?
- No.
- And you didn't come here to see her?
- No!
- You were lying!
- Yes, I was lying.
- What about the letter you wrote me?
Is that a lie?
- No, I wrote the letter.
- Well, what did it say?
- It said, "Dear Mr. Brenner.
I think you need these lovebirds after
all. They may help your personality."
- That's what it said.
- But you tore it up?
- Yes.
- Why?
Because it seemed stupid and foolish.
- Like jumping into a fountain in Rome.
- I told you what happened!
You don't expect me to believe that,
do you?
I don't give a damn what you believe!
- I'd still like to see you.
- Why?
I think it might be fun.
That might've been good enough in Rome,
but it's not good enough now.
- It is for me.
- Well, not for me.
- What do you want?
- I thought you knew.
I want to go through life...
jumping into fountains naked.
Good night.
- Miss Daniels, is that you?
- Yes.
Hi.
Is something wrong?
Is that cut beginning to bother you?
No, it's not the
cut that's bothering me.
- Would you like some brandy?
- If you have some, I'd love it.
I'll get it. Why don't you sit down.
Oh, would you like a
sweater or something, a quilt?
No. No, thank you.
Won't you call me Melanie?
All right.
- Thank you.
- Gets a bit chilly here
at night sometimes,
especially if you're over near the bay.
Well, how did your evening go?
Did you meet Lydia?
Or would you rather
I changed the subject?
I think so.
Well, how do you like our little hamlet?
I despise it
I suppose it doesn't offer
much to the casual visitor,
unless you're thrilled by a
collection of shacks on a hillside.
It takes a bit of getting used to.
- Where are you from originally?
- San Francisco.
How did you happen to come up here?
A friend invited me up
for a weekend a long time ago.
Look, I see no reason
for being coy about this.
- It was Mitch Brenner.
I guess you knew that anyway.
- I suspected as much.
Well, you needn't worry.
It's been over and
done with a long time ago.
- Annie, there's nothing between
Mr. Brenner and me.
- Isn't there?
Well, maybe there isn't.
Maybe there's never been
anything between Mitch and any girl.
What do you mean?
I think I'll have some of that.
I was seeing a lot
of him in San Francisco.
One weekend,
he invited me up to meet Lydia.
When was this?
Oh, four years ago,
shortly after his father died
- Of course, things may be different now.
- Different?
With Lydia.
- Did she seem a trifle distant?
- Mm, a trifle.
Well, then perhaps things
aren't quite so different.
You know,
her attitude nearly drove me crazy.
When I got back to San Francisco,
I spent days trying to figure out...
what I'd done to displease her.
- Well, what had you done?
- Nothing.
I simply existed. So what's the answer?
A jealous woman, right?
A clinging, possessive mother?
Wrong. With all due respect to
Oedipus, I don't think that was the case.
Then what was it?
Lydia liked me. That's the strange part.
Now that I'm no longer a threat,
we're very good friends.
- Then why did she object to you?
- Because she was afraid.
- Afraid you'd take Mitch?
- Afraid I'd give Mitch.
I don't understand.
Afraid of any woman who would give Mitch
the one thing Lydia can give him: Love.
That adds up to a jealous,
possessive woman.
No, I don't think so.
You see, she's not afraid of losing Mitch.
She's only afraid of being abandoned.
Someone ought to tell her
she'd be gaining a daughter.
No. She already has a daughter.
Well, what about Mitch?
Didn't he have anything to say about this?
Well, I can understand his position.
He'd just been through a lot
with Lydia after his father died.
He didn't want to risk
going through it all again.
Oh, I see
So it ended. Not right then, of course.
We went back to San Francisco, saw each
other now and then,
but we both knew it was over.
Then what are you
doing here in Bodega Bay?
I wanted to be near Mitch
Oh, it was over and done with,
and I knew it, but...
I still wanted to be near him.
I still like him a hell of a lot,
and I don't want to
lose that friendship... ever.
Hello.
No, no, no, I wasn't asleep.
Yes, just a little while ago.
Sure. Hold on.
It's Mitch.
For you.
Hello? Oh, yes, this is Melanie.
Fine, thank you.
No, no trouble at all.
I simply followed the road.
Well... There's no need to apologize.
I can understand...
That's very kind of you.
No, I'm not angry.
Well, I couldn't.
I have to get back to San Francisco.
No, I wouldn't want to
disappoint Cathy, but...
I see.
All right. Yes, I'll be there.
Good night, Mitch.
He wants me to go to Cathy's party
tomorrow afternoon. I said I would.
It should be fun.
I'll be there, too, to help.
Oh, it seems so pointless.
Well, I think I'll go to sleep.
It's been a busy day.
My luggage.
That's pretty.
Where'd you get that? Brinkmeyer's?
Mm-hmm. Do you think I should go?
Well, that's up to you.
No, it's really up to Lydia, isn't it?
- Never mind Lydia. Do you want to go?
- Yes.
- Then go.
- Thank you, Annie.
Oh. Wonder who that can be.
Is someone there?
- Who is it?
- Look.
Poor thing.
Probably lost his way in the dark.
But it isn't dark, Annie.
There's a full moon.
Cathy, that's very good. Very good.
Okay. Here we go.
Attagirl. Come on.
Don't let him get you.
No, I really shouldn't have any more.
I'm driving.
Well, actually, I'm trying to get you to
stay for dinner.
A lot of roast beef left over.
- No, I couldn't possibly.
I... have to get back.
- All right.
- Cheers.
Why do you have to rush off?
What's so important in San Francisco?
Well, I have to get to work tomorrow,
for one thing.
- You have a job?
- I have several jobs.
- What do you do?
- I do different things on different days.
Like what?
Well, on Mondays and Wednesdays, I work
for the Travelers' Aid at the airport.
Helping travelers?
No, misdirecting them.
I thought you could read my character.
On Tuesdays, I take a course in
General Semantics at Berkeley...
finding new four-letter words.
- That's not a job, of course...
- You mean, you don't have to...
And on Thursdays,
I have my meeting and lunch.
In the underworld, I suppose
I shall disappoint you.
We're sending a little
Korean boy through school.
We actually raise money for it.
You see, Rome...
That entire summer, I did nothing but...
Well, it was very easy to get lost there.
So when I came back,
I thought it was time I began...
I don't know... finding something again.
So, on Mondays and Thursdays,
I keep myself busy.
- What about Fridays?
- Fridays? They're free.
I sometimes go to bird shops on Fridays.
I'm very glad you do.
A nice, innocent, little day.
Oh, yes.
I have an Aunt Tessa.
Have you got an Aunt Tessa?
Mm-mm
Mine is very prim and straight-laced.
I'm giving her a mynah bird
when she comes back from Europe.
Mynah birds talk, you know.
Can you see my Aunt Tessa's face...
when this one tells us one or two of
the words I've picked up at Berkeley?
You need a mother's care, my child.
- Not my mother's.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
What have you got to be sorry about?
My mother? Don't waste your time.
She ditched us when I was 11 and
ran off with some hotel man in the East.
You know what a mother's love is?
- Yes, I do.
- You mean it's better to be ditched?
No. I think it's better to be
loved. Don't you ever see her?
I don't know where she is.
Well, maybe I ought to
go join the other children.
All right. Here we go. One...
two...
three.
There you go.
Look! Look!
Hey! No touching allowed!
Oh!
Help me get the children into the house.
There you go.
Have they gone, Mitch?
- I think so.
- Is anyone hurt?
Jenny got a scratch down her cheek,
but it's nothing.
That makes three times.
Mitch, this isn't usual, is it?
The gull when I was in the boat yesterday,
the one at Annie's last night...
Last night? What do you mean?
A gull smashed into Annie's front door.
Mitch, what's happening?
I... I don't know.
Do you have to go back to Annie's?
No. I have my things in the car.
Stay and have something to eat before
you start back. I'd feel a lot better.
- Would you like some mustard with that?
- No, thank you.
Why didn't Annie stay?
Said something about going home
to take a call from her sister.
What's the matter with them?
- What's the matter with all the birds?
- Where did you want this coffee?
- Here on the table, honey.
- Hurry up with yours, Mitch.
I'm sure Miss Daniels
wants to be on her way.
I think you ought to stay the night,
Melanie.
We have an extra room
upstairs and everything.
That road can be a
pretty bad one at night.
If I go across to Santa Rosa, I'll come
out on the freeway much earlier, won't I?
Yes, and the freeway is much quicker.
But she'll be hitting all the heavy
traffic going back to San Francisco.
Just listen to those lovebirds.
Mitch.
Cover your faces! Cover your eyes!
That's a sparrow, all right.
- We know what it is, Al.
- Did you have a light burning
or something?
Yes, but there wouldn't have been
that much light going up the chimney.
Sometimes birds are attracted by light.
Sure is a peculiar thing.
All right, but we've got
to do something about it!
I don't think I get you, Mitch.
Do about what?
Well, the birds invaded the house.
What's more likely... they
got in the room and just panicked.
I'll admit a bird will
panic in an enclosed room,
but they didn't just get in: :
They came in, right down the chimney.
My wife found a bird in the back seat
of her car once.
Tell him about the party.
We had a party here this
afternoon for Cathy, for her birthday.
- How old is she?
- Eleven! In the middle of the party,
some seagulls came down at the children!
Miss Daniels was
attacked by a gull yesterday.
Yeah. Were the kids
bothering the birds or something?
If you make any kind of a
disturbance near them,
they'll come after you.
Al, the children were playing a game.
Those gulls attacked.
Now, Lydia, "attack" is a
pretty strong word, don't you think?
I mean, birds just don't go around
attacking people without no reason.
The kids probably scared them,
that's all.
These birds attacked.
You got quite a mess here,
I'll admit that.
Maybe you ought to put some
screen on top of your chimney.
- You want help cleaning up?
- No. I can handle it.
It shouldn't be too much of a job.
I'll take Cathy up to bed.
I think I should stay, don't you?
It would be nice if you could.
- My things are in the car.
Do you want to go with me?
- All right.
- Well, anything else I can do, Mitch?
- No thanks, Al.
- We'll be all right.
- Good night, Lydia.
Sure is peculiar.
Mitch. Mitch. Mitch!
- Yes, Mother?
- I'm going to drop Cathy off now.
I'll probably drive
over to the Fawcett farm.
Okay.
Morning.
Good morning, George.
Is Mr. Fawcett around?
I think so, ma'am. Ain't seen him this
morning, but he ought to be in there.
Thanks.
Dan, are you home?
Uh...
Mother!
What is it, dear? What's the matter?
Oh!
Al Malone, the deputy, just called.
He wants me over at the Fawcett place.
Some detectives from
Santa Rosa will be there.
- Will it be all right?
- Yes. I was just taking your mother
in some tea.
Oh, be careful, please.
And you be careful?
Mitch?
No, it's me, Mrs. Brenner.
- I thought you might like some tea.
- Oh. Thank you.
- Where's Mitch?
- Al Malone wanted him out
at the Fawcett farm.
Why? Didn't Al believe my story?
He was calling from the farm.
Then he saw. Oh, he must have.
They sent for the Santa Rosa police.
What good will they do?
Do you think Cathy's
all right at the school?
Yes, I'm sure she's fine.
Do I sound very foolish to you?
Oh, no.
I keep seeing Dan's face.
And they have such
big windows at the school.
All the windows are
broken in Dan's bedroom.
- All the windows!
- Try not to think about that.
I wish I were a stronger person.
I lost my husband four years ago,
you know.
It's terrible how you... you depend on
someone else for strength, and then...
suddenly all the strength is gone,
and you're alone.
I'd love to be able to relax sometime.
I'd love to be able to sleep.
- Do you think Cathy's all right?
- Annie's there.
She'll be all right.
I'm not like this, you know?
N ...Not usually.
I don't fuss and fret about my children.
When Frank died...
You see, he understood the children.
He really understood them.
He had the knack of entering into
their world, of becoming part of them.
- That's a very rare talent.
- Yes.
Oh, I wish, I wish...
I wish I could be like that.
I miss him.
Sometimes, even now,
I wake up in the morning and I think,
"I must get Frank's breakfast."
And I get up, and there's a very
good reason for getting out of bed,
until of course...
I remember.
I miss talking to him.
Cathy's a child, of course, and Mitch...
Well, Mitch has his own life.
I'm glad he stayed here today.
I... I feel safer with him here.
- Would you like to rest now?
- No.
No, don't go.
I feel as if I don't
understand you at all, and I...
I want so much to understand.
Why, Mrs. Brenner?
Because my son seems
to be very fond of you.
And I don't quite
know how I feel about it.
I don't even know if I like you or not.
Is that so important, your liking me?
Well, yes. I think so.
Mitch is important to me.
I want to like whatever girl he chooses.
And perhaps if you don't?
Well, then I don't think
it'll matter much to anyone but me.
Oh, I think it would
also matter to Mitch.
Mitch has always done
exactly what he wanted to do.
But, you see,
I...I don't want to be left alone.
I don't think I could
bear to be left alone!
Oh, forgive me.
This business with the
birds has upset me, I...
I don't know what I'd
do if Mitch weren't here.
Why don't you try to sleep now,
Mrs. Brenner?
I wish I was stronger.
Do you think she's all right?
Do you think she's
all right at the school?
- Would you like me to go for her?
- Oh, I...I couldn't ask it.
- Oh, I don't mind, really.
- Would you?
- I'd feel so much better.
- I'll go right now.
Melanie?
Thanks for the tea.
I married my wife in the month of June
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee now, now, now
I brought her home by the light of the moon
Ristle-tee,
rostle-tee Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee now, now, now
She combs her hair but once a year
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee now, now, now
With every stroke she shed a tear
Ristle-tee,
rostle-tee Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Rustical quality
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee now, now, now
He brought her home
by the light of the moon
Ristle-tee,
rostle-tee Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee Now, now, now
She combed her hair But once a year
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee Now, now, now
With every stroke She shed a tear
Ristle-tee,
rostle-tee Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee Now, now, now
She swept up her floor But once a year
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee Now, now, now
She said that brooms Were much too dear
Ristle-tee,
rostle-tee Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee Now, now, now
She churns her butter In her dad's old boot
Ristle-tee, Rostle-tee Now, now, now
And for a dash She'd use her foot
Ristle-tee,
Rostle-tee Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee Now, now, now
The butter it came out All grizzle-y gray
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee Now, now, now
The cheese it took legs and ran away
Ristle-tee,
rostle-tee Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee Now, now, now
She let the critter get away
Ristle-tee,
rostle-tee Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee Now, now, now
I asked my wife to wash the floor
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee Now, now, now
She gave me my hat
And she showed me the door
Ristle-tee,
rostle-tee Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality Now, now, now
I married my wife in the month of June
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee Now, now, now
I brought her home by the light of the moon
Ristle-tee,
rostle-tee Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee Now, now, now
She combed her hair But once a year
Ristle-tee,
rostle-tee Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee Now, now, now
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee Now, now, now
All right, children.
Now, please put your song books away,
then stand up alongside your desks.
We'll go out for recess as
soon as everybody gets ready.
We are not going into the playground...
until everybody has quieted down.
- Close that door. Quickly. Please.
- What?
- What is it?
- Look.
We've got to get the
children out of here.
Shh, shh, shh!
All right, children. Now, quiet.
Quiet. Miss Daniels would like to see...
how we conduct
ourselves during a fire drill.
I would like you to show her
how quiet and obedient you can be.
Oh, uh, we're going out of school now.
Leave school
We want those of you who
live nearby to go directly home.
Home?
I want the rest of you to go down the
hill all the way to the hotel.
Is that clear?
Yes, Miss Hayworth.
Melanie?
I want you to go as quietly as possible.
Do not make a sound
until I tell you to run.
Then run as quickly as you can.
Now, does everybody understand?
Yes, Miss Hayworth.
All right, John, you lead the way.
Cathy! Cathy!
Well, Daddy, there were hundreds of them.
No, I'm not hysterical. I'm trying to
tell you this as calmly as I know how.
All right, Daddy. Yes, Daddy.
Well, just now. Not 15 minutes ago.
At the school.
No, I don't. Just a minute.
What's the name of the school?
- Just the Bodega Bay School.
- The Bodega Bay School.
Well, I don't know how
many children... 30 or 40.
No, the birds didn't attack until
the children were outside the school.
- Help you, Mrs. Bundy?
- I need some change, Mr. Carter.
Crows, I think.
Well, I don't know, Daddy. Is there a
difference between crows and blackbirds?
There is very definitely a
difference, Miss. Thank you.
They're different, Daddy.
Well, I think these were crows.
Well, yes. Hundreds of them.
Yes, they attacked the children.
Attacked them!
Well, I don't know when,
but I simply can't leave now, Daddy.
All right. Yes. Good-bye.
They're both perching birds, of course.
But quite different species.
The crow is Corvus brachyrhynchos,
and the blackbird is
Euphagus cyanocephalos.
Thank you.
- You have the number at the Fawcett farm?
- Right here in this book, miss.
I can't see that it makes
any difference, Mrs. Bundy.
Crows or blackbirds, if the school
was attacked, that's pretty serious.
I hardly think that either species...
would have sufficient
intelligence to launch a massed attack.
Their brainpans are not big enough to...
I just came from the school, madam.
I don't know anything about
their brainpans, but...
Well, I do. I do know.
Ornithology happens to be my avocation.
Birds are not aggressive creatures, miss.
They bring beauty into the world.
It is mankind, rather, who...
Sam! Three southern fried chicken.
Baked potato on all of them.
Yes, may I speak to Mitch Brenner, please?
- Yes, I'll wait.
- It is mankind, rather, who insists upon...
making it difficult for
life to exist upon this planet.
Now, if it were not for birds...
Mrs. Bundy, you don't seem to understand.
This young lady said there
was an attack on the school.
- Impossible!
-  Oh, Mitch?
Oh, I'm glad I caught you.
Something terrible has ha...
It's the end of the world!
Two Bloody Marys, Deke.
- What actually happened at the school?
- Bunch of crows...
attacked the school kids.
It's the end of the world.
"Thus saith the Lord God...
"unto the mountains and the
hills, and the rivers and the valleys.
"Behold I, even I...
"shall bring a sword upon you.
And I will devastate your high places."
Ezekiel, chapter six.
"Woe unto them that rise up early
in the morning,
that they may follow strong drink."
Isaiah, chapter five.
It's the end of the world.
I hardly think a few birds are going
to bring about the end of the world.
- These weren't a few birds.
- I didn't know there were many crows...
in Bodega Bay this time of year.
The crow is a permanent
resident throughout its range.
In fact, during our Christmas count,
we recorded...
How many gulls did you count, Mrs. Bundy?
Which gulls, Mr. Sholes?
There are several varieties.
The ones who've been
playing devil with my fishing boats.
- Have you had trouble with gulls?
- One of my boats did, last week.
This young lady was hit
by a gull only Saturday.
- Deke, I'm still waiting for
those Bloody Marys.
- Coming right up.
Could you ask them to lower their voices,
please? They're frightening the children.
A whole flock of gulls
nearly capsized one of my boats.
Practically tore the skipper's arm off.
- You're scaring the kids. Keep it low.
- All right.
Yeah, but he's scaring me, too.
Are you trying to say that all these...
Nah, that sounds impossible, Sebastian.
Deke, look, I'm just telling you
what happened to one of my boats.
The gulls were after your fish, Mr. Sholes.
Really, let's be logical about this.
What were the crows after at the school?
What do you think they were after?
Miss, uh...
Daniels.
I think they were after the children.
- For what purpose?
- To kill them.
- Why?
- I don't know why.
I thought not. Birds have
been on this planet, Miss Daniels,
Since archeopteryx,
140 million years ago.
Doesn't it seem odd that
they'd wait all that time...
to start a... a war against humanity?
- No one called it a war.
- Scotch, light on the water.
You and Mr. Sholes
seem to be implying as much.
Who said anything about a war?
All I said, some gulls...
- Want some more coffee?
- No.
...came down on one of my boats.
They could have been after the fish,
just like you said.
- The Captain should have shot at them.
- Huh?
Gulls are scavengers, anyway.
Most birds are.
Get yourselves guns and wipe
them off the face of the Earth!
- That would hardly be possible.
- Why not, Mrs. Bundy?
Because there are 8,650 species...
of birds in the world today, Mr. Carter.
It is estimated that 5,750,000,000 birds...
live in the United States alone.
The five continents of the world...
Kill them all.
Get rid of the messy animals.
...probably contain
more than 100 billion birds.
It's the end of the world.
Those gulls must have been after the fish
- Of course!
- Hurry up, children. Finish your lunch.
Are the birds gonna eat us, Mommy?
Hell, maybe we're all getting
a little carried away by this.
Admittedly, a few birds did act strange,
but that's no reason to believe that...
I keep telling you, this isn't a few birds.
These are gulls, crows, swifts...
I have never known birds of
different species to flock together.
The very concept is unimaginable.
Why, if that happened,
we wouldn't have a chance!
How could we possibly hope to fight them?
We couldn't, you're right.
You're right, Mrs. Bundy.
What's the matter?
Something wrong out here?
We're fighting a war, Sam
A war? Against who?
Against birds!
I'm glad you all think this is so amusing
You've frightened the children half out
of their wits. If the young lady said...
she saw the attack at a school,
why don't you believe her?
- What attack? Who attacked the school?
- Birds did. Crows.
You're all sitting around here debating!
What do you want them to do next?
Crash through that window?
- Mommy!
- Ssh. Put on your coat.
Why don't you all go home,
lock your doors and windows?
What's the fastest way to San Francisco?
The freeway, ma'am
How do I find it?
I'm going out that way, lady.
You can follow me
- Well then, let's leave now.
- Haven't finished my drink yet.
I got here as fast as I could.
Where's Cathy?
- She's with Annie. She's all right.
- Al, why aren't you over at the school,
Where the attack was?
Because I just got back from
Dan Fawcett's place
- He was killed last night by birds.
- What?
Hold it, you don't know that for a fact.
What are the facts?
The Santa Rosa Police
think it's a felony murder
They think a burglar
broke in and killed him.
How do they explain the
dead birds all over the floor?
Santa Rosa Police figure they
got in after the old man was killed.
Were the Santa Rosa
Police at your school today?
- Are you coming?
- Now take it easy, lady.
There isn't a bird anywhere in sight!
"Look at the birds of the
air. They do not sow or reap.
Yet your Heavenly Father feeds them."
Something like this
happened in Santa Cruz last year.
The town was just covered with seagulls.
- Please finish your drink.
- That's right, sir. I recall it.
A large flock of seagulls got lost in a fog,
and headed into the town
where all the lights were.
They made some mess, too,
smashing into buildings and everything.
- They always make a mess.
- The point is that no one seemed
to be upset about it.
They were all gone next morning, just
as though nothing at all had happened.
- Poor things.
- I'm leaving! Are you coming?
All right, all right!
Well, hope you folks
figure this thing out!
It's the end of the world!
I better get back to the cannery.
What do I owe you, Deke?
- S...Sebastian, hold it a minute.
- Huh?
I...I don't want to be an alarmist,
- but...
- No one ever said you were
I think we're in real trouble.
I don't know how this started, or why,
but I know it's here and
we'd be crazy to ignore it.
- To ignore what? The "bird war"?
- Yes, the "bird war. "
The bird attack, plague...
Call it what you like,
they're massing out there someplace,
and they'll be back.
- Ridiculous.
- C...Come here.
Unless we do something right now,
unless we get Bodega Bay on the move,
they...
Look, Mitch.
Even if... Even if this is true,
even if all the birds...
- Don't you believe it's true?
- No, Mitch, frankly I don't.
- There's no reason I...
- Well, it's happening.
Isn't that a reason?
- I like Bodega Bay as well as
the next man...
- Fine, then help me.
You're an important man.
If you help, they all will.
Help how? What do you want to do?
Mrs. Bundy said
something about Santa Cruz.
About seagulls getting lost in a
fog and flying in towards the lights.
- We don't have fog this time of year!
- Make our own fog!
- How do you figure to do that?
- We can use smoke pots,
the way the Army uses them.
Look!
They're attacking again.
Melanie, you stay in here. Come on, Al!
Look out!
Look at the gas.
That man's lighting a cigar!
Hey, you! Watch out! Don't drop that match!
- Get out of there!
- Mister, run!
Hey!
Why are they doing this?
They said when you got here,
the whole thing started!
Who are you? What are you?
Where did you come from?
I think you're the cause of all this.
I think you're evil! Evil!
Oh, God!
I think they're going!
We can get Cathy at Annie's now.
The crows again. Shh!
Come on.
- Oh, no.
- Stay here. S...Stay here.
Cathy! Where's Cathy?
Mitch, don't!
Oh, don't leave her there, Mitch.
Oh!
Come on.
Shh.
Wh...When we got back
from taking Michele home...
we...we heard the explosion and we went...
we went outside to see what it was.
All...All at once the...
the birds were everywhere!
All at once she pushed me inside...
and they covered her!
Annie... She pushed me inside!
Give me another one, darling.
How long have they been gathering there?
Oh, about 15 minutes.
Seems like a pattern, doesn't it?
They strike, then disappear,
and then start massing again.
Doesn't look so very different, does it?
A little smoke hanging over the town,
otherwise...
You want to try your father again?
No, I tried a little while ago.
The phone's dead.
- Still got power, haven't we?
- Yes.
Mitch, I'm getting something on the radio.
Come on.
I can't get any of the local stations.
I think this is San Francisco.
"...and the work of a team
of professionals. " End quote.
In Bodega Bay early this morning,
a large flock of crows...
attacked a group of children who were
leaving the school during a fire drill.
One little girl was seriously injured
and taken to the hospital in Santa Rosa,
but the majority of
children reached safety.
We understand there was
another attack on the town,
but this information is rather sketchy.
So far, no word has come through...
to show if there
have been further attacks.
On the national scene today,
in Washington...
Well, is that all?
I'll have to get some more water.
Mustn't let this fire go out.
- Did you get the windows in the attic,
Mitch?
- Yes, I got them all, dear.
- When do you think they'll come?
- I don't know.
If there are bigger birds, Mitch,
they'll get into the house.
- Well, it's just a chance we'll
have to take.
- Maybe we ought to leave.
No, not now!
Not when they're massing out there.
- When?
- W...We'll just see what happens.
Where will we go?
I...I don't know.
I think we're safe here for the time being
- Let's get the wood in now.
- What happens when you run out of wood?
- I don't know!
We'll break up the furniture.
- You don't know!
You don't know! When will you know?
When we're all dead!
If only your father were here...
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Mitch.
Make yourself some coffee, won't you?
"In assuming the tasks of the presidency,
I said that few generations..."
- Where are they heading?
- Somewhere inland.
- Santa Rosa?
- Maybe.
Come on. Let's get the wood.
Mitch? Can I bring the lovebirds in here?
No
- But, Mom, they're in a cage.
- They're birds, aren't they?
Let's leave them in the kitchen,
huh, honey?
Mitch, why are they doing this, the birds?
- We don't know, honey.
- Why are they trying to kill people?
I wish I could say.
I...I'm sick, Melanie.
- I want to...
- I'll go with you.
They're going.
Mitch?
Oh, Mitch!
Melanie! Melanie!
Oh, poor thing! Poor thing!
Listen, get some water,
bandages and antiseptic. Quickly!
Bandages. It's terrible.
Cathy, get some brandy.
- No, no, no!
- No, no, it's all right.
No, it's all right,
it's all right, it's all right.
It's all right. It's all right. No.
No. Shh! Shh!
Cathy, get the lamp.
We've got to get her to a hospital.
- We can't, Mitch.
There's no place we can go.
- There's San Francisco.
- We'd never make it.
- We have to try.
We'll go by way of Bay Hill Road.
Then we don't have to go through town.
We can't stay here. She needs help!
I'm frightened. Terribly frightened.
I don't know what's outside there.
We better get started
before another attack comes.
We'll take Melanie's car.
That'll be faster than the truck.
- Can you finish the bandaging?
- I'll try.
All right.
Mitch? See if you can get
anything on the car radio.
The bird attacks have
subsided for the time being.
Bodega Bay seems to be the center,
though there are reports...
of minor attacks on
Sebastopol and a few on Santa Rosa.
Bodega Bay has been
cordoned off by roadblocks.
Most of the townspeople
have managed to get out,
but there are still some
isolated pockets of people.
No decision has been arrived at
yet as to what the next step will be,
but there's been some discussion as
to whether the military should go in.
It appears that the bird attacks come
in waves, with long intervals between.
The reason for this
does not seem clear as yet.
Did you hear anything on the radio?
It's-It's all right. Come on.
No. No!
Shh. Shh.
- Mitch?
- Shh!
Stay there.
Can I bring the lovebirds, Mitch?
They haven't harmed anyone.
A...All right. Bring them.