Christmas present from OpenSubtitles.org
Log-in and enjoy VIP benefits until start of 2017
**
When I made love to him
I dwell in the mystery
of our oneness.
It was a feeling so spiritual
It was as though I
should remove my shoes
in the presence of the holy.
With my lips.
I traced my name upon his skin,
and I'd find God there.
With my heart pressed
against his chest
his breath breathing
life into my soul,
I could live again.
I'd see my lover there.
And no longer was it,
that I want him, need him
or loved him, but that...
..I was him.
This was Chris, my
mission companion.
Five years ago, we
were separated,
after it was discovered,
that we were slightly more
than just mission companions.
I was immediately sent home,
and Chris was allowed to
stay in Clackamas Falls.
But we kept in touch.
And after his mission,
We went on a trip
across America.
We had time of our lives.
For a few months, we weren't
Elder Smith and Elder Merrill.
We had no obligations
and no pressure from our
families or the church.
We were just Chris and RJ.
On our own and loving
every minute of it.
After some time, we faced
the reality, that we would
eventually, have to go home.
I drove into Salt Lake,
Chris' home town.
We agreed to take care of
our respective loose ends.
And he talked about transferring
to Poisy State with me.
We kissed and said goodbye.
And I went home to Idaho Falls.
I never saw him again.
I sent letters, I'd call...
And nothing.
If only I knew, what
happened to him,
then maybe, I'd
have some closure.
These days I live in Seattle.
I'm neither Mormon, nor gentile.
I was never formally
excommunicated.
I just stopped associating
myself with the church at all.
But... I still wear
my temple garments
I still have a food storage.
And I still have a deep love...
for our Heavenly Father.
So, from what you've
been telling me...
you've been working
hard to stay focussed
and maintain the
standing of the Church.
Yes, sir.
Six months ago, I was intimate
with my mission companion,
even though I knew it was wrong.
Do you still think that you are
unfazed of same-sex attraction?
I am much stronger now.
Would you like to continue
your service to your Church ?
Yes, I would.
More than anything.
As I said before,
our Heavenly Father doesn't
present to us any temptation...
that we do not have the
power to overcome.
It's a choice, that we make
To act in virtue, or
give in to temptation.
Considering your humility and
desire to do the right thing,
I see no need for
disciplinary action.
Thank you.
It is an honor to witness
two young people...
So deeply in love,
and so dedicated
to the church and
our Heavenly Father.
Marriage is for eternity
It is the love,that
will last in this life...
.. and the next.
Your dedication...
to the Church and to this
family, has brought you here.
You've been given
a second chance.
I know...
that you have the courage...
and the strentgh, to stay on
the right track, this time.
I love you, son.
I love you too.
Now, what do you say, we
get back in there and
join what's left of the party.
I'm so sorry, Dad.
I'm so sorry, for everything.
Now, Chris...
You've done the right thing.
- Alright?
- Yes
I am so proud of you.
- Are you okay?
- Yes sir, I'm fine.
I'm gonna go join the party.
You take a minute.
- Come when you're ready.
- Yes sir.
Okay, I'm gonna be late.
You know I have somewhere
else to be too.
I know.
I have a meeting...
in like 30 minutes.
And ?
- I got to go.
- No..
You know I wrestled
in Highschool...
and College.
Okay. Okay.
- Now, you shouldn't eat that stuff.
- And why not?
- It's loaded with sugar?
- I like sugar.
Thank you.
- Want some?
- No
You know? I'm nervous
about tonight.
Don't be.
Are you sure you ready for this?
No.
- You think it's time, they met us?
- Yup.
I gotta go.
I'm gonna be late.
Bye !
Sorry.
Hey, Rodney!
- RJ? I'm his mother.
- Oh... Well, how are you?
Unfortunately, very badly.
I'm sorry to hear that...
Is everything okay?
Sorry RJ, But Rodney died.
- You want some chicken?
- Is really good!
Amazingly good. You
gonna love it.
Who is calling me?
- I do not know.
- Sorry.
- You want one of Mummy's?
- No, no?
Hello?
Speaking.
Yes, Mam! How are you?
Oh no!
Did I ever tell you
about Rodney?
A little...
I met him on my mission, with
my mission companion Chris,
He was a veteran of Iraq.
He had PTST, so
We tried so hard to
convert him, but...
We'd always end up hanging
out and smoking pot..
He was always so accepting
of Chris and I.
Yes.
You did talk about him.
- Are you going to the funeral?
- I think so.
Okay.
Sorry, I'm late. How long
are you waiting for?
About twenty minutes.
- Hello, sorry.
- It was nothing.
Mom, Dad, this is Paul.
- It's a pleasure to finally meet you.
- Nice to meet you, Paul.
- Hi - Hi.
- Good to meet you.
- Good to meet you too.
- So, how was your flight?
- Bumpy.
- Do I want to ask?
- Yes, we will ask.
What do you want to drink?
- I mineral water..
- I Coca Cola.
- Well, I drink.
- Thank you.
- So Coca-Cola?
- Yes
So... Mr. and Mrs. Smith,
How long are you in town?
- Just till Sunday evening...
- We're just here for the weekend
- We don't want to be in the way.
- Dad you're not in the way.
- I do not know, we never hear from you.
- Tom... - No!
I'm not trying to start anything,
I'm just saying,
I wish to hear from my son more.
I misshim.
Mary Ann calls at
least once a week.
- Okay, I'll check in more
- That would be nice.
So Paul, what do you do?
- I am a personal trainer.
- Oh that's nice.
- Paul is working on his MBA.
- Oh really?
Tell RJ that has to
completing his masters.
- I'll tell you the same.
- Okay, okay.
Maybe at some point...
but... Not now.
- And how's work?
- It goes well, yes.
I'm not independent, I
am in the office too...
But additionally
nothing interesting.
I do not know. Nothing
too exciting.
How is the shop, Dad?
Well. All is well. I
can not complain.
Do you know Mr. Smith,
my father is a mechanic.
Really?
Yes, he works primarily
on Swedish automobiles.
- Well... they know how to make cars...
- Yes.
- Gloria? - Yes -. I'm RJ.
How nice to finally meet you.
- I'm so glad you came.
- No, I would not miss it for anything.
You know, not many people knew
and I did not go there often.
Nice to meet two of
his good friends.
- I also loved meeting her.
- Thank you.
Rodney was a complex man.
And through the hardships
that life threw at him,
he had this amazing
ability to make us laugh.
Some of you may not know
this about Rodney, but
he was a religious man.
Though he may not have
considered himself, to be so.
Though he alluded the
Doctrines of Faith,
he embodied their essence.
And as a lifelong seeker,
he had an amazing ability
to help people find their way.
There is a heaven.
And Rodney is there.
- Amen - Amen.
I'm sorry for your loss.
Thank you.
RJ!
I almost forgot
to give you this.
- He was going to mail it to you.
- Thank you.
- You keep in touch now.
- I will.
I'm sorry your loss.
I will miss him.
I am too.
- Take care now, you.
- I will.
And don't open that here.
- Chris!
- Chris.
Yes?
How are you?
Yeah, ehm...
Can we go somewhere and talk?
- What do you wanna talk about?
- Maybe we can catch up.
- Hi - Hi.
What a day.
Yes.
Did you get to speak to him?
- To Rodney?
- Yeah...
No... not really.
I spoke to him a few times
after the end of the mission.
But we lost contact.
- You talked to him?
- A few months ago. Yes.
- Sometimes I visited.
- Great.
I can't believe he's gone.
Wish I had a chance
to say goodbye.
He had nothing but
fond memories of you.
It's good to hear.
It's surreal, is not it?
Yes.
Sitting here with you
is very surreal.
- How long has it been?
- Five years. - Five years.
- You did this?
- I did it, but...
I said a month or
two or so and...
- Ok -. Yes.
Well, how's life?
I'm happily married,
I live in Salt Lake
I have a little
daughter, three years
I can not believe that.
I work in pharmaceutical sales, so...
life's pretty good.
- Are you married?
- Yes
She's amazing, she's
like an angel.
I don't have a picture to show, but...
she's incredible.
- I'm happy for you.
- Thank you.
What about you?
I'm the Earth and Culture
editor at a Seattle magazine.
Yes, and I've ehm...
I've written a couple of
short non-fiction books.
- Really? - Yes.
- Can I find them anywhere?
Yeah, they're in
some bookstores.
I haven't really inquired after
all means of distribution,
but yeah, they're there.
- Oh.
- I'll look for them.
- Cool.
Are you seeing anybody? Or...
- I've been seeing someone for a while.
- Ok.
- We are doing well.
- What is her name?
Paul.
It's reaslly good
to see you, Chris.
It's good to see you too.
I'm sorry it's under
these circumstances.
Yes, me too, but...
our Heavenly Father had a plan.
Listen, I hate to make this
brief, but I have a really early
flight tomorrow morning, and
it has been a very long day.
It looks like they're
closing up here anyhow,
so I'm going to bed.
- But it was nice.
- Yes, it was good.
Can I walk you up?
You wanna walk me to my room?
Yes.
- Yes, of course.
- Okay. Yeah.
That'll be fine.
Thanks,
Well, this is me.
Chris.
Are you sure there's nothing
else you wanna talk about?
What exactly would
you like to talk about?
You can't just pretend,
that nothing happened.
R.J.
Its good to see you, and I'm
glad you're doing well...
but I came here to pay
my respects Rodney...
So did I.
Then I need you to respect that.
Okay.
Good night.
♫ ♫
♪ I can withstand ♪
♪ All tragedies ♪
♪ And sins, inflicted ♪
♪ upon me ♪
♪ And sickness without remedy ♪
♪ With my heart ... ♪
- Hey
- Hey.
Thank you.
- Hope you don't mind I'm here?
- No
- How are you?
- I'm good, how are you?
Good.
You look tired?
Yes, a little, I am.
- I hope you're hungry?
- You cooked for me?
- Oh, maybe.
- Thank you.
It looks amazing.
I wanted something
ready when you got here.
- It's great.
- Want some?
You look so good in your suit.
Thank you.
Hey guess what?
What?
I'm fiinally gonna
get my red jacket.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Congratulations baby!
- Thank you.
- I'm so proud of you.
- Feels good.
- Yeah?
I'm so sorry.
What's wrong?
It's been a rough couple
of days, you know.
Yeah.
It's okay.
I'm so sorry.
- I think I'm too tired.
- Yes I know.
I love you.
- Hey.
- How are you?
- Okay, and you?
- Good, how's work?
- It's good, how was your day?
- Fantastic...
- So much work.
- Good, good.
Do you want anything?
I tell you in just a minute...
This is such a nice surprise.
Hey, what's up?
You know I've always
been honest with you.
Yes.
I don't think we should
see each other for a while.
Why?
Cause I don't think I can give
you what you need, right now.
God, what is this?
I mean, we have met your family.
We did meet your parents.
I know...
I know, it's taken me a
long time to get here,
but I am here, with
everthing that I am.
You are everything
that I ever wanted.
It's always been you...
who's been holding us back.
- You know that?
- I know that.
I know what this is about.
I know!
You go...
..you go do...
whatever it is, that
you have to do.
But I want you to know...
that I ...
I may not still be here, just
waiting for you,
when you get back.
Please stay.
He handles all the marketing.
Can you hold on a second?
Hey, I was wondering, do you think
you need me around next week?
You haven't really
been here much, Rick.
Right, but I was thinking about
taking a writing vacatioin,
I'm working on a story.
I think you gonna love it
- Okay, that'll work, yeah.
- Great,l thank you.
- Are you leaving now?
- Yeah.
Okay, fine.
- Where are you gonna go?
- Ehm...
♪ Here I make my solemn vow ♪
♪ To Keep His light in front of me ♪
♪ In spite of what the dark allows ♪
♪ Of what harm comes unto me ♪
...and the love in our heart.
We say these things in the
name of Jesus Christ.
- Amen - Amen.
- Dig in.
- yammm...
Peaches, you like sucking?
Are you dipping?
Dipping in the water?
You like that?
- This is realy good. - Yes?
- Should cook every night.
Thank you.
What's the noise?
- Are you expecting anybody?
- No, you? - No
What was that noise?
Hi.
- Is this a bad time?
- Yes.
What are you doing here?
Why would you come to my house?
How do you know where I live?
Explain yourself!
- I got your address from Gloria.
- Gloria.
Are you crazy?
- Hi - Hi.
Are you gonna introduce
me to your friend?
- Yes. Honey, this is my friend RJ.
- RJ, this is my wife, Emily.
- Hi, nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you too.
Thanks for stopping by.
It was good to see you.
Oh...
Actually, we're having dinner. You're
welcome to join us, if you'd like.
Sure, yeah.
- Yes, of course.
- Thank you.
- OK, come on in.
- Yeah.
So, ehm, RJ, how do you and
Chris know each other?
Well... that's a good question...
Chris, would you
like to, maybe...
Yeah, ehm...
RJ and I met, when I was on
my mission in Clackamas Falls.
- Really? - Mmm...
- Well, it's wonderful.
- RJ was my mission companion.
- Wow.
And, do you live here
in Salt Lake City?
- No, actually, I live in Seattle.
- Seattle?
- So, what brings you here?
- I'm here for work.
- What kind of work?
- I am a writer.
A writer? Wow!
- Like for a magazine or...
- Yeah, actually...
- Magazine... Which magazine?
- The Seattle Magazine.
And they're doing a piece
on Salt Lake City?
No, no actually...
the story I'm working on, has a little
bit to do with the Salt Lake, so...
I thought I'd come down
here for some inspiration.
- Great. - Mmm...
- How long are you in town?
I don't know. I guess until
the story is finished.
Where are you staying?
Well, ehm...
Okay, honey.
I think it's her bedtime.
I'm sorry, is it me?
I'm so sorry, if it was me.
Okay.
Come.
Let's go.
- Hi - Hi.
Why are you here? Why...
You came to my house?
- I just wanted to talk to you.
- Ok
Let's talk.
- Maybe not now...
- Yes, maybe not right now.
- I'm so sorry.
- Ok - She is really tired.
- It's a little late.
- Yeah.
Anyway, what I...
I don't have any
place to stay yet,
I think I might just go
to a motel nearby, maybe?
Oh, you don't need to do that.
We have so much space.
You can stay with us, if you'd like.
- If you want.
- Sure!
Yeah, is that okay
with you, Chris?
Yeah, of course.
You're more than welcome to stay,
for the night, if you'd like.
Great.
You guys probably have a
lot of catching up to do ?
- Yeah!
- We do. We do.
This is you, at the
end of the stairs.
The bag looks heavy,
I should help.
No, it's okay.
Alright.
Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Yes of course.
Well, you're probably super tired.
So you know...
If you need anything
just let me know, okay?
I will. Thank you so much.
- Yeah, it's so nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you too.
- Well, have a good night.
- You too.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
Meet me at Mercury Grove on North
Canyon at 7am. Please. Chris.
What are you doing?
- Ricky, what are you doing?
- I just want to talk.
I do not want to talk
about the mission.
Okay.
So let's talk about
something else.
- I like your jacket.
- Thanks.
RJ.
I'm married.
- And I'm living honorably.
- Okay.
I didn't mean to
interfere with you.
It's too late for that.
Don't you think it's
a little crazy?
You showing up out of
nowhere, like this?
Yes it is, but going to
Clackamas Falls
And Rodney dying and
seeing you again.
It's just...
it sparked something in me.
And all of a sudden,
I'm 20 years old,
And you walked into my life.
And years of confusion and
shame jusst disappear.
Because I found somebody.
That knows me, that
understands me.
I can't find that anywhere else.
It comes close, but...
It's not the same.
And then, suddenly I'm here.
Why did you cut me out
of your life, Chris?
I had no choice.
All I want, is to be
a part of your life.
- That's not possible.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
I have a meeting to go to.
You still go to church RJ?
No, regretfully I don't.
Well, you should.
What are you doing, Chris?
What do you mean?
We spent a year of
our lives together.
We made love.
We fell in love.
You're not straight!
- I feel sorry for you.
- Why?
Because you are
living a life of sin.
And you are obsessing
over something that never
should have happened !
It was a phase !
The Lord has declared
that no unclean thing
shall inherit the
Kingdom of Heavens.
Our sin makes us unclean.
Unworthy to be in the presence
of our Heavenly Father.
Verily, verily, I
say onto you...
woe be unto him that
lieth to deceive
because he supposeth that
another lieth to deceive
for such are not exempt
from the justice of God.
You are living a lie.
And you brought your
entire family into it.
How dare you bring
my family into this?
Chris, I don't want to fight,
I didn't come all this way,
to end things like this.
- But I'm worried about you.
- You're worried about me?
This coming from a guy, who
traveled 800 miles, uninvited!
I'm more worried about you.
Good, it shows that you care.
I've always cared about you.
Did you ever care about me?
- Chris, Chris!
- What?
I'm gonna be here
for a few days.
If you want to talk,
just get a hold of me
- Hello?
- Hi
- Hey.
What are you doing?
You can't eat rice with chopsticks.
I don't know how they..
Just eat it with a fork.
- I didn't see that.
- Thank you.
Here we go.
It's easier with broccoli and
beef, I'm just saying...
It's okay, your trial with rice.
- I read through one of your books.
- Oh really? - Yes.
Whichj one?
I don't even know. I'm sorry.
It's embarassing
No, it's okay.
It was very eloquently
written, what I did read.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Do you remember...
when we first met Rodney?
Yeah.
He was just smoking pot...
in front of a couple of missionaries.
- And no shame.
- Like you do.
Like you do.
And that apartment...
It just smelled of beer, and mildew and...
And urine.
yeah, little bit of urine.
I think I saw a live
possum in his kitchen.
I saw a dead one.
I think it was the same one.
He was really good.
- Yes,he was a character.
- Definitely.
- Those were good times
- Yeah, they were.
So,,,
the last time I saw you...
you were the epitomy
of a collegiate wrestler.
- Not so much anymore
- But you look the same though.
Thank you.
I mean, I lead a simple life.
You know, I go to work...
I come home and...
Paul was there all the time.
We were home buddies.
You were ?
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
And I'm sorry about
what I said earlier.
- Were both angry...
- I was very angry.
It's fine. Fifty-fifty.
So, what about you?
How's life as a
pharmaceutical rep?
I hate it.
It's an atrocious job,
that pays very well.
So, why don't you
do something else?
When I figure out,what
I want to do, I'll...
stop being a pharmaceutical rep.
It seems some time, to
figure out, what that is.
Yes.
You will ...
You'll figure it out.
Yes.
You know, it's funny when...
you're younger...
you just assume that
life is gonna...
line up, and make
sense, at some point.
You have this vision...
of what you want
your life to be.
Mission, family, job, ehm...
You create this idea
of what you want your
life to be like.
You create these
images in your head.
And as you go along,
these images shatter.
As if they were nothing.
They're so easily inceived.
and so easily broken.
And all you have left
to do, is just...
to accept life.
Just the way it is.
Life is a journey, isn't it RJ?
Uh-huh.
I should probably get going.
- Yeah.
- ehm, this was fun.
Yes it was.
And ehm, if I don't
see you again...
I just want you to know that...
I'm really glad, we did this.
Me too.
- You'll be welcome...
- No, no.
I guess, this is the
closure I came here for.
It's not what I wanted.
But maybe this is all there is.
- This is wonderful, Emily.
- It really is. - Thank you.
She's trying to make me fat?
- No.
- Right.
Says the guy who gets up at
4:30 every morning to work out.
So, how are sales?
Good, can't complain.
I think, the toughest
part of my job is,
I travel so much and
I'm away from my girl.
You work so hard.
But he's got the
next two weeks off.
So, I've got him all to myself.
- About time.
- Yeah.
I don't know how you
do it, with all the...
hotels, airports...
How do you sleep?
I get used to them.
So, I don't know
about you, but...
I could use a little
bit of dessert.
Honey, how about you and Emily go to
the store and get some ice cream?
Chris and I can chat about
a few matters of the Church.
Sounds like a great idea.
- I wouldn't mind ice cream.
- Sure, yes sir.
I'll miss you.
Ehm, any particular flavor?
- How about vanilla.
- Yeah, vanilla is great.
Okay.
I'm glad we finally have an
opportunity to be alone and chat
Yeah. Yeah, me too.
You know, I think you're a man that
really seems to have it all figured out.
Thank you.
Chris, do you consider
yourself to be openminded?
Yes, yes... for the most part.
Cause there's something, I like
to show you, if that's okay.
- Ok . - Great.
Great, now before I begin,
I wanna ask you to...
try to suspend the way you
normally read Scripture?
Try to listen to this with...
a delicate touch:
This is ehm...
not something I can
bring up to anyone.
which is why I'd rather discuss
it with someone like you.
- No problem.
- Okay
Chris, today I'd like
to talk about Andrew.
Now, who was Andrew?
He was an apostle.
- He's the brother of Simon-Peter.
- Right.
Now, we don't know very
much about Andrew.
But tonight, let's allow
Andrew to take our hand...
and lead us to the Gospel
of John, Chapter 13
Jesus Christ says
to his disciples:
Most assuredly, I say to you,
one of you will betray me.
The disciples looked at one  another,
perplexed about whom he spoke.
One of his disciples, the
one, who Jesus loved,
Was lying on his chest.
Simon Peter therefore
motioned to him, to ask Jesus
of whom he was speaking.
So, while lying next
to Christ, he asked:
Lord, who is it?
So, the Lord, sitting among
the other disciples,
while the one he loved,
lies on the heart of Christ.
On his chest.
After dinner Jesus disrobes
and pours water into a basin
and begins to wash
the disciples' feet.
There's nothing more
gentle and holy...
then washing another's feet.
Aaron... can I...
interject there for a moment...
- I do not know...
- Just hold on, hold on.
- Hear me out.
- Alright.
I spent a lot of time
thinking about this.
And I can't see it any other
way, then how it's written.
There is a tenderness
in these words.
Christ loves these men
dearly, and one above all.
And when he touches them...
It is a delicate and
beautiful act of kindness...
And love.
And while others
may say, that...
by loving his disciples,
Jesus fell in love
with humanity.
I can explain to you,
why I believe...
That this Scripture
does not refer...
to a call, to a love
for human kind.
But instead,
refers more specifically
to his love
- of any...
- You can stop right there.
I know what you're
trying to insinuate,
and frankly, I don't like it.
- Chris, I'm just being...
- That's enough!
Okay, okay.
I didn't mean to make you angry.
I'm sorry.
Chris, I think you and
I, are a lot alike.
- I too am struggling.
- I'm not struggling.
Okay.
I went to a small
highschool in Arizona.
This kid transferred
in to sophomore year.
and he wasn't exactly popular.
They called him "the narc".
He was always telltaling,
he was just obnoxious.
He was very devoted
to Christ, however.
We bonded, in that sense.
Over time, we became
good friends.
Great friends even.
And when the other
kids would say to me:
Why do you spend time with that guy?
I did not care.
Because in his heart,
he was a good man.
His name was Marshall Harris.
Your zone leader, when
you were on the mission.
Chris, I know what happened in
Oregon with your mission companion.
And I don't judge you for it.
I know your struggle, and...
I know it well.
And I want you to know
we can help one
another, through this.
Let me help you through this.
No temptation has seized you,
except what is common to men.
And we need not be ashamed.
Get out.
- I care about you, Chris.
- Get out of my house!
We got bananas and raspberries.
To make splits.
Is everything okay?
I suddenly lost my appetite
for ice cream, Emily.
I'm sorry.
I'll be seeing you, Chris.
Goodbye, Emily.
What happened?
He ehm...
He wasn't feeling well.
I'm gonna get ready for bed.
That's a ladybug on a leaf.
- Hey sweety.
- Hey.
Hey ehm, what time are you
and RJ getting together?
Around three, I think.
Okay, so I call Kirsten and have
her come just a little earlier.
I won't be around tonight. I have
to help setup for the debut.
What's happening tonight?
It's my red jacket debut.
Congratulations again baby.
It's great.
Isn't that a rabbit?
What is that?
Thank you.
Um...
Did you call the
catering company?
Ask them to add 2 more tables, and the
china and the flowers, like Ida ?
No.
No, I completely forgot.
I'm sorry.
- Honey, it's your parents anniversary.
- Yes I know!
I just forgot, and I'm sorry.
I'll get on it.
Yes, okay.
Okay.
Thank you.
I'd like to level with you.
Okay.
I'm sorry ...
for abandoning you.
I'm sorry for the
way I treated you.
That was cruel.
And I'm sorry for not responding to any
of your letters, or phone calls.
I received them all.
Your letters.
And they touched me, deeply.
But I couldn't respond.
I truly loved...
the time, that we spent together.
But once I returned home,
I felt my father's shadow.
And his position and
the high authority,
looming over me.
Like a cloud.
He recommended that I go
to reparative therapy.
Which I did.
And eventually... I was deemed
worthy enough to continue...
my service to the church.
And then I met Emily.
And we had this amazing,
intense connection.
And I thought:
"Finally, a cure."
I sincerely believed...
that, if I got married, that I
would be given the strength...
to overcome this.
But every time I see a man
that I'm attracted to,
it's like something inside
of me is screaming,
to get out!
There is this message,
that is sent and received.
Instantly.
I am a religious man, RJ.
I know you are.
But I feel forsaken.
I have so much
pain, in my heart.
And I just deal with it.
It feels as if there's...
this...
axe, that is thrust
into my chest...
This pain.
The fasting, the prayers...
It consumes my life.
And there is...
little energy left,
for anything else.
I am not living honorably.
Chris, I feel so...
I care so much...
about you.
Look at me.
There is nothing wrong with us.
We're just victims...
Of a culture that
doesn't accept us.
May I touch you?
That face...
I've seen you in my dreams.
What? I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I thought that's
what you wanted.
It is.
What do you want me to do?
You see...
I missed you.
I missed you too.
I wanted this for so long.
This I pledge, as a
"Star Recruiter".
To live, by the Golden
Rule Philosophy.
To encourage and support
my team members.
This I pledge, as a brand
new "Star Recruiter".
Excellent. Give a round of
applause, ladies and gents.
So right now I have a special...
for you, it's fifty
percent off any product,
when you spend $ 40 or more
on beauty essential products.
Which is really good.
You had mentioned a
lipstick you wanted to try?
- Sure.
- Okay.
Are you alright, dear?
Honey?
Can I help you with something?
Dear?
Hey, baby.
Have you been sitting
here since I left?
Where were you?
Were you with RJ?
Yeah.
You think I'm such a fool.
What are you talking about?
Come on.
I know what you've been doing.
My heart is broken, Chris.
And I think I've always known.
But I hid it in the back
of my mind, because...
I thought, I could trust you.
You need to come clean.
- You need to be honest with me.
- What's wrong?
- I saw you. Chris.
- You saw what?
And you call yourself
a man of faith ?
I saw you...
with your friend RJ.
At that hotel, just
ten blocks from here.
You kissed him.
The way you kiss me.
I'm so stupid.
Because all the
signs were there.
They were just there...
and I ignored them.
- I'm so stupid.
- No.
No.
God only knows, what you do, when
you're out, travelling for work.
In one city after the
next, staying in hotels,
meeting strangers.
- Have there been others?
- No.
I don't believe you.
- I don't believe a word you say. No one?
- Emily.
There's been nobody else.
Have you been going to
see him in Seattle?
No.
I haven't seen him
since my mission.
Since your mission.
Hmm...
I couldn't imagine
what that was like.
What about me and Kelly?
- Has that thought ever crossed your mind?
- Yes
Yes, of course.
I'm so sorry, Emily.
Can we pray this away ?
It's the last thing we can do.
I will do, whatever it takes.
But you have to stop this.
I need you.
I need you. Chris.
What do we do?
What can I not give you...
that he can?
Please don't ask me that!
I have been devoted to you.
And this family.
The feelings that
I have for him...
I can never have for a woman.
Seeing him again, brought
everything back.
And I have tried,
to become something, that I
thought I was supposed to be.
But I can't.
I failed you.
I don't know what
to do with that.
I will not accept that.
You made a promise to me.
For eternity.
Is that what you want, Chris?
A life without me?
Destroying me?
Destroying us?
If that's what you
want, Chris...
You have to tell your family.
And tell them what?
The truth.
Hey guys.
- Come on in.
- How are you darling?
Good.
Have a seat, please.
So, what's the big news, guys?
We're still waiting on one person.
Chris, who?
Hey, come on in.
- It's okay.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
This is my friend, RJ.
Hey.
What is he doing here?
I wanted him here.
Trust me, okay?
So, how do you know
Chris and Emily, RJ?
- I'm just a friend.
- Okay.
I've known Chris for a while.
- That's great.
- Yeah.
- So what's going on?
Ehm...
Chris and I have something,
we'd like to tell you.
This isn't easy for me to say.
But I haven't been completely
honest with any of you.
And I feel like I
should come clean.
I...
I... I'm...
I'm gay.
I'm in love with him.
Chris.
I know that you love Emily.
But...
I guess, I just always kind
of assumed, you know ?
I do love you.
And I want you...
Both of you...
to be happy.
Thank you.
Son, we can work this through.
We can work this through again.
Again?
You...
You are a homewrecker !
Please make him leave.
I don't understand why.
Why did you invite him
here, in the first place?
I need him here.
- I'm gonna leave.
- No.
I think you should.
I knew who you were, as soon as
you walked through that door
and I think you should get up
and walk out, and
never come back.
Chris, I feel like this
is a family matter.
I.. I don't even understand
why I'm here.
Yeah, neither do I.
I think you should do exactly
what my father said.
- And you should go!
- Greg, sit down!
Chris!
How could you do this to Mom
and Dad, and let alone Emily?
What are you thinking man?
This has nothing
to do with them.
My brother is not gay.
- I've known him my whole life.
- I would know.
- Okay.
- RJ. RJ.
- I'm so sorry too.
Greg.
Greg!
- Please sit down.
- Greg! Greg!
- Sit down!
- Greg, please sit down.
Emily, honey, I'd love to know
your thoughts on all this.
I love you. I feel like
a failure, as a wife.
No.
But I'm not ready
to give up yet.
So... you're gay and
you're in love with a man.
That doesn't explain or
answer to me how you're...
you're going to leave your wife!
Abandon me!
And your daughter.
Your family, your church,
your Heavenly Father.
All, so that you can just...
have some momentary
self-indulgent fling!
This is about who I am.
I don't expect you
to forgive me.
But I hope, one day,
you can understand.
And you can help me, to
help Kaylee to understand.
- But this is something I have to do.
- No...
- Honey?
you do not abandon me.
You have to let me go.
No.
No, honey.
No. No. Never!
I can not let you go.
Why did you do this to me !?
I do not do it to hurt you
This is not the case, dear...
I hate you!
You get out of my house!
Hi.
You know my dad
never told my mum
about what happened
on our mission?
He kept it from her.
She could barely
look at me, today.
My dad's asked me to write a
letter to everyone we know,
telling them the truth.
I'm gonna do it.
I'm gonna honor him, and do it.
I'm gonna wait till after the anniversary
party and then, send them off.
One by one.
Hello?
- Is this Thomas Smith?
- Yes, it is.
Hello Thomas, this
is Noah Merrill,
I'm calling you from
Salt Lake City.
Yes, I know who you
are, of course.
Ehm, to what do I owe the honor?
Well, I'm afraid
this call is ehm...
regarding a rather...
sensitive issue.
Ehm, sure.
What is this regarding?
Several years ago, your
son RJ and my son Chris
were mission companions.
I see.
And I don't know, if
you knew this, but...
RJ is currently in
Salt Lake City.
No. I didn't know that.
Well...
he is, and ehm...
he's complicating things
for Chris and his wife.
They've been meeting at a
hotel, near Chris' home.
and ehm.. I just think it
would be good if you...
were to call RJ and convince
him, to go back to Seattle.
Brother Merrill, I...
I know, this must be
difficult for you, but...
RJ is a grown man.
I can call him and ask him to
leave Salt Lake City, but...
that doesn't mean he'll go.
Thomas, Chris and his wife are
thinking about
getting a divorce.
He's been doing great,
he's come so far.
Your son has just...
he brings confusion in the
spirit of Chris' life, and
I hate to say it, but I really
I think it was RJ, who seduced
Chris on his mission trip.
Again: I'm sorry for what you and
your familyare going through.
But to put the blame solely
on RJ, it's just not fair.
Your son is a part of
this, as much as RJ.
You know that.
Chris was fine until RJ
showed up at his door.
Noah,
I think you and I are a lot more
similar than we might guess.
I don't think so.
What kind of a father would let his
son parade around as a pansy ?
Now, hang on just one minute!
I'm very sorry for what you and
your family are going through,
but my son is a good boy.
He's a good boy and whatever is
happening in Salt Lake City,
is being reciprocated by your son,
or else, RJ would have left by now!
I am proud of my son.
And, this hasn't been
easy on me, but...
I love him, so much.
And he struggled too.
As has Chris.
RJ has been on a very
powerful spiritual journey...
to come to peace,
with who he is...
no matter what the
church says about it.
And Brenda and I...
we've started our journey.
And now, brother Merrill...
you and your family
have to begin yours
And if you ever say anything
bad about my son again...
you and I are gonna
have a problem.
Do you understand me?
Chris.
Why did I see him ?!
Now I see the damage I've done.
I'm holding on to
something from my past.
It's not just Chris.
It's everything that's locked
in me that's L.D.S.
♪ Here I make my solemn vow ♪
♪ To Keep His light
in front of me ♪
♪ In spite of what
the dark allows ♪
♪ Of what love comes unto me ♪
♪The seas may rage
for endless years ♪
♪ The wind may test and age me ♪
♪ Still I will keep his light in my heart ♪
♪ I know he will save me ♪
♪ Here I give myself to him ♪
♪ In sweet and clear surrender ♪
♪ I know his love is pure and true ♪
♪ I know his soul is tender ♪
♪ And if I sink under the waves ♪
♪ If Black Knight comes to claim me ♪
♪ I know my soul will be redeemed ♪
♪ My love for Him will save me ♪
Well, I just wanted
to start by saying
welcome to my family and
to my favourite people.
What else can I say but congratulations.
I love you both.
Well, let's get
uncle Noah appear.
I think he has something
he wants to say to us all.
Thank you.
I want to thank you all
for coming here tonight.
It is the 25th year, that
I've spent with my soul mate,
the love of my life,
Debra Merrill.
You know when I met her in a
conference centre in Cleveland, Ohio
I knew right away that is was more
than just a coincidence, that...
It was fate.
And...
I'm honoured...
to have such a
wonderful woman...
in my life.
And ehm...
and our three beautiful
children, and...
Emily, our daughter-in-law.
You see...
you don't get to choose, who
you love in this world.
Our Heavenly Father makes
those choices for us.
And...
in the end...
all we have, is family.
What are you doing?
- I'm leaving.
- Why?
You have no idea...
how happy I am, to have spent
this last week with you.
There's always a part of
me, that's gonna love you.
So before I go...
I wanna do something for you.
What?
Forgive me.
I just saved you a lot
of dollars, okay?
Do you know yet, what you're
gonna say to your father?
I already told him the truth.
But he can't accept it.
So I assume, all I've left
to say is: "I'm sorry".
But you've already done that.
Honey, you can't hold this in.
You need to talk to somebody.
I'm not a good person, am I?
Honey, of course you are.
I don't think this was a
surprise, to any of us.
Don't you think,
your dad is upset because he's...
shocked by this?
No.
I need you to
understand something.
Mom, can we please
talk about this later?
No.
We need to talk about this now.
You need to
understand something.
- You made these choices.
- Okay, Mom.
No, you don't listen.
I can't stand as a human being.
You made the choice...
to go on a mission.
You made the choice to get
married in the temple.
And these choices, honey...
they gave your father hope.
They gave me hope too.
Oh, honey,
All we have in this
life is each other.
- You know that?
- Yeah.
And honey, I love...
I love our life
And I love our family,
our eternal family...
and I love being L.D.S.
And I love our Heavenly Father.
I know, this has been
so hard for you.
But let me tell you...
as hard as this is,
you have to know,
that you are a child of God.
You are, and He loves you.
And if He can't accept you,
the way that you are.
just the way,He made you,
I let you know, I will.
Okay?
I will.
And your father will come around.
He will.
I've really hurt Emily, though.
Honey, she's gonna
need some time.
Okay?
And you'll give her that.
But right now you need
to work on Chris, okay?
Give her some time.
And then, you can help her.
And help Kaylee to understand,
what she's going through.
And what is happening
around her.
Okay?
My boy...
- I love you.
- It's gonna be okay.
- Yeah.
Whatever that stunt was,
you pulled last night...
it's made the 20 years,
that I've given the church,
mean nothing.
Nothing at all.
Of course they meant something.
And you broke that poor
girl's heart, with your lies.
You know that, right?
And I've raised
you, to be honest.
To be honest, I would have
to admit, to being gay.
I've been praying this
away, since I was a child.
I've been guilty every
day of my life.
Do you really want
me, to live the rest
of my life,
feeling this way?
If it means your
loyalty to God...
Then yes, I do.
- I have to go, Chris.
- Dad?
I have to go.
Can we please finish
this conversation?
We have nothing left to discuss.
Chris, what are you doing?
I am not letting you leave, without
finishing this conversation.
So you're embarrassed
to have a gay son?
Yes, I'm embarrassed
to have a gay son.
Why?
Cause it goes
against God's Laws.
I am your child.
I'm your son!
I live to make you proud.
I've manufactured
my entire life,
to please you,
because I love you.
Because I am proud of my father.
You're breaking my heart, Dad.
Please don't walk away from me.
Because I can't do
this without you.
You taught me to tell the
truth, no matter what.
And I'm finally doing that,
and you don't like it.
But I'm doing exactly what
you taught me to do.
I just want you to
have a good life.
I don't want you to struggle.
All I ever wanted, was to
make life easy for you.
I can't give you a second
helping with this.
I'm gonna be okay, Dad.
Everything is going to change.
But I promise you, I'm
going to be okay.
After the anniversary dinner,
the last thing I expected
was a letter from Chris.
He said many things.
But what stood out to
me, was three words:
I forgive you.
You see, I love Salt Lake.
Trying to convince myself,
that never seeing him
again, is for the best.
But in my heart...
I know it's not an issue...
of if I'll see him again.
But when.
***
Christmas present from OpenSubtitles.org
Log-in and enjoy VIP benefits until start of 2017