You take every case
personally, too.
(quietly): Enough.
- No, Rule Ten-- it's B.S.
"Never get personally involved
on a case."
Rule Ten served as a
firewall to your feelings.
They're both dead.
FRANKS: Your wife and daughter died
in the crash.
MAN:
I'm terribly sorry, Jethro.
(thunder cracks)
Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
(both grunt)
You expose this
witness, it ends me.
FBI Agent Tobias Fornell.
You think there's anything
you could say
that would surprise us?
I killed the man
who killed my family.
- You're barely hanging on.
VANCE: Gibbs!
It's Fornell. You need to get
to Mercy Point Hospital fast.
(tires screeching)
(panting):
You're gonna miss the turn.
(horn honking)
(tires screeching)
Careful!
(panting)
Need a little more
warning next time!
You're gonna be okay, Fornell.
We're almost there.
I've never seen
anyone this blue before.
Hurry.
Hey!
We need help!
In the back!
Come on.
Hurry, hurry.
Okay, we're at the hospital.
You're going to be fine.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
Uh, one second
she's laughing,
and the next,
she's laying on the ground.
What's her name?
Emily. Emily Fornell.
- Emily?
SPENCER: Come on...
Can you hear me? Emily.
Nothing. I can't find a pulse.
Call the cardiac team.
Counting for chest compressions.
One, two, three...
♪ NCIS 16x24 ♪
Daughters
Original Air Date on May 21, 2019
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
♪﻿﻿﻿ ♪
(gasps)
Hey.
Tobias.
Gibbs.
You're here.
Thank you. Thank God.
Hey, we came as soon
as we heard.
Where's Emily, huh?
Hey, Jack.
With the doctors.
What happened?
She was at some
college party.
I guess she collapsed.
They said she was
blue, Gibbs. Blue.
- And what are they saying now?
- They don't know.
It could be anything
between a bee sting
and a pulmonary embolism.
Her lungs are fine,
but we finished running
her blood, and...
She's gonna be okay?
We've stabilized her, yes,
but she is still in
critical condition.
I want to see her.
Of course.
- You family?
- Uncle.
Then you should
probably come with.
Okay.
I'm here, baby.
I'm here.
Why is she on a ventilator?
She wasn't getting
enough oxygen.
I thought you said
it wasn't her lungs.
Correct.
We were able to rule out a
pulmonary event rather quickly.
So what is it?
Has your daughter undergone
any surgeries recently?
FORNELL:
No.
Been prescribed any medication
for any pain syndromes?
No.
You got something to say,
say it.
Your daughter overdosed
on opioids.
(stammers)
Where did you get
your medical degree?
I know it's a hard
thing to hear,
but right now we've
got bigger problems.
Bigger than telling me that
my daughter is a dope addict?
Tobias...
I never suggested
she's an addict,
but that's a tomorrow
problem. Right now
we have a right-now problem.
She's not responding
to naloxone.
- It's a drug that we use...
- I know what it is!
Something you give
to dope addicts.
She appears to
be allergic.
It's caused a cascade response
in her vascular system.
That's interfering
with her sinus rhythm.
What does that mean?
We are walking
a very fine line.
Too much antidote, and we could
stop your daughter's heart.
Too little, and she
could asphyxiate.
No.
You have to prepare yourself
for the possibility
she won't survive the night.
- No.
But rest assured, we are doing
everything in our power to...
Everything in our power?!
Hey, hey.
Then why are you
the only one standing here?
Why is my little girl
alone in this room
when you've got a whole building
full of brainiacs
with medical degrees?
Mr. Fornell...
And how many more
at home sleeping?
So why don't you wake
their sorry asses up
and tell them to get in here and
figure this out? Do you hear me?
All hands on deck!
So no more standing around.
Get to work.
And save my daughter's life!
Look, I'm not gonna
press charges.
I appreciate it.
I get it.
I really do.
And he looks like
he's calmed down now.
It won't happen again.
No, it won't.
If he wants
to be let back inside,
he's gonna need
to leave his bazooka at home.
Hey, how's she doing?
- Same. Sloane's with her.
- And Fornell?
Yeah. We should probably
hang on to this for a while.
We stopped by that college
party like you asked.
TORRES:
And talked to Emily's friends.
BISHOP:
They said there's no way
she would have taken anything.
They think
maybe her drink was spiked.
Apparently
that's been happening a lot
on her campus lately.
So not an overdose.
A crime.
It's not our jurisdiction,
but we alerted Campus P.D.
They're all over it.
FORNELL:
I said I want them all.
Is something wrong
with your hearing?
Yeah, I heard you,
but the answer's no.
There a problem?
Yeah. I would like
to buy my daughter some flowers,
and this jackass
is giving me a hard time.
He wants them all.
I told Grumpelstiltskin here
he's more than welcome
to purchase up to two.
And you are more
than welcome to take those two
and shove them up your...
- Tobias, hey, come on.
- Two.
- Come on.
- Sorry.
- Let's go.
I'm not really!
What kind
of hospital pharmacy
has a limit
on flower arrangements?
It wasn't an overdose.
She was drugged.
I suppose that should
make me feel better.
Except now
I want my gun back.
Campus P.D.-- they're on it.
Campus P.D. Wouldn't trust them
to write a jaywalking ticket.
Gibbs, I know
you haven't been playing
with a full deck lately,
but you need
to get your ass down to...
And you need to get
your head in the game.
Emily needs you, Tobias.
Your daughter needs you.
What you need to do is
go upstairs right now
and sit by her bed.
And I'm gonna go home and
pick up some clothes for you.
And you're not gonna
yell at anybody,
and you're not
gonna shoot anybody.
Got it?
Got it.
Where you going now?
To find some nail polish.
(sniffs)
DIANE:
Yeah, that's a great idea.
I mean, it's not like Tobias has
a drinking problem or anything.
Go ahead and shoot.
See if I care. I'm already dead.
Oh, and thanks for
that, by the way.
Ruined my favorite
wool coat.
Got blood all over it. Dick.
This is not happening.
(laughing):
Yes. Yeah, it's happening.
The question you really
have to ask yourself is,
what's happening?
Yeah, I'm asking.
Here's a hint. You're talking
to your dead ex-wife.
It's usually a red flag.
But the real question is,
what are you doing
being a cabana boy
instead of going to find
the punk who dosed
my little girl?
What? Excuse me!
Tobias doesn't need
your old boxers.
He needs you on the job.
This case is not even
NCIS jurisdiction.
How did you ever father a child
with such a little,
tiny, shriveled....?
I am not doing this.
I'm not doing this.
Looks like we might
be doing this.
Why does this stairwell smell
like burnt cheese?
What do you want from me?
I want
what my other ex-husband wants.
I want you to find the guy
who drugged our daughter.
It's not that simple.
Oh, you have got to let
this Rule Ten nonsense go.
So you're personally
involved in the case.
Big deal. You also have
no fashion sense. Life goes on.
When you get personally
involved, you make mistakes.
No, that is just
a big fat excuse
for the real problem here,
and you know it.
You are running, Jethro.
You're running scared.
So you need to ask yourself--
are you a man or a mouse?
'Cause if you're a man,
get your head in the game!
I want Emily Fornell's case.
Took you long enough.
I already wasted
too much time.
All right, well,
I'll skip my prepared speech
and go right
to the highlight reel. No.
Leon, whoever drugged her
is still out there.
They did it before.
They are gonna do it again.
Almost a dozen
cases last month.
Next time could be a lot worse.
As much as I would love
to unleash you on the bastard
that did this to Emily,
I cannot sanction it.
- Come on!
- Gibbs, your personal connection
to this case is bad enough, and
with the lack of jurisdiction,
that's a good way to get us
all fired and probably worse.
Duck!
Jurisdiction--
or in Latin,
iuris dicende causa--
the administration of justice.
It came into use
in the latter part
of the 14th century...
- Skip ahead, Duck.
Ah, right.
Last year
the owner of the property
where the alleged criminal act
occurred
hired a contractor
to add a second story.
Unfortunately,
the contractor sued the
property owner for fraud.
That case is
now in court.
Mm-hmm.
Last month, however,
this same contractor
was hired,
but this time
on a Navy off-base house.
I see.
So, now...
this Navy contractor
is in a legal dispute...
Stop. You had me
at iuris dicende causa.
Yes,
it's within
our purview
to investigate
when one of our contractors
is involved
in a criminal probe.
However tangential.
We good to go?
Torres, talk
to any other victims.
Bishop, McGee,
interview everyone
who was at the party.
(phone rings)
See if there's
any cell phone footage.
Chapsnats. Whatever.
On it.
Tell Sloane to work up
a profile on our suspect.
Is everything okay?
What do you think
that was about?
I...
Maybe he got
a Chapsnat.
(laughing):
I'm not kidding, Dad.
I hate flowers.
You never got the memo?
What kind of
self-respecting girl
does not like flowers?
That's sexist,
twice over.
Hi, Uncle Gibbs.
Hi, Em.
Feeling better?
Fine, actually.
One minute she looks
like death warmed over...
- Hey!
- and the next she is critiquing
my interior decorating skills.
EMILY: The doctor said they found the
sweet spot with the naloxone.
I just... can't believe
this happened to me.
- Forget about that.
- I'm so careful, too.
Do you know who did it?
No.
Not yet. But we're going to.
Torres is on it.
We can forget
about that, too.
You're gonna be okay.
That's what's important.
Uh, when you going home?
One more test
and she's all yours.
Nurse?
EMILY (chuckles):
I can walk.
What happened to my toes?
GIBBS:
Looks like
your father happened.
I was just returning
the favor.
You touch my feet again,
and I'm filing
a restraining order.
(chuckles)
What was with the 911?
So, Vance gave you
jurisdiction?
Well, yeah, but it sounded
like you don't want our help.
Oh, I want.
This-- This opioid thing.
Always made me crazy,
but now it's personal.
Right there with you.
Some punk drugged
my little girl.
Some dealer sold that punk
the drugs.
Promise me
that we will get them.
Every single
last one of them.
Yeah, right there with you.
The chemist who made
the drugs, his mom,
her dog walker, and screw
probable cause and warrants.
We're gonna find them
wherever they are,
and we're gonna put a bullet
in their heads.
I know this is just the fight
you've been itching for.
Promise me. Promise me
we're gonna get them all.
So you didn't actually
see the guy
who spiked Emily's drink?
I didn't see him
do it, no,
but Olivia and Hannah
said they did.
ALEXIS: Uh, tall guy. Was lurking
around her all night.
Had a nose ring.
Do you have a name?
No, but, Spencer,
you talked to him?
Just for a second.
ALEXIS: Can't believe
this happened to Emily.
She doesn't drink,
doesn't smoke.
Is she gonna be okay?
Yes. She's already home
from the hospital.
McGEE: But this could've been
a whole lot worse.
Is there anything else
you guys can think of?
No.
Um...
nope.
Care to try that answer again?
I found
this...
by the bar when we were
cleaning up this morning.
Is there a reason
you didn't mention this sooner?
Because it could be anybody's.
And we didn't want to get
the wrong person in trouble.
- But...
it's possible the person
who spiked Emily's drink
dropped this.
And we definitely
want to get him
in trouble.
Well, if this is
what I think it is,
someone's definitely
getting in trouble.
Starting with you two,
if I find out
you're withholding
any other evidence.
Seven of the victims
on her campus
were able to give us
descriptions of the guy
they think
drugged them.
- How many had nose rings?
- One.
That's our guy.
Yeah, now all we got to do
is just find him.
And I can help
with that.
I analyzed the pill
Emily's friend found
at the party.
It has the exact same
chemical composition
as the opioid
she was drugged with.
Our guy must've dropped it.
Any DNA?
Uh, nothing usable.
But... through the magic
of chemical science,
I still
have a lead. The pill
is not pharmaceutical grade.
Take a look at
the optical isomers...
No.
Yeah, we're not gonna do that.
Oh, right, I forgot.
You're both Level IIs.
Bottom line, this
is a bootleg drug.
And if we can figure out
where this drink-spiking jerk
got it...
It might lead
back to him.
Kase,
good work.
Torres, BOLO on the pill.
See if it shows up
in any other drug busts.
And don't mention
any of this to Fornell.
Copy that.
Fornell?
Level II?
(typing)
"Fifth-grade
science or lower"?
Okay, I'll take that.
Why can't we mention
this to Fornell?
Well, what would your dad do
to some guy
who tried to drug you?
Probably the same thing
that you'd do
if someone tried
to do that to Bishop.
(doorbell rings)
Here. You're late.
Meatloaf is
getting cold.
It wasn't much better warm.
You're more than welcome
to cook our next meal.
Here.
Have a date rape straw.
It can detect five
common sedatives. A gift
from my helicopter parent.
Sounds like
a smart parent.
Well, can you please
tell him that I'm fine?
It happened,
it's over. I would like
to put this behind me.
He is right here.
And the best defense
is a good offense.
Says the man who put
a five-pound dongle
on my key chain.
- Yeah.
Pepper spray.
It'll stop a bear.
Ooh. Almost forgot.
(sighs)
Help.
DIANE:
For once I'm with Tobias.
Back him up.
Back him up,
or I'm gonna
set up shop
in your bathroom.
Bears can be dangerous.
Good boy.
FORNELL:
Like it?
It's a blinding
flashlight.
1,000 lumens.
It'll stop a bear, too.
That's it.
I'm leaving.
I have a student newspaper
meeting in an hour.
I'll walk you
to the car.
I'll go with.
Nobody's coming with.
I can walk myself to my car.
And any bear that gets
in my way is a dead man.
(sighs)
It was a hell of a lot easier
when I could solve all
of her problems by just
taking her in my arms and
singing "Hush, Little Baby."
Ooh! She forgot
the stun gun.
Well?
Nope.
No?
So you're just gonna
ignore me now?
Pedro Hernandez.
You never answered
Tobias's question.
Are you gonna
get them?
- Get who?
- Don't play dumb.
The punk who drugged
my little girl.
The dealer who gave
the punk the drugs.
- My team's working on it.
- Your team?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, your team has
to follow the rules.
Sometimes the bad guy gets away
when you follow the rules.
He hasn't gotten away yet.
If it comes to it,
are you going to do for my baby
what you did for yours?
What do you want from me?
I want to know
who you are!
I don't know who I am!
Who are you
talking to?
Nobody.
Yes, you were.
And you had...
I don't know.
Your tone.
It was familiar.
It was the Diane tone.
Were you having a conversation
with our dead ex-wife?
No.
Look, it's
perfectly normal.
People talk
to deceased family members
all the time.
You can be honest about it.
Is that
what you were doing?
Yeah, maybe.
(laughing):
Oh, my God.
You-- you're really going crazy.
(phone ringing)
Going totally crazy.
And you've got
Diane stuck in your head.
Yeah, it's Gibbs.
No. No, that's Fornell.
(laughing continues)
He's fine.
Where?
All right. Be there.
I'm fine.
You're not fine.
GIBBS:
Where is he?
Over here.
Police found him passed out.
Looks like a drug overdose.
Paramedics revived him
with naloxone.
They found these
in his pocket.
Same triangle mark as the pill
Emily was drugged with.
Special Agent Gibbs, NCIS.
Need to ask
a few questions.
Can you take
the cuffs off him?
No, this guy's
going to jail.
What's the charge?
Possession of a narcotic
without a prescription.
Was he dealing?
No.
Cuffs stay on.
You got two minutes.
What'd you want to ask me?
You got a family?
I did.
My wife didn't want the kids
to see me like this, so...
I'm trying to get clean.
I am. It's just...
When you're ready...
call me.
So, what'd you really
want to ask me?
Where'd you get these?
The guy's name
is Professor Ralphie.
That's what everyone
calls him, anyway.
Lives by the campus.
Sells to all the kids.
You got an address?
I'll even draw you a map.
(hip hop playing inside)
NCIS. Open up.
He was a
pharmaceutical rep.
Lost his job for
skimming meds.
(sighing):
Oh, for Pete's sake.
Are you waiting
for an invitation?
Kick it in.
Maybe this'll help.
♪ When I stepped in the game,
all of you knew my name ♪
♪ When I leave, I'll be good
long as I got same... ♪
Gibbs...
GIBBS:
Nose ring.
It's our guy.
I'll check the back.
Gibbs?
Hi, Uncle Gibbs.
EMILY: If I had known Ralphie
was in trouble,
I would've called 911.
The foam cone around
his nose suggests anoxia
following
pulmonary edema.
In layman's terms, that is...
Heroin overdose.
I don't get it.
He told me
he doesn't touch the stuff.
Needle in his arm
suggests otherwise.
Dust for prints.
What are you gonna tell my dad?
Question is,
what are you gonna tell him?
It's not what you think.
I just came by to pick up
a little something,
and Ralphie invited me
to party,
so I stayed.
So he didn't spike your drink
the other night, did he?
Is he your boyfriend?
No.
He's your dealer.
FORNELL:
Your what?
Your dealer?
- My daughter has a dealer?
- Dad, calm down.
Oh, Dad is not calming down.
Then back off.
He's just a friend.
Everything is under control.
Really? Almost dying
in the ER one day
and getting high
with a corpse the next
is your idea of "under control"?
What does out of control
look like?
You need help, Emily.
My life is none
of your business.
None of my what?
I am the only parent
that you have left,
in case you didn't notice.
- How dare you?
(exhales)
You get back here.
Boss, we got a problem.
You think?
No, the syringe.
There's no prints on it.
It's been wiped clean.
JIMMY:
Yeah, and check this out.
I found a secondary
injection point.
Looks like he was jabbed
from behind. Gibbs,
I think this crime scene
was staged.
This wasn't
an accidental overdose.
- It was a murder.
SPENCER: A what?
What are you doing here?
I live here.
You live with an opioid dealer
who's got a nose ring?
That slip your mind
when we talked this morning?
SPENCER: Do these handcuffs
have to be so tight?
Yes.
This is all a big
misunderstanding.
Great. Can't wait
to hear all about it.
DIANE:
Me, too.
(whispering):
You got to be kidding me.
Sorry, what's that, boss?
You got to be kidding me
that this is all
a big misunderstanding.
Yeah, that's real smooth,
Woodchuck.
Excuse me, boss.
Nice watch, McGee.
Thanks. Let's go.
- You coming?
- No.
I am most definitely not coming.
All right.
- What now?
You mean, besides
my daughter being a drug addict?
And I blame you.
Me?!
You're a piece of work, Diane!
When I was killed, Tobias
needed you more than anything,
and where were you?
I was right here.
Yeah, "right here,"
getting him fired from the FBI.
He was a single father
trying to raise a teenage girl
all by himself,
struggling with alcoholism,
and you take away the one thing
that was keeping him stable?
- And now look what happened.
- I know what happened.
Y-You don't think that I know?
- Oh, blah, blah, blah.
- Not a day goes by
that I don't think about what happened.
Yada, yada, yada, tell it
to the judge.
(sighs)
What are we doing here?
You still haven't answered
Tobias's question.
And now you haven't
answered mine.
- Which is what?
- Somebody got
my baby hooked on drugs.
And now she's wrapped up
in a murder?
You got a question
in there somewhere?
Yeah. If your badge
can't get this guy,
are you gonna get him anyway?
This is all your fault.
You owe Tobias.
You owe all of us.
Hey.
(chuckles): I heard about your
famous elevator talks, and,
and I was walking by,
a-and I thought I heard...
Yeah, but you're alone,
so, uh...
You know what? I'm just gonna
stand here with my eyes closed
until you walk away.
Where you been?
Impounding Ralphie's
car. Where's Emily?
I don't know,
she won't talk to me.
But I need to find out
where this started,
who gave her that first pill.
You don't go
straight to dealers.
So I figured I'd come
where the action was.
Yeah.
Okay, what do we know
on the victim?/
Um...
(clears throat)
Before Professor Ralphie
was a pharmaceutical rep,
he was a student
at Emily's college.
Pharmacy school, which
he flunked out of.
Winning.
BISHOP: Other than a few
jaywalking tickets,
he's managed to stay
under the radar.
TORRES: Not much in
his credit card statements.
Then again, dealers
are mostly cash.
Actually, I...
What?
Actually, I should go.
Try to talk to Emily again.
Maybe she knows something.
Okay, who killed him?
Rival dealer?
Maybe a drug buy gone bad?
Oh, my gut says, if we want
to find Ralphie's killer,
we find out where he was
getting his supply.
What do you want from me?
We want to know where Ralphie
was getting his supply.
I don't know.
I put an ad on the school
website for a roommate.
Ralphie answered.
I, I hardly know the guy.
Please don't play dumb.
It's so unattractive.
I'm not playing, okay?
I'm an art major.
My brother was the smart one.
Well, then, maybe you should
call him up and have him explain
to you obstruction of justice.
Wh-What did I obstruct?
Well, for starters, you told me
that Olivia and Hannah
saw someone spike Emily's drink.
McGEE: Except we spoke
to both of them,
and they never said that.
Maybe I heard wrong.
Or maybe you knew that
Emily had a drug problem.
And you were covering up
for her because you knew
that it would lead
back to you.
(laughs): O-Okay,
you guys are way off base.
Sure, I knew Emily was using,
but I didn't know
how bad it had gotten.
I would have never introduced
her to Ralphie if I'd known.
Okay, your
"get out of obstruction" card
is about to expire.
Where does your roommate
get his supply?
Going once...
...going twice.
- Whoa-- hey, hey.
He got his supply
from some pill-happy doctor
that Emily
had introduced him to.
Do you have a name?
No.
I-I swear.
But... his office
was in Littleton.
He was a podiatrist, I think?
Hey, hello there.
I'm Dr. Berman.
- Tobias Fornell.
- Yeah.
So, uh, my nurse tells
me that you're suffering
from a little, uh, hammertoe?
Been a problem for years.
Oh, okay, well, let's take
a look at it, shall we?
By any chance,
does my last name
sound familiar to you? Fornell?
No, but, uh, my nurse tells me
that you're a new patient.
I am, but my daughter
used to come here.
I dropped her off a few times.
Her name's Emily.
Doesn't ring a bell.
Your foot is perfectly normal,
Mr. Fornell.
(laughs)
Oh, there is absolutely nothing
normal about me, trust me.
(both chuckle)
I'm here
because I saw your name
on a credit card statement
belonging to a drug dealer.
(laughs): I'm not sure
I'm following. Uh...
A drug dealer...
...who's been selling drugs
to my daughter.
It's funny,
isn't it,
that both she and he should go
to the same pill-happy doctor.
It's what we call in the biz
a coincidence.
Except maybe it's not.
You following?
No.
You'll have to excuse me.
Oh, I will not.
I will not excuse you.
I will never excuse you.
Well, no, so I'm confused.
Did you find the doctor or not?
Well, it wasn't that hard.
There was one podiatrist
in Littleton,
but there was a small problem.
What?
Uh, Fornell beat us to him.
He must have seen
something in the squad room
that tipped him off.
How bad?
We got there just in time,
but Fornell was getting ready
to waterboard the guy.
The doc said he's not gonna
press charges...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I know the drill.
BERMAN:
I have done nothing wrong.
Your daughter came to me and she
was in pain, so I treated her.
She had a bone spur, you
prescribed her opioids?
- Oh, thank God.
- What do you do for a hangnail, morphine?
Fornell asked me to review
his daughter's medical records.
I think I made things worse.
- Tobias.
- Have you ever heard of aspirin?
Tobias, calm down.
Everybody else, sit down.
Special Agent Gibbs. I only have
one question for you.
You know that guy?
Sit down.
Do you know that guy?
Look, your agents have already
told me about your concerns,
but I can assure you,
I have
never prescribed anyone
enough opioids for them
to start dealing,
much less this guy.
You got my little girl
hooked on drugs.
- I saw him once.
JIMMY: Okay, all right.
It says here
you were Luna Bay Labs'
top prescriber in the district?
Got a free trip to Cancun.
Her friends said that
she'd never touched the stuff
until you prescribed
it. And for what?
To work on your tan?
Everything I've done
is perfectly legal,
so if your drug dealers
are selling drugs, they're
getting it from someplace else.
And-- yeah, and you are free
to audit my records
if you don't believe me.
(knocking on door)
Hey.
You done auditing
those records?
What's taking you so long?
Working on it.
Thought you and Emily were
seeing Dr. Grace tonight.
She won't go.
Found out today
she hasn't been
to class in weeks.
Her school doesn't even have
a student newspaper.
Gibbs, how did I miss this?
How did I totally
and completely miss this?
Everybody did.
The harder
I try to help her,
the more I'm driving her away.
I am over my head.
I don't know what to do.
I need...
I need her mother.
What are the chances
you're really talking to...?
No. No way.
- Just ask her what I should do.
- No.
Tobias, it's not gonna happen.
And tell me what she says.
Easy peasy.
Tobias, look,
I'm not really talking
to Diane. I just...
You're losing your mind?
Fine, I'll take that.
Because I'm losing my daughter,
and you know what that
will do to me, so if there's...
if there is even
a one-out-of-a-thousand chance
that you are talking
to our ex-wife,
then humor me. I beg you because
I'm at the end of my rope.
Jethro, tell me what sh-she says
I should do, please.
Okay.
- She says...
DIANE: What?
What?
Nice to know
things don't change.
Well, certainly
not that sweater.
God, I told you to get
rid of that years ago.
What do I do, Diane?
Stop trying to do anything.
Take off your Mr. Fix-It hat
and just be there
for your daughter.
That's not very actionable.
Emily doesn't need
action right now,
she just needs her father,
not solutions.
You just be...
her father.
I'm sorry
I couldn't protect you.
I'm sorry I didn't answer
the phone that night.
(phone rings)
Yeah. Gibbs.
McGEE:
Boss, hey.
We finished auditing
that doctor's records.
GIBBS:
And?
He was telling the truth.
He wasn't prescribing enough
pills for Ralphie to deal.
Ralphie was prescribing them
to himself.
Yeah, looks like Ralphie
stole a prescription pad
from the doctor's office,
has been forging scripts.
And then was getting them filled
with a pharmacist
who was willing to look
the other way.
Got a name, bring 'em in.
Who?
Time to buy some more flowers.
You're kidding me.
The flower Nazi?
Yup.
Thank you.
Don't mention it,
and by that, I mean...
Never mention it.
I know.
You had to know
the prescriptions
Ralphie was bringing you
were forged.
I mean, tens of thousands
of pills from the same doctor?
You can't prove
what I know.
I can prove that the syringe
that was used to killed Ralphie
was sold in your store.
Yeah, I sell a lot of syringes.
So, what's funny
about this one is
that the murderer
tried to, uh, wipe it
of its prints,
but you know what he forgot?
It's not my problem.
He forgot to wipe the needle,
so we were able
to pull touch DNA,
and it was yours, in fact,
which kind of makes it
your problem now.
Just in time. He is about
to sing like a bird.
Look, it-it was
an accident, okay?
Who's Grumpelstiltskin now?
I-I got worried
when NCIS started
poking around.
I went to warn Ralphie,
and things just got out of hand.
And that's case closed,
gentlemen.
This case, yeah,
but if you want
to kill the snake,
you got to cut off the head.
Gibbs...
...we gonna go
all the way or not?
Don't forget the date.
What now?
Look,
it really was an accident.
Where'd you get the pills
you sold to Ralphie?
Same place I get
all my pills,
from the pharmaceutical companies.
- No.
Emily Fornell had counterfeit
opioids in her blood.
Which means that
you were filling
Ralphie's forged prescription
with gray market pills.
Pills that were
coming across
the border from Canada,
so I hear.
From who?
Sounds like Gibbs been
working a side project.
I want a name.
No way.
You're going to prison
for murder.
You do not want to mess
with this guy.
Oh, yeah, I do.
Yeah, I do. Trust me.
Well, I don't.
Maybe I go to prison,
maybe I-I get off.
You're not gonna get off.
I give you that name,
I'm a dead man.
You are already dead.
Emily...
I'm going back to my dorm.
I just came by
to pick up a few things.
- We need...
- To see Dr. Grace?
No, we don't, but maybe you do.
If you think so.
There's nothing wrong with me.
And nothing that
needs to be fixed.
And there's nothing
for you to do.
All I need from you
is for you to leave me alone!
(softly):
I need help, Daddy.
I know.
(crying)
I'm so sorry.
I'm so, so sorry.
Me, too, baby. Me, too.
I love you so much.
- Your mother, too.
- I know.
She told me.
When I was in
the hospital,
I had a dream
that I saw her.
She said she loved me
to the moon and back
and that Gibbs's house
smelled like burnt cheese.
(laughs)
Yeah, we got him.
And I didn't have to get
all Pedro Hernandez
on anybody, either.
Except you're not done
with this one yet, are you?
Why are you here?
Aside from me losing my mind.
Oh, please,
you were never that sane
to begin with.
But why now?
Because you needed a kick
in the pants to take this case.
Remind me why again?
When you get
personally involved,
you make mistakes.
Right.
Except you and I both know
that that rule is crap.
The reason that you don't want
to get personally involved
is that you're afraid
to feel, Jethro.
Ever since your family
was killed,
you shut yourself off
so you wouldn't have
to get hurt again.
And work, the one place
where you were really alive,
well, couldn't have that,
so you had to build up walls
there, too.
And that is the reason that
I am really here, Jethro,
'cause now those walls
are starting to crumble.
You're starting
to let people in again,
and it is scary
and, for someone
like you, dangerous.
So you reached out for help.
Voilà.
I'm just talking to myself.
Yeah, maybe,
but at least
you're talking.
And when you're ready
to talk some more,
we're all here for you, inside.
All you got to do is ask.
You don't have to face
the danger alone.
(clattering upstairs)
All right, what now?
Hello, Gibbs.
No time for pleasantries.
You're in danger.
Well, aren't you gonna
say something?
Ziva.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man