1
00:00:02,520 --> 00:00:17,520
街區大作戰 Attack The Block 2011

2
00:01:38,520 --> 00:01:47,520
字幕製作：TGHD電玩人

3
00:01:52,875 --> 00:01:54,284
嗨 媽
Hi, Mum.

4
00:01:59,749 --> 00:02:02,663
對不起 以前沒時間打電話
Sorry, I couldn't call sooner. Haven't had the chance.

5
00:02:08,083 --> 00:02:12,159
沒 我正在走回公寓 下班了
No, I'm just walking back to the flat My shift ran over.

6
00:02:17,041 --> 00:02:19,280
很多孩子在放煙花
Loads of kids with firework burns.

7
00:02:20,999 --> 00:02:22,989
爸爸好嗎
How's Dad?

8
00:02:29,708 --> 00:02:32,077
下周怎麼樣
What about next weekend?

9
00:02:32,124 --> 00:02:34,493
我可以坐火車去 住一夜
I could take the train up, stay the night

10
00:02:46,333 --> 00:02:49,035
我週日給你打電話 做個安排
I'll call you on Sunday. We'll make a plan.

11
00:02:51,791 --> 00:02:53,781
要掛了
Gotta go now.

12
00:02:54,583 --> 00:02:56,952
好 再見
OK. Bye.

13
00:03:07,041 --> 00:03:08,865
來
Go on, man.

14
00:03:08,958 --> 00:03:10,948
到她身後
Hey, cut across her.

15
00:03:19,791 --> 00:03:21,248
天
Oh, fuck.

16
00:03:26,791 --> 00:03:29,244
給我手機 給我手機
Give me the phone, give me the phone. Give me the phone!

17
00:03:30,833 --> 00:03:33,830
錢 包 把包給我
The money, the purse. Give me the purse, give it to me.

18
00:03:34,166 --> 00:03:35,575
別不老實
Don't fuck about.

19
00:03:35,624 --> 00:03:37,614
喂 拜託
Hey. Please.

20
00:03:38,583 --> 00:03:40,324
-給我戒指 -不值錢
Give me that ring. It's not worth...

21
00:03:40,374 --> 00:03:42,364
閉嘴 想死嗎
Shut up. Wanna get murked, innit?

22
00:03:47,208 --> 00:03:48,866
-笨蛋 -放開我
Stupid... Get off me!

23
00:03:49,624 --> 00:03:51,282
怎麼了
Oh! Oi, what?

24
00:03:52,833 --> 00:03:56,115
-你太勇敢了 -快點吧 警察要來了
Boy, you're too brave. Quick, fam, 'fore the feds come.

25
00:03:56,166 --> 00:03:57,623
管什麼警察
Fuck the feds, man.

26
00:03:58,583 --> 00:03:59,826
拿去吧
Take it.

27
00:04:04,541 --> 00:04:06,365
看 看
Look, man. Look.

28
00:04:07,458 --> 00:04:08,619
天
Fuck!

29
00:04:15,541 --> 00:04:18,622
-喂 她跑了-她有股邪氣
Oi, she's duckin'. Hey, fam, she's ghostin'.

30
00:04:20,208 --> 00:04:22,910
-別管了 -有人炸我們
Allow it. Somebody's bombin' us, blood.

31
00:04:22,958 --> 00:04:25,411
-是個煙花 -這麼大的煙花
No, man, it's just a firework. Some big firework.

32
00:04:25,541 --> 00:04:27,614
正好 說不定車上有很多財物
Nice whip. Could be bare valuables in there.

33
00:04:48,999 --> 00:04:50,385
Raargh!

34
00:04:50,416 --> 00:04:52,157
天 有東西
Shit. There's something... Whoa!

35
00:05:03,249 --> 00:05:05,038
是什麼東西
What the fuck was that?

36
00:05:05,083 --> 00:05:07,831
像猩猩的東西 真的
Some orang-utan type thing, I'm not even lying, bruv.

37
00:05:07,874 --> 00:05:10,825
它逃走了 像是小精靈
Hey, it's breezin', man. It looked like Dobby the house elf.

38
00:05:10,874 --> 00:05:13,327
摩西被小精靈劃傷了
Moses got shanked by a Dobby.

39
00:05:14,624 --> 00:05:17,159
我去追它 我要殺了它
I'm chasing that down. I'm killing that.

40
00:05:18,083 --> 00:05:19,161
看著
Watch.

41
00:05:19,249 --> 00:05:21,571
-復仇 -我要踩死它
Payback, fam. I'm proper stampin' that.

42
00:05:21,624 --> 00:05:24,575
-這是冒險 -第二回合 哥們 第二回合
It's gone in adventure. Round two, bruv. Round two.

43
00:05:24,624 --> 00:05:26,531
遊戲時間 哥們
Playtime, bruv.

44
00:05:32,374 --> 00:05:33,747
我帶了工具
I got my tool.

45
00:05:33,791 --> 00:05:36,539
都別妨礙我 我要干死它
No man stunting. I'm gonna fuck this thing up!

46
00:05:36,583 --> 00:05:38,289
你有意見啊 摩西
Yo, you got beef now, Moses.

47
00:05:41,791 --> 00:05:44,824
-派斯特 有鞭炮嗎 -有
Yo, Pest, got them bangers? Yeah.

48
00:05:44,874 --> 00:05:46,532
扔進去
Jam, man.

49
00:06:02,416 --> 00:06:03,873
交給我
It's mine.

50
00:06:06,124 --> 00:06:08,790
幫幫我 幫幫我
Hey, back me! Back me!

51
00:06:19,208 --> 00:06:23,829
-天 真臭 -我們把他打殘了
Ah, no, man, that is rank. Hey, we broke it up.

52
00:06:23,874 --> 00:06:27,073
-那是什麼 -已經死了
What is that, cuz? That ain't no is. That's a was.

53
00:06:27,124 --> 00:06:29,659
我說過 是一種怪物 像猴子
I told you, some exotic creature, like a monkey thing.

54
00:06:29,708 --> 00:06:32,871
它是從天上掉下來的 難道天上下猴子嗎
That fell out of the sky. You trying to tell me it's raining monkeys?

55
00:06:32,916 --> 00:06:34,953
不是猴子 猴子都有毛
That ain't no monkey. Monkeys ain't bald.

56
00:06:34,999 --> 00:06:37,617
是個怪東西 我不知道是什麼
No, that's some weird thing. I don't know what that is.

57
00:06:37,666 --> 00:06:40,035
-不好說 -知道是什麼嗎
I ain't even gonna say. You know what that is?

58
00:06:40,083 --> 00:06:43,116
我告訴你們是什麼 那是外星人 真的
I'll tell you what that is. That's a alien, bruv. Believe it.

59
00:06:43,166 --> 00:06:45,950
肯定來自外太空 想佔領地球
It must have come from outer space, trying to take over Earth.

60
00:06:45,999 --> 00:06:48,238
但是降落錯了地方
But it landed in the wrong place.

61
00:06:48,291 --> 00:06:50,281
來錯了地方
The wrong place!

62
00:06:50,333 --> 00:06:53,247
-歡迎來到倫敦 -歡迎來找死
Welcome to London, mo fucker. Welcome to the ends, brother.

63
00:06:53,291 --> 00:06:56,372
在這一片 沒人敢招惹我們 知道嗎
This is the block. And nobody fucks with the block, do you get me?

64
00:06:56,416 --> 00:06:59,034
這一片街區
The B-L-O-C-K.

65
00:06:59,083 --> 00:07:02,128
Brap. Brap. Brap. Brap. Brap...

66
00:08:02,249 --> 00:08:04,867
-你怎麼了 -出事了
You all right, love? Not really.

67
00:08:05,583 --> 00:08:06,992
-你住在附近？-是的
Do you live here? Yeah.

68
00:08:07,041 --> 00:08:09,410
-來 我送你回家 -謝謝
Come along, I'll take you home. Thank you.

69
00:08:09,458 --> 00:08:11,413
來
Come on.

70
00:08:13,416 --> 00:08:16,746
你真可憐 剛才臉色蒼白
You poor thing. Pale as a ghost, you were.

71
00:08:16,791 --> 00:08:19,326
肯定嚇得不輕
Must have given you such a nasty shock.

72
00:08:19,416 --> 00:08:22,662
-你真不喝茶嗎 -不了 喝水就行
You sure you don't want a cup of tea? No, thanks. Water's fine.

73
00:08:25,166 --> 00:08:27,452
該死的煙花
Bloody fireworks.

74
00:08:28,166 --> 00:08:30,914
應該禁止燃放
I think they should ban them.

75
00:08:30,958 --> 00:08:34,288
就好像發生了第三次世界大戰
Could be the third world war out there, you wouldn't know the difference.

76
00:08:34,333 --> 00:08:36,323
警察怎麼說的
What did the police say?

77
00:08:37,791 --> 00:08:42,199
他們說今晚是他們最忙的一天 也沒來
Said it was one of the busiest nights of the year. Bet they don't even turn up.

78
00:08:42,958 --> 00:08:46,039
如今年輕人都不怕警察了
Only it's not like the kids are scared of 'em no more.

79
00:08:46,083 --> 00:08:49,578
帶著刀 牽著大狗 好像街區是他們的一樣
Walking around with knives, great big dogs, like they own the block.

80
00:08:49,624 --> 00:08:53,617
說句粗話 真是他媽一群混蛋
Excuse my French, but they're fucking monsters, ain't they?

81
00:08:54,790 --> 00:08:57,076
是啊 一群混蛋
Yeah. Fucking monsters.

82
00:08:58,957 --> 00:09:01,410
-它的肋骨 -你找到什麼了嗎
..its ribs and that. Have you found anything?

83
00:09:03,166 --> 00:09:05,868
求你給我兩英鎊 我去雞肉世界
I beg you give me two pound to go to Chicken World, fam.

84
00:09:05,958 --> 00:09:07,415
真噁心
That's disgusting.

85
00:09:07,458 --> 00:09:09,448
摩西 我們把它帶到哪兒
Moses, where are we gonna take that thing?

86
00:09:09,541 --> 00:09:12,574
給羅恩吧 他經常看國家地理雜誌
Take it to Ron's. He watches that National Geographic shit.

87
00:09:12,624 --> 00:09:14,946
整天只是抽大麻
All man ever does is blaze,

88
00:09:14,999 --> 00:09:17,368
給植物澆水 看自然頻道
water them big buds and watch the nature channel.

89
00:09:17,416 --> 00:09:20,662
他能鑒定這是什麼東西 我給他打電話
He'll identify that thing for real. Let me bell him up.

90
00:09:20,749 --> 00:09:23,533
難以置信 倫敦出現了怪獸
It was madness, fam. The beast of Brixton.

91
00:09:23,583 --> 00:09:25,454
被我們揍得不輕
We were crazy kicking that.

92
00:09:25,541 --> 00:09:27,910
沒 媽媽 我踢球了
No, Mum. Playing football.

93
00:09:28,624 --> 00:09:32,747
我買了香腸比薩 你給我的錢
Yeah, I had pepperoni pizza. You gave me the money.

94
00:09:32,791 --> 00:09:35,575
一種沒見過的生物
Some kind of non-found-out-about creature.

95
00:09:35,624 --> 00:09:37,448
就像「戰爭機器」上的生物
Yeah, like Some Gears Of War thing.

96
00:09:37,541 --> 00:09:41,369
我知道 10點之前回來 我保證 媽媽
Yes, I know. Back by ten. I swear, Mum, back by ten.

97
00:09:41,416 --> 00:09:45,409
她是護士 不掙錢
Ah, she's a nurse. They don't get paid nothing, fam.

98
00:09:45,458 --> 00:09:48,574
摩西 你怎麼老是桃選窮人
Oi, Moses. Why you always picking the poor people, man?

99
00:09:54,541 --> 00:09:56,531
我們走
Hey, let's walk, bruv. Whoo!

100
00:10:07,791 --> 00:10:09,331
哇
Woy.

101
00:10:10,124 --> 00:10:14,164
-摩西 你的臉怎麼了 -和一個天上來的外星人打架了
Moses, what happened to your face? Battled an alien that fell from the sky.

102
00:10:14,208 --> 00:10:15,914
-你真逗 -這是什麼
You're funny. Eurgh, what is that?

103
00:10:15,958 --> 00:10:17,616
對不起 我都不敢看
I'm sorry, I can't even look at that.

104
00:10:17,666 --> 00:10:20,533
-萬聖節過去一周了 -不是真的 是假的
Halloween was last week. That ain't real. That's a creation.

105
00:10:20,583 --> 00:10:22,407
-摸摸看 -快拿開
Touch it. Shove that thing in my face

106
00:10:22,458 --> 00:10:24,578
否則我就抓你
and them fangs are going up in your tits.

107
00:10:24,624 --> 00:10:27,657
-拿開 -說不定有傳染病
Move it from me. Grow up. Could be diseased, you get me?

108
00:10:27,749 --> 00:10:30,746
我可不想染上性病
I don't want no chlamydia.

109
00:10:30,791 --> 00:10:33,113
你是說從天上掉下來的？
So you're telling me that fell out of the sky?

110
00:10:33,166 --> 00:10:35,619
-是的 -它傷了你的臉？
Yeah. And did that to your face?

111
00:10:36,583 --> 00:10:38,952
-是的 -所以你殺了它？
Yeah. So, you killed lt?

112
00:10:39,624 --> 00:10:40,785
是的
Yeah.

113
00:10:42,124 --> 00:10:43,830
你真是壞小子啊
Such a bad breed, Moses.

114
00:10:45,624 --> 00:10:47,614
天 它還活著
Fuck! It's alive!

115
00:10:49,124 --> 00:10:52,952
-迪亞喜歡你 摩西 -她勾引你呢
Tia is moving to you, Moses. She's on your balls, cuz.

116
00:10:53,041 --> 00:10:55,494
她可是我表姐
Hey, that's my cousin you're chatting about.

117
00:10:55,583 --> 00:10:57,952
喂 看我跳
Hey, man. Hey, hey, hey, watch this jump.

118
00:10:58,958 --> 00:11:00,664
你下來
Get down, man.

119
00:11:00,749 --> 00:11:03,118
-我真的能行 -頑皮小子
Trust, I can do it. Humpty-Dumpty.

120
00:11:03,208 --> 00:11:05,874
我們可不想去救你 下來吧
We ain't cleanin' your guts off the floor, Biggz. Come on.

121
00:11:05,958 --> 00:11:09,370
-我真的能行 -是啊 你行
Oh, I swear I could do that. Yeah, yeah, sure you can, man.

122
00:11:16,124 --> 00:11:18,659
-別放火了 加文 -我不叫加文
Oi, Gavin, you pyro. My name ain't Gavin.

123
00:11:18,749 --> 00:11:20,573
我叫破壞 他叫搶劫
It's Mayhem and he's Probs.

124
00:11:20,624 --> 00:11:23,408
破壞和搶劫 真的嗎
Probs and Mayhem? Seriously?

125
00:11:23,458 --> 00:11:25,993
-這是什麼 -不關你的事
Urgh, what is that? That's none of your business.

126
00:11:26,083 --> 00:11:28,618
真噁心
That's sick, man.

127
00:11:28,666 --> 00:11:30,537
你們去哪兒 讓我們一起去吧
Where you going? Let us come with you.

128
00:11:30,583 --> 00:11:33,450
是啊 摩西 讓我們跟著你吧 我們是壞孩子
Yeah, Moses, let us roll with you. We're bad boys.

129
00:11:33,541 --> 00:11:36,622
走開 這是大人的事 你們太小了
Go away. This is big man business. You're too tiny.

130
00:11:36,666 --> 00:11:39,284
等你們長了毛 再來找我吧
Yeah, get in touch when you get your first pube.

131
00:11:39,333 --> 00:11:40,576
你去死吧
Go suck your mum.

132
00:11:40,666 --> 00:11:42,882
Oooh! Whoo!

133
00:12:02,958 --> 00:12:05,541
~Whoop whoop, that's the sound of da police

134
00:12:05,583 --> 00:12:07,917
~Whoop whoop, that's the sound of the beast

135
00:12:07,958 --> 00:12:10,375
~Whoop whoop, that's the sound of da police

136
00:12:10,416 --> 00:12:12,798
~Whoop whoop, that's the sound of the beast

137
00:12:12,833 --> 00:12:15,760
~Whoop whoop, that's the sound of da police

138
00:12:15,791 --> 00:12:18,884
~Whoop whoop, that's the sound of...

139
00:12:19,291 --> 00:12:20,748
嗨 爸爸
Hey, Dad.

140
00:12:20,791 --> 00:12:23,824
對 正在去電影院的路上
Yeah, just on my way to the cinema.

141
00:12:25,833 --> 00:12:28,368
好 我保證明早把車停在外面
Yes, I promise, it'll be parked outside in the morning.

142
00:12:28,416 --> 00:12:30,406
好 我要掛了 再見
OK, Dad. Gotta go. Bye-bye.

143
00:12:34,666 --> 00:12:37,580
我按過了 電梯太慢了
I pressed it already. Taking 'nough time.

144
00:12:50,333 --> 00:12:52,406
我坐另一個電梯
I'll... I'll just... I'll get the next one.

145
00:12:53,999 --> 00:12:56,368
電梯直達頂樓套房
Express elevator to the penthouse suite.

146
00:12:57,958 --> 00:13:00,244
你記得他們穿什麼衣服嗎
Do you remember what they were wearing?

147
00:13:00,291 --> 00:13:03,454
其中一個戴著毛帽子 有穗
One of them had one of those woolly hats with those tassels.

148
00:13:04,374 --> 00:13:07,122
那個把我推倒的 那個帶頭的
<i>The one that pushed me over, the main one,</i>

149
00:13:07,166 --> 00:13:09,405
戴著黑色棒珠帽 紅邊
<i>had a black baseball cap with a red brim.</i>

150
00:13:10,791 --> 00:13:12,580
我只記得這些
<i>That's all l can remember.</i>

151
00:13:12,624 --> 00:13:15,621
看見他們的臉了嗎 在附近見過他們嗎
<i>Did you see their faces? Have you seen them around?</i>

152
00:13:15,666 --> 00:13:17,739
沒有 他們戴著帽子和圍巾
<i>No. They had hoods and scarves.</i>

153
00:13:17,791 --> 00:13:19,580
想讓我報警嗎
You want me to call the police?

154
00:13:19,624 --> 00:13:22,372
最好是隨我們開車在附近轉轉
The best thing is to come with us for a drive around the block,

155
00:13:22,416 --> 00:13:24,038
或許能看見他們
see if we can spot them.

156
00:13:24,083 --> 00:13:26,156
然後可以把你送到朋友那裏
Then we can drop you with a friend afterwards.

157
00:13:26,208 --> 00:13:27,581
不用了
No, thanks.

158
00:13:27,624 --> 00:13:30,740
我不會讓一群青少年嚇得不敢回家
I'm not gonna be scared out my own home by a bunch of bloody teenagers.

159
00:13:32,458 --> 00:13:34,247
羅恩
Yo, Ron!

160
00:13:35,749 --> 00:13:37,953
喂 羅恩
Yo, Ron!

161
00:13:41,166 --> 00:13:42,244
怎麼了
All right?

162
00:13:43,416 --> 00:13:46,781
不知道 完全不知道
No idea. Not a bloody clue.

163
00:13:46,833 --> 00:13:51,952
或許是動物園裏 猴子和魚雜交的
Maybe there was a party at the zoo and a monkey fucked a fish.

164
00:13:53,583 --> 00:13:55,573
我來的時候 看見他們帶著它
I saw them with it on the way up.

165
00:13:55,624 --> 00:13:59,534
-以為是在遊樂場贏的 -真臭啊
Thought they'd won it at the funfair. Smells real though, don't it?

166
00:13:59,583 --> 00:14:01,573
比大便還臭
Smells like a shit did a shit.

167
00:14:07,874 --> 00:14:10,540
-你想買點大麻嗎 -好
You wanna buy a bit of weed, then? Yeah.

168
00:14:10,583 --> 00:14:13,118
好 來
Yeah, come on.

169
00:14:13,166 --> 00:14:15,203
閉嘴
Shut up, man.

170
00:14:15,249 --> 00:14:16,576
你們幹得好
Well done, lads.

171
00:14:16,624 --> 00:14:19,372
你們發現了科學界未知的物種
You've discovered a species hitherto unknown to science,

172
00:14:19,416 --> 00:14:23,872
可能原本不似乎陸生生物 你們把它的頭踢進去了
quite possibly non-terrestrial in origin, and you kicked its fucking head in.

173
00:14:26,458 --> 00:14:28,744
坐 我一會就回來
Take a seat. I'll be back in a minute. Yeah.

174
00:14:28,791 --> 00:14:31,872
我們會發財的 因為是我們發現的
We're getting rich off that, you know, cos we discovered it.

175
00:14:31,958 --> 00:14:34,327
-網上拍賣 -通知媒體
eBay, fam. Alert the media.

176
00:14:34,374 --> 00:14:36,281
出價最高的可以獨家採訪
Exclusive rights to the highest bidder.

177
00:14:36,333 --> 00:14:38,122
太陽報 他們什麼都信
The Sun. Believes anything.

178
00:14:38,166 --> 00:14:41,365
不行 太陽報會把它打扮得像封三女郎
No, no, no, no, no. The Sun'll dress it up like one of them Page Three girls.

179
00:14:41,416 --> 00:14:43,074
要給衛報打電話
You wanna call The Guardian, blood.

180
00:14:43,124 --> 00:14:46,454
-正規報紙發表 人們才會相信 -小報給的錢多
People will believe it in a proper paper. No, tabloids pay more money.

181
00:14:46,541 --> 00:14:48,780
不能告訴報社 會讓聯邦調查局沒收的
You can't call the paper. FBI will confiscate it.

182
00:14:48,833 --> 00:14:52,032
聯邦調查局？這是英國 沒有聯邦調查局
FBI? This is England, there ain't no FBI.

183
00:14:52,083 --> 00:14:54,073
只有軍情六處之類的
It's Section Six or something.

184
00:14:54,124 --> 00:14:57,287
-我們需要能鑒定的專家 -查查黃頁
We need an expert to verify that thing. Look in the Yellow Pages.

185
00:14:57,333 --> 00:15:00,780
找找熟悉隕石的專家
Look for scientist people who know about all them meteor things.

186
00:15:00,833 --> 00:15:03,202
黃頁？第一個是不是就是外星人
Yellow Pages? Like, what, "A" for aliens?

187
00:15:04,374 --> 00:15:05,996
-干 -我們需要律師
Cheers. We need a lawyer,

188
00:15:06,041 --> 00:15:07,533
或者經濟人之類的
a manager or something.

189
00:15:07,583 --> 00:15:09,739
聯繫西蒙「外星達人」
Bell Simon Cowell. Alien's Got Talent.

190
00:15:13,124 --> 00:15:14,533
開玩笑 開玩笑
Jokes, man, jokes.

191
00:15:17,666 --> 00:15:20,617
我在大學學過動物學
Actually, I did this zoology module at uni.

192
00:15:21,666 --> 00:15:24,368
靈長類動物學 哺乳動物學 都學過
Primatology, mammalogy, all that shizzle.

193
00:15:24,416 --> 00:15:28,575
那個東西 不屬於我學過的任何動物綱目
That thing in there don't belong to no taxon I've ever studied.

194
00:15:28,624 --> 00:15:31,290
這是布魯斯 很可靠的顧客
You met Brewis, then? Very reliable customer.

195
00:15:32,333 --> 00:15:34,323
你好
Gwanin'.

196
00:15:34,958 --> 00:15:36,747
走開
Hey, move, blood!

197
00:15:37,291 --> 00:15:39,447
喂 喂
Hey, hey!

198
00:15:39,624 --> 00:15:42,242
算了 算了
Allow it, allow it, allow it...

199
00:15:43,624 --> 00:15:46,290
-羅恩 -你喝威士忌嗎
Yo, Ron. You want a bourbon?

200
00:15:46,333 --> 00:15:49,994
讓我把它留在大麻室裏 它能值很多錢
Let me keep that thing in the weed room. Could be worth bare money.

201
00:15:50,041 --> 00:15:52,114
是這個街區最安全的地方
That's the safest place in the block.

202
00:15:53,458 --> 00:15:57,368
我很願意 但我說了不算 我只是在這裏工作
Look, I'd love to, but it's not my decision. I only work here.

203
00:15:57,458 --> 00:15:59,448
你問問老闆吧
Why don't you come and ask the boss?

204
00:15:59,541 --> 00:16:01,994
-哈茲在這裏？ -對 他在大麻室
What, Hi-Hatz is here? Yeah, he's in the weed room.

205
00:16:02,083 --> 00:16:04,073
來吧
Come on.

206
00:16:07,333 --> 00:16:09,418
~Get That Snitch

207
00:16:14,833 --> 00:16:16,823
哈茲
Hi-Hatz.

208
00:16:18,666 --> 00:16:19,993
哈茲
Hi-Hatz!

209
00:16:23,583 --> 00:16:25,573
哈茲
Hi-Hatz!

210
00:16:26,874 --> 00:16:29,113
摩西 聽見我的音樂了嗎
Yo, Moses, hear my beats?

211
00:16:29,666 --> 00:16:32,284
-聽到了 -是我的新曲子
Yeah. Yeah, that's my new trick.

212
00:16:34,291 --> 00:16:36,922
~Get that snitch Get the strap

213
00:16:36,958 --> 00:16:39,007
~Don't give a fuck ~Blat, blat, blat...

214
00:16:42,458 --> 00:16:43,831
是正經事
That's serious.

215
00:16:44,708 --> 00:16:47,789
看 他有個布偶
Ah, check it out, he's got a puppet.

216
00:16:52,291 --> 00:16:54,162
是在大學做的嗎
You made that in college or something?

217
00:16:54,708 --> 00:16:57,243
做的真像
You got mad skills for puppets.

218
00:16:57,291 --> 00:16:59,364
什麼都有了
Looks proper rotten and everything.

219
00:16:59,416 --> 00:17:01,620
在公園找到的 是不是 摩西
Found it over the park, didn't you, Moses?

220
00:17:01,666 --> 00:17:03,407
他想放在這裏
He wants to know if he can keep it here.

221
00:17:03,458 --> 00:17:05,116
他覺得能值很多錢
He reckons it's worth bare money.

222
00:17:05,166 --> 00:17:06,658
真的嗎
True say?

223
00:17:06,708 --> 00:17:08,698
拿過來
Yo, bring it, bring it, bring it.

224
00:17:09,791 --> 00:17:12,422
<i>~Get that snitch Get me strap</i>

225
00:17:12,458 --> 00:17:14,840
<i>~Don't give a fuck Blat, blat, blat</i>

226
00:17:14,874 --> 00:17:17,256
<i>~Get that snitch Get me strap</i>

227
00:17:17,291 --> 00:17:20,005
<i>~Don't give a fuck Blat, blat, blat</i>

228
00:17:20,041 --> 00:17:22,375
<i>~Get that snitch Get me strap</i>

229
00:17:22,416 --> 00:17:24,419
<i>~Don? give a fuck..</i>

230
00:17:28,624 --> 00:17:30,413
喂 隨便你吧
Yo. Do whatever you want.

231
00:17:30,458 --> 00:17:32,164
我不在乎這玩意
I don't care about that bullshit.

232
00:17:35,874 --> 00:17:37,496
你還從羅恩那裏買大麻？
You shot my food from Ron still?

233
00:17:37,583 --> 00:17:39,123
有時是
Sometimes.

234
00:17:41,958 --> 00:17:44,411
有更好的方式可以掙錢
There's better ways to make P's in the ends, you know.

235
00:17:44,499 --> 00:17:47,911
到你這個年齡 該長進了 賣點白粉
Man of your age should step his game up. Move some white.

236
00:17:50,998 --> 00:17:52,988
我把這個借給你
I'm gonna put you on bail.

237
00:17:53,666 --> 00:17:55,455
賣出300塊錢給我
Get me 300 back from this.

238
00:17:58,040 --> 00:17:59,497
你現在是我的人了
You're my boy now.

239
00:18:02,124 --> 00:18:05,952
不過有一點 這一片我是老大 知道嗎
One thing, though. This is my block, get me?

240
00:18:10,874 --> 00:18:12,911
雌蛾
<i>The female lands.</i>

241
00:18:12,958 --> 00:18:16,619
如果環境適合 它就會釋放出激素
<i>If this new territory is hospitable, she releases a pheromone</i>

242
00:18:16,666 --> 00:18:20,410
雄蛾在一英里以外都能感覺到
<i>which can be detected by the male of the species from over a mile away.</i>

243
00:18:20,458 --> 00:18:22,282
布魯斯
Brewis.

244
00:18:22,374 --> 00:18:24,115
喂 布魯斯
Oi, Brewis.

245
00:18:24,166 --> 00:18:26,203
喂 來
Oi, come on.

246
00:18:26,249 --> 00:18:27,955
你沒事吧
You all right?

247
00:18:27,999 --> 00:18:29,408
沒事
Yes, fam.

248
00:18:32,416 --> 00:18:36,030
-你什麼意思 -哥們
What you on about, man? Oh, fam, boy.

249
00:18:38,708 --> 00:18:39,786
我知道 哥們
I know, fam.

250
00:18:39,874 --> 00:18:42,788
怎麼了 喂 你笑什麼
Hey, what, bruv? Hey, why are you smiling, bruv?

251
00:18:42,833 --> 00:18:44,953
-為什麼笑 -他肯定找到工作了
Hey, what's that? Hey, I bet he got a job.

252
00:18:44,999 --> 00:18:47,155
-是嗎 -他被收下了
Eh, is it? He got recruited, innit.

253
00:18:47,208 --> 00:18:48,866
你兜裏是什麼
What's that in your pocket, bruv?

254
00:18:48,916 --> 00:18:51,369
哈茲要提拔你
Hi-Hatz is gonna step you up.

255
00:18:55,583 --> 00:18:58,118
這是什麼 你兜裏是什麼
What's that? What's that in your pocket, man?

256
00:19:03,041 --> 00:19:04,581
喂 來看看
Yo, check it.

257
00:19:04,624 --> 00:19:06,946
-怎麼了 -又有了
What, bruv? More.

258
00:19:06,999 --> 00:19:08,989
-又有什麼了 -那東西
More what? Them tings.

259
00:19:11,041 --> 00:19:12,912
這只是火箭吧
It's just rockets, innit?

260
00:19:13,041 --> 00:19:15,659
不 火箭降落之前先上升
Nah. Rockets go up before they come down.

261
00:19:15,708 --> 00:19:17,947
這些東西只是降落
Them things are pure comin' down.

262
00:19:18,291 --> 00:19:19,949
-和那個不一樣 -哪個
They're the same. Same as what?

263
00:19:19,999 --> 00:19:21,989
-擊中汽車的那個 -是啊
As what hit that car before, fam. Trust.

264
00:19:22,041 --> 00:19:23,996
又來了很多小精靈
Nah. More of them nasty little gremlins.

265
00:19:24,041 --> 00:19:26,659
-天上下小怪物 -很多怪物
It's raining Gollums. Bare creatures.

266
00:19:27,624 --> 00:19:30,408
有個落在停車場了 很近
Hey, that one landed in the park, fam, close.

267
00:19:30,458 --> 00:19:33,704
-漂亮的煙花 -不 這是外星人入侵
Oh, lovely fireworks. Nah, mate, it's a alien invasion.

268
00:19:33,791 --> 00:19:36,160
-當然 -我們下去吧
Course it is. Let's get down there, cuz.

269
00:19:36,208 --> 00:19:39,075
-去收拾它們 -我要殺它們
Let's go fuck them up! I'm killin' them straight

270
00:19:39,124 --> 00:19:42,205
-我們抄傢伙 -來
Ay, let's get tooled up, blood. Come, come.

271
00:19:42,249 --> 00:19:44,073
去消滅害蟲
Ay, somebody call pest control?

272
00:19:48,291 --> 00:19:50,613
都是好孩子啊
Quite sweet really, aren't they?

273
00:20:00,124 --> 00:20:02,790
-嗨 -緊急情況 讓開
Hi. Emergency situation! Move, move!

274
00:20:02,833 --> 00:20:05,830
-別推我們 -我們明天還要考試呢
Don't shove us! Some of us have got exams tomorrow!

275
00:20:16,208 --> 00:20:19,040
-你去哪兒了 -我來拿補胎工具
Where have you been? Got to get the puncture repair kit.

276
00:20:19,083 --> 00:20:22,365
-怎麼 你又要出去？-我去補車胎 10分鐘就回來
Why? You're not going out again. Just to mend my tyre. Ten minutes.

277
00:20:22,416 --> 00:20:25,034
-喂 10分鐘 說真的 -我保證
Hey. Ten minutes, I mean it. I promise.

278
00:20:32,416 --> 00:20:33,908
你的腿怎麼了
What happened to your leg?

279
00:20:33,958 --> 00:20:36,411
沒什麼 踢球的時候拉傷一塊肌肉
Nothing, Nan. I pulled a muscle playing football.

280
00:20:45,916 --> 00:20:48,783
-一會就回來 奶奶 -別去惹麻煩
Back in a bit, Nan. Now, don't you go getting into trouble.

281
00:20:48,833 --> 00:20:50,823
肯定不會
Course not, Nan.

282
00:21:01,374 --> 00:21:03,198
-丹尼斯 你去哪兒 -去外面
Dennis, where are you going? Out!

283
00:21:03,249 --> 00:21:05,453
-那就帶上你的狗 -不 我忙
Then take your dog. No, man, I'm busy.

284
00:21:05,499 --> 00:21:07,785
你必須帶上
I'm not asking, I'm telling.

285
00:21:08,958 --> 00:21:12,288
伯格 來 來 我們去打小怪物
Pogo. Come, come, come. Come, let's go savage some Gollums.

286
00:21:37,291 --> 00:21:39,281
我們走
Whoa! Let's go!

287
00:21:44,624 --> 00:21:46,033
走 走
Go, go, go!

288
00:21:46,083 --> 00:21:49,413
喂 摩西 怎麼了 等著我們
Hey, Moses, what's happening? Wait for us.

289
00:21:49,458 --> 00:21:53,119
等等 這不公平 我們也想去
Wait. It's not fair, man. We wanna come too.

290
00:21:54,333 --> 00:21:56,039
小精靈又來了
Hey, what, the Dobbies came again.

291
00:21:56,083 --> 00:21:58,701
-裏面可能有東西 -讓草都著火了
There might be something in it. Set the grass on fire.

292
00:21:58,791 --> 00:22:00,413
-一團糟 -我說過的
Messed up, man. I told you, fam.

293
00:22:00,458 --> 00:22:03,160
-一顆流星 是真的 -是的 很多呢
A meteor, for real. Ay, loads came down, innit.

294
00:22:03,208 --> 00:22:05,412
我們要把它們都幹掉 都抓住
We gotta take them all out. Gotta catch them all.

295
00:22:05,458 --> 00:22:07,578
冷靜 比格茲 這可不是口袋小精靈
Calm down, Biggz, this ain't Pok矇mon.

296
00:22:12,874 --> 00:22:14,580
照照
Yo, shine the light.

297
00:22:23,791 --> 00:22:27,037
-就像化石 -不 這不一樣
Like a fossil, innit. No, that's different.

298
00:22:27,083 --> 00:22:28,659
根本不是同一種東西
That ain't even the same thing.

299
00:22:28,708 --> 00:22:30,449
要大3倍呢
That looks triple the size, blood.

300
00:22:32,291 --> 00:22:35,490
不知道誰敢和它打
I'd like to see the brother who'd fight that.

301
00:22:35,583 --> 00:22:39,576
我想回家 鎖上門 玩實況足球
Right now, I feel like going home, locking my door and playing FIFA.

302
00:22:41,791 --> 00:22:43,580
什麼聲音
Hey, what was that?

303
00:22:43,624 --> 00:22:45,946
伯格 別跑
Pogo. Pogo, whoa. Stay.

304
00:22:45,999 --> 00:22:47,077
別跑
Stay.

305
00:22:48,791 --> 00:22:51,493
-那裏 -天啊
There. Holy fuck.

306
00:22:51,583 --> 00:22:53,538
-哪兒啊 -塔頂
Where, fam? Where? On top of the tower.

307
00:22:53,583 --> 00:22:56,285
-哪個塔 -沒長眼嗎 你看
Which tower? Ain't you got your contacts in? Look.

308
00:23:02,458 --> 00:23:04,199
伯格 伯格
Pogo! Pogo!

309
00:23:04,249 --> 00:23:05,410
不要
No, man!

310
00:23:08,458 --> 00:23:11,242
它在幹什麼 它去哪兒了
What's it doing? Where's it gone, man?

311
00:23:14,374 --> 00:23:15,950
它來了
It's coming.

312
00:23:19,791 --> 00:23:22,954
-我能看見它的眼睛 -拿不準是不是眼睛
Ah, I can see its eyes. Not sure them things is eyes.

313
00:23:25,916 --> 00:23:27,871
-我們快走 -我要走了
Hey, let's bounce, bruv. I'm gone, fam.

314
00:23:27,916 --> 00:23:29,906
大家都跑
Everyone run!

315
00:23:31,458 --> 00:23:33,448
外星人 快跑
Aliens! Run! Leave, leave, leave!

316
00:23:34,958 --> 00:23:37,790
-他們說是外星人？ -我也聽見了
They say aliens? That's what I heard, man.

317
00:23:37,833 --> 00:23:39,823
笨蛋 當我們嚇大的啊？
Doughnuts. They think we're scaredy-cats.

318
00:23:39,874 --> 00:23:41,698
看
Look, man.

319
00:23:41,791 --> 00:23:42,952
天
Shit, man!

320
00:23:50,874 --> 00:23:52,864
快點 比格
Hey, come on, Biggz, man.

321
00:23:57,499 --> 00:23:57,913
車
Bully van!

322
00:23:57,916 --> 00:23:59,289
警車

323
00:24:19,499 --> 00:24:21,785
趴下 過來
Stay down! Come here!

324
00:24:22,583 --> 00:24:25,249
把手伸出來 伸出來
Give me your hand! Give me your hand!

325
00:24:30,999 --> 00:24:33,452
-該死的警察 -趴下 趴下
Man, fuck the five-o! Stay down, stay down.

326
00:24:33,583 --> 00:24:34,661
冷靜
Hey, calm.

327
00:24:40,291 --> 00:24:41,664
有毒品
We got wraps.

328
00:24:41,708 --> 00:24:44,741
MD403 需要支援 巴拉德路
Mike Delta 4-0-3, need assistance, Ballard Street.

329
00:24:44,791 --> 00:24:47,788
-你被捕了 罪名是... -四英吋彈簧刀
You are under arrest on suspicion of... Four-inch flick blade.

330
00:24:47,833 --> 00:24:49,242
藏有一類毒品
..possession of Class A drugs.

331
00:24:49,291 --> 00:24:53,284
你有權保持沉默...
You do not have to say anything...

332
00:24:53,374 --> 00:24:54,701
被搶劫者的手機
Victim's mobile phone.

333
00:24:54,791 --> 00:24:57,742
你說的都可能成為證據 明白嗎
Anything you do say may be given in evidence. Do you understand?

334
00:24:57,791 --> 00:25:00,160
巴拉德路 完畢
Ballard Street, over.

335
00:25:00,916 --> 00:25:03,369
-他問你明白嗎 -明白 明白
He said, do you understand? Yeah, yeah, yeah.

336
00:25:03,458 --> 00:25:04,950
快點帶我上警車
Hurry up and get me in that van.

337
00:25:08,791 --> 00:25:11,954
-你能完全肯定是他嗎 -肯定
Are you absolutely positive that's him? Positive.

338
00:25:11,999 --> 00:25:15,245
其他幾個都在橋上 你們知道吧
And the rest of them are up on that walkway. You know that, don't you?

339
00:25:16,833 --> 00:25:18,455
警察把他帶上警車了
He's brucking him in the van, bruv.

340
00:25:20,291 --> 00:25:21,700
看看車後面
Behind the cars, check it.

341
00:25:27,458 --> 00:25:30,574
-它在哪兒 -屋頂上 到屋頂上了
Hey, where is it? The roof, fam, clock that roof.

342
00:25:43,916 --> 00:25:47,660
總部 巴拉德路 我們拘捕了一名嫌犯 完畢
Control, re Ballard Street. We got a prisoner coming in. 557, over.

343
00:25:53,041 --> 00:25:56,620
另外 請注意 其他四名嫌煩仍在附近
Also, please advise, er...four other suspects still in the area.

344
00:25:58,208 --> 00:26:00,198
你現在不牛X了吧
Not so tough now, are we, fella?

345
00:26:09,416 --> 00:26:11,253
Aaargh! Aaargh!

346
00:26:16,958 --> 00:26:18,782
天
Oh, shit!

347
00:26:29,874 --> 00:26:33,535
-天 警察被殺了 -我們要去救摩西
Nah. Feds got savaged. Shit, man. We gotta back Moses.

348
00:26:33,624 --> 00:26:36,077
算了吧 我可不敢靠近它
Fuck that, bruv. I ain't going nowhere near none of that.

349
00:26:36,166 --> 00:26:40,159
-想想我們用什麼嚇壞小怪物的 -鞭炮沒什麼用的
Think. Think what scared the little one. Bangers ain't gonna do nothin', fam.

350
00:26:40,208 --> 00:26:41,830
不是鞭炮
I ain't talking about bangers.

351
00:26:41,874 --> 00:26:44,113
讓我出去
Let me out, man!

352
00:26:44,166 --> 00:26:45,587
Oh!

353
00:26:46,833 --> 00:26:49,202
-你穩住 -是你在發抖
Hold it steady. I ain't the one with the shakes.

354
00:26:49,291 --> 00:26:51,447
-快點-你倆都快點
Hurry up, man. Come on, you lot, man.

355
00:27:00,916 --> 00:27:03,285
開門 讓我出去
Open the door! Let me out!

356
00:27:14,249 --> 00:27:15,658
掩護我
Yo, cover me, fam.

357
00:27:27,874 --> 00:27:30,576
為伯格報仇 安息吧 狗
This is for Pogo. Rest in peace, dog.

358
00:27:51,291 --> 00:27:52,949
怎麼了
What?

359
00:28:02,458 --> 00:28:03,915
你現在才來
Took your time, man.

360
00:28:09,083 --> 00:28:11,618
-笨警察把鑰匙留下了 -那就開車吧
Dumb feds left the keys! Then let's jack it!

361
00:28:20,916 --> 00:28:22,906
甩掉它 甩掉它
Throw it off, man! Throw it off!

362
00:28:25,291 --> 00:28:27,909
喂 比格 在地下車庫和我們碰頭
Yo, Biggz, meet us at the underground garages.

363
00:28:34,583 --> 00:28:36,550
Ire Feelings

364
00:28:36,583 --> 00:28:39,297
~Skanga, skanga, skanga, skanga...

365
00:28:49,666 --> 00:28:51,075
天
Fuck.

366
00:28:52,624 --> 00:28:55,491
慘了 慘了
Oh, bad, bad, bad, bad, bad, bad, bad.

367
00:29:04,083 --> 00:29:06,203
羅恩 我是布魯斯
Ron, it's Brewis.

368
00:29:06,249 --> 00:29:10,491
哥們 可能有人用汽油彈炸了我爸的車 我也拿不準
Mate, someone's like petrol-bombed my dad's car or... I don't know.

369
00:29:10,583 --> 00:29:12,123
到處都是警察
And there's po-po everywhere.

370
00:29:12,166 --> 00:29:14,784
-我需要回去 -你冷靜
<i>I need to come back up. All right, calm down.</i>

371
00:29:15,166 --> 00:29:17,121
我帶瞭望遠鏡 你在哪兒
I've got the binoculars out. Where are ya?

372
00:29:17,166 --> 00:29:20,080
公園旁邊的路上 在樹叢後
I'm by the road by the park. Behind a bush.

373
00:29:20,124 --> 00:29:22,079
你能看見什麼
<i>What can you see?</i>

374
00:29:22,124 --> 00:29:26,911
幾輛消防車停在酒館外面 我覺得…
Couple of fire engines parked up by the off-licence, and I think...

375
00:29:27,999 --> 00:29:30,617
-等等 不會吧 -怎麼了
<i>Hang on. Fuck me. What?</i>

376
00:29:31,374 --> 00:29:34,040
音像店關門了
Blockbusters has shut down.

377
00:29:34,083 --> 00:29:37,495
-對 沒警察吧 -沒有 你沒事
<i>Right. No police, though? No, you're all right.</i>

378
00:29:37,583 --> 00:29:40,118
回來吧 看不見警燈
Come back up. Not a blue light in sight.

379
00:29:56,416 --> 00:29:57,837
Whoa!

380
00:30:03,624 --> 00:30:05,910
不要 不要
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.

381
00:30:05,958 --> 00:30:08,162
糟糕
Oh, shit, shit, shit.

382
00:30:08,208 --> 00:30:11,289
這是噩夢 告訴我我在做夢
This is a bad dream. Tell me I'm dreaming.

383
00:30:12,291 --> 00:30:15,288
讓我出去 開門
Let me out! Open the door!

384
00:30:15,708 --> 00:30:17,366
等等 哥們 等等
Wait, blood, wait, blood.

385
00:30:17,416 --> 00:30:20,781
開車的不是警察 是青少年
That ain't even police at the wheel, that's youths in there.

386
00:30:21,833 --> 00:30:25,577
-我們怎麼辦 -把槍給我
What we gonna do, bruv? Give me the strap.

387
00:30:26,166 --> 00:30:29,365
讓我出去 開門
Let me out! Open the door!

388
00:30:29,416 --> 00:30:31,406
開門
Open the door!

389
00:30:32,624 --> 00:30:35,242
對不起開車不好 我聖誕節就去學開車
Sorry about the driving. I'll get lessons for Christmas.

390
00:30:35,291 --> 00:30:38,039
-那是什麼東西 -我們覺得可能是外星人
What were those things? We're thinking probably aliens.

391
00:30:38,083 --> 00:30:41,034
-你該走 -後面情況會更糟
You should leave. Before the situation gets more nuts.

392
00:30:42,624 --> 00:30:43,951
那就走吧
Go on, then.

393
00:30:48,208 --> 00:30:50,364
不謝謝我們救了你嗎
Ain't you gonna thank us for saving your life?

394
00:30:51,166 --> 00:30:52,409
我的大英雄
My fucking hero.

395
00:31:09,249 --> 00:31:11,571
-哈茲 那是意外 -真的 哥們
Yo, Hi-Hatz, it was a accident. Nah, trust, bruv.

396
00:31:11,624 --> 00:31:13,579
有很多怪物在追我們
There's bare creatures chasing us.

397
00:31:13,624 --> 00:31:16,159
又像狼又像猩猩的外星人 真的
Big alien-gorilla-wolf motherfuckers. I swear.

398
00:31:16,208 --> 00:31:19,952
從太空掉下來的怪物 襲擊摩西 就被他殺了
Some creature fell from outer space and jumped Moses, so he bored it.

399
00:31:20,041 --> 00:31:22,494
如今它的大批同胞來了
And now its brethren have come down in force, blood.

400
00:31:22,541 --> 00:31:25,243
摩西被警察抓住了 怪物襲擊警車
Moses got shiffed by the feds and the things attacked the van

401
00:31:25,291 --> 00:31:27,411
殺了警察 我們就開走了警車
and savaged the bluefoot, so we jacked the van.

402
00:31:27,458 --> 00:31:30,160
我們現在是在逃命 真的
We're running for our lives now, cuz. Believe!

403
00:31:32,458 --> 00:31:36,866
搶了警車 撞了我的車 又胡說什麼外星人
Jack a bully van, crash it into my whip and then chat shit about aliens to me?

404
00:31:37,916 --> 00:31:41,744
大事不妙 這小子還戴著手銬
This is making me nervous, blood. That boy's still cuffed, you know.

405
00:31:41,833 --> 00:31:44,617
-警察會嚴密追查的 -你打算告發我？
Police are gonna be all over this. You trying to snake me?

406
00:31:49,958 --> 00:31:53,572
怎麼你們想和我打？想殺我？
What, you wanna bring arms to me now? You wanna murk me?

407
00:31:54,208 --> 00:31:58,781
-想和我作對？ -聽我說 我沒說謊
You wanna war with me? Listen to me, cuz, I'm not even lying.

408
00:31:58,833 --> 00:32:00,076
如果要騙你
If we was making it up,

409
00:32:00,166 --> 00:32:02,832
不至於傻到編出外星人吧
don't you think we'd make up something better than aliens?

410
00:32:02,874 --> 00:32:04,615
再說一遍這個詞
Say that word one more time.

411
00:32:06,624 --> 00:32:09,491
我說過的 不信的話你到屋頂看看
I told you, bruv. On the roof, if you don't believe me.

412
00:32:09,583 --> 00:32:11,075
什麼 什麼在屋頂上
What? What's on the roof?

413
00:32:11,124 --> 00:32:12,581
-其中一個... -快說
One of them... Say it!

414
00:32:12,624 --> 00:32:15,740
其中一個猩猩狼人
One of them big gorilla-wolf motherfuckers.

415
00:32:19,083 --> 00:32:21,452
哈茲 上面確實有東西
Yo, Hi-Hatz, there is something there, bruv.

416
00:32:29,291 --> 00:32:31,957
喂 去看看是什麼
Yo, go see what that is.

417
00:32:31,999 --> 00:32:33,989
-我才不去 -去
No way, bruv. Move!

418
00:32:34,958 --> 00:32:36,616
真是的
Shit.

419
00:33:02,291 --> 00:33:03,748
喂 哈茲
Yo, Hi-Hatz, bruv.

420
00:33:03,791 --> 00:33:05,698
-沒什麼 -天
There's no... Oh, shit!

421
00:33:12,791 --> 00:33:14,662
天
Oh, shit!

422
00:33:14,708 --> 00:33:16,912
-帶店裏的鑰匙了嗎 -帶了
Got the key to your lockup? Yeah.

423
00:33:21,083 --> 00:33:24,662
跟我來 跟我來
Follow me, follow me!

424
00:33:24,999 --> 00:33:27,036
摩西 膽小鬼
Moses! Pussyhole!

425
00:33:27,083 --> 00:33:29,239
我會殺了你 等著吧
I'm gonna get you killed, blood! Watch!

426
00:33:36,041 --> 00:33:37,830
我就說過 外星人入侵
I told you, man. Alien invasion.

427
00:33:37,874 --> 00:33:40,243
整個倫敦 我早就料到了
London-wide. For real. I knew it from the start.

428
00:33:40,374 --> 00:33:41,831
警車上有定位儀
Them vans got tracker beacons.

429
00:33:41,874 --> 00:33:44,078
-警察隨時都會來 -我們完了
Police will be here any minute. We're fucked.

430
00:33:44,124 --> 00:33:46,577
等警察發現屍體和警車 我們就完了
When the feds find the bodies and the van, we are fucked.

431
00:33:46,624 --> 00:33:50,368
不會 如果到處都是外星人 警察今晚會忙得不可開交
No. If it's happening all over, the police are gonna be too busy tonight.

432
00:33:50,458 --> 00:33:52,993
全國戒嚴 軍隊巡邏 直升機
National emergency, army on the streets, helicopters,

433
00:33:53,083 --> 00:33:54,789
就像「惊變28天」那樣
all that 28 Days Later shit.

434
00:33:55,374 --> 00:33:57,578
我們要離開街道 回到街區
We need to get off the streets. Back in the block.

435
00:33:57,624 --> 00:33:59,200
就像什麼都沒發生
Like none of this ever happened.

436
00:33:59,249 --> 00:34:01,038
對 老大 回到街區
Yes, boss. Back in the block!

437
00:34:01,083 --> 00:34:03,073
那裏有怪物 我們回去怎麼辦
How do we do that with them things out there?

438
00:34:03,124 --> 00:34:04,782
那是送死
That's suicide, man.

439
00:34:09,208 --> 00:34:10,997
-你知道嗎 -什麼
You know what? What?

440
00:34:11,041 --> 00:34:13,494
我嚇得要命 但同時...
I'm shitting myself, innit. But at the same time...

441
00:34:14,041 --> 00:34:15,284
怎麼了
What?

442
00:34:15,333 --> 00:34:16,991
又很刺激
This is sick.

443
00:34:53,249 --> 00:34:54,907
天
Fuck!

444
00:34:56,499 --> 00:34:58,655
他們在後面
They're on us!

445
00:34:58,708 --> 00:35:01,492
-分開 到街區碰頭 -快 快
Split! Meet at the block! Oi, pedal, pedal, pedal!

446
00:35:01,541 --> 00:35:02,784
傑羅姆 快
Jerome, pedal!

447
00:36:59,291 --> 00:37:01,411
走樓梯
Stairs, blood!

448
00:37:01,458 --> 00:37:03,413
快 快
Move, move, move, move!

449
00:37:03,458 --> 00:37:05,247
比格呢 派斯特呢
Where's Biggz? Where's Pest?

450
00:37:06,874 --> 00:37:09,243
快
Hurry up!

451
00:37:11,499 --> 00:37:13,205
快跑
Go on, run!

452
00:37:13,249 --> 00:37:14,871
關門
Close the door, man!

453
00:37:16,708 --> 00:37:18,330
靠
Fuck!

454
00:37:18,374 --> 00:37:19,617
拿著
Grab it!

455
00:37:25,416 --> 00:37:27,419
Aarghh!

456
00:37:55,624 --> 00:37:58,290
喂 告密的
Hey, snitch!

457
00:38:00,499 --> 00:38:02,205
讓開 讓開
Move, man! Huh? Move!

458
00:38:02,249 --> 00:38:03,622
快讓開
Fucking move!

459
00:38:06,458 --> 00:38:08,827
-來 哥們 -把包解下來
Hey, come on, blood! Get the bag off him!

460
00:38:12,083 --> 00:38:15,164
-誰給比格打電話 -我還剩一條短信
Somebody bell Biggz. Where's Biggz? I got one text left.

461
00:38:15,208 --> 00:38:17,447
-我停機了 -別打電話了
I got no credit. Drop call everybody.

462
00:38:17,499 --> 00:38:21,327
-祈禱別人打過來吧 -一條短信解釋不清
Pray someone calls back. This is too much to explain in one text.

463
00:38:32,999 --> 00:38:34,989
滾出我的公寓
Get out of my fucking flat!

464
00:38:36,416 --> 00:38:38,655
閉嘴吧
Shut up, man. Pss...

465
00:38:38,708 --> 00:38:41,575
-我讓你們出去 -告密的 別激動
I said, get out! Yo, snitch, calm yourself.

466
00:38:41,624 --> 00:38:43,164
我們不是來找你的
This ain't about you no more.

467
00:38:43,208 --> 00:38:46,787
再靠近我 我就拚命的喊叫
Come anywhere near me and I swear I will scream this fucking block down!

468
00:38:46,833 --> 00:38:49,286
今晚外面還有比我們更危險的呢
There's worse things out there than us tonight.

469
00:38:49,374 --> 00:38:51,743
哥們 我看過她的證件
Hey, bruv. I saw her ID card thingy.

470
00:38:51,833 --> 00:38:54,784
-她是個護士 -那就幫幫我 我需要這條腿
She's a nurse, innit. Help me, then. I need this leg.

471
00:38:54,833 --> 00:38:57,072
還需要用腿來逃跑呢
I need it to be able to run away from them things.

472
00:38:57,124 --> 00:38:58,865
你覺得我會幫你？
You think I'm gonna help you?

473
00:38:58,916 --> 00:39:02,495
你們攻擊我 搶劫我 又派狗咬警察
After you attacked me, and robbed me, and then set those dogs on the police?

474
00:39:02,541 --> 00:39:05,207
-前兩句對 後一句不對 -狗？
Yes to the first two, no to the last one. Dogs?

475
00:39:05,249 --> 00:39:07,867
狗的牙會發光嗎？狗會沒有眼睛嗎
Dogs with glow-in-the-dark jaws? Dogs with no eyes?

476
00:39:07,916 --> 00:39:10,451
大得像猩猩 你覺得是狗嗎
Dogs the size of gorillas? D'you think they're dogs?

477
00:39:10,499 --> 00:39:13,864
那你拿狗食餵它們吧 它們是外星人
Go out there and try feedin' 'em some Pedigree Chum. They're aliens.

478
00:39:13,916 --> 00:39:17,328
不管是什麼 反正不是外星人
Whatever the fuck they are, they're not fucking aliens.

479
00:39:17,374 --> 00:39:20,704
-你髒話太多了 -是啊 你嘴很髒
You swear too much, man. Yeah, you got a potty mouth, man.

480
00:39:20,791 --> 00:39:23,077
反正它們已經進了大樓了
Whatever they are, they're inside the block.

481
00:39:23,124 --> 00:39:24,830
會殺死所有人
They're after everyone.

482
00:39:24,874 --> 00:39:28,037
我們如今是同一陣營的 知道嗎
Yeah, we're on the same side now. You get me?

483
00:39:32,999 --> 00:39:36,245
-別報警 -你最好給驅魔師打電話
No feds. You'd be better off calling the Ghostbusters.

484
00:39:36,291 --> 00:39:39,454
在這一片 要按照我們的方式明白嗎
This is the block. We take care of things our own way. Get me?

485
00:39:39,499 --> 00:39:41,785
-你在開玩笑嗎 -你看他是開玩笑嗎
You're joking? Does it look like he's jokin'?

486
00:39:41,833 --> 00:39:45,577
我本想叫救護車 他需要去醫院
I was gonna call for help. Your friend needs to go to hospital.

487
00:39:45,624 --> 00:39:48,621
你也是 如果傷口感染了 也是致命的
So do you. If those wounds get infected, they could kill you.

488
00:39:48,666 --> 00:39:51,663
不 他喜歡傷疤
Nah, he likes his scars, innit. Fuck!

489
00:39:51,708 --> 00:39:53,414
他在不停流血 救救他
He's bleedin' to death! Help him!

490
00:39:53,458 --> 00:39:55,329
我們不會傷害你的
We ain't gonna do nothing.

491
00:39:56,041 --> 00:39:57,699
救救他
Fix him.

492
00:40:00,249 --> 00:40:01,492
真是的
Jesus.

493
00:40:14,791 --> 00:40:18,701
這是極為神奇的自然現象
<i>It's one of me most extraodinary spectacles in nature.</i>

494
00:40:18,791 --> 00:40:20,698
那幾個小子或許說的對
What if those kids were right?

495
00:40:21,541 --> 00:40:23,994
說不定我爸車上的洞
What if they're connected - that freak show animal

496
00:40:24,041 --> 00:40:25,414
真和怪物有關
and the hole in my dad's car?

497
00:40:25,458 --> 00:40:29,037
說不定真有外星人入侵 警察正在調查
What if there is some kind of invasion and the police are out there?

498
00:40:29,708 --> 00:40:31,994
我不能再次被捕
I can't get busted again.

499
00:40:32,041 --> 00:40:34,245
-你曾經被捕？ -是的
You've been busted? Yeah.

500
00:40:35,374 --> 00:40:39,663
褲兜裏有半盎司大麻 不小心放進洗衣機
Left half an oz in my jeans, put them in the washing machine by mistake and...

501
00:40:39,708 --> 00:40:43,618
洗出來以後 我媽的內褲臭的要命
I shit you not, my mum's underwear came out stinking of skunk.

502
00:40:43,708 --> 00:40:48,329
被我爸聞到了 就不給我零花錢了
My dad obviously caught a whiff and cut off my allowance.

503
00:40:49,541 --> 00:40:51,531
再有下次 就要我的命了
Next time, it'll be my testiklees.

504
00:40:51,583 --> 00:40:53,869
你很艱苦啊
Yeah, it's tough times for you, mate.

505
00:40:54,749 --> 00:40:58,031
諷刺的是 我如今要賣兩倍的大麻 才有錢付房租
The irony is, now I've gotta sell twice the amount just to pay the rent.

506
00:40:59,041 --> 00:41:00,865
你不是說你住在家裏嗎
I thought you said you lived at home?

507
00:41:02,249 --> 00:41:05,495
對 是租了家裏的房子
Yeah, well, I mean... I mean "rent" in the proverbial sense.

508
00:41:05,541 --> 00:41:08,787
你也是沒辦法
Oh, yeah. Well, you gotta do what you gotta do, you know.

509
00:41:08,833 --> 00:41:12,826
總要掙錢吃飯嘛
A man's gotta put bread on the table - proverbially speaking, of course.

510
00:41:12,874 --> 00:41:14,450
是啊
Fo-shizzle.

511
00:41:14,499 --> 00:41:17,117
聽著 就算是外星人入侵
Listen, even if it is an alien invasion,

512
00:41:17,208 --> 00:41:19,281
也不過4英尺高 又是瞎子
they're four foot high, they're blind

513
00:41:19,333 --> 00:41:22,200
一群孩子就把它們收拾了
and they got kicked to death by a group of kids.

514
00:41:22,249 --> 00:41:25,116
-我們沒什麼可擔心的 -是啊
We got nothing to worry about. Yeah.

515
00:41:25,208 --> 00:41:26,700
-是不是？ -是啊
All right? Yeah.

516
00:41:40,124 --> 00:41:42,197
對不起把你沙發弄髒了
Sorry I messed up your couch.

517
00:41:42,874 --> 00:41:45,576
-沒關係 -要不要我脫了褲子？
Don't worry about it. D'you want me to take 'em off?

518
00:41:46,416 --> 00:41:47,873
沒必要
That won't be necessary.

519
00:41:47,916 --> 00:41:50,072
真不用？我短褲很好看的
You sure? I got nice boxers on.

520
00:41:50,791 --> 00:41:52,532
Calvin Klein名牌 今天剛買的
Genuine Calvin Klein. Fresh today.

521
00:41:54,374 --> 00:41:56,743
-疼的話就說一聲 -不會的
Tell me if this hurts. Try me.

522
00:41:57,624 --> 00:41:58,785
疼
Ow! Hurts.

523
00:41:59,708 --> 00:42:02,622
-這樣呢 -疼 疼 疼
How about this? Hurts, hurts, hurts, hurts, hurts!

524
00:42:02,666 --> 00:42:05,201
你斷了幾根小動脈 可能骨折了
You've torn a few minor arteries. You might have a fracture.

525
00:42:05,291 --> 00:42:07,660
你需要治療 否則就失血過多
This needs treating before you lose too much blood.

526
00:42:07,708 --> 00:42:09,579
-那就治療吧 -我不行
Do it, then. I can't do it.

527
00:42:09,624 --> 00:42:12,077
沒有設備 也沒有這個技能
I don't have the equipment or the skill.

528
00:42:12,124 --> 00:42:13,616
我剛畢業
I've only just graduated.

529
00:42:13,666 --> 00:42:15,988
沒學過治療外星人咬傷
And I missed the class on alien bite wounds.

530
00:42:16,041 --> 00:42:17,533
別胡說了
Stop hyping, man.

531
00:42:17,583 --> 00:42:19,620
把墊子給我
Pass me that cushion.

532
00:42:20,458 --> 00:42:23,621
把墊子給我!
I said, pass me that cushion!

533
00:42:31,916 --> 00:42:33,871
別對我撒氣
Oh! Don't take it out on me.

534
00:42:36,499 --> 00:42:38,703
我以前沒見過你
I ain't seen you around here before, you know.

535
00:42:38,791 --> 00:42:41,990
-你在這裏住了很長時間？-幾個月
You lived here long? Couple of months.

536
00:42:42,041 --> 00:42:44,197
你家裏不錯
Hmm. Nice place you got.

537
00:42:44,249 --> 00:42:47,081
謝謝 正考慮搬家
Thanks. Thinking of moving.

538
00:42:47,124 --> 00:42:49,161
可惜了 為什麼
Shame. Why?

539
00:42:49,208 --> 00:42:52,407
-不喜歡這一片 -怎麼會呢
I don't like the area. What do you mean, don't like the area?

540
00:42:52,458 --> 00:42:53,915
這一片挺好啊
What's wrong with the area?

541
00:42:56,416 --> 00:42:58,038
別動
Fam, stay.

542
00:43:22,874 --> 00:43:24,698
放開我
Get off me!

543
00:43:26,249 --> 00:43:28,038
-怎麼回事 -它們找到我們了
What was that? They found us.

544
00:43:28,083 --> 00:43:31,413
怎麼會呢 樓裏這麼多住戶
How could they find us? There's, like, 160 doors in this block.

545
00:43:31,458 --> 00:43:34,657
你們黑幫火拚 別把我牽涉進去
Whatever gang war you're involved in, leave me out of it, please.

546
00:43:36,458 --> 00:43:38,662
這不是黑幫火拚
Hey, this ain't got nothin' to do with gangs.

547
00:43:38,708 --> 00:43:41,990
和毒品、流行樂、遊戲中的暴力也沒關係
Or drugs. Or rap music. Or violence in video games.

548
00:43:42,041 --> 00:43:45,204
-我今晚真是倒霉 -彼此彼此
This is the worst night of my life. Feeling's mutual.

549
00:43:49,666 --> 00:43:52,201
-拼了 -摩西 不要
Moses, don't, man!

550
00:44:05,124 --> 00:44:06,664
摩西
Moses.

551
00:44:06,708 --> 00:44:08,284
忍者啊
Ninja!

552
00:44:08,333 --> 00:44:10,039
一擊斃命
Tango neutralised.

553
00:44:22,833 --> 00:44:25,037
看 這是狗嗎
See? Is that a dog?

554
00:44:25,791 --> 00:44:28,326
-不 -不 這不是狗
No. No, that is not a dog.

555
00:44:29,208 --> 00:44:30,997
是黑色的
That's black.

556
00:44:31,041 --> 00:44:32,533
黑的看不清
Too black to see.

557
00:44:32,583 --> 00:44:35,616
從沒見過這麼黑的
That's the blackest black ever, fam.

558
00:44:40,083 --> 00:44:42,997
比我表哥還黑
That's blacker than my cousin Femi.

559
00:44:44,208 --> 00:44:46,364
喂 那個女的呢
Oi, where's that woman?

560
00:45:14,874 --> 00:45:17,788
不管你們去哪裏 我也一起去
Wherever you're going, I'm coming with you.

561
00:45:17,833 --> 00:45:20,784
你們為我帶來了麻煩 理應幫幫我
After what you put me through tonight, it's the least you can do.

562
00:45:20,833 --> 00:45:23,451
不行 她很煩人
No way, man. She's bare annoyin'.

563
00:45:23,499 --> 00:45:26,331
讓她走 讓外星人殺了告密的
Make her leave. Let that snitch get murked.

564
00:45:26,374 --> 00:45:28,494
丹尼斯 你怎麼這麼混蛋
Dennis, why you acting like such a prick?

565
00:45:28,541 --> 00:45:30,578
我需要那個護士 你要讓我死嗎
I need the nurse. Do you want me to die?

566
00:45:30,624 --> 00:45:33,575
沒時間在這裏爭論 我們要走 快
We can't stand around here arguing. We need to roll. Now!

567
00:45:34,291 --> 00:45:36,032
-我叫薩曼莎 -我叫傑羅姆
My name's Sam. Jerome.

568
00:45:36,083 --> 00:45:37,824
-我叫派斯特 -幹什麼啊
I'm Pest. No, man.

569
00:45:37,874 --> 00:45:38,868
他叫丹尼斯
Dennis.

570
00:45:39,708 --> 00:45:41,200
你叫摩西吧
You're Moses, right?

571
00:45:43,874 --> 00:45:45,450
你需要一件武器
You're gonna need a weapon.

572
00:46:10,083 --> 00:46:12,239
向前走 向前走
Move along, please. Move along.

573
00:46:20,833 --> 00:46:22,574
拿來 拿來
Yo, bring it, bring it, bring it.

574
00:46:23,333 --> 00:46:25,999
把東西拿來 哥們
Bring it, bring it, bring it. Yo, bring the thing, blood.

575
00:46:27,041 --> 00:46:29,494
-怎麼了 -出了大事
What's happening, man? Something fucked up.

576
00:46:29,583 --> 00:46:32,995
哈茲 外面到處都是路障和警察
Hi-Hatz, bruv, there's bare feds in the area, roadblocks and everything.

577
00:46:33,041 --> 00:46:35,280
我們先沉住氣 等風頭過去
Maybe we should chill out till things die down.

578
00:46:35,333 --> 00:46:38,330
-你讓我沉住氣？ -我只是說等風頭過去
Are you telling me to chill out? No. Wait till things cool down.

579
00:46:38,374 --> 00:46:40,827
-你讓我冷靜？-當我沒說
You telling me to cool down? Ah, forget it, bruv.

580
00:46:41,541 --> 00:46:43,614
上車
Get in the car.

581
00:46:45,999 --> 00:46:48,617
快上車
Get in the car now!

582
00:46:51,041 --> 00:46:53,327
他們用偷來的警車撞了我的車
They mash up my whip with a bully van they stole,

583
00:46:53,374 --> 00:46:55,696
用什麼外星人來威脅我
start threatening me about aliens or some shit,

584
00:46:55,791 --> 00:46:58,788
嚇唬我 說我會被捕
facing me down, telling me I'm gonna get shifted.

585
00:46:58,833 --> 00:47:01,202
會不會開車啊 混蛋
Hey, watch where you're going, you prick!

586
00:47:01,249 --> 00:47:05,787
然後一條大狗 一個猩猩狼人
Then, some like...some like big dog, some big gorilla wolf motherfucker,

587
00:47:05,833 --> 00:47:10,289
從屋頂下來 撲向唐克斯 把他的脖子都咬斷了
comes down from the roof, rolls Tonks, tears his neck all the way out. Believe.

588
00:47:11,833 --> 00:47:14,499
-那麼是不是狗 -我不管是不是
So was it a dog, then? Don't give a fuck what it was.

589
00:47:14,541 --> 00:47:16,496
當場把它打死了
Shot that ting. Died easy.

590
00:47:17,208 --> 00:47:19,743
我們今晚要去教訓那幾個小子 知道嗎
And we gotta learn them youngers tonight, you get me?

591
00:47:19,833 --> 00:47:21,657
這一片我是老大
That's my block!

592
00:47:21,708 --> 00:47:23,545
~Don't give a fuck

593
00:47:23,583 --> 00:47:24,673
~Blat, blat, blat

594
00:47:24,708 --> 00:47:27,255
~Get that snitch Get the strap

595
00:47:27,291 --> 00:47:29,708
~Don't give a fuck Blat, blat, blat...

596
00:47:55,583 --> 00:47:58,450
攜帶攻擊武器 要判四年的
You get four years for carrying an offensive weapon, you know.

597
00:47:58,499 --> 00:48:01,615
-我覺得這次情況特殊 -是嗎
I think this situation's a bit different. Is it?

598
00:48:01,666 --> 00:48:04,996
在路上走 隨時都會有怪物撲上來
Walking around, expecting to get jumped at any moment?

599
00:48:05,041 --> 00:48:07,078
對我來說太平常了
Feels like just another day in the ends to me.

600
00:48:07,124 --> 00:48:09,826
-他帶我們去哪兒 -迪亞的公寓
Where's he taking us? Tia's flat.

601
00:48:09,874 --> 00:48:13,618
-去她家裏不也一樣？-有安全門
How will we be any safer in her place? Security gate.

602
00:48:13,666 --> 00:48:17,706
她沒見過女孩子們打架 所以才這麼問
She wouldn't be asking that question if she'd seen them girls fight.

603
00:48:22,999 --> 00:48:24,705
是比格 他還活著
Ay, it's Biggz. He's alive.

604
00:48:26,791 --> 00:48:30,037
-比格 還以為你死了呢 -我打了50遍電話了
<i>Yo, Biggz, we thought you was dead. I called you 50 times, blood.</i>

605
00:48:30,083 --> 00:48:33,246
在這種時候 你的手機怎麼還靜音啊？
What's your phone doing on silent at a time like this for, fam?

606
00:48:33,291 --> 00:48:34,664
-你在哪兒 -在垃圾箱裏
<i>Where you at? In the bin.</i>

607
00:48:34,708 --> 00:48:37,824
就是上次小流氓們追我時 躲的那個垃圾箱
Same bin I was at that time them boys from Aylesbury was after me.

608
00:48:39,249 --> 00:48:42,163
有個怪物想把我撞出來 來救我
One of them things is trying to headbang me out. Rescue me, yeah?

609
00:48:42,208 --> 00:48:45,869
沒這麼簡單 怪物進了大樓穿過住戶們
Ain't that simple, bruv. Them things are in the block, busting through doors.

610
00:48:45,999 --> 00:48:49,080
只有你還有電話費 多打電話 把消息傳出去
You're the only one with credit. Call everyone, spread the word.

611
00:48:49,124 --> 00:48:50,700
讓他們都不要出門 知道嗎
Tell them to stay inside. Get me?

612
00:48:50,791 --> 00:48:52,864
我們到了迪亞家 就給你打電話
<i>I'll bell you back when we get to Tia's.</i>

613
00:48:53,708 --> 00:48:55,200
天
Fuck this, man!

614
00:49:00,208 --> 00:49:01,665
-比格 -聽著
<i>Yo, Biggz. Listen, listen.</i>

615
00:49:01,708 --> 00:49:05,287
我要告訴很多人 但是只剩下一塊錢電話費 我只能說一遍
<i>I've got one pound credit and bare people to call. I can only say this once.</i>

616
00:49:05,333 --> 00:49:06,991
我們需要支援 外星人襲擊
<i>We need backup. Alien attack.</i>

617
00:49:07,041 --> 00:49:10,572
慢點說 我什麼都聽不懂 慢點說
Slow down. I don't understand a word you're saying. Speak slowly.

618
00:49:10,624 --> 00:49:12,828
沒時間 慢點說
<i>This ain't no time to be speaking slowly!</i>

619
00:49:12,874 --> 00:49:15,907
摩西和丹尼斯正去迪亞家 你給別人打電話
<i>Moses and Dennis are heading to Tia's. Call everyone!</i>

620
00:49:15,999 --> 00:49:18,913
讓大家回去 我們殺的怪物是真實的
<i>Tell them to come back! That thing we killed was for real!</i>

621
00:49:18,999 --> 00:49:21,072
還有一個更大的在這裏
<i>Now there's bigger ones battering me...</i>

622
00:49:21,124 --> 00:49:23,872
等你打完遊戲再說吧
Phone me later when you ain't playing Xbox.

623
00:49:32,208 --> 00:49:34,577
看啊 雷吉納德和加文沒死
Check it. Reginald and Gavin survived.

624
00:49:34,624 --> 00:49:38,036
別這麼稱呼我們 我們叫破壞和搶劫
Don't answer those names no more. It's Probs and Mayhem.

625
00:49:38,083 --> 00:49:39,789
哥們 我們看見了外星人
Fam, we saw the aliens.

626
00:49:39,833 --> 00:49:41,870
它們從我們身邊跑過去了
They ran past us, straight.

627
00:49:41,916 --> 00:49:43,657
我們有槍
We got tools.

628
00:49:45,708 --> 00:49:48,705
-收下我們吧 -不會是真槍吧
Let us roll with you, man. That's not real, is it?

629
00:49:48,791 --> 00:49:51,623
-他看樣子才六歲 -我九歲半了
Jesus, he looks about six I'm nine and a half.

630
00:49:51,666 --> 00:49:55,197
-這不是鬧著玩的 加文 給我 -放手
That ain't a toy, Gavin. Give me that. Hey, leave it!

631
00:49:57,874 --> 00:49:59,829
放開 放開
Hey. Hey, let go, fam. Oi, let go.

632
00:49:59,874 --> 00:50:02,243
雷吉納德 加文
Yo, Reginald, Gavin!

633
00:50:03,249 --> 00:50:06,246
回家 鎖上門 做作業 看火影忍者
Go home, lock your door. Do your homework. Watch Naruto.

634
00:50:06,291 --> 00:50:08,198
反正別出門 知道嗎
Just stay inside tonight, get me?

635
00:50:09,791 --> 00:50:11,781
那是我表哥的槍 還給我
That's my cousin's! I gotta give it back!

636
00:50:11,833 --> 00:50:14,202
別抱怨了 你們還有大水槍呢
Stop bitching, You got a Super Soaker still.

637
00:50:14,249 --> 00:50:16,784
噴水就能把怪物打死嗎
You really think they'll die if you shoot water at them?

638
00:50:16,833 --> 00:50:19,617
裏面可不是水 對不對
Ain't water in it. Is it?

639
00:50:21,458 --> 00:50:25,451
你不能把人都帶進來 他們惹了什麼事
You ain't bringing all them in here. No. They're involved in something.

640
00:50:25,499 --> 00:50:28,034
有人在追他們 他們有槍
Someone's chasing 'em. They got weapons.

641
00:50:28,124 --> 00:50:29,948
看 還有一個在流血
And, look, that one's bleedin'.

642
00:50:30,041 --> 00:50:31,996
還有那個女的 我都不認識她
And that woman, I don't even know her.

643
00:50:32,041 --> 00:50:35,406
我可不想趟這個渾水
I'm not getting myself involved in a situation I don't need to be in.

644
00:50:36,124 --> 00:50:37,995
這是我的家
It's my house, Dimples.

645
00:50:38,041 --> 00:50:39,202
來吧
Come.

646
00:50:40,541 --> 00:50:42,697
放開我
Get off me, man.

647
00:50:50,666 --> 00:50:54,410
外面只有一架直升機
There's only one helicopter out there. Copper chopper.

648
00:50:54,499 --> 00:50:57,829
也不是軍方的 只在這一片轉悠
Ain't even military. And it's only around these ends.

649
00:50:57,874 --> 00:51:00,492
看來不是倫敦全部範圍 只在這一片
This ain't London-wide. This is localised.

650
00:51:00,541 --> 00:51:03,988
-隻有你這麼想 -還是在你夢裏
Yeah, localised in your head. Localised in your dreams.

651
00:51:04,041 --> 00:51:06,031
被警察追捕 我信
Drapsed by the feds? Yes.

652
00:51:06,083 --> 00:51:09,365
殺人的大猩猩狼人 我不信
Big gorilla-alien-wolf monsters killing everyone? Uh-uh.

653
00:51:09,416 --> 00:51:11,655
-或許它們只到這一片 -行了
Maybe they only fell on these ends. Please!

654
00:51:11,708 --> 00:51:15,038
就算是外星人 世界上這麼多好地方
What kind of alien, out of all the places in the whole wide world,

655
00:51:15,083 --> 00:51:17,831
何必單單入侵倫敦一個貧民區
would invade some shitty council estate in South London?

656
00:51:17,874 --> 00:51:22,033
-是來打架的 -它們衝我們而來 不管有沒有準備好
One that's looking for a fight. They're coming for us. Ready or not.

657
00:51:23,291 --> 00:51:25,826
不管有沒有準備好 我來了
~Ready or not, here I come

658
00:51:25,874 --> 00:51:28,327
-你無處可藏 -打擾一下
~You can't hide Excuse me.

659
00:51:28,416 --> 00:51:29,873
它們會找到你的
~They're gonna find you

660
00:51:29,916 --> 00:51:31,740
聽我說
Listen to me!

661
00:51:31,833 --> 00:51:33,953
我的臥室有個死的
There's a dead one in my living room.

662
00:51:34,041 --> 00:51:37,122
不信你就去看看 我住在一樓
I live on the first floor. Go and look if you don't believe me.

663
00:51:37,166 --> 00:51:40,117
直接走進去就行 已經沒有前門了
You can walk right in. There's no front door any more.

664
00:51:40,166 --> 00:51:43,247
摩西 你怎麼和數學老師談戀愛了？
Moses, when did you start going out with your maths teacher?

665
00:51:45,666 --> 00:51:47,952
-你怎麼認識她的 -以前見過
How d'you know that woman? We met earlier.

666
00:51:48,041 --> 00:51:49,498
他搶劫了我
He mugged me.

667
00:51:49,541 --> 00:51:52,657
-真的嗎 -這我信
Whey! For real? That part I believe.

668
00:51:52,708 --> 00:51:55,161
真的嗎 你搶劫了她？
That true? You rob that woman?

669
00:51:55,208 --> 00:51:58,869
是的 不過後來她治療了我的腿 我們把她從怪獸手下就出來
Yeah. But afterwards she fixed my leg and we saved her from the monster.

670
00:51:58,958 --> 00:52:01,078
所以 我們現在是好朋友了
So...we're mates now and it's all sweet.

671
00:52:01,749 --> 00:52:04,035
-我們是英雄 不是嗎 -英雄？
We're heroes, innit? Heroes?

672
00:52:04,749 --> 00:52:07,830
五個英雄拿刀對付一個女人 得了吧
Five of you and a knife against one woman? Fuck off!

673
00:52:07,874 --> 00:52:09,414
天 好冷酷
Raah. Cold.

674
00:52:09,458 --> 00:52:12,290
別胡編 沒到那個程度
Nah, nah, nah, don't build it up, luv. It weren't all that.

675
00:52:12,333 --> 00:52:15,496
-我們沒碰過你 -用刀子只是為了節省時間
We never even touched you. The blade was to get it over with quick.

676
00:52:15,541 --> 00:52:17,531
-我們和你一樣害怕 -刀子？
We was as scared as you. Blade?

677
00:52:18,416 --> 00:52:21,863
你真沒用怎麼老是惹麻煩？
You're such a waste. Why's it always trouble with you?

678
00:52:21,916 --> 00:52:25,281
為什麼非要搶劫人、打人或者被捕呢
Why's it always someone gettin' robbed or beaten up or gettin' arrested?

679
00:52:25,333 --> 00:52:28,165
這事我們解決不了 必須報警
We can't deal with this on our own. We have to call the police.

680
00:52:29,041 --> 00:52:31,992
可以相信我 我會說實話
You can trust me. I'll tell them what really happened.

681
00:52:32,041 --> 00:52:33,663
警察會幫他們？
Think the police will help them?

682
00:52:33,708 --> 00:52:36,077
可能不會逮捕你 但會逮捕他們
They might not arrest you, but they'll arrest them.

683
00:52:36,124 --> 00:52:39,952
罪名是殺死兩個警察 盜竊警車 拒捕
For the murder of two police officers, vehicle theft, resisting arrest -

684
00:52:40,041 --> 00:52:42,825
今晚的事都會歸到我們頭上
everything that happened everywhere in the ends tonight.

685
00:52:42,874 --> 00:52:44,698
以前就無緣無故逮捕我們
They arrest us for nothing already.

686
00:52:46,499 --> 00:52:48,619
知道我懷疑什麼嗎
You know what I reckon, yeah?

687
00:52:48,666 --> 00:52:51,035
我懷疑是警察派來的
I reckon the feds sent them, anyway.

688
00:52:51,124 --> 00:52:54,038
政府培育的怪獸 專門殺黑人
Government probably bred those creatures to kill black boys.

689
00:52:55,124 --> 00:52:58,489
先是給這一片帶來了槍 然後是毒品
First they sent drugs to the ends, then they sent guns.

690
00:52:59,166 --> 00:53:01,156
現在又送怪物來殺我們
Now they sent monsters to get us.

691
00:53:01,208 --> 00:53:03,198
他們不在乎我們
They don't care, man.

692
00:53:03,249 --> 00:53:05,156
嫌我們自相殘殺的不夠快
We ain't killin' each other fast enough,

693
00:53:05,208 --> 00:53:07,163
就讓怪物來加快這一過程
so they decided to speed up the process.

694
00:53:08,458 --> 00:53:10,614
是的
Believe.

695
00:53:12,624 --> 00:53:16,285
派斯特 我說過不能抽 要抽去窗外
Pest, I told you not to do that! Do it out the window, yeah?

696
00:53:16,333 --> 00:53:18,122
這是鎮痛 不信問問護士
It's pain relief. Ask the nurse.

697
00:53:21,833 --> 00:53:24,202
喂 那是什麼
Excuse me, but what is that?

698
00:53:30,916 --> 00:53:33,036
天啊
Oh, my days!

699
00:53:37,624 --> 00:53:39,863
-你對付不了兩個 -你看著
You can't take two, fam. Watch me.

700
00:53:42,749 --> 00:53:45,202
該死 就是玩具槍
Shit. It is a toy!

701
00:53:55,041 --> 00:53:57,659
救命 摩西
Help! Hey, Moses!

702
00:54:00,166 --> 00:54:01,244
丹尼斯
Dennis!

703
00:54:18,499 --> 00:54:21,034
-摩西 -它朝你去了 摩西
Moses. It's coming for you, Moses!

704
00:54:27,624 --> 00:54:29,164
喂 混蛋
Oi, you fucker!

705
00:54:30,416 --> 00:54:32,453
迪亞 你幹什麼
Tia, what you doing?

706
00:54:34,166 --> 00:54:35,160
回去
Back!

707
00:54:37,041 --> 00:54:39,908
揍它 殺了它
Bash it! Kill it! Kill it!

708
00:54:54,541 --> 00:54:56,531
-不要停 -用力 殺它
Don't stop! Harder! Cut him!

709
00:55:02,291 --> 00:55:04,281
殺它 用力
Kill him! Harder!

710
00:55:10,708 --> 00:55:12,366
天
Oh, shit!

711
00:55:24,124 --> 00:55:27,406
喂 小子 幹什麼呢
Yo, youngers, wagwan?

712
00:55:27,458 --> 00:55:28,915
沒幹什麼
Nothing much. All right.

713
00:55:28,958 --> 00:55:31,031
槍不錯 和誰打呢
Nice weapons. Who you fightin'?

714
00:55:31,083 --> 00:55:33,203
-外星人 -是嗎
Aliens. Is it?

715
00:55:33,249 --> 00:55:35,535
-最近看見摩西了嗎 -誰要找他
Seen that yout Moses lately? Who wants to know?

716
00:55:36,624 --> 00:55:40,285
他找我們幫忙打外星人
He called us for backup. Help him fight the aliens off.

717
00:55:40,374 --> 00:55:41,713
Bang! Bang! Bang!

718
00:55:42,541 --> 00:55:45,492
他在哪兒
So, where's he at?

719
00:55:57,874 --> 00:56:00,409
記得你們之前殺過的那個小的嗎
You know that little one you killed before?

720
00:56:00,458 --> 00:56:02,034
那是個錯誤
That was a mistake.

721
00:56:02,083 --> 00:56:04,831
它們不是來殺我們的 是來殺你的
They weren't going for us. They were going for you.

722
00:56:04,874 --> 00:56:07,243
任何事情都有後果
Actions have consequences, you know.

723
00:56:07,333 --> 00:56:09,489
你到處惹事生非
Everywhere you go, bad things happen.

724
00:56:10,166 --> 00:56:12,535
離我們遠點 摩西
Stay away from us, Moses.

725
00:56:30,041 --> 00:56:33,074
你們走吧 我不希望再有人死去
You should leave. I don't want no one else to die.

726
00:56:33,124 --> 00:56:36,454
-我不管 我幫你 -我哪裏也不去
Fuck that, bruv. I got your back. I ain't going nowhere.

727
00:56:36,499 --> 00:56:40,030
它們殺了丹尼斯 我們要把它們都殺了
They took Dennis. We gotta kill all them things, bruv.

728
00:56:43,874 --> 00:56:45,247
快來
Come on!

729
00:56:48,749 --> 00:56:50,538
快
Come on!

730
00:56:57,041 --> 00:56:58,865
輕鬆
Easy kill.

731
00:57:03,499 --> 00:57:05,489
快跑啊 快
Run, man! Come on!

732
00:57:05,541 --> 00:57:08,492
還愣著幹什麼
What are you waiting for? Shit!

733
00:57:08,541 --> 00:57:10,282
開門 快
Open the door! Go!

734
00:57:22,291 --> 00:57:25,407
你好 我是丹尼斯 如果你是女孩 就留言
<i>Wagwan, it's young Den. If it's girls, leave a message.</i>

735
00:57:25,458 --> 00:57:27,199
如果是男的 到街區找我
<i>Mandem, I'm on the block, innit.</i>

736
00:57:27,249 --> 00:57:29,156
丹尼斯 我打了很多電話
Dennis, fam, I made bare calls.

737
00:57:29,208 --> 00:57:32,289
很多人來幫我們 但都進不來
Everyone's come down to back us, blood, but no one can get inside.

738
00:57:32,333 --> 00:57:34,489
警察封鎖了這一片
Feds have the block on lockdown.

739
00:57:34,541 --> 00:57:37,325
你還有一分鐘
<i>You've got one minute remaining.</i>

740
00:57:37,374 --> 00:57:40,704
我話費不多了 也不能在垃圾箱久呆了
I ain't got much credit. And I can't be in this bin much longer.

741
00:57:40,749 --> 00:57:42,289
我要試試
I need to make a break for it.

742
00:57:43,041 --> 00:57:45,078
出去以後再見
I'll see you at the other side, yeah?

743
00:57:53,041 --> 00:57:54,878
Aargh!

744
00:57:55,666 --> 00:57:57,537
怎麼回事
Hey, what the fuck, man!

745
00:57:59,749 --> 00:58:02,035
怎麼沒人來救我
Why won't someone flippin' rescue me?

746
00:59:02,624 --> 00:59:05,456
做別的電梯吧 哥們
Better get the next one, blood.

747
00:59:35,874 --> 00:59:37,864
快
Go, man!

748
00:59:40,916 --> 00:59:43,285
-剛才是誰 -是哈茲
Who was that? That's Hi-Hatz.

749
00:59:43,374 --> 00:59:45,696
-就是個混蛋 -為什麼對我們開槍
Man's a sausage. Why is he shooting at us?

750
00:59:45,749 --> 00:59:47,905
他的朋友被吃了 他很生氣
His best friend got ate and he's a bit vexed.

751
00:59:49,874 --> 00:59:51,829
我現在理解他的心清了
I know exactly how he feels.

752
00:59:51,874 --> 00:59:54,540
誰告訴我 這是怎麼回事啊
Would someone please tell me what the fuck is going on?

753
00:59:54,624 --> 00:59:58,238
誰在追你們 為什麼另一個電梯裏都是死人
What's chasing you? Why is the other lift full of bits of dead people?

754
00:59:58,291 --> 00:59:59,831
我們要下去
What? We need to go down.

755
00:59:59,874 --> 01:00:03,618
不能下去 下面很多人在等著我
I ain't going down. There's too many things down there out to get me.

756
01:00:03,708 --> 01:00:08,246
是的 很多警察 黑幫 還有兇狠的怪獸
True say. Bare police, crazy gangsters and fucked-up monsters down there.

757
01:00:08,291 --> 01:00:11,075
那就不下去 我們能去哪兒
OK. Good. Let's not go down. Where can we go?

758
01:00:11,124 --> 01:00:14,370
-去羅恩的大麻室 -羅恩的大麻室是什麼
We're going to Ron's weed room. What's Ron's weed room?

759
01:00:14,416 --> 01:00:17,248
有很多大麻的房子 是羅恩的 那裏安全
It's a big room full of weed. And it's Ron's. It's good.

760
01:00:17,291 --> 01:00:19,660
-就像堡壘一樣 -好主意
It's like Fort fucking Knox up there. Plan.

761
01:00:19,708 --> 01:00:20,951
19樓
19.

762
01:00:21,958 --> 01:00:26,117
B隊 跟著我 呆在原地
Bravo Team, on me, on me. Hold positions.

763
01:00:28,874 --> 01:00:32,867
真沒勁 它們都走了
This is long, man. They've all gone.

764
01:00:36,041 --> 01:00:38,363
沒有 你看
No, they ain't. Check it.

765
01:01:03,166 --> 01:01:05,701
盡頭就是
Down the end. Raah.

766
01:01:09,416 --> 01:01:11,620
我不行 大麻抽多了
I am too high for this shit.

767
01:01:12,291 --> 01:01:13,700
是啊
Trust.

768
01:01:17,124 --> 01:01:19,872
-我想殺它們 -我也是
I wanna shoot those things, man. Same here, bruv.

769
01:01:19,916 --> 01:01:22,830
-我也一樣 -那就干
Times three. Done now.

770
01:01:49,416 --> 01:01:52,330
-鞭炮 鞭炮 -介紹一下 我叫布魯斯
Bangers, man, bangers! I'm Brewis, by the way.

771
01:01:52,374 --> 01:01:54,245
-我叫薩曼莎 -在前兜裏
Sam. Front pocket, man.

772
01:01:54,958 --> 01:01:58,702
本來要去Fulham參加派對的 卻被困在大樓裏
I'm meant to be at a party in Fulham. Now I'm trapped in this bloody block.

773
01:01:58,749 --> 01:02:02,079
派斯特 準備好打火機 遞過來
Yo, Pest. Get ready with that lighter. Yeah, pass it, pass it.

774
01:02:02,124 --> 01:02:04,197
-你呢 -我住在這裏
What about you? I live here.

775
01:02:05,124 --> 01:02:06,616
真的嗎
Really?

776
01:02:06,666 --> 01:02:07,993
挺好
Wicked.

777
01:02:08,041 --> 01:02:09,865
我準備好了
I'm set.

778
01:02:25,916 --> 01:02:28,202
光 靠近
Lights. Stay close.

779
01:02:29,041 --> 01:02:31,327
走 走
Go. Go, go.

780
01:02:31,744 --> 01:02:37,577
製作:dianwanren

781
01:02:37,708 --> 01:02:40,954
-快 別停下 -等等我
Hurry up, man. Keep moving. Wait for me.

782
01:02:46,333 --> 01:02:48,323
朝洞裏打
Fire in the hole.

783
01:02:59,208 --> 01:03:01,328
放開我
Get the fuck off me, man.

784
01:03:03,041 --> 01:03:05,327
天 後面有一個 快跑
Jesus. There's one behind us. Run!

785
01:03:13,041 --> 01:03:15,955
傑羅姆 你在哪兒
Jerome, where are you, man?

786
01:03:22,541 --> 01:03:24,081
傑羅姆
Jerome!

787
01:03:27,041 --> 01:03:29,825
傑羅姆 你在哪兒
Jerome! Where you at?

788
01:03:29,874 --> 01:03:31,532
傑羅姆
Jerome!

789
01:03:31,624 --> 01:03:33,282
傑羅姆
PEST:Jerome?

790
01:03:39,416 --> 01:03:42,863
我什麼都看不見 快 快
I can't see shit, man! Come on, come on. Come on.

791
01:03:43,916 --> 01:03:45,906
派斯特 摩西
Pest? Moses?

792
01:03:46,458 --> 01:03:48,448
派斯特 摩西
Pest! Moses!

793
01:03:49,499 --> 01:03:52,496
傑羅姆 你在哪兒
Aaarghh! Jerome, where you at?

794
01:03:52,541 --> 01:03:55,538
-光 光 -正在找
Oi, lights, man, lights! Trying to find 'em, man.

795
01:03:57,166 --> 01:03:59,370
我要回去 靠近光
I'm going back. Stay by the lights.

796
01:04:01,291 --> 01:04:03,826
你在嗎
Are you there, man?

797
01:04:04,666 --> 01:04:06,656
它們沿樓梯上來了 快
They're coming up the stairs, quick.

798
01:04:06,708 --> 01:04:08,330
傑羅姆
Jerome?

799
01:04:14,041 --> 01:04:15,284
救我
Help! Help!

800
01:04:20,416 --> 01:04:22,620
跟我來
Aargh! Follow me!

801
01:04:22,666 --> 01:04:25,332
它們殺了傑羅姆 摩西
They got Jerome. Moses!

802
01:04:25,374 --> 01:04:28,407
它們殺了傑羅姆
They took him! They took Jerome!

803
01:04:30,874 --> 01:04:33,078
天
Man! Oh!

804
01:04:35,374 --> 01:04:37,494
為什麼打我
What the fuck was that for?

805
01:04:38,958 --> 01:04:42,405
摩西 哥們 快 它們會殺了你
Moses, blood! Come on, man, they'll kill you!

806
01:04:45,041 --> 01:04:46,617
摩西
Moses!

807
01:04:55,041 --> 01:04:58,406
-羅恩 羅恩 -讓我們進去
Yo, Ron! Ron! Ron, man, let us in!

808
01:04:58,458 --> 01:04:59,867
-羅恩 -開門
Ron! Open the door, man!

809
01:04:59,916 --> 01:05:02,285
-讓我們進去 -開門
Hey, let us in, man! Hey, open the door!

810
01:05:02,374 --> 01:05:04,743
-怎麼了 -我們要藏在你的大麻室
All right? We need to hide in your weed room.

811
01:05:04,833 --> 01:05:07,072
是這個大樓唯一安全的地方了
It's the only safe place left in the block.

812
01:05:08,124 --> 01:05:10,114
那不一定
I don't know about that.

813
01:05:10,874 --> 01:05:13,078
-快點 -好吧
Ah, come on! Hurry up! All right, all right.

814
01:05:13,124 --> 01:05:14,533
快
Come on.

815
01:05:16,541 --> 01:05:18,910
你好 摩西
Wagwan, Moses?

816
01:05:20,624 --> 01:05:21,867
對不起
Sorry.

817
01:05:28,958 --> 01:05:32,039
-是你殺了怪物 -哈茲
You killed that thing. Hi-Hatz, bruv...

818
01:05:32,083 --> 01:05:35,662
-是你把它引來的 -我不想惹麻煩
You brought it in the ends. I don't want no trouble.

819
01:05:35,708 --> 01:05:37,497
你把警察引來了
You brought fed in the ends.

820
01:05:37,541 --> 01:05:39,661
聽我說
Listen to me, bruv.

821
01:05:39,708 --> 01:05:44,032
你讓這片遭到外星人入侵
You brought an alien invasion to the ends.

822
01:05:45,041 --> 01:05:46,119
天
Shit.

823
01:05:46,208 --> 01:05:47,700
你身後
Behind you, bruv.

824
01:05:47,749 --> 01:05:49,656
-別騙我 -我沒騙你
Don't chat me. I'm not even lyin'..

825
01:05:49,708 --> 01:05:51,449
閉嘴
Shut up!

826
01:05:51,499 --> 01:05:53,157
我要做了你
I was gonna make you.

827
01:05:53,208 --> 01:05:55,874
我要殺了你
Now...I'm gonna dead you.

828
01:05:56,541 --> 01:05:58,697
這一片我是老大 知道嗎
This is my block. Get me?

829
01:06:01,666 --> 01:06:03,123
不知道
Not really.

830
01:06:44,333 --> 01:06:46,655
真希望我沒去追小怪物
Wish I'd never chased after that thing.

831
01:06:48,208 --> 01:06:50,412
真希望沒搶劫你
Wish we never murked you.

832
01:06:52,249 --> 01:06:54,784
真希望沒拿哈茲的白粉
I wish I never took that white off Hi-Hatz.

833
01:06:55,499 --> 01:06:58,662
真希望聽比格的 回家玩實況足球
Wish I'd just gone home and played FIFA like Biggz said.

834
01:06:59,874 --> 01:07:01,864
誰有大麻嗎
Anyone got skins?

835
01:07:03,166 --> 01:07:05,156
沒有
No.

836
01:07:05,958 --> 01:07:09,121
這麼多大麻 卻不能抽
Bare weed and no skins.

837
01:07:09,166 --> 01:07:11,239
這是最痛苦的事
This is my worst nightmare.

838
01:07:11,958 --> 01:07:15,370
聽著 我們不知道你住在這裏
Listen, yeah. We never knew you lived in the block.

839
01:07:16,499 --> 01:07:19,331
如果認識你 絕不會搶劫你
If... If we knew you, we wouldn't have stepped you.

840
01:07:19,374 --> 01:07:23,284
不住在這裏的 就可以搶劫了嗎
It would have been OK to mug me if I didn't live here? Is that how it works?

841
01:07:23,374 --> 01:07:25,032
你怎麼這樣
Boy, you's tetchy.

842
01:07:25,083 --> 01:07:27,287
他是向你道歉呢
He's tryin' to apologise to you, man.

843
01:07:30,708 --> 01:07:32,828
你很漂亮的
You're quite fit, you know.

844
01:07:34,833 --> 01:07:36,953
-有男朋友嗎 -有
Have you got a boyfriend? Yeah.

845
01:07:37,708 --> 01:07:40,243
對你真心嗎 他在哪兒
Are you sure about him? Where is he?

846
01:07:40,291 --> 01:07:42,744
今晚可沒見他來找你
Cos he ain't exactly looking after you tonight.

847
01:07:42,833 --> 01:07:45,700
-他在加納 -你男朋友是非洲人？
He's in Ghana. You go out with an African man?

848
01:07:45,749 --> 01:07:49,196
不 他是紅十字會的志願人員 去救助兒童了
No, he's helping children. He volunteers for the Red Cross.

849
01:07:49,249 --> 01:07:51,204
是嗎
Oh, is it?

850
01:07:51,874 --> 01:07:54,327
怎麼不救助英國兒童
Why can't he help the children of Britain?

851
01:07:54,416 --> 01:07:56,406
嫌不在國外？
Not exotic enough, is it?

852
01:07:56,458 --> 01:07:58,448
不能曬曬皮膚？
Don't get no nice suntan.

853
01:08:11,458 --> 01:08:14,870
摩西 你的夾克怎麼這個顏色
Raah. Moses, your jacket's gone rave.

854
01:08:17,041 --> 01:08:18,498
在紫外線下反光
It's glowing in the UV light.

855
01:08:22,833 --> 01:08:24,906
也許是一種信息素
Maybe it's some kind of pheromone.

856
01:08:25,624 --> 01:08:27,330
是什麼
Maybe it's a what now?

857
01:08:27,374 --> 01:08:30,076
就是能引起同類注意的
Er...it's an eco-hormone that triggers a social response

858
01:08:30,124 --> 01:08:32,031
一種激素
in members of the same species.

859
01:08:32,749 --> 01:08:35,912
也許這是雌性的激素 其他的是雄性
Maybe that's a female and the others are male,

860
01:08:35,958 --> 01:08:39,323
就是這東西把他們吸引而來
and that... that... that stuff is what's attracting them here.

861
01:08:39,374 --> 01:08:41,329
它們能聞到我們
They're smelling us.

862
01:08:42,708 --> 01:08:45,030
它們從天上而來 是不是？
They fell out of the sky, yeah?

863
01:08:45,083 --> 01:08:50,498
也許它們靠太陽風在太空漂浮 就像孢子
Well, maybe they like drift through space on... on solar winds, like spores,

864
01:08:50,541 --> 01:08:53,159
到了一個星球
and...whatever planet they land on first,

865
01:08:53,208 --> 01:08:56,075
雌性就釋放信息素 供雄險來追蹤
the female leaves a pheromone trail for the males to follow it,

866
01:08:56,124 --> 01:08:58,328
找到雌性 繁衍
find it, breed, et cetera.

867
01:08:59,499 --> 01:09:01,655
就像蜜蜂、甲蟲、蛾子
Like bees, like beetles, like moths.

868
01:09:01,708 --> 01:09:04,077
哪有這模樣的蛾子
Some fucking funny-looking moth.

869
01:09:05,124 --> 01:09:06,202
沒錯
Yeah.

870
01:09:06,249 --> 01:09:08,618
不管是什麼 你們沾上了這種激素
Well, whatever it is, you're covered in it

871
01:09:08,708 --> 01:09:12,748
好像能激怒外星人
and it seems to be piquing the interest of a rather hostile alien species.

872
01:09:12,791 --> 01:09:15,824
我只是說 或許你脫下這外套
I'm just just saying, maybe if you took those clothes off,

873
01:09:15,874 --> 01:09:17,663
它們就不會知道我們在這裏了
they wouldn't know we were here.

874
01:09:17,708 --> 01:09:20,492
你喜歡他？想讓他脫光衣服？
You fancy him or something? Are you trying to get him naked?

875
01:09:20,541 --> 01:09:22,863
不 我是想救你們的命
No, I'm trying to save your life.

876
01:09:24,374 --> 01:09:27,371
再回答你剛才的問題
And in answer to your question earlier...

877
01:09:30,874 --> 01:09:33,030
太好了
Ah, thank fuck.

878
01:09:34,249 --> 01:09:37,910
哥們 我發誓再也不罵你了
Bruv, I swear I will never cuss you again.

879
01:09:43,749 --> 01:09:46,071
布魯斯
Yo, Brewis.

880
01:09:46,124 --> 01:09:49,038
碰過它的人都被殺了
Everyone who touched this thing got murked, you know -

881
01:09:49,708 --> 01:09:51,366
丹尼斯
Dennis...

882
01:09:51,416 --> 01:09:52,825
傑羅姆
Jerome...

883
01:09:52,874 --> 01:09:54,331
唐克斯
Tonks...

884
01:09:54,374 --> 01:09:56,447
還有碰過我的警察
them feds when they tried touch me,

885
01:09:57,208 --> 01:09:59,412
只要是身上粘了氣味的
everyone who had that scent on them.

886
01:10:00,249 --> 01:10:02,618
既然它們沿著氣味
So if they follow the smell on that, then...

887
01:10:04,249 --> 01:10:06,535
我就能引開它們
..maybe I can lead 'em.

888
01:10:06,624 --> 01:10:10,285
-帶他們去哪裏 -能炸掉它們的地方
Lead them where? Somewhere I can blow them up.

889
01:10:11,291 --> 01:10:14,703
是我殺了它 把它們都引來
I killed that thing. I brought them in the block.

890
01:10:16,499 --> 01:10:18,489
就要由我去了結
I've gotta finish what I started.

891
01:10:28,208 --> 01:10:31,324
-它撲向我們怎麼辦 -那就扔鞭炮
What if it jumps at us? Then throw the banger.

892
01:10:31,374 --> 01:10:33,696
-沒打中怎麼辦 -那就逃跑
What if I miss? Then we run.

893
01:10:33,749 --> 01:10:35,953
被它殺了 怎麼辦
What if it kills us?

894
01:10:36,041 --> 01:10:41,705
你老是這麼膽小鬼 沒人會叫你「破壞」的
No one is gonna ever call you Mayhem if you keep on acting like such a pussy.

895
01:10:49,041 --> 01:10:53,365
我說的是實話 以前雖然騙過你 但這次真是實話
I'm tellin' the truth! I know I lied to you before, but it's for real this time, I swear!

896
01:10:53,416 --> 01:10:56,698
我會告訴你爸 聽見了嗎
<i>..I'm calling your dad. You hear me?</i>

897
01:10:56,749 --> 01:10:58,325
快扔 快扔
Throw it, throw it, throw it!

898
01:10:59,291 --> 01:11:00,452
快 快
Now, now, do it!

899
01:11:00,541 --> 01:11:03,207
-你在聽嗎 -媽 我要掛了
<i>Are you even listening? Mum, I gotta go.</i>

900
01:11:03,249 --> 01:11:05,073
照我說的做 別出門
Just do as I say and stay indoors.

901
01:11:05,958 --> 01:11:09,240
我保證再也不做壞事了
I won't ever do anything bad again, I promise.

902
01:11:09,291 --> 01:11:12,822
我愛你 媽媽 我愛你
<i>I love you, Mum. I love you. Five minutes!</i>

903
01:11:31,749 --> 01:11:35,328
-我隨時樂意幫你的忙 -你才不管呢
Any time, blood. Any time. We don't give a fuck, man.

904
01:11:35,374 --> 01:11:37,198
武裝警察 不許動
Armed police. Stay where you are!

905
01:11:37,249 --> 01:11:38,706
糟糕
Fuck.

906
01:11:45,041 --> 01:11:47,327
-你好 比格 -你們來幹什麼
Wagwan, Biggz. What are you doing?

907
01:11:47,374 --> 01:11:49,992
-有武警 -真的嗎
Armed police, fam. Swear down?

908
01:11:50,041 --> 01:11:52,410
真的
Swear down.

909
01:11:52,458 --> 01:11:54,614
你們把怪物燒慘了 漂亮
You burnt that thing good. Ratings.

910
01:11:54,666 --> 01:11:57,663
-輕鬆 -小菜一碟
Easy peasy. Lemon squeezy.

911
01:11:59,666 --> 01:12:01,372
你們叫破壞和搶劫吧
Probs and Mayhem, right?

912
01:12:02,499 --> 01:12:04,489
對
Yeah.

913
01:12:21,749 --> 01:12:23,241
你沒沾上激素
You look clean.

914
01:12:24,458 --> 01:12:25,701
看起來不錯
You look good.

915
01:12:27,040 --> 01:12:29,113
我肯定我們是對的
I'm betting my life we're right about this.

916
01:12:30,041 --> 01:12:33,869
要不是我大麻抽多了 我肯定自己去的
Believe me, I'd go out there myself if I wasn't so profoundly stoned.

917
01:12:34,166 --> 01:12:36,156
我也是
Likewise.

918
01:12:42,958 --> 01:12:46,786
-樓下 191房間 -樓下 191房間
One floor down. 191. One floor down. 191.

919
01:12:46,873 --> 01:12:49,077
-到了給我打電話 -好
You bell me when you get there. Yeah.

920
01:12:50,041 --> 01:12:52,363
派斯特 把戒指給我
Yo, Pest, give me that ring.

921
01:12:53,833 --> 01:12:55,206
什麼戒指
What ring, man?

922
01:12:56,499 --> 01:12:59,034
真是的 那是我們的
Oh, man, that's ours.

923
01:12:59,624 --> 01:13:01,910
-值很多錢呢 -給我
It's worth bare P, man. Give it!

924
01:13:04,416 --> 01:13:06,074
真是的
Raasclaat, man.

925
01:13:13,166 --> 01:13:14,623
謝謝
Thanks.

926
01:13:17,708 --> 01:13:20,741
就算你跑得比它們快 就算能跑到
Even if you outrun them, even if you make it,

927
01:13:20,791 --> 01:13:22,200
你怎麼出來呢
how are you gonna get out?

928
01:13:24,041 --> 01:13:26,078
別擔心我
Don't worry about me, man.

929
01:13:27,458 --> 01:13:29,413
你不必這麼做 摩西
You don't have to do this, Moses.

930
01:13:30,916 --> 01:13:32,823
有必要
Yeah, I do.

931
01:13:58,708 --> 01:14:00,449
喂
Oi. Hi.

932
01:14:00,499 --> 01:14:02,157
這安全嗎
Is it safe?

933
01:14:04,749 --> 01:14:07,663
不安全 知道了 祝你好運
No. All right. Good luck.

934
01:15:08,249 --> 01:15:10,867
-你肯定這裏沒人？ -是的
<i>Are you sure no one's here? Yeah.</i>

935
01:15:18,208 --> 01:15:19,665
你和誰住在一起
Who do you live with?

936
01:15:20,833 --> 01:15:22,242
只有我叔叔
Just my uncle.

937
01:15:26,624 --> 01:15:28,116
他人呢
Where's he?

938
01:15:29,083 --> 01:15:31,618
有時來住
Comes and goes.

939
01:15:31,666 --> 01:15:33,490
一般都不來
Goes, mostly.

940
01:15:42,749 --> 01:15:44,325
你有個弟弟？
You got a little brother?

941
01:15:44,374 --> 01:15:45,535
沒有
No.

942
01:15:46,749 --> 01:15:49,533
-你多大？ -15
<i>How old are you? 15.</i>

943
01:15:51,541 --> 01:15:53,117
看起來不止15歲
You look older.

944
01:15:53,833 --> 01:15:54,994
謝謝
Thanks.

945
01:16:01,958 --> 01:16:03,367
關上廚房門
Shut the hatch.

946
01:16:03,416 --> 01:16:05,240
關上窗屍
<i>Lock the window.</i>

947
01:16:05,291 --> 01:16:07,447
前門插上
<i>Leave the front door on the latch.</i>

948
01:16:07,499 --> 01:16:10,034
把煤氣開到最大
<i>Turn all the gas all the way up.</i>

949
01:16:14,416 --> 01:16:17,497
以最快速度離開大樓 聽見了嗎
<i>Get out the block as fast as you can. You hear me?</i>

950
01:16:20,874 --> 01:16:22,283
祝你好運 摩西
Good luck, Moses.

951
01:16:23,041 --> 01:16:24,498
再見
Later.

952
01:16:24,541 --> 01:16:26,614
摩西對付怪物
Moses versus the monsters.

953
01:16:26,666 --> 01:16:29,533
殺了它們 都殺了
Kill 'em. Kill all them things.

954
01:16:30,541 --> 01:16:32,365
得了吧
Allow it.

955
01:18:31,708 --> 01:18:33,366
-是摩西嗎 -摩西
Is that Moses? Moses!

956
01:18:33,416 --> 01:18:34,410
摩西
Moses.

957
01:19:29,166 --> 01:19:31,832
-天 -還有一個怪物嗎
Oh, shit. Is that more of the monsters?

958
01:19:31,874 --> 01:19:33,117
好像是
Sort of.

959
01:19:34,874 --> 01:19:37,030
武裝警察 放下武器
Armed police! Put your weapons down!

960
01:19:37,083 --> 01:19:38,954
趴在地上 趴在地上
Down on the ground! Down on the ground!

961
01:19:45,833 --> 01:19:49,115
武裝警察 放下武器 手放在頭上
Armed police! Drop your weapon! Hands on head!

962
01:19:53,874 --> 01:19:55,864
馬上放下武器
Drop your weapon now!

963
01:20:07,708 --> 01:20:09,663
-放開我 -這一個？
Get off me! This one?

964
01:20:09,708 --> 01:20:11,532
放開我
Aaargh, get off.

965
01:20:12,541 --> 01:20:14,661
放開我
Get off me. Aaargh.

966
01:20:14,708 --> 01:20:16,449
不要反抗 不要反抗
Stop resisting. Stop resisting.

967
01:20:16,499 --> 01:20:20,706
-我沒反抗 是你推我 -我都不住在這裏
I ain't resisting. You're pushin' me over. I don't even live here.

968
01:20:20,749 --> 01:20:23,533
我是登記殘疾人 你在傷害我
I am registered disabled. You're hurting me.

969
01:20:23,583 --> 01:20:25,869
你警號多少 警號多少
What's your number? What's your number, huh?

970
01:20:25,916 --> 01:20:29,281
我知道我的權利 我是國際大赦組織的
I know my civil liberties. I'm a member of fucking Amnesty.

971
01:20:29,333 --> 01:20:30,494
放開我
Get off me!

972
01:20:40,249 --> 01:20:44,456
摩西拯救了地球 打敗了外星人的入侵
Our Moses saved the planet! He saved the planet from alien invasion.

973
01:20:44,499 --> 01:20:46,572
他是英雄 是傳奇
He's a hero. He's a legend.

974
01:20:46,624 --> 01:20:49,657
摩西 給我打電話 我們會找人幫你
Moses. Call me, yeah? We'll get you help.

975
01:20:49,708 --> 01:20:51,828
-給我打電話 -摩西
Call me. Yo, Moses.

976
01:20:51,874 --> 01:20:53,864
摩西 摩西
Hey, Moses. Moses.

977
01:20:55,583 --> 01:20:57,490
為什麼老是抓不該抓的人
Why do you always arrest the wrong people?

978
01:20:57,541 --> 01:21:00,823
摩西是英雄 你們不明白嗎 他拯救了街區
Moses is a hero, don't you get it? He saved the block.

979
01:21:00,874 --> 01:21:02,532
打擾一下 長官
Excuse me, sir.

980
01:21:02,624 --> 01:21:05,408
這是薩曼莎·亞當斯 報搶劫案的那個人
This is Samantha Adams, the woman that called in the mugging.

981
01:21:05,458 --> 01:21:09,286
亞當斯小姐 你今晚曾和我們的兩個警察一起出去了吧
Miss Adams, I believe you were out with two of my officers earlier tonight?

982
01:21:09,916 --> 01:21:12,867
-知道他們死了吧 -知道 我當時也在
You know they lost their lives? Yeah. I was there.

983
01:21:12,916 --> 01:21:14,622
我們受到攻擊
We were attacked.

984
01:21:14,666 --> 01:21:16,822
那兩個人 你們逮捕的那兩個
Those boys there, the ones you're arresting...

985
01:21:16,874 --> 01:21:18,829
你確認是他們呢
Can you confirm it was them?

986
01:21:18,874 --> 01:21:20,615
別受他們的威脅 小姐
Don't let them intimidate you, miss.

987
01:21:23,458 --> 01:21:26,160
不 我認識他們 他們是我的鄰居
No. I know them. They're my neighbours.

988
01:21:26,874 --> 01:21:28,532
他們保護了我
They protected me.

989
01:21:28,624 --> 01:21:30,993
喂 摩西 摩西
Yo, Moses. Hey, Moses.

990
01:21:31,083 --> 01:21:34,530
摩西 摩西
Moses! Moses! Moses!

991
01:21:34,624 --> 01:21:37,408
摩西 摩西
Moses! Moses! Moses!

992
01:21:41,249 --> 01:21:42,990
放開我
Get off!

993
01:21:43,041 --> 01:21:46,371
摩西 摩西
Moses! Moses! Moses!

994
01:21:49,374 --> 01:21:50,630
Brap! Brap!

995
01:21:50,666 --> 01:21:53,083
Brap! Brap! Brap!

996
01:21:53,124 --> 01:21:55,376
Brap! Brap! Brap!

997
01:21:55,416 --> 01:21:57,406
摩西 哥們
Moses, bruv.

998
01:21:58,374 --> 01:22:00,364
你聽見了嗎
Can you hear that?

999
01:22:01,624 --> 01:22:05,831
摩西 摩西
Moses! Moses! Moses! Moses!

1000
01:22:06,499 --> 01:22:08,205
在為你歡呼呢
That's for you, man.

1001
01:22:08,538 --> 01:22:12,238
字幕製作：TGHD電玩人

1002
01:22:13,499 --> 01:22:14,885
片尾曲 《冷血青年》
Youths So Cold

1003
01:22:15,041 --> 01:22:17,090
~In the streets it's getting hot

1004
01:22:17,124 --> 01:22:20,548
~And the youths them a-get so cold

1005
01:22:20,583 --> 01:22:23,000
~Searching for food for the pot

1006
01:22:23,041 --> 01:22:25,624
~They'll do anything to fill that gap

1007
01:22:26,916 --> 01:22:28,965
~In the streets it's getting hot

1008
01:22:29,041 --> 01:22:32,335
~And the youths them a-get so cold

1009
01:22:32,708 --> 01:22:34,711
~Searching for food for the pot

1010
01:22:35,249 --> 01:22:37,666
~They'll do anything to fill that gap

1011
01:22:38,708 --> 01:22:41,173
~As generation comes and goes

1012
01:22:41,208 --> 01:22:44,301
~You gotta make preparation while the youths them grow

1013
01:22:44,791 --> 01:22:46,758
~It's what you reap, it's what you sow

1014
01:22:46,791 --> 01:22:48,840
~The youth, them are the light and the future

1015
01:22:48,874 --> 01:22:51,007
~So that's when you know

1016
01:22:51,041 --> 01:22:52,842
~If education is the key

1017
01:22:52,874 --> 01:22:56,464
~Then tell me why the big guns they make it so expensive for we

1018
01:22:56,874 --> 01:22:59,042
~Give them the key Oh, set them free

1019
01:22:59,083 --> 01:23:01,381
~Ah-eeeeee!

1020
01:23:03,083 --> 01:23:05,132
~In the streets it's getting hot

1021
01:23:05,166 --> 01:23:08,508
~And the youths them a-get so cold

1022
01:23:08,874 --> 01:23:10,877
~Searching for food for the pot

1023
01:23:11,374 --> 01:23:13,672
~They'll do anything to fill that gap

1024
01:23:14,958 --> 01:23:17,007
~In the streets it's getting hot

1025
01:23:17,041 --> 01:23:20,383
~And the youths them a-get so cold

1026
01:23:20,749 --> 01:23:22,752
~Searching for food for the pot

1027
01:23:23,291 --> 01:23:25,969
~They'll do anything to fill that gap

1028
01:23:39,374 --> 01:23:41,423
~You gotta find a better way

1029
01:23:41,458 --> 01:23:42,927
~Cos when me look at Babylon

1030
01:23:42,958 --> 01:23:44,877
~Me see a bare foul play

1031
01:23:44,916 --> 01:23:46,919
~And so the Gideon stay

1032
01:23:47,624 --> 01:23:49,709
~Yeah, yeah!

1033
01:23:51,249 --> 01:23:54,508
~All nation come together know that King Selassi has the truth

1034
01:23:54,541 --> 01:23:56,626
~And the light and the way

1035
01:23:57,374 --> 01:24:00,384
~Here's the people, lead them in the right way

1036
01:24:03,291 --> 01:24:05,340
~Cos in the streets it's getting hot

1037
01:24:05,708 --> 01:24:09,050
~And the youths them a-get so cold

1038
01:24:09,458 --> 01:24:11,461
~Searching for food for the pot

1039
01:24:11,916 --> 01:24:14,214
~They'll do anything to fill that gap

1040
01:24:15,541 --> 01:24:17,544
~In the streets it's getting hot

1041
01:24:17,624 --> 01:24:20,918
~And the youths them a-get so cold

1042
01:24:21,333 --> 01:24:23,336
~Searching for food for the pot

1043
01:24:23,874 --> 01:24:26,256
~They'll do anything to fill that gap

1044
01:24:27,624 --> 01:24:31,712
~You got to show the people there's still a brighter way

1045
01:24:33,541 --> 01:24:37,084
~I know for sure the sun will come out today

1046
01:24:39,708 --> 01:24:43,216
~Vanity's an illusion, will have to fade away

1047
01:24:43,249 --> 01:24:45,252
~Yeah

1048
01:24:45,749 --> 01:24:49,671
~And all the wicked deeds that done I know you got to pay

1049
01:24:49,708 --> 01:24:51,675
~Yeah, yeah

1050
01:24:51,708 --> 01:24:53,711
~Cos in the streets it's getting hot

1051
01:24:54,124 --> 01:24:57,466
~And the youths them a-get so cold

1052
01:24:57,874 --> 01:24:59,877
~Searching for food for the pot

1053
01:25:00,333 --> 01:25:02,631
~They'll do anything to fill that gap

1054
01:25:03,791 --> 01:25:05,959
~In the streets it's getting hot

1055
01:25:06,041 --> 01:25:09,335
~And the youths them a-get so cold

1056
01:25:09,708 --> 01:25:11,876
~Searching for food for the pot

1057
01:25:11,916 --> 01:25:14,677
~They'll do anything to fill that gap

1058
01:25:15,541 --> 01:25:17,923
~As generation comes and goes

1059
01:25:17,958 --> 01:25:21,134
~You gotta make preparation while the youths them grow

1060
01:25:21,624 --> 01:25:23,543
~It's what you reap, it's what you sow

1061
01:25:23,583 --> 01:25:25,799
~The youth, them are the light and the future

1062
01:25:25,833 --> 01:25:27,670
~That's when you know

1063
01:25:27,708 --> 01:25:29,675
~If education is the key

1064
01:25:29,708 --> 01:25:33,500
~Then tell me why the big guns they make it so expensive for we

1065
01:25:33,874 --> 01:25:36,090
~Give them the key Oh, set them free

1066
01:25:36,124 --> 01:25:38,422
~Ah-eeeeee!

1067
01:25:39,874 --> 01:25:42,172
~Give them the key Oh, set them free

1068
01:25:42,208 --> 01:25:44,211
~Ah-eeeeee!
