Shit.
[car approaching]
You pair of deuces lookin' for work...
l suggest you get your scrawny asses in here pronto.
(Aguirre) Up on Brokeback...
the Forest Service has got designated campsites...
on the allotments.
Them camps can be 3, 4 miles from where we pasture the woollies.
Bad predator loss if there's nobody lookin' after 'em at night.
Now, what l want is a camp tender...
to stay in the main camp, where the Forest Service says.
But the herder...
he's gonna pitch a pup tent on the QT with the sheep...
and he's gonna sleep there.
You eat your supper and breakfast in camp...
but you sleep with the sheep 100%.
No fire, don't leave no sign.
You roll up that tent every mornin'...
in case Forest Service snoops around.
[phone ringing]
Yeah?
No.
{man chattering on phone]
No!
Not on your fuckin' life.
You got your dogs, your .30-30, you sleep there.
Last summer l had goddamn near 25% loss. l don't want that again.
You.
Fridays at noon, be down at the bridge...
with your grocery list and mules...
and somebody with supplies will be there at the pick-up.
Tomorrow mornin' we'll truck you up to the jump-off.
Jack Twist. Ennis.
Your folks just stop at Ennis? Del Mar.
Well, nice to know you, Ennis Del Mar.
[dog barking]
{man chattering on TV]
My second year up here.
Last year, one storm, the lightnin' killed 42 sheep.
Thought l'd asphyxiate from the smell.
Aguirre got all over my ass, like l was supposed to control the weather.
But beats workin' for my old man. Can't please my old man, no way.
That's why l took to rodeoin'. You ever rodeo?
You know, l mean, once in a while.
When l got the entry fee in my pocket.
Yeah.
Are you from ranch people?
Yeah, l was.
Your folks run you off?
No, they run themselves off. There was...
one curve in the road in 43 miles, and they miss it.
So the bank took the ranch...
and my brother and sister, they raised me, mostly.
[lighter clicking] Shit, that's hard.
Can l? Thank you.
[clears throat]
[sheep bleating]
[men chattering]
(Basque) Don't let them stray.
Joe will have your ass if you do.
Only thing, don't never order soup.
Them soup boxes are hard to pack.
Well, l don't eat soup.
[horse neighing]
[dogs barking]
You wanna watch it there. That horse has a low startle point.
Doubt there's a filly that could throw me.
Let's git, unless you wanna sit around tyin' knots all day.
@@[Ennis whistling]
[Jack chattering]
[dog barking]
[sheep bleating]
[Ennis sawing]
[water rushing]
Oh, shit.
Can't wait till l get my own spread...
and l won't have to put up with Joe Aguirre's crap no more.
l'm savin' for a place myself.
Alma and me, we're gonna get married when l come down off this mountain.
Shit, that stay with the sheep, no fire bullshit.
Aguirre got no right makin' us do somethin' against the rules.
[horse snuffling]
[egging]
[thunder rumbling]
No more beans.
Damn. Shit!
l don't know. Something wrong?
Yeah, so what....
Why didn't we get the powdered milk and the spuds?
That's all we got.
Well....
Here's next week's.
Thought you didn't eat soup. Yeah, well, l'm sick of beans.
Too early in the summer to be sick of beans.
Come on.
@@[humming]
Come on. Come on.
[growling]
[horse neighing]
[bear roaring]
Hold on. Whoa, whoa!
[mules braying]
Shit.
Whoa. Come back here!
[horse snuffling]
Whoa there, whoa.
All right. Fuck it.
(Ennis) Okay, you bastard.
Where the hell you been?
Been up with the sheep all day, l get down here hungry as hell...
and all l find is beans.
[muttering]
[pans clattering]
What in the hell happened, Ennis?
l come on a bear is what happened.
Goddamn horse spooked and the mules took off...
and scattered food everywhere.
Beans is about all we got left. Got whiskey or somethin'?
Dumb-ass mule.
l can't believe that. God damn.
Let me see.
Shit.
Well, we gotta do somethin' about this food situation.
Maybe l'll shoot one of the sheep.
Yeah, what if Aguirre finds out, huh?
We're supposed to guard the sheep, not eat 'em.
What's the matter with you? There are a thousand of 'em.
l'll stick with beans.
Well, l won't.
[gun fires]
[whooping]
Yeah!
Gettin' tired of your dumb-ass missin'.
[laughing] Let's get a move on.
Don't want the Game and Fish to catch us with no elk.
Come on. Shit.
Yeah, l'm commutin' four hours a day.
l come in for breakfast, l go back to the sheep.
Evenin', get 'em bedded down.
Come in for supper, go back to the sheep.
Spend half the night checkin' for damn coyotes.
Aguirre got no right to make me do this.
You wanna switch? l wouldn't mind sleepin' out there.
That ain't the point. The point is, we both ought to be in this camp.
Goddamn pup tent smells like cat piss or worse.
l wouldn't mind bein' out there.
Well, l'm happy to switch with you...
but l warn you, l can't cook worth a damn.
l am pretty good with a can opener, though.
You can't be no worse than me, then.
Here you go.
[coughs]
You won't get much sleep, l'll tell you that.
Yup. Come on.
[clucks tongue]
[bird calling]
[horse snuffling]
Shot a coyote up there.
lt's a big son of a bitch. He had balls on him the size of apples.
He looked like he could eat himself a camel.
You want some of this hot water?
[mutters]
lt's all yours.
[urinating]
Mmm.
l don't rodeo much myself.
l mean, what's the point...
of ridin' some piece of stock for eight seconds?
Money's a good point. True enough.
lf you don't get stomped winnin' it, huh?
Yeah.
Well, my old man, he was a bull rider.
Thank you.
Pretty well-known in his day.
Though he kept his secrets to himself.
Never taught me a thing, never once come to see me ride.
[grunts]
Your brother and sister do right by you?
They did the best they could after my folks was gone.
Considerin' they didn't leave us nothin'...
but $24 in a coffee can.
l got me a year of high school.
That was before the transmission went on the pickup.
And then my sis left. She married a roughneck, moved to Casper.
And me and my brother...
we went and got ourselves some work on a ranch up near Worland.
Till l was 19. Then he got married.
And no more room for me.
That's how come me end up here.
What?
Man, that's more words than you've spoke in the past two weeks.
Hell, that's the most l've spoke in a year.
But my dad, he was a fine roper.
Didn't rodeo much, though.
He thought rodeo cowboys was all fuck-ups.
The hell they are.
Well....
[exclaims]
[whooping] There you go.
[exclaiming]
l'm spurrin' his guts out! Wavin' to the girls in the stands!
He's kickin' me to high heaven, but he don't jackboard me! No!
[clattering]
[laughing]
l think my dad was right.
[bleating]
[bird calls]
@@[harmonica playing]
Tent don't look right.
Well, it ain't goin' nowhere. Let it be.
That harmonica don't sound quite right either.
That's 'cause it got kind of flattened when that mare threw me.
Oh, yeah? Yeah.
l thought you said that mare couldn't throw you.
She got lucky.
Yeah, well, if l got lucky, that harmonica would've broke in two.
[grunts]
[chuckling]
(Jack) @ l know l shall meet you on that final day @
@ Water-walking Jesus, take me away! @@
[drumming]
Very good. Oh, yeah.
My mama, she believes in the Pentecost.
Oh, yeah?
What exactly is the Pentecost?
l mean, my folks, they was Methodist.
The Pentecost.
l don't know, l don't know what the Pentecost is.
Mom never explained it to me. l guess it's when the world ends...
and fellas like you and me, we march off to hell.
Speak for yourself.
You may be a sinner, but l ain't yet had the opportunity.
Thank you.
[bottle clinking] (Ennis) Shit!
l'm gonna go up to the sheep now.
(Jack) Give 'em hell.
[horse snuffling]
[slurring] No, l'm....
You can hardly stand. lt's too late to go to them sheep.
Well, you got an extra blanket?
l'll just roll up out here, grab 40 winks...
and l'll ride out at first light.
You'll freeze your ass off when that fire dies down.
Oh, that's good.
You're better off sleepin' in the tent.
Yeah.
All right.
[shivering]
[Jack sighing]
Ennis! What?
Just quit your yammerin' and get in here!
[pans clattering]
[blankets rustling]
[Jack whispering] Come on, come on.
(Ennis) What are you doin'?
[both breathing heavily]
[belt clinking]
[both moaning]
[gasping]
[Ennis grunting]
[birds chirping]
See you for supper.
Yeah. Come on.
[wind whistling]
[thunder rumbling]
[dog howling]
[dog barking]
Come on.
[dog whimpering]
[flies buzzing]
[sheep bleating]
This is a one-shot thing we got goin' on here.
lt's nobody's business but ours.
You know l ain't queer.
Me, neither.
l'm sorry.
lt's all right.
Lie back. Come on.
Twist.
Your Uncle Harold's in the hospital with pneumonia.
Docs don't expect he'll make it.
Your ma sent me to tell you, so here l am.
Bad news.
There ain't nothin' l can do about it up here, l guess.
There's not much you can do about it down there, neither.
Not unless you can cure pneumonia.
[wind howling]
[thunder clapping]
God damn! Jesus!
Them sheep will drift if l don't get back up there tonight!
You'll get pitched off your mount in a storm like this.
You'll wish you hadn't tried it!
lt's too cold! Close it up!
[men chattering in Spanish]
What are we supposed to do now, huh?
Get on in there and untangle 'em Chilean sheep out of ours, l guess.
Oh, where is it? Shit!
God, half the goddamn paint brands have wore off!
We gotta try. The least we can do is get the count right for Aguirre.
Fuck Aguirre! Oh, yeah, fuck Aguirre.
What if we need to work for him again? You think of that?
We gotta stick this out, Jack.
@@[harmonica playing]
You'll run them sheep off again if you don't quiet down.
[exclaiming]
What are you doing?
Aguirre came by again.
Says my uncle didn't die after all.
Says bring 'em down.
Bring 'em down, why? lt's the middle of August.
Says there's a storm comin', movin' in from the Pacific.
Worse than this one.
That snow barely stuck an hour. Huh?
Besides, that son of a bitch, he's cuttin' us out a whole month's pay.
lt ain't right.
Well...
l can spare you a loan, bud, if you're short on cash.
Give it to you when we get to Signal.
l don't need your money, huh?
You know, l ain't in the poorhouse. Shit!
All right.
Time to get goin', cowboy.
[Jack chuckling]
Come here! This ain't no rodeo, cowboy!
(Jack) Oh, shit!
[Jack laughing]
[both grunting]
[exclaims]
Ennis. Ennis.
Come here. You okay?
You okay? Yeah.
[shushing]
[Jack groaning]
[bleating]
Some of these never went up there with you.
Count ain't what l'd hoped for, neither.
You ranch stiffs, you ain't never no good.
[engine faltering]
Wanna give it some gas?
[revving]
l can't believe l left my damn shirt up there.
Yeah.
You gonna do this again next summer?
Well, maybe not.
Like l said, me and Alma is gettin' married in November.
So...
l'll try to get somethin' on a ranch, l guess.
And you?
Might go up to my daddy's place and give him a hand through the winter.
l might be back.
lf the Army don't get me.
Well, l guess l'll see you around, huh?
Right.
[gasping]
[retching]
[exclaiming]
What the fuck are you lookin' at? Huh?
(Minister) ''And forgive us our trespasses...
''as we forgive those who trespass against us.
(all) ''Lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil.
''For thine is the kingdom, the power and the glory, forever. Amen.''
Under the powers vested in me...
l now pronounce you man and wife.
You may kiss the bride. And if you don't, l will.
[all chuckle]
[all clapping]
[Alma shrieking]
You all right? No.
[Alma laughing]
Stop!
No, please don't!
(Timmy) My old lady's tryin' to get me to quit this job.
She says l'm gettin' too old to be breakin' my back shovelin' asphalt.
l told her strong backs and weak minds runs in the family.
[laughing] She didn't think that was too funny.
l told her it keeps me fit.
Mornin'. Mornin'.
(boy) PuIIed in Iast night. Didn't want to wake you up.
(girI) Oh, no, I was just....
I thought I'd teII you before the Sergeant showed up.
Parking this traiIer on the beach is iIIegaI.
[knocking on door]
Yeah!
Well, look what the wind blew in.
Hi, Mr. Aguirre.
l was wonderin' if you was needin' any help this summer.
You're wastin' your time here.
What, you ain't got nothin'?
Nothin' up on Brokeback?
l ain't got no work for you.
Ennis Del Mar ain't been around, has he?
You boys sure found a way to make the time pass up there.
Twist...
you guys wasn't gettin' paid to leave the dogs baby-sit the sheep...
while you stemmed the rose.
Now get the hell out of my trailer.
[vehicle approaching]
{man chattering on TV]
[babies crying]
How my girls doing?
All right. Jenny's still got a runny nose.
[babies continue crying]
[babies screaming]
[shushing]
Ennis, could you wipe Alma Jr.'s nose?
lf l had three hands, l could.
Come here. Come here. Oh!
Girls all right?
Yeah. Jenny stopped her coughin'.
l think l should take the girls into town this weekend.
Get 'em an ice cream. Somethin'.
Can't we move to town?
l'm tired of these lonesome old ranches.
No one's around for Junior to play with.
Besides, l'm scared for Jenny...
scared if she has another one of 'em bad asthma spells.
No, rent in town is too high.
There's a cheap place in Riverton, over the Laundromat.
l bet l could fix it up real nice.
l bet you could fix this place up real nice if you wanted to.
Ennis. Hmm?
l know you'd like it, too.
Real home, other kids for the girls to play with.
Not so lonely like you were raised.
You don't want 'em to be so lonely, do you?
Yeah.
Come here.
lt ain't so lonely now, is it?
Are you sure the girls are asleep? Yeah.
[panting]
Come here.
Ennis.
(maIe announcer) Let 'er rip and snort, boys!
Jack Twist, hangin' on for dear Iife!
And down he goes! Watch out there, feIIa!
He's comin' for you. Send in the cIowns!
Okay, a fine ride by Mr. Twist. Shit!
Four seconds for him.
Give 'em a hand, foIks, our very own rodeo cIowns!
@@{Trust in Lies by The Raven Shadows featuring Tim Ferguson playing]
Give us a beer, Doug.
l'd like to buy Jimbo here a beer.
Best damn rodeo clown l've ever worked with.
No thanks, cowboy.
lf l was to let every rodeo hand l pulled a bull off of...
buy me liquor, l'd have been a alcoholic long ago.
Pullin' bulls off of you buckaroos is just my job.
So save your money for your next entry fee, cowboy.
You ever try calf ropin'?
Do l look like l can afford a fuckin' ropin' horse?
@@[band playing]
[people chattering]
Shouldn't we move a little closer?
{maIe announcer chattering] No. Come on, let's don't. Jenny'll get scared.
[fireworks exploding]
[biker #1 whooping]
Look at this crowd!
Bound to be a lot of pussy on the hoof in a crowd like this.
(biker #2) All swelled up with patriotic feeling...
and ready to be humped like a frog.
So, where do you figure the most pussy is at?
[baby crying] Las Vegas or California?
Hell, l don't know...
but if you make it between Montana and Wyoming, l'd take Wyoming--
Hey! You might want to keep it down, l got two little girls here.
Fuck you. Asshole.
Probably quit givin' it to his wife after his kids was born.
[laughing] You know what that's like. Yeah.
Ennis, let's move. Let's just move, okay?
[fireworks exploding]
[babies crying]
Now, l don't want any trouble from you.
You need to shut your slop-bucket mouths, you hear me?
You ought to listen to your old lady, then.
ls that right? Yeah. Move somewhere else.
What about it? You wanna lose about half your fuckin' teeth, huh?
Not tonight, bud. l'd sure rather not.
(maIe announcer) Here she comes, Iadies and gentIemen!
[crowd cheering] Oh, boy, Iook at her fIy!
This is Lureen Newsome from right here in ChiIdress, Texas!
Come on, foIks, she's gotta hear it, Iet's give her a big hand!
She's turnin' on two!
She's around three!
Come on, foIks! HeIp her home!
Come on! Come on!
And the time is 16 and 9!
Here's Cheyenne Hodson from Cody, Wyoming!
Come on, girI!
She's headed around two!
Is there anybody here from Wyoming? Ma'am.
How about it, foIks?
Come on, Cheyenne!
And her time is 17 and 2!
Here comes Scotty Griffiths, out of Lubbock, Texas.
Come on, Scotty!
Damn it! Let's give Scotty Griffiths a big hand, foIks.
Better Iuck next time, cowboy.
Boy, I teII you, foIks, what a heck of a way to make a Iiving!
Next up is an up-and-comer!
Jack Twist from aII the way up in Lightning FIat, Wyoming.
He's onboard SIeepy today! Let's hope he's not!
Okay!
There they go, foIks! And Iook at SIeepy go, boy!
He's broke free today, foIks! Come on, spin and spin and spin!
Oh, boy! Good ride, cowboy! WeII, Iet's see what the judges say!
I teII you, foIks, that sure Iooked Iike the winnin' ride to me!
@@[band playing lively country music]
You know that girl?
l sure do. Lureen Newsome.
Her dad sells farm equipment. l mean, big farm equipment.
$100,000 tractors, shit like that.
What are you waitin' for, cowboy? A matin' call?
@ No one's gonna Iove you Iike me @
@ No one eIse, can't you see? @
@ No one, no one @
@ No one's gonna Iove you Iike me @
@ I know sometimes you feIt @
@ So IoneIy @
@ I know @
@ You feIt so sad and bIue @@
[crickets chirping]
@@{country music pIaying on radio]
[both moan]
Oh, wait, hold on.
You don't think l'm too fast, do you?
Maybe we should put the brakes on?
Fast or slow, l just like the direction you're goin'.
You are in a hurry. My daddy's the hurry.
He expects me home with the car by midnight.
[baby crying]
Come here, come here.
Hi, Monroe. Hey, Ennis.
ls Alma here?
Yeah, she's in the condiments aisle.
The what? Ketchup.
Thanks.
(man) Your boy gonna play again this year?
(Alma Jr.) Excuse us! Yeah, excuse me.
Hey, honey. Honey, what are y'all doing here?
Big hurry.
My boss called and, well, he wants me to go up to the ranch.
(Alma Jr.) Mama.
l guess all the heifers must've decided...
[baby crying] to calve at the same time.
l figured l could drop the girls off with you.
Ennis, well...
l got a million things l gotta do here before l can leave.
l don't get off for another three hours.
Mama, l need crayons. Not now, Alma.
Ennis, please, you promised you'd take them tonight.
Alma, l can't afford not to be there when the heifers calve.
Right, it'd be my job if l lose any of 'em.
What about my job?
Okay, all right, l'll call my sister.
l'll see if she can take 'em. All right. All right.
You be a good girl for your mama, all right?
l'll be half the night.
Bring home some ground steaks if you think of it.
[baby shrieking] Come here. Oh, Alma, please!
Oh, boy.
Okay. Monroe, l'm so sorry.
lt's okay. lt's okay, Alma.
l'll clean this up just as soon as l call my sister...
to come get the girls.
Really, Alma, it's okay. l'll get it.
Alma, come with me. Watch your feet.
Alma.
lt's just like my hand.
(Jack) Honey, got a surprise for you.
(Lureen) Hey.
l got two whole boxes of formula for you.
You did?
1 20 cans. 1 20?
L.D., where did you put 'em?
Oh, hell, back seat of the car, where l left 'em.
Rodeo can get 'em.
L.D., l can already see who little Bobby looks like.
Good job, little girl.
He's the spittin' image of his grandpa.
lsn't he just the spittin' image of his grandpa?
[gurgles]
Yeah.
(Lureen) Look at those eyes.
Hey.
(Ennis) Hey, honey.
[sizzling]
Hey, Ennis, you know somebody, name of Jack?
Maybe. Why?
'Cause you got a postcard. lt come general delivery.
ls he somebody you cowboyed with, or what?
No, Jack, he rodeos, mostly.
We was fishin' buddies.
[birds chirping]
(Alma) You can color that one, too.
(Alma Jr.) l'll color the beach.
Maybe we could get a baby-sitter. Huh?
Take your friend to the Knife and Fork?
No, Jack ain't the restaurant type.
We'll more likely just go out and get drunk.
That's if he shows.
Okay, we take one more bite, and then you're finished with dinner.
There, that's a good bite. All right, you're excused.
Please. Thank you.
[vehicle approaching]
Jack fuckin' Twist.
(Jack) Son of a bitch.
Come here.
[door opening]
Alma, this is Jack Twist.
And, Jack, this is my wife, Alma.
Howdy. Hello.
[Alma Jr. chattering]
You got a kid.
Yeah, l got two little girls. Alma Jr. and Jenny.
l got a boy. Yeah?
Eight months old. Smiles a lot.
l married the prettiest little gal in Childress, Texas.
Yeah? Lureen.
So me and Jack, we're gonna head out and get ourselves a drink. Yeah?
Sure enough. Pleased to meet you, ma'am.
We might not get back tonight...
when we get to drinkin' and talkin' and all.
Ennis?
Would you get me a pack of smokes?
lf you need smokes, Alma, they're in the top pocket of my blue shirt.
There in the bedroom.
[door shuts]
Four years. Damn! Yeah, four years.
Didn't think l'd hear from you again.
l figured you were sore from that punch.
Right next summer, l drove back up to Brokeback.
Talked to Aguirre about a job, and....
He told me you hadn't been back, so l left.
Went down to Texas for rodeoin'.
That's how l met Lureen.
Made $2,000 that year, bull ridin'. Nearly starved.
Lureen's old man makes serious money, farm machine business.
Of course, he hates my guts.
And the Army didn't get you? No, too busted up.
And rodeoin' ain't what it was in my daddy's day.
Got out while l could still walk.
Swear to God, l didn't know we was goin' to get into this again.
Yes l did. l red-lined it all the way.
l couldn't get here fast enough.
What about you? Me? l don't know.
l don't know.
Old Brokeback got us good, don't it?
What are we gonna do now?
l doubt there's nothin' we can do.
So now l'm stuck with what l got here.
Makin' a livin' is about all l got time for now.
[birds chirping]
[door opens]
[footsteps approaching]
[door shuts]
[door opening]
Hey.
Well, me and Jack is headed up the mountain for a day or two.
Do ourselves a little fishin'.
You know, your friend could come inside, have a cup of coffee.
Well, he's from Texas.
Texans don't drink coffee?
You sure that foreman won't fire you for takin' off?
You know, that foreman, he owes me.
l worked through a blizzard last Christmas. You remember that?
Besides, l'll only be a couple of days.
Bring fish, Daddy. A big, big one!
Come here. Come here.
Come here.
See you Sunday, latest.
l'm starvin'. Want to get somethin' to eat?
Yup.
[Alma sobbing]
(Ennis) Last one in!
[both exclaiming]
ls there anything interestin' up there in heaven?
Well, l was just sending up a prayer of thanks.
For what?
For you forgettin' to bring that harmonica.
l'm enjoying the peace and quiet.
You know it could be like this, just like this, always.
Yeah? How do you figure that?
What if you and me had a little ranch somewhere...
a little cow-and-calf operation? lt'd be a sweet life.
l mean, hell, Lureen's old man...
you bet he'd give me a down payment to get lost.
l mean, he more or less already said it.
No, l...
l told you it ain't gonna be that way.
You know...
you got your wife and baby in Texas.
You know, l got my life in Riverton.
ls that so?
You and Alma, that's a life? Now you shut up about Alma.
This ain't her fault.
The bottom line is...
we're around each other...
and this thing grabs hold of us again...
in the wrong place...
in the wrong time...
and we're dead.
l tell you...
there were these two old guys ranched up together down home.
(Ennis) EarI and Rich.
And they was a joke in town...
even though they were pretty tough oId birds.
Anyway, they found EarI dead...
in an irrigation ditch.
They took a tire iron to him, spurred him up...
and drug him around by his dick tiII it puIIed off.
You seen this? Yeah, l was what? Nine years old.
(Ennis) My daddy, he made sure me and my brother seen it.
Hell, for all l know, he done the job.
Two guys living together? No way.
Now, we can get together once in a while...
way the hell out in the middle of nowhere, but....
''Once in a while.''
Every four fucking years?
Well, if you can't fix it, Jack, you gotta stand it.
For how long?
(Ennis) As long as we can ride it.
There ain't no reins on this one.
[swing squeaking]
(Ennis) lt's nearly suppertime.
Where the hell do you think you're going?
(Alma) To work!
l thought you had the day off! Well, you thought wrong!
The girls need to be fed. Well, you take care of it!
Alma! Alma!
Supper's on the stove!
No one's eatin' unless you're servin' it!
l already promised l'd take the extra shift!
Fucking tell 'em you made a mistake, then!
God damn it, Alma! Alma!
[birds chirping]
[swing squeaking]
You girls need a push or somethin'?
(both) No.
(Jack) Listen to her purr, gentlemen!
You ain't gonna get that with your Caddy!
l told you what she could do, and now let me show you.
[tractor engine starting]
(farmer) Say, didn't that pissant used to ride the bulls?
He used to try.
[door closing] Honey, have you seen my blue parka?
(Lureen) Last time l seen it, you was in it...
day we had that big ice storm.
Well, could have sworn l seen it in here.
You know...
you've been going up to Wyoming all these years.
Why can't your buddy come down here to Texas and fish?
Because the Bighorn Mountains ain't in Texas.
And l don't think that his pickup could make it down here, anyway.
(Lureen) New model comin' in this week, remember?
You're the best combine salesman we got.
You're the only combine salesman, in fact.
Yeah, l'll be back in a week. That is, unless l freeze to death...
and l'll freeze if l don't find that parka.
Well, l don't have your goddamn parka.
You know, you're worse than Bobby when it comes to losin' stuff.
Well, speakin' of Bobby, did you call his school...
about gettin' him a tutor?
l thought you were gonna call.
l complain too much. That teacher don't like me. Right.
Now it's your turn. Okay, fine, so l'll call later.
[keys clicking]
Right. Fine.
Goodbye.
(Jack) Got 1 4 hours of driving ahead of me.
See now, it don't seem fair...
you goin' up there two, three times a year...
with him never comin' down here.
{man on TV chattering]
[clearing throat]
[girls chattering]
Ennis, they got an opening over at the power company.
Might be good pay.
Well, as clumsy as l am, l'd probably get electrocuted.
(Alma Jr.) Daddy, the church picnic's next weekend.
Will you be back from fishing by next weekend?
[grunts] Please, Daddy? Please!
Well, all right, as long as l don't have to sing.
Daddy. Thank you.
You forgettin' somethin'?
{TV chattering]
[footsteps pattering]
[door closing]
[truck approaching]
(Jack) You're late.
(Ennis) Look what l brought.
This way.
[both chattering]
[laughing]
There you go! No hands!
(Jack) lt's all yours, buddy! lt's all yours.
Come on, come on.
[cows lowing]
{TV chattering]
Come on in, AIvin.
(man) I've been trying to caII you for hours.
lt's Saturday night, you know, we could still smarten up...
and head on over to the church social.
That fire and brimstone crowd?
l think it'd be nice.
[moaning]
[gasping]
Ennis.
As far behind as we are on the bills...
it makes me nervous not to take no precaution.
lf you don't want no more of my kids...
l'll be happy to leave you alone.
l'd have 'em, if you'd support 'em.
[Ennis clearing throat]
(judge) Custody of the two minor chiIdren...
Alma Del Mar Jr. and Jennifer Del Mar...
is awarded to plaintiff.
Defendant is ordered to pay child support to plaintiff...
in the sum of $1 25 per month for each of the minor children...
until they reach the age of 18 years.
Del Mar divorce granted, this sixth day of November, 1975.
@@{King of the Road by Roger Miller playing on radio]
@@[whistling]
@ King of the road! @@
ln you go.
[truck honking]
{radio chattering]
What are you doin' here, huh?
l got your message about the divorce.
Come here.
Well, this here's Jack. Jack, these are my little girls.
There's Alma Jr. and Jenny. Hi.
Say hi, girls. (both) Hi.
[clearing throat]
l got your card that the divorce came through.
Yeah. So here l am.
l had to ask about 10 different people in Riverton...
where you had moved to.
l guess, l thought that this means you....
No, Jack, l don't know what to say.
See, l got the girls this weekend and....
Jeez, l....
l'm sure as hell sorry. You know l am.
See, l only get them once a month, and l missed last month.
So l just.... Because of the roundup.
So....
Well.... Yeah, all right.
Jack.
l'll see you next month, then.
[door shuts]
{radio chattering]
@@{A Love That WiII Never Grow OId by Emmylou Harris playing on radio]
[sobbing]
[crickets chirping]
[people chattering in Spanish]
@@{Quizas Quizas Quizas by Rick Garcia playing]
@@[music playing]
[man chatters]
[speaks Spanish]
{TV chattering]
(Lureen) Comin' up.
Here we go. Here we are!
[grunting]
Whoa there, Rodeo.
The stud duck do the carvin' around here.
You bet, LD. l was just saving you the trouble.
Bobby, if you don't eat your dinner...
l'm gonna have to turn off that television.
Why, Mama?
l'm gonna be eating this food for the next two weeks.
Hey, you heard your mama.
You finish your meal, and then you can watch the game.
[sighing]
Daddy?
Daddy.
Hell, we don't eat with our eyes.
(L.D.) You want your boy to grow up...
to be a man, don't you, Daughter?
[clearing throat] Boys should watch football.
Not until he finishes eating the meal...
that his mama took three hours to fix.
Now you sit down, you old son of a bitch!
This is my house, this is my child...
and you are my guest. Now you sit down...
before l knock your ignorant ass into next week.
[L.D. grunts]
[whirring]
[clearing throat]
[cutlery rattling]
Daddy, tell about when you rode broncs in the rodeo.
Well, that's a short story, honey.
lt was only about three seconds l was on that bronc.
The next thing l knew, l was flying through the air...
only l was no angel like you and Jenny here.
l didn't have no wings.
And that's the story of my saddle bronc career.
{TV chattering]
There you go.
[water flowing]
You ought to get married again, Ennis.
Me and the girls worry about you bein' alone so much.
Well, once burned....
You still go fishing with Jack Twist?
Not often.
You know, l used to wonder how come you never brought any trouts home.
You always said you caught plenty...
and you know how me and the girls like fish.
So, one night, l got your creel case open...
night before you went on one of your little trips.
Price tag still on it after five years.
And l tied a note to the end of the line.
lt said, ''Hello, Ennis, bring some fish home. Love, Alma.''
And then you come back lookin' all perky...
and said you caught a bunch of brownies and you ate them up.
Do you remember?
l looked in that case first chance l got...
and there was my note still tied there.
That line hadn't touched water in its life.
That don't mean nothing, Alma.
Don't try and fool me no more, Ennis.
l know what that means. Jack Twist.
Alma. Jack ''Nasty''!
You didn't go up there to fish. You and him--
Now you listen to me, you don't know nothing about it.
[crying] l'm going to yell for Monroe.
You do it and l'll make you eat the fucking floor.
Get out!
And you, too! Get out! Get out!
Get out of my house, Ennis Del Mar! You hear me? You get out!
Daddy?
[dishware shattering]
Alma?
(Jenny) Bye, Daddy!
(Alma Jr.) Bye.
[tires screeching]
Hey, asshole, watch where you're goin'!
Jesus. What....
Jesus....
(driver) You stupid fuck!
[grunting]
God damn!
[groaning]
God. God damn.
Oh, fuck!
Damn it!
All l'm sayin' is, what's the point of making it?
lf the taxes don't get it, the inflation will eat it all up.
You should see Lureen punchin' numbers in her adding machine.
Hunting for extra zeros, her eyes gettin' smaller and smaller.
lt's like watchin' a rabbit tryin' to...
squeeze into a snake hole with a coyote on its tail.
That's some high class entertainment, if you ask me.
For what it's worth.
You and Lureen, it's normal and all?
Sure.
She don't ever suspect?
You ever get the feelin'...
l don't know...
when you're in town...
and someone looks at you...
suspicious, like he knows.
Then you go out on the pavement and everyone's lookin' at you...
like they all know, too?
Well, maybe you ought to get out of there, you know?
Find yourself someplace different, maybe Texas.
Texas?
Sure, and maybe you can convince Alma...
to let you and Lureen adopt the girls.
Then we could just live together, herdin' sheep.
And it'll rain money from L.D. Newsome...
and whiskey will flow in the streams. Jack, that's real smart.
Go to hell, Ennis Del Mar.
You wanna live your miserable fucking life? Then go right ahead.
Fine. l was just thinkin' out loud.
Yup, you're a real thinker there. God damn....
Jack fucking Twist.
Got it all figured out, ain't he?
[people chattering]
(man) All right, hon.
@@{DeviI's Right Hand by Steve Earle playing]
Just finished my shift. Wanna dance?
l was on my way to the-- l'm Cassie. Cassie Cartwright.
Ennis. Del Mar.
No more dancin' for me, l hope.
You're safe. Yeah?
My feet hurt. Hard work, is it?
Yeah, drunks like you demanding beer after beer...
smokin'. Gets tiresome.
@@{It's So Easy by Linda Ronstadt playing]
What do you do, Ennis Del Mar?
Well, earlier today, l was castrating calves.
What are you doing?
Trying to get a foot rub, dummy.
All right.
That good?
@@[bluegrass music playing]
And then l pledged Tri Delt at SMU.
And l sure never thought...
l'd end up in a poky little place like Childress.
Then l met old Randall here at an Aggie game...
and he was an animal husbandry major.
So we've been here for a month and he got the foreman job...
over at Roy Taylor's ranch. Like it or not, here l am!
Was you Tri Delt? l was Kappa Phi myself.
Well, even though we ain't quite sorority sisters...
we just may have to dance with ourselves, Lureen.
Our husbands ain't the least bit interested in dancin'.
They ain't got a smidgen of rhythm between them.
lt's funny, isn't it?
Husbands don't never seem to wanna dance with their wives.
Why do you think that is, Jack?
l don't know, l never give it any thought.
Wanna dance?
Yes, thank you. (Jack) Do you mind?
No, it's all right. Go ahead. All right.
(LaShawn) Pardon us.
Thank you for asking me to dance with you.
l really appreciate that. Randall never does.
Last time l did, l think it was our wedding.
lt's a good thing you and Lureen happened along when you did...
or else we'd still be stuck on the side of the road...
in that darn pickup.
l told Randall we ought to take the car.
Of course, he'd never listen to me.
[laughing] He wouldn't listen to me if he was goin' deaf tomorrow.
l told him it'd take more than chewing gum and baling wire...
to fix that pickup.
Well, he's never been very mechanical, though.
[crickets chirping]
Come over here and ask....
[people chattering]
You ever notice how a woman will powder her nose...
before she goes to a party?
And then she'll powder it again once the party's over.
l mean, why powder your nose just to go home and go to bed?
Don't know.
Even if l wanted to know...
l couldn't get a word in with Lashawn long enough to ask.
Woman talks a blue streak. Lively little gal.
[clearing throat]
You'll like working for Roy Taylor.
He's solid, Roy. Yeah, Roy. He's a good old boy.
He's got a little cabin down on Lake Kemp.
Got a crappie house, little boat.
Said l could use it whenever l want.
We ought to go down there some weekend.
Drink a little whiskey, fish some.
Get away, you know?
(LaShawn) That was right out of SMU.
l could've had my pick of pretty much any job in North Dallas.
So my pick was Neiman Marcus, which was a disaster...
because, honey, where clothes is concerned, l got no resistance.
l was spending more than l made. More than Randall ever will make.
We come out here...
thinkin' that ranchin' was still big hats and Marlboros.
Boy, were we behind the times.
(Ennis) Hey there, Junior. You ready?
[truck door closing]
@@{country music pIaying]
(Cassie) What do you think?
Your daddy ever gonna see fit to settle down again?
Don't know. Maybe he's not the marrying kind.
You don't think so?
Or you don't think l'm the one for him?
[people chattering]
You're good enough.
@@{MeIissa by The Allman Brothers playing]
You don't say much, but you get your point across.
Sorry. l didn't mean to be rude.
[Ennis clearing throat]
All right.
You're stayin' on your feet, cowboy.
Excuse me, darling.
So l'll pick you and Jenny up next weekend, after church.
Fine.
You all right?
Yes.
Are you sure?
Daddy, l was thinking, what with the new baby and all...
Ma and Monroe have been awful strict on me.
More on me than Jenny even.
l was thinkin', maybe l could....
Maybe l could come stay with you.
l'd be an awful good help, l know l would.
Now, you know l ain't set up for that.
With the roundup comin'...
l won't ever be home.
lt's all right, Daddy.
l'm not sayin' that l wouldn't-- lt's all right, l understand.
Well, see you on Sunday, then.
Bye.
Bye, sweetheart.
Going to snow tonight for sure.
Yup.
All this time and you ain't found nobody else to marry?
l been puttin' the blocks...
to a good-lookin' little gal over in Riverton.
She's a waitress. Wants to go to nursing school or somethin'.
l don't know.
What about you and Lureen?
Lureen's good at making hard deals in the machinery business...
but as far as our marriage goes...
we could do it over the phone.
l kind of got this thing going with...
a ranch foreman's wife over in Rutters.
What? l'm bound to get shot...
by Lureen or her husband each time l slip off to see her.
You probably deserve it.
Tell you what.
The truth is...
sometimes l miss you so much, l can hardly stand it.
[truck door closing]
l guess l'll head up on to Lightning Flat.
See the folks for a day or two.
There's somethin' l been meanin' to tell you, bud.
Well, it's likely November before l can come out here again.
After we ship stock and before winter feedin' starts again.
November.
What in the hell ever happened to August?
Well....
Christ, Ennis.
You know, you had a fucking week to say some little word about this.
Why is it we're always in the friggin' cold?
We ought to go south where it's warm, you know!
We ought to go to Mexico.
Mexico?
Hell, Jack, you know me. About all the travelin' l ever done...
is around a coffee pot, looking for the handle.
(Ennis) Come on, Jack. Lighten up on me.
We can hunt in November.
Kill us a nice elk.
l'll try if l can get Don Wroe's cabin again.
We had a good time that year, didn't we?
There's never enough time, never enough.
You know, friend...
this is a goddamn bitch of an unsatisfactory situation.
You used to come away easy. Now it's like seein' the Pope.
Jack, l got to work.
ln them earlier days, l'd just quit the job.
You....
You forget what it's like bein' broke all the time.
You ever hear of child support?
l'll tell you this, l can't quit this one...
and l can't get the time off.
lt was hard enough gettin' this time.
The trade-off was August.
Well, you got a better idea?
l did, once.
(Ennis) You did, once.
Well, have you been to Mexico, Jack Twist?
'Cause l hear what they got in Mexico for boys like you.
Hell, yes, l've been to Mexico. ls that a fucking problem?
l'm going to tell you this one time, Jack fucking Twist.
And l ain't foolin'.
What l don't know, all them things that l don't know...
could get you killed if l come to know them.
l ain't jokin'.
Yeah, well try this one, and l'll say it just once.
Go ahead! l'll tell you what.
We could have had a good life together.
Fucking real good life. Had us a place of our own!
But you didn't want it, Ennis.
So what we got now is Brokeback Mountain!
Everything's built on that! That's all we got, boy. Fucking all.
So l hope you know that, if you don't never know the rest!
God damn it. You count the damn few times...
that we have been together in nearly 20 years...
and you measure the short fucking leash you keep me on...
and then you ask me about Mexico and you tell me you'll kill me...
for needin' somethin' l don't hardly never get!
You have no idea how bad it gets!
And l'm not you! l can't make it...
on a couple of high-altitude fucks once or twice a year!
You are too much for me, Ennis.
You son of a whoreson bitch!
l wish l knew how to quit you!
Then why don't you?
Why don't you just let me be, huh?
lt's because of you, Jack, that l'm like this.
l'm nothin'.
l'm nowhere.
lt's okay. Get the fuck off me!
[grunting]
[sobbing]
lt's all right. lt's all right.
Damn you, Ennis.
l just can't stand this anymore, Jack.
Come on now, you're sleepin' on your feet like a horse.
My mama used to say that to me when l was little.
And sing to me.
@@[humming]
l got to go.
See you in the morning.
@@{country music pIaying]
[phone ringing]
Excuse me.
Hey.
Ennis Del Mar.
Where you been?
Here and there.
l left word for you with Steve at the ranch.
And you must've got those notes l left at your place.
Looks like l got the message, in any case.
Carl?
Yeah, Carl's nice.
He even talks.
Good for you.
Yeah.
Good for me.
l don't get you, Ennis Del Mar.
l'm sorry.
l was probably no fun anyways, was l?
Ennis, girls don't fall in love with fun.
[sobbing]
[door closing]
[telephone ringing]
(Lureen) Hello. HeIIo, this is Ennis DeI Mar.
Who? Who is this?
Ennis Del Mar. l'm an old buddy of Jack's.
(Lureen) Jack used to mention you.
You're the fishing buddy or the hunting buddy, l know that.
Would have let you know what happened...
but l wasn't sure about your name or address.
Jack kept his friends' addresses in his head.
That's why l'm callin', to see what happened.
Oh, yeah.
Jack was pumpin' up a flat on the truck...
out on a back road, when the tire blew up.
The rim of the tire slammed into his face...
broke his nose and jaw and knocked him unconscious on his back.
By the time somebody come aIong, he'd drowned in his own bIood.
He was onIy 39 years oId.
HeIIo? HeIIo?
HeIIo.
Was he buried down there?
We put a stone up.
He was cremated, like he wanted.
Half his ashes was interred here, the rest was sent up with his folks.
He use to say he wanted his ashes scattered on Brokeback Mountain...
but I wasn't sure where that was.
I thought Brokeback Mountain might be around where he grew up.
Knowing Jack...
it might be some pretend place...
where bluebirds sing and there's a whiskey spring.
No, ma'am...
we was herdin' sheep on Brokeback one summer...
back in '63.
Well, he said it was his favorite place.
l thought he meant to get drunk. He drank a lot.
ls his folks still up in Lightning Flat?
They'II be there tiII the day they die.
Thank you for your time.
I sure am sorry.
We was good friends.
Get in touch with his folks.
l suppose they'd appreciate it if his wishes was carried out.
About the ashes, l mean.
[cows lowing]
[bird cawing]
Want a cup of coffee, don't you? Piece of cherry cake?
Yes, ma'am, l'll have a cup of coffee...
but l can't eat no cake just now. Thank you.
l feel awful bad about Jack.
Thank you.
l can't begin to tell you how bad l feel.
(Ennis) l knew him a long time.
l come by to say that...
if you want me to take his ashes up there on Brokeback...
like his wife said he wanted to...
then l'll be happy to.
l'll tell you what.
l know where Brokeback Mountain is.
Thought he was too goddamn special to be buried in the family plot.
(John) Jack used to say....
''Ennis Del Mar,'' he used to say.
''l'm gonna bring him up here one of these days...
''and we'll lick this damn ranch into shape.''
He had some half-baked notion...
the two of you was gonna move up here...
build a cabin...
help run the place.
Then, this spring...
he got another fella gonna come up here with him...
build the place, help run the ranch.
Some ranch neighbor of his from down in Texas.
Gonna split up with his wife and come back here...
so he says.
But, like most of Jack's ideas...
never come to pass.
(mother) l kept his room like it was when he was a boy.
l think he appreciated that.
You are welcome to go up to his room, if you want.
Yeah, l'd like that. Thank you.
[bird cawing]
(John) Tell you what.
We got a family plot. He's goin' in it.
Yes, sir.
You come back and see us again.
Thank you, ma'am.
@@{radio pIaying]
(Ennis) Hey there, Junior. Hey, Daddy.
[car door closing]
Come here.
Like the car?
Yeah. ls it yours? lt's Kurt's.
l thought you were seein' Troy. Troy?
Daddy, that was two years ago.
Troy still playing baseball?
l don't know what he's doing. l'm seein' Kurt now.
Well, what does Kurt do? Works out in the oil fields.
So he's a roughneck, huh? [laughing] Yeah.
l guess you're 19, you can do whatever you want. lsn't that right?
Sure.
[glass tinkling]
Daddy, you need more furniture. Yeah, well...
if you got nothin', you don't need nothin'.
So, what's the occasion?
Me and Kurt...
we're getting married.
Well....
So how long have you known this guy for?
About a year.
Our wedding will be June 5, at the Methodist church.
Jenny will be singing and Monroe is gonna cater the reception.
Now this Kurt fella...
he loves you?
Yeah, Daddy.
He loves me.
Was hopin' you'd be there.
Yeah.
l think l'm supposed to be on a roundup down near the Tetons.
You know what?
l reckon they can find themselves a new cowboy.
My little girl, getting married.
[grunts]
[bottle thuds]
To Alma and Kurt.
Jack, l swear....