Forget it, loser.
Oh, Mr. Lombardo.
- Hey.
- Hey, bro.
Mr. Lombardo, what's up?
- Hey, man.
- Hey.
Jennifer...
Did you see his eyes?
What are you looking at, dork?
Fuck off.
I appreciate you guys coming down.
The only thing I'm gonna miss
in this dump is...
Settle down.
Well, we've come to the halfway point
of our senior seminars.
Settle down.
- Beats study hall, doesn't it?
- No!
- That you, Jimmy?
- At least in study hall I can meditate.
What he means is, "masturbate."
Something with which I'm sure you've
had hands-on experience, Kirk.
It wasn't me, man.
It wasn't me.
I'm innocent.
We've all heard the terms
"date rape," "sexual harassment."
We've discussed some of these issues
right here in this very room.
Our guests today come from
the Blue Bay Police Department.
Detectives Duquette and Perez...
...are here to give us
what we hope...
...will be a fresh perspective
on the subject...
...and to address any questions
that any of you might have.
Now, let's give them
a warm welcome.
- Thank you.
- I'm out of here.
- Why don't we begin with a question.
- This prick can kiss my ass.
As I was saying...
...why don't we begin
with a question.
- What is a sex crime?
- Not getting any.
What's with that?
She's the one who walked out.
- Suzie Toller.
- I busted her last year for possession.
Poor kid did six months
in Camp Nine.
- Six months? First offense?
- I didn't hand down the sentence.
She was dirty.
I busted her.
Hey, Carol.
I appreciate you guys
taking the time to come.
Our pleasure.
Why do I get the feeling you don't
like the guidance counselor?
Don't tell me you can't see through
his routine. He's a total hound.
You mean pussy hound?
Actually, I thought
he was kind of cute.
I'd do him.
Steady.
Steady the bow, Jimmy.
That's good.
Drop the main.
All right, guys, let's de-rig
and I'll see you all Monday.
Hey, ladies, my car needs a wash.
Do you do windows?
Good work, guys.
A.C., see you Monday.
- See you, Mr. Lombardo.
- All right, buddy.
All right.
I could definitely party
on one of those.
It's a stinkpot, Jimmy.
You wanna be a real boatman,
you wanna get yourself one of those.
Yeah.
That's a real boat.
Thank you for getting me
into this class.
No way my old man was gonna
spring for the fees.
Hey, you're working for it, and you're
learning your way around a boat.
I put myself through college
working on boats.
- Beats flipping burgers.
- Yeah.
Can I play too, or is it just for boys?
So who's washing your Jeep
this weekend, Mr. Lombardo?
The senior car wash, remember?
Washing that old Jeep of mine
is a waste of time.
Not at all.
How about if Nicole and I do it?
We're working as a team.
I tell you what. I'm going out
to the glades Saturday.
Why don't you come over Sunday
and wash all the mud off.
Deal.
I was counting on my mom
to give me a ride, but she's not here.
Surprise, surprise.
So I was wondering
if you could give me one.
Mr. Lombardo, you really wouldn't
want me to walk, would you?
I mean, like,
something bad might happen.
- What about you, you need a lift?
- Yeah, but I got my bike.
Hey, no problem.
Okay, try it.
Suzie, you need a lift?
We got room for one more.
Jesus. Where'd she get those shoes,
"Whores 4 Less"?
Try it again.
Nice to see you kids getting along.
- Don't forget Sunday.
- I won't.
- Is that Sam Lombardo?
- Hi, Mom.
Sam, hi.
Hi, Sandra.
Why don't you come on in
and have a drink.
Sorry, Sandra, I gotta run.
- Hi, Mr. Lombardo.
Hi, girls.
Look. He forgot.
- I knew it.
- No, I didn't.
Check out my Jeep.
Nice and dirty for you.
But you might wanna wait
till the other car leaves.
You mean the Mercedes
isn't yours too?
My Benz is blue.
You know that, Nicole.
Sam, I'm leaving.
So where's your hose,
Mr. Lombardo?
The hose, Kelly,
is right in front of the Jeep.
Kelly Van Ryan's
gonna wash your Jeep?
Come on, Barbara.
It's for a good cause.
Sam the philanthropist.
Yeah, well, you know what they say:
A little hard work never hurt anyone.
Okay.
- Have fun at the club.
- Okay.
Wow.
Looks brand-new.
Aren't you forgetting something?
Your coupon.
We gotta have it.
Oh, yeah, that thing.
- Can't we just...?
- Rules are rules, Mr. Lombardo.
Okay, let me look for it.
Mr. Lombardo,
we're running kind of late.
How about if Nicole goes on
to the Mansons'?
You can give me a ride
when you find it.
No, no, just give me a minute. Okay?
- Go.
- Are you sure?
Oh, Frankie.
Oh, God.
Oh, God!
Goddamn it!
- Hello, this is Blue Bay High School.
- Hello.
Your son or daughter
was absent today, Monday...
Jesus H. Christ!
- What?
- Oh, nothing.
Come on.
- Art, this is a hell of a fish you caught.
- It's a barracuda.
If you weren't so busy
chasing booty...
...you'd have come with me
and caught one for yourself.
Don't tell me you're gonna
eat this thing.
Why not?
It's a barracuda. It's poisonous.
It'll kill you.
Shit, man, I could say that
about most of the girls you date.
Sandra Van Ryan for Sam.
- Sandra, what's up?
- Kelly skipped school today, Sam.
Have you heard anything?
Not a word.
Never mind.
I found her.
Pull!
Listen, Sam, it was really good
seeing you the other day.
Sandra, I'm real busy right now, so...
I haven't found anyone who can
handle my boat the way you can.
- Yeah, well...
- I know you're fucking Barbara Baxter.
- So what?
- So maybe I'm a one-woman man now.
Aw, poor Sam.
Really think you'll get one of these
Blue Bay women to marry you?
- Are you finished, Sandra?
- Grab a clue, honey.
You're a hired hand, a good lay.
That's as far as it goes.
Enjoy it, while it lasts.
Goodbye, Sandra.
Pull!
You seem to find guns therapeutic.
Maybe I ought to try it.
So let me guess.
Some boy didn't call and screwed up
your whole weekend.
So you're taking the day off. Right?
Which one of your deck hands
is that?
Whichever one I want.
Okay, Kelly, what's the matter?
What is it?
I miss Dad.
Jesus.
I miss him too, sometimes.
No, you don't.
He didn't have to kill himself, Kelly.
Oh, Kelly...
I don't know why he did it.
I really don't.
Can l...?
Can I get you anything?
Do you want a Valium?
I was raped.
- What, honey? I can't hear you.
- I said, I was raped.
What?
I was raped...
...by Sam Lombardo.
Sam Lombardo?
My daughter does not
get raped in Blue Bay!
And you're saying that
Sam Lombardo raped her?
That son of a bitch must be insane
to think he can do this to me.
We understand your feelings,
Miss Van Ryan...
...but please,
we need some time with Kelly.
We'd like to take her statement alone.
- Are you all right with this, baby?
- Yeah.
Okay.
Would you like to take a break
for a minute?
I just wanna get it over with.
We'd like to videotape this statement.
I know this isn't pleasant, Kelly,
but these are serious charges...
...and we need to know everything that
happened between the two of you.
Are you ready?
He started rubbing my shoulders.
I let him.
I mean, he's a nice guy.
The next thing...
...his hand was in my shorts.
You know, from behind.
His fingers...
- His fingers...
- Take your time.
They were in me.
Both places, you know?
Did he put himself inside you?
Yes.
I said "Stop."
I screamed.
I mean, that's how it
sounded in my head.
He hurt me.
Did you try to fight him?
Well, he had my wrists
pinned behind me.
Then what?
He kept saying, "Let it happen.
Let it happen."
And then he just stopped.
You mean he withdrew?
I don't know. It's really hard
to remember, exactly.
Try, Kelly.
I know one thing he said.
He said, "Don't worry.
I didn't come."
I can't forget that.
He said, "No little girl
can ever make me come."
"No little girl can ever
make me come." Jesus.
Too bad. We might have had
some physical evidence.
What?
Maybe there's no physical evidence
because nothing happened.
You want my gut? There it is.
I think she's acting.
I think she set it up to be alone
with him so he'd come on to her.
She's upset because he didn't.
Maybe she set it up that way.
Maybe not.
The guy never should've had her
there in the first place.
The line I have on him,
he's done half the women in Blue Bay.
That doesn't make him a rapist.
What about asking her
to take a polygraph?
What about asking the pope
to take a piss test?
This is Blue Bay, Gloria.
Ask a Van Ryan to take a lie detector
test and Tom Baxter will cut you down.
You afraid of Tom Baxter now?
You afraid of Sandra Van Ryan?
End of discussion.
You both know what to do.
Start with his neighbors, coworkers.
Talk to Kelly's friends.
- You know what that'll mean for him.
- Yeah.
And you heard Kelly's statement.
The guy's dirty. Bring me a case.
All right.
Good work, Jimbo.
I'll see you Monday.
All right.
That's what's left of my sailing class.
Talk to me, Artie.
Kelly Van Ryan
is accusing you of rape.
Jimmy told me.
Apparently, I'm the last one
to know about it.
Sam, I...
Sandra Van Ryan has been
on the horn all day...
...with every member
of the school board.
She's pushing for suspension.
And the board's just gonna roll over
for her without hearing my side?
This is insane.
I'm innocent, goddamn it.
You gotta believe that.
All I can tell you, Sam,
is hang in there.
They clear you, you get reinstated...
You never get clear
of something like this.
It stays with you.
It follows you around forever.
You're gonna need some help, Sam.
You're gonna need an attorney.
Right. And maybe you can tell me
which attorney in South Florida...
...is gonna wanna go up against
the Van Ryans in court.
I'm here to see Ken Bowden.
- Do you have an appointment?
- Oh, yeah. Sam Lombardo.
Okay, then.
Mr. Bowden,
your 10:30's here.
Will you show him in, please?
What brings you
to this part of town?
Well, I was, until yesterday...
...a guidance counselor
at Blue Bay High School.
A student there
is accusing me of rape.
Male or female?
- The student is Kelly Van Ryan.
- As in Sandra Van Ryan?
As in, I'm fucked.
Why don't you tell me about it?
- Shit, where do I begin?
- Start with...
...your relationship with the girl, Kelly.
She's a student. I was her counselor.
Beyond that, there's no relationship.
You got nothing to worry about.
- What did you do to your neck?
- This?
I don't have to wear it all the time.
There was an insurance guy
around here earlier.
All right, let me tell you
how I charge.
Georgie, hey.
We gonna catch some wind?
Mr. Lombardo, I'm afraid
I can't park your car today.
You can't park me?
I'm meeting Barbara for lunch.
Can you get this parked, Georgie?
We're running late.
Right away, Mr. Baxter.
You're finished here, Lombardo.
Take a hike.
Barbara, let's go.
Maybe you didn't hear me, Lombardo.
You're finished in Blue Bay.
I find you around my daughter again,
you'll be finished, period.
- Get the fuck out of here.
- Mr. Lombardo, please.
That's all right, George.
Sam, honey.
Haven't seen you in a while.
- Welcome back.
- Rum and Coke.
Hey! Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
- Cool?
That's too bad, motherfucker.
Sam?
Lombardo?
Whoa, man! It's me.
Sorry, man. Things have been
getting a little weird around here.
I can see that.
Come on in.
You're sure this Frankie Condo guy
is the guy that did this to you?
It was him, all right.
He was driving
Sandra's Range Rover.
You tell that to the cops, we can
go after Sandra Van Ryan right now.
- Forget it.
- The lady has deep pockets.
Believe me, I know how deep
her pockets are.
I thought I might be able to save
my house. Some sort of equity loan.
Guess who's on the
board of directors at the bank?
I don't need any more trouble
from this woman.
You think making some sort
of statement's gonna stop her?
With the shit I got on Kelly?
Yeah.
A year ago...
...when her old man
blew his brains out...
...Kelly lost it, ran away.
They found her in a fleabag motel
some place, coked out of her gourd.
Meanwhile...
...you, Sam, are voted
Educator of the Year...
...or some crap.
They put the two of you
in front of a jury...
...they're gonna look stupid.
They know it.
Why do you think they haven't
taken your statement yet?
Because they're busy
looking for dirt.
And they're not gonna find it.
Right?
Ken, I don't fuck my students.
He's just showing off
for you now.
Hey there, Ruby.
I see you still got Walter.
I was hoping something
had eaten him by now.
- Can I help you with something?
- Suzie called us.
Where would we find her?
You know the way.
You won't shoot her, will you?
I don't believe she's armed.
Yeah?
Jesus, it took you guys
long enough.
What if someone was trying to
strangle me or fuck me in the ass?
I mean,
you guys do sex crimes, right?
My partner, Detective Perez.
It's Céline. He's okay. He had a good
line on what cheap fucks people are.
Yeah, so Suzie, you called us.
Remember?
Did they arrest Mr. Lombardo?
No.
- Will they?
- I don't know.
That bothers you?
I wanna go outside.
When was this that Sam Lombardo
gave you the ride?
About a year ago.
And when you arrived at your trailer,
was anyone there?
- Nope.
- So you were alone.
Yeah.
Did he come in with you?
- I guess.
- You guess. Well, did he or didn't he?
Okay. Yeah, he did.
And then what? Did he touch you?
Did you maybe flirt with him a little?
Suzie, look, I know you feel bad.
- Just tell us the truth.
- I didn't say a thing to him.
He just put his arm around me
and told me I was pretty.
I could be really pretty, he said.
Did you ask him to stop?
Shit.
What difference does it make?
No one believes me anyway.
- Did Sam Lombardo rape you?
- Yeah. Okay? He did.
He pushed me to the floor
and he did it to me.
- Now are we done?
- Almost, Suzie.
Almost.
At some point,
were you able to fight him off?
No. He stopped by himself.
Okay? Is that it?
Leave me alone.
- Don't touch me!
- All right, take it easy. Take it easy.
He stopped.
And that was it? He just left?
Yeah.
He did say one thing first.
What was that?
He said, "No little bitch
can ever make me come."
Open the gate.
- Hey, counselor, how about a smoke?
- Hello, Jinxy.
You know, it's really a
bad news, good news situation.
You were denied bail,
but you got a real attorney...
...instead of a public defender.
I'm telling you, Ken, I'm innocent.
You are preaching to the choir.
You're not alone.
So you're the new
chicken licker.
Sandra, can we get your comment?
Can I just have your feelings
at this time?
Mr. Lombardo will get
what he deserves.
Can you tell us anything?
- Are you confident about the case?
- Very. Yes.
The Lombardo rape case
has galvanized the upscale town...
...of Blue Bay with its tabloid appeal.
Now just arriving, Sandra Van Ryan...
...jet-set real estate heiress
and part of the powerful Blue Bay elite.
And the girl from the wrong side of the
tracks. In the end, the jury...
...must choose between the words
of these 18-year-old girls...
...and that of Sam Lombardo.
Reporting from the courthouse steps,
I'm Nancy Duerr.
Eyewitness News.
The State of Florida
v. Sam Lombardo.
The Honorable Sylvia B. Waxman
presiding. All rise.
We gotta stand up.
Please be seated.
Now sit down.
Would you like more time, Kelly?
I know that this is hard, Kelly...
...but I have one more question.
And even though it's something
we've been over...
...I want us all
to be very clear about it.
Kelly, when you saw
that Mr. Lombardo...
...intended to have sex with you...
...what were your exact words?
What did you say?
I told him "No."
I said,
"Stop, Mr. Lombardo. Please."
I screamed for him to stop.
You screamed for him...
...to stop.
And did he?
No.
He raped me on the floor
of his shitty house.
Thank you.
It's day two of the Lombardo rape case
and the second alleged young victim...
...of the former guidance counselor
has taken the stand.
Yesterday, Kelly Van Ryan delivered
an emotional account of events...
...and was not swayed by
defense counsel's cross-examination.
We'll come back live later
with an update of these proceedings.
Reporting from the courthouse
steps, I'm Nancy Duerr...
...Eyewitness News.
Good morning, everybody.
Ms. Toller.
When you were...
...picked up for shoplifting
your freshman year at Blue Bay...
...and you were allowed
to make one call...
...you called Mr. Lombardo.
Isn't that correct?
Ms. Toller?
- Yes.
- And when you were expelled...
...for destruction
of school property...
I broke a fucking window.
And it wasn't even my fault.
Ms. Toller, you will wait until
you are asked before responding...
...and you will refrain from
using profanity in this court.
It was Mr. Lombardo who appeared
with you in lieu of a parent conference.
Is that right?
Yes.
It seems to me...
...that Mr. Lombardo
was your friend.
He was.
But all that changed when...
...according to your testimony...
...Mr. Lombardo...
...raped you...
...on April 23 of last year,
is that right?
- Yes.
- But then in May...
...when you were arrested
for possession of narcotics...
...and again allowed a phone call...
...you called Mr. Lombardo.
- So what?
So what?
Oops, Suzie.
So one month after you say this man
raped you, you go to him for help?
Sounds as if you still considered
Mr. Lombardo a good friend.
- I needed help.
- I'm sure you did.
But Mr. Lombardo
wasn't there this time.
It was summer, he was gone...
...and you spent six months
in a state correctional facility.
Did that make you mad, Suzie...
...that Sam was gone?
That he wasn't there?
Is that why you're saying
these things about Mr. Lombardo...
...your friend?
- I said them because they happened.
Ms. Toller, are you gonna
sit there today, under oath...
...and swear that Samuel Lombardo
raped you?
I said he did.
Let me ask you a question,
Ms. Toller.
Did you enjoy
being a guest of the state?
Because I promise you,
if you are lying about this...
...and I believe you are...
...that you will be visiting
that facility again quite soon.
Which is why I'm gonna ask you
again now, under oath.
Suzie...
...did Samuel Lombardo rape you?
Ms. Toller, you will have to
answer the question.
- Ms. Toller.
- Goddamn it!
- This was not my idea.
- Objection, Your Honor.
Ms. Toller is clearly responding
to defense counsel's badgering.
Court would like to hear
what Ms. Toller has to say.
Ms. Toller?
Sam Lombardo didn't rape me.
He didn't rape Kelly either.
He didn't do anything.
This is ridiculous. The witness has
been threatened by defense counsel!
I think I made it plain this court
intends to hear Ms. Toller's story.
Ms. Toller.
I just wanted to hurt
Mr. Lombardo.
He was my friend at first.
And then I got busted,
and he didn't stick up for me...
...and I had to go away
to that hell hole.
It's like you're his favorite,
and then "Who cares?"
Make her stop.
When Kelly said that
we should do this...
...I thought, "Cool."
- Kelly!
All these big shots screwing me over,
like that cop, Duquette.
- Now they're gonna get screwed.
- I'm sorry, Your Honor.
I have to object.
Your Honor, please, may I be heard?
Mr. Baxter, you are not
trying this case.
Go sit down.
Kelly's pissed
at Mr. Lombardo too.
She's in love with him.
He's been her fantasy
since her old man died.
Then she found out he was doing
her mom, and that was it.
What? Kelly!
You skanky bitch!
Get your fucking hands off of me!
Don't you know who I am?
- I'm gonna have you fired on Monday!
- Right this way.
Just get the hell away from me.
Jesus, man! Let loose!
I'm just thinking about where
I'm gonna stay.
I lost my house.
Waking up from
a goddamn nightmare.
You'll get over it.
We have got a knockdown,
airtight, motherfucker lawsuit...
...against Sandra Van Ryan.
Just like that?
These people ruined your life, bro.
I told you they were gonna go too far.
They went overboard! They did!
They'll settle. Believe me.
They'll be begging to settle.
Oh, yeah! Here we go!
Hey, wait up! Come on, girl.
In a startling turn of events,
Sam Lombardo has been dismissed...
...following a reversal of testimony
by one of his alleged victims.
Excuse me. Over here.
Excuse me. Can anybody read?
Hey! Sandra!
I want you to nail that shyster's balls
to the nearest wall.
We could have,
if Ms. Not-So-Bright here...
...hadn't thrown things.
- Fuck off.
I cannot believe you're just gonna
let them get away with this shit!
All on the word of
one little white-trash bitch.
I don't think you get it, Sandy.
Your princess here
committed perjury.
It'll be all I can do to keep
her fucking little ass out of jail.
Well, what are we going to do?
- You're gonna love this place, Tom.
- Thank you.
That jalapeño pork platter
will kill you.
I mean, you can't eat sushi every day
of the week.
Bowden, why don't you
cut the crap...
...and tell me
what your client really wants.
Okay, Baxter.
My client wants your client
to saddle up...
...so we can ride her ass
straight to the bank.
You know, Ken.
May I call you Ken?
There will be other cases,
other days.
The way I see it...
...Tommy...
...is that everybody's gotta
eat some shit sometime.
You like yours hot?
Yeah.
- Here's your coffee, Sam.
- Thank you.
Ken.
Sorry I'm late.
Hold my calls, Lenore.
Okay, Mr. Bowden.
Thank you, Sandra.
I'll be seeing you.
- Okay?
- Okay. Yeah.
Nice to see you, Tom.
Come by.
We'll have lunch.
See you at the club.
See you at the club, Tommy!
Hey, Tom.
What did you shoot today, pal?
Hey, my man!
This is for you.
- You did good, Ken.
- Yeah.
Thanks.
I know there's a part of you that wishes
none of this had happened, but it did.
So take the money
and enjoy yourself.
All right? Find a happy place.
Lenore, would you see
Mr. Lombardo out, please?
- Goodbye, Sam.
- Bye, Lenore.
Take care of my lizards?