She-Hulk? She-Hulk. She-Hulk.
Lady-Hulk, Girl-Hulk, She-Hulk. Give 'em what they want.
Previously on She-Hulk...
That name better not stick.
What if you made a profile as She-Hulk?
I'm not proud of this.
Is there anything worse than dating in your 30s?
I have to admit, I was a fan.
I mean, your battle with Titania in court,
- it was incredible.
Supporters of the Free Titania movement are celebrating
- that she's been cleared of all charges. - Boo.
I've got court documents filed by Titania Worldwide LLC.
She's suing me over the name "She-Hulk"?
But that's my name.
Strength is beauty. Beauty is strength.
What makes you beautiful?
She-Hulk by Titania.
Be strong, be beautiful. Own who you are.
I am strength. I am beauty.
I own who I am.
She-Hulk by Titania,
a luxurious new line of skin care, beauty, and wellness products
created by Titania exclusively for you.
She-Hulk by Titania.
You're listening to Pro Say, Law 360's podcast.
A quick word from our sponsor.
Hey, Titaniacs, can't wait to see you all.
- Ched! - Yo. What's up, Jen?
You can't just walk into my house!
What do you want me to tell you? I just did.
I'm making a killing selling these signed She-Hulk products.
They love you. The people love the She-Hulk.
- So I need your John Hancock for me. - I'm not signing those.
What do you mean? I'm supporting your business venture.
No, this is not mine. It has nothing to do with me.
- It's got your name here on the label. - This is someone else.
This woman, Titania, has trademarked my name.
That's dumb. Why would you let her do that?
I didn't let her, Ched.
You know, Jen,
the way trademark works is,
whoever gets there first, gets it.
So if you would've done yours first, she wouldn't have been able to do that.
Thank you.
She tweeted that she'd be here connecting with her fans.
You follow her?
It's for reconnaissance. Where are you going?
- To talk to her. - Yeah, we are.
But we're not waiting in line. You kidding?
We enter with confidence. That's how it works. Excuse us.
What is this?
"Snake venom lip plumper."
She's literally selling snake oil.
"Beauty serum."
"Beauty oil."
"Beauty tonic." How are these not all exactly the same thing?
Are you kidding? They're completely different.
Free samples?
These are all for me and that girl.
- Thank you so much, thank you.
I'm so sorry, little child, but the line starts way back there.
I don't wanna cut.
I want you to stop, and take all of this down.
What's the issue?
You're using my name to sell your trashy products, and you're suing me?
Get over it, Jennifer. The name She-Hulk is mine.
Excuse me?
Could you take a photo?
Oh, my God, yes. Back up a little bit. Just give me some space.
- She's gonna... - You taking it?
Just one, and that is it.
I can't believe she stole my name.
But you said you didn't like that name anyways.
- I don't. - Okay.
It's just what people decided to call me. It's not who I am.
I'm still Jennifer Walters.
She-Hulk is just a thing that happened to me.
- That's a really good perspective to have. - I admit there are parts that I enjoy.
- Okay, you're not done. - Like the amazing hair, no hangover.
Walking home with headphones on without being afraid.
- Every woman's dream. - But I'm not a different person
who needs a different name.
Okay. So you're not mad at the name She-Hulk?
No, I don't care about it.
- Okay. So you're totally over it? - Yeah, like, the most over it.
You're crushing your stapler.
What?
Why does she have to charge her fans so much for everything?
Because that's smart, Nikki. That's why she is rich and you're broke.
What's happening, Nik?
Oh, I was just talking to myself.
I can't pretend I'm here for a friendly visit. I need a favor.
Oh. well, you know my price.
- Return favor. Plus interest. - Done.
- Okay. - Stand in line with me
waiting for a sneaker drop?
The Iron Man Threes are coming out. They're limited to one pair per customer.
Why do you need two pairs?
One to rock and one to stock.
Okay, so you're telling me that you collect shoes
to look at that you're never gonna wear?
I respect that.
I'm not gonna brag to you or anything,
but I do have some pretty rare limited editions
that I got from my drip broker.
Through your... Excuse me, your what?
Yeah, I got a guy, Alonzo, the drip broker.
He can find anything you're looking for, fashion-wise.
Can this drip broker find someone who could do custom clothing
for, say, a super-human sized person?
No doubt.
Okay. I'm gonna need to call in my favor right now.
- You haven't done my favor. - I'm letting you slide on the interest.
You're right.
- You're right. Slick Nik. Slick Nik.
I just wanted to thank all of my beloved Titaniacs
- for helping me reach my... - I'm over it. I really am.
Alonzo says that it's a front for a superhero clothing business.
Okay.
- Hi, are you ready to order? - Hey, how you doing, man?
My boy Alonzo sent me.
Alonzo. Okay, what's the order?
No, no. My boy, Alonzo,
the drip broker.
He sent me.
For the superhero stuff.
What is that, Chinese? I'm not Chinese.
Well, I said we're not cops.
And I said it in Chinese.
I feel so much shame.
- He's mad. I offended him. I... - Okay.
Come to the back.
- All right. - Creepy back-room situation.
- This kind of hustle. - Okay.
What do you need? I got everything.
Captain America shield, Thor hammer.
Avengers T-shirt.
This says, "Avongers."
You don't like Avongers? I got Avingers.
Oh, with an I.
I kind of like this.
Okay, no, we don't want bootleg stuff, okay?
I want custom-made clothing for a superhero.
Question, if you're not the guy, then do you know who the guy is?
He won't meet you. He's exclusive.
Okay. So you do know the guy.
Okay, fine. I'll buy one of your Avongers T-shirts.
- And a matching hat. - Yes, I wanna complete the ensemble.
Okay.
No.
Hi.
I wanted to talk to you about making clothing for my client...
Do you have a referral?
Titania referred me.
I saw you shrug. Rejected.
Actually, my client is an Avenger.
- She's one of the top-tier ones, sir. - Yes.
Fifteen-minute consultation. My assistant will set up the appointment.
I can still see you.
- Okay. Okay. - Yes, sir. Thank you.
Is everything all right, sir?
No.
Why did I pass a billboard on Santa Monica Boulevard today
advertising a She-Hulk booty boost smoothie?
Oh, so, that's not actually me.
So that name was never really mine, officially.
Everyone in the media just started calling me that.
But now this incredibly awful, slightly super-powered woman...
Uh, yeah, I'm gonna stop you, 'cause none of that's my concern.
Okay.
GLK and H made She-Hulk the face
of our superhuman law division.
And now, we find ourselves in the middle of a frivolous lawsuit.
No one hires a firm that can't handle its own messes.
I am going to fix this, sir.
No, you won't.
I'm surprised and relieved you aren't foolish enough
to try to represent yourself.
At least you know that basic rule.
I'm taking this on as a professional courtesy,
but moving forward, we are not colleagues.
I'm the attorney, you're the client. That's the only way this can work.
Agreed?
Agreed.
Why didn't you trademark your pseudonym?
I never even thought about it, you know? Why would I?
Did Doctor Strange have to trademark his name? Did Thor?
You chose two examples of people who use their real names.
This is the person who legally outmaneuvered you?
Yeah.
We need to show strength. Countersue.
Establish you were using the name
in a professional capacity before the trademark date,
and Titania is profiting off name recognition
already established in the marketplace.
If you're gonna be my client, dress like you respect yourself,
and not like a football player pleading no contest to a DUI.
Nikki?
Yes? Wasn't lurking. I was close by.
You obviously spend a lot of time thinking about what you wear.
- Why don't you help her? - I'm actually already on top of that.
I got you a consultation with the guy who makes clothing for superheroes.
- Oh, I don't think I really need that. - You do, yeah.
Nice suit, Shrek.
All rise. Court is now in session.
Your Honor, we move to dismiss this entirely frivolous suit.
My client owns the trademark for She-Hulk.
Ms. Book may enjoy wasting the court's time,
but you can be certain that I do not.
Ms. Book?
Thank you, Your Honor.
As you will see, there are no issues of fact here
that would require proceeding to trial.
Since the first public appearance of Jennifer Walters in her Hulk form,
the public has unanimously identified her with the name She-Hulk.
In fact, the name had not even been recorded
in public discourse until that debut.
We have a number of news items and broadcast quotes
I'd like to enter into record.
Simply put,
the defendant is exploiting goodwill towards my client
and her better-known cousin,
in order to sell her non-FDA approved sham products.
We ask the court to grant our motion
for summary judgment, and order our requested remedies.
Okay.
First of all, "sham"?
Why don't you try telling that to the thousands of testimonials
from my fans who have had nothing but amazing results
with my exclusive line of She-Hulk Foot Exfoliants,
which I just so happen to have a little sample of,
and offer into evidence, thank you.
No, we don't need...
Can we please stay on track here?
What my client is trying to say is that She-Hulk was not...
You can sit down.
What my client is trying to say is that Ms. Walters was not interested
in the She-Hulk name until it became associated
with this incredibly successful line of products.
If we may.
- She-Hulk! Hey, She-Hulk! - I will not answer to that name.
You know why? 'Cause it's not my name.
She-Hulk! She-Hulk!
My name never has been, and never will be She-Hulk.
It's lazy, it's reductive, and it's straight-up garbage.
Any response, Ms. Book?
Actually, yes. We have one more clip to show.
Tell us, how did you come up with the name She-Hulk?
Some random guy on the news came up with it.
But it stuck, and so now, whether I like it or not,
I am forever She-Hulk.
My client clearly stated that she is She-Hulk.
This is just one instance.
Can you prove a pattern of Ms. Walter's personal use of the name?
Yes, Your Honor, we definitely have more to present.
You'd better.
Or I'm inclined to side with the defendant.
We'll recess until Thursday.
- Appointment for She-Hulk.
- We told him you're an Avenger. - What?
...all of the care instructions on the tag.
I will not be held responsible for customer stupidity.
This one.
Oh, my God!
Is the hag convention in town?
Luke, Nikki Ramos. This is the She-Hulk.
- Jennifer Walters. - Never heard of you.
My client list is very exclusive because my work is impeccable.
Well, like I told you before, she's gonna be one of the Avengers.
- You said she was one. - It hasn't been announced yet.
They're still working out the deal, but she is.
The Hulk is her cousin.
- By blood? - Yeah.
And she is going to be a megastar.
- Her? - Okay, is this really necessary?
I just want you to make me a new suit.
Okay, what kind of superhero-ing do you do?
Do you need built-in weaponry? Waterproofing, fire-resistance?
No, I don't need a suit like that. I just need a business suit.
Everything I make stands up to the highest combat standards.
I don't make basic shit.
Yeah, I don't really need any of that. I'm a lawyer.
She's a... You're a...
- A lawyer. - She's a lawyer.
That's so cute. I love that. That's so cute.
This one. Thank you.
This is a waste of my time and my talents. Please get out.
Okay, but she needs a suit
that's gonna fit her both as Jen and as She-Hulk.
Something that requires a lot of talent. Can we show him?
Yeah. All the way down, small, impish.
- Large, superhuman.
Do you think you could design a suit that would adapt to both of my bodies?
Come on. Ever done a Hulk before?
- This is huge. This is huge. - Tinsley!
Order extra bolts of the stretch wool. We're going to need
a lot of fabric.
Why was he so mean? In fashion, it's cool to be mean.
She's so impeccable. Where does she shop?
Somewhere with valet parking.
Oh, no. Remember that date I went on with the guy with the fetish?
- I know her. - She's a client. Of course, you do.
He's so creepy and disgusting. Monstrous.
- Hi! Todd, right? - She-Hulk!
Didn't know you worked here.
Yeah! Are you a client, or...
I am. I'm one of the biggest.
Just had a meeting with my favorite lady lawyer.
No touching.
We should, um...
Yeah, we should reconnect soon.
- Absolutely. That would be great. - Yeah. Drinks on me.
Okay.
- You rolled over so quickly. - So quickly.
- But the drinks are on him. - So quickly.
See you outside in ten.
Yeah, and you looked at that guy's dating profile and you were like,
"I'll give him a couple of precious hours of my life."
And I sat across... No, She-Hulk.
She-Hulk sat across from him for an entire dinner.
Yeah, and he for sure is telling all his friends like,
"Yo, bro. Went on a date with She-Hulk."
- Oh, my God. - What?
He went on a date with She-Hulk.
Yeah.
Because I made a dating profile as She-Hulk,
and went on several dates as She-Hulk, showing a clear pattern of using the name.
Every single one of those dates is a corroborating witness. This...
Is how I win this case.
By parading all the questionable men you dated in a courtroom.
- Jen, that's going to be embarrassing. - Yeah.
Ms. Book.
Your Honor, we have compelling evidence my client did in fact self-identify
with the moniker She-Hulk
well before Titania filed for the trademark.
Please proceed.
My client used "She-Hulk,"
not as a name to exploit in order to sell product,
but as a genuine part of her identity.
As you can see in the "About Me" section, my client wrote, and I quote,
"Mean, green and straight-poured into these jeans."
And to answer the question, "What are you looking for in a partner?"
my client wrote,
"A sturdy back and reinforced king-size bed.
"JK. JK. JK."
We'd like to call our witnesses.
'Sup?
Yeah, she's like, "It's me. The real She-Hulk. Impressed much?"
She came across a little tryhard, to be honest.
I'm just not about that.
I specifically remember her referring to herself as She-Hulk,
in the third person, and as a writer myself,
I found that grating.
Yeah, no, she confided in me
that she was initially embarrassed by the name She-Hulk.
But then she embraced it.
That's the beautiful part.
I guess I'm the kind of guy a woman can really open up to.
So you would say you really connected with She-Hulk?
She-Hulk and I had an intense connection.
We had a great date.
She battled demons, I mean, come on.
Would you have gone on the date
if She-Hulk had instead presented as Jennifer Walters?
Look, I don't mean to be rude, but...
No.
She's not really my type.
But She-Hulk. She-Hulk's incredible. She's amazing.
In light of this new testimony, the court finds in favor of...
Jennifer Walters, aka She-Hulk.
Motion for summary judgement is granted.
Titania and her subsidiaries will cease usage
of the She-Hulk name effective immediately.
All current products on the market must be recalled.
This isn't over, hater.
- Hey, Titania. - What?
I'm so sorry that happened to you.
- What you getting into later? - Fine. You can buy me things. Let's go.
Hey.
I love you so much, Titania.
MAN 2: Titania!
Thank you for that.
I mean, I might need to schedule several sessions of therapy,
but we won.
Look, Walters,
what that extremely attractive man said in there,
you can do better. You deserve better.
- Can I buy you a drink to say thanks? - Sure.
Here you go. I'm so happy we're doing this.
Cheers.
Quite a strategy.
I don't know any other lawyer
who would humiliate themselves that way to win a case.
Yeah, you can always count on me to throw myself under the bus.
It's why Holliway pays me the medium bucks.
He couldn't have gone through that.
He's never had to prove his value to a parade of underwhelming men.
Right?
Like, think about everything that She-Hulk brings to the table,
and those guys were my best option.
You can have literal superpowers,
and some guy with Internet will still think he can do better.
Yes! Oh, my God! The things we put up with.
I am so happy we're friends now.
What... Did I just say that out loud?
- Thanks for the drink. - Of course.
I thought you were getting better clothes.
Oh, yeah, my clothes!
Hey, Luke.
Just here to get my suits.
Here. Try this.
Thank you.
Ooh! I like it!
Of course you do, because I'm a genius.
I made you a little something extra.
- I don't know that I'll really have an... - Just say thank you, Jennifer.
Thank you.
Hello, this shouldn't be left out in the open.
Tinsley, does client confidentiality mean nothing to you?