(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC CONCLUDES)
(THUNDER CRASHES)
(ROARS)
(HIGH-PITCHED WHIRRING)
(SOFT TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(JENNA GROANING,
BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GROANING GROWS LOUDER)
(DOG SNIFFING)
(JENNA GROANING)
No, I can't.
I can't get them off.
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
No. No, they're everywhere.
(CRYING)
I can't.
No! Don't call the police.
I can't call anyone.
Come and get me.
No, I'm not.
I feel like you're not
listening to me.
(GROANING)
(PANTING)
(WHIMPERING)
(DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
Hello?
(BARKING CONTINUES)
Anybody there?
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(DOG CONTINUES BARKING)
JENNA: I called 911.
They're on their way.
(DOG GROWLING)
(BARKING)
(DOG WHIMPERING)
(LOCK CLICKS)
(GRUNTING)
(SNIFFING)
Breaking news at this hour.
Actress and activist
Jenna Janero
is officially considered
a missing person.
Neighbors heard
sounds of distress...
NARRATOR: Your kids want
something sweet for breakfast,
but you want to make sure
they stay healthy?
Meet Gardner's Diet Bananas.
That same delicious taste,
only half the calories.
...now the CEO of the largest
health and wellness
brand in America,
Zoe Shannon will be sitting down
with Sally Jones
to talk about Shell,
the company that promises
to keep you looking
younger forever.
But coming up after the break,
self-driving cars
are getting more Americans
to where they want to go,
but can they also
lead to cancer?
That story and...
AUTOMATED VOICE: We have arrived
at your destination.
Have a safe day.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(DEVICE BEEPING)
BRETT: (OVER PHONE)
So, how did it go?
SAMANTHA:
Oh, I'm just going in now.
BRETT: Okay.
Clearly, studio movie,
but they're really open
to a discovery here.
AUDREY: (OVER PHONE)
Director is excited to meet.
SAMANTHA: Well,
I really feel like
I connect with
the character and...
AUDREY: Love that.
BRETT: We believe in you, Sammy.
SAMANTHA: Okay, well,
I'm getting in the elevator,
so I might lose you.
BRETT: Break a leg, kiddo.
SAMANTHA: Bye. Bye.
(ELEVATOR BELL CHIMES)
(MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
Holy shit. Samantha Lake?
Samantha. (CHUCKLES) Hi.
Hi. Wow.
Oh, wait, um, it's...
It's Chloe.
Chloe, yes.
Yes.
Chloe Benson?
Right.
Redmount Road?
Oh, my God, yes.
You used to babysit me.
(LAUGHS)
Wow, oh... Yeah.
Jesus, you got really, uh...
I mean, you're big
or grown-up.
Well, it's been,
like, ten years.
Has it really been that long?
CHLOE:
What are you doing here?
Wait, are you reading
for this, too?
That's crazy.
I'm not reading.
I'm meeting with the director.
CHLOE: Oh, cool.
Mm-hmm.
CHLOE: What part
are you meeting for?
I didn't know you wanted
to be an actress.
Oh, I don't, really,
but my management
wants me to diversify
my social audience,
so it's basically more
exploratory at this point.
Wonderful.
Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
(DOOR OPENS)
Okay.
CASTING DIRECTOR: Samantha Lake?
That's you.
That's me.
Break a leg.
You, too.
(CHUCKLES)
Can't wait to tell my folks
that we ran into each other.
They're gonna die.
Hey, guys. (CHUCKLES)
Samantha. Yay, we love you.
Aw, thank you. I love you, too.
Well, we are up against it,
so are you cool
to just dive right in?
Oh, yeah, uh... Wow, okay.
(LAUGHS) Whoa. Sure.
Uh, is the director, um...
Oh, ultimately, he wasn't able
to make it work
with his schedule,
but he will be watching
everybody's tapes.
SAMANTHA: Oh, okay.
Yeah, I'm sorry. I just...
I'm so... I thought
this was just a meeting, so...
My... That's what my agent said.
I wasn't, um, ready to read.
Everybody's reading.
Everybody's reading. Right.
PRODUCER: Sam.
Long time.
SAMANTHA: Yeah, it's good
to see you again.
Did you, uh, take a break?
'Cause I feel like
I... I haven't seen you
in a minute.
Yeah, no. No, no break.
CASTING DIRECTOR: Okay,
should we get started?
Yeah. (EXHALES)
(WHISPERS) Take this off,
just to get comfortable.
Just... Okay.
Um...
(STAMMERS) In my own time?
CASTING DIRECTOR:
Whenever you're ready.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
SAMANTHA:
I wanted to be noticed.
I'd wanted it for so long.
I was really willing
to do anything.
And to be anyone, just...
just have another person
look at me.
Really look at me and think
that I was funny or...
I was clever or...
(CAT PURRING)
(MUTTERING)
...pretty. (LAUGHS SOFTLY)
I guess I just wanted you
to look at me
and see someone else.
And I thought
that I would be noticed.
(CAT MEOWS)
SAMANTHA: I thought
that I would be seen.
That people would look
at me and I'd think,
"They know.
They know what's in there.
They can see me."
Sounds really foolish,
doesn't it? (CHUCKLES)
I guess I am foolish.
Otherwise...
I wouldn't be here,
sitting in front of you...
asking you to give me
another chance, Your Honor.
Yeah.
Sorry. I didn't cry.
I think I should've
cried, maybe?
(SOBBING)
(SNIFFLING)
SAMANTHA: (OVER RECORDING)
Sorry. I didn't cry.
I think
I should've cried, maybe?
CASTING DIRECTOR:
Such a great instinct.
We got it, though.
SAMANTHA: Maybe just...
Should I...
Do you want one more?
I'm happy to just do one more,
if you want.
CASTING DIRECTOR:
You know what? I...
(SIGHS)
I thought it was great.
SAMANTHA: Great. Awesome.
PRODUCER: Perfect. Thank you.
SAMANTHA: Okay.
Thanks so much.
Good to see you.
CASTING DIRECTOR:
Thank you, Sam. Great stuff.
(CHUCKLES)
PRODUCER: Good actor,
but you'd never get
the studio to sign off.
She's what, 40-something?
CASTING DIRECTOR: I know.
I was just thinking
the same thing.
PRODUCER: Do you want
to grab some lunch?
I'm gonna have Benji
go get something for us.
CASTING DIRECTOR:
I want you to take a look
at this next girl, Chloe Benson.
She's a tad young for the role,
but stunning.
She just tested for, uh...
SAMANTHA: Hey, guys,
I'm so sorry, just,
I forgot my... my phone.
Okay. Really great to see you.
Thank you.
CASTING DIRECTOR:
Good to see you...
(RECORDING STOPS)
(CHUCKLES, SNIFFLES)
BRETT: You.
You are so fucking good.
You know that?
"Singular Samantha."
BRETT: They're going another way
on the movie, but...
Who got it?
BRETT: Uh... (STAMMERS)
I don't think they made
that call yet.
AUDREY: They're looking
at someone who is, um...
Less experienced.
(LAUGHING) Oh. So, younger?
Fresh face.
Right, well, the character
is a divorced
single mother of two,
so I don't know how young
they can go, but...
Um, well, look,
I'm glad we're here because
I wanted to talk to you guys.
I may not even be...
This is a very
competitive landscape,
and I've always tried
to be honest with you.
You've never really gone
for the nips or tucks,
and I get that.
I respect it.
Thank you.
And I can say this to you,
woman-to-woman.
With all the
developments lately,
we're seeing new demands
on talent to meet...
enhanced standards.
To meet an expectation.
Wow. Okay.
AUDREY: Nobody's asking you
to lose weight.
BRETT: Mm. Mm-mm.
I love that you have a...
I love that you don't have
a traditional body type.
We need more women like you.
Thank you.
BRETT: I love it, too.
Just for the record.
We want you to consider
some treatment options.
BRETT: Oh, yeah. Yeah.
What about the Shell clinic?
Oh, yes.
BRETT: Yes.
Sorry, what about it?
BRETT: Yeah, we represent
them now for branding.
We can have the office
set something up.
Oh, I...
Thank you, but I don't know
if I'm... I'm there yet.
Maybe down the line...
Everybody does something.
There's no shame in it.
Right.
Give it a shot.
And if it doesn't work,
well, it doesn't work.
SAMANTHA: Okay, uh, yeah,
I mean, I'll think about it.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
SAMANTHA: (PANTING)
What do you know about Shell?
I know it works.
Do you remember Jen Bryer
from seventh grade?
Yeah.
I saw her at Gelson's last week.
Looked like she was still
in seventh grade.
Isn't it kind of like,
I don't know, un-feminist?
Zoe Shannon's, like,
the richest woman in America.
And she looks fucking hot.
That's feminist as fuck.
I thought you hated her.
I mean, everyone has
to say they hate her,
but, like, obviously obsessed.
SAMANTHA: (EXHALES) Yeah.
Do you want to get
a drink after this?
I can't.
I have that date tonight.
LYDIA: With who? Tattoo guy?
Yeah.
LYDIA: Hot.
Oh, yeah.
DEVIN: So, with the IPO...
That's "initial
public offering."
SAMANTHA: Mm-hmm.
DEVIN: That's what that means.
Uh, we're probably gonna be
moving forward.
And most importantly,
I'm gonna pay back my dad.
SERVER: I'll take this for you.
Thank you.
(CHUCKLES)
That's amazing.
Yeah, you...
A little something in...
What? What is it? Oh.
DEVIN: Yeah.
Oh, really? Oh.
Oh, is it... oh, God.
(CHUCKLES) Don't look.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Is it gone?
DEVIN: Yeah.
Thanks.
Yeah, no, you got it.
Hey, so you look
so familiar to me.
What is it that you...
you do again for a living?
Oh, I'm an actress.
DEVIN: No way.
Yeah.
Mostly television.
I knew... I knew
that I recognized you.
SAMANTHA: Really?
Yes. Absolutely.
What... what have I seen you in?
Oh, probably nothing.
DEVIN: Well?
Uh, I was on a show that was
quite popular for a while.
It was called
Hannah Got a Heart.
Oh, yeah, no, I know that show.
Uh, the girl
with the talking heart.
SAMANTHA: Yes.
Yeah.
SAMANTHA: The previous
heart's owner talked to her.
(LAUGHS SOFTLY) Hilarious.
(SAMANTHA CHUCKLES)
What was that like?
SAMANTHA: Oh...
Uh, it was the first pilot
I ever did
that got picked up,
so that was good. (CHUCKLES)
Then I got to work
with all these
really experienced
people, and...
But, I mean, it was a bad show.
(LAUGHS)
DEVIN: (CHUCKLES) Right?
Oh, um, well, no, it's...
cheesy, yeah, for sure.
But I got to do
what I loved, so...
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, but it was a bad show.
Why would you want to be
on a bad show?
Yeah.
I liked it.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
I had a really
good time tonight.
Really?
Yeah.
Oh.
Well, I had a nice time, too.
(LAUGHS SOFTLY)
Good.
(LAUGHS)
(GRUNTS)
Oh, sorry.
Did you, um, feel that?
It's just, um...
I have psoriasis.
It's kind of embarrassing.
It's not contagious or anything.
Oh.
(LAUGHS) Yeah.
Sometimes when it rains,
it flares up a little.
Oh, that's... that's cool.
SAMANTHA: Yeah.
Is it?
Yeah, no, I just, um...
It's not, like, all over
my body or anything.
DEVIN: For sure.
It's, like, in certain spots.
Yeah. (CLEARS THROAT)
Yeah, no, actually,
I just, um...
I have to be up pretty early
tomorrow, so...
Oh, you... you do?
Yeah.
Yeah. Um...
Okay.
So...
All right. That's fine.
Yeah. Yeah.
Maybe some...
other time?
(EXHALES SHARPLY) Yeah.
Okay.
Totally. Would love that.
'Cause you have to get up early.
Yeah. Super early.
Okay.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
SALLY: First things first.
You say you've had
the treatment yourself.
Yeah. Yes, I have.
SALLY: So, I have to ask,
how old are you, really?
ZOE: I knew you were gonna
ask me that question.
I just turned 68 in May.
SALLY: You look amazing.
ZOE: Thank you.
SALLY: But you'll admit,
there's an awful lot of secrecy
about your business.
All I want for our clients
is to free them
of self-doubt and inhibition.
To make them feel good,
feel better,
inside and out.
I mean, you can't fight
the future.
And the future is here.
(THUNDER CRASHES)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(EXHALES)
KEN DOLL: Welcome to Shell.
We hope you enjoy
your visitation.
Thank you.
(UPBEAT MUSIC CONTINUES)
(MUSIC CONCLUDES)
Hi. I'm Samantha Lake.
I'm here to check in
for my appointment.
Wonderful. So, I'll just
need your signature
on a few things, okay?
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
(SIGHS)
RECEPTIONIST: This is our
non-disclosure agreement...
to protect our more
high-profile clients.
Right. Mm-hmm.
RECEPTIONIST:
Your doctor will be able
to answer any questions
in your consultation.
We'll just need that signature,
and you can make your way over
to the changing station.
(COMPUTER CHIMES)
Thank you.
RECEPTIONIST: Um, ma'am?
That way. (LAUGHS)
(SOFT UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
Hello. I'm Dr. Thaddeus Brand,
and I'm here to tell you
about Shell...
fish. (CHUCKLES)
There are organisms existing
in this world today
that do not experience
the process known as senescence.
Put more simply,
these creatures...
the jellyfish, the common hydra,
flatworms, sponges, axolotls,
the lobster...
these creatures do not age,
thanks to the telomerase enzyme,
which protects the ends
of their chromosomes.
Several years ago,
I discovered a unique linkage
between crustacean enzymes
and the exoskeletal
growth process.
By introducing
a genetically altered version
into human cells,
we were able to arrest
the outward signs of aging...
Ms. Lake,
if you'd like to follow me,
I can escort you
to the changing station.
Okay.
...at Shell,
immortality begins today.
(QUIET CHATTER NEARBY)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
DR. HUBERT:
Hold on one second.
Ms. Lake?
Hi. I'm Dr. Hubert.
We're a little early,
but I can change the...
No, actually, I was just
looking for the, um...
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
You know what? I'm sorry,
Doctor, this just...
This isn't for me, so...
I see.
Is it all right if I ask why?
It's just a little...
Ah, spooky?
Yeah.
DR. HUBERT: (CHUCKLES)
Yeah, I get that.
Look...
why don't we have
a conversation,
and if you're still
having any doubts afterwards,
I will walk you out myself.
We also have amazing ice cream.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
I was treating this burn victim.
This is an image of the damage
right before her
B-One procedure.
That is two weeks after,
and after her first
skin shedding,
no markings anywhere.
In a few months,
it was all gone.
That's impressive.
The treatment doesn't just
halt the aging process.
It facilitates cellular repair,
making it more durable
for the skin to actually heal
and... and be faster at it.
The psoriasis, how long have
you been dealing with that?
A while.
I mean, it's like, you know,
it comes and goes.
Well, I see no reason
why we can't
eliminate flare-ups altogether.
(PEN SCRIBBLING)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Is it dangerous?
The procedure? 'Cause,
you know, I've heard stories.
We had one patient
whose head exploded,
but that was
a technical malfunction.
Highly unlikely
that's gonna happen again.
That was a joke, by the way.
(CHUCKLES)
No, I know.
(DR. HUBERT CHUCKLES)
I mean, it is a surgery.
There's bound to be some risks,
but it is completely painless
and it's far less invasive
than Botox or LASIK.
I had LASIK.
DR. HUBERT: Yeah, I see that.
You know...
new patients come in here
all the time,
and they want, like,
bigger muscles
or higher cheekbones,
and I can't help those people.
But if you're interested
in moving forward,
your psoriasis will fade away,
you will be healthier
and you'll feel better.
If you're consistent
with the treatment,
in 20 years,
you will not look one day older
than you do right now.
So, what flavors do you have?
Flavors?
Ice cream.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(DR. HUBERT CHUCKLES)
WOMAN: (OVER SPEAKER)
This will allow you time
to relax
as the serum is delivered
intravenously
and begins to work its magic.
Following your I.V. treatment,
you will be taken
to the rebirth chamber
for the next stage
of your Shell experience.
Once the procedure begins,
our exclusive
laser technology...
Sam?
Jesus.
CHLOE: (CHUCKLES) No way.
(SAMANTHA CHUCKLES)
(CHLOE GASPS)
Can you believe this?
No, I can't.
Isn't it wild
when you just, like,
keep running into someone?
Yeah. Yeah, it's unsettling.
Totally. (CHUCKLES)
I heard you got that movie.
That's...
I mean, wow. Congrats.
CHLOE: Oh, the movie.
It sucks, I can't do it.
SAMANTHA: You can't?
(SIGHS)
I'm not supposed to
tell anyone yet,
but I think I'm gonna be
the new Catwoman.
What?
CHLOE: Isn't that crazy?
Jesus. Yeah.
Such a bummer.
It was a really cool script.
Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
Mm-hmm.
Aren't you a... aren't you
a little young for this?
Young for what?
For the treatment.
I mean, you're what, 22?
Mm-hmm.
(SAMANTHA LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLES) Oh, sorry.
Sorry.
I'm just... I think I'm nervous.
You probably won't
remember this,
but when I was a kid,
you took me to this
swimming class
and we were all supposed to
jump off this diving board,
I was totally freaking out.
And you said this thing
to calm me down.
It was so simple, you said,
"Maybe you're not as scared
as you think."
And you were right.
I jumped and I was fine.
I still say it to myself
sometimes when I get nervous,
which is a lot. (LAUGHS, SNORTS)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
CHLOE: I don't know.
Maybe you're not as scared
as you think.
Maybe you got this.
(SIGHS)
(CHLOE CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(DOOR WHOOSHES CLOSED)
(WHIRRING)
DR. HUBERT: Nurse,
how we looking?
Levels are good.
DR. HUBERT: We're gonna get
started, okay?
Okay, Doctor.
See you on the other side.
I think we should begin.
(LATCH LOCKS)
(WHIRRING)
(MACHINE HUMMING)
(WHIRRING CONTINUES)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: System on.
(LOUD WHIRRING)
Initializing body scan.
(WHIRRING RHYTHMICALLY)
(CRACKLING, SIZZLING)
It's all over. You were great.
Did it go okay?
Without a hitch.
(SIGHS) I had some weird dreams
during the procedure.
Yeah, it's completely normal.
It's just the anesthesia.
And that is not permanent.
It's just to cover up the scars
until it heals.
And you see the psoriasis
is all cleared up.
Just be careful
on your way down.
Nurse, can you sign out
Ms. Lake for me?
Someone at reception will
schedule a follow-up,
all right?
Is that it?
You are good to go.
Thank you, Doctor.
How do you feel?
I feel good.
(ENTRY BELL CHIMES)
(ANIMALS CHITTERING NEARBY)
(DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
SAMANTHA: Hi. I'm Samantha Lake.
Hi.
SAMANTHA:
And I'm here to pick up my cat.
Okay. What's the cat's name?
SAMANTHA: Salem.
Like Sabrina.
Hmm?
TYLER: Sabrina
the Teenage Witch.
She had a cat named Salem, too.
Yeah.
No one has ever gotten
that reference.
I get the reference.
Yeah.
Yes, you do.
(CHEERY MUSIC PLAYING)
(SALEM WHIMPERING)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
LYDIA: Shut the fuck up.
You think you'll actually
get to meet her?
Well, it's at her house.
Yeah, but there's probably
gonna be, like,
a lot of people there.
You need to text me
the whole time.
Okay, I'm done.
You go ahead. I'm staying on.
Freak.
(BEEPING)
(EXERCISE BIKE WHIRRING FASTER)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
("YOUNG AT HEART" PLAYING)
(LIVELY CHATTER NEARBY)
♪ Fairy tales can come true ♪
♪ It can happen to you ♪
♪ If you're young at heart ♪
(LIVELY CHATTER, LAUGHTER)
♪ For it's hard, you will find ♪
♪ To be narrow of mind ♪
♪ If you're young at heart ♪
♪ You can go to extremes ♪
♪ With impossible schemes... ♪
My babies. Happy holidays!
Oh, gosh, you look gorgeous.
(WHISPERS) Did you end up
getting divorced?
I know. I know, I'm so happy.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Come on.
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
I've seen you. I've seen you.
(ALL LAUGHING)
How are you? Happy holidays.
Hi!
How is your, um...
♪ Don't you know
That it's worth... ♪
ZOE: So, how's your family?
MAN: Oh, they're doing...
WOMAN: They're great.
ZOE: They're great. Wonderful.
♪ To be young at heart ♪
Um...
Excuse me one second.
You go get a drink. You, too.
(LAUGHTER)
♪ For as rich as you are ♪
♪ It's much better by far... ♪
Samantha Lake. My God.
I heard you came
into the clinic.
I told the guys
I wanted to meet you.
When my mother was sick,
we watched every episode
of your show.
(CHUCKLING) Oh, wow. Um...
I'm so embarrassed.
No, don't be.
I mean, sure,
it's a little cheesy.
We fucking loved it.
Plus, it kept us from cutting
each other's heads off.
And you look...
exactly the same.
Oh, well, thanks to you.
Stop it.
(CHUCKLES)
Who did you have? Tennyson?
Uh, Dr. Hubert.
The best.
Plus, he's, like, hot, right?
(LAUGHS) Um, yes.
ZOE: Walk with me
while I check on the kitchen.
Okay.
How tall are you?
SAMANTHA: Five-three...
ZOE: Oh.
...and a half.
I'm five-eight.
Just reached it this year.
Grew, inch and a quarter.
You got taller?
Yeah, every skin cycle.
I mean, you wouldn't think that
that little extra would matter,
but, ooh, let me tell you.
Nobody said
it would make me taller.
(ZOE SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CATERER SPEAKING SPANISH)
ZOE: Mm, mm, mm! Oh!
So fucking good.
(BOTH SPEAK SPANISH)
(MUTTERS) Um, you don't cook?
Do you cook?
No. I mean, not like you.
I have watched your entire
Chef Class series.
Aw, you're so sweet.
Well, I love learning.
Just last week, I was
at this Greek fishing village
learning how to make
a traditional stifado,
but we did it with fish.
Oh!
Anyway, next time you're here,
I'll make it for you.
Wow. Well, I don't know
what that is,
but I feel like
I'm going to love it.
("DECK THE HALLS"
INSTRUMENTAL PLAYING)
(QUIET, LIVELY CHATTER)
ZOE: How do you not know her?
MAN: I've never seen her.
ZOE: She was on the Heart show.
MAN: Oh.
Mmm.
ZOE: It's like
a guilty pleasure.
Don't you think there's a...
Samantha.
Honey, look over here.
(SCOFFS) Don't we look related?
(CHUCKLES) Oh.
Ki... Kind of.
ZOE: Like we could be cousins.
Maybe.
ZOE: Second cousins.
Yes.
Absolutely.
See?
I knew it.
SEBASTIAN: Mm-hmm.
Yeah, I see it.
Let's all thank our lovely host
for this gorgeous meal
with these gorgeous faces.
We love you, Zo.
Thank you. Bon appétit.
GUESTS: Bon appétit. Cheers.
(SIGHS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Hmm.
This is delicious.
What is it?
Mm. It's me.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, really.
Normally, we throw out
the old skin,
but it's very protein-rich,
almost no fat.
Well, almost.
(GUESTS LAUGHING)
Wow.
MAN: I think this is the best
you've ever tasted.
Mm, you would know.
(GUESTS CHUCKLING)
I've had a lot of her.
Mm-hmm.
You like it?
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(MUNCHES)
Mmm.
(GUESTS CHUCKLING)
ZOE: Beautiful.
Touch of gray,
the wrinkles around the eyes.
Mm.
It suggests a depth and sadness,
don't you think?
Yeah, totally.
Yeah, but for a woman,
I mean, you chose
the perfect moment.
You're glowing head to toe.
Thank you.
We...
Okay, we're going swimming.
Okay.
Join us.
(SIGHS)
(MUFFLED MUSIC PLAYING
IN DISTANCE)
(MUFFLED MUSIC CONTINUES)
(ZOE MOANING)
(MOANING GETS LOUDER)
(ZOE BREATHING HEAVILY)
(FAINT BUZZING SOUND)
(VIBRATOR BUZZING)
Creep.
(SIGHS)
I'm so sorry. I was just...
I was looking for the bathroom.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
It's fine.
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
All these people...
Sometimes I just need
to center myself.
Um, I think I might head...
head out soon, so...
Oh, you're not gonna bitch out
already, are you?
I have to f...
I have to feed my cat.
(SCOFFS)
I remember the first month
of treatment
was the most fun I ever had.
You don't feel that way?
(SAMANTHA BREATHING SHAKILY)
I do feel it.
But, um...
When I first told my mom
I was moving to L.A.,
she said,
"No matter how much
you doll yourself up,
they'll still notice
that you don't belong there."
Mm. She sounds like
a real bitch.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
I think she's probably right,
'cause I'm always the girl
with the run in my tights
or the food in my teeth.
(CHUCKLES)
I don't see any food
in your teeth.
You are the personification
of pulchritude.
Good word, huh?
It means "beauty."
I love it
'cause it sounds disgusting.
You need to get out
of your head, Sam.
When you understand
how others perceive you,
it's much easier
to get what you want.
I want you to do something
for me.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
I want you to look
in this mirror...
and do not leave this room
until you make yourself come.
Zoe, that's...
ZOE: Yes.
You got it.
I want you to see how I see you,
how the world will see you
going forward.
Confident.
(CHUCKLES)
Strong.
Sexy.
I'll know if you didn't do it.
(UPBEAT MUSIC CONTINUES)
(VIBRATOR BUZZING)
(LIVELY CHATTER)
(WATER SPLASHING)
(LIVELY CHATTER, LAUGHTER)
At that rate, it's just so late.
SAMANTHA: One moment,
everything was perfect,
and then... we met.
And it all just fell apart.
I just wanted for so long
to be noticed.
I wanted them to look
at me and think...
that I was smart or...
funny or...
(CHUCKLES)
...pretty.
I guess I just wanted you
to look at me
and see someone else.
FIRST A.D.: And that's a cut!
We've got it.
(LAUGHS)
(GROANS)
(BELL RINGING)
(BUSY CHATTER)
Thank you.
FIRST A.D.: Good job, Sam.
(LAUGHS)
FIRST A.D.: All right,
moving on. Scene 11's next.
("WALKING ON SUNSHINE" PLAYING)
♪ Mm, yeah ♪
♪ I used to think
Maybe you loved me ♪
♪ Now, baby, I'm sure ♪
(CAMERA SNAPPING RAPIDLY)
♪ And I just can't wait
Till the day ♪
♪ When you knock on my door ♪
♪ Now every time
I go for the mailbox ♪
♪ Gotta hold myself down ♪
(LAUGHING)
♪ 'Cause I just can't wait
Till you write me ♪
♪ You're coming around ♪
♪ I'm walking on sunshine
Whoa-oh ♪
♪ I'm walking on sunshine ♪
♪ Whoa-oh ♪
♪ And don't it feel good? ♪
♪ Hey, all right, now ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ And don't it feel good... ♪
ZOE:
I was looking for you.
Come inside. The kids
are gonna play us something.
Okay.
Mm.
They're so good.
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
I MEAN, I'M... (INHALES)
...speechless.
I know.
Well, Rafi is the dark horse.
He wanted a harp.
And we were like,
"What about a cello?"
And... But he wanted that harp,
so I got him a fucking harp,
and he actually plays it.
SAMANTHA:
How are your kids so young?
ZOE: It's the B.I.
Keeps your uterus
fresh as a daisy.
Ronny didn't want children,
but I knew I would wear him down
one day.
(SAMANTHA CHUCKLES)
Luckily, we waited.
It's a real time suck.
Mm-hmm. Where is Ronny?
I don't think I've met him yet.
ZOE: Oh, no, we don't
live together. No.
We're...
non-domestic co-parents.
People think it's weird,
works for us.
We still sleep together.
Hey, Doc?
Mm-hmm?
What's taking so long?
Patience.
All good things come
to those who wait.
(GROANS)
But I'm starving. Hurry up.
What about Hubert?
Oh. I'm...
I don't know.
Yes. He is age-appropriate.
He's attractive. He's smart.
He's rich.
Exactly.
I think he can do
way better than me.
Oh, he'd be lucky to have you.
What? You're in this cool
new movie, you're...
funny, and you're...
Well, okay,
you're not that funny...
(LAUGHS)
...but you're hot.
Thanks.
You're way too nice to me.
(CHUCKLES)
No.
We're friends.
Friends tell each other
the truth.
Can I tell you a secret?
Oh, yeah.
So, Shannon isn't
my real last name.
It's not?
Mm-mm.
No. My real last name?
Zilt.
It's Zilt?
ZOE: My last name is Zilt.
(GIGGLES)
ZOE: It's awful.
(GAGS) It's, like,
Norwegian for "venison."
Like the meat?
ZOE: Like the meat.
(LAUGHS)
Changed it my senior year,
never looked back.
Well, my name's not
my real name, either.
ZOE: You see?
We're both pretending
to be someone we're not.
(LAUGHS)
I like you.
Thank you.
We should be friends.
Best of friends.
LYDIA: Please.
You two are inseparable.
I've been replaced.
(GROANS)
You literally have no good
snacks anymore.
It's all Shell food.
It's healthy food.
LYDIA: Exactly.
You're turning into Zoe.
Soon you'll be
60 percent flaxseed.
Look, if you don't want to do
this assistant thing,
it's totally fine.
You volunteered, but if
you're not comfortable...
LYDIA: No, no, no, no.
Wait. No. I do.
Okay, well, maybe start
with the unpacking, then.
Okay. Geez Louise.
(GASPS)
Aw...
Look at this.
This is not unpacking.
This is looking at things.
No, no. Look.
I look terrifying.
Yeah.
Well, we both do.
LYDIA:
Mm. Skinny, though.
Well, we were 12, so...
(CHUCKLES)
...everyone's skinny.
What's that?
What's what?
On your neck.
What do you mean?
What...?
That?
Yeah.
Do you feel that?
Well... Yeah, what is it?
Is that a mole?
I don't have a mole there.
So, is it a bite?
I don't know.
LYDIA: Can you feel that?
Yeah, don't touch it.
I don't know.
Get that checked out.
Okay.
Okay, can you please continue?
You were on a roll there.
Yes. Yes.
Of course.
You had one thing out.
LYDIA: Uh-huh.
Where do you want all these
precious photo albums to go?
Um... try the living room.
Thank you.
LYDIA: Got it.
DR. HUBERT: All right.
I'm gonna count to three, okay?
SAMANTHA: 'Kay.
DR. HUBERT: You know what?
This is a sticky guy.
Three. Two.
Got it.
Ow.
Now, I'll run a biopsy.
But I don't think this is
any cause for concern.
(SIGHS)
It's too early for
the molting thing, right?
DR. HUBERT: Correct.
Though the coloring
is a little unusual.
This is just excess skin.
It might spread a little more
before it dissipates,
but this is totally benign.
Okay.
(PEN SCRIBBLING)
DR. HUBERT:
I'm going to prescribe you
a topical cream,
to be on the safe side.
Also, on the back
is my cell phone.
Just in case there's a moment
where you, you know...
In case I wake up
with six toes? (CHUCKLES)
Exactly.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(CAR LOCK CHIRPS)
(SOFT TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIGHS)
(ENGINE REVS)
(DOORBELL RINGING)
(INTERCOM BUZZES)
I'm Detective Flores.
This is Detective Abramson.
Nice place.
SAMANTHA: Thank you.
Uh, I'm still unpacking,
but, um...
Sorry, do you want a coffee
or tea, or can I get you...
We won't take up
too much of your time.
Okay.
You're a patient at
the Shell clinic, correct?
Yeah. I was just there.
Oh.
And you also had an appointment
on the 12th of December, right?
I'd have to check.
Sorry, am I in trouble
or something?
Well, I hope not.
Did you have a conversation
with another patient
when you were visiting that day?
Chloe Benson?
Um, I signed an NDA,
so I don't think...
Is everything all right?
FLORES: Ms. Benson's missing.
Missing?
FLORES: Yeah.
That day at the clinic,
that was the last time
anyone saw her.
SAMANTHA: Wow.
We checked with all her people,
and no one's heard from her.
Including you, I'm guessing?
SAMANTHA: Yeah.
We spoke to her family.
They mentioned that you two
had reconnected, so...
we were just wondering
if she'd reached out.
Um...
No. We don't know
each other very well.
I was her babysitter.
A long time ago, obviously,
so, yeah.
No. Sorry.
FLORES: Hopefully,
she'll turn back up.
But if she happens to reach out,
do us a favor and call directly.
Okay.
My wife and I are big fans
of Hannah Got a Heart,
by the way.
Oh.
It's a nice show.
It's very funny.
Thank you.
Well, all right.
ZOE: Honestly,
maybe they're not real cops.
They're probably competitors.
I've heard stories--
scams, spies,
trying to scare people into
spilling info
about the procedure.
They've been trying to figure
out our formulation for years,
and they cannot get
the science right,
and I've heard
they've made people sick.
Like, deformed. It's...
abhorrent.
These people will do...
They'll do anything.
Gracias.
They seemed like
real cops to me.
Well, honey, you can be
overly trusting.
Yeah.
Maybe you could talk
to someone, you know,
find out if Chloe's okay.
It would just...
It would make me feel better.
Consider it done.
Mm. I have to get this.
You. Want to go away
next weekend?
St. Barths?
Mm.
ZOE: Hey, I'm on.
How's your cabana boy?
I thought you'd be arrested
by now.
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
Okay, just don't do anything...
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(INSECTS TRILLING)
(ALARM PANEL BEEPING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Disarmed.
This is an emergency.
You must connect me with the
city electrical generating...
(INSECTS TRILLING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES)
(FAUCET CREAKS)
(TV PLAYING QUIETLY)
(GLASS SHATTERS IN DISTANCE)
(SAMANTHA BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(GLASS FRAGMENTS CLINKING)
(GASPS, GROANS) Shit.
(SALEM YOWLS)
(GASPS)
(EXHALES) Oh, my God.
(MEOWS, PURRS)
What are you,
hitting the bottle again?
Huh? You a little drunkard?
(MEOWS)
Okay.
(SALEM PURRS, MEOWS)
(GROANS SOFTLY)
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
(RINGING CONTINUES)
Hello?
(STATIC ON LINE)
WOMAN: (OVER PHONE) Sam?
Yeah?
WOMAN: (OVER PHONE)
I didn't know who else to call.
Something's really wrong
with me.
Who is this?
They're always watching, Sam.
Chloe?
CHLOE: They're always watching.
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(RECEIVER CLATTERS)
(BELL RINGING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(RHYTHMIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Sam, what time was the call?
9:00, 9:30?
It was around 9:00.
Yes, on her home phone.
Copy. Yeah.
We can't get around that?
All right, got it.
Yeah, thank you for checking.
All right. Bye.
It was a blocked phone number.
So it was probably just
someone prank-calling you.
I don't know, I mean, why would
she have your home phone?
You're scratching a lot.
Can I get a coffee?
Sorry, I just didn't sleep
at all last night. Thank you.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Yep.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
CREW MEMBER:
Sam? Ten-minute warning.
Just a minute, please.
And they're waiting for you
in hair and makeup
whenever you're ready.
Sam?
Hey, sorry.
Your latte, madam.
SAMANTHA: Thank God.
Do you have any Advil?
LYDIA: Ooh. Um, I don't,
but I can go ask the medic
if they have any.
Yes, yes. That would be great.
Thank you.
Okay.
Oh, also,
your Vanity Fair interview's
happening like now.
(SIGHS) Okay.
He's been waiting for a minute,
so you might want
to go outside...
Can we please just
reschedule that?
Sam, it's Vanity Fair.
Hi. Hey. Um, we're almost ready.
Would you like me to have
wardrobe grab your shorts?
Um, is it a medium?
Uh, a medium and a tight. Yeah.
Okay. So, are we gonna see
the shorts on screen or what?
I don't think so, but I...
Well, it doesn't matter,
then, does it?
It's cool, Sam. You can wear
the sweats in this one.
Thank you.
Sammy, Sam, Sam. What's up?
Hey, hey.
FIRST A.D.:
All right, here we go.
Let's lock it up. Roll sound.
CREW MEMBER:
Seventeen, take one. Marker.
(SIGHS) Okay.
FIRST A.D.: And action.
So, are you gonna
arrest me or what?
I'm thinking about it.
FIRST A.D.: Now, that's a cut.
All right, we're gonna go again.
Hey, that was really good,
but we need a beat
before the kiss.
I took a beat, yeah?
Right, but a longer beat.
Okay, longer beat.
Just say "longer beat," yeah?
(SCOFFS) I took a beat.
(EXHALES)
Yeah. Um, do you mind,
in the kiss,
just a little less
breathing on me?
Because I'm not
feeling too great.
I'm... I'm kissing you.
I got to breathe.
Yeah, that's true. Okay.
Yeah. Yeah.
FIRST A.D.: All right,
we're gonna go again...
It's fine.
...Let's lock it up. Roll sound.
CREW MEMBER:
Seventeen, take two. Marker.
Okay.
(SIGHS)
FIRST A.D.: And action.
Um... (EXHALES)
So, uh... so, you gonna
arrest me or what?
I'm thinking about it.
(KISSES)
(GAGS, RETCHES)
(CREW EXCLAIMING)
What the fuck? What the fuck?
CREW MEMBER 1: Did you see that?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
CREW MEMBER 2: Was that blood?
LYDIA: Sam?
Sam, you okay?
Sam? Sam?
Hi, Samantha.
Simon from Vanity Fair.
Hi.
I was hoping we could
get an interview...
(SAMANTHA RETCHING, COUGHING)
(CREW EXCLAIMING)
What the fuck?
What is this?
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
I'll get you a towel
in just a...
SAMANTHA: I'm so sorry.
Please don't print that.
(QUIET CHATTER)
Sam.
No.
LYDIA: Sam. Sam. Sam.
You okay... Do you want me to
get you a medic or something?
No, leave me alone. I'm fine.
Sam.
I'm fine.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
(KNOCKING ON THE DOOR)
PRODUCER: Sam.
It's Bob.
We just wanna make sure
everything's okay.
SAMANTHA:
I just need some privacy.
Please don't come in.
Sure thing, kid.
Anything you need.
Anything at all.
(WHISTLING)
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
Where is she?
(DOOR OPENS)
ZOE: Sammy?
I'm here.
I got your message.
I'm so sorry.
No, no. I'm here, baby girl.
I didn't know what to do.
Zoe, I think something's
really wrong with me.
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
All right.
We'll take care of that.
Thank you.
Okay. We'll clean it up.
All right?
We'll clean it up.
(CREW APPLAUDING)
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
This is my driver, Cornelius.
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
ZOE: I called the clinic.
They're sending someone
right away.
Whatever this is, we'll fix it.
(SIGHS) Did you speak to Hubert?
No one told you.
Um, he was let go.
Let go? Why?
Some blowup with Brand.
Who the fuck knows?
(SIGHS)
I'm gonna make you some tea.
Thanks.
Rosa, can you bring us some tea?
ROSA: Yes, Miss Zoe.
What about Chloe?
Did you hear back about her?
ZOE: Hmm?
The girl who went missing.
Oh, Chloe. Yes. No.
I asked around, and apparently,
she moved to Paris.
Paris?
Some modeling job, I think.
Huh.
Maybe we should reach out
to her directly,
because if the same thing...
happened to her...
I'm not gonna call
some random girl in France
that I don't know
just to make you feel better.
Look,
you're freaked out
about your skin.
I get it.
I'm gonna go check on that tea.
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
(WATER RUNNING)
Where'd you go?
(CHUCKLES) Sorry,
I just had to use the bathroom.
Try this.
It'll make you feel better.
What?
Don't like it?
No, it's... still hot.
Who'd you call?
Hmm?
When I was in the other room,
I heard you call someone.
Sounds like you called
a couple people.
Unless you were just
talking to yourself.
Oh, maybe.
I'm sorry,
I am a little out of it.
But no, I didn't...
I didn't call anyone.
So, I think that
maybe I should go.
You mind if look at your phone?
What?
Well, I mean, if you
weren't talking to someone,
do you mind if I take a look?
If you're telling the truth,
you can call me a crazy cunt,
and we're done with it.
I want to go to a...
ZOE: (WHISPERS) Sam.
I want to go to a doctor.
Honey,
you need to stay here.
No, I'm...
I want to go to a hospital.
ZOE: Take a deep breath.
Take a deep breath.
Why... why are you doing this?
Doing what?
Trying to keep me here.
You sound paranoid.
I'm acting like someone
who cares about you,
which you probably
don't understand
because your mother raised you
to feel shitty about yourself.
Sorry. It's true.
You need someone you can trust
and who knows.
I don't know if I do...
trust you.
Wow. Okay.
That's fucking ungrateful.
I'm sorry, I just,
I know you feel like...
You don't know how I feel,
and you don't care or you
wouldn't be turning on me.
Turning on you?
Yeah.
This isn't about you.
This isn't about me?
What do you think would happen
if you walked out of here
with these disgusting things
on your body?
You think that would
help my stock price?
You think that would be good
for my fucking brand?
You know what they call a woman
trying to improve themselves?
A punch line.
Every botched Botox injection
is a cautionary tale.
"Oh, God, did you see
what they did to her face?
It's so sad."
And then, if you let
nature take its course,
you're dismissed
as "old" and "irrelevant."
"She aged gracefully."
Now, that's just
another way of saying,
"She is wrinkly and unfuckable."
But we have a solution now.
We can maintain
our sexual power,
and we can live
without judgment.
So I am asking you...
nicely...
do not fuck all this up.
(CUP CLINKS)
(SCREAMING)
ZOE: (YELLS) Rosa!
(ROSA IN SPANISH)
Oh, fuck!
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTING)
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
(TIRES SCREECH)
Get in! Get in!
Sam, come on! Get in! Get in!
(INDISTINCT, FRANTIC CHATTER)
What is happening? Sam.
Ow! Ow, fuck.
Are you okay? Okay.
Go, go, go.
(BOTH SCREAM)
Go, Lydia. Go!
LYDIA: Okay, okay.
What the fuck, Sam?
What is going on?
(GROANS) Fuck.
Why are there people
chasing you?
(GROANS) Okay. Oh, fuck.
What is that?
On your hand. What is that?
SAMANTHA: Oh, shit.
Sam, is that from the treatment?
I don't know.
You're gonna be okay.
Was that Zoe's house?
Yeah. Yeah.
That was a cool house.
Yeah, it's really cool.
Yeah, it was cool.
(GROANS) Fuck.
Are you sure you don't want me
to go in with you?
I'll be all right.
Just stay here.
LYDIA: Okay.
(GROANING)
(CAR HORNS HONKING IN DISTANCE)
(ENTRY BELL JINGLING)
I'm sorry. I didn't get lunch.
You want to order something?
FLORES:
What happened to your ankle?
Have you seen this before?
Mm.
I think this has something to do
with why Chloe disappeared.
And now it's happening to me,
and I'm...
I'm scared that
they're gonna do something
to try to keep me quiet.
I need your help...
Slow down. They?
Yes, Shell. Zoe Shannon.
"Zoe Shannon," Zoe Shannon?
ZOE: (OVER RECORDING)
What do you think would happen
if you walked out of here
with these disgusting things
on your body?
You think that would
help my stock price...
Mm-hmm.
...you think that would
be good for my fucking brand?
Stop the recording.
What?
You can't record people
without their knowledge.
California state law.
FLORES: Aren't you worried
about the NDA?
Fuck the NDA. I need a doctor,
and I need protection.
ABRAMSON:
Just think about this carefully.
Nondisclosure agreements
are a powerful document.
You know, in fact,
you've already put yourself
at significant legal risk.
FLORES:
You might want to reconsider.
You're in a tough spot.
Don't make things
harder for yourself.
You work for them.
Look, we can take you
someplace safe,
get you help right now.
All that stuff about Chloe?
FLORES:
It's true. She's missing,
and we want to find her
for her own protection.
ABRAMSON:
Just like we want to help you.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUMBLING ALONG TO RADIO)
♪ Everybody's doing ♪
♪ A brand-new dance now ♪
♪ Come on, baby
Do the Loco-Motion ♪
♪ I know you'll
Fucking like it ♪
♪ If you give it a chance now ♪
(OVER RADIO) ♪ Come on
Baby, do the Loco-Motion ♪
(GASPS)
♪ My little baby sister... ♪
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ It's easier than learning... ♪
(CHUCKLES) Hi. (CLEARS THROAT)
FLORES: Samantha,
you're sick. Okay?
I don't really think that
there's much of a choice here,
is there?
I mean, given the specificity
of your condition?
I think we should get you back
to full health,
and then you can explore
your theories.
Okay.
Okay. I'll pay.
You can ride with us.
I'm just gonna use the bathroom
before we go.
Mm-hmm.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
(BELL JINGLING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
SAMANTHA: Oh, fuck.
(WHIMPERING, PANTING)
Shit.
Mm. (YELLS) Flores!
WORKER: Hey.
Move!
What the fuck?
Get out of my way!
Taxi2Me.
ABRAMSON: Get the fuck
out of the way!
Taxi2Me!
WORKER: Hey, hey! Hey, hey!
FLORES: Stop! Move! Move it!
ABRAMSON: Don't know
where she went. You see her?
FLORES: Abramson! Over here!
Hurry up!
(DOOR OPENS)
(ELECTRIC CAR APPROACHES)
(TIRES SCREECH)
ABRAMSON: There she is!
FLORES: Oh, fuck. Goddamn it!
ABRAMSON: Come on.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Welcome to Taxi2Me.
You are in a 25-mile-per-hour
driving zone.
Please buckle up
for your safety.
Faster. Can you go...
Excuse me, could you
go faster, please?
AUTOMATED VOICE: You are in
a 25-mile-per-hour driving zone.
Go faster, you fucking fuck.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
It sounds like you want
to submit feedback
about my driving.
Is that correct?
Please remain seated
with your seatbelt fastened.
It appears you are trying
to use manual drive.
Yes.
AUTOMATED VOICE: No problem.
You can sign up
for free using the Taxi2Me app.
(SIGHS)
Are you fucking kidding me?
AUTOMATED VOICE: Please do not
damage the vehicle.
(TIRES SQUEALING)
ABRAMSON:
That's her right there!
Speed up a little bit.
Whoa, slow down, slow down.
Right... right there.
Why are you driving
so fucking slow?
Hey, pull over. Pull over.
Pull over!
Uh, speed up right here.
We can cut her off at the light.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Prepare to stop.
Traffic light ahead.
Light, light,
light, light, light!
(TIRES SCREECH)
Jesus Christ. (PANTING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Accident ahead.
Would you like to reroute?
You'll save seven minutes.
SAMANTHA: What?
Yes, yes, yes, yes,
yes, yes, reroute.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Rerouting now.
(PANTING)
(BYSTANDERS MURMURING)
(SIRENS APPROACHING)
HOST: (OVER TV)
You lost 2.8 pounds.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING OVER TV)
HOST: (OVER TV)
That means you lost 1.12%
of your body weight, giving you
an overall total of 6.42.
Alicia, that puts you
in last place
of the leader board right now.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
HOST: (OVER TV)
You are in jeopardy of being...
(TV SHUTS OFF)
(INSECTS TRILLING)
Do you have any ice cream?
Come on in.
SAMANTHA:
Whatever's happened to Chloe,
Zoe knows.
I know there's something
she's not telling me. (SIGHS)
Sorry, I just, I didn't know
who else to call.
Okay. I don't mean to scare you,
but we don't have much time.
I got to get you to the clinic.
And the drive is long,
so let's go.
Come on.
No. Fuck that. Do it here.
(PILL BOTTLE OPENS)
(PILLS RATTLE)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Painkillers. You'll need 'em.
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
DR. HUBERT: All right.
Here we go.
This is to help you breathe
and protect your eyes, okay?
Breathe normally.
I'm gonna put you in now, okay?
Give me your hand.
(GROANING)
It's okay. It's okay.
Keep going. Keep going.
We have to do this. Come on.
(WHIMPERS)
It's gonna be a little bit more
than you want.
Just, you have to sit.
(MUFFLED) There you go.
(SAMANTHA WHIMPERING)
There you go.
You need to go down.
Just go down.
I'm gonna push you down, okay?
(WATER SPLASHES)
(GROANING, WHIMPERING)
DR. HUBERT: I'm sorry,
but we have to up the pH levels.
(SAMANTHA GROANS)
(SAMANTHA SCREAMING)
I know it hurts, Sam. I know
it hurts. No. It's okay, Sam.
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(SAMANTHA GASPING)
Trust me. It's almost done.
(SCREAMING CONTINUES FAINTLY)
DR. HUBERT: (MUFFLED)
Breathe. It's okay. Breathe.
Breathe.
Keep breathing for me, okay?
It's almost done.
It's working, Sam.
It's working.
(SAMANTHA GASPING)
(MUSIC CONCLUDES)
(LIGHT MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHUCKLES)
(GROANS SOFTLY)
(SIGHS)
Oh, I should've knocked.
I'm sorry.
It's gone.
Thank you.
Oh. Just sucks
you don't do sprained ankles.
This is for you.
Oh. Breakfast in bed.
All I had to do was grow
a bunch of scales.
Well, it's good you came
when you did.
Yeah.
Look, I'm just gonna say it.
I'm really sorry.
There were a lot of things
I didn't know about
what they were doing, and...
kind of talked you
into the treatment.
I... I just feel, if I knew...
Well, you're right.
It is all your fault.
(KETTLE WHISTLING)
That's coffee.
Um, I'll be right back.
Okay.
(OPENS DRAWER)
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
DR. HUBERT:
How do you take your coffee?
Just take it black, please.
Thank you.
(WATER RUNNING)
(WATER STOPS)
Oh. Scared me.
SAMANTHA: Why do you have
a prescription bottle
with Chloe Benson's name on it?
(CHUCKLES) Okay.
I can explain.
Great.
I mean,
Chloe was one of my patients,
and her skin began to calcify,
just like yours,
and...
you know,
she came to me for help,
and we...
started a relationship.
Yeah.
Oh.
I don't know.
Listen, I know it sounds crazy,
but I love her.
God help me, I still do,
even now that she's...
Even now that...
that she's what?
Okay. I'm sorry.
I can't actually talk
to you about this, so...
Did you do something to her?
No.
I tried everything I can
to stop it,
but I might have made
things worse.
I don't actually know. I...
Where is she?
Stop this for a second.
You can't see her.
She here?
Sam. Sam, you can't see her.
Okay?
Chloe?
You can't... Sam.
Samantha, stop this.
Chloe?
Come back.
Sam. Can you just stop
for a second?
SAMANTHA:
Chloe, can you hear me?
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Chloe?
She can't hear you.
Chloe.
Stop.
I'm trying to protect you, okay?
Hey, just please stop. Stop.
Just stop, I said. Stop.
I don't want anyone
to get hurt, okay?
SAMANTHA: Let me go.
DR. HUBERT: Okay?
(SCREAMS) Fuck. Fuck.
(LOCK CLICKS)
(BANGING AT DOOR)
SAMANTHA: Chloe?
DR. HUBERT: Sam!
(DOOR RATTLING)
DR. HUBERT: I don't know
what they'll do to her.
Sam!
SAMANTHA: Chloe?
DR. HUBERT: Sam! Open the door!
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Sam? Open the door.
Open the door.
(CREAKING, THUDDING)
(WATER SLOSHING)
(CLANGING)
(CHITTERING)
(SCRATCHING,
BANGING AGAINST DOOR)
(SCREECHING)
Fuck.
(RATTLING, BANGING)
(GASPS)
(CHITTERING)
(GASPING)
(SCREECHING IN DISTANCE)
(PANTING)
(GURGLING)
(MUFFLED SCREAM)
(MUSIC CONCLUDES)
(HEAVY, DISTORTED BREATHING)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Who are you people?
Where am I?
My name is Randolph Chan.
I'm a lawyer
for the Shell Group, and, uh,
this is Dr. Brand,
our CEO and founder.
(COUGHS)
RANDOLPH: Let me be the first
to say that I am truly sorry
for what you experienced.
We were all as shocked
and disturbed as you
to learn
of Dr. Hubert's actions.
Where's Chloe?
RANDOLPH: Oh.
Uh, you'll be pleased to know
she's safe and sound.
She's, uh, here at the clinic
with our finest doctors,
where she'll receive
the best medical care she can.
Under the circumstances.
What happened to her?
Well, um, like you, uh,
Ms. Benson suffered
some unfortunate side effects
from her last procedure.
DR. BRAND: In certain patients,
these epidermal calcifications
become somewhat irregular.
We were very transparent
about the risks involved.
If you had read
your nondisclosure
agreement carefully,
it was right there
in plain English.
I don't care what it says.
I will talk... to an attorney.
I will talk to... reporters.
ZOE: Go ahead.
SAMANTHA: I... I...
Lawyer up, Sam. Call the press.
Let's see where that takes you.
I... I...
I don't think it's gonna take
you anywhere very lucrative.
Especially considering
that you will not have a career
to support yourself,
not when we're done with you.
And then your psoriasis
will return.
Along with relentless
cell deterioration,
crow's-feet, saggy skin,
gray hair. Come on.
On and on and on.
(RANDOLPH CLEARS THROAT)
Um, in...
anticipation
of your discretion, uh...
we put together a proposal,
including a generous
share package
and life-long treatments
at the clinic, free of charge.
No...
ZOE: Fuck, Sam.
Don't be so naive.
People die every week
on penicillin.
Every move forward
in medical science
has consequences,
but the health benefits?
They're undeniable.
Is the science perfect?
Not yet.
But when you want
to make an omelet,
you got to...
Kill some people?
Take the offer, Sam.
You have a chance
to be a strong woman
achieving full potential.
And you get to look
amazing doing it.
Why?
ZOE: Because you can, uh,
realize success. To be accepted.
Why?
Why what? Stop saying "why."
SAMANTHA: Why is it necessary?
Now you're just being obstinate.
SAMANTHA:
No, I really want to know.
Why do I have to care
whether I look amazing or not?
(SIGHS) Oh, Sam.
Because we're animals.
There's only so much room
at the top of the food chain.
So you care what you look like
because how you look
determines who survives.
And you care, or you wouldn't be
sitting here right now.
Mm.
You need me
to believe that, right?
Because if I didn't,
or if it...
if it wasn't true, then...
you'd have nothing.
(CHUCKLES)
Can you even imagine it?
A life that wasn't
just lived on the surface?
I bet you can't.
Zoe Zilt.
So, in regards
to your little offer...
(SNIFFLES) ...I'm good.
Thank you.
I'm going home,
and I'm taking Chloe with me.
(CHUCKLES)
(GROANS)
ZOE:
She's not going anywhere.
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS) Make the call.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(PHONE WHOOSHES, CHIMES)
Bring her in.
(ALARM BLARES)
(DOOR CLANGING OPEN)
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
(STEAM HISSING)
(LOW CHITTERING)
ZOE: I hope
you're not squeamish.
Hubert's attempt to remedy
Chloe's symptoms
only accelerated her mutation.
DR. BRAND: As with the other
affected patients,
we see the same pattern
of runaway calcification
and cell replication.
But in this unique case,
the growths are so extensive,
the new enzymes have overpowered
her cellular structure.
She's no longer human.
She's something more...
crustacean.
I think we can both agree
that she...
Chloe needs to stay here.
At the clinic,
where she's receiving
expert medical attention.
Chloe?
(GASPS)
(BANGING ON GLASS)
(OXYGEN TANK HISSING)
(ELECTRICAL CRACKLING)
That glass doesn't break, right?
(SCREECHES)
(SCREAMS)
Oh, fuck!
(CLATTERING)
(SCREAMS)
(WHIMPERING)
(DR. BRAND SCREAMING)
(CHLOE SCREECHING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(RANDOLPH SCREAMING)
(CHLOE CHITTERING)
(SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
(RANDOLPH CONTINUES SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING STOPS)
(CHLOE SCREECHING)
(PANTING)
ZOE: Shit.
(WHIRRING)
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
(POWER WHIRRING DOWN)
SAMANTHA: Shit.
(ALARM BUZZING)
(BANGS ON DOOR)
Sam!
Sam! Sam!
Open it. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
I thought you forgot
all about me.
No, of course not.
(PANTING)
Are you okay?
No, I'm not fucking okay!
All right. Stupid question.
Okay, so we have to
get out of here
because Chloe turned
into a giant lobster
and she's running around
trying to kill everybody.
What?
Shit.
(WHIMPERS)
(CHLOE SCREECHING)
(GASPING)
(CRUNCHING)
Come on, come on.
(SCREECHING, CHITTERING)
ZOE: Where do you ladies
think you're going?
Oh, give it a fucking rest, Zoe.
But, Sam... the optics.
(ELECTRIC CRACKLING)
(SIGHING)
(IN SINGSONG VOICE) Samantha.
It hurts me...
when you turn on me like this.
I saw myself in you.
Sure, I'm taller, I'm richer,
I have better business acumen
and upper arm definition.
But we wanted the same thing.
A friend, a gal pal,
someone to confide in.
You know it was me, right,
who got you cast in that movie?
No one would hire you,
not even after the treatments.
And I felt bad.
I had pity for you
because your life,
it's just so pathetic.
I should have known
you weren't built a winner.
Mm.
You think I just had
all of this handed to me?
You got to take it.
(CLANG)
(GRUNTS)
How's that
for upper arm definition?
(PANTING)
(DOORS CREAKING)
(LOW GROWLING)
(CLAWS CLICKING ON FLOOR)
(HISSING, SCREECHING)
(GUTTURAL GROANING)
(CLATTERING)
(LOW GROWLING)
(HISSING)
(GROWLING)
(SCREECHING)
(GASPS)
(ROARING)
(GASPS) Oh, fuck.
(STATIC CRACKLES)
Oh! Sam!
AUTOMATED VOICE: System on.
(VOICE REPEATING, DISTORTING)
(WHIRRING)
Sam!
(DOORS CREAKING)
(WHIRRING)
(MUFFLED) Sam!
(WHIRRING INTENSIFIES)
(ZOE GROANING LOUDLY)
(SIZZLING)
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(SIZZLING)
(SCREAMING)
(WHIRRING SLOWS)
Sam.
Sam, come... Come on, Sam.
(DINGS, CHIMES)
(MONITOR BEEPING STEADILY)
You should've called me.
I didn't want to scare you, Mom.
You can call your mother
anytime,
no matter what happens.
Thanks, Mom.
AUDIENCE: Aw.
I'm gonna go find that nurse.
And a stiff drink.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHS, APPLAUDS)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
So funny.
That, of course, was a scene
from Hannah Got a Heart,
the show that
first introduced us
to the incomparable
Samantha Lake.
Let's start with the book,
Skin Deep, The Rise and Fall
of a Cosmetic Empire.
I know there are various
lawsuits that still
need to play out,
but tell us about it.
I truly hope that
my story and this book
can serve as
a cautionary tale and... (SIGHS)
I don't know, maybe give people
a little bit of hope.
SALLY: Does it surprise you
that Shell continues to be
a successful business?
SAMANTHA:
People want to look good.
Right?
SALLY: Yeah.
I get it. So do I.
(BOTH LAUGH)
It's no longer
the most important thing
to me in my life.
Mm.
And... (SIGHS)
I'm a lot happier for it.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(LAUGHTER, CHATTER)
("THE LOCO-MOTION" PLAYING)
(BELL DINGS)
♪ Everybody's doing
A brand-new dance now ♪
♪ Come on, baby
Do the Loco-Motion ♪
♪ I know you'll get to like it
If you give it a chance now ♪
♪ Come on, baby
Do the Loco-Motion ♪
♪ My little baby sister
Can do it with ease ♪
♪ It's easier
Than learning your ABCs ♪
♪ So come on, come on
Do the Loco-Motion with me ♪
♪ You gotta
Swing your hips now ♪
♪ Come on, baby, jump up ♪
♪ Yeah, jump back ♪
♪ Well, I think you
Got the knack, whoa-oh ♪
♪ Now that you can do it
Well, let's make a chain now ♪
♪ Come on, baby
Do the Loco-Motion ♪
♪ Chug-a chug-a motion
Like a railroad train now ♪
♪ Come on, baby
Do the Loco-Motion ♪
♪ Do it nice and easy now
Don't lose control ♪
♪ A little bit of rhythm
And a lot of soul ♪
♪ So come on, come on
Do the Loco-Motion with me ♪
♪ The Loco-Motion ♪
♪ Come on, come on
The Loco-Motion ♪
Come on, come on, come on ♪
♪ Move around the floor
In a Loco-Motion ♪
♪ Come on, baby
Do the Loco-Motion ♪
♪ Yeah, do it holding hands
If you get the notion ♪
♪ Come on, baby
Do the Loco-Motion ♪
♪ There's never been a dance
That's so easy to do ♪
♪ It even makes you happy
When you're feeling blue ♪
♪ So come on, come on
Do the Loco-Motion with me ♪
♪ You gotta
Swing your hips now ♪
♪ Ooh
Come on, baby, jump up ♪
♪ Yeah, jump back ♪
♪ Well, I think you
Got the knack, whoa-oh ♪
♪ Do the Loc, do the Loc
Do the Loc, the Loco-Motion ♪
♪ Come on, baby
Do the Loco-Motion ♪
♪ Do the Loc, do the Loc
Do the Loc, the Loco-Motion ♪
♪ Come on, baby ♪
(SONG CONCLUDES)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC CONCLUDES)