MasterChef is back, searching for
the country's best amateur cook.
Go, go, go, go.
Ooh! You've got a towel on your
head. I have. I'm very hot.
Each week, 14 new contestants battle
for a place
in Friday's quarterfinal.
This is a gastronomic triumph.
Only the best will make it through
to the final challenges.
Please, quick, come on, guys.
It looks absolutely stunning.
All different people from all walks
of life,
but they have one burning ambition.
Sharpen the knives,
it's MasterChef time.
These seven home cooks all think
they've got what it takes
to become MasterChef champion.
But at the end of today's heat
only three will make it through
to Friday's quarterfinal.
The thing to do right at the
beginning
is just not to be the worst!
John and Gregg are really...
They're a little bit scary.
I'm not going to hide.
But I'm confident I will bring
something
that not a lot of other
people would bring.
Under normal circumstances
I can be a bit naughty.
If I can hold my nerve, I hope to
bring some fun in there.
A warm welcome
to the MasterChef kitchen.
I wish you the best of luck.
Try and relax and enjoy it.
This, your first test,
is the market test.
You can cook for us
anything you like.
Sweet, savoury, adventurous,
classic,
just something that shows us
the cook that you are.
Off you go.
The contestants now have ten minutes
to plan their dish,
but can revisit the market
at any time.
Today's ingredients include quail,
chorizo, cod, bone marrow
and squid.
There's also a range of cheeses,
flours and grains.
And a selection of fruit
and vegetables.
Blimey, that's a big 'un.
People who love food,
it's every person's dream.
It's sort of quite breathtaking,
really.
I'm going to do, I think,
some kind of gnocchi.
Made it a few times in practice,
so we'll see what happens under
the pressure.
There are so many beautiful things
to cook with,
so it's a real opportunity.
You and I have got high expectations
because we've seen the talent
we've got already.
We know how good they've got to be.
It has to taste fantastic and
it has got to demonstrate skill.
I think I'll be OK, yeah.
Just got to concentrate on one dish
and make that the
best-tasting dish possible.
Ladies and gentlemen, your chance to
impress, one hour and ten minutes.
Cook very well because at the end of
this, three of you are going home.
Let's cook.
35-year-old Kenny lives in Worthing,
West Sussex,
with his wife
and two young children.
My first sort of memories of food
was that my mum cooked a lot,
she's from a big Irish family.
My mum always said if you just put a
bit of love into it, that generally
will make the food taste better.
I'm just going to give it
my best shot,
try and have a bit of fun
and we'll see what happens.
What do you do now, Kenny?
I'm a bank manager.
I've been working for the bank
sort of 15 years,
so it's my first sort of proper job
and I just stuck with it and I love
it, yeah.
You have got what people
used to call a good, steady job,
so why MasterChef?
My passion has always been food
and this is a chance to do something
different. This is something for me.
What are you making? Well, I'm
trying to keep it quite classic,
so I'm going to do some pan-roasted
quail, a red wine sort of reduction.
I'm going to do some celeriac puree,
fondant potato.
Are you going to use
the bone marrow?
I've used the bone marrow
in the sauce
just to get a bit of flavour into it
and if I make something that tastes
all right, I'm there, aren't I?
You're halfway there.
I'm halfway there!
Kenny's roasting a quail.
He's got to make sure he pan- fries
the outside first,
so it goes a little bit crispy.
Lots of seasoning on the inside,
lots of butter, please, Kenny.
Make it opulent.
Red wine sauce with bone marrow is
called sauce Bordelaise.
It's the best type of red wine sauce
in the world
because that bone
marrow makes it rich and wonderful.
But it's got to be reduced down
properly
and it has got to be
absolutely beautiful.
27-year-old Elena has recently taken
up knitting and calligraphy,
but her day job is in finance in the
City of London.
I've worked in pressurised
environments,
so I like to think I deal with
pressure quite well.
But again, you never know.
It's kind of a brand-new challenge
and every challenge is different.
Elena, what are you making?
I'm going to do ravioli filled
with ricotta and spinach,
a bit of Parmesan, pumpkin veloute.
A little bit of kale pesto and
probably some Parma ham crispy bits.
Why are you here on MasterChef?
I come from a huge family
of foodies.
My dad's Greek Cypriot and my mum's
Indian from the West Indies,
so from Trinidad and Guyana.
So I've grown up with
the Greek influence,
I've got the Indian influence
and I've got the West Indian
influence as well.
As long as that filling
has got lots and lots of seasoning
in it, brilliant.
Making a great veloute
is a wonderful thing.
Lots of skill on show.
There is no reason why she shouldn't
get it done.
She seems quite cool and collected.
15 minutes. You've had 15 minutes.
55-year-old Chris takes his culinary
inspiration
from eating in fine dining
restaurants.
The first time I had really good
food, I was just blown away.
I thought...
I didn't realise food could taste
so good, so I wanted to do that.
But at the moment I'm wondering
if I can still boil an egg!
Chris, you look like the love child
of Patrick Stewart
and Gregg Wallace.
That's very kind of you to say so.
We're obviously mirroring
each other.
What do you do? Me, I'm a dentist.
Are there any links at all between
cooking and dentistry?
Yeah, planning,
hopefully you are reasonably good
with knife skills and concentrating
and working to time.
What's the dish, Chris?
It's cod en papillote with fennel
on a fennel beurre blanc
with beans and crushed potatoes.
I'm really pleased
you're cooking fish.
Do it well.
The danger with cooking fish en
papillote is,
you don't know when it's cooked.
I hope he gets it right.
He's doing a fennel beurre blanc,
fantastic,
a butter sauce made with lots
of wine and shallots
which should be lovely and sweet.
It could eat beautifully as long
as he gets that fish cooked
absolutely right.
Barrister George is a keen fly
fisherman
who catches and smokes his
own trout.
Food for me is just one of the most
enjoyable experiences in life.
I'm never happier than when
I'm eating good food.
So if I'm able to cook good food
for other people,
that makes me doubly happy.
George, you look remarkably
comfortable. Are you? I don't know.
I wish now that I had picked
the quail before someone else did.
Right, snooze, you lose. Yes, quite.
George, what are you making?
Some gnocchi with radicchio.
That's going to go with some
of the mushrooms,
the chorizo,
and I made a little basil,
garlic oil kind of like a pesto,
but not quite.
Who do you cook for now?
I tend to cook for my wife
and my family.
I tend to try and be the boss
in the kitchen.
Does your wife consider you
to be the better cook?
I don't know about that,
she's French,
so she's got it in her,
whereas I have to fight
to bring it out of myself.
Good gnocchi is all about lots and
lots of fluffy, dried potato,
a little bit of flour
all mixed together.
And then he's got a sort of like
a pesto affair of oil and basil,
but there is no sauce
with that gnocchi.
It is at the end of the day
a potato dumpling,
and any dumpling needs sauce.
30 minutes have gone, so you've got
40 minutes left.
Graphic designer Tasha enjoys
combining her visual flair
with her love of food.
When I take inspiration for my
dishes I look at art,
the way things are spatially
on a plate.
The negative and positive space.
So I'm hoping my creativity is going
to be my strongest point.
Tasha, what are you going to make?
I'm going to do some mushroom filled
ravioli with a chorizo oil.
Why pasta?
I think it's going to show you
some skill,
some invention
and I think it'll be really tasty.
If you do skill, invention
and tasty, that's got to be enough.
And hopefully, it will look nice
as well.
And presentation,
of course, presentation.
You've nailed them all.
Tasha, happy?
Yeah, fine, just want to wipe my
eyes, but I can't! Come here.
Thank you.
Thin pasta please, Tasha.
Make sure it's really well seasoned.
And she's serving that
with a chorizo oil.
I just hope there's enough sauce
to make sure that that ravioli is
lovely and unctuous.
32-year-old Mans was born in Lebanon
and has lived in France,
Dubai and now in London.
My dream would be to open my own
fine dining, Lebanese restaurant.
Lebanese cuisine is very hearty,
it's very, very comfort food.
But there is a way for it to be
a little bit more fancy.
Mans, what are you going
to make for us?
I'm making a smoked aubergine paste
with ricotta.
A pomegranate and tomato chive salad
and with it is
salt-and-pepper squid.
Is your food, do you think,
representative of your life
and your travels?
Yes, I think so.
In what way? I like to mix flavours
from all around the world,
so this is what I'm trying to do
today
and hopefully it will work out.
We've got ricotta cheese
with pomegranate and squid?
I think Mans is playing with fire.
I think it's dangerous but if
he makes it work, great!
You've got 20 minutes left, guys,
20 minutes.
Lyn from Derby has been cooking
since the age of ten, when her mum
gave her
free rein in the kitchen.
I'm just obsessed with food.
But I do get a little bit nervous
cooking for other people
because I'm not great
at being critiqued.
I'm dreading it!
What do you do for a living, Lyn?
I've been a probation officer for
about 15 years and I have worked in
a prison for about four.
I should imagine, like cooking,
you've had your triumphs and your...
near misses? Yeah, you do, yes,
get some triumphs and when you get
the triumphs,
they are something to
be very, very, very proud of.
What are you making for us?
I've gone for the quail and I have
just pan-fried that.
I've made a bonbon
from the leg meat.
Pomme puree, some kale
and a red wine reduction.
Lyn, fascinated by your food.
Lyn's taken apart her quail,
she's taken the legs and made
a bonbon out of it.
She's pan-fried the breast.
She's taken the bones and made
a sauce which is thick and rich.
Lyn looks like she might be a cook.
The problem we've got today is,
we've got a room full of them.
You know what?
It's going to have to be really
good today, really good.
You have one minute.
The pasta hasn't split,
that's the main thing.
Nearly there.
Come on, Kenny.
Quick.
That's it, guys. Stop.
Are you all right? Yeah.
Gosh, that was awesome, wasn't it?
Yeah!
They are all great, aren't they?
They are indeed.
Kenny, we want to taste your food.
Come on.
Bank manager Kenny is serving
pan-roasted quail
with celeriac puree,
fondant potato, buttered ceps,
beetroot, crispy spinach and
a red wine and bone marrow sauce.
A fair amount of work there.
If that's all properly cooked,
much to be admired.
Your quail is cooked beautifully,
I love the way you've roasted it
on the breast.
Your fondant is soft and buttery,
I really like it.
Your sauce is properly powerful.
But I don't like your beetroot
because I don't think it has got any
place on the plate at all.
OK. You don't have to chuck
everything at it, Kenny.
Of course. Because some of that is
sound as a pound.
That sauce is really very, very rich
indeed because of the bone marrow.
Your puree is perfectly smooth.
I've got a sneaking suspicion that
you have quite a bit of technique
up your sleeve.
I'm feeling good, ready to go,
next round, maybe.
Well done, mate. Thank you.
That was really good.
I think it went really well. You
managed it. Well done.
27-year-old Elena has made ravioli
filled with ricotta and spinach,
kale pesto, crispy pancetta and a
sage and pumpkin veloute.
Nice sauce, nice pasta,
but the spinach and ricotta filling
is really wet,
so it's spilling out into the sauce.
I really like
the sweet pumpkin sauce.
For you to make a veloute, make a
filling, make a ravioli, very good.
It's like the adrenaline is just...
I think I can cook better
but I'm definitely proud of myself,
you know.
Barrister George has cooked gnocchi
with wild mushrooms, pine nuts,
Swiss chard, endive, and basil and
garlic oil.
Your gnocchi are nice and light.
I like the selection of mushrooms
and chard
and a bit of endive in there as
well.
But there's nothing gluing
it together.
It needs a sauce of some type
so that those dumplings puff up
a little bit and take a bit
of that sauce on.
It's very easy to make gnocchi
heavy and dense.
Yours are light and pillow-like.
I also like the zing of fresh herb,
but without a sauce, it's dry and
it just hasn't got enough flavour
to cover what is a bowl
of potato dumplings.
Aargh.
If the reasons that I go home
are because I didn't quite put
enough of the sauce on the plate,
then that will bug me.
God, it's daunting.
Probation officer Lyn is serving
pan-fried breast of quail
on mashed potato, a quail leg
bonbon,
buttered kale and a red wine sauce.
The bonbon has got loads of spice in
it with pepper, lots of garlic.
It's crispy on the outside, you can
taste the quail, it's really good.
Your sauce is rich with red wine.
Your mashed potato, although it's
got lumps in it,
is really well-seasoned and
really, really lovely.
Bonbons are fabulous.
OK. The potato is buttery and your
sauce is sweet.
It's deep, it's great.
I'm really happy with the breast.
You've handled that bird
really well.
You have a very good touch,
very good palate,
I'm very impressed with that.
I never expected to get
that kind of feedback.
I'm bowled over, it was awesome.
I'm so excited.
Well done!
Mans has made salt-and-pepper
squid...
..and served it on a puree of smoked
aubergine, ricotta,
lemon and garlic and a salad
of chives,
tomatoes and pomegranate seeds.
You are a fusion man, aren't you?
I am.
Your squid's cooked nicely with
its salt and pepper outside,
being a little bit spicy,
a little bit crispy.
There's lots of lovely flavour
of cumin and garlic
in with your aubergine.
But that sweetness of pomegranate
and cheese and squid,
I find unnerving.
I'm not a fan of squid and cheese
and I'm not a fan of squid
and pomegranate.
I thought I'd hate ricotta,
aubergine and pomegranate,
but I don't.
I could dip some bread into it,
but I can't get used to dipping
squid into it, I'm afraid.
I'm not sure it's
something that you've had before.
No. I think it's something you may
have made up. Yes. Exactly.
I took a huge risk
by doing this dish.
Then again, I like mixing
ingredients
and sometimes it works and if it
doesn't work,
well, tough luck for me.
Well done. Are you all right?
Graphic designer Tasha has cooked
mushroom and Parmesan ravioli
with crispy chorizo cubes and
a chorizo, thyme and sage oil.
Not bad on your pasta,
it's slightly too thick,
therefore a little bit chewy
around the edge.
But the inside of your ravioli is
absolutely lovely.
Soft mushrooms, fair amount of
cheese in there as well,
giving it a real salty zing.
Your oil is not delivering
enough flavour.
Right. I like the warmth that comes
from the big hunks of chorizo,
but you need to put paprika
with that oil.
There's some tasty bits and there's
a few little mistakes.
It's a bit of a blur.
Hopefully, if I go through, I'll
get those silly mistakes correct.
Finally, Chris has prepared cod en
papillote, with crushed potatoes,
green beans and chard,
with brown shrimps in a fennel
beurre blanc sauce.
You can most certainly cook
a piece of fish,
it's coming apart in nice, big, wide
flakes.
Beurre blanc, perfect
accompaniment to that cod.
I think there are some really lovely
bits about this dish.
It's just a bit rough
in the way it looks.
But I think it's a good start.
I was sort of shell-shocked.
It's quite an experience.
They seemed to quite like some parts
of it, so I'm holding on to that.
What are we going to do here then,
John? I have a star today.
I think Lyn's quail was
just fantastic.
The flavours, Gregg!
I agree with you. The most important
thing are good cookery foundations,
and Lyn can cook.
The other dish that I loved was also
a dish of quail
and that was from
Kenny, the bank manager.
Kenny can cook as well.
Heart and soul of that dish was
great
and that sauce bordelaise was
fabulous. Can we talk about Chris?
Cooking en papillote and making
a beurre blanc, that's classic,
classic cooking, and he can do it.
Yeah, Chris, our dentist, I think
did really well.
So Chris now joins Lyn and Kenny.
Mans can actually cook squid.
But aubergine, ricotta cheese,
squid and pomegranate seeds?
That doesn't work!
Mans, I like some of your Lebanese
flavours, but not all together.
George frustrates me in that I think
he made excellent gnocchi,
but you've got to put some heavy
sauce in there.
Flavour, he did not deliver. True.
Elena did good pasta work.
She made a very decent
pumpkin veloute.
There was definitely skill
on show there.
However, the issue was that filling
of wet ricotta.
Tasha's ravioli was a little bit
thick
where the two sheets of pasta met.
Beautiful mushroom filling.
The oil itself didn't have
a great deal of punch.
I'd like it to be a bit more saucy,
a bit more unctuous.
If this is it, I'll be gutted.
I want to prove to you
how good I can be.
In the time, I did what I wanted
to do,
but often, one thing
makes the difference.
That was really fun, but intense.
I think that's just whetted my
appetite.
It is a bit infectious,
the adrenaline rush.
I'm here for the adventure.
I know it's going to be a hard one,
because only three will make it,
but I really want to go through.
Who can go further
in the competition?
Who has got more to show?
Very, very well done.
With a roomful of decent cooks,
it's a real shame that all of you
can't go through.
There's three cooks who we thought
today were outstanding.
Kenny.
Lyn.
And Chris.
Congratulations, you three are
going through to the next round.
Well done. Well done.
That means we've only got one more
place to give.
The fourth person going through
to the next round...
..is Elena.
Congratulations.
Mans, Tasha, George,
thank you very much, guys.
Nice to have met you. Thank you.
I was pleased with what I produced.
But on the day,
there were better chefs, so...
I'm sure I can only savour
a couple of things,
because I've had such a great time
and would have wanted it
to go further. But it happens.
I'm not going to be doing squids
any more.
Ever. I didn't do my cooking style
justice at all tonight.
But c'est la vie.
Today has a real sense of occasion,
because we've invited three
wonderful guests in here
to taste and help judge your food...
Previous finalist Jack Lucas
and champions Mat Follas
and Natalie Coleman.
You impress all three of them,
you are good!
Ladies and gentlemen, three
quarterfinal places to give.
Two courses, your own food.
One hour and 15 minutes. Let's cook.
I've done these dishes for dinner
parties and friends.
People usually liked it.
Practised it a few weeks ago
and I got Nancy, my wife,
to come in periodically and ask me
lots of questions
to try and put me off.
It's got to be really good food
without any mistakes.
What are you going to cook, Chris,
that's going to get you a
quarterfinal place?
Seared tuna, covered in sesame seed,
with lots of Asian flavours,
drizzled with ginger.
It's going to be on a bed of
coriander
and it's got little garlic chips
and chilli on top.
And a main course of...?
It's a tarragon chicken with smoked
lardons, mushrooms,
tarragon and with a bit of Madeira
in it, really rich sauce,
chicken skin chard
and hasselback potato.
Why would you want
a quarterfinal place?
I want to be a better chef.
This pushes you,
this moves you along,
from where you would be
in your normal life.
Oh, that's a brave chap, innit,
who comes in here and
just sears a bit of tuna!
It could well be a good tactical
move,
doing something delicious
but simple as a starter,
putting all your energy and time
into a more complex main course.
Chicken with tarragon,
it's proper comfort food and I'm
really excited about it.
I just hope he does it justice.
Elena is playing with two very,
very classical dishes.
Beef carpaccio,
served with matchstick fries,
a mustard dressing and burnt onions.
I mean, that's a great combination.
I love a carpaccio,
but it's not showing a great deal
of cookery skill.
Her second course is a duck breast
with celeriac puree, cavolo nero,
blackberry sauce,
lovely, lovely flavours,
but cooking that duck is not as easy
as everybody thinks.
Elena, you've got little sort of
calling cards.
Yeah, every five minutes, I should
have done a bunch of stuff.
Right, so each one of those cards is
a five-minute pack?
Yeah. Very clever, good planning,
I like it.
I can be quite slow, so I'm trying
to be as fast as I can.
Slow is something you really
don't want to be on MasterChef.
I know, I know.
Where are you right now?
A little bit behind.
What do I need to do?
Two courses for four people in
an hour and 15 minutes.
I don't think I've ever done
that before.
So I've really got to keep tidy and
don't kind of get into a messy flap.
I feel a little bit nervous.
I won't lie.
It's what sort of drives you,
isn't it?
Yeah, I am absolutely buzzing.
Two courses for
a quarterfinal place. Yeah.
What are they? I'm doing a
venison loin with a champ croquette,
some carrot puree
and a juniper sauce.
Dessert, I'm doing a fig
and almond tart,
with some Chantilly cream and a
spiced fig syrup.
You look like you're a bit nervous
about this round.
I loved the first one and to get
that taste of success,
you know what it's like. It pushes
you forward, doesn't it?
We shall see!
Venison and juniper and a croquette
sounds fabulous,
absolutely fantastic.
Cor! An almond and fig tart
with the fig syrup.
There are lots of reasons to fall
in love with Kenny's food.
That is not the issue.
Has Kenny actually bitten off
more than he can really chew?
He looks pushed,
to the point of manic.
And he's already cut himself
twice.
This whole thing,
this thing is bonkers!
I keep pinching myself.
Am I actually here?
It's bonkers!
Lyn. What are you going to cook
for us?
I'm starting with a pan-fried
duck breast.
I'm doing a stuffed cabbage parcel.
What's your cabbage parcel
stuffed with?
Essentially, it's stuffed
with cabbage.
And a red wine, port
and blackberry sauce.
My next dish is a spiced
hazelnut biscuit,
with a baked chocolate
and orange ganache.
Is your ganache spreadable
or is it a disc?
Theoretically,
I am meant to quenelle it.
You may or may not get quenelles.
So I really need to work
on my presentation.
Lyn is putting cabbage
inside a cabbage.
I don't know why she's not using a
forcemeat inside the cabbage,
because that would be really lovely
with the duck meat.
Dessert is a baked
chocolate ganache.
Chocolate ganache to me is the
spreadable stuff
you put on top of a cake.
So is it like a baked chocolate
mousse or a baked chocolate biscuit?
I don't understand what a baked
chocolate ganache is.
I know what I've got to do.
I'm just running out of time.
But I will get something out,
hopefully.
I feel sorry for the guys today,
because it is quite stressful.
I remember I sort of fell to pieces
in this round.
I was a little bit late,
so I don't envy them today.
MasterChef has done wonders for me,
it opens doors.
My dream was that sort of seaside
cafe, doing really good quality,
relatively simple food.
I've achieved that and
I'm enjoying what I do.
I remember this challenge, looking
back on it, with fond memories.
Actually, I think it went quite well
for me,
but it is absolutely terrifying.
But for me, show potential,
deliver things on time
to schedule and you will ace
this challenge.
Here's to some good food, guys,
I hope that we're going
to get fed well.
Salute. Cheers. Cheers.
Ten minutes on your first course,
please.
Now, I quite like the sound of this.
It's quite simple, tuna, just sesame
coat it, cook it nice and pink,
just a really nice sear on the
outside is all it needs.
That looks good, mate. Thank you.
I hope it tastes good. I think the
key to this dish
is those Asian flavours and not
overbalancing with too much garlic.
I feel sorry for my other half
tonight,
after eating them garlic chips!
Three minutes, young Chris.
What else has to go on here?
Just the garnishes.
Good job I don't shake like this
at work!
Are you happy with it?
Yeah. Good. Off you go.
Thank you. Well done, mate.
Well done.
Hello. Hello.
Thank you.
This is a seared tuna with black
sesame seed on the outside,
with an Asian style dressing on
coriander with garlic chips.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Thank you.
It smells really, really good.
It looks really pretty.
He's made quite a good effort.
The tuna is cooked nicely. I like
the sesame crust on the outside.
He has got the coriander,
the chilli, the garlic in there,
but actually, that sauce,
where is it?
I want more of it, I want something
to give it some depth of flavour.
There's a hint of it on the plate,
it smells good,
so he had a good sauce.
If he put plenty of that on the
plate, there's a good dish here.
The heat of the chilli, along with
the sweetness of the fish,
that lovely toastiness of the sesame
seeds is wonderful.
That's a nice dish.
15 minutes now...
until your chicken, yeah? Thank you.
Go on, chef!
I've done this dish between eight to
ten times,
but never under this sort of time
pressure.
It has always been relaxed,
for friends and relatives.
And with a glass of wine!
I love the sound
of his second course,
chicken in a creamy tarragon,
it's a favourite in my house.
It's completely different
to his starter.
Quite French in its approach.
Hasselback potatoes, so important
that he slices those potatoes
really finely and they crisp up.
Yeah, you've got four minutes,
Chris. OK.
Looks like you're on time.
I like to try and be to time
if I can.
Oh, you've got some good things
going across that plate, chef.
Yeah! What's left? Your chards.
Chards.
Well done.
Nice. Nice.
Hello, again. Hello. Hi.
Wow.
Thank you very much.
This is a tarragon chicken
and a mushroom sauce.
A chicken chard, hasselback potatoes
and then spinach and pine nuts,
enjoy, thank you. Thanks. Thanks.
It's a nice looking dish, it smells
great, I can't wait to try it.
Mmm! That is so good.
He has got it, hasn't he? Well done.
I love this.
The chicken was cooked perfectly.
I loved the spinach
and pine nut puree.
The sauce with the mushrooms
and morels was delicious.
It's thick, it's creamy,
it's unctuous.
The skill of a cook is in making
a sauce more than anything else.
Yeah, that sauce is good.
Well done, Chris.
Soft chicken, fantastic.
Smoky sauce with a little bit
of sweetness from the Madeira,
a little bit of aniseed
from the tarragon, fabulous.
That's a yummy dish, made by someone
cooking what they like to eat.
Glad it's over. I thought they came
out really well,
but it doesn't matter if I'm pleased
or not, does it?
It really doesn't count!
I only cooked that dish originally
because I liked it!
Lyn. Yeah? You've got five minutes.
Yeah. Are you on time?
Yeah. I'm done. Wow!
What's left, what's left to do, Lyn,
before you plate up? Nothing.
So, Lyn's main,
this sounds fantastic.
Duck breast, celeriac,
Savoy cabbage.
Hearty, it's wholesome,
it's autumnal.
Cabbage parcel sounds
quite interesting,
I wonder what she's put in there.
Maybe she's made a nice stuffing?
She just has to cook
her duck perfectly,
nice puree and we'll be happy.
Two minutes, Lyn.
Yeah. OK.
Whoa! Don't... All right. Sorry.
I'm not very delicate,
have you noticed?
Right. Are you done with your duck?
I don't know.
That one looks a right mess.
Yeah, I'm done with the duck.
Off you go.
Ladies first. Sorry, I'm a bit
clumsy.
That's all right. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
And breathe.
So, I've made for you pan-fried
duck breast with celeriac puree,
stuffed Savoy cabbage parcel
and a red wine, port and blackberry
sauce. I hope you enjoy.
Looks amazing.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
My duck is cooked nicely,
it's nice and pink.
The celeriac puree is nice.
The cabbage parcel's great.
It's got a lot of flavour in it.
The sauce is thin but it has
a really nice shine to it.
It's got quite a nice flavour,
but it's a little bit sweet.
Lyn has a presentation issue.
Look at the sauce!
Creamed cabbage, celeriac puree
and duck, cooked by Lyn.
Great. Her flavours are good.
You've got four minutes. Thank you.
Your gel, how long does it take
to set?
About a minute.
It's a very quick set.
Ganache OK? It's cooked, yes.
I've got to quenelle it, though.
Is that wet enough to quenelle?
Yeah.
It's meant to be
a rough-look quenelle.
I love chocolate in a dessert.
It's one of my favourite things.
But what is a baked ganache?
When you work with chocolate,
would you normally bake it,
unless it has flour,
and it's more like a fondant?
It'll be interesting to see
what it turns out like.
I can't quenelle.
I don't think that texture will
quenelle properly,
even if you were better at it.
Lots of work there,
classic flavours,
should go together really,
really well.
Two minutes.
We need gels, go, go, go, go.
Has it set? Yes!
MOUTHS: Yeah!
Come on.
Are you done? Yeah? OK.
I think I am.
You've got it done, Lyn.
Took a lot of effort and quite a bit
of skill
to get all these things
done, but what is it?
Hi.
Thank you.
For your dessert, there is a baked
chocolate and orange ganache,
a spiced hazelnut biscuit, and
orange gel and Chantilly cream.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
I think it's a lot of picky things.
I quite liked eating it,
dipping the biscuit into the
chocolate
and the cream and everything.
The biscuit is light and has got
a good texture, good taste.
I think the Chantilly cream is sweet
enough, it's quite pleasant.
I think the flavour in the dark
chocolate is bitter,
but the texture is just wrong,
it set so firm.
It's got all the flavours of
a really good pudding here.
I think she's just confused
with presentation.
It's obvious that Lyn knows
how to bake a biscuit,
she knows how to make a chocolate
ganache, she knows what Chantilly is
and she knows how to make a jelly.
She doesn't know what to do with
them once she's made them,
but she knows how to make them!
It wasn't a disaster, but there were
things that just went wrong.
I feel like an emotional wreck.
Ten minutes, Kenny.
KENNY LAUGHS
Quick, quick, quick, quick.
Come on, buddy.
Kenny is cooking us a venison loin,
champ croquette and a juniper sauce.
All of those elements are quite
difficult to do well.
The croquette, got to make sure that
the mash is nice and smooth
and creamy inside, no lumps, we
don't like lumpy mash.
You've got five minutes, Kenny.
OK, man. Where is your venison?
It's in now. I think I'm taking it
out, you know.
I think this sounds great,
it's classic.
Venison loin,
get it cooked perfectly.
Don't overcook it! No, no, no,
that would be a travesty.
Come on, Kenny, come on, come on.
Got two minutes, Kenny.
OK, OK, all right!
OK, croquettes, croquettes.
No. That pan is going to be hot!
I know, I know. I'm on it,
I'm on it.
Right, we're running out of time,
Kenny,
really, really running out of
time. Watch out for this claret.
That is as rare as
a kind-hearted bank manager.
KENNY LAUGHS
You got that right, Gregg.
Plates a wipe and that's done, yeah?
Hold on, hold on. There's just the
beetroot to chuck on the side.
Kenny. Looks good. Thank you, mate.
Thank you. I'll serve you next.
What I've cooked for you today
is roast loin of venison,
with a champ croquette,
some carrot puree,
roasted beetroot
and a juniper sauce.
Lovely. Looks lovely.
Thank you very much.
All right. Take care. Thank you.
Thank you.
I'm quite excited by this dish.
Beetroot looks amazing,
the glaze on it and it looks like a
nice champ croquette.
So, yeah, the boy's done good.
The venison is cooked perfectly.
For me, that sauce is as good
as it gets. Mmm!
It packs a massive punch of flavour.
Epic. The croquette is amazing.
It's really crispy on the outside
and then little fluffy pillows
of mashed potato heaven.
It's amazing.
That is stunning food.
I have no criticism of that dish
at all.
Now, that is super yummy.
Absolutely super yummy.
It's a generous, well-flavoured,
well-cooked plate of food.
Great.
You've got 15 minutes to make them
look
the most beautiful tarts
we have ever seen.
Thank you very much, cheers.
Now, I love the sound of Kenny's
dessert.
We have got a fig and almond tart.
I presume it's going to be
like a frangipane,
so maybe a little bit gooey in the
middle, which will be nice.
Figs, I am personally not a fan of
figs, so this has to convert me.
And that fig syrup, a little bit of
spice in there to bring it together
into something really delicious.
Sounds good.
Five minutes, but you're well
under way, right?
I'm well under way, yes.
They look great, Kenny. Thank you.
You need a nice chunk because I hate
it when there's not enough cream.
They look fantastic.
Well done. Thank you. Nice.
Love it, love it, love it.
Where's me spoon?
Hello.
There we go. There's yours.
Thank you very much. No problem.
Thank you. No problem.
So here we've got a fig and almond
tart with a spiced fig syrup
and a Chantilly cream. I hope you
enjoy it. Thank you.
By the way, your main...
That is spot on, isn't it?
Look at the pastry skills.
That's some real talent to do
that.
That is amazing.
It's so sticky and gooey
and sweet and...
Oh, that is like a bundle of joy.
That is tart heaven.
The pastry was buttery,
it was perfectly short,
the filling was slightly gooey, but
cooked through, the figs were soft.
I think it's fantastic.
I think that's probably the best
fig tart I've ever had.
That is absolutely superb.
A nice looking tart. Look at that.
Oh, yes. I may be a while.
That's delicious.
Lots and lots of spice
in that syrup.
Love the strong almond
in the background.
The pastry is nice and short and
crispy.
Just enough fig in there for it to
be soft, but still concentrated.
That is lovely, John.
I feel knackered.
I've been through the wars,
but I feel great.
I feel really good.
If it's not good,
I couldn't taste it yet,
but hopefully they're all right.
Elena, five minutes on your first
course. OK.
It's quite clever, beef carpaccio,
you can do it quite simply but still
deliver from a taste perspective
and from a presentation point of
view.
Can I put my duck on?
Quick, quick, quick, you've got
to put the food out. Come on.
You've got two minutes, then you
need to serve your starter.
OK. I don't suppose you need me to
tell you
you're right up against it, do
you? No.
Elena, you've got to get these
starters out, mate.
They're waiting for you.
Now, now, now. OK.
What's left to go on there now?
The little bit of dressing,
the matchstick potatoes.
The capers and the onions.
Yes. That is quite a lot.
OK, your time is now up.
I literally need one more minute
if that's OK. Quick.
Onions go on now? Yes.
Mate, you haven't got time
to do that, really sorry.
You haven't got time to do this,
they've got to go on.
Right now, you are two minutes over.
That's the last thing, right?
And then I'm just going to do
a couple of shavings of Parmesan,
I'm done.
Can we go? Yeah.
You're three minutes over.
Let's go. I'm done.
It's a bit scruffy, mate, innit?
Oh, amazing. Thank you.
That looks good.
I hope you enjoy it. Thank you.
Thank you.
For Elena's first course
she's made beef carpaccio
with charred onion petals,
matchstick fries and a garlic,
Parmesan and mustard dressing.
It looks pretty.
My only concern is that the beef
hasn't been seared on the outside.
I think those shoestring fries are
amazing, crispy on the outside.
And then there's that garlic sauce.
I think it works really nicely.
I'm impressed with that,
it's a nice bit of garlic.
That's what seasons the meat.
Maybe it needs a bit of a kick
of pepper.
However, I think it's really nice.
That's a really lovely,
tasty plate of food.
There's not a lot of cooking
going on here.
It's a scruffy dish,
it's a late dish,
but it's a dish that tastes good.
I still need to process
both of my sauces
and finish off basically plating
and everything.
So I'm up against it.
You've got just five minutes left,
are you ready to plate?
I will be ready to plate.
No, you kind of need
to be ready now.
I'm trying my hardest for you.
So pan-fried duck breast,
celeriac puree.
I love celeriac.
Pickled raspberries, delicious.
Yeah, it sounds like my cup of tea.
I like a bit of duck, crispy on the
outside and pink on the inside,
not flapping away.
How's that? Nice and pink.
A bit under. A bit under?
Yeah.
You're now over time, Elena.
So we've got crisps to go on,
we've got blackberries to go on,
we've got sauce to go on.
Anything else? No.
Cooking a sauce, a really good
sauce, takes time.
It's really important she gets it
glossy
and it needs to be quite thick
and coat the back of a spoon
quite nicely.
You are now four minutes over.
Off you go. Thank you.
Hello. Hello.
Thank you.
For the second course I've made you
pan-fried duck breasts
with celeriac puree, pickled
blackberries, sauteed cavolo nero,
blackberry and port sauce
and celeriac crisps.
Hope you enjoy.
My duck is still a little bit
quacking, but I'd still eat it.
I'm not too fussy.
It's not completely flying away
from the plate.
It eats beautifully.
I think the flavour balances,
she's got her seasoning spot on.
There's room for improvement
in some aspects.
I think the celeriac puree could be
a little bit creamier.
I think the sauce is a little bit
too thick
but it's got great flavour.
I think the time probably caught up
on her.
I think it shows a little bit
in the dish.
Parts of the duck are edible,
but there are certain parts
that aren't.
The berry sauce is more like jam
rather than a sauce.
It's a perfect combination
of flavours
not delivered perfectly because she
ran out of time.
It's frustrating.
I'm a bit disappointed because I
went over and my duck was under,
which isn't the right combination.
That was really, really tough
for me.
I'm just happy I wasn't later,
to be honest.
We had some fantastic cooking
here today,
none better than Kenny.
Really good flavours, really good
cooking, really good presentation.
That fella seems to have it all.
We loved it and so did our guests.
The other person I think who did
very, very well today was Chris.
Yes. His little Asian tuna was
pretty good.
But the quality of his chicken!
I was looking around for a bit
of bread to dip in that sauce.
That was quality.
Kenny and Chris are through.
Who takes that last
quarterfinal place?
Elena had timing issues.
Her starter of beef carpaccio
didn't look great at all,
in fact it was scruffy.
I thought it tasted good.
The main course, we had a duck which
wasn't cooked very well at all.
And again,
that main course was late.
Lyn's flavours were good.
I liked the quality of her sauce
and the duck was fine,
but it was a mess.
And that's the frustration with Lyn,
is that she's got the flavour
profile
but she ain't got the finesse.
I want it so badly.
I would give you my husband
right now
in exchange for a quarterfinal
place!
You can cook in your kitchen all you
want,
but this is all about testing
yourself
and kind of really seeing
what you've got.
All you can do is hope that,
you know, you've done enough,
so we'll see.
For me, there's one person who I
believe has the potential
to go further in the competition.
You guys today did really,
really well.
We ate very well indeed.
And we've made a decision.
Kenny...
Chris...
..you've done more than enough
to go through to the quarterfinal.
Well done. Thank you.
We have one more place.
The contestant going through
to the quarterfinal...
..is Lyn.
Elena, great competition, thank you.
Well done, thank you.
I feel quite gutted. Probably in my
heart of hearts.
I know I could have cooked better.
But I'm still really pleased and I'm
still going to look back on this
as one of the best things I've done.
I'm a quarterfinalist.
I can't actually believe it.
I don't think it's sunk in.
I'm absolutely in shock.
I just feel incredible.
I'm not a big crier, but I keep sort
of welling up.
I'm buzzing, I'm buzzing.
It's just a massive achievement.
Absolutely elated.
To have impressed people that you
respect so much with your food
on two occasions now,
it sort of vindicates
that I can cook. It's great.
On Wednesday night, the heats come
to an end as the last group of cooks
battle for a place
in the quarterfinal.
He knows what's going on in my head.
Anybody else brought a mascot
with them?
Genius idea. It's great.
This is good stuff, John,
it's good stuff.