(All characters, organizations,
and events in this drama are fictitious.)
What do you take me for?
Don't be mistaken.
I'm aware of the truth.
I know that you see me as faulty...
and that this is as rotten
as you described.
Do you know
what the real issue is though?
You keep crossing the line
just because I choose to play dumb.
Jin Jung, don't.
In this case, you've gone too far.
That's why...
I'm going to take all of you down.
Get up. I'm just getting started.
What is the meaning of this?
How dare you muddy up
our clean waters?
(Seoul Central District
Prosecutors' Office)
(HR Announcement)
(Prosecutor Jin Jung
of Criminal Division 3...)
(Transferred to Civil Affairs Division)
(Fair prosecution serving the people)
Excuse me, do you know
where the Civil Affairs Division is?
I think it's way down there.
Thanks.
(Waste Disposal)
(Promoting an impartial world
and social justice)
(Civil Affairs Division)
Gosh.
(The Role of Prosecutors)
(Public Service Reports)
- New guy.
- Right.
As of today, I was transferred
to the Civil Affairs Division.
I'm Jin Jung.
Welcome. The name is Park Jae Kyung.
Right.
What is this place anyway?
It says right there.
The Civil Affairs Division.
I read the sign,
but I didn't think such a place existed.
- What's your graduating class?
- Sorry?
From the Judicial Research
and Training Institute.
I went to law school.
What kind of trouble did
someone so young cause to land here?
It's been around
way longer than you have,
so show respect.
Where are the others?
It's just me. The others quit.
Sorry?
We'll get into details later on.
Since you're here, get to work.
Time to work.
Over there.
(Bad Prosecutor)
(Episode 2)
Good evening, sir.
Is this an illegal taxi service?
- Of course not.
- Right?
- We're trying to root it out.
- Sure.
What is this about?
We're hoping to root out
illegal taxi services.
We don't do things like that.
Right? Of course.
Good evening, then.
This must be your first time
calling for a taxi.
What name should I put
your number under?
I see you're a quiet one.
I'll take you
straight to your workplace.
That'll be 30,000 won in cash.
Although, I wouldn't mind a tip.
Good evening, I'm here to promote
the end of illegal taxi services.
Where on earth did he come from?
Could you lower your window?
Hey, girl.
I'm sorry to ask you this,
but I need a favor.
Did you call me a girl?
- What the...
- Get back here.
- Come here.
- Hey.
Seriously?
Hey, stop where you are.
You with the illegal taxi service.
Let's not make this harder.
You have nowhere to go,
so get back here.
No, don't jump the wall.
I told you not to do that.
What the... Darn it.
Why you...
Hey!
Darn it.
Chul Ki!
Move!
Out of my way!
- What the...
- Hey!
He's exhausting me.
Darn it.
Gosh.
Are you done running?
Get over here, then.
Who are you people? Are you cops?
No, I'm a prosecutor.
A prosecutor?
As if I would fall for that lie.
What kind of prosecutor
comes to work dressed in that?
Tell me about it.
I don't know what I'm doing myself.
Anyway, we caught you,
so get over here.
No.
Hey!
Don't do this.
Not everyone can make that jump.
There's a good chance
you'll fall and die.
- Get over here.
- Come down.
Come on.
- I'm still panting.
- Maybe for you, but not for me.
Wait!
Hey!
Unbelievable.
Did he actually make the jump?
Hey!
You startled us!
Are you all right?
- Help me.
- I told you not to jump.
Call an ambulance.
What on earth
were you up to out there?
You were to do public service,
not break someone's leg.
What are you, a thug?
Also, who on earth is this guy?
I'm Investigator Lee Chul Ki.
I asked to be transferred here.
Give me a break.
I see you have
a loyal investigator by your side.
If this is how it's going to be,
quit already.
No one will stop you.
Is this your way of complaining?
Are you annoyed because
I told you not to do your job?
That's right.
This is me complaining.
- What?
- Should I be honest with you?
I don't get
what I'm doing around here.
This is all I've done so far
in this division.
(Motel)
Investigating an extramarital affair.
Tracking down a runaway dog.
Who are you people?
You should go home.
Wait. Hey.
Please take him home. Thank you.
Getting a taxi for a drunk guy.
And chasing after a dog
that had run away again.
Those have been my tasks.
Even the police substations
don't take care of these tasks.
Besides, why are the substations
making us handle these requests?
And why are we
actually handling them?
- Like chauffeurs on call?
- Yes, just like them.
Why?
Because that's what we do here.
I'm not making you do them
because I want to bully you.
You're supposed to take care of
those requests here...
until you retire at the age of 63.
Do you know
the real name of this office?
The garbage disposal office.
They want disobedient prosecutors
like you to quit on their own.
They can't exactly tell that
to your face.
What if I don't resign?
You will be doing this
for the rest of your career.
Here are the civil complaint files.
(Our puppy ran away again.)
It's the darn dog again?
Darn it.
That illegal taxi guy will sue.
It will be a headache for everyone.
Go to him and say, "I'm sorry."
- What?
- Or you can resign.
Beat it. Go already.
Did you find out anything
about the victim, Park Ye Young?
I haven't found
any hard evidence yet.
I looked into the surrounding areas
around her house, but...
But nothing?
Like someone had gotten rid of it?
And Kim Hyo Jun
still refuses to see us?
I've been reaching out. But...
Prosecutor Jin.
Yes?
Can I ask you something?
What is it?
In the backseat...
Imagine how desperate
I must be to do that.
I can't find a way to fix this,
and I'm stuck doing this job.
I should seek their help.
(BBS, Buddhist Radio Station)
Buddha, it's today.
You should ask him for help too.
Ask him to give us a lead.
Merciful Buddha,
please have mercy on us.
(Paradise Hospital)
What?
Come on. I'm eating.
If you need to say something,
just spit it out and leave.
Now that you're in the hospital,
- you don't look too bad.
- That's...
up to the doctor to evaluate.
I'll include the doctor's note
when I file a lawsuit.
You can check it then.
Well, about what happened...
- I'm...
- Can you get me my phone?
Over there.
Right next to you.
What are you doing?
(Did you see Ye Young's news?)
Give it to me.
(Dong Sik, Han Ju)
(Dong Sik)
(Yoon Ju)
Wait. Give me that.
(- Pick me up at 9 p.m.
- Who are you going to see?)
(- Him.
- I'll call you when I get there.)
What are you doing?
My goodness!
Give it to me.
Oh, my.
What are you doing?
Hey, Chul Ki.
Be on the lookout.
Wait. Why does he have to be
on the lookout at a hospital?
Gosh. Don't kill me.
So let me get this straight.
Park Ye Young worked
at a hostess bar. Right?
Yes. That's right.
I was just delivering...
No. I was just driving the car.
And I know nothing about the rest.
I'm telling the truth.
Who is this "him"
in the text message?
He was just Ye Young's regular John.
He buys her meals
and gives her some pocket money.
She told me she had a sponsor.
Goodness. Come on.
Who was her pimp?
- What?
- You said she worked at a bar.
Someone must have owned
the hostess bar.
Who introduced the John
to Park Ye Young?
Oh, that...
I don't know that much
about this business.
Oh, no. Be careful.
You have to tell us.
He's really going to let you go.
I'll talk.
- Yu Jin Cheol.
- Who?
His name is Yu Jin Cheol.
He's the owner of the hostess bar.
Come on. Help me up already.
Yu Jin Cheol?
(Seoul Central District
Prosecutors' Office)
How's Prosecutor Jin doing?
He's doing his best...
by taking care of
all the menial tasks in the world.
I'm trying to think
this is for the better.
Gosh. That punk.
He needs to learn his lesson.
His name is Yu Jin Cheol.
He runs a few hostess bars
in Gangnam.
According to my intel,
he sets up big names in finance
and politics with girls.
More importantly,
I think he's connected
to Deputy Chief Lee.
To Deputy Chief Lee?
We can't treat this lightly.
I need you to look into this.
Okay. I will.
(MS Lions, SD Bears)
The chauffeur was telling the truth.
This is the guy.
So he was managing
Park Ye Young, right?
I'll get ready for work.
We're working late today.
We don't even have time
to prepare for it.
Strangely, this feels so real.
Let's get the gang, Chul Ki.
When they cross us,
we must teach them a lesson.
How do you want your hair done?
Wait. Step aside.
- Step back.
- Ma'am.
I'll be honest.
You know this isn't right.
You can't just join and leave
this industry as you please.
The big boss is asking for you.
You can get your haircut
some other day.
Come on, ma'am.
I can't breathe.
I want a nice haircut.
(Husband)
Hey, Prosecutor Jin.
(- Will you kiss me?
- I'm wearing sexy underwear.)
You're going to make
a hole in that paper.
Enough with your silence.
You need to start talking now.
This. What are you
going to do with this?
Should I fax this
to a tabloid agency now?
You see this girl?
She said she didn't know anything
about dating and was afraid.
After all that nonsense,
she was caught making out with a man!
- How much money do you want?
- Come on.
You need to make me an offer first.
How much are you willing to pay?
You.
What are you doing here?
The location tracking app
for couples.
Prosecutor Jin told me
to keep an eye on you.
Come on out. He wants to see you.
Gosh. Darn it.
- Who is she?
- No.
No. Just get to the point.
Money or your golden goose?
You have to choose one.
- Hurry up.
- Mr. Ko Joong Do.
I respect your choice
And I refuse your refusal
There's only one choice to make
The choice is up to you
You're working so hard
in the middle of the night.
Madame here says...
that she left something
in Mr. Yu Jin Cheol's office.
Can you open the door for us?
Excuse me, but who are you?
Her name is Viola Park.
She runs galleries
in Apgujeong and Cheongdam.
What's your relationship
with Mr. Yu?
It's private.
Do I need to explain more?
By the way,
why are you answering for her?
Let me make a call to check.
Jin Cheol is with his wife right now.
You might make him
feel uncomfortable if you call him.
But I still need to check.
It won't take long. Please wait.
(Security office)
This is Mr. Yu Jin Cheol's phone.
Who is this speaking?
I'm Mr. Yu's new secretary.
Who is this calling?
I see. I'm calling
from the security office.
I called because Mr. Yu has visitors.
A lady from a gallery is here
to take her belongings.
I called to check.
Mr. Yu.
He said you could let them in.
Driver Kim, you can stay here.
We came by taxi.
Why am I Driver Kim?
Driver Kim will wait here.
Thank you.
I'll help you find your belongings.
It's okay.
It would be faster
if two people looked for them.
Do you think you can handle it?
Pardon?
This is a private space
for Jin Cheol and me.
Come in if you want to lose your job.
Goodbye, ma'am.
Password.
(CEO Yu Jin Cheol)
Should I kill him?
"Z."
What?
Where's my phone?
My gosh.
What? Goodness.
What happened?
Darn it.
(User)
Find anything that's related
to a woman named Park Ye Young.
It could be pictures or videos.
I don't know.
(Joong Do's USB)
(Copy to Joong Do's USB)
(Copying 379 files
to Joong Do's USB)
How can I help you?
Jin Cheol's here, right?
Gosh.
Why doesn't he answer my calls?
He's not in his office at the moment.
I'll leave a message for him.
Can I have your name?
Viola Park.
Pardon?
I'm so annoyed already.
I can't believe this.
My name is Viola Park.
Park Viola in Korean.
I see.
You're Park Viola?
There's another Viola Park?
My goodness.
Do they have the same name?
Hey, you!
Hey. Stop right there.
Stop!
- Hello?
- What's going on out there?
I was so surprised. I almost died.
There's another Viola Park.
A woman with the same name.
What did you say?
I almost got caught.
I almost died, my goodness.
- What about me?
- What?
Didn't you come out with me?
Gosh, you didn't!
(Completed)
Don't move.
Viola Park?
- Viola?
- Hey, stop!
Let's go.
- Hello?
- Prosecutor Shin A Ra...
executed a search and seizure
on Yu Jin Cheol's office.
Okay.
Are you okay?
I don't think
we can do anything here today.
Viola Park. My gosh.
(Jinseung Electronics Market)
(Computer Doctor)
You're here.
Eun Ji. Joong Do.
It's been a while.
You didn't get into trouble, right?
Why would you say that?
I'd like to punch your face though.
You want to punch my face?
I only said that to myself.
Well, I heard it.
Go ahead, then. Punch me.
Prosecutor Jin, I think we have it.
(Seocho-dong Park Ye Young)
Open it.
(April 10, April 11, April 12)
(August 3, August 7,
August 10, August 12)
August 12?
That was the day she died.
(August 12)
This was it.
This was why Deputy Chief Lee
frantically wanted the case closed.
How dare you muddy up
our clean waters?
Is this about your nomination
as the district head prosecutor?
As of this moment,
you two are off this case.
I told you never to contact me.
The prosecution has been taking
a lot of interest in me lately.
I'll be needing your protection.
You ask boldly for someone
who should be begging.
Should there be a reason
for me to be groveling?
You of all people should know
what would happen to you...
if I chose to open my mouth.
You'll soon take office
as district head prosecutor.
If you don't want me
to be at your ceremony,
take action.
Soon-to-be district head prosecutor.
Locate Yu Jin Cheol right away.
And the flash drive?
(August 12)
- But...
- Let go.
Give it here.
It's all in here, right?
Of course.
(Summarized Indictment)
(Defendant: Ko Joong Do)
I'm finally getting rid of this.
This was a contract for slavery.
In no way am I a slave.
This isn't the Joseon Dynasty.
How many of these does he have left?
That would be 23.
Gosh, 23. That's a lot.
You piece of trash.
Hey.
What about Yu Jin Cheol?
I have him grounded.
Okay.
Darn it. Which punk did this?
What on earth?
Gosh.
Goodness.
Who could've been so mean?
Was it you?
Hop in.
I'll take you someplace nice.
What is this place?
The sign says it all.
It's the Civil Affairs Division.
Such a place exists.
Anyway,
you may be older than me,
but I don't see bad guys
as human beings.
So don't mind me speaking casually.
I looked into you.
Distribution of drugs,
money laundering,
sex trafficking, and tax evasion.
You led a busy life.
Good job, young man.
Where did you get this?
I hope for your sake
that it was a rhetorical question.
You're not in a position
to ask me that right now.
All these charges...
will mount up to at least ten years.
It's 2022,
so even if you get in fast enough,
you'll be out by 2032.
By then, cars will be flying,
and cyborgs will live among us.
What do you want?
Now we're finally talking.
The Seocho-dong murder case...
and Deputy Chief Lee Jang Won.
He was the last one
to meet the victim that day.
That makes him the prime suspect...
in her murder case.
An investigation into a deputy chief
who is currently in office...
can't be brought up
based on a photo like this.
We need something explosive
that'll justify the action.
Like a witness statement
from the man who took the photo.
(Statement of Facts)
Write down the nature
of his relationship with her.
Also, state what you saw and heard
on the day of the murder.
Grab your chance to escape
when it presents itself.
Why is there a need
to weigh your options?
Shouldn't you care about
saving yourself first?
Prosecutor Jin?
We have
a search and seizure warrant.
(Search and Seizure Warrant)
What are the charges?
Aggravated assault.
CEO Kim Hyung Gyun of Rich Fund
pressed charges against you.
You should've listened to me.
Execute the warrant.
On whose authority?
How dare you cause a scene
at this late hour.
Don't you know
that I rule this place?
What happens here
will be dealt with internally.
That's the rule I established
when I first took charge of this office.
It's the same with people.
Anyone who works here
is considered family,
and I won't let others
take my family away.
Now, get lost.
Sir.
We knew you'd come through for us.
Got it.
I hear such a rule doesn't exist.
Is that so?
Then there's nothing I can do.
What... What do you mean by that?
Get searching.
Shall we?
I found you to be violent as well.
Can you let me through? Gosh.
Yu Jin Cheol.
We'll soon see each other again.
Whatever.
I mean it.
I always catch who I'm after.
No matter what it takes.
Let's go.
Get Yu Jin Cheol to China.
Out of Tae Ho's and Jin Jung's reach.
Yes, sir.
Kim Tae Ho, you darn twerp.
Prosecutor Jin
had Yu Jin Cheol in custody...
but Prosecutor Oh had him released?
Prosecutor Oh is receiving orders
from Deputy Chief Lee.
What you said seemed to be right.
There is a connection...
between the deputy chief
and the owner of the hostess bar.
Why did Prosecutor Jin
go after Yu Jin Cheol though?
I don't think it was
to get him off the streets.
Jin Jung's after the deputy chief?
It seems like...
Prosecutor Jin is still looking into
the Seocho-dong murder.
I'll talk to him
once we wrap things up.
The details...
How dare you target someone
to build an investigation?
You think you call
the shots around here?
Your inauguration ceremony
is tomorrow.
I was going to report my findings
once I was done.
You must always have
the last word, don't you?
I've had enough of you
looking down on me.
As if I wouldn't know...
why you're looking into Yu Jin Cheol.
Just you wait and see.
Once I'm the district head prosecutor,
you will be the first one I get rid of.
I shouldn't have let you see that.
Forget it ever happened.
(Interrogation Room)
I apologize, Prosecutor Shin,
but Prosecutor Oh said
not to let just anyone in.
Do I seem like just "anyone" to you?
I'll ask you once again nicely.
Move.
I'll cut right to the chase.
Let's go after
Deputy Chief Lee together.
Promise me that you will help
me and Senior Prosecutor Kim.
Then I'll help you
get out of here now.
Then let's make one thing clear.
That we will do everything my way
starting now.
I'm in.
Gosh.
(Prosecutor Oh Do Hwan)
- Hello.
- You can leave now.
And I need to check something.
But play it cool.
Darn it.
What's wrong?
- You can't breathe?
- No.
Why can't you breathe?
You can't breathe? What's wrong?
(Emergency staircase)
I think I'm okay now. I feel better.
You saved my life. Seriously.
Thank you.
Shouldn't you go see a doctor?
I finally understand...
why you arrested Yu Jin Cheol.
What's the point of going through
all that trouble to arrest him?
They cut him loose right away.
Now that Yu Jin Cheol is exposed,
Deputy Chief Lee
won't just sit back and watch.
He will try to bury the case...
and ship Yu Jin Cheol
out of the country.
Don't even think about getting help
from the police.
Who's going to disobey him?
He'll be the district head tomorrow.
Okay. Let's make a call first.
A call?
There's no point in wasting time.
Let's catch him now.
- Hey, Prosecutor Jin.
- Hey.
I'm on my way. Get him.
- Let's go.
- Now?
(Motel Uraejang)
You had him followed?
Hey, that's against...
Don't be so unreasonable.
We just started.
You agreed to let me do it my way.
I knew it.
You and I will never see eye to eye.
We'll see eye to eye
if we face each other.
But let's look straight for now.
(Descending life line)
(Uraejang Bathhouse)
Gosh. What do we do?
So he already got away?
Hello?
What? Yes.
I think he figured out
that we were tailing him.
I found this in the microwave.
I didn't find anything else.
He suddenly became so meticulous.
It was Oh Do Hwan.
Someone had to handle him
until he left the country.
Searching for the target now.
By the way, who are they?
I'll explain later.
- Let's go with plan B.
- We have plan B?
The target has entered
Gyeongin Expressway.
Yu Jin Cheol.
We'll soon see each other again.
If you were going
to track him with that,
why did you make us tail him?
If he's on Gyeongin Expressway,
he's heading to Incheon.
(Gyeongin Expressway)
If he continues on this road...
Yeonan Pier.
He's going to stow away on a ship.
I need you two to run
forensic analysis on the phone.
Call me if you find anything useful.
It's already fried.
That's not possible.
- I'll deduct two.
- Four!
Two is fine.
- Where is he?
- That way.
What is this? He's not even here.
He's definitely here.
The target began to move.
(Yeonin Fishery)
- It's the truck.
- What?
- Darn it. Wait!
- Stop!
What's going on?
Let me check the vehicle.
What? He's not there?
What are you doing? Gosh.
What's this?
Come on. Darn it.
(Yeonin Fishery)
I'll call you right away...
once Deputy Chief Lee
becomes the district head.
You must keep a low profile
until then.
Listen.
Why must I leave the country?
How can I trust you guys?
I need to talk to him directly.
Turn the car around.
I told you to turn
the car around, you jerk!
You little... Hey!
Listen to me carefully, Mr. Yu.
We're not doing this
for Deputy Chief Lee's sake.
We're doing this for you.
I couldn't care less
about your relationship with him.
But if I turn the car around now,
you will be heading...
to prison.
Gosh. I'm too chatty, aren't I?
I'll get going now.
I'm certain we're missing something.
What could that be?
What do you think
about asking for help?
Do you want me to put out an APB?
I doubt Deputy Chief Lee
will just let me do that.
I need a warrant first
to put out an APB.
Right. The APB.
Not you too.
We'll never get a warrant for this.
Exactly.
Since we can't get a warrant,
he's not even on the wanted list.
Why stow away out of the country?
Yu Jin Cheol doesn't have to leave
because he's not the suspect.
No one but us knows
that he's connected...
to Park Ye Young's murder.
If he's not going to stow away...
Text messages or records.
I don't care what it is.
Prioritize anything
relevant to the airport.
Hurry up. I'm getting anxious here.
Gosh. I'm doing the best I can
to restore this phone.
Just give me some time
to do my thing.
I got it.
Hey!
My goodness.
It's a 10 p.m. flight to Shanghai.
The flight to Shanghai
is boarding now.
(9:42 p.m., Wednesday, September 14)
- Your ticket is checked.
- Thank you.
- Hello.
- Hello. Welcome.
- You can go inside.
- Hello.
- Hello. Please show your ticket.
- You can go this way.
- Thank you.
- You should go in and turn right.
Good job.
It's a 10 p.m. flight to Shanghai.
Check the boarding list
and check Yu Jin Cheol's location.
He's a prime witness
to a murder case.
Even if you tell us to do that,
we have no right to stop the flight.
It's not like he's under
the prohibition of departure.
Sir, I'm Prosecutor Shin A Ra...
from the Seoul Central District
Prosecutors' Office.
We have a situation.
Can't you help us out this one time?
Well, then...
Send me the warrant via fax.
We don't have time for that.
I'm busy, so I'll hang up now.
Wait, sir. Hey!
(9:52 p.m., Wednesday, September 14)
(9:53 p.m., Wednesday, September 14)
Please put your luggage
in the overhead compartment.
Would you please put the table back
in its place?
(International Departures)
(10:20 p.m., Shanghai)
Did the flight to Shanghai
leaving at 10 p.m. take off?
Please check Flight JZ1852.
They said the plane was moving
to the runway now.
Let's go back.
It's over.
It's not a taxi.
How are you going to stop a plane?
He took off. It's over.
Let's go.
No, there's still a way.
We'll do something crazy.
(Airport Information)
Hello, this is the information desk.
How can help you?
I put a bomb on a plane.
Pardon?
Can you repeat that?
The flight to Shanghai
that leaves at 10 p.m.
There's a bomb on that plane.
Stop the plane.
Or you'll see a pool of blood
at this airport.
Hello?
Call security.
Goodness. What have you done?
Why would you even ask?
I don't know either.
Let's go.
- Hey.
- What?
Stop Flight JZ1852 this instant.
Here's an announcement.
Our flight, JZ1852, is...
going back to the airport...
- due to security reasons.
- What?
Please follow the instructions...
- directed by the crew members...
- What's going on?
- and stay seated for a moment.
- Excuse me.
Here's an announcement.
Due to security reasons,
all flights will be delayed.
As soon as the problem is solved,
we will help you board your flight.
- We'd like to thank...
- It's been delayed.
all of you who visited the airport
for your cooperation.
(All flights are delayed
at the moment.)
Here's an announcement again.
Due to security reasons,
all flights will be delayed.
As soon as the problem is solved,
we will help you board your flight.
We'd like to thank...
How do I board my flight?
- I mean...
- How long do we have to wait?
- Bring the person in charge.
- Please wait, sir.
- What's going on?
- I'm sorry.
Thank you for your cooperation.
- What's going on?
- What?
Let's go.
(International Arrivals)
- What's going on?
- We're here to search the plane.
Please follow our directions
and calmly evacuate the plane.
Everyone will get off the plane.
What are they doing?
- It's going to take an hour?
- My goodness.
(Passage for the employees
of the airlines)
- What if there really is...
- We need to know about it.
a bomb on the plane?
My goodness.
- Is this really happening?
- Why aren't they coming?
- What's going on? Tell us.
- So...
they will come out this way, right?
The passengers from the plane.
They need some time
to look for the bomb.
Look at his face.
He doesn't realize
what he just caused.
He'll have a plan.
I think.
I really hope so.
Otherwise, we're going down together.
He's over there.
Yu Jin Cheol!
Darn it.
Move!
- Gosh.
- Goodness. Move.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
- What are you doing?
- Excuse me. I'm sorry.
- Excuse me.
- I'm sorry.
Excuse me.
Where is he?
Yes, Prosecutor Jin.
Yu Jin Cheol is gone. Find him.
Yes, sir.
Darn it.
Stop!
Hey!
What?
- What's going on?
- Don't follow me.
- Goodness.
- Hey!
- My goodness.
- Are you okay?
Darn it.
Move!
He's going down. Hurry!
Yu Jin Cheol!
- Who's that?
- Yu Jin Cheol!
Who are you?
Give me a break.
Unbelievable.
Come here.
Don't come near me.
Don't come any closer.
Hey.
It's not going to change anything.
It's over now.
I'm not joking.
I'll really kill her.
I'll kill her!
Don't come any closer.
You'll be in trouble
if you keep doing this.
Don't come near me.
He's really mad right now.
You don't want to get caught
that easily, right?
Let's have one round then.
All right. You're dead.
You punk...
Why you...
Get over here.
Take that.
This way.
Darn it.
The last four digits
of your phone number are 0070,
isn't it?
You have impeccable timing.
I'm afraid you'll have
to come with us.
What on earth is going on?
Handle him.
No, you have the wrong guy.
What are they doing?
- This is the guy.
- Come on.
- Wasn't it him?
- No way.
(Seoul Central District
Prosecutors' Office)
Where's Yu Jin Cheol?
He disappeared from the airport.
And Prosecutor Jin?
Get the door.
He is being held by airport security.
That crazy brat.
And he calls himself a prosecutor?
I'll get hold of Yu Jin Cheol
as soon as possible.
You do that.
And...
make sure that tomorrow's
inauguration ceremony...
goes smoothly.
Yes, sir.
Congratulations,
District Head Prosecutor Lee.
(District Head Prosecutor Lee,
congratulations on your promotion.)
(Seoul Central District
Prosecutors' Office)
(Prosecution Service)
(Ministry of Justice)
(The 63rd District Head Prosecutor
Lee Jang Won...)
(of the Seoul Southern District
Prosecutors' Office)
(Inauguration Ceremony)
(The 63rd District Head Prosecutor
Lee Jang Won...)
The 63rd District Head Prosecutor
Lee Jang Won...
of the Seoul Southern District
Prosecutors' Office...
will deliver his inauguration speech.
Please give him
a warm round of applause.
(The 63rd District Head Prosecutor
Lee Jang Won...)
(of the Seoul Southern District
Prosecutors' Office)
(The 63rd District Head Prosecutor
Lee Jang Won...)
(of the Seoul Southern District
Prosecutors' Office)
My family at the prosecutors' office,
I stand before you today...
as the newly appointed
district head prosecutor...
of the Seoul Southern District
Prosecutors' Office.
And this is what I promise you.
From here on out, we...
We, the prosecution,
will be trusted by the people.
Rather than giving in to power,
we will fight against it if we must.
Our goal is to be
honest and incorruptible,
and...
What on earth just happened?
- What was that about?
- What's going on?
I got the cramps
from being crammed in that space.
Can you stay right there?
- Why that...
- Mic check.
Hello, reporters
and fellow prosecutors.
I'm Jin Jung.
I address you here
at the ceremony...
to tell you...
that the prosecutors' office
is more rotten...
than you believe it to be.
- What?
- What is he saying?
- Are you out of your mind?
- Come on.
Evidence that'd prove
a man's innocence was destroyed,
cases were fabricated,
and then they were closed.
What I stated didn't happen elsewhere.
Right here.
It was done at this office known as...
the nation's top
law enforcement agency.
- What?
- Is that true?
Now, watch what happens next.
What do you think you're doing?
I'll show you what I'm getting at.
Lee Jang Won,
you are under arrest...
as the prime suspect
in the Seocho-dong murder case.
- What?
- What on earth?
- What did he just say?
- No way!
- Are you kidding me?
- What is he doing?
- Can you believe it?
- Is he insane?
Congratulations
on your life being over.
Ripped and resynced by YoungJedi
(Bad Prosecutor)
Arrest Prosecutor Jin.
- I'll be in charge of his case.
- There's no need for that.
I heard Prosecutor Kim
pulled strings for me.
It was to get rid of the cancer
poisoning this office.
Get rid of Prosecutor Jin.
- Drop your weapon.
- Yu Jin Cheol's gone.
I had no choice
but to give a false statement.
We're going after
Deputy Chief Lee's flash drive.
If things go south,
we'll be sentenced to
at least five years in prison.
What's life without a little risk?
Let's go and get the bad guy.
Only a nutcase would think to steal
from the deputy chief's office.
The world's dirty enough,
and it needs
at least one person like me.
(Subtitles are provided by KOCOWA.)