Well.
I'm simply making the point that I didn't
care that well aware of that.
But perhaps you misjudged him.
To you,
he is every bit the principal described.
We're all entitled to our opinions.
You insist on this challenge, Mr..
The least you can do is convince
a tsunami access the military.
Firstly, we are merely friends.
Secondly,
if we're more than that which we are not.
I couldn't possibly ask Barnabas
to change his rules.
Some of us have shopping to do,
but the market is that way.
I'm going to head office
and Hanwell Street trying new hat.
Let me guess.
Does this have anything to do
with a certain Barnabas?
I don't have time for this.
You seeing him today?
Goodbye, Lizzie.
Yes. What is it?
I have
that information on the lady
detective, sir.
No, the Scarlet.
Mr. Doyle, assistant to Dr. Flint.
My employer had hoped
that you might grant us to meet her.
Dr. Flint would like to.
Hi on a rather sensitive issue.
But I up to the job, young lady.
I can assure you
I've had many satisfied clients.
By the looks of you.
Well, when would see you fall over?
We received this anonymous letter.
It advised that a bottle of our elixir
had been poisoned
and placed on the shelf
of one of our market stalls.
We had it tested, and indeed it does
contain a toxin derived from a plant
known as the Angel of Infernal.
£1,000 to be left to St Pancras Station.
If it is not forthcoming, the money
demanded would increase in a second.
Poisoning will occur.
This is day two, several days ago.
The deadline has passed.
Why didn't you engage me sooner?
We wish to keep it from public knowledge.
As such, you will have to sign
a confidentiality agreement.
Oh. Well, I'll have to read it
thoroughly first.
Do you want this case or not, young lady?
My name is Miss Scarlet.
If I'm to be your client, I shall call it
whatever I damn well please.
I'm sorry.
I'm extremely busy
with other cases at the moment.
So in regards to you, please,
I will, of course, find time to take it.
Where do I sign?
You just sit there.
I am the very.
Modern.
Collection.
Vegetable, vegetable and mineral.
I knew the kings of England unequipped
to fight.
Just protocol from marathon to Waterloo
in order to stop the article.
I'm very good at integrals,
differential calculus.
I know the scientific names of beings,
animal killers in.
Short matters vegetable.
Animal and mineral.
I am the very model of a modern meat. You.
Hello, Father.
I thought it impossible
that you could disappoint me any further,
but clearly I was wrong.
I'm glad.
Your mother isn't alive to. See this.
You're officially a police detective.
Oh, a flying fox,
for example.
Where's Inspector Wellington?
Can I help you, sir?
You were meant to teach my son
to be a detective.
Yet now I find him filing here
like some junior clerk.
I can explain, sir.
Your son is an extremely proficient
police officer.
However, he has been in the force
for barely half a year,
and entering it detective level
means he still has a great deal to learn.
My son requests this position.
No, sir.
I took the decision
to put my own administration justice,
since I felt it imperative that he acquire
the knowledge from the ground up.
Listen carefully, Inspector Warrington,
because I'm going to tell you
exactly what he's going to happen here.
Fitzroy will be
reinstated as a police detective
with immediate effect.
The feeble, insubstantial character
that has blighted him
since birth will be knocked out of him
and he will be turned into a man
that his family can finally be proud of.
Police Commissioners Words are not mine.
He's insisting that Fitzroy make inspector
by the end of the year.
Police Commissioner.
Who gets the Police Commissioner at once?
Become serious, sir.
My job is to ensure the effective
running of this constabulary.
Of my kindness.
Financial planning.
The last few months
I've been petitioning the Commissioner
to push the Home Office to review budgets.
This city has grown with eight extra
miles of new residential streets
to patrol and Tottenham alone.
Surely the fate of a son
is entirely separate matter.
So you have a lot to learn
if you think that is the case.
Fitzroy is a sort of a
decent young man, but he's no detective,
let alone suspect material.
The streets are getting
more violent year on year
and if he is placed back in action,
he will not only put his own life at risk,
but my men to
take us here.
You and I have been odds recently.
However,
in this instance, there is nothing
you have said that I do not concur with.
But be that as it may, I'm afraid
we have no choice in the matter.
Which is why I've made a decision.
So Fitzroy will be.
Taken from your command
and placed under Detective Phelps.
Phelps? He's the last.
But in that case, please give up or die
trying.
And I am sure his family
will receive a medal with him.
Sure will go down well with his father.
Listen to me, lady.
You. You've got a good future
ahead of you.
Fitzroy
will only block in your reputation.
Is that what you want?
Of course not so good.
And he will transfer to Detective Phelps
with immediate effect.
And that is an order?
Yes. Sir.
Good afternoon, Mr.
Scott.
I was in need of your advice.
I question the poisonous properties
of a particular plant.
Mr. Cole, my break is over,
and I must return to my duties.
I cannot wait to hear on the street
discussing botany with you.
I quite understand.
So perhaps I should come inside.
British Library.
To me, a ten minute stroll
from this very spot.
I'm sure you'll find the answer
to all manner of questions
within its hallowed walls.
If you'll excuse me.
I was asking after you this morning.
Yes. I have, of course,
gave a very agreeable account of you.
How can you continue to do so?
What are you saying exactly?
You scratch my back
and I'll scratch yours.
Now, you two should not say
such unseemly things.
It is not. Christian.
If you help me,
I will continue to sing your praises.
But that is blackmail.
That is business.
So do we have a deal?
He's a man.
He seems to be watching you.
We got Mr.
Barnes
ciphers siphons.
Come to God.
It's your father's handiwork.
I see. Of, sir.
I'd like to convey how much I'm looking
forward to coming back to the field.
But I think there's been some mistake.
I've been told to report
to Detective Phelps.
No mistake.
But Detective Phelps loathes me.
He thinks I'm just some spoiled toff
born with a silver spoon in my mouth.
Detective Phelps is a very good officer.
He's a thug.
Detective Phelps, as your superior,
and you will show respect.
As I understood. Yes, sir.
Not if there's nothing else.
I just.
I don't understand
why I can't stand your command.
You somehow suggesting
that I'll give you an easier time?
Of course not.
So good.
I'll get back to work.
Yes, sir.
Why are you following me?
I long to meet the lady detective.
It's Patrick Marsh. Right.
Then I'll ask you instead
by following me.
Now, when I first heard about you,
Scarlett, I assumed
being a detective was a mere hobby.
You might find the odd rich lady's
missing poodle that you'd soon tired.
In fact, my men were so amused by the idea
of a female detective,
they took bets on how long you'd last.
But weeks went by.
And months you still in the game
and somehow you became less amusing.
What do you want?
You are determined, ambitious,
hungry.
The Holy Trinity.
In short, I want you to come work for me.
She was talking into my office,
took turns.
I've heard of your agency, Mr.
Nash, and the means
by which you and your men investigate.
I hear blackmail is your favorite tool.
Sure.
You know better than to listen to rumors.
Thank you for your offer, but no,
thank you.
The police call off your dogs.
It is a shame.
Since we are kindred spirits.
As an Irishman,
I know what it is to face prejudice.
I can assure you
we have nothing in common.
That's not strictly true.
In the defense case, for one,
there is a reason why you were brought
onto this case so late in the day.
Dr. Flint came to see me first,
but I was too expensive.
Of course. So we went to see Dillon's son.
But they were also too
costly for the old miner.
So we went around the city,
but to no avail, until he found someone
with the lowest fees in London.
You. You're selling yourself short.
Would I charges no business of yours?
It is when I have to undercut you.
I'll be sending one to amend.
Little to think. Now I've changed my mind.
You can have my services for free now.
Unless, of course.
You wish to reconsider my offer.
On that case.
May the best man win.
I look forward to it, Miss Scarlett.
I do love a challenge.
The Royal Botanical Society is
always happy to welcome the new members.
Ms.. Belfry.
That is music to my ears, Mr. Humphreys.
I'm only an amateur enthusiast,
but I do love to be close to nature.
Yeah. Oh, hi.
What a lovely shrub.
Oh, that's his new shrub, Miss Belfry.
That is a
Osmond.
Regardless, to be precise.
How I do have to be corrected, Mr.
Humphreys.
In fact,
perhaps you might give me
your expert advice on another plant,
the Angel of Inferno and its poisonous
properties and exotic location
have quite captured my imagination.
As you have captured mine, my dear.
And please correct me if I'm wrong,
but did I read that it not only grows
on the volcanic slopes of Guatemala,
but also here in society?
Indeed, we do have the plant.
However, due to its toxic capabilities,
it is kept in a section for members only.
And at present
you are not a member.
I could add your name to our waiting list.
Oh, a very long waiting list.
Or perhaps as curator,
I may be able to move your name
to the top.
This kind, Mr. Humphreys.
But might
I have a little put your membership
list first.
As an unmarried lady, it's imperative
I associate with only the right.
Sort of course.
I have the list in my office.
However,
I am overdue for my next appointment.
So perhaps you could
come back tomorrow.
Oh, I do love roses.
Oh, my goodness.
You seem to be my.
I dear Miss Belfry.
Ill fitting famous Humphreys.
Might I attend to my injury
in the privacy of your office?
My appointment can wait
alone.
So I do not need your help, Mr.
Humphreys.
Nor would I be free to give it to you
at this precise moment.
Spell for you.
See, the police are here and require
my assistance on an urgent matter.
Membership list, Mr.
Humphreys. Of course. Inspector Bates
spoke to Bates.
He say
I want acquainted with the officers
at Scotland Yard,
but have not had mentioned to you before.
You are well acquainted with Scotland
Yard.
Well, Crusty madam,
you don't look like a lawbreaker to me.
How exactly are you acquainted,
Miss Palfrey?
My uncle works for the Home Office.
Oh, many friends in that department.
Well, shouldn't it, Mr.
Fenchurch?
Oh, yes, Mr. Fenchurch.
On a number of occasions, just to shine,
a woman's reputation can be lost forever.
But why?
So many of his colleagues have frequented
that particular East End brothel?
It's just unfortunate
that he was caught. Hmm.
I don't wish to be rude, Mr.
Humphreys,
but this is a confidential matter.
Absolutely, Inspector.
If you don't mind, Mr.
Palfrey.
Well, even a better idea than I have.
Doubtless, because he was.
I didn't see him.
Action, son.
The man has a.
Sons, a liar and a crook.
As a means of investigation.
In order to.
For the Metropolitan Police
use them against results.
More questions asked.
Well, he's undercutting me with a client.
Client
who sees himself as a very unpleasant man.
So if you have some pleasant company,
then you come to the wrong place
at a horrible day.
Every man I've had to do with
has been detestable.
I've got to drop by.
I'm glad you did, too.
The fact is this Nash has ten times
my resources, and I need your help.
Unless my world doesn't revolve around
you, I have my own problems.
I'm trying to hunt down a blackmailer.
If I don't,
another bottle of this will be poisoned.
Well, worst natural in the case.
Nash.
Winning the case is worse
than a member of the public dying.
Don't use my words.
I didn't realize this is serious.
And then please be informed.
No, it's highly confidential.
Not when there's a threat to life.
It isn't.
But I signed a confidentiality agreement.
You think that I want or need more cases.
But as an officer of the law,
when there is a danger
to the general public,
then the police must investigate.
Fine.
I need time to write up my notes.
I'll bring you what I have
by the end of the day.
I don't know.
Look what the look that is covering
a multitude of calculations
that are currently racing through your.
Had no idea what you're
talking about, William.
Of course you don't.
End of the day, Eliza.
You should have a proper dinner at home
this evening.
Eating supper at your desk is not right.
I don't know what your father would say.
Actually,
I do know what your fathers say. Dan.
Father Ivy.
She doesn't listen anyway.
What exactly are you looking for?
Whoever this poisoner is,
they had access to the botanical society.
It's the only place
other than Guatemala
that grows this angel of Inferno.
I've tried to establish
who the members are,
but as yet have only found a few of those.
I can find
absolutely no connection to Dr. Flint.
Shouldn't
you be on your way to Scotland Yard by now
for a chance
to show your findings with respect to.
Well, I will.
But I have until the end of the day,
determined to find some leads first.
Scotland Yard cracked this case.
I wanted to get some credit. Moreover,
I just didn't want Nash to win.
Well, can't you get my sister to help you?
Well, I would if I knew where he was.
Why does he disappeared then?
Not to ask.
I saw Mr.
Potts earlier.
He said he liked to.
And you had to do so.
You didn't see him today?
I left this stuff.
Used to for use, really?
As a cure for everything.
Coughs and clothes, a better kitted out,
stubborn stains than any soap can,
I can assure you, Dr. Flint is no doctor.
Nor is this
elixir anything other than flavored water.
Silicone.
Excuse me,
but I remember a certain young lady
used to love it as a girl,
but that they needed a different name.
Flint and Doyle's magic medicine.
In fact, sometimes I think
you pretended to have a sore throat
just so I could give you a spoonful.
Did you just say Flint and Doyle.
For one reason, to breathe out
to, like, the sound of that water?
There is a crackle.
On your chest, Cedric.
What have I told you about going out
without a blanket?
I told him many times, Doctor Stan.
Hoped that he should get a new carriage
with him to stoke faster
than the nearest child, the sculptor.
Please forgive the unexpected visit,
but I was hoping to have a private word
with Mr.
Doyle.
You have two surgeries to do.
I can say to me.
Your unwillingness to share your findings
suggest you have made no move.
No matter since.
Now I have an additional agency
looking for me.
Yes, I'm aware of that national sense.
Not that he has any sense.
They are confident that they will have
the blackmailer in custody
by this time tomorrow. Come along
now, please.
Cedric, come to.
My practice
so I can drop you at home on the way.
You wish to speak to me?
Please?
I'm the remedy you manufacture.
At one time,
it had a slightly different name.
Flint and Doyle's magic medicine.
My father met Dr.
Flint when he went to India looking
for ingredients for a health remedy.
They became partners
and my father moved over here.
Nobody would have bought a product
called Flint and Mahajan.
So my father changed his name to Doyle.
I know all too well that dilemma.
It's still my
father's name that hangs outside
my office.
They built the business together.
And then when my father died. Dr.
Flint took his name off the product.
Surely such an action
would cause some resentment.
The Flint has been a good employer to me.
And if I am under suspicion.
Then you're mistaken.
I have to consider all possibilities, Mr.
Doyle.
If you will excuse me, I have work to. Do.
As you wish.
I do apologize.
My past.
You still know my past faith.
What are you talking about?
She's taken my purse.
I've done no such thing.
I saw.
But take it and put it in her pocket.
That particulars?
Yeah. She has it, you see.
Come with me, madam.
It was me who took it.
Inspector Wellington.
And nice to see you.
Riding in for a laser.
She's not our office.
Oh, well,
she's not here either, I'm afraid.
Would you like to leave a message?
She was meant to
deliver some information to me,
but it seems to have slipped from mine.
Two men. Have I come in? Wait.
I was just about to have dinner.
Oh. Oh, not the most welcome, gingerbread.
An intention of bringing me that file?
None whatsoever.
She's not up for anything
other than her own gain.
Well,
that's a little bit Inspector Wellington.
Yes. As a force.
But she's just trying
to make her way in. Life
will be missed, boss.
I think you Miss Watson.
Inspector.
I think you should agree with me.
Don't use the past.
Of course. Remaining a headache.
You seem impossible.
You can be
sure those weren't my exact words.
No, your exact words were impossible,
untrustworthy, uncrossed.
Miss Scott, it can be somewhat
single minded, but I think what Ms..
Would is scientists also have some truth
is, scarlet is a woman trying
to build a business in a world
usually the preserve of a man.
Come on in.
You know the.
Deficit is low.
If anything, I admire her fortitude.
Now you've changed your tune.
I remember you saying.
What this really is.
Did you know the painter for.
But don't think so.
I'm pretty moist.
It's a pleasure to cook food. It
should have a
damn good explanation
when I catch up with.
Food to go.
I had no idea you were down here
all night.
I'll be sure to mention that Inspector
Wellington, when I thank him
for bailing me.
Frozen in the bail jar.
Because someone's got Mr. So stupid.
My dear Mr.
Carlos, what a pleasure it is to be once
again in your convivial company.
Likewise, Mr. Sinclair.
You are the reason for my bail.
Indeed I am.
And I'm quite certain
that a woman with such an inquiring mind
must have many questions
as to why Basil Sinclair
would do such a thing.
Allow me to explain, my dear.
The simple fact is that whenever
you have a featured
in my publication,
it has sold exponentially.
And as chief correspondent
of the Illustrated Police News,
it would be remiss of me not to pursue
the further adventures of the
Lady Detective.
You want to write a story about me?
My dear Miss Scarlet, if you wish to call
your latest investigation of Mr.
Ray, that is your prerogative.
I myself would rather an intoxicating
blend of blackmail, poison and witchcraft.
My investigation is highly confidential,
but I can confirm
there's no witchcraft involved.
As a steward of the people,
it would be cruel of me.
Deprive them of my tales
of this great city of ours.
Do I make myself quite clear? No.
I will write this article
with or without your cooperation.
And either you will be my heroine or Mr.
Nash will be my hero.
The choice, as they say,
is yours.
This is blackmail.
This is business.
Oh, yes.
I recall Mr.
Watkins outside.
I'll be out in a minute. Mr. Price.
All I want you to take much.
Longer, and I'll give myself that night.
I want a scalp. That is right.
Generate on the Cooper mole.
That's the plan.
If there's more, I'm with Aria.
So to Fitzroy's to come with me.
A case has just come up
and I think there's help
for the governor, said the new governor.
I'm telling you that Fitzroy is with me.
That's true.
Thank you, sir.
That's not what you're talking about.
Come along.
I assume this visit is confirmation
of your desire
to become a member of this belfry.
Although I am rather
concerned regarding this
wayward uncle of yours in the Home Office.
Since the scandal,
my family have cut ties.
Well, in that case, I would be honored
to brief you on every detail.
However, you might remember my mention
of a rather long waiting list, sir.
Perhaps dinner to discuss
moving your name to the top.
Oh, that would have been delightful.
However, I find myself
somewhat under the weather.
My over enthusiasm with the roses.
Yesterday,
my little break has become infected.
My dear Miss Belfry, it's nothing.
Just some foul smelling pus.
Extremely frustrating,
as it also prevented me
from attending your lecture last night.
Well.
It's more of a book launch.
The Village Trust was selling
their new publication to raise funds.
That's a very good cause.
Medicine for the poor.
That book has a chapter
on your Angel of Inferno.
Apparently, the toxin derived from
the leaves has a luminous quality.
A cloud that glows in the dark.
Extraordinary.
May I buy a copy of the book?
Oh, that nice police inspector
who you met in my office.
He attended the launch.
He bought the last copy.
Did he find what he was looking for
in your membership list?
I have no idea.
The confidential case, apparently.
But he did say
he was close to making an arrest.
This book, what is it called?
Here is a copy of the advertisement
from last night's launch.
You'll find the book in any good bookshop.
Kilo cure
the poisonous properties of plants.
Now to the other matter.
Dinner.
Let me just find my diary.
Shall we say
Monday?
Which should give your infection
time to heal?
Here we are. So,
Miss Belfry.
Before you start huffing and puffing.
Firstly, I need a cough. No cough.
Secondly, I have no inclination to be like
two again.
I want that case file.
I would have given it to you last night
had I not been arrested on some trumped up
charge made by Nash.
I spent the night in a cell. And yes,
I have been released 4 hours.
And I could have brought it to you.
But I'm professional, William.
And I wanted one last crack
at finding lead.
That I am.
What's he doing as a cheat in a good job?
Well, you never actually said to me.
I've said that to you many times.
Not nearly
enough. Here, have the damn case.
I'm at a dead end anyway,
which I'm sure will an easy.
This issue on in professionalism.
I apologize.
I have had a very trying few days,
but I meant what I said.
I delayed handing in the case because
I do want you to think well of my skills.
Fine.
Come on. Well, am I good?
At least getting the credit to know
that this is bastard one objective.
Only to induce guilt so that I would
consent to you working case with me.
But is unfounded. Unfair?
Absolutely not true.
Just stop talking and bring the file.
For the last year, Dr.
Flint has been looking for land
to build an additional factory.
He found some cheap
wasteland in the East End, but it had
already been earmarked by a charity.
They were going to build a hospital
for the poor.
But Flint outbid them
and bought the land instead.
This is good work.
Indeed, Detective.
This charity would be called the Village
Trust by any chance.
The very one
list of members of this Village Trust.
Yes, sir.
Sir. Mr.
Doyle attends the fundraiser
for the Welsh Trust book,
which means he must support their cause.
Medicine for the poor.
And the same
which trust was the benevolent
association of Flint to build a hospital.
Until Flint stole the land.
Mr. Doyle
was also personally betrayed by Flint
when his father's name was taken off.
The remedy.
He should have bee upon it,
but instead is just a lowly assistant.
It sounds like we've
got our man, Mr.
Doyle.
Still breathing.
Just you
doing?
He's been poisoned.
How does how chauvinist.
I received this
same envelope.
Same typeface
from the blackmailer.
I could have told you that.
What does it say?
I haven't opened it
because I do not care what it says.
Whoever is doing this
is taking the only thing I care about.
He is the closest thing to a soap.
Cedric Nichols is a strong young man.
He will receive the best care here.
Understand her?
How is Mr.
Doyle really?
Extremely poorly.
If it was the kind of souls
Nicholas Doyle.
Thought of himself.
You speak of the Batman.
Really?
Dr. Flint should pay the money.
Demanded to stop this madness. Yes.
£2,000 is nothing to him.
My belief is he could be next to me.
Excuse me.
I must confer with the doctors here.
Fitzroy's made a list
of all the members of the wolves trust.
I don't need to see that sort of.
I know the that matters.
The curator
at the Royal Botanical Society.
Mr. Humphreys.
He had access to the poisonous plant.
The ancient invader.
And the poisons.
Luminous, you said? Indeed.
And this second blackmail letter
you mentioned.
But this is still sealed.
Oh, well,
I thought it would enhance your story, Mr.
Sinclair.
The lady detective
so saw of the blackmailer.
She had no need to open the second letter.
Bravo, Miss Scarlett.
I do believe you have missed your calling.
You are a natural when it comes to the art
of spinning a story.
Almost as good as myself.
That is high praise, indeed.
Even the chief correspondent himself.
Oh, yes.
Just as I thought.
You see, Mr. Sinclair,
letter X has a distinctive, faulty
mark in both.
Just like the first blackmail letter.
Which means they were all typed
from the same typewriter.
Curator's typewriter? Precisely.
So this
Humphreys had access to the poison
and to the typewriter that wrote
both of the blackmail letters.
And he was also a member
of the footage Trust.
They had a cheap plan to build a hospital,
but Dr.
Flint outbid them.
He bought the land for himself
to build a new factory instead.
This extortion was an act of revenge.
No witchcraft there?
No, I'm afraid not.
Although
the luminous quality of the poison
had a touch of black magic, does it not?
Indeed.
I'm meeting is about to enter in precisely
one hour at the Botanical Society
when Mr. Humphreys will be arrest.
I assume you'd like to attend.
So you see, Dr.
Flint, my evidence points
quite firmly to Mr.
Humphreys here.
Well, that's counter, Lieutenant.
I am no blackmailer. I'm a scholar.
I was just explained to my client,
Dr. Flint, how he deduced Mr.
Humphreys was the culprit.
You make sure you put our contact details
in your piece.
Sinclair will wish to pass up
an opportunity for promotion.
You were under the pay of Nash all along.
Mr. Nash,
as one of our most generous advertisers.
We must have our patrons where we can.
And sharing
my evidence is just the ticket.
That's a tad ungrateful, Miss Scarlett.
Without my bill,
you'd still be in a police cell.
You're
the reason I was there in the first place.
Why do you keep calling her Miss Scarlet?
This is Miss Belfry.
The lady that wished to join the society.
Because just as I am no police inspector.
Mr. Humphreys, this is no lady.
She is a private detective.
Impressive. Is she not
well?
I'd love to stay and chat,
but I'm afraid
I really must get on.
Let's take him down to Scotland Yard.
Please. Please.
There's been a terrible mistake.
Dr. Flint.
I knew Mr.
Sinclair was double crossing me.
That's why I lied to him to mislead Nash.
Mr. Humphreys is not your blacksmith.
But the typewriter.
That particular make the Remington first
edition has a common fault
with this letter X.
If Humphreys is not the blackmailer,
then who is?
Hey, mister.
How could you do this to me?
We're going to build a hospital.
A place where the poor
could finally be nursed and looked after.
We've spent years
fundraising to buy that piece of land
somewhere we could finally afford.
Then you come along and take it from us
because it was cheap.
Cheap, heliocentric.
The money Dr.
Stanhope demanded
was to be funneled back into the charity.
As recompense for what they paid out
in planning permission
and architect's drawings over the years,
but also have gone some way
to finding another site for the hospital.
How did you know it was him?
Well, he knew the increased amount
the blackmailer was demanding
without having seen the letter
sealed until I opened it in my office.
And contrary to what I told Mr.
Sinclair, Mr.
Humphries is not a member of the witness
trust.
But Dr. Stanhope is.
He's the chairman.
He's also on the board of the Botanical
Society and had access to the poison.
I found.
About McManus.
Dr. Stanhope administered
a mild dose of poison.
His intention was to render Mr.
Doyle unconscious not to kill him.
I have
reinstated your father's name on that.
And who will be my partner?
No, she's right.
I want her company to buy that land
and to donate it
to the hospital for
the poor can still be built.
And they should donate using your father's
name.
My friend.
My dear friend.
I will never trust that Toad
Sinclair again.
Why do you trust him in the first place?
As a mystery to me.
I heard what you did for young
Fitzroy,
pulling him from that raid on a gang.
Cannot speak highly enough of you.
They're not just a gang.
They are the most brutal criminals
in the city.
He's very lucky to have got them.
Please don't give me that indulgent smile.
Self-Indulgence, affection.
Of course it is, William.
Do not presume to be able to read my mind.
If I could, then I'm quite sure
that we would never speak again.
To give my best to Mr.
Potts. I'm not going to the military.
I know, I know.
But from what I've seen,
I look at frequent visits and I seems
critical of the
Miss Scarlet Detective Fitzroy.
And drag your eyes from the Scarlet
from woman to fraud case has just.
Come on, Detective. Yes, sir.
The Jeweler's and Montgomery Street
and Blue.
And get everything you can find them.
Yes, sir.
Inspector,
I hear you plucked John Fitzroy from
Detective Phelps to assist you instead.
Yes, sir.
He has encyclopedic knowledge on poisoned
sciences, insight on a case cycle.
Peter, you say. Hmm.
Impressive.
We'll get to it, Detective.
Yes, sir.
You disobeyed another direct
order, Inspector.
I apologize, but I didn't.
I was born on the streets
of Glasgow, just like you.
And I was supposed the day I was born,
to not assume my comfortable position
here.
Who's telling me otherwise?
Commissioner,
I have a whiskey with your name on it.
Waiting on my desk. Oh,
I hope it's a large one.
Large and strong.
It's just how I like my woman.
The Scarlet
Witch, to congratulate you in person
on your magnificent with my pleasure.
Thank you.
How nice to have the opportunity
to wish you commiserations in person.
This match for, I believe this evening's
edition of the Illustrated Fools News
will be leaving the princess on its way
to be devoured by its readership.
Only later to discover
that the genius, Mr.
Lash, keeps the wrong man.
No matter.
Sinclair released an apology
to Mr. Humphries in the next edition.
Oh, I think you'll find that a man
such as Mr.
Humphries
will want a little more than that.
A lawsuit, perhaps.
What woman
you are not afraid of even more.
I could have you work for me than ever.
Well, my answer is still no.
Then what can I do
to make you change your mind?
Nothing.
There's always something.
Even you,
Miss Scarlet, will have your price.
I suppose a contract blackmail.
However, perhaps I'd rather
you come to me willingly
not to coerced.
I can play as dirty as you, sir.
So believe me when I say
you do not me as an enemy.
No. I want you as my employee
to take some time.
But we offer.
Until then.
It's not so.