MULHOLLAND DR.
What are you doing?
We don't stop here!
Get out of the car.
The boys found this...
on the floor in back
of the Caddy.
Yeah, they showed me.
Could be unrelated.
Could be.
Any of those dead kids wearin'
pearl earrings?
No. Could be someone's missin' maybe.
That's what I'm thinkin'.
Just one more bag after that.
I just wanted to come here.
To Winkie's?
This Winkie's.
Okay.
Why this Winkie's?
It's kind of embarrassing...
Go ahead.
I had a dream about this place.
Oh boy.
You see what I mean?
Okay, so you had a dream about this place.
Tell me.
Well...
it's the second one I've had...
but they are both the same...
they start out that I'm in here but...
it's not day or night.
It's kinda half night, you know?...
but it
looks just like this...
except for the light.
And I'm scared like I can't tell ya.
Of all people,
you're standing right over there...
by that counter.
You're in both dreams
and you're scared.
I get even more frightened when I see
how afraid you are and...
then I realize what it is.
There's a man...
in back of this place.
He's the one who's doing it.
I can see him through the wall.
I can see his face...
I hope that I never see that face ever...
outside of the dream.
That's it.
So...
you came to see if it's out there?
To get rid of this god-awful feeling.
Right thing.
It's around here.
Dan? You all right?
Dan? Dan?
Hello?
The girl is still missing.
Talk to me.
The same.
Oh...
I can't believe it!
It's time to say goodbye, Betty.
It's
been so nice travelling with you.
Thank you, Irene.
I was so excited and nervous.
It was sure great to have you to talk to.
Remember I'll be watching for you on the big screen.
Okay Irene.
Won't that be the day.
Good luck, Betty dear.
Take care of yourself and be careful.
I will. Thanks again.
Thanks again.
Betty, it was so nice meeting you
All the luck in the world.
Bye.
My bags!
Where to?
1612 Havenhurst.
Got it!
Ten bucks says you're Betty.
Yes, I am, Mrs. Lenoix.
It is Mrs. Lenoix isn't it?
Oh, in all my living glory, baby.
Pleased to meet you.
- Just call me Coco.
Everybody else does.
Wait there, and I'll go get the key.
OK, Coco.
Wilkins?!
Wilkins?!?!
If that damned dog craps in the courtyard
one more time...
I'm just gonna bake his little butt for breakfast.
You don't have pets do you?
- No, I don't.
They're allowed,
I just don't like 'em here... for obvious reasons.
You know, there was a man that lived here once...
that had a prize fighting kangaroo.
Well, You just wouldn't believe...
what that kangaroo did to this courtyard.
Let's see your Aunt's apartment
... it's a good one.
I can hardly wait!
It's unbelievable!
I told ya.
- Wow!
Well, you and your Aunt probably have an understanding,
so here's the key.
And if you need anything,
just give a holler.
Everybody in this building's
pretty much okay with me...
or they wouldn't be here.
If you want, later on
I'll introduce you around.
No hard feelings if you don't.
Oh my! I'm sorry. My Aunt ... Ruth didn't tell
me someone was going to be here.
- I'm so sorry.
- It's OK
I'm Ruth's niece.
My name's Betty. I'm
sure she told you I was coming.
I'm sure she told you I was coming.
There was an accident.
I came here.
I understand.
I saw the dress.
Sorry. Are you all right?
What happened?
A car...
a car accident.
Oh... You OK?
I think so.
I was just...
taking a shower.
Oh my god. I'm sorry. I'll let you get
back to that. I'm going to get unpacked.
I'll let you get back to that.
I'm going to get unpacked.
What's your name?
I'm sorry. I'll get out of here
and we can talk later.
My name's...
Rita.
Hi...
do you work with my Aunt?
No... I...
- Sorry...
it's none of my business.
She has pretty red hair...
She's letting me stay here while she's working on a movie...
that's
being made in Canada...
but I guess you already know that.
I couldn't afford a place
like this in a million years.
Unless of course I'm discovered
and become a movie star.
Of course, I'd rather be known as
a great actress than a movie star,
but sometimes people end up being both
and so that is,
I guess you'd say, sort of why I came here.
I'm sorry,
I'm just so excited to be here...
I mean I just came here from Deep River, Ontario...
now I'm in this...
dream place.
You can imagine how I feel.
Oh... What? Sit down...
Where were you hurt?
We should call a doctor.
- No
But, this could be serious.
- No, I...
I need to sleep.
If you have a concussion
you shouldn't sleep.
It will feel okay if I sleep.
I just need to
lie down here and sleep.
You see Adam... there are some suggestions
that are to be brought forward ...
and I know you said you
would entertain suggestions
and that's all anybody here
is asking you to do.
What are you talking about?
An open mind...
You're in the process of
re-casting your lead actress and
I'm...
We're asking you to
keep an open mind.
What was it last time?
OK. Let's try the next one.
He's not gonna like it.
We'll see.
Ah... Castigliane brothers.
Let me introduce you around...
please ... take a seat.
this is Mr. Darby,
whom you know
and this is the director Adam Kesher...
and his manager Robert Smith.
Oh,
She's very pretty.
May I offer you, gentlemen...
anything?
Espresso.
- Nothing.
- What's the photo for?
- An espresso.
No, that's it.
I think you're gonna enjoy your espresso
this time.
I've done quite a bit of a research
knowing how hard you are to please.
This one comes highly recommended.
What's the photo for?
It's a recommendation...
a recommendation to you, Adam,
- It's not a recommendation.
- This is the girl.
What girl?. For what?.
What is this, Ray?.
We'd be happy to put her
on the list for consideration.
You'd be pleased to know
there's quite a lot of interest in this role.
Interest?. No.
There's six of the top
actresses that want this thing.
This is the girl.
- Ray, take care of this.
- Hold on, Adam.
Hold on?.
There's no way.
There's no way!
Napkin.
- Pardon?
- Napkin.
Of course.
Excuse me.
Is that all sir?.
Shit.
Sorry!
That was a highly recommended...
That's considered one of the finest
espressos in the world, Sir.
What's going on here?
There's no way that girl is in my movie.
HELP ME!!!
This is the girl.
Hey!
That girl is not in my film!
It's no longer your film.
This is the girl.
Did the Castigliane brothers get out of
that limo?
- They two guys in dark suits?
- Yeah.
- Yes.
- Keep that door open.
Castigliane brothers?
Beat it, pal.
Good afternoon, Mr. Roque.
Her name's Camilla Rhodes.
The director doesn't want her.
Do you want him replaced?.
I know they said...
Then?
Then...
that means we should...
Yes?.
Shut everything down ...
Is that something that...
do you want us...
to shut everything down?
Then we'll shut everything down.
Oh man, that's unheard of ...
an accident like that ...
who could have foreseen that?
- That's unreal, right?
Hell, right.
Unbelievable.
So, bro, God you're good!
What have you been doin'?
Just doin' some stuff
for this guy.
Yeah?. Making ends meet, huh?
Hardly.
I know, man.
Look at my digs.
Times are tough, bro.
Hey, man,
it's not that bad.
I hope you're not goin' to get in any trouble.
It was just a thing.
The story made you laugh.
- It was a funny story.
- Fucking car accident.
It's it?...
It's the famous black book.
The history of the world
in phone numbers.
Oh, man!.
Something bit me
BAD!
God!
Hey man!
She's hurt bad! Could you come here
and call on the phone. Please I need you!
She's hurt bad!
You gotta call the hospital
Come on man!
I'm serious about this!
I can't do everything by myself!
Hey man!.
OH!
...okay Aunt Ruth... I'll try.
I'm gonna study those lines
until I know them inside out.
Yep, either here
on this fabulous leather couch...
or I'll take them with a coffee in the courtyard...
like a regular movie star.
Oh! I got a real
shock to find your friend Rita here.
She was in the shower and I opened the
door ...
... what do you mean?
... She was in an accident.
... Rita, your friend.
No, Coco unlocked the door.
... No, she didn't see her.
... She's sleeping.
I'm sure there's some explanation for this
Aunt Ruth,
I don't think we have to do that.
Please don't worry...
we don't need the police.
You're awake...
I think I misunderstood.
I thought you knew my Aunt and
that's why you were here.
I just talked to my Aunt on the phone and she wants me
to call the police.
I'm... sorry. I ...
What is it Rita?
I thought when I woke up...
I thought sleep would do it...
What's wrong?
I don't know who I am.
What do you mean?
You're Rita.
I'm not. I don't know what my name is.
I don't know who I am!!
This is your purse.
Your name must be in your purse.
You want to know, don't you?
I ... yes, but ... I ...
- Open it!
You sure you don't want anything?
- Not here...no thanks.
Not a coke or something?
No... thanks though...
I'll take a
cigarette if you have one.
Sure, reach inside my shirt pocket there.
Any new girls on the street lately?
No.  I haven't seen any.
A brunette?
... maybe a little beat up?
You'll keep your eyes open for me won't
you baby?
- Sure.
- You bet you will.
That money.
You don't know where it came from?
When you think of them...
the money... the key...
does it make you remember anything?
something ...
...something there is.
What did you say?
They fired everyone.
Who fired everyone?
Ray did!
Please I'm talking on the phone,
and then they closed the set...
everybody's gone.
You'd better
get down here Adam!
You've got to talk to Ray
you've got to fix this.
I'm going home.
Home?!
Meet me at the office.
We've got to do something...
... you've got to do something Adam!
I'm going home, Cynthia.
Adam, this isn't like you.
Please come to the office.
- There must be something we can do.
- I'm going home.
I wonder where you were going.
Mulholland drive.
Mulholland drive?
That's where I was going...
Mulholland Drive.
Maybe that's where the accident was.
There must be a police report.
We could call...
We could call anonymously from a pay phone...
just to see if there was an accident.
Come on. It'll be just like in the movies.
We'll pretend to be someone else.
I want to walk around anyway.
I'm
in Hollywood and I haven't even seen any of it.
Come on Rita.
Do you feel up to it?
Okay... but just
...just to see.
Just to see
if there was an accident...
on Mulholland Drive.
Lorraine?
Lorraine... you home?
Lorraine...
Now, you've done it!
Just forget you ever saw.
It's better that way.
What the hell are you even doing here?
What are you doing?
THAT'S MY JEWELRY!!!
That bastard
You bastard!
He's probably upset Lorraine.
WHAT.. ARE ... YOU ... DOING!!!???
STOP IT!!!
Adam, STOP IT!!!
What're you doin'
You're hurting me!
That's not a way to treat your wife, buddy.
I don't care what she's done.
Throw him out!
Get out!
Let's hide it.
There's one.
Hollywood Police Department
I'm inquiring about an accident that
happened last night on Mulholland Drive.
Hold please.
I'll connect you to traffic.
- Sergeant Baxter,
- Hi. I'm inquiring...
well, I heard a sound last night
that sounded sort of like a carcrash and
I want to know if there was an
accident on Mulholland Drive.
Yes, there was.
- Can you tell me what happened?
- No. I can't.
- Was anyone hurt?
- May I have your name please?
There was an accident.
He wouldn't tell me anything else,
but that was your accident Rita.
I just know it was.
Maybe there's something about it in the papers.
Come on we'll buy a cup of coffee
and we can see.
Maybe it happened so late it's not going
to be in today's paper.
There's nothing?
Not that I can see.
That's Ok.
Thanks...
... Diane.
That'd be all?
You want your check?
Rita, you want something?
- No. Just the coffee.
- I'll take our check.
What is it Rita?
-Shhhh.
I remember something...
- What is it?
- Diane Selwyn.
Maybe that's my name.
D.Selwyn ... it's the only one.
I'm gonna call.
It's strange to be calling yourself.
Maybe it's not me.
Hello... this is me.
Leave me a message.
It's not my voice...
but I know her.
Maybe that isn't Diane Selwyn's voice.
Maybe that's your roommate...
or if it is Diane Selwyn...
she can tell you who you are.
Maybe.
- Yeah, right ... get lost!
- Is this Adam Kesher's house?
Like hell it is! Get out ... NOW!!
Get out!
Get out of here!
He's never coming back! Ever!
I guess you don't understand English.
She said to leave.
Here's the door.
OUT!
- Yeah...what is it, Cookie?
- I'm sorry Mr. Kesher...
but there seems tobe some problem
with your credit cards.
What??... I pay you cash, Cookie.
Fact is two guys from your bank came by.
My bank?
- How'd they know I was here?
- I don't know.
What did they say?
I'm afraid they said
you're maxed out at your bank...
and your line of credit has been cancelled.
It's unbelievable.
Look...
I don't know what's going on.
That's so much baloney.
I've got enough cash for you Cookie.
I known... I known...
Don't worry...
I'm sorry.
It was my duty to inform you.
People you're hiding from,
they know where you are.
Right.
I'm sorry
Hello?
Someone's maybe shut off my money!
I know.
Where are you Adam?
What do you mean you know?
Somebody called. When they couldn't get you...
they told me you were as good as broke.
I didn't believe them,
so I made a few calls.
- And?
- You're broke!
But I'm not broke!
I know, but you're broke.
Where are you?
I'm at Cookie's Downtown.
Do you know somebody called the "The Cowboy"?
- "The Cowboy"?
- Yes
Yeah, the Cowboy.
This guy, the Cowboy,
wants to see you.
Jason said he thought it would be a good idea.
Oh, Jason thought it would be a good idea
for me to go to see the Cowboy.
Should I wear my ten gallon hat and my six shooters?
Listen. Something tells me this guy is connected
to what's happening,
and I think you should do it and I think you should
do it right away.
What's going on, Cynthia?
It's been a very strange day...
and getting stranger.
Where do I meet this Cowboy? I mean...
do I have to ride out to the range?
Sort of, funny boy.
If I tell him the
meeting's on...
you have to go to the top of
Beachwood Canyon.
There's a corral up there where he'll be.
You've got to be kidding me!
Will you meet with him?
Yeah, sure.
It's been that kind of a day.
When?
I'll call him, right away...
then I'll call you back.
You could stay at my place, if you want it.
Cynthia... I don't think it'll be a good idea.
I'm just offering a place to stay.
And I appreciate the offer, Cynthia.
I'll find a place.
Now go on and give the Cowboy a yodel
and get back to me.
Okay, but you don't know what you're missing.
Just get along little dowgie and call me back.
It's right about here on Sierra Bonita.
That's not too far away.
What's wrong with that?
I'm not sure about this.
I know you're afraid of something.
We'll be careful. Promise.
Tomorrow we'll go over there...
and we'll find out.
It'll be okay.
It's probabily Coco
Yes?
May I help you?
Someone is in trouble.
Who are you?
What are you doing in Ruth's apartment?
She's letting me stay here.
I'm her niece. My name's Betty.
No it's not.
That's not what she said.
Someone is in trouble.
Something bad is happening!
I'm sorry, but I don't know who you are
and...
Louise...
What are you doing Louise?
Oh, Coco! I've been
trying to find you all afternoon since
3:00 o'clock.
That one is in my room
and she won't leave.
I want you to get her out.
I want you to get her out now.
This is Louise Bonner. I'm sure she
meant well.
Louise, this is Betty,
this is Ruth's niece.
In fact and
fortunately I was just on my way here to see Betty.
Betty's a young actress and I was just delivering...
some faxed pages of a scene
for a big audition tomorrow.
- Well, here they are honey.
- Oh, thank you.
Now come along Louise
and I'll take you home.
I'm sorry. It happens sometimes.
Come on.
No, she said it was someone else
who was in trouble.
Stop it, Louise. I'm taking you home...
Come on.
- Goodnight Betty.
- Goodnight.
Goodnight.
Cowboy!
- Howdy!
- Howdy to you.
Beautiful evening.
Sure want to thank ya for coming
all theway up to see me...
from that nice hotel Downtown.
No problem.
What's on your mind?.
Well now, here's a man who wants to get
right down to it.
Kinda anxious to get to it are ya?
Whatever.
A man's attitude...
... a man's attitude
goes some ways
the way his life will be.
Is that somethin' you might agree with?
Sure.
Now... did you answer because you thought
that's what I wanted to hear...
or did you think about what I said...
and answer cause you
truly believe that to be right?
I agree with what you said... truly.
What did I say?
That a man's attitude determines to a
large extent how his life will be.
So since you agree...
you must be a person who does not care about the good life.
How's that?
Well, stop for a little second and
think about it.
Can you do that for me?
Okay, I'm thinking.
No. You're not thinkin'
You're too busy being a smart aleck to be thinkin'.
Now I want ya to think
and stop bein' a smart aleck.
Can you try that for me?
Look ... where's this going?
What do you want me to do?
There's sometimes a buggy.
How many drivers does a buggy have?
One.
So let's just say I'm drivin' this buggy...
and you if fix your attitude you can
ride along with me.
Okay.
I want you to go back to work tomorrow.
You were re-casting the lead
actress anyway...
audition many girls for
the part.
When you see the girl that was
shown to you earlier today, you will say:
This is the girl.
The rest of the cast can stay.
That is up to you.
But that lead girl is not up to you.
Now, you will see me one more time...
if you do good.
You will see me two more times...
if you do bad.
Good night.
You're still here?
I came back.
I thought that's what you wanted.
Nobody wants you here!
Really?
My parents are right upstairs!
They think you've left.
- So... surprise...
- I can call them... I can call my dad...
But you won't...
If you're trying to blackmail me...
it's not going to work.
You're playing a dangerous game here.
You know what I want...
it's not that difficult.
Get out!
Get out before I call my dad ...
he trusts you...
you're his best friend.
This will be the end of everything.
What about you?
What will your dad think about you?
Stop! Just stop! That's what you said
from the beginning.
If I tell what happened...
they'll arrest you and put you in jail.
so get out of here before...
Before what?
Before I kill you.
Then they'd put you in jail.
Then I cry, cry, cry, and then I say with big emotion:
I hate you... I hate us both!
Such a lame scene.
But you are really good.
Thank you dahling!
Hi there!
Who are you?
Betty, can I see you outside for a minute?
- What is it Coco?
- Your aunt called
I was afraid of that.
She wants to know
who's staying in her apartment.
It's just for a night or two,
until she finds her own place.
I tried to explain that to Aunt Ruth,
but the connection was bad...
and her plane was leaving,
and she got it all mixed up.
I kept telling her it was my friend Rita...
and she kept saying
she didn't know any Ritas...
Look at me straight, sweetie.
Coco... she's very nice.
Honey... you're a good kid.
What you're telling me is a load of horse-pucky
even though it comes from a good place.
Now, I'm gonna trust you
to sort this thing out
- Thank you.
- Don't make me out to be a sucker.
Louise Bonner says there's trouble in there.
Remember last night?
Well, sometimes she's wrong,
but if there is trouble
get rid of it.
Is everything all right?
Is it bad for you that I'm here?
No, no, everything is A-okay.
Now, I've gotta fix that sandwich!
And my audition is in one hour.
I hope I'm back in a couple of hours.
- Don't drink all the coke.
- Good luck!
When I get back I'll have the cab
waiting, so be ready to go.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Come in.
Betty Elms, I'd like you to meet...
Jack Tuptman, my assistant,
Woody Katz who we've
cast in the part...
of "Chuck".
He'll do the scene with you.
Bob Brooker, the director
and Julie Chadwick...
Now, our surprise guest is:
Linney James.
Alas we can't afford her to cast our show,
but as casting agents go...
she's the best.
Why thank you, Wally.
Hello Betty.
Very pleased to meet you.
This is my assistant, Nicki.
Oh, and the ever lovely Martha,
Martha Johnson, who
you met out front.
Hi.
So shall we get it to go?
Would you like a water or a coffee
before we begin?
No, no, I'm fine.
Well then, let's everyone take a seat.
Betty, why don't you join Woody over there
and we'll play the scene.
Bob, do you have anything you wish to say...
something to Betty before we begin?
No... it's not a contest,
the two of them with themselves,
so don't play it for real...
until it gets real.
Okay.
Just tell me where it hurts, baby.
What?
Hey Bobby, I want to play this one nice and close,
like
we did with that other girl,
what's her name? The one with the black hair.
That felt kinda good.
- Whaddya think?
- That's good, Woody.
Just don't rush that line again.
I told you...
the line where you say, "Before what?"
Bobby, acting is reacting...
I just play off 'em. They all say:
They're gonna arrest you like that...
put you in jail...
They all say it the same way,
so I react like that.
What's your name?
- Betty
Yeah... Betty, look... You don't rush it. I
don't rush it.
We're gonna play it nice and close...
just like in the movies. OK?
Dad's best friend goes to work.
And ... ACTION!!!!
You're still here?
I came back.
I thought that's what you wanted.
- Nobody wants you here.
- Really?
My parents are right upstairs!
They think you've left.
So ... surprise!
I can call them...
I can call my dad...
But you won't...
You're playing a dangerous game here...
if you're trying to blackmail me...
it's not gonna work.
You know what I want..
it's not that difficult.
Get out...
Get out before I call my dad.
He trusts you...
You're...
his best friend.
This will be the end of everything.
What about you?
What will your dad think about you?
Stop...
stop it!
That's what you said from the beginning.
If I tell them what happened...
they'll arrest you...
and put you in jail,
so get out of here...
before...
Before what?
Before...
I kill you.
Then they'd put you in jail.
I hate you...
I hate us both!
- I'm going to take her over there.
- Yeah big time!
Wow!
Well, there it was.
There it was all right!
Baby, you got away with it!
Very good. Really.
I mean it was forced maybe...
but still humanistic.
Yeah,
very good,
really.
Oh I thank you Betty...
and I really mean that sincerely.
I mean, it was extraordinary.
You've done your Aunt proud...
and I'm going to tell her
the first chance I get.
Now, you and I...
are gonna speak again soon.
Thank you Mr. Brown.
Thank you, Wally.
I'm sure you all have a
lot to talk about.
We'll walk Betty out.
Well, yes indeed.
And it was our pleasure, Linney.
Don't you be a stranger around here.
- We'd love to have you here.
- Come on, Betty.
Thank you again, Mr. Brown.
It was nice meeting all of you.
Wow!
How do you find her...
God, that was awful!
Not you Betty.
You were stellar and I mean that
But poor Wally.
He'll never get that picture made.
- Why?
Wally's days were up twenty years ago.
You know Woody Katz
is only doing it for a favor?
And the cast is terrible...
Oh, God, terrible
Poor old fool Wally...
It was very nice
and he seems so sweet.
and Wally... Mr. Brown...
is a very close friendof my Aunt's, so...
Settle down, Betty. Don't get me wrong.
I love Wally.
I ought to. I was married
to him for ten years.
And I love actors, all actors.
We just get a little catty sometimes.
Now we want to take you across
and introduce you to a director...
who's a head above the rest
He's got a project that you would kill!
Knock it right out of the park.
~ Sixteen reasons ~
~ why I ~
~ love you ~
~- One
- The way you hold my hand ~
~ - Two
- Your laughing eyes ~
~ - Three
- The way you understand ~
~ - Four
- Your secret sighs ~
~ They're all part ~
~ of sixteen reasons ~
~ why I... love you ~
~ - Five
- The way you comb your hair ~
~ - Six
- Your freckled nose ~
~ - Seven
- The way you say you care ~
~ - Eight
- Your crazy clothes ~
~ That's just half of sixteen reasons ~
~ why I ~
~ love you ~
~ - Nine
- Snuggling in the car ~
~ - Ten
- Your wish upon a star ~
~ - Eleven
- Whispering on the phone ~
~ - Twelve
- Your kiss when we're alone ~
~ - Thirteen
- The way you thrill my heart ~
~ - Fourteen
- Your voice so neat ~
~ - Fifteen
- You say we'll never part ~
~ - Sixteen
- Our love's complete ~
~ Those are all ~
~ the sixteen reasons ~
~ why I ~
~ love you ~
~ Sixteen reasons ~
~ why I ~
~ love you ~
Cut it!
Thank you very much, Carol.
I'm coming back.
Check it again?
Check it again!
Thank you!
Will tell you what happens next!
Thank you very much, for coming in
I know how busy you are.
Oh, are you kidding me? I love this script!
Show me where to sign!
Look... I love you...
but there's no way they're gonna let me cast this thing
until I've seen everyone.
- I'll let you know as soon as I can.
- I know you will.
cause my manager's
gonna be bugging you day and night.
... and me.
- It'll be my pleasure. Now, get out of here.
- Oh, you're just so cruel to me...
don't forget me.
I'm the girl that's going to play this part.
See ya later.
Hank... where's Hank?
- Who's next, Hank?
- Camilla Rhodes.
- Is she ready?
- Already.
- Bring her in.
- Camilla Rhodes next.
Sylvia North's story,
Camilla Rhodes, take one.
Ok, here we go...
Let's lock it up, please!
- Roll sound please...
- That's it!
Playback!
ACTION!
~ Why haven't I told you? ~
~ Oh, baby I've told ~
~ every little star ~
~ just how sweet I think you are ~
~ Why haven't I told you? ~
Get Jason over here.
Cindy ... Adam wants to see Jason.
~ I've told ripples in a brook ~
~ Made my heart an open book ~
~ Why haven't I told you? ~
~ Friends ask me "am I in love" ~
~ I always answer "yes" ~
~ Might as well confess ~
~ If the answer's yes ~
~ Maybe you may love me too ~
~ Oh my darling if you do ~
~ Why haven't you told me? ~
Did you want to tell me something, Adam?
This is the girl!
Excellent choice, Adam.
Oh... my goodness.
I have to be somewhere.
I promised a friend.
I'm sorry. I must go...
It should be around here...
2590... That's it.
Up there!
- Does it look familiar?
- No.
- Don't stop!
-What is it? What do you see?!
- Those men in front, in the car.
- Do you know them?!
No... but...
-Keep going.
Go around to the back.
Selwyn... number 12.
Now, you've got me scared.
See, I told you there was nothing
to be afraid of!
Betty wait... wait
Oh no... don't.
No one's home.
Yes?
Number 17.
But it said number 12.
I switched apartments with her.
She's in 17.
It's down in the end on the left.
She hasn't been around for a few days...
- Oh... we'll leave her a note.
- I'll go with you.
She's still got some of my stuff.
You go ahead.
I've got to get that.
I guess you're not Diane Selwyn.
Guess I'm not.
Still no one's home I guess.
C'mon do it.
C'mon help me in. Come on.
I'll open the front door.
C'mon.
I know what you're doing.
I know what you have to do,
but let me do it.
Let me do it.
You look like someone else.
Good night, Betty.
You don't wear it in the house.
What?
The wig.
Just I'm looking at myself again...
I'll take it off to sleep.
And you don't have to sleep on that couch.
No, it's okay.
No it's not.
This is a huge bed.
C'mon, just get in and get a good night sleep.
It's more confortable than the couch, isn't it?
Yes.
Thank you, Betty.
It's nothing.
I shouldn't have let you sleep
on the couch last night.
No... I mean...
Thank you for everything.
You're welcome.
Good night, sweet Betty.
Good night.
Have you ever done this before?
I don't known!
Have you?
I want to with you...
I'm in love with you.
Silencio.
No hay banda.
No hay orquestra.
Silencio.
Rita?
- No hay banda.
Rita, wake up
- No, no...
- It's ok, it's ok.
No it's not ok.
What's wrong?
Go with me somewhere...
It's 2 o'clock
It's 2 o'clock in the morning.
Go with me somewhere...
Sure. Now?
Right now!
No hay banda!
There is no band!
Il n'est pas de orquestra!
This is all...
a tape-recording.
No hay banda!
and yet
we hear a band.
If we want to hear a clarinette...
listen...
Un trombon "?coulisse".
Un trombon "con sordina".
Sient le son du trombon in sourdine.
Hear le son...
and mute it... drop it...
It's all recorded.
No hay banda!
It's all a tape.
Il n'est pas de orquestra.
It is...
an illusion.
Listen...
Senoras y senores...
el club Silencio les presenta
la llorona de Los Angeles:
Rebekah del Rio.
Betty?
Donde estas?
Hey, pretty little girl...
time to wake up.
- Where have you been?
- What do you want?
My lamp and dishes...
C'mon Diane,
it's been three weeks.
I put your dishes in that box.
- That's my ashtray.
- Take it.
Anytime...
I'm just making sure, Diane.
- That is it?
- Yeah
Ah, by the way, those two detectives
came by again, looking for you.
Camilla!
You've come back!
What was that you were saying, beautiful?
I said:
You drive me wild.
We shouldn't do this anymore...
Don't say that...
Don't ever say that!
Don't Diane,
Stop it...
Diane STOP!
I've tried to tell you this before.
It's him, isn't it?
I'm not trying to show you how to do the scene.
Just watch me...
and I think you'll understand what I'm getting at.
Don't seat so rigid...
just, just relax...
You two are here alone...
and it's real comfortable...
like you've known each other forever...
ven if you don't say anything...
It's real comfortable.
Hank, can you just clear the set...
there's too many people around here...
Let's get this worked out...
Clear the set!
Everyone get another cup of coffee.
- Everyone please!
- Can Diane stay?
Yes, true. Diane can stay.
Hank, let Diane stay.
Now when she starts to cry...
don't pull her toward you.
Let her fall in to you...
Let her fall.
When you kiss her...
It's just a continuation of that move
There is no break...
Kill the lights!
Don't be mad!
- Don't make it be like this!
- Oh, sure.
You want me to make this easy for you? No!
No-fucking-way it's not gonna be!
It's not easy for me!!!
Hello, it's me...
leave a message...
Hello?
Diane, the car is waiting.
Are you ok?
You comin'?
Good...
It means so much to me.
Go on... the car is right outside the house..
It's been waiting, ok ?
Ok.
It's 6980, Mulholland drive.
Mulholland drive.
What are you doing?
We don't stop here...
A surprise...
Shortcut.
C'mon sweetheart.
It's beautiful.
A secret path.
Ah, perfect timing!
Welcome, Diane.
Well...
Here's to love...
Ah, here she is...
I don't believe you met my mother...
Hi, I'm Diane Selwyn.
Just call me Coco, everybody does...
- Pleased to meet you...
- Let's eat...
I'm starving...
I'm sorry, I was late.
I'm from Deep River, Ontario...
a small town.
So, you rolled in here from Canada.
I've always wanted to come here.
I won this ballet contest...
that sort of led to acting...
you know, wanting to act.
When my aunt died...
anyway, she left me so money...
she worked here...
In the movies?
Yes.
How did you meet Camilla?
On a "Sylvia North Story".
Camilla was great in that.
Yeah, I wanted the lead so bad.
Anyway, Camilla got the part.
The director...
Bob Brooker?
Yes.
Hadn't so much of me...
anyway, that's when we became friends.
She helped me...
getting some parts
in some of her films.
I see.
So, I got the pool...
and she got the pool-man.
I couldn't believe it
I wanted to buy that judge a Rolls-Royce.
Sometimes good things happen.
So, I guess we saved the best for last...
Do you want to tell them?
No, you to tell them.
Camilla and I...
are going to be...
Sorry about that.
No, I'm fine.
This is the girl.
Don't show me this photothing here.
It's just an actress' photo, everybody's got one.
You got the money?
Sure do.
Ok, once you hand that over to me, it's a done deal.
Are you sure you want this?
More than anything in this world.
When it's finished, you'll find this where I told you.
What's it open?
Silencio