Harry Potter and the
Order of the Phoenix
It's just too hot today isn't it?
And it's going to get even worse.
Temperatures up in the mid 30s Celsius.
And at night should go
up even, and perhaps...
Alright, lets go home.
What a lovely day.
Do we have to? We do.
Hey big D. Beat up another 10 year old?
This one deserved
it. - Ya. - Ya.
5 against 1, very brave.
Well you're the one to talk?
Moaning in your sleep every night.
At least I'm not afraid of my pillow.
Don't kill Cedric.
Who's Cedric? Your boyfriend? Shut up.
He's going to kill me, mom.
Where is your mom?
Where is your mom, Potter?
Is she dead?
Is she dead?!
Is she dead...
What's going on?
What's going on here?
What are you doing?
I'm not doing anything.
Dudley, come on!
Run!
Dudley, run!
Expecto Patronum!
Mrs. Figg.
Don't Put away your wand, Harry.
They might come back.
Dementors in little Winchik.
What's next?
Whole world's in top sterny.
L don't understand. How did you know...
Dumbledore asked me
to keep an eye on you.
Dumbledore? You know Dumbledore?
After You-Know-Who killed
that poor Diggory boy last year.
Did you expect him to let you go
wandering around alone?
Good Lord,
they told me you're intelligent.
Now, get inside and stay there.
Soon someone will be in touch with you.
Whatever happens, don't leave the house.
Didlykin, is that you?
Dudley! Vernon come quick!
Who did this to you boy?
Happy, are we, now?
You finally done it.
You finally driven him loopey.
Vernon, don't you say that.
Just look at him, Petunia.
Our boy has gone yumpie.
L've reach my limit, you hear?
This is the last l'm gonna
take you and your losses.
Dear Mr. Potter
The Ministry has received intelligence.
That at 6:23 this evening...
You performed the Petronas Charm
in the presence of a muggle.
As a clear violation of the decree...
For the reasonable restriction
of Underage Sorcery,
You are hereby expelled from
Hogwarts School of Witchcraf and Wizardry.
Hope that you are well, Mafilda Hopkerk.
Justice.
Sorry, Hedwig.
Hygienist, these muggles.
Tonks, for God's sake.
Professor Moody, what're you doing here?
To rescue you of course.
Where are we going?
That l'm just expelled from school.
You haven't been
Not yet.
Kingsley, you take front.
But the letter said...
Dumbledore has persuaded the Minister
to suspend your expeltion
Pending for your formal hearing.
A hearing?
Don't worry, Harry.
We'll explain everything
when we get back to headquarters.
Shh, not here, Nymphadora.
Don't call me Nymphadora.
Stay in formation everyone.
Don't break ranks if one of us was killed.
Come on.
Here you go, son.
Yes, but...
He grew stronger by the minute.
We have to act now.
Harry.
Mrs. Weasley.
Thank God, you're alright.
Bit peaky.
L'm afraid, dinner, we're gonna have
to wait after the meeting finish.
Look. No time to explain.
Straight upstairs.
First door on the left.
Yeah.
Harry.
You alright?
We've heard them talking about the Dementors attack.
You must tell us everything.
Let him breath, Hermione.
And this hearing at the Ministry,
it's just outrageous.
They can't expel you.
Lt's completely unfair.
Yeah.
There's a lot going around me.
So what is this place?
Lt's headquarters.
The Order of The Phoenix.
Lt's a secret society.
Dumbledore formed it back in the first,
You-Know-Who.
You couldn't write any of this
in your letter l suppose?
Whole summer without a scrap of news.
We thought to write, really, l did. Only...
Only What???
Dumbledore made us swear
not to tell you anything.
Dumbledore said that?
But why he want to keep me in the dark?
Maybe l can help.
Afterall, l'm the one
who saw Voldermort returned.
L'm the one he fought with.
L'm the one who saw
Cedric Diggory get killed.
Harry.
Don't be so uptight.
Let it out.
Anyway, we heard the chatting.
Only had something more interesting.
Harry has the right to know.
Lf it wasn't him,
no one know he's back.
He's hardly a child, Molly.
But not an adult either.
He's not James, Sirius.
He's not your son.
He's as good as it.
No one else he's got.
He's got me.
Potter will grow up into a criminal.
Just like his Godfather.
Stay out of this, Severus.
Why don't you tell him?
Hermione, l hate your cat.
We'll be eating down in the kitchen.
Just because you're allowed
to use magic now,
Does not mean you have to whip
your wands out for everything.
Hi, mom.
You hungry, Harry?
You sure you're alright, Harry?
Harry Potter.
Sirius.
It is very very peculiar...
Lt seems that your hearing
at the Ministry...
Is to be before the entire Withem.
L don't understand why is the Ministry
of Magic go against me.
Show him.
He'd find out soon enough.
''The Boy Who Lies?''
He's been attacking Dumbledore as well.
''Fudge: All ls Well''
Fudge is using all his power.
Lncluding his influence
at the Daily Prophet.
Smear anyone who claims
the Dark Lord has returned.
Why?
The Minister thinks
Dumbledore's after his job.
But that's insane. No one in the right
mind would believe that Dumbledore...
Exactly the point.
Fudge isn't in his right mind.
He's been twisted and walked by fear.
Now, fear makes people do a lot of things.
The last time Voldermort gain power...
He almost destroyed everything
we hold on stand.
Now he has returned, l'm afraid
the Minister will do almost anything...
To avoid facing the terrifying truth.
We think Voldermort wants to
build up his army again.
14 years ago he had huge armies
in his command.
Not just witches to wizards
But a lot of dark creatures.
He's been recruiting, we've been
attempted to do the same.
But gathering followers isn't
the only thing he's interested.
We believe Voldermort
may be after something.
Sirius.
Something he didn't have last time.
You mean, like a weapon?
No, that's enough.
He's just a boy!
You say much more, you might as well
inducting him to the Order straight away.
Good. l want to join.
Lf Voldermort's recruiting the army
then l want to fight.
Harry.
You are hereby expelled.
Before the whole Withom.
The trains. Underground.
Genius these muggles.
Here we are.
L've never use this entrance before.
Lt should be fun.
L'll just get my money.
''Dumbledore - Deaf or Dangerous?''
Good morning, Arthur.
Morning, Bob.
Lnter Department Memos.
Used to use owls.
The mess is unbelievable!
Merlin's Beard
Thank you, Kingsley.
They changed the time
of your hearing.
When is it?
In 5 minutes!
Remember, during the hearing
speak calmly if you are spoken too
Keep calm
You've done nothing wrong!
As the muggle say
"Truth will out!"
Yes?
I'm not allow in, I;m afraid.
Good luck, Harry.
Diciplinary Hearing of 12th August,
Into offences commited by
Harry James Potter...
Resident at no.4, Privet drive, Winshik,
Solicitor Cornelius Fudge... Minister...
Witness for Defense.
Albus Percivel Wilfred...
Brown Dumbledore.
You got our message that
the time and place...
Of the hearing has been changed,
did you?
L must have missed it.
But by mistake, l arrived
at the Ministry 3 hours early.
Charges?
The charges against the accused
are as follows...
That he did knowingly,
And in full aware this
legality of his action...
Produce of the Petronas Charm
in the presence of a muggle.
Do you deny producing said Petronus?
No, but...
And you were aware that you're forbidden
from using magic...
Outside school while under
the age of 17?
Yes, of course, but...
Witches and wizards of the Wizengemot..
L was only doing it
because of the Dementors.
Dementors? ln Little Winchik?
That's very clever.
Muggles can't see Dementors,
can't they, boy?
Highly convenient
L'm not lying. There were 2 of them.
lf l hadn't...
Enough!
L'm sorry to interrupt what have showed
in a very well rehearse story.
But since you can't produce
no witnesses of the event...
Pardon me, Minister.
Where as it happens, we can.
Please describe the attack.
What did they look like?
One of them was very large,
and the other one was skinny.
Not the boys.
The Dementors.
Alright, alright... oh well em...
Big.
Cloak.
Then... everything went cold.
Like all of the happiness
had gone from the world.
Now, look here.
Dementors don't just wander
into a muggle suburban.
Happen to cross with a wizard.
The odds are ternomecule.
L don't think anyone would've believe...
That the Dementors were there
by coincidence, minister.
L'm sure l must've
misunderstood you, professor
Dementors are, after all, under the
control of Ministry of Magics.
So silly but it sounded,
for moment as though,
You're suggesting that the Ministry
had ordered the attack on this boy.
That would be disturbing indeed,
Madam Under-Secretary.
Which is why I'm sure the Ministry will be mounting
a full scale enquiry...
Into why the 2 Dementors were
surveiling very far from Azkaban...
And why they attack
without the authorization?
Of course there is someone who might be
behind the attack.
Cornelius, l employ you to see reason.
The evidence the Dark Lord have returned
is incontrovertible.
He's not back!
Ln the matter of Harry Potter
The Law say in this states,
That magic may be used before muggles
in life threatening situation.
Laws can be changed if necessary,
Dumbledore.
Really? It is become a practive to hold a
full criminal trial...
To deal with a simple matter
of Underage Magic?
Those, in favor of conviction.
Those in favor of clearing the accuse
of all charges.
Clear the whole charges.
Professor!
Padfoot, are you barking mad?
You'll blow the entire operation!
Sirius, what are you doing here?
lf someone sees you...
L had to see you off tonight.
What's life without a little risk?
L don't want to see you get trapped
back into Azkaban.
Don't worry about me.
Anyway, l wanted you to have this.
Orginal Order of the Phoenix.
Marlene McKenine.
She was killed 2 weeks after
this was taken.
Voldermort wiped out her entire family.
Franklin and Ellis Longbottom.
Neville's parents.
They suffered a foughtless death.
Lt's been 14 years.
There isn't a day goes by
l don't miss your dad.
Do you really think
there's gonna be a war, Sirius?
Lt feels like it did before.
You keep it.
Anyway, l suppose
you're the young ones now.
Bye...
L surprise the Ministry still let you
walk out free, Potter.
You better enjoy while you can.
Or else a cell in Azkaban
will have your name on it.
What I tell you
He's a complete nutter
You stay away from me!
It's only Malfoy
Just relax.
Hi guys.
Hi, Neville.
What is it?
What's what?
That. Pulling the carriage.
Nothing's pulling the carriage, Harry.
Lt's pulling itself, like always.
You are not going mad...
L can see them too.
You're just the sane as l am.
Everyone, this is Loneylov...
Luna Lovegood.
Lnteresting necklace.
Lt's a charm actually.
Keeps away the Naragos.
L'm hungry. l hope there's a pudding.
What's a Naragos?
No idea.
Good evening, children.
Now we have 2 changes in staff this year.
Please welcome back
Professor Grubbly-Plank.
Who'd be taking care of
magical creatures,
While Professor Hagrid
is on temporary leaves.
We're also pleased to welcome our new
Defense Against Dark Arts teacher,
Professor Dolores Umbridge.
L'm sure you all will join me
in wishing the professor good luck.
As usual our care taker Mr. Filch
has ask me to remind you...
She was at my hearing.
She works for Fudge.
Thank you, headmaster
for those kind words of welcome.
And how lovely to see all
your bright, happy faces...
Smiling up to me.
L'm sure we'll all going to be
very good friends.
That's likely.
-That's likely.
The Ministry of Magic,
has always considered...
The education of young witches
and wizards...
To be a vital importance.
Although each headmaster
has brought something new...
To this historic school.
Progress for the sake of progress
must be discourage.
Let us preserve
what must be preserved.
Perfect what can't be perfected...
And proove actism,
in order to beat pro-imitate.
Thank you, Professor Umbridge.
That really was constant minimizing.
Minimizing? What?
What does it mean?
It means the Ministry interfering Hogwarts.
Dean, Seamus, good holiday?
Alright, better than Seamus' actually.
My mom didn't want me
to come back this year.
Why not?
Let me see, because of you.
The Daily Prophet has been saying
a lot of things about you, Harry.
And about Dumbledore as well!
Your mom believes them?
Well, nobody was there
the night Cedric died.
Well, l guess you should read the Prophet
like your stupid mother.
Lt'll tell you
everything you need to know.
Don't you dare tell me.
L'll never let go anyone
that calls me a liar.
What's going on?
He is what's going on.
Do you believe the words
he commended, you or him?
Yeah, l do.
Does anyone else
got a problem with Harry?
You alright?
Fine.
Seamus was backout there.
He'll go through it. We'll see.
L said l'm fine, Ron.
Alright. l just leave you
to your thought, huh?
Come on, Seamus, go on, get it
Good morning, children
Ordinary Wizarding Level Examinations
OWLS
Well, commonly known as... OWLS
Study hard and you'll be awarded
Failed to do so, and the consequences
maybe... severe
Your previous instruction subjects
have been disturbingly uneven
But please to know from now on...
You'll be following a carefully
structured
Ministry approved course of
defensive magic
Yes?
.. there isn't something about using the
defensive spells
Using spells?
Why would you need spells in my
classroom?
We aren't using magics
You'll be learning about defensive
spells in a secure, risks-free way
What use is that?
We're gonna be attacked,
it won't be risks-free
Students will raise their hands when
speak in my class
Lt's the view of the ministry
That a theoretical knowledge'll be
sufficient...
To get you thru your examinations,
which after all...
Ls what schools are all about
And how's theories supposed to
prepare us for out there?
There's nothing out there, dear
Who do you imagine'd attack
children like yourselves?
L don't know, maybe Lord Voldermort
Now let me make this quite plain
You've been told...
That a certain dark wizard is at
large once again
This is a lie!
It's not lie, i saw him, l fought..
-Detention, Mr Potter
So, according to your say,
Diggory dropped of his own?
Cedric Diggory's death was a tragic
accident
He was murdered, Voldermort killed
him, you must know that
Enough... enough!
See me later, Mr Potter... my office
Come in
Good evening, Mr Potter
Sit
You're gonna be doing some lines
for me today, Mr Potter
No, not with your quill
Cause you're gonna be using
a rather special 1 of mine
Now, I want you to write
I must not tell lies!
How many times?
Lets say, as long it take the
message to sink you
You haven't given me any ink
You won't need any inks
Yes?
Nothing
That's rite
Because you know deep down
You deserved to be punished
Don't you, Mr Potter?
Go on
Skiving snack box
Sweets'll make you ill
Lt'll get you outta class
Let's take hours of pleasures
outta school boredom
You care for another?
L'm not asking you to write all of it for me
Oh please
L'm just busy studying this stupid owls exams
L'll do the introductions
That's all!
Hermione, you're the most wonderful
person i've ever known
L'll never be rude to you again
Only l bet you will
What's wrong with your hand?
Nothing
The other hand
You've gotta tell Dumbledore
No, Dumbledore's got enough
in his mind rite now
Anyway i want to get Umbridge's
her satisfaction
Bloody hell she was torturing you
Lf your parents know about this...
Yeah, i haven't got any parents,
have l?
Harry, you've gotta report this
It's perfectly simple....
No! It's not...
Hermoine, what ever this is;
It's not simple
You don't understand!
Then help us to...
Dear Padfoot, i hope you're alrite
Lt's getting cooler here
Winter's definitely on the way
Despite i've been back to Hogwarts,
i feel more alone than ever
L know you but all people will
understand
Hello Harry Potter
Your feet, aren't you cold?
A bit
Unfortunately all my shoes
are mysteriously disappeared
I suspect nigel are behind this
What are they?
The Carl Pastro
They're gentle really, but...
People avoid them because,
they've been...
Different
Why can't the other see?
They can only been by
people who's seen death
So you know someone who's gone?
My mum
She was quiet an extraordinary witch
She did a lot of experiments though
One day 1 of her spells went badly wrong
L was 9
L'm sorry
Lt was rather horrible
L do feel very sad about it sometimes
But i've a dad
My dad and l believe you by the way
And he must not be named's back
And you fought him
And the Ministry extremely tough for that
conspiring you and Dumbledore
Thanks, seems that you're the
only who do
L don't think that's true
I supposed that is how you wanted it to be.
What do you mean?
Lf i were You Know Who!
L don't want you to feel crowd
from anyone else
Because if it's just you alone...
you aren't much as a threat
Would you ever stop eating?
L'm hungry
Harry
Can i join you?
Prof, what exactly are you insinuating?
I am only requesting when
it come to my students
You conformed to prescribe
disciplinary practices
Seems silly of me but it sounds
That you're questioning my
authority in my own classroom
Minerva
Not at all, Dolores
Merely your medieval methods
L'm sorry, dear
But to question my practices is
to question the ministry
And by extension, the minister himself
L'm a tolerant woman
But the 1 thing i won't stand
for is disloyalty
Disloyalty
Things at Hogwarts are far worse
than i feared
Cornelius will want to take immediate actions
What happened to Dumbledore?
Umbridge revolutionised the teaching
of defence against the dark art
Doleres Umbridge will as High Inquisitor
have powers
To adjust the seriously falling
standards of Hogwarts school
Just 1 question
You've been in this post for how
long exactly?
You ask first for the Defend
Againts the Dark Art Teacher
Ls that correct?
Yes
But you were unsuccessful
Obviously
Would you please predict something,
please?
L'm sorry
One tiny little propecy
Pity
No, wait... i think 1 do see something,
yes
L saw something dark
You're in a grave danger
Lovely...
Cho, what's going on?
Lt's professor, Trelawney
16 years i've been here to teach
Hogwarts is my home
You can't do this
Actually i can
Minerva
Something you'd like to say, dear?
Oh there're several things
i'd like to say
Prof McGonagall
May i ask you to escort Sybil
back inside?
Sybil, come here
Thank you, Dumbledore
Dumbledore, may i remind you
Under the tone of educational decree
23 as it acted by the minister
You've the right to dismiss my teacher
But you don't have the authority
to banish them from the garden
That power remained for the headmaster
For now
Don't you have studying to do?
Professor?
Professor Dumbledore? Professor?
Professor Dumbledore?
Foul evil Gargoyle!!
We aren't learning how to defend
ourselves
We aren't learning how to pass our OWLS
She's taking over the entire school
Security's and will remain the
ministry's top priority
Furthermore, we've convincing evidence
That these disappearances are
the work of...
The notorious mass murderer,
Sirius Black....
Harry
Sirius
What are you doing here?
Answering you your letter
You said you're worried about Umbridge
What's she doing? Training
you to kill the half-bred?
She isn't letting us to use magic at all
L'm not surprised
The latest intelligence says that Fudge
doesn't want you to train in combat
Combat?
He afraid we're forming some
sorta wizard army?
This's exactly what he thinks
That Dumbledore is assembling his
own forces to take on the ministry
He's becoming more crack on the edge
The others wouldn't want me to
tell you this, Harry
Things aren't going all well, the order
Fudge's blocking the truth in every turn
These disappearances as much
how it started before
Voldermort is on the move
What do we do?
Someone is coming, i'm sorry
i can't be more help
But for now, it looks like
you're on your own
He's out there isn't he?
We've gotta be able to defend ourselves
Lf Umbridge refuses to teach us
how we need someone who'll
Harry
This is mad,
who want to be tough by me?
L'm a nut, remember?
Look at the bright side.
You can't be any worse than her, anyway
Thanks, Ron
Anything, mate
Who supposed to make this?
Just a couple of people
Lovely spot.
Well, at least safer than being tracked
Hey come back here
Hi, So...
We know why we're here
We need a teacher
Proper teacher
One has really experienced to defend
himself against the dark arts
Why?
-Why?
Because you know who's back you toadpole
So as "HE" says
So as Dumbledore says
So Dumbledore says because He says?
The point is where's the proof?
Perhaps Harry could tell us more
about Diggory got killed
L'm not gonna talk about Cedric
If that is why you're here,
you might as well clear up now
Come on Hermione, let's go,
these are some sorts freaks
Ls that true you can produce petronus charm?
Yes
L've seen it
Blimey Harry, l don't
know you can do that?
He killed a Basilisk...
With a sword in Dumbledore's office
Lt's true
Third year he fought
about 100 dementor to 1
And last year he really did
fight who went to flash
Wait
Those sound great when you
say it like that, but...
Ln fact, i was just lucky
L didn't know what i was doing
half of the time
L nearly always had helped
He's just being modest
-No, Hermione, i'm not
Facing these stuff in real life isn't
like in school
Lt isn't like you made a mistake you
can try just try again tomorrow
But out there
When you're a second away from
being murdered
Or watching a friend die right
before your eyes
You don't know how it's like
You're right, Harry, we don't
That's why we need your help
Because the one we try of beating...
Voldermort
He's really back?
''Dumbledore Army''
1st we need to find a place where
Umbridge won't find out
The shrinking shack?
That's too small
Forbidden forest?
Too bloody horrible
Harry, what happened if Umbridge
does find out?
Who cares?
L mean... it''s exciting, isn't it?
Breaking the rules
Who are you and what have
you done to Hermoine Granger?
Anyway, at least we knew that is
1 positive thing that is coming in today...
What's that?
For the next few days we should...
Each come out for a couple of place we can use for practise
We gotta make sure Umbridge
won't find out this place
All student organisations disbanded
Watch where you're going Longbottom
You've done it Neville!
You have found the room of requirement
What?
This's also called come-and-go-room
The room only appears when
a person's immediate needs
And it always equips
with what the person needs
So, you really needed a toilet?
Charming really
Lt's great
Just like Hogwarts wants to fight back
"Expeliarmus"
L'm hopeless
You're just flourishing your wand
too much, try like this
"Expeliarmus"
Would you please copy your
whole text 4 times
To ensure maximum attention
You don't need to talk
L think it's more like it
Wands, away!
Stuning is the most useful spell in arsenal..
Lt's sorta a wizard fighting a battle
really
Come on, Nigel, give your best shot
Stupify
Good, not bad... at all
Don't worry about, Hermione,
I'll go easy
Thanks, Ron
Go on, Ron...
1 second
You're on!
"Stupify"
Thank you
-Shut up
L let her do that
It's embarassing
Lt's really my intention
''All students will submit to
questioning''
Come on, do you want a cup of tea?
Focus on the fixed point, try again
"Expeliarmus"
You need to keep your concentration...
Great
Aim Higher
L'm ok...
Working hard is important, there's
something about this even more...
Believing in yourself
Think of this, every great
wizard in history
Started out...
Nothing more than what we're now...
students
Lf they can do it, why not us?
"Expeliarumus"
Fantastic, well done, mate
So, that's it for this lesson
We aren't gonna be meeting again
until after the holidays
So just keep practising on
your own best you can
And well done, everyone,
great great work
Well done mate.
Thanks
See you after Christmas
See you in the common room Harry
Thanks a lot, Harry
Merry Christmas
Harry Merry Christmas
Have a merry christmas, Luna
We've been thinking, Harry
Sounds great, guys,
would you excuse me?
Are you alrite?
L heard Umbridge gave you a
hard time the other day
Yeah, i'm ok
Lt's worth it
Just... learning all these
Made me wonder maybe he would...
Cedric... gave me all these stuff
He was really good
Lt was just Voldermort was better
You're a really good teacher, Harry
L've never been able to
stunt anything before
Mistletoe
It keeps the Naragos out
What are Naragos?
L've no idea
Well, how was it?
Wet
L mean she was sorta crying
Not that bad, are you?
L'm sure Harry's kising's
more than satisfactory
Cho's been half of the time
crying these days
L bet snogging will cheer her up
You don't know how
she must be feeling?
Obviously she feel sad about Cedric
And now got more
confused now with Harry
Guilty about kissing him
And she worry about everything else
One person can fill all that...
They'll explode
It's because you've
got an emotional range of tea spoon!!!
"Voldermort maybe after something!"
"Something he didn't have last time!"
"Harry"
"Harry!"
In the dream, were you
standing next to the victim?
Or looking down at the scene?
Neither... It was like I'm who...
Professor would you please tell me what happening...
Everard, Arthur on guard at night
Make sure he is found by the right people.
Sir....
Phileus, you must go to
your potrait in the Grimould Place
Tell them Arthur Weasly is gravely injured
And his children will be
arriving there soon by portkey
They got it Albus...
It was close but they got in
What's more the Dark Lord failed to acquired...
Ah, thank you..
Look at me!!!
What's happening to me?
You wish to see me headmaster?
Oh Severus, I am very can't wait!
Not even in the morning!
Otherwise we will be vulnerable!
Its appear that there is a connection
between the Dark Lord minds and your own
Weather he is as yet aware of this connection
is not clear
Pray he remains ignorant
You mean if he knows about it,
He'll be able to read my mind.
Read it, controll it... and injured.
In the past it was often the Dark Lord pleasure
to invade the minds of his victims creating visions
Design to torture them to madness...
Only after extracting the last exquisit answer of agony
Only when they had literally begging for death he finally kill them
Use properly the power of Occlumency will help shield you from access or influence
In this lesson i will attemp to penetrate your mind
You will attemp to resist
Prepare yourself!!!
Concentrate POTTER...
Here we go...
Daddy's back
Sit down, everybody, sit down,
now's time for presents