I don 't know about you,
it's just too hot today, isn 't it?
And it's going to get even worse.
Temperatures in the mid-30s Celsius...
... that's the mid-90s Fahrenheit,
tomorrow, maybe even hitting 1 00.
So, please, remember to cover up
and stay cool...
... with the hottest hits on your FM dial.
Come on, guys, time to go home.
Come on, Iove, off you get.
-Do we have to?
-Yes, we do.
I'II make you your favorite dinner
to compensate.
He squeaIed Iike a pig, didn't he?
Yeah, briIIiant punch, Big D.
Did you see his face?
Hey, Big D.
Beat up another 1 0-year-oId?
-This one deserved it.
-Yeah.
-Five against one, very brave.
-WeII, you're one to taIk.
Moaning in your sIeep every night?
At Ieast I'm not afraid of my piIIow.
''Don't kiII Cedric. ''
Who's Cedric, your boyfriend?
-Shut up.
-''He's going to kiII me, Mum. ''
Where is your mum?
Where is your mum, Potter?
She dead?
Is she dead?
Is she a dead Pott--?
-DudIey.
-DudIey, Iet's go.
-What's going on?
-What are you doing?
-I'm not doing anything.
-We're getting out of here, DudIey.
Come on, DudIey, hurry up.
DudIey, run.
Expecto Patronum.
Mrs. Figg.
Don't put away your wand, Harry.
They might come back.
Dementors in LittIe Whinging,
whatever next?
-WhoIe worId's gone topsy-turvy.
-I don't understand. How do you know--?
DumbIedore asked me
to keep an eye on you.
DumbIedore asked you?
You know DumbIedore?
After You-Know-Who
kiIIed that poor Diggory boy Iast year. . .
. . .did you expect him to Iet you
go wandering on your own?
Good Lord, boy.
They toId me you were inteIIigent.
Now, get inside and stay there.
Expect someone wiII be in touch soon.
Whatever happens, don't Ieave the house.
It is hot. That's right, hot everywhere.
There's sweat. There's stifling.
Diddykins?
Is that you?
Duddy. Vernon, come quick.
We're going to have to
take him to a hospitaI.
Who did this to you, boy?
Happy, are we, now?
You've finaIIy done it.
You've finaIIy driven him Ioopy.
v ernon, don't say that.
WeII, just Iook at him, Petunia.
Our boy has gone yumpy.
I've reached my Iimit, do you hear?
This is the Iast I'm gonna take
of you and your nonsense.
-Dear Mr. Potter.
-What?
The Ministry has received inteIIigence
that at 6:23 this evening. . .
. . .you performed the Patronus Charm
in the presence of a MuggIe.
As a cIear vioIation. . .
. . .of the Decree for the ReasonabIe
Restriction of Underage Sorcery. . .
. . .you are hereby expeIIed. . .
. . .from Hogwarts SchooI
of Witchcraft and Wizardry.
Hoping you are weII, MafaIda Hopkirk.
Justice.
He's not very weII.
Sorry, Hedwig.
Very cIean, these MuggIes.
-Tonks, for God's sake.
-UnnaturaI.
Professor Moody.
-What are you doing here?
-Rescuing you, of course.
But where are we going?
The Ietter said I've been expeIIed.
You haven't been. Not yet.
KingsIey, you take point.
But the Ietter said--
DumbIedore persuaded the minister
to suspend your expuIsion. . .
-. . .pending a formaI hearing.
-A hearing?
Don't worry. We'II expIain everything
when we get back to headquarters.
Not here, Nymphadora.
Don't caII me Nymphadora.
Stay in formation, everyone.
Don't break ranks if one of us is kiIIed.
Come on, you, around the corner.
Come on.
In you go, son.
There've been no sightings.
No deaths. No proof.
He aImost kiIIed Harry.
If that isn't proof enough. . . .
Yes, but guarding you-know-what
is the most important. . . .
We must trust DumbIedore on this.
Was he abIe to protect Harry Iast year?
Tonight I say it's time to take action.
CorneIius Fudge is a poIitician first
and a wizard second.
-His instinct wouId be to ignore it--
-Keep your voices down.
He's getting stronger and stronger
by the minute. We have to act now.
-Harry.
-Mrs. WeasIey.
Heavens, you're aII right.
Bit peaky, but I'm afraid dinner wiII wait
untiI after the meeting's finished.
Nope. No time to expIain.
Straight upstairs, first door on the Ieft.
Yeah.
MudbIood, werewoIves,
traitors, thieves.
If my poor mistress
knew the scum they Iet into her house. . .
. . .what wouId she say to oId Kreacher?
Oh, the shame.
-Freaks.
-There, there, mistress.
Scum of the earth.
Not like it was in the days of my fathers.
Kreacher is here.
Oh, Harry.
Are you aII right? We overheard them
taIking about the Dementor attack.
-You must teII us everything.
-Let the man breathe, Hermione.
And this hearing at the Ministry.
It's just outrageous.
I've Iooked it up.
They simpIy can't expeI you.
-It's compIeteIy unfair.
-Yeah.
There's a Iot of that
going round at the moment.
So, what is this pIace?
-It's headquarters.
-Of the Order of the Phoenix.
It's a secret society.
DumbIedore formed it back when
they fought You-Know-Who.
CouIdn't have put any of this
in a Ietter, I suppose?
I've gone aII summer
without a scrap of news.
We wanted to write, mate.
ReaIIy, we did.
-OnIy. . . .
-OnIy what?
OnIy DumbIedore made us swear
not to teII you anything.
DumbIedore said that?
But why wouId he keep me in the dark?
Maybe I couId heIp.
I'm the one
who saw VoIdemort return. . .
. . .the one who fought him,
who saw Cedric Diggory get kiIIed.
-Harry.
-Thought we heard your duIcet tones.
-Don't bottIe it up, though. Let it out.
-If you're aII done shouting. . . .
Do you wanna hear something
a IittIe more interesting?
If anyone has a right to know, it's Harry.
If it wasn 't for Harry...
... we wouldn 't even know
Voldemort was back.
He's not a child, Molly.
But he's not an adult either.
-He's not James, Sirius.
-Well, he's not your son.
He's as good as.
-Who else has he got?
-Hey, Ginny.
-He's got me.
-How touchingly paternal, Black.
Perhaps Potter will grow up
to be a felon, just like his godfather.
Now, you stay out of this, Snivellus.
-Snape's part of the Order?
-Git.
--about your supposed reformation.
-I know better.
-So why don 't you tell him?
-Get off it.
-Quick.
-Get it up.
-Crookshanks.
-Stop it.
-Get off, you bIoody cat.
-Crookshanks. Leave it aIone.
-Get it up.
-Hermione, I hate your cat.
-Bad Crookshanks.
WeII, we'II be eating
down in the kitchen.
Just because you're aIIowed
to use magic now. . .
. . .does not mean you have to
whip your wands out for everything.
Hi, Mum.
You hungry, Harry?
You sure you're aII right, Harry?
Gave us quite a turn.
Harry Potter.
Sirius.
This is very, very pecuIiar.
It seems your hearing in the Ministry
is to be before the entire Wizengamot.
I don't understand. What has
the Ministry of Magic got against me?
Show him. He'II find out soon enough.
He's been attacking DumbIedore as weII.
Fudge is using aII his power, incIuding
his infIuence at the Daily Prophet...
. . .to smear anyone who cIaims
the Dark Lord has returned.
Why?
He thinks DumbIedore's after his job.
No one in their right mind
couId beIieve that--
ExactIy the point.
Fudge isn't in his right mind.
It's been twisted and warped by fear.
Now, fear makes peopIe
do terribIe things, Harry.
The Iast time
VoIdemort gained power. . .
. . .he aImost destroyed
everything we hoId most dear.
Now he's returned, and I'm afraid
the minister wiII do aImost anything. . .
. . .to avoid facing that terrifying truth.
We think VoIdemort
wants to buiId up his army again.
Fourteen years ago,
he had huge numbers at his command.
And not just witches and wizards,
but aII manner of dark creatures.
He's been recruiting heaviIy, and we've
been attempting to do the same.
But gathering foIIowers
isn't the onIy thing he's interested in.
We beIieve. . .
. . .VoIdemort may be after something.
Sirius.
Something he didn't have Iast time.
You mean Iike a weapon?
No. That's enough. He's just a boy.
You say more and you might as weII
induct him into the Order.
Good. I want to join. If v oIdemort's
raising an army, then I want to fight.
Harry.
You are hereby expelled.
Before the entire Wizengamot.
Trains. Underground.
Ingenious, these MuggIes.
Here we are.
I've never used the visitors' entrance
before. ShouId be fun.
Right. Good.
I'II just get my MuggIe money.
TerribIe. Lost a Iot of GaIIeons
trading on the potions market.
Daily Prophet, Iadies and gentIemen.
Anybody for Daily Prophet?
DumbIedore: Is he daft,
or is he dangerous?
-Morning, Arthur.
-Morning, Bob.
InterdepartmentaI memos.
We used to use owIs.
Mess was unbeIievabIe.
MerIin's beard. Thank you, KingsIey.
They've changed the time
of your hearing.
When is it?
In five minutes.
Department of Mysteries.
And I'm confident, minister,
that you wiII do the right thing.
Yes, but we must be--
Remember, during the hearing,
speak onIy when you're spoken to.
Keep caIm.
You've done nothing wrong.
As the MuggIes say, truth wiII out.
Yes?
I'm not aIIowed in, I'm afraid.
Good Iuck, Harry.
DiscipIinary hearing
of the 1 2th of August. . .
. . .into offenses committed
by Harry James Potter. . .
. . .resident at Number 4 Privet Drive,
LittIe Whinging, Surrey.
Interrogators: CorneIius OswaId Fudge,
Minister of Mag--
Witness for the defense.
AIbus PercivaI WuIfric. . .
. . .Brian DumbIedore.
You got our message
that the time and pIace of the hearing. . .
-. . .had been changed, did you?
-I must have missed it.
But by a happy mistake, I arrived
at the Ministry three hours earIy.
The charges?
The charges against the accused
are as foIIows:
''That he did knowingIy. . .
. . .and in fuII awareness
of the iIIegaIity of his actions. . .
. . .produce a Patronus Charm. . .
. . .in the presence of a MuggIe. ''
-Do you deny producing said Patronus?
-No, but--
And you were aware that you were
forbidden to use magic outside schooI. . .
-. . .whiIe under the age of 1 7?
-Yes, I was, but--
Witches and wizards
of the Wizengamot--
I was onIy doing it
because of the Dementors.
Dementors?
In LittIe Whinging?
That's quite cIever.
MuggIes can't see Dementors,
can they, boy?
-HighIy convenient.
-I'm not Iying.
-There were two of them, if I hadn't--
-Enough.
I'm sorry to interrupt what I'm sure
wouId be a very weII-rehearsed story. . .
. . .but since you can produce
no witnesses of the event--
Pardon me, minister,
but as it happens, we can.
PIease describe the attack.
What did they Iook Iike?
WeII, one of them was very Iarge
and the other rather skinny.
Not the boys. The Dementors.
Oh, right, right. WeII, big.
CIoaked. Then everything went coId. . .
. . .as though aII the happiness
had gone from the worId.
Now, Iook here. Dementors don't just
wander into a MuggIe suburb. . .
. . .and happen across a wizard.
The odds are astronomicaI.
I don't think anyone wouId beIieve. . .
. . .the Dementors were there
by coincidence, minister.
I'm sure I must have misunderstood you,
professor.
Dementors are, after aII, under
the controI of the Ministry of Magic.
And it's so siIIy of me, but it sounded
for a moment as though. . .
. . .you were suggesting that the Ministry
had ordered the attack on this boy.
That wouId be disturbing indeed,
Madam Undersecretary. . .
. . .which is why I'm sure the Ministry
wiII be mounting a fuII-scaIe inquiry. . .
. . .into why the two Dementors
were so very far from Azkaban. . .
. . .and why they mounted an attack
without authorization.
Of course, there is someone. . .
. . .who might be behind the attack.
CorneIius, I impIore you to see reason.
The evidence that the Dark Lord
has returned is incontrovertibIe.
He is not back.
In the matter of Harry Potter. . .
. . .the Iaw cIearIy states. . .
. . .that magic may be used before
MuggIes in Iife-threatening situations.
Laws can be changed if necessary,
DumbIedore.
CIearIy. Has it become practice
to hoId a fuII criminaI triaI. . .
. . .to deaI with a simpIe matter
of underage magic?
Those in favor of conviction?
Those in favor
of cIearing the accused of aII charges?
CIeared of aII charges.
Professor.
Padfoot. Are you barking mad?
You'II bIow the entire operation.
Sirius, what are you doing here?
If somebody sees you. . . .
I had to see you off, didn't I?
What's Iife without a IittIe risk?
I don't wanna see you
get chucked back in Azkaban.
Don't worry about me.
Anyway, I wanted you to have this.
OriginaI Order of the Phoenix.
MarIene McKinnon.
She was kiIIed
two weeks after this was taken.
VoIdemort wiped out her entire famiIy.
Frank and AIice Longbottom.
NeviIIe's parents.
They suffered a fate worse than death,
you ask me.
It's been 1 4 years.
And stiII a day doesn't go by
I don't miss your dad.
Do you reaIIy think
there's going to be a war, Sirius?
It feeIs Iike it did before.
You keep it.
Anyway, I suppose
you're the young ones now.
I'II see you at the train.
Bye-bye, darIing.
I Iove you.
HoId my hand, Iovey.
There they are.
They're in the far carriage.
Bye.
I'm surprised the Ministry's
stiII Ietting you waIk around free.
Better enjoy it whiIe you can.
I expect there's a ceII in Azkaban
with your name on it.
-What'd I teII you? CompIete nutter.
-Just stay away from me!
It's onIy MaIfoy.
What'd you expect?
Hi, guys.
-Hey, NeviIIe.
-Hey there, NeviIIe.
What is it?
-What's what?
-That. PuIIing the carriage.
Nothing's puIIing the carriage, Harry.
It's puIIing itseIf, Iike aIways.
You're not going mad.
I can see them too.
You're just as sane as I am.
Everyone, this is Loony Love--
Luna Lovegood.
What an interesting neckIace.
It's a charm, actuaIIy.
Keeps away the NargIes.
Hungry.
I hope there's pudding.
-What's a NargIe?
-No idea.
Good evening, chiIdren.
Now, we have two changes
in staffing this year.
We're pIeased to weIcome back
Professor GrubbIy-PIank. . .
. . .who'II be taking
Care of MagicaI Creatures. . .
. . .whiIe Professor Hagrid
is on temporary Ieave.
We aIso wish to weIcome our new
Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher. . .
. . .Professor DoIores Umbridge.
And I'm sure you'II aII join me
in wishing the professor good Iuck.
Now, as usuaI, our caretaker, Mr. FiIch,
has asked me to remind you--
She was at my hearing.
She works for Fudge.
www.myvideo.tk
Thank you, headmaster,
for those kind words of weIcome.
And how IoveIy to see aII your bright. . .
. . .happy faces smiIing up at me.
I'm sure we're aII going
to be very good friends.
-That's IikeIy.
The Ministry of Magic
has aIways considered. . .
. . .the education of young witches
and wizards to be of vitaI importance.
AIthough each headmaster. . .
. . .has brought something new
to this historic schooI. . .
. . .progress for the sake of progress
must be discouraged.
Let us preserve
what must be preserved. . .
. . .perfect what can be perfected. . .
. . .and prune practices
that ought to be prohibited.
Thank you, Professor Umbridge.
That reaIIy was most iIIuminating.
-IIIuminating? What a Ioad of waffIe.
-What's it mean?
Magic is forbidden in the corridors. . . .
It means the Ministry's
interfering at Hogwarts.
Dean, Seamus.
-Good hoIiday?
-AII right.
Better than Seamus', anyway.
Me mum didn't want me
to come back this year.
-Why not?
-Let me see. Because of you.
The Daily Prophet's been saying a Iot
of things about you and DumbIedore.
What, your mum beIieves them?
Nobody was there
the night Cedric died.
I guess you shouId read the Prophet,
then, Iike your stupid mother.
-Don't taIk about my mother.
-I'II have a go at anyone caIIing me a Iiar.
-What's going on?
-He's mad, is what's going on.
Do you beIieve the rubbish he's
come out with about You-Know-Who?
Yeah. I do.
Has anyone eIse
got a probIem with Harry?
-You aII right?
-Fine.
Seamus was bang out of order, mate.
-But he'II come through, you'II see.
-I said, I'm fine, Ron.
Right. I'II just Ieave you
to your thoughts, then.
Harry.
Bring it over here. Over here.
Oh, go on, Seamus. Go on, get it.
Good morning, chiIdren.
Ordinary Wizarding LeveI examinations.
O-W-Ls.
More commonIy known as OWLs.
Study hard and you wiII be rewarded.
FaiI to do so,
and the consequences may be severe.
Your previous instruction in this subject
has been disturbingIy uneven.
But you'II be pIeased to know,
from now on. . .
. . .you wiII be foIIowing a carefuIIy
structured, Ministry-approved. . .
. . .course of defensive magic. Yes?
There's nothing in here
about using defensive speIIs?
Using speIIs?
WeII, I can't imagine why you wouId
need to use speIIs in my cIassroom.
We're not gonna use magic?
You'II be Iearning about defensive speIIs
in a secure, risk-free way.
What use is that?
If we're attacked, it won't be risk-free.
Students wiII raise their hands
when they speak in my cIass.
It is the view of the Ministry. . .
. . .that a theoreticaI knowIedge
wiII be sufficient. . .
. . .to get you through
your examinations. . .
. . .which, after aII,
is what schooI is aII about.
And how's theory supposed
to prepare us for what's out there?
There is nothing out there, dear.
Who do you imagine
wants to attack chiIdren Iike yourseIf?
Oh, I don't know.
Maybe Lord VoIdemort.
Now, Iet me make this quite pIain.
You have been toId. . .
. . .that a certain dark wizard
is at Iarge once again.
-This is a Iie.
-It's not a Iie. I saw him. I fought him.
Detention, Mr. Potter.
Cedric Diggory dropped dead
of his own accord?
Cedric Diggory's death
was a tragic accident.
It was murder. VoIdemort kiIIed him.
Enough!
Enough.
See me Iater, Mr. Potter. My office.
Come in.
Good evening, Mr. Potter.
Sit.
You're going to be doing some Iines
for me today, Mr. Potter.
No, not with your quiII.
Going to be using
a rather speciaI one of mine.
Now. . .
. . .I want you to write,
''I must not teII Iies. ''
How many times?
WeII, Iet's say for as Iong as it takes
for the message to sink in.
You haven't given me any ink.
Oh, you won't need any ink.
Yes?
-Nothing.
-That's right.
Because you know, deep down. . .
. . .you deserve to be punished.
Don't you, Mr. Potter?
Go on.
-Skiving Snackboxes.
-Sweets that make you iII.
Get out of cIass whenever you Iike.
Obtain hours of pIeasure
from unprofitabIe boredom.
Care for another?
-I'm not asking you to write aII of it.
-PIease.
I've been busy studying
for these stupid OWL exams.
I'II do the introduction. That's aII.
Hermione, you're honestIy the most
wonderfuI person I've ever met.
-And if I'm ever rude to you again. . . .
-I'II know you've gone back to normaI.
What's wrong with your hand?
Nothing.
The other hand.
-You've got to teII DumbIedore.
-No.
DumbIedore's got enough
on his mind right now.
I don't want to give
Umbridge the satisfaction.
BIoody heII, Harry.
The woman's torturing you.
-If the parents knew about this. . . .
-I haven't got any of those, have I, Ron?
Harry, you've got to report this.
-It's perfectIy simpIe. You're being--
-No, it's not.
Hermione, whatever this is,
it's not simpIe.
You don't understand.
Then heIp us to.
Dear Padfoot...
...I hope you're all right.
It's starting to get colder here.
Winter is definitely on the way.
In spite of being back at Hogwarts,
I feel more alone than ever.
I know you, of all people,
will understand.
HeIIo, Harry Potter.
-Your feet. Aren't they coId?
-Bit.
UnfortunateIy, aII my shoes
have mysteriousIy disappeared.
I suspect NargIes are behind it.
-What are they?
-They're caIIed ThestraIs.
They're quite gentIe, reaIIy, but peopIe
avoid them because they're a bit. . . .
Different.
But why can't the others see them?
They can onIy be seen
by peopIe who've seen death.
So you've known someone
who's died, then?
My mum.
She was quite an extraordinary witch,
but she did Iike to experiment. . .
. . .and one day,
one of her speIIs went badIy wrong.
-I was 9.
-I'm sorry.
Yes, it was rather horribIe.
I do feeI very sad about it sometimes,
but I've got Dad.
We both beIieve you, by the way.
That He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named
is back, and you fought him. . .
. . .and the Ministry and the Prophet
are conspiring against you.
Thanks. It seems you're about
the onIy ones that do.
I don't think that's true.
But I suppose
that's how he wants you to feeI.
What do you mean?
WeII, if I were You-Know-Who. . .
. . .I'd want you to feeI cut off
from everyone eIse. . .
. . .because if it's just you aIone. . .
. . .you're not as much of a threat.
-Do you ever stop eating?
-What? I'm hungry.
Harry.
Can I join you?
Pardon me, professor,
but what exactIy are you insinuating?
I am mereIy requesting
that when it comes to my students. . .
. . .you conform to the prescribed
discipIinary practices.
So siIIy of me, but it sounds. . .
. . .as if you're questioning my authority
in my own cIassroom. . .
. . .Minerva.
Not at aII, DoIores,
mereIy your medievaI methods.
I am sorry, dear.
But to question my practices
is to question the Ministry. . .
. . .and by extension,
the minister himseIf.
I am a toIerant woman. . .
. . .but the one thing
I wiII not stand for is disIoyaIty.
DisIoyaIty.
Things at Hogwarts
are far worse than I feared.
CorneIius wiII want
to take immediate action.
What's happened to DumbIedore?
Having already revolutionized...
... the teaching
of Defense Against the Dark Arts...
...Dolores Umbridge will,
as high inquisitor, have powers...
. . .to address the seriousIy faIIing
standards at Hogwarts SchooI.
Just one question, dear.
You've been in this post
how Iong, exactIy?
You appIied first for the Defense Against
the Dark Arts post, is that correct?
Yes.
But you were unsuccessfuI?
ObviousIy.
CouId you pIease predict something
for me?
I'm sorry?
Move those mouths.
One teensy IittIe prophecy?
Pity.
No, wait. Wait, no.
I think I do see something.
Yes, I do. Something dark.
You are in grave danger.
LoveIy.
Cho. What's going on?
It's Professor TreIawney.
Sixteen years I've Iived
and taught here.
Hogwarts is my home.
You can't do this.
ActuaIIy, I can.
Something you'd Iike to say?
Oh, there are severaI things
I wouId Iike to say.
There. . . .
Professor McGonagaII, might I ask you
to escort SybiI back inside?
SybiI, dear. This way.
Thank you.
DumbIedore, may I remind you
that under the terms. . .
. . .of EducationaI Decree Number 23,
as enacted by the minister--
You have the right
to dismiss my teachers.
You do not, however, have the authority
to banish them from the grounds.
That power remains
with the headmaster.
For now.
Don't you aII have studying to do?
Professor.
Professor?
Professor DumbIedore. Professor!
Professor DumbIedore.
That foul, evil, old gargoyle.
We're not Iearning
how to defend ourseIves.
how to pass our OWLs.
She's taking over the entire schooI.
Security has been and will remain
the Ministry's top priority.
Furthermore,
we have convincing evidence...
... that these disappearances
are the work...
...of notorious
mass murderer Sirius Black.
Harry.
Sirius.
-What are you doing here?
-Answering your Ietter.
You said you were worried
about Umbridge. What's she doing?
Training you to kiII haIf-breeds?
-She's not Ietting us use magic at aII.
-WeII, I'm not surprised.
The Iatest inteIIigence is that Fudge
doesn't want you trained in combat.
Combat?
What does he think,
we're forming some sort of wizard army?
That's exactIy what he thinks.
That DumbIedore is assembIing
his own forces to take on the Ministry.
He's becoming more paranoid
by the minute.
The others wouIdn't want me
teIIing you this, Harry. . .
. . .but things aren't going at aII weII
with the Order.
Fudge is bIocking the truth
at every turn. . .
. . .and these disappearances
are just how it started before.
VoIdemort is on the move.
WeII, what can we do?
Someone's coming.
I'm sorry I can't be of more heIp.
But for now, at Ieast,
it Iooks Iike you're on your own.
He reaIIy is out there, isn't he?
We've got to be abIe
to defend ourseIves.
And if Umbridge refuses to teach us
how, we need someone who wiII.
Harry.
This is mad.
Who'd wanna be taught by me?
I'm a nutter, remember?
Look on the bright side: you can't be
any worse than oId toad face.
-Thanks, Ron.
-I'm here for you, mate.
Who's supposed to be meeting us, then?
Just a coupIe of peopIe.
LoveIy spot.
Thought it wouId be safer
off the beaten track.
Matey, come back here.
Hi.
So you aII know why we're here.
We need a teacher.
A proper teacher.
One who's had experience defending
themseIves against the Dark Arts.
-Why?
Because You-Know-Who's back,
you tosspot.
-So he says.
-So DumbIedore says.
So DumbIedore says because he says.
The point is, where's the proof?
If Potter couId teII us more
about how Diggory got kiIIed. . . .
I'm not gonna taIk about Cedric, so if
that's why you're here, cIear out now.
Come on, Hermione. They're here
because they think I'm some freak.
Is it true you can produce
a Patronus Charm?
Yes.
I've seen it.
BIimey, Harry.
I didn't know you couId do that.
And he kiIIed a basiIisk, with the sword
in DumbIedore's office.
It's true.
Third year, he fought off
about a hundred Dementors at once.
Last year, he reaIIy did fight off
You-Know-Who in the fIesh.
Wait.
Look, it aII sounds great
when you say it Iike that. . .
. . .but the truth is,
most of that was just Iuck.
I didn't know what I was doing
haIf the time. I nearIy aIways had heIp.
-He's just being modest.
-No, Hermione, I'm not.
Facing this stuff in reaI Iife
is not Iike schooI.
In schooI, if you make a mistake,
you can just try again tomorrow.
But out there. . .
. . .when you're a second away
from being murdered. . .
. . .or watching a friend die
right before your eyes. . . .
You don't know what that's Iike.
You're right, Harry, we don't.
That's why we need your heIp.
Because if we're going to have
any chance at beating. . .
. . .VoIdemort. . . .
He's reaIIy back.
Right. First we need to find
a pIace to practice. . .
. . .where Umbridge won't find out.
-The Shrieking Shack.
-It's too smaII.
-Forbidden Forest?
-Not bIoody IikeIy.
Harry, what happens
if Umbridge does find out?
Who cares?
I mean, it's sort of exciting, isn't it,
breaking the ruIes?
Who are you and what have you done
with Hermione?
Anyway, at Ieast we know
one positive thing that came from today.
What's that?
Cho couIdn't take her eyes off you,
couId she?
Right. Over the next few days,
we shouId each come up. . .
. . .with a coupIe of possibiIities
of pIaces we can practice.
We've got to make sure, wherever it is,
there's no chance she can find us.
WiII do, Harry.
All student organizations
are henceforth disbanded.
Any student in noncompliance
will be expelled.
Watch where you're going,
Longbottom.
You've done it, Neville.
You found the Room of Requirement.
The what?
It's aIso known as
the Come and Go Room.
The Room of Requirement onIy appears
when a person has reaI need of it.
And it's aIways equipped
for the seeker's needs.
So say you reaIIy needed the toiIet. . . .
Charming, RonaId.
But, yes, that is the generaI idea.
It's briIIiant. It's Iike Hogwarts
wants us to fight back.
Expelliarmus.
I'm hopeIess.
You're just fIourishing your wand
too much. Try it Iike this. Expelliarmus.
You wiII pIease copy
the approved text four times. . .
. . .to ensure maximum retention.
-There wiII be no need to taIk.
-No need to think's more Iike it.
-Expelliarmus.
-Wands away.
Stunning is one of the most usefuI speIIs
in your arsenaI.
It's a wizard's bread and butter, reaIIy.
So come on, then, NigeI.
Give it your best shot.
Stupefy!
Good. Not bad at aII, NigeI. WeII done.
Don't worry. I'II go easy on you.
Thanks, RonaId.
-Come on, Ron.
-You can do it.
-One SickIe.
-You're on.
Stupefy.
-Thank you.
-Shut up.
I Iet her do that.
It's good manners, isn't it?
It was compIeteIy intentionaI.
Up you come.
WouId you Iike a cup of tea?
Now, focus on a fixed point
and try again.
Expelliarmus.
Very good. Keep your concentration.
Great.
A IittIe higher.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
-Stupefy.
Those wishing to join
the Inquisitorial Squad for extra credit...
...may sign up
in the high inquisitor's office.
Diminuendo.
Working hard is important, but there's
something that matters even more:
BeIieving in yourseIf.
-Expelliarmus.
-Levicorpus. Got it.
Think of it this way.
Every great wizard in history
has started out. . .
. . .as nothing more
than what we are now: students.
If they can do it, why not us?
-Stupefy.
-Expelliarmus.
Expelliarmus.
Reducto.
-Expelliarmus.
Expelliarmus.
Fantastic, NeviIIe. WeII done, man.
So that's it for this Iesson.
Now, we're not gonna be meeting again
untiI after the hoIidays.
So just keep practicing on your own
as best you can.
And weII done, everyone.
Great, great work.
WeII done, mate.
Thanks.
See you after Christmas.
See you in the Common Room, Harry.
-Thanks a Iot, Harry.
-No worries.
-Thank you so much.
-Not at aII. Merry Christmas.
-Thank you, Harry.
-Thank you. Merry Christmas.
-Merry Christmas.
-Have a good Christmas.
-Have a great Christmas, Luna.
-We've been thinking.
We couId aIways sIip Umbridge
some Puking PastiIIes.
Or Fever Fudge. They give you
massive, pus-fiIIed boiIs--
Sounds great, guys.
WouId you excuse me?
Are you aII right? I heard Umbridge
gave you a rough time the other day.
Yeah. I'm okay.
Anyway, it's worth it.
It's just, Iearning aII this. . .
. . .makes me wonder whether,
if he'd known it. . . .
Cedric did know this stuff.
He was reaIIy good.
It's just, v oIdemort was better.
You're a reaIIy good teacher, Harry.
I've never been abIe
to stun anything before.
MistIetoe.
ProbabIy fuII of NargIes, though.
What are NargIes?
No idea.
Well, how was it?
Wet.
I mean, she was sort of crying.
That bad at it, are you?
I'm sure Harry's kissing
was more than satisfactory.
Cho spends haIf her time
crying these days.
You'd think a bit of snogging
wouId cheer her up.
Don't you understand
how she must be feeIing?
WeII, obviousIy
she's feeIing sad about Cedric. . .
. . .and confused about Iiking Harry
and guiIty about kissing him. . .
. . .confIicted because Umbridge might
sack her mum from the Ministry. . .
. . .and frightened of faiIing her OWLs
because she's worrying about everything.
One person couIdn't feeI aII that.
They'd expIode.
Just because you've got
the emotionaI range of a teaspoon. . . .
Harry.
Voldemort may be after something.
Something he didn 't have last time.
Harry.
In the dream,
were you standing next to the victim. . .
. . .or Iooking down at the scene?
Neither. It was Iike I. . . .
WiII you pIease just teII me
what's happening?
Everard, Arthur's on guard duty
tonight.
Make sure he's found
by the right peopIe.
-Sir.
-Phineas.
You must go to your portrait
at GrimmauId PIace.
TeII them that Arthur WeasIey
is graveIy injured. . .
. . .and his chiIdren wiII be arriving there
soon by Portkey.
They've got him, AIbus. It was cIose,
but they think he'II make it.
What's more,
the Dark Lord faiIed to acquire it.
Oh, thank goodness. Next we need to--
Look at me!
What's happening to me?
You wished to see me, headmaster?
Oh, Severus. I'm afraid we can't wait.
Not even tiII the morning.
Otherwise, we'II aII be vuInerabIe.
It appears there's a connection. . .
. . .between the Dark Lord's mind
and your own.
Whether he is, as yet, aware of this
connection is, for the moment, uncIear.
Pray he remains ignorant.
You mean, if he knows about it, then. . .
-. . .he'II be abIe to read my mind?
-Read it, controI it. . .
. . .unhinge it.
In the past, it was often
the Dark Lord's pIeasure. . .
. . .to invade the minds of his victims. . .
. . .creating visions designed
to torture them into madness.
OnIy after extracting the Iast exquisite
ounce of agony. . .
. . .onIy when he had them IiteraIIy
begging for death, wouId he finaIIy. . .
. . .kiII them.
Used properIy,
the power of OccIumency. . .
. . .wiII heIp shieId you
from access or infIuence.
In these Iessons, I wiII attempt
to penetrate your mind.
You wiII attempt to resist.
Prepare yourseIf.
Legilimens.
Concentrate, Potter. Focus.
Ho, ho, ho. Merry Christmas.
Here we go.
Daddy's back.
Sit down, everybody, sit down.
That's it. Now, presents.
-And a nice big box for Ron.
-Big box for you. And. . . .
Fred and George. Come on, open up.
-I want to see your faces.
-Yes.
-Try it on.
-Thanks, Mum. It's perfect.
-Just what he wanted, actuaIIy.
-Yeah. Right. Thanks, Mum.
Come on, then, everybody.
Let's cIear this away.
Oh, Harry, Harry.
There you are.
-Happy Christmas.
-Thank you.
-LoveIy to have you with us.
Now, Daddy. Pass that to Daddy.
-Thank you.
-Has everybody got?
Fred? George?
-Hermione.
-A Christmas toast.
To Mr. Harry Potter. . .
. . .without whom I wouId not be here.
-Harry.
Harry.
That is deIicious.
I shaII be needing some more of that.
Daddy, don't forget Iast Christmas.
I can't understand
why you don't want to wear it, RonaId.
I Iook Iike a bIoody idiot, that's why.
No more than usuaI, Ron.
I don't know why. . . .
Nasty brat, standing there
as boId as brass.
Harry Potter,
the boy who stopped the Dark Lord.
Friend of MudbIoods
and bIood-traitors aIike.
-If my poor mistress onIy knew. . . .
-Kreacher!
That's enough of your biIe.
Away with you!
Of course, master.
Kreacher Iives to serve
the nobIe house of BIack.
Sorry about that.
He never was very pIeasant,
even when I was a boy.
Not to me, anyway.
What, you grew up here?
This is my parents' house.
I offered it to DumbIedore
as headquarters for the Order.
About the onIy usefuI thing
I've been abIe to do.
This is the BIack famiIy tree.
My deranged cousin.
I hated the Iot of them.
My parents with their pure-bIood mania.
My mother did that after I ran away.
Charming woman.
I was 1 6.
Where did you go?
Round your dad's.
I was aIways weIcome at the Potters' .
I see him so much in you, Harry.
You are so very much aIike.
I'm not so sure.
Sirius, when I was. . . .
When I saw Mr. WeasIey attacked,
I wasn't just watching.
I was the snake.
And afterwards,
in DumbIedore's office. . .
. . .there was a moment
when I wanted to--
This connection
between me and VoIdemort.
What if the reason for it
is that I am becoming more Iike him?
I just feeI so angry aII the time.
And what if, after everything
that I've been through. . .
. . .something's gone wrong inside me?
What if I'm becoming bad?
I want you to Iisten to me
very carefuIIy, Harry.
You're not a bad person.
You're a very good person
who bad things have happened to.
You understand?
Besides, the worId isn't spIit
into good peopIe and Death Eaters.
We've aII got both Iight and dark
inside of us.
What matters
is the part we choose to act on.
That's who we reaIIy are.
Harry, time to go.
When aII this is over,
we'II be a proper famiIy.
You'II see.
Come on.
ReaIIy?
Harry. Harry.
Hagrid's back.
I'm sorry.
I wiII say this one Iast time.
I'm ordering you to teII me
where you've been.
I toId you. I've been away
for me heaIth.
-Your heaIth?
-Yeah. Bit of fresh air, you know.
Oh, yes. As gamekeeper,
fresh air must be difficuIt to come by.
If I were you,
I shouIdn't get too used to being back.
In fact, I mightn't bother
unpacking at aII.
This is top-secret, right?
DumbIedore sent me
to parIey with the giants.
Giants?
You found them?
WeII, they're not that hard to find, to be
perfectIy honest. They're so big, see?
I tried to convince them
to join the cause.
But I wasn't the onIy one
that was trying to win them over.
-Death Eaters?
-Yes.
Trying to persuade them
to join You-Know-Who.
-Did they?
-I gave them DumbIedore's message.
Suppose some of them remember
he was friendIy to them. I suppose.
And they did this to you?
Not exactIy, no.
Oh, go on, you have it, then,
you dozy dog.
It's changing out there.
Just Iike Iast time.
There's a storm coming, Harry.
We'd aII best be ready when she does.
We have confirmed
that 1 0 high-security prisoners...
...in the early hours of yesterday evening
did escape.
And of course, the Muggle prime minister
has been alerted to the danger.
We strongly suspect...
. . .that the breakout was engineered. . .
. . .by a man with personaI experience
in escaping from Azkaban. . .
. . .notorious mass murderer Sirius BIack. . .
...cousin of escapee
Bellatrix Lestrange.
DumbIedore warned Fudge
this couId happen.
He's gonna get us aII kiIIed
just because he can't face the truth.
Harry.
I wanted to apoIogize.
Now even me mum says the Prophet's
version of things don't add up.
So, what I'm reaIIy trying to say
is that I beIieve you.
NeviIIe?
Fourteen years ago. . .
. . .a Death Eater
named BeIIatrix Lestrange. . .
. . .used a Cruciatus Curse
on my parents.
She tortured them for information. . .
. . .but they never gave in.
I'm quite proud to be their son.
But I'm not sure I'm ready
for everyone to know just yet.
We're gonna make them proud, NeviIIe.
That's a promise.
Make it a powerfuI memory,
the happiest you can remember.
AIIow it to fiII you up.
Keep trying, Seamus.
George, your turn now.
Expecto Patronum.
A fuII-bodied Patronus
is the most difficuIt to produce. . .
. . .but shieId forms can aIso be equaIIy
usefuI against a variety of opponents.
Wow, that was reaIIy good.
Fantastic, Ginny.
Just remember, your Patronus can onIy
protect you for as Iong as you stay focused.
So focus, Luna.
Think of the happiest thing you can.
Expecto Patronum.
-I'm trying.
-I know. It's good.
This is reaIIy advanced stuff, guys.
You're doing so weII.
Expecto Patronum.
I'II make short work of this.
Bombarda Maxima.
Get them.
Been watching them for weeks.
And see, ''DumbIedore's Army'' . . .
. . .proof of what I've been teIIing you
right from the beginning, CorneIius.
AII your fear-mongering
about You-Know-Who. . .
. . .never fooIed us for a minute.
We saw your Iies for what they were:
A smokescreen for your bid
to seize controI of the Ministry.
NaturaIIy.
No, professor.
He had nothing to do with it. It was me.
Most nobIe of you, Harry, to shieId me,
but as has been pointed out. . .
. . .the parchment cIearIy says
''DumbIedore's Army,'' not ''Potter's. ''
I instructed Harry
to form this organization.
And I, and I aIone,
am responsibIe for its activities.
Dispatch an owI to the Daily Prophet.
If we hurry, we shouId stiII make
the morning edition.
DawIish, ShackIeboIt,
you wiII escort DumbIedore. . .
. . .to Azkaban. . .
. . .to await triaI
for conspiracy and sedition.
I thought we might hit this IittIe snag.
You seem to be Iaboring
under the deIusion that I'm going to--
What was the phrase?
--come quietIy.
WeII, I can teII you this:
I have no intention
of going to Azkaban.
Enough of this.
Take him.
WeII, you may not Iike him, minister. . .
. . .but you can't deny. . .
. . .DumbIedore has got styIe.
Boys and girls are not permitted
to be within eight inches of each other.
Those wishing to join
the Inquisitorial Squad for extra credit....
Students will be submitted to questioning
about suspected illicit activities.
Any student in noncompliance
will be expelled.
Harry.
You did everything you couId.
No one couId win against that oId hag.
Even DumbIedore
didn't see this coming.
Harry, if it's anyone's fauIt, it's ours.
Yeah, we taIked you into it.
Yeah, but I agreed.
I tried so hard to heIp,
and aII it's done is make things worse.
Anyway, that doesn't matter anymore.
Because I don't want to pIay anymore.
AII it does is make you care too much.
And the more you care,
the more you have to Iose.
-So maybe it's just better to. . . .
-To what?
To go it aIone.
Hagrid.
Any idea where he's taking us?
Hagrid, why can't you just teII us?
I've never seen the centaurs so riIed.
And they're dangerous
at the best of times.
The Ministry restricts
their territory much more. . .
. . .they'II have a fuII uprising
on their hands.
Hagrid, what's going on?
I'm sorry to be so mysterious, you three.
I wouIdn't be bothering you at aII with it,
but with DumbIedore gone. . .
. . .I'II IikeIy be getting the sack
any day now.
And I just couIdn't Ieave
without teIIing someone about him.
Grawpy.
Down here, you great buffoon.
Brought you some company.
I couIdn't just Ieave him, because--
Because he's my brother.
BIimey.
WeII, haIf brother, reaIIy.
He's compIeteIy harmIess, just Iike I said.
LittIe high-spirited, is aII.
-Grawpy, that is not poIite.
-Hagrid, do something.
We taIked about this.
You do not grab, do you?
That's your new friend, Hermione.
Grawpy.
Grawp.
Put me down.
Now.
You aII right?
Fine.
Just needs a firm hand, is aII.
I think you've got an admirer.
You just stay away from her, aII right?
He gets his own food and aII.
It's company he'II be needing
when I'm gone.
You wiII Iook after him, won't you?
I'm the onIy famiIy he's got.
FeeIing sentimentaI?
-That's private.
-Not to me.
And not to the Dark Lord,
if you don't improve.
Every memory he has access to
is a weapon he can use against you.
You won't Iast two seconds
if he invades your mind.
You're just Iike your father.
Lazy, arrogant.
-Don't say a word against my father.
-Weak.
-I'm not weak.
-Then prove it.
ControI your emotions.
DiscipIine your mind.
Legilimens.
Harry.
Sirius.
I may vomit.
Stop it.
Is this what you caII controI?
We've been at it for hours.
If I couId just rest.
The Dark Lord isn't resting.
You and BIack, you're two of a kind.
SentimentaI chiIdren forever whining
about how unfair your Iives have been.
WeII, it may have escaped your notice,
but Iife isn't fair.
Your bIessed father knew that.
In fact, he frequentIy saw to it.
-My father was a great man.
-Your father was a swine.
-Legilimens.
-Protego.
Come on, Moony, Padfoot.
Snape. Expelliarmus.
Nice one, James.
-Dad.
-Impedimenta.
Snivellus Greasy.
Right. Who wants to see me
take off SniveIIy's trousers?
Snivellus Greasy.
Enough.
Your Iessons are at an end.
I--
Get out.
-What's your name?
-MichaeI.
Your hand's gonna be fine, MichaeI.
Yeah. It's not as bad as it seems. See?
It's fading aIready.
You can hardIy see ours anymore,
and the pain stops after a whiIe.
As I toId you once before, Mr. Potter. . .
. . .naughty chiIdren
deserve to be punished.
You know, George. . .
. . .I've aIways feIt our futures Iay outside
the worId of academic achievement.
Fred, I've been thinking
exactIy the same thing.
AII right, professor!
Here you go.
Ready when you are.
I need that prophecy.
You'II have to kiII me.
Oh, I wiII.
But first, you wiII fetch it for me.
www.myvideo.tk
Crucio.
Sirius.
Harry, are you sure?
I saw it. It's just Iike
with Mr. WeasIey.
It's the door I've been dreaming about.
I couIdn't remember
where I'd seen it before.
Sirius said VoIdemort
was after something.
Something he didn't have the Iast time,
in the Department of Mysteries.
Harry, pIease, just Iisten.
What if VoIdemort
meant for you to see this?
What if he's onIy hurting Sirius
because he's trying to get to you?
What if he is?
I'm supposed to just Iet him die?
Hermione,
he's the onIy famiIy I've got Ieft.
What do we do?
We'II have to use the FIoo Network.
Umbridge has the chimneys
under surveiIIance.
Not aII of them.
Alohomora.
AIert the Order if you can.
-Are you mentaI? We're going with you.
-It's too dangerous.
When are you going to get it
into your head? We're in this together.
That you are.
Caught this one
trying to heIp the WeasIey girI.
You were going to DumbIedore,
weren't you?
-No.
-Liar.
-You sent for me, headmistress?
-Snape, yes.
The time has come for answers, whether
he wants to give them to me or not.
Have you brought the Veritaserum?
I'm afraid you've used up
aII my stores interrogating students.
The Iast of it on Miss Chang.
UnIess you wish to poison him--
And I assure you, I wouId have
the greatest sympathy if you did.
--I cannot heIp you.
He's got Padfoot.
He's got Padfoot at the pIace
where it's hidden.
Padfoot? What is Padfoot?
Where what is hidden?
What is he taIking about, Snape?
No idea.
Very weII.
You give me no choice, Potter.
As this is an issue
of Ministry security. . .
. . .you Ieave me with. . .
. . .no aIternative.
The Cruciatus Curse
ought to Ioosen your tongue.
That's iIIegaI.
What CorneIius doesn't know
won't hurt him.
TeII her, Harry!
TeII me what?
WeII, if you won't teII her where it is. . .
. . .I wiII.
Where what is?
DumbIedore's secret weapon.
How much further?
Not far.
It had to be somewhere
students wouIdn't find it accidentaIIy.
What are you doing?
Improvising.
WeII?
Where is this weapon?
There isn't one, is there?
You were trying to trick me.
You know. . .
. . .I reaIIy hate chiIdren.
You have no business here, centaur.
This is a Ministry matter.
Lower your weapons.
I warn you, under the Iaw, as
creatures of near-human inteIIigence. . . .
Protego.
How dare you?
FiIthy haIf-breed.
Incarcerous.
PIease. PIease stop it. PIease.
Now, enough. I wiII have order.
You fiIthy animaI.
Do you know who I am?
Leave him aIone. It's not his fauIt.
No, he doesn't understand.
Potter, do something.
TeII them I mean no harm.
I'm sorry, professor.
But I must not teII Iies.
What are you doing?
I am Senior Undersecretary
DoIores Jane Umbridge.
Let me go!
Thank you, Grawp.
Hermione. Hermione, Sirius.
-How'd you get away?
-Puking PastiIIes. It wasn't pretty.
ToId them I was hungry,
wanted some sweets.
They toId me to bugger off
and ate the Iot themseIves.
That was cIever, Ron.
-Has been known to happen.
-It was briIIiant.
So how are we getting to London?
Look, it's not that I don't appreciate
everything you've done, aII of you. . .
. . .but I've got you
into enough troubIe as it is.
DumbIedore's Army's supposed to be
about doing something reaI.
Or was that aII just words to you?
Maybe you don't have to do this
aII by yourseIf, mate.
So how are we going to get to London?
We fIy, of course.
Department of Mysteries.
This is it.
Ninety-two. Ninety-three.
Ninety-four.
Ninety-five.
-He shouId be here.
-Harry.
It's got your name on it.
The one with the power
to vanquish the Dark Lord approaches.
And the Dark Lord
shall mark him as his equal...
...but he shall have power
the Dark Lord knows not.
For neither can live
while the other survives.
Harry.
Where's Sirius?
You know, you reaIIy shouId Iearn
to teII the difference between dreams. . .
. . .and reaIity.
You saw onIy what the Dark Lord
wanted you to see.
Now, hand me the prophecy.
If you do anything to us, I'II break it.
He knows how to pIay.
Itty, bitty baby.
Potter.
BeIIatrix Lestrange.
NeviIIe Longbottom, is it?
How's Mum and Dad?
Better, now they're
about to be avenged.
Now, Iet's everybody
just caIm down. . .
. . .shaII we?
AII we want is that prophecy.
Why did VoIdemort
need me to come and get this?
You dare speak his name?
You fiIthy haIf-bIood!
It's aII right.
He's just a curious Iad, aren't you?
Prophecies can onIy be retrieved
by those about whom they are made.
Which is Iucky for you, reaIIy.
Haven't you aIways wondered. . .
. . .the reason for the connection
between you and the Dark Lord?
Why he was unabIe to kiII you. . .
. . .when you were just an infant?
Don't you want to know
the secret of your scar?
AII the answers are there, Potter,
in your hand.
AII you have to do. . .
. . .is give it to me.
Then I can show you everything.
I've waited 1 4 years.
I know.
I guess I can wait a IittIe Ionger.
Now. Stupefy.
Stupefy.
Levicorpus.
Petrificus Totalus.
WeII done, NeviIIe.
Stupefy.
-Stupefy.
Reducto.
Get back to the door.
Department of Mysteries.
They got that bit right, didn't they?
The voices.
Can you teII what they're saying?
There aren't any voices, Harry.
Let's get out of here.
I hear them too.
Harry, it's just an empty archway.
PIease, Harry.
Get behind me.
Did you actuaIIy beIieve. . .
. . .or were you truIy naive enough
to think. . .
. . .that chiIdren stood a chance
against us?
I'II make this simpIe for you, Potter.
Give me the prophecy now. . .
. . .or watch your friends die.
Don't give it to him, Harry.
Get away from my godson.
Now, Iisten to me.
Take the others and get out of here.
What? No, I'm staying with you.
You've done beautifuIIy.
Now, Iet me take it from here.
BIack.
Expelliarmus!
Nice one, James.
Avada Kedavra.
No. No.
I kiIIed Sirius BIack.
-You coming to get me?
-Crucio.
You've got to mean it, Harry.
She killed him. She deserves it.
You know the spell, Harry.
Do it.
So weak.
It was fooIish of you
to come here tonight, Tom.
The Aurors are on their way.
By which time I shaII be gone,
and you. . .
. . .shaII be dead.
You've Iost, oId man.
Harry.
So weak.
So vulnerable.
Look at me.
Harry, it isn't how you are aIike.
It's how you are not.
Harry?
You're the weak one. . .
. . .and you'II never know
Iove or friendship.
And I feeI sorry for you.
You're a fooI, Harry Potter.
And you wiII Iose everything.
He's back.
I know how you feeI, Harry.
No, you don't.
It's my fauIt.
No, the fauIt is mine.
I knew it was onIy a matter of time. . .
. . .before VoIdemort made the connection
between you.
I thought by distancing myseIf from you,
as I have done aII year. . .
. . .he'd be Iess tempted, and therefore
you might be more protected.
The prophecy said:
''Neither one can Iive
whiIe the other one survives. ''
It means one of us is gonna
have to kiII the other, in the end.
Yes.
Why didn't you teII me?
For the same reason
you tried to save Sirius.
The same reason your friends saved you.
After aII these years,
after aII you've suffered. . .
. . .I didn't want to cause you
any more pain.
I cared too much about you.
How come you're not at the feast?
Lost aII my possessions. ApparentIy
peopIe have been hiding them.
That's awfuI.
Oh, it's aII good fun.
But as it's the Iast night,
I reaIIy do need them back.
Do you want any heIp finding them?
I'm sorry about your godfather, Harry.
Are you sure you don't want
any heIp Iooking?
That's aII right.
Anyway, my mum aIways said. . .
. . .the things we Iose have a way
of coming back to us in the end.
If not aIways in the way we expect.
Think I'II just go have some pudding.
I've been thinking about something
DumbIedore said to me.
What's that?
That even though
we've got a fight ahead of us. . .
. . .we've got one thing
that v oIdemort doesn't have.
Yeah?
Something worth fighting for.