(SLOW INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOOR OPENING)
MR. AARON: Okay, Abrams.
Allende.
Bernstein.
Brown.
Come on, come on.
Attaboy, Todd.
Buckley.
Cohen.
Garcia.
Paul.
Take a seat, Lisa.
I just wanted to take a minute
to talk to you about your test.
Sure.
Now, I know you had a little help.
Well, I mean, I didn't cheat,
if that's what you mean.
I'm just saying I know you had a little help.
A lot of people did.
Well, be that as it may...
I mean, I'll take it over again if you want,
but, like, what would be the point?
It's not like I'm ever gonna actually
need to know this stuff in my daily life.
Well, that's just not necessarily true, Lisa.
Haven't you ever developed
an interest in something
that you didn't initially think
you were gonna develop an interest in?
Um...
No, not really.
(MR. AARON CHUCKLES)
Haven't you ever...
Haven't you ever been put
in a new situation
and found that
after overcoming its difficulties,
you had developed a new set of skills
and new experiences along the way?
No, I really haven't.
Okay.
Anyway, it was open-book.
So, what's the difference
between using a book
and, like, I don't know,
using somebody else's mind
who's really good at math?
I mean, it's not like this person
did the whole test for me.
-Oh,no?
-No, I did some of it.
Well, next time I'd appreciate it
if you did it all.
Okay?
You are so fair.
What did he say to you?
Nothing.
Mr. Aaron and I have an
understanding about my math problem.
MR. KLElN: So the President of
the United States, William B. McKinley,
authorizes the use of
private detectives to break the strike
and they went out there
and shot 'em down!
Just like they did in Virginia,
just like they did in Pennsylvania.
Because they didn't care!
They did not care!
And that's basically it.
That's basically all there is to say.
All right? Go ahead.
-Uh, Becky.
-BECKY: Well...
Mr. Klein! I mean, was there ever, like,
a good president of the United States?
(SCATTERED LAUGH)
MR. KLElN: I don't know, Becky.
I think that's a good question.
What do you think?
You. Lionel. What do you think?
Did we ever have a good president?
Um... I don't know.
I guess most of them have just been,
like, totally corrupt.
MR. LEWlS: Lisa?
Can I just say that I'm not necessarily,
like, a big fan
of all the presidents of the United States,
especially the current one.
But I still don't think
it's necessarily all that useful
to categorize every president
as universally corrupt,
because that just seems
really general to me.
Especially if you're gonna judge them
by the standard
of whatever they're supposed
to traditionally be like
in some mythical version of America
that probably never existed to begin with.
Lisa has raised a salient point.
(STUDENTS LAUGH)
MAN: Tell him to be polite,
tell him to answer the questions,
and I'll arrange for his bail
in the morning. Yes.
DARREN: Hey, how'd you do?
Hey, Darren. It was fine.
Thank you so much.
So he didn't give you a hard time
or anything?
Well, he knows I'm not planning
to go into mathematics or anything.
He was totally cool about it.
-He's so cool.
-Oh, yeah, everybody loves Mr. Aaron.
What's that supposed to mean?
Nothing. The man is very lovable.
What are you doing now?
I was gonna go look for a cowboy hat.
Why?
Because my dad is supposed to
take me and my brother
to this ranch in New Mexico
to go horseback riding
and I don't think it would be right
to appear on horseback in New Mexico
without the appropriate
equestrian paraphernalia, Darren.
You wouldn't understand these things.
-That is a definite possibility.
-Anyway, thanks again.
Well, before you venture forth
on your bizarre quest for a cowboy hat...
-Yes, Darren?
-What are you up to later?
-Like tonight.
-I don't know.
You wanna go to a movie?
What, you mean, like on a date?
No, not on a date, just go to a movie.
I don't know if it's a fucking date!
All right. Calm down.
What do you wanna see?
I don't know,
I don't even know what's playing.
I don't know if it's a date.
Let's just forget about it.
I hate the fuckin' movies anyway.
They're just bullshit. They're all bullshit!
Okay, take it easy. I'm sorry.
I was just asking!
What if it was a date, anyway?
Would that be so horrendous?
Oh, my God. Are you like...
Are you asking me out?
(DARREN MUMBLlNG)
-I don't know.
-Are you?
(STUTTERS) Yeah. I mean...
-I feel like we're already really close...
-Oh, my God.
...and I think we'd be a really good match.
Well, I would definitely have to
think about this.
Absolutely. Give it some thought.
Okay. I will.
Okay.
-Why do you look like that?
-Like what?
-What do you want from me?
-Not a thing!
All right. I'll see you later.
All right.
Hello!
(TRUMPET PLAYlNG OUTSlDE)
Hi.
-ls Mom home?
-She went to the store.
(PLAYlNG PlANO)
-Hey!
-BECKY: What are you doing tonight?
Nothing. Darren wants me
to go to the movies with him.
Oh, my God. What's that about?
(CHUCKLES) I have no idea.
(PEOPLE SPEAKlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY)
(lNAUDlBLE)
LlSA: Becky, there is not a cowboy hat
to be found in the entire Upper West Side.
And I am very depressed about it.
BECKY ON PHONE: The Upper West Side is
saving you from yourself
because no one wants to see
you in that hat.
Hey! Hey!
-Where'd you get...
-How you doin'?
Your hat!
What?
(MUFFLED) Where'd you get
your cowboy hat?
What?
What are you, crazy?
Hi.
Where'd you get your cowboy hat?
-My hat?
-Yeah! Your cowboy hat!
You like my cowboy hat? Really?
Yes! Where did you get it?
-(THUD)
-(SCREAMS)
(BRAKES SCREECHlNG)
(GROANlNG)
(PEOPLE SPEAKlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY)
WOMAN: Somebody see what happen?
MAN 1: Somebody call an ambulance!
Call an ambulance.
Everybody just step back!
I'm calling one right now!
LlSA: Can you hear me?
MAN 2: Get an ambulance!
-Someone's calling one!
-Ma'am, can you hear me?
-Can you hear me?
-PATTERSON: I don't know! Where am l?
LlSA: You're on Broadway and 75th Street
in New York.
Between 75th and 74th Street.
LlSA: You were in a bad accident.
PATTERSON: Who are you?
-My name is Lisa.
-What do you mean? Am I dead?
LlSA: No, you're not dead.
You were in a traffic accident,
but you're gonna be...
What do you mean? What happened?
-You were run over by a bus.
-You've got to be kidding me.
-A bus?
-Yeah.
MAN 1 : Is there a doctor anywhere?
PATTERSON: Is it still happening?
-An ambulance is on its way.
-LlSA: The accident's over.
-I think you're a little confused.
-I'll say I'm confused.
MAN 1 : Here. Let me just try...
-PATTERSON: No! Don't let go!
-Ma'am!
-Don't let go of me! Don't let go of me.
-LlSA: I won't.
I won't. I'm not gonna let go.
Thank you. Thank you, honey.
She needs a tourniquet
or she's going to die.
Okay, let me just...
Oh, my God!
(PEOPLE EXCLAlM lN SHOCK)
Jesus Christ!
Help! God, what's happening to me!
I'm sorry.
I'm trying to put a tourniquet on you.
Ma'am, we need to get a tourniquet on you.
Do you have a belt? You can use your belt.
I just can't see where to do it.
LlSA: You're gonna be all right,
so just hang on.
Thank you, honey. Just don't let go of me.
LlSA: They're gonna put
a tourniquet on you.
What do you mean? Are they doctors?
No, they're not doctors.
They were just passing by.
-Well, get 'em the fuck away from me!
-MAN 1 : Ma'am!
Ma'am! We're only trying to help you!
Never mind that!
Just try putting it around...
Do you wanna do it?
You know how to do it. You wanna do it?
Are you kidding me!
PATTERSON: I can't see anything.
Are my eyes open or closed?
They're open.
(FRlGHTFULLY) What do you mean?
(SOBBlNG) You were in a terrible accident.
But you're gonna be fine,
so just hang on, okay?
MAN 1 : There's no place to put it.
I can't even find a...
Will somebody call the fucking ambulance!
Calm down! We already called them!
They're obviously not coming fast enough,
so maybe you should call them again!
Why not call them again?
(PATTERSON GASPlNG)
-You're gonna be...
-Could somebody...
Could somebody call my daughter?
Sure! We can call her. What's her name?
Just tell me her name
and give me her number.
It's Lisa.
No, that's my name.
Is that your daughter's name?
What? What are you talking about?
I'm sorry. I'm not trying to be confusing.
My name is Lisa.
Is that your daughter's name?
Jesus Christ, just call her!
Would you call her?
I can't call her
if you don't give me the number.
I got it. I got it!
Ma'am?
-You're gonna be okay.
-KlD: You're gonna be okay!
LlSA: What's your daughter's number?
Sweetie,
-I don't think I'm gonna make it.
-(WEEPlNG) Oh, no!
Please hang on. The ambulance is
gonna be here any minute!
So just hang on, okay?
-Please!
-MAN 1 : It's okay.
-She's gone.
-LlSA: No! No!
-MAN 1 : She's gone.
-Please let go of me!
Please, let go of me! Please, let go of me!
Just hang on.
They're gonna be here any minute, okay?
So just hang on!
You're gonna be okay!
(SlREN WAlLlNG lN THE DlSTANCE)
-You were going the speed limit?
-Yeah.
Lisa? You're Lisa? I just want to ask you
a few questions, okay?
Yeah, sure.
MlTCHELL: Now, just tell me
everything you saw,
even if you think it might not be important.
All right?
Think of it like a movie.
Like you're watchin' a movie
-in your head...
-lt was green as I came to the intersection.
-LlSA: Could somebody call my mother?
-We already called your mom,
but I'll have 'em put another
call in to your mother right now, okay?
I know this is hard for you,
but we gotta get this
while it's still fresh in your mind, okay?
Some of these questions might seem like
they don't make a lot of sense to you.
(SOBBlNG) They do make sense.
Just ask me!
Okay, that's what I'm doin'. All right?
So now I'm gonna ask you,
from where you were standing,
could you see the traffic light?
Could you tell me if it was red?
Yellow? Green?
DETECTlVE: She just came out of nowhere?
MlTCHELL: What color was the light?
Boy, I'm sorry...
(lNDlSTlNCT)
I...
-I guess it was green?
-Green?
I think it was just an accident.
-DETECTlVE: Where were you at?
-I was on Broadway.
(DOOR OPENlNG)
(VlDEO GAME BEEPlNG)
-What happened to you?
-Nothing.
JOAN: Hello?
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SAD lNSTRUMENTAL MUSlC PLAYlNG)
(lNAUDlBLE)
So, does anybody know who she was?
I don't know. I guess she lived around here
if she had all these Fairway grocery bags.
-What did they do with her leg?
-I have no fucking idea.
Hey...
-(KNOCKlNG ON DOOR)
-(DOOR OPENlNG)
JOAN: Lisa? Are you sure
you don't want me to call in?
Oh, no, thanks.
I mean, thank you. That's really sweet.
But I'm supposed to go see Becky anyway,
and I don't really want to sit here
thinking about it all night.
Go to work. I'll be all right.
LlSA: Hey. Hey, Darren.
DARREN: Hey.
(PEOPLE APPLAUDlNG)
-WOMAN: Joan?
-Yeah?
-You got some flowers.
-Can you bring 'em in?
JOAN: Oh, that's good.
I'm glad you guys liked it.
WOMAN: You were great.
JOAN: Well, we have a lot of work to do,
but it'll be good.
WOMAN: The critics are gonna love it.
They don't even know me anymore.
-Hey, are you comin' out?
-Um... I don't know. I'm not sure.
-Come on.
-Maybe I will.
I don't know if I'm going to.
But I might.
-See you later.
-Bye.
-Goodnight.
-JOAN: See you later.
Hi, are you Ramon?
Yes. Hello. You were wonderful again.
Oh, you're so sweet.
And thank you for the beautiful flowers.
-You're very welcome.
-And you've seen the show before?
Yes, two times.
Gosh. That's a lot! (CHUCKLES)
It's a beautiful performance.
I'm sure you will have a big success.
Well, right now, we're just trying
to focus on what we're doing.
I don't know if you are busy,
but would you allow me to buy you a drink?
If you like to ask your friends...
-I'm sorry. I can't. I'm just on my way home.
-Okay, that's no problem.
Tomorrow I'm going to London
for a few days.
Perhaps when I come back.
Um...
-Yeah.
-Okay.
-I'm sorry. I really have to go.
-Okay. That's no problem.
Anyway, thanks again
for the beautiful flowers!
-It's a privilege to meet you.
-It's nice to meet you, too.
-Goodnight.
Hey.
-I thought you were at the movies.
-Yeah, it wasn't very good.
(lN FUNNY VOlCE)
I was doing a show in Detroit
and this woman came backstage,
and she's like, "Wanna come back
to my place and do some cocaine?"
I was like,
"l know the kind of pussy..."
Why you pop in
at 4:00 in the morning?
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
You'll get us thrown out.
Oh, oh. Do the Shirley Temple!
Come on, do the Shirley Temple.
Okay.
(SlNGlNG AS SHlRLEY TEMPLE)
On the good ship Lollipop
It's a sweet trip to the candy shop
And there you are
Happy landing on the chocolate bar
Ifyou eat too much
Oh! Oh! You'll...
Keep going!
That's awesome!
VlCTOR: Wait, what's that one?
Do the baby.
-(NORMAL VOlCE) No, it's too weird.
-VlCTOR: You have to do the baby.
Some inspiration.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(lMlTATES BABY CRYlNG)
-It's so disturbing.
-I know. It's too weird.
-No, it's not.
-Have another drink.
I think we can tell I've had enough.
(lNAUDlBLE)
Matthew, if you would read
the role of France.
And, Anthony,
why don't you read Burgundy?
Ah, Burgundy.
And I guess I'm gonna hog
the part of Lear again.
Okay, Anthony?
Uh...
"Royal Majesty, I crave no more
than what your highness offered,
"nor will you tender less."
"Right, noble Burgundy,
"When she was dear to us,
we did hold her so,
"But now her price is fall'n."
RAMON: My family are from Colombia.
My father worked in the diplomatic service.
Really? Wow.
I grew up five years in Panama
and nine years in Paris.
And what do you do, Ramon?
I have a company.
We design computer software
to help companies
in South American countries
that use an incompatible software,
so the computers can talk to each other.
It's a big problem in South America
where there is not so much coordination
in computer communication.
Right now is a lot of opportunity for us
because for the big software companies,
we are still the backwoods.
That's changing quite fast.
(RAlN PATTERlNG)
Can I give you a lift?
Oh, no, thank you,
I'm just gonna grab a cab. But thanks.
May I call you sometime?
Okay. Sure, that would be great.
May I have your telephone number?
(MOANlNG)
-LlSA: Mom?
-Just a minute!
-Can I come in?
-Just a second, please. Hold on.
Come in.
Can I talk to you?
Sure. What's up?
LlSA: I'm supposed to go back to
the police to confirm my statement
the day after tomorrow.
So what do you think I should do?
(SlGHS)
Well, I don't know, sweetie.
I mean, that bus driver probably has
a family to support.
He could probably lose his job.
So I think you should really think
about that before you say anything.
Okay?
Yeah.
MR. KLElN: Think of the implications
of what you're saying.
I'm saying what is the frame of reference
for the average Arab on the street?
-Angie.
-Yeah. My mother's family is from Syria,
and they're not exactly
in love with the current regime.
And I definitely don't agree
with a lot of their religious views,
especially when it comes to
the oppression of women.
But I just wanna say
that Americans have no idea
how much people hate them
all over the world.
BECKY: It's pretty clear to us now, Angie.
And all my relatives in Syria think what
we did in Afghanistan was terrorism, okay?
-MR. LEWlS: Anthony?
-Not to mention lraq.
-Syria is a theocratic military dictatorship.
-No, it's not. Sorry.
Syria is not
a theocratic military dictatorship?
I think we have a pretty good idea how
much people hate us now, actually, Angie.
No, we don't.
They blew up our city, okay?
So, yeah, I think we have a pretty good idea
-and personally, I don't give a shit.
-You should.
The people who blew up the World Trade
Center were a bunch of sick monsters.
-Oh, they were monsters?
-Yes!
Why, because they're Arabs?
No, because they killed 3,000 people
for no reason.
Maybe they think they had a reason!
-Like what?
-One at a time!
-ANGlE: Why did we drop bombs on them?
-What should we have done?
ANGlE: Why did we invade lraq?
BECKY: They declared war on us.
ANGlE: No, they didn't.
Iraq didn't declare war on anybody!
-They didn't do anything to us!
-MR. LEWlS: Come on, guys, one at a time!
-Anthony.
-They did have a reason.
Thank you.
They wanted to establish a medieval
lslamic caliphate in the Middle East
and destroy Western civilization.
-Where did you read that?
-It's on their website.
-Okay, forget it.
-Angie!
-No! Forget it!
-Go ahead with what you were saying!
No! Why should l?
But why are you defending someone
who murdered 3,000 people?
I'm not!
Why are you defending a country that
unilaterally invaded two Muslim countries
and supports the lsraeli occupation
of Palestine?
Give me a break!
And drops bombs on women and children
and then calls other people terrorists
for doing the exact same thing?
-Because it's not the same thing!
-Yes, it is!
MR. LEWlS: Come on, guys.
MR. KLElN: Lionel! Go ahead.
Yeah, I just want to ask
why is it okay to drop bombs on men
but it's not okay to drop bombs
on women and children?
I mean, isn't that just like reverse sexism?
I don't know. I agree it's a bullshit term.
-This is totally stupid.
-MR. KLElN: Monica!
I think the whole class should
apologize to Angie, actually,
'cause all she did was express her opinion
about what her relatives in Syria think.
-Thank you!
-And everyone started screaming at her
Iike she was defending the Ku Klux Klan!
They are the Ku Klux Klan!
They throw acid in women's faces.
-Who? Afghanistans?
-Why not drop bombs on the Ku Klux Klan!
Because they're white?
Six people raised their hands
before you, Lisa.
MR. LEWlS: Come on, guys.
ANTHONY: The correct term is Afghans.
Okay, I'm not even saying
I disagree with you.
I'm just saying it's pathetic
the way people in this class treated Angie
just for saying something
they didn't happen to agree with.
Because that's censorship. Right?
-Right?
-It's not censorship!
-Right on!
-This class is not the government.
-It's censorship.
-Oh, my God, no, it's not!
We work out of Highway One
out in the Bronx.
Near the Bronx Zoo.
-Oh, okay.
-But for a situation...
Hey, how are you doin'?
But for somethin' like this,
we usually find a local precinct
or an apartment.
Whatever will expediate
the situation most effectively.
Have a seat wherever you want.
Just pull up a chair.
According to this statement,
the light was green
when the bus passed through
the intersection.
Yes.
So you're saying she walked
against the light?
Yeah.
It's true. Two years of college,
two years at the magazine.
Two years with you.
I'm kind of a two-year gal!
What's funny about that?
What did you think of the play?
It was okay.
(PHONE RlNGlNG)
-Hello?
-LlSA: Hi, Dad!
Yeah! Hi!
-How are you?
-l'm okay. I'm fine.
I'm just sitting here, looking at the ocean,
tryin ' to do a little work,
Iistening to some music.
-How are you?
-I'm okay.
Are you practicing your horseback riding?
Oh, yeah, I've really been riding a lot.
I'm gettin ' these really bad saddle sores.
-Are you?
-(CHUCKLES) No, I'm kidding.
Yeah. Do you know
Claremont Stables on 89th
between Columbus and Amsterdam?
-Yeah.
-Well, it might be really worth your while
to go over there and maybe sign up
for a couple oflessons.
-No...
-I'd be happy to...
I'm sorry, what?
I was just saying
I'd be very happy to spring for it
if you want to take a couple of lessons.
I think it would pay off in the end.
-Thanks. I actually may take you up on that.
-Yeah, just let me know.
-I appreciate that.
-So, how's school?
School's okay.
I'm kind of fucking up in geometry.
But I assume you're not torpedoing
your scholarship or anything like that?
-Nope. The scholarship's on.
-Okay, good.
Well, math was never my
strong suit either, so...
I guess I'm following in your
footsteps in that regard.
Well, l'm proud to hear it.
So, how are you?
Um... I'm okay. Things are okay.
They're a little slow and a little frustrating.
But there's one or two projects we're
going after that seem to look promising.
And l don 't know, l think it's okay.
Okay.
How's the boyfriend situation?
Oh. The same.
-Nobody...
-They're all kind of the same.
Well, I know
this is not going to go anywhere,
but our next workshop is comprised,
for the most part,
of strapping young men of about
17 years old who,
for some peculiar reason,
are interested in using their brains
to get on with their lives.
Nobody really understands
why or how this happened,
but if you're interested in meeting any
of them when you come out next time...
Yeah, I don't really go for
the California type, but thanks.
Well, I don't either, per se.
It depends on the person, obviously.
Hard to argue with.
I think I'll stop generalizing now.
Well, that's about it on my end, sweetie.
I'll give you a call in a week or two.
-Give my love to Curtis.
-Okay. Well...
-I love you.
-I love you, too. Bye.
-You do know I have two kids, right?
-Yes. I would like to meet them.
-You are really smooth.
-(RAMON CHUCKLES)
I would love to meet your kids.
I have two boys myself. I'm not smooth.
Would you like to have a nightcap?
I just...
I feel like we used to be really close, like,
up until a few days ago,
and I'm really not getting that
from you anymore.
Becky, give me a break.
(BECKY SCOFFS)
(PARTY MUSlC BLARlNG)
(SNORTS)
Now you wanna do the other nostril
because you always want
to be symmetrical. Very important.
(SNORTS)
(LAUGHS) You are so funny.
(SNORTlNG)
Symmetry.
So, what do we do now?
-Now we make out.
-Paul! What about your girlfriend?
I'm sorry. It just sounded like
you asked me about my girlfriend.
Oh, never mind.
(lNDlSTlNCT HlP-HOP MUSlC PLAYlNG)
I don't know, man. I don't wanna get into it.
You know I really love you, right?
Not really.
I gotta go home.
I'm just gonna head out, too.
You need a little help, I take it?
(DARREN LAUGHS)
(HORNS HONKlNG)
-(KNOCK ON DOOR)
-RAMON: Joan, are you all right?
Yes, fine. I'll be out in a sec.
Okay, we're gonna start with
a few simple stretches.
I want you all to watch me first,
and then you'll follow.
All right, so left arm goes up.
And then all the way over to the side,
you're gonna feel a long stretch
along the side of your body.
MR. AARON: All right.
-Mr. Aaron?
-Yes, Becky... Lisa?
Are you still mad at me about the test?
What's going on, Lisa?
LlSA: Because maybe the bus driver
is completely devastated as it is,
and I'm just gonna be this rich girl who
calls up the cops to ease her conscience.
What does your being rich
have to do with anything?
-You know what I mean.
-No, I don't.
I don't mean literally rich.
I mean rich compared to the bus driver.
Lionel? I'm going to need five minutes.
I just thought you wanted to know that
there's a lot of people out here
and it's kind of hard to breathe.
You better close that door now, Lionel.
I'm sorry, I gotta let these guys in.
I don't want to leave you hanging.
Look, if you're hurting,
-we could get a cup of coffee after school.
-I'd do that.
(lNAUDlBLE)
(TV PLAYlNG)
Hey, does this dress make me look fat?
Um... A little.
Well, there's nothing I can do about it.
Where are you going?
The opera.
Why are you going to the opera?
Turns out he's a big opera fan.
Anyway, don't you think it sounds kind
of fun? We should all go sometime.
No, thanks.
-Why not? I bet you'd like it.
-I don't like that kind of singing.
You like classical music.
Yes, that's true,
but I don't like opera singing.
-When have you ever...
-It's like their entire reason
for existing
is to prove how loud they can be.
I don't really find that all that interesting.
Yeah. I know what you mean, but it's not
all like that. You like TThe Magic Flute.
Okay. I guess I'm wrong. I guess I do like
opera singing. I just didn't realize it.
-What is the matter with you?
-Nothing at all.
Why are you pushing this?
I don't want to go to the opera!
Yes, okay. I'm not pushing anything.
All you have say is, "No, thanks."
I did and then you were like, "Why not?"
So then I told you,
and then you started debating me,
Iike you assumed that I've never
thought this through for myself,
which I have, many times!
Okay, well that was a really contemptuous
assumption on my part.
I don't actually like the opera that much
myself, but I'm trying to expand my mind,
maybe that's wrong.
(JOAN SlGHS)
I'm sorry. I guess I'm a little nervous
about you guys meeting Ramon.
Why? What's the big deal? Why are you so
influenced by what Curtis and me...
...what Curtis and I think?
Hey, why does everything I say annoy you?
Jesus Christ, I'm just sitting here.
Here, you be me, and say anything
and I'll respond to you
the way you've been responding to me this
whole conversation.
-Go ahead, you say something to me...
-No! I'm not gonna do that.
-Why not?
-Because it's dumb!
I'm horrible. I get your point!
Oh, okay. Whatever.
Was that supposed to be an
imitation of me?
Mmm. Okay, withdrawn.
Are you coming to my opening night?
I will if I have to.
-You're a little cunt, you know that?
-Yes. You're a big cunt.
Okay, let's not start talking
to each other that way.
You just called me a cunt, Mom.
-I'm sorry I said that...
-Why? It's refreshing.
If you're saying you're not aware you've
been really annoyed with me,
or really irritable with me and it doesn't
matter if I express it exactly accurately,
-because you know what I'm trying to say.
-Not really.
If you're really saying that you're
completely unaware of that,
then I have to say I don't think you're
being honest about it.
Now, maybe I'm doing something horrible
to you without being aware of it,
but I have a show opening in two weeks,
I'm really nervous about it,
I'm seeing a new person
and I'm obviously anxious
about you and Curtis liking him,
you were involved in this horrible,
traumatic accident,
you're going on this crazy horseback riding
trip with your father...
-Oh, my God!
-...which sounds like a recipe for disaster.
And on top of everything else, Lisa,
ever since I told you about Ramon,
you have been treating me like I'm insane.
-I think you're exaggerating.
-Now, what am I supposed to do?
-What am I supposed to do?
-Just stop whining about everything!
It doesn't matter. None of it matters at all.
You've been in a million plays,
you always get freaked out
because of what some dumb critic
is gonna say about your dumb play.
I don't frankly give a shit about Ramon
or who you're going out with this week.
I never go out with anyone.
-I don't care!
-Don't talk to me like that!
I've barely had a date
for the last two years!
Yeah, but I don't care about any of it.
It doesn't matter.
Your boyfriend doesn't matter.
Your play doesn't matter, except to you.
I don't care about New Mexico,
because to tell you the truth,
I'm probably not even going.
-What do you mean?
-Want to know something else, Mom?
There are more important problems
in the world than our relationship.
There is a whole city out there
full of people who are dying,
so who gives a shit
if I like your fucking boyfriend?
It is so trivial. Why are you bothering me
with all this? It doesn't matter.
(DOOR BELL RlNGlNG)
Well, should I have him come up now?
(VOlCE BREAKlNG)
Or should I have him wait downstairs?
Do whatever you want. I don't care.
Lisa, I don't even know what
we're talking about.
I know you don't. That's the problem.
Oh, give me a break.
Everything is all right?
Oh, yeah. Oh.
I'm so excited to be going to the opera.
I don't think I've really gone more than
one or two times.
I wish it wasn't Norma,
but still it's fun to go.
What if we went to see
something else instead?
-You don't want to hear Norma?
-Oh, no, I don't mean that.
I just meant, wouldn't it be funny
if we walked into one of the other events?
Like, what if we just went to see
the Daniel Goldfarb play instead?
RAMON: I think you will enjoy this.
(OPERA MUSlC PLAYlNG)
(SlNGlNG)
-It's beautiful.
-Shh.
(PEOPLE CLAMORlNG ON TV)
This is the dumbest book I've ever read.
(TV CHANNEL CHANGlNG)
(MUSlC PLAYlNG)
(TELEPHONE RlNGlNG)
-Yo.
-LlSA: Hey, Paul.
-Hey.
-lt's Lisa Cohen.
Yeah, how's it going?
Okay. What have you been up to?
Seeing some questionable movies,
and not deciding where to go to college.
Sounds good.
So, I was just thinking...
This is gonna sound really queer,
but by any chance
would you want to meet somewhere
and, like, take away my virginity?
Um... All right.
Really?
To what do l owe this inconceivable honor?
Actually, it's because of my deep,
passionate feelings for you, Paul.
That's pretty much what l figured.
Do you wanna give me your address?
Oh, um...
It's 252 West 85th Street.
Okay.
All right. I'll be there in like a halfhour,
-or more.
-Okay.
-All right. I'll see you.
-Bye.
(TELEPHONE RlNGlNG)
-Hello?
-DARREN: Hey.
-What are you up to?
-Writing my Lear paper.
That's impressive.
Not really.
I've just never known you to be
so devoted to your studies before.
So, what did you do tonight?
Actually, Darren, I don't really feel
like talking right now.
Okay.
Okay?
Yeah. I'll talk to you later.
Okay.
-Bye.
(SOBBlNG)
(DOOR BELL RlNGlNG)
-Hey.
-Hey, come in.
I think I just alienated one of
your neighbors by smoking in the elevator.
Really? What did they say?
She basically said there was no smoking
in the elevator.
That's original.
So, this is the living room.
-Very livable.
-We like it.
My mom hasn't read any of these books,
by the way.
Have you?
Some of them. Not all of them.
This book is a very cool book.
Yeah, I think The Third Reich may be a little
bit too much for me right now.
It's pretty hard to put down
once you get started.
Do you want anything to drink?
I'd take a beer.
Okay, that's in the kitchen.
This is my room. Ta-da.
Very nice.
These are some drawings I did.
Not that I should be
showing them to you, because
I know you're like a really
good artist, right?
I would like to be a really good artist.
At this point, I think it would be more
accurate to say I'm good at drawing.
Yeah, I just do it for fun.
But I've always really liked it.
-So, can I ask you something?
-Yes?
This is probably gonna sound
very immature,
but how can you be so relaxed,
knowing what we're about to do?
Or is it just like no big deal to you?
Okay, that was a really stupid question,
and I'm totally embarrassed right now.
I'm actually more embarrassed
than I've ever been in my life.
If you wanna go home now,
that's totally okay.
Easy there. Don't be embarrassed.
It's basically, like,
the world's greatest activity,
but it's not actually worth
getting nervous about.
Yeah, I don't usually get nervous
because I think it's worth it,
I usually get nervous
because I can't help the way I feel.
There is that philosophy.
You are so funny.
Do you have an ashtray?
You can just chuck it out the window.
PAUL: How would one just
chuck it out the window?
Oh, you just slide the little door...
(WlNDOW SLlDES OPEN)
LlSA: Like that?
PAUL: Yes.
LlSA: Am I supposed to go really fast
at the end or something?
PAUL: Yeah, but we're gonna
move on before that.
Here.
Oh, oh. You don't have to do that.
PAUL: I know. I want to.
(PANTlNG) But don't do that.
I'm just embarrassed.
-Let me do it to you.
-All right.
LlSA: Uh... Um...
Any general guidelines?
PAUL: Just be careful.
LlSA: Okay.
PAUL: Are you ready?
Yeah.
PAUL: Okay.
Now, this is a little tricky.
It's probably gonna hurt a little at first,
but then it's gonna get better.
Just be patient.
There are certain technical difficulties on
my end that have to be addressed,
or it's not gonna happen.
Okay. You sound insane. (LAUGHS)
Okay, ready?
Yeah.
Okay.
LlSA: Mmm-hmm.
Okay, hang on.
Okay, there we go.
Does it hurt now?
Kind of, yeah.
Okay, just try to relax.
It'll get better in a second...
-Did you bring a condom?
-Uh-huh.
-Shouldn't you put it on?
-I will in a second.
-This is really kind of hurting.
-Okay, one second.
-LlSA: I love you.
-What?
LlSA: Nothing.
PAUL: Okay. Hold on.
-Shit.
-What?
PAUL: Okay, one second. Oh! Sorry.
Sorry.
(PAUL EXHALES)
Oh!
Sorry about that.
(PAUL PANTlNG)
Kind of got away from me.
-LlSA: Did any of it get inside me?
-I don't know.
Yeah. It definitely did.
Honest to God, it's probably okay.
The odds are
overwhelmingly that it's okay.
(DOOR BELL RlNGlNG)
That's my little brother.
-Hey, Curtis.
-Hi.
(CHEERS lN lTALlAN)
JOAN: I loved it. It was so exciting.
But how about those people
yelling "bravi"and "brava "?
-RAMON: How do you mean?
-Well, it's just so pretentious.
"Bravi, bravi. "
Why can't they just say "bra vo "?
Well, it's the plural. It's what they say
to acknowledge the ensemble.
No, I know it's correct,
but don't you think there's just something
a little pretentious
about some of those people?
-Pretentious?
-I don't mean they didn't really enjoy it,
but you know how you can
be enjoying something,
but you're also kind of looking around,
out of the corner of your eye,
because you know people are watching you
enjoy it?
Yes, but I wouldn't say that it
was pretentious.
In ltalian you say "bravo "for the man
and "brava "for the woman,
and "bravi"for the whole company.
Uh-huh. Okay, I see what you mean.
You use the masculine for the male singer
and the feminine for the female singer.
Anyway, I really enjoyed it. Thank you.
We'll have to go again.
It was so glamorous.
(ON PHONE)
Accident lnvestigation, Detective Mitchell.
My name is Lisa Cohen. I was a witness
in a bus accident case a few weeks ago.
Yeah, hi, Lisa. What can I do for you?
Well, are you allowed to tell me how
to get in touch with that woman 's family?
I really wanted to send some flowers
or something,
or is that like classified information?
No, the family's been notified.
Let me see what I got.
She mentioned she had a daughter.
Just hold on a second.
How are you doing, okay?
I'm okay.
(SlGHS)
All right, let me just...
Okay, I don't have anything for a daughter.
The only contact I have is a cousin,
Abigail Berwitz.
-I got a phone number in Arizona.
-Okay.
-520-5555.
-Mmm-hmm.
I'm trying to reach Abigail Berwitz?
-This is Abigail.
-Hi.
My name is Lisa Cohen.
You don't know me.
Yes? Hello?
I'm actually calling about your cousin,
Monica Patterson?
Okay?
Um...
I was actually there when she had...
During the accident, I didn't know her,
but I was holding her hand at the time.
Yes? What can l do for you?
(PlANO PLAYlNG)
Uh, um...
Okay, well...
I saw her obituary in the paper,
but can you hold on one second?
(SHOUTlNG)
Can you shut up for five minutes?
CURTlS: What am I supposed to do?
I have to practice.
LlSA: I don't give a shit!
Sorry. Um...
I didn't see anything about a funeral.
I assume they had one.
As far as l know, they're doing
something or other next week, but...
I'm sorry, I was also wondering...
She said something about her daughter?
-No.
-She wanted someone to get in touch...
No. Her daughter's not alive.
She passed away quite a long time ago.
Oh, my God.
-Was she sick? Or was it...
-She had leukemia.
-Oh, my gosh.
-Mmm-hmm.
-And do you mind if I ask...
-Could l just interrupt?
How did you get this number?
This is harassment!
I'm sorry. I'm not trying to harass you.
I've been getting calls about this
for three weeks, and l gotta tell you people,
I didn 't have any kind ofrelationship
with Monica whatsoever.
The person you should be calling is
Emily Morrison, who was Monica 's friend.
She 's the person who 's been
dealing with all of this in New York.
It has nothing to do with me.
I'm sorry!
I didn't really know who to contact.
Now, l can give you her number,
but l would very much appreciate it
ifthe calls would stop.
Yeah...
-Can you hold on while I get a pen?
-Yes.
All right.
Okay.
(CHlLDREN SHOUTlNG)
-Hi, are you Lisa?
-Yes.
As most of you know,
Monica was not a religious woman.
Anybody who ever had to sit through
a wedding or a funeral with her
knows how she felt about
formal occasions.
So Harry, Elise and l,
we were talking about this,
decided we would just have everyone over,
and let anyone who wanted to talk about
Monica, just talk about her.
Maybe share some remembrances.
Some of us know each other
and some of us don't.
But we're all here...
We're all here because we loved Monica
and because we want to pay tribute to her
in a way
that might conceivably not enrage her.
(PEOPLE CHUCKLlNG)
(SlGHS)
Now, I don't wanna tell anyone
what to think, or how to feel.
And I don't want to kid myself about
the stupid, meaningless way that she died,
because that would really
make her throw up,
but I don't want it to become
the summation of her life,
because it's not.
When her Lisa died...
When her Lisa died, I said to her,
"How can you stand it?"
And she said, "First of all, I can't.
"But I don't want to take away
the 12 years she did have
"and turn them all into leukemia,
because they weren't."
And so I do think
it's important to remember
that despite the fact that she got ripped off,
she was the most fully developed person
l, personally, have ever known.
She was also impossible to get along with,
(PEOPLE CHUCKLlNG)
but that's another story.
So, now I've said my little piece.
And now I want to talk a bit about
the first time we ever met.
She was 21.
WOMAN: It's okay, Emily.
(SOBBlNG) I know.
I was 19.
Even though I realize it's impossible for my
children to believe I was ever that young.
Hi, Dad.
Yeah, hi, how're you doing?
Okay, how are you?
I'm just sitting here listening to some
music, having a delicious glass ofbeer.
That sounds pleasant.
Yeah. How's everything going?
How's the boyfriend situation?
Well, there's this one guy I sort of had
something going with, but...
-But he kind of has a girlfriend, so...
-Uh-huh.
I realize I'm incredibly enthralling.
You are. You're very lucky. You're a very
beautiful girl, and you've got brains.
-That makes you a little dangerous.
-Don't forget mature.
Well, I hope you're not too mature.
-No, don't worry.
-Good. That was a very good answer.
Anyway, I do think it's a pretty
longstanding relationship.
Then you know what? You just do nothing.
Do absolutely nothing. And I guarantee
you one of two things will happen.
Either you're going to get the guy to
start doing back flips to get your attention
or you're going send him a crystal clear
signal that if he doesn't do back flips,
-he's not gonna get your attention.
-I think he already knows I like him.
Uh-huh? Okay...
I think I might have
spilled the beans on that one.
That's okay, because now,
ifyou stop acknowledging him,
if you suddenly give him nothing,
I guarantee you,
the guy is going to go berserk
and forget his girlfriend,
unless he's just not interested.
In which case, you just gotta
take your lumps, which is tough.
Okay, thanks, Dad. I'll be sure to try out
the technique next time I see him.
Well, everything's okay here.
-Things are a little slow, but...
-Actually, Dad?
Yeah?
I actually have something
kind of serious I want to ask you about.
Okay.
I'm kind soliciting people I respect
for their views on this.
Okay, what's up?
(DOG BARKlNG)
Do you think I should go back
to the police, or what?
Well, first ofall, l'm very glad
you told me about this.
I want you to let me call my friend
who's a lawyer,
just so we can find out
what some ofthe ramifications would be.
Maybe the three of us could talk on
the phone and possibly...
-Hey.
-Hey, babe.
Actually, Dad, please don't call anybody.
-Did you get my message?
-Um... I got a message.
-Hello?
-KARL: Sorry.
About the flowers for my mother?
Just one second. Annette just walked in.
I'm sorry.
That's okay.
Who are you talking to?
I guess I would just like to know later
that I would have done the right thing
by myself, if you see what I mean,
because I don't think I have so far.
Not that I'm trying to
make this woman's horrible death
into my own personal moral gymnasium...
Right. Well, that's that Shaw quote, right?
-What?
-The Shaw quote? That great Shaw quote.
(STAMMERS)
"The Englishman sees the world
as expressly
"designed to be
his own personal moral gymnasium. "
I think it's in one ofthose
wonderful prefaces.
I don't know where I read it.
-Who is that?
-It's Lisa.
Oh, good. Will you please ask her...
-Anyway...
-Hold on. I'm sorry, Lisa.
Can you hold on one second?
Yes?
Please ask if there's anything
we don't know about
that she won't eat, for the trip.
I have to call the ranch
because they do all the meals
-ahead oftime.
-KARL: Okay, l will.
I really will.
We're just in the middle of something.
Karl, I was supposed to call them last
week. You said you were going to call her.
If I hear about this fucking ranch one more
time, I'm going to blow my brains out.
I'm just in the middle ofsomething.
I don 't... What do you want me to do?
Fine, but if they put anything
in the baskets she can't eat,
well she's not going to have anything
to eat.
-I will ask her...
-The last time she came out here,
we went to three different
restaurants and she...
I will ask her. We're just right in the middle
of something, okay?
Okay. Tell her I said, "Hi."
I will. Okay.
Hello?
Yes. Hi.
Mom?
(GASPS)
(WATER RUNNlNG)
LlSA: Monica!
(PANTlNG)
(DOORBELL BUZZlNG)
(lNAUDlBLE)
(BOY SHOUTlNG)
MRS. MARETTl:
There's somebody here to see you.
Hi.
I'm really sorry to bother you.
We never met. I'm Lisa Cohen.
Yeah. What can I do for you?
Well, do you remember me
from the bus accident?
I don't know. What's this about?
Would it be okay
if I talked to you for a minute?
What do you want to talk about?
(CHUCKLES) I don't understand.
I just wanna talk about the accident
for a minute.
I don't want anything,
and I'm not here to do anything bad.
I just wanted to talk to you about it.
Where did you get my address?
I called information.
I was gonna call first, but...
It would have been better.
We're about to sit down.
I don't get what...
All right. Let's go outside.
I'm sorry. Could I use your bathroom?
-No, let's just go outside.
-Gerry, let her use the bathroom.
I don't want her to use the bathroom.
I don't understand what this is.
It's right down the hall, honey.
Hey, will you kids settle down, please?
I'm not kidding!
-What's the matter with you?
-Who is she?
Some girl that was at the accident.
Nothing is the matter.
I let her use the fucking bathroom.
Who is she?
-Honey, just do me a favor and wait inside.
-No, I want to hear what this is.
Look, we're just...
Okay. What?
Okay.
I hope this isn't going to insult you
too much.
Insult me?
I was just wondering if you felt bad
at all about what happened.
-About the accident?
-Yeah.
Honey?
Are you just upset about the accident?
Yes! I'm upset about the accident.
I'm very upset about the accident.
And I wanted to talk to you about it
for a minute.
Why is that so strange?
-Gerry, why don't we all go inside?
-Could I please talk to you alone?
Okay, what is going on here?
Nothing's going on here.
So why don't you calm down?
Look, go ahead inside.
Let me find out what this is.
In the meantime, why don't you make sure
those kids aren't killing each other,
all right?
All right.
No, you know what? Let 'em kill each other.
Give us all a rest.
All right, Lisa. What?
I just...
-Well... I just want you to know...
-Yes? What? Speak.
Well, you probably already know,
obviously, that
I told the police, on the police report, that l
thought the whole thing was an accident.
Uh-huh. Right. Because it was an accident.
Well, I mean...
I know you didn't do it on purpose.
-"On purpose"?
-But it wasn't like...
What? What? Speak. What?
Well, I mean...
We were looking at each other.
Who was looking at each other?
You and me?
Well, yeah.
I mean, not like romantically or anything.
-Romantically?
-Scratch that. That's not even relevant.
You're not coming through
very clearly here.
If you could just let me...
From my point of view,
the way I remember the accident is
you were wearing this cowboy hat,
and I was out that day to buy a cowboy hat,
so I was waving at you,
because you were wearing one,
and you were kind of waving back.
And...
I know I was distracting you,
but I did see the bus
go through the red light,
and that's when it hit that woman.
(SlGHS)
Okay.
-I'm getting a little confused here.
-Only nobody said that to them,
and I wanted to acknowledge with you
that that's what happened.
I don't know what you really mean
by "waving at you."
-Were you trying to catch the bus?
-No. Yes. But I wanted to
-ask you about your cowboy hat.
-Maybe I was waving at you,
Iike waving at you to say,
"Step away from the bus."
Because if the bus was in motion,
I would be waving you away for your own
safety, but that's all that would be.
You don't remember looking at me
and waving at me?
Not really. No.
Well, I think we both remember
something different.
-Your brother's on the phone.
-Tell him I'll call him back.
(DOOR CLOSES)
I'm not trying to get you in trouble.
I know you're not, because you can't,
because I didn't do anything wrong.
There was no criminality found.
That's it. The report is final.
So you're just gonna leave it?
I'm gonna leave it because that's all it was.
If something else had happened,
I'd take that to whatever that was.
It was tragic. It's a tragedy.
But there's only a certain speed
that those brakes can react.
That's the physical limitation
of the machine.