And I'm asking this
even though Patrice and I had
a great Christmas together
staying right here in L.A.
Gotta love this city.
No matter how many people
leave for the holidays,
traffic still blows.
- Stop ducking my question.
- I'm not ducking your question.
My situation with the captain is
completely different
than yours with Patrice.
So she's the captain again now, huh?
Okay, I'll answer your stupid question.
You don't stop dating someone
because it's going well.
And if Sharon and I were dating,
- which we're not...
- Which you are, but... never mind.
I wouldn't worry about our future
just because I disappointed
some people in the past.
Except for some reason that no one...
Including myself... can understand,
I always seem to hurt women's feelings.
So... why go on...
If there's only
one way that it can end?
Hey, sounds like all hell
is breaking loose out there.
- You got that right.
- I'll call you back.
Hold on... hey!
Flynn! Where are you?
Why go on?
Synced by emmasan
www.addic7ed.com
What do you got?
Guy ready to do a triple
gainer with a twist, sir.
Right onto the freeway. Over there.
We're waiting on a crisis counselor.
1056A reported on an overpass.
Officer assistance
required for road closure.
110 southbound.
How you doing, buddy?
Can we talk?
Can I talk to you?
I'm Andy Flynn. What's your name?
Leave me alone.
All right, but at least let me know
who I'm talking to.
Bill.
My...
My name is Bill.
Just... would you give me a moment, please?
Okay, Bill, but you got
to give me a moment, too.
You don't want to hurt anybody else, do you?
Easy, easy, Bill. Listen.
You jump, you're gonna cause
a big accident down there,
and innocent people are gonna die.
You don't want that, do you?
Wait.
You gotta know, it wasn't my fault.
Oh, man, then I can help you.
Look, I've been where you are.
Wanting to call it quits.
But it's not the answer, buddy.
Look, listen to me.
Life is temporary.
Dead is forever.
No, come on, you don't want that, do you?
Give me your hand. Bill!
Come on. Bill, take my hand, man.
Yeah, that's... that's it.
I got you. I got you.
Come on, that's right. Atta-way.
You got it. Yeah, that's it.
Hey. Hey, good man.
Way to go.
Oh, whoa, whoa. Okay.
Come on, have a seat. That's...
Good job.
That was step one.
Now let's figure out step two, okay?
What's your last name, Bill?
George.
You have any I.D. on you?
I left my wallet in the truck.
William Scott George, age
31, registered sex offender.
Served two years and two
months in Delano State Prison
for unlawful sex with a minor.
Yeah, now he's
graduated to murder.
In his prior, he slipped a 16-year-old
a few drinks before taking
her back to his place.
Yeah. Picked a charming
lad to save, Father Flynn.
What was I supposed to do, push him?
Well, not into traffic. All
right. Who's the victim?
Suicidal dirtbag says he doesn't know.
No I.D. in her pajamas.
God. Pajamas.
Rigor's just barely setting in.
I'd say three or four hours.
Time of death somewhere
between 4:45 and 5:45 A.M.
No visible bruising or wounds.
Nothing defensive.
Left wrist has some ligature markings.
- Like she was bound?
- Not sure.
Nothing on the right wrist.
Visually? Hard to give
the girl's cause of death.
So he was trying to kill himself
because she died of natural causes?
Hey. I call 'em as I see 'em.
Buzz. Hey, check this out.
Our guy likes to party a little.
Our molester travels prepared.
Gross.
Before Sanchez brought Bill's
truck to the print shed,
we found this parking pass
stuffed under the driver's seat
dated yesterday, but no address.
- Maybe he has another place.
- As a sex offender,
he's required to register every
residence with the State.
Shocking that he didn't follow the rules.
My two cents... He was willing to die
rather than I.D. the victim, because...
He knows her family.
Or he just happened to grab some girl
wandering through his neighborhood
dressed in her pajamas.
Seems unlikely.
To even think about a
deal in this situation,
Mr. George needs to tell us what happened.
Bill, I promised
that I would help you,
and I'm doing that.
But you have to help me and Sharon out
a little, too, okay?
So look. Now that you've
had some time to think...
I don't know the girl.
I told you I don't know her.
Bill, I've been doing this a long time,
and I'm aware that things
aren't always what they seem.
We don't even have a cause of
death on this young lady yet.
It could be that she passed away
from natural causes
during a sleepover.
I could see why that would make you nervous.
This is why I wanted to jump.
It doesn't matter what the hell I tell you.
You are never gonna believe me.
You're wrong about that, Bill.
I want to believe you, and Andy does, too.
I did not know this girl!
I did not know her!
Okay, okay!
Just tell us how she came to be
in the back of your truck,
and we'll go from there.
I work the graveyard shift at the paper.
It's one of my jobs.
And on mondays when
"L.A. Sexy's" run is ready,
I deliver it to all the
boxes from 3:00 A.M. to 6:30.
And then, this morning, when I got home...
There she was,
on the bed like that.
I'll verify his employment
in the porn industry.
Yeah, and see where Sykes is
with the warrant for his house.
He seems determined to be unhelpful.
You come home to find a
strange girl dead in your bed,
and you don't think to call us?
I lost it. Okay?
I-it's tough living where I do.
People have started throwing rocks
through my windows, egging my truck.
I am an ex-con and a sex offender.
That's not a cop-friendly bio.
Right. So you carried the girl's body
out of your house, and you placed her
in the back of your pickup.
Where were you taking her?
I don't know. I couldn't figure that out.
And so you decided to kill yourself
over a girl you never met?
I did... I didn't know her.
I didn't know the girl.
Why don't we send you back
to your house with Andy,
and you can walk him through what happened,
and we'll try and document it.
Yeah. You think you can
do that with me, Bill?
Hey,
isn't that Robby Oderno
from missing persons?
- What's he doing here?
- Yeah, and who's he talking to?
Hey, Bill, have you ever
seen those people before?
- No, I-I don't know them.
- Flynn, Flynn, come on.
All right, you sit tight.
Hey, Oderno!
Oderno!
- Yes, yes, yes, yes.
- What's the deal?
What... are you looking for somebody?
Yeah, Mr. and Mrs. O'Hara's
16-year-old daughter Annie
disappeared from home last night.
A little early for missing
persons to be involved.
She's autistic and given to wandering.
She wears a G.P.S. bracelet,
which according to the mother's iPad,
is pinging from in there.
Yeah, that's okay, Robby. We found her.
Uh, we also have a warrant for the house.
Oh, God.
Excuse me. Look, I'm sorry,
but my daughter is in there.
Now either you're gonna have
to do something about it,
- or we will.
- You can't just wait outside this guy's place.
Well, how do you know who lives here?
Well, everybody in the neighborhood knows
the guy's a registered sex offender.
Can't you guys just break down the door?
- Oh, my God.
- Do you have a picture of your daughter
- we can see, ma'am?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Uh, her name is, uh, Annie. There you go.
Do you mind if, uh, we keep this for a bit?
- Oh, that's fine.
- Mr. and Mrs. O'Hara, come with me, please.
Come on.
Sweep and clear,
and I will take care of the parents.
- Could you record this, please?
- Yes, sir.
Buzz...
Wait. How did... how did you
have the keys to his house?
- Well, just stay calm, ma'am.
- He has the keys to his house!
- No, that's all right.
- Jen.
- It's okay.
- That's him.
- What?
- That's the guy in the back seat right there!
Hey, you bastard! Hey!
What did you do to her?!
You sick bastard!
What did you do to my
daughter? Where is she?
Hey! You need to be calm, please!
Calm down, please!
If you hurt my baby, I will kill you!
- Kill you!
- All right.
I'm fine! I'm fine. I'm fine.
Oh! What are you doing here?
I locked my keys in my car.
Okay. I'll get you mine.
- Thank you.
- How'd it go with Emma?
Is there something new
about the Phillip Stroh case?
Uh, yeah. He... He fired his attorney,
and... and now he's going, um...
- Pro-per.
- Does that mean representing himself?
- Yes.
- That's it then.
Yes, he's going pro-per,
and he's trying to give up information
on people he's defended... Stroh is...
so that Emma will take the
death penalty off the table
and there won't be a trial.
But everything he wants to tell her,
- Stroh has to run by a, uh...
- Special master.
Yeah. Yeah, to see what's
privileged and what isn't.
Anyway, if he ends up giving information
to Emma that she wants, I'm done.
Mm.
What?
Um, I'm glad about the deal.
And I was just wondering why Emma
didn't talk to me about it... too.
Well, maybe because she's irritated
I'm still living with you.
I mean, I'm pretty sure
instead of Santa Monica,
she wanted me to go to college in, like,
- New Zealand or something like that.
- Mm-hmm.
Oh, uh, but since I am here,
she wants me to write an impact statement.
Ah. An impact statement.
Yes? Come in.
- Oh...
- Oh, excuse me.
Oh, my God, it's like you
have radar or something.
Don't worry, I'm not here for you.
I'll see you Thursday like always.
Your mother said there was something
she wanted me to see from a suspect's house.
Yes. These.
Red paper hearts.
They're all handmade.
We found about 20 of them on
our suspect's refrigerator,
each with a little message, like this one...
"Have a great day. XOXO." Written in crayon.
You know, maybe he had Annie
thinking that she loved him.
Given our victim's autism,
our question is this...
Could she have made and
written these cards by herself?
Autism exists on a broad spectrum.
Some kids are almost fully functional.
Some are... unreachable.
Annie's file says she was
wearing a G.P.S. alert bracelet
with a Q.R. code containing
her medical history.
Right here, doc. Let's see.
Contact info for her family.
Records of pediatrician visits.
A note about ways to
calm her if she's agitated.
It recommends prone restraint to hold her
and soft whispers to calm her.
All fairly typical. Well.
I'm not sure if she wrote on these cards,
but she didn't make them.
You wouldn't hand this girl
sharp objects like scissors.
But since she was a wanderer,
maybe your suspect had seen her out before.
Or she was leaving to meet him.
You found the bracelet broken?
And tossed underneath the suspect's bed.
She could have reacted to some
stress in her environment,
and your guy might not
have known how to calm her.
Were there any other signs of a struggle?
No. No blood. Nothing was broken.
The bed was made.
Cleanest house I've ever seen,
almost like no one lived here.
Or like he tried to straighten
up really good after.
No forced entry. Not
even one window unlocked.
If somebody dropped her body
there like Mr. George says,
- how'd they get in?
- Then like I said,
maybe she was wandering his way at night.
And this morning is the first
her family knew about it.
It could be.
Listening to you interview the parents
might give me a better
idea of how Annie lived.
Thank you for volunteering that, Joe.
- Glad to do it.
- Amy and Julio,
try to get as much information as possible
from Mr. and Mrs. O'Hara before
you tell them the bad news.
Yeah. Okay.
Thank you.
When was the last time you saw Annie?
Uh, it was 8:00, 8:30,
somewhere around there. Yeah.
Bedtimes are the one
thing that's been easier lately.
Actually, you know, I did pop my head in.
It was around, uh, 10:00.
She was already asleep.
I mean, I should have locked her in.
I just... she was... She
was so sound asleep.
Sometimes when she gets up in the morning,
if her door isn't open, she panics.
Were there any activities
or social circumstances
where Annie was out of your
supervision during the day?
No.
No, no, it's a 24/7 situation.
We're big believers in constant interaction.
There's a lot of evidence
to support that approach.
Sounds like they were
doing the right things.
Ray always said I couldn't do it.
It was too much to handle.
- Yeah.
- Honey, don't get upset about Ray again.
Ray, ma'am? Who's Ray?
Jen's first husband, Ray Sutton.
He was not an ideal parent, period.
Let's run Ray Sutton and see what turns up.
Because when Bill gets an attorney,
he will check on Mr. Sutton if we don't.
But to his credit, he knew it.
He never ducked out on
child support, even though
I told him it wasn't necessary.
Screw his money.
Ray wanted perfect kids.
Perfect kids are hard to come by.
Well, has she run off before?
You know, maybe it's
because she's a teenager,
but...  yeah.
I mean, lately if you leave the door open
- or you turn your back for a second, she's...
- We did.
We put more locks on the door.
- She run off at night, too?
- Um...
Yeah, it's a fairly new problem, yeah.
Um, last week I was on the phone, and...
The sliding glass door to the patio, um,
was open behind me, and...
I mean, she was five blocks
away before I found her.
She was, uh...
She was at the park.
She loves the swings.
I mean, she'd swing all day if she could.
It's okay.
Does Annie know how to read and write?
At about a second grade level, yeah. Why?
Could she have made these?
Um...
Where... where are these from?
Front of Mr. George's refrigerator.
Uh... Yeah, A-Annie, um...
- She... she can't make this.
- Are you telling me my daughter did what?
- She made valentines for that bastard?
- Look, she's not...
She's not in a relationship with anybody.
She doesn't know him.
- Yes?
- Okay? She doesn't know him.
- Okay.
- Where is she?
Dr. Morales is ready for you, captain.
- Where's my daughter?
- Did he rape her? Did he...
Let's call and arrange for
an attorney for Mr. George.
Where... where did he take
my little girl? Is she...
We found your daughter.
We know where she is, ma'am, yes.
My apologies on the delay.
We're backed up with the
post-Christmas blues.
Yeah, well, I took one jumper
off your table this morning.
Every little bit helps.
So, your teenage girl.
- Annie.
- Hmm?
Her name is Annie.
Annie. Right.
Uh, cause of death is
positional asphyxiation.
Meaning someone applied too
much pressure to her torso.
Actually, kept the lungs from being able
to expand and contract.
By sitting on her, lying on her, what?
Possibly. However it happened,
she wasn't able to breathe,
and if that goes on long enough, you die.
Could this have occurred
during a sexual assault?
Your victim was a virgin.
But she could have died before the suspect
had a chance to do anything.
She starts screaming,
he tries to shut her up.
It's a terrible story
I keep hoping to not have to repeat.
This rules out a longer sexual relationship.
- Unless he was grooming her for it.
- Hmm.
I mean, he's no idiot, Bill.
And he's hiding stuff.
Feels like maybe worse stuff.
Anything else, doc?
Hmm? Oh. Yeah.
I found multi-colored fibers in her mouth
from some kind of rainbow fabric.
I could send them to the lab
to determine what they are.
Have a look.
Did you see anything
like this at Bill's house?
No. Like Buzz said,
- the guy's place was pristine.
- Hmm.
I think we need to locate where
he uses that parking pass.
Maybe we'll find a blanket or pillow there.
Or maybe we'll find another girl
who makes him hearts with hugs and kisses.
homework before the semester starts?
Oh, uh, no. This is my impact statement.
I want to be sure to say, like,
I'm still willing to testify,
because I want Stroh gone
one way or the other.
But I want the judge to know
that I'm not the same kid
who was in the park anymore.
And not having to talk
about that would be...
great.
It would be, yes.
What?
Two things.
You were never the person in the park.
You were there because of circumstances,
not because of who you are.
Yeah. I think that's mostly true.
It is entirely true.
Well, it doesn't feel entirely true.
Rusty, you were beneath the age of consent,
and that makes what
happened to you criminal.
You got to remember that.
And the other thing is that
Emma jumped the gun here, and I wish that
she hadn't told you that she
was gonna try and make a deal
- with Stroh, because...
- She's not?
Well, I don't know. It's possible.
All right, the thing is, um, Stroh...
As a lawyer who used to
represent sex offenders,
Stroh may have protected several criminals
that he will trade for leniency.
He would do that?
Highly organized killers like Stroh,
they often plan way ahead.
Why does he still have privilege? Stroh?
Certain communications, like
between you and Dr. Joe,
for example, or a lawyer and a client,
can't be given to the police or a D.A.
Unless they involve future crimes.
So the special master is...
The special master decides
what Stroh can reveal, if
anything, from his past.
Come by work this afternoon.
Andrea's gonna be there.
She will explain everything.
Oh! I... I take it there's news.
We've had a hit on our suspect's truck, sir.
Two months ago Bill had an accident
outside the gates of Fairfax Heights.
Oh. Probably the largest
apartment complex in America.
Uh, that's the one. Security e-mailed a copy
of the parking passes they use.
It's a match to the one we
found in the suspect's truck.
So this goes to Bill's crash pad?
No. It's a visitor pass,
and there's no apartment in his name. But...
I talked them into signing consent forms
for their security footage
from two nights ago.
Okay, we have him, sir. We have him.
Bill enters Tower 14 at 8:11 P.M.
He goes up to the third floor.
And wait until you see who
he was going to visit, sir.
Meet Kayla,
daughter of Bill's current girlfriend.
Where is her mother?
She's on her way here.
All right, get the captain. And Dr. Joe.
It's his job to ask her
the disgusting questions.
And I'm thinking, Flynn,
that they're going to want
those paper hearts, too.
Yeah.
My daughter makes these all the time.
She just loves Bill.
Well, he treats her like a princess.
The night before last, Bill
was at your apartment?
Yeah, like he is most nights.
He goes to work around 11:30.
Wh-why are you asking
about Bill? Is he okay?
I-I called, but I haven't
heard from him since he left.
How do you know Bill?
We met at his day job.
He works at the car wash near my office.
And we just hit it off.
Even after he knew I was a single mom,
which is usually when guys suddenly remember
they have something else to do.
Bill was never bothered by Kayla at all.
Uh-huh. And how is their
relationship... Kayla and Bill?
Fine. Great. Why are you asking that?
Ms. Kemp, are you aware Mr. George
is a registered sex offender
and served two years for
unlawful sex with a minor?
What, are you kidding me?
And you're asking me about Kayla?
You think he did something to her?
Ms. Kemp, we're only
covering our bases here.
With your consent, we'd like
to search your apartment
just to make sure everything is okay,
and have Kayla talk to a specialist
- to assess the situation.
- Oh, my God.
Did he...
Let's not jump the gun. No. First...
First... first, let's talk to Kayla.
Let's hear what she has to say.
- All right?
- Oh, my God.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Bill's awesome.
He leaves early, so I
hide them in his truck.
The hearts.
Mom says a kind word from a friend
can get you through a rough day.
And Bill's a friend?
Oh, yeah. He's the best.
He takes me to Dodgers games, the movies.
And sometimes we just kick back.
Is your mom with you
when you're kicking back?
It depends on work schedules.
Kayla, can I ask you, um...
While you're kicking back
with him on your own,
has Bill ever asked you to
keep a secret from your mom?
If it's called a secret, I can't tell you.
Well... but...
It's my job to hold on to secrets
and not tell anyone.
Mom can't know.
- Promise not to tell.
- I do.
I almost don't want to know the answer.
Oh, my gosh, I can't believe
I'm going to say this out loud.
Okay.
Bill wants to ask mom to marry him.
And he wanted to make sure
I was cool with it first.
How about that, huh?
Would you like that?
If your mom and Bill got married?
Oh, yeah.
My mom deserves a decent guy.
And I wouldn't let anyone
take Bill away from her.
No one gets Bill but us.
She seems unaffected.
- Uh-huh.
- After everything she's been through...
- So why didn't Bill mention her?
- My mom needs this.
Or her mother?
Because he had plans, that's why.
They obviously didn't know
anything about his past.
Has the suspect's public
defender come in yet?
She's in there with him now.
Let's inform her that Bill
has nothing left to hide.
He'll either make a deal, or he won't.
Tori Kemp wants to know
why you haven't been returning her calls.
I'm sorry. Just catching up here.
Who is Tori Kemp? Your client, Jane,
has a secret girlfriend
with a 13-year-old daughter.
I've been chatting with Kayla, too,
and here's what bothers
me about all this, Bill.
You never told me about
Ms. Kemp and her daughter,
and you never told them
about your life in prison.
You've been keeping a lot of secrets
from a lot of different people.
Tori and Kayla...
They were why I was on that bridge, Andy.
What, you... you dragged them into this?
You said you wanted to help me.
How... how is that helping anything?
You know, Bill, Andy here likes you.
Me? Well... I'm a little more suspicious.
And in my travels through depraved parts
of the criminal world,
I've heard the theory
floated that sexual predators
try to get close with single moms,
and to get even closer to their kids.
Why did you tell them about me?
Why did you tell them? Why?
Did you think that was necessary?
You lied to me. The whole time, you lied.
Look, Bill, they're just
trying to push your buttons.
- You lied. You lied.
- If they had any evidence
you'd done anything with Kayla,
you'd already be under arrest.
My client was under the impression
you were trying to verify his story.
Well, that didn't work out, Jane,
so we're going to do this instead.
If your client would like
to tell us the details
of how he murdered Annie
and attempted to dispose of her body,
then we'll bring a D.A. in here
with a deal for life in prison.
Or he can drag the people
he pretends to love
through an expensive and pointless trial.
Mr. George, I advise you to take your time.
- Why? Why?
- 'Cause these...
Why, why? Everybody
knows, so why wait, okay?
You have a pen, Andy?
Not before a D.A. gets here with an offer!
- Mr. George, you will not take that pen.
- I revoke my right to counsel.
Shut up!
Just start at the beginning.
Oh, my God!
Let go! Bill! Bill, let go!
Why did you tell them?
That, um, that Kayla girl...
Sh-she okay?
She didn't present as someone
who'd been molested,
if that's what you mean.
And, uh, her hopes for
her mom seemed genuine.
Well, Ms. Kemp might have loved the guy,
but she was definitely
getting a pig in a poke,
as we used to say.
You know, it's... it's interesting
how Bill George could turn his life around
enough so that he could
have an adult relationship
- to begin with.
- Uh, I don't know.
He's older. People's attractions change
with negative reinforcement.
Though that's hard to do.
Tell me about it.
I myself...
Ah, well...  I myself
find I'm seeing...
and, uh...
I'm definitely having second
thoughts about it all...
Seeing someone who is so very much different
from anyone I've ever
dated in my adult life.
Oh. How different?
Huge?
In, uh, what way?
Well, um, she's...
It's... she's very close to my own age.
I mean, I don't go out with women over 40.
Well...
- Why don't you just drop her?
- What?
Stop seeing her if she's not what you want.
Well...
Who said she's not what I want?
Oh, I thought you did.
I most certainly did not.
And here's something else I'll tell you.
In a relationship, doctor,
it's not always about what you want.
Sometimes it's about what
the other person wants.
Well, if you say so, lieutenant.
Excuse me. Would you see this report
gets filed with your captain?
Thank you.
Psychologists.
What took you so long?
Did you serve the warrants?
Well, what'd you find?
The clasp from the broken bracelet.
And the blanket that Annie's
face was pressed into
while someone sat on her ribs.
And you found this in Tori Kemp's apartment?
- No.
- Worse than that.
What could be worse than that?
In Annie's bedroom.
Annie was killed in her own house.
Her bracelet broke in the struggle.
Any sign of forced entry?
None.
But the fibers in the blanket
are a definitive match to the
ones found in Annie's mouth.
She's lying face down, prone,
gasping for air on her own bed.
What do we have on Annie's parents?
I looked on their browser history.
There's a ton of visits to
the Megan's Law Database.
And over a dozen times last month,
someone searched Bill George's page.
And that background check we
did on Annie's natural father,
- Ray Sutton?
- No priors,
no arrests, and he lives in Colorado.
And he says he doesn't
have keys to the house.
Well, someone does, though,
if Annie died in her own room.
Or someone has keys to Bill George's house,
because neither showed
signs of forced entry.
You said Bill's house was pristine.
Bill said his windows have
been broken... several times.
So he had to have them fixed several times.
Wait, whoa, whoa.
If you're suggesting
that we talk to this nut job again,
I'm chaining him to the floor.
Bill, your doors had dead bolts on them.
Nobody popped them.
Your windows, all locked.
No one had access to your house except you.
So who else could have entered?
He doesn't know. Why don't
you ask one of the neighbors?
Apparently they watch his
house like guard dogs.
How are you so sure one of
them didn't kill the girl
- just to frame my client?
- Why?
Now it's the neighbors setting him up?
That's a new legal theory.
Because, "hi, I'm your new neighbor,
and I'm a registered sex
offender, nice to meet you."
Bill, you said your windows were broken.
Several times, yes.
I would walk in to find a
rock lying on the floor...
- Bill.
- And shards of glass everywhere.
Did you pay someone to fix your windows,
or did you do it yourself?
Of course I didn't fix them.
I called a repair guy.
Do you have his contact info?
There's a receipt in my kitchen.
I save everything. A guy
in prison told me that.
Keep records, receipts,
check stubs, tickets,
whatever, just in case.
I even saved the rocks.
You... you want them, too?
Bill, you work two jobs.
One of them's all day long.
How did this repairman
get in to fix your window?
With a spare key
that I leave out over the front door.
You think somebody set him
up to get into his house?
Ask him. He'll tell you.
Annie's parents were at Bill's
even before we got there.
Following a G.P.S. signal on a bracelet.
Which led them directly to someone
they'd looked up online a hundred times.
Sir.
Maybe we should brief Mr. and Mrs. O'Hara
on our progress.
Ah.
And let's get Hobbs in here.
I think we're ready.
You said that you have new information.
Um, yes, we now believe
that Annie was killed in her bedroom.
What? I'm sorry, what...
- What... are you saying this man...
- No. No, no, that doesn't...
- That doesn't make any sense.
- Broke into our house and hurt our little girl
- while we slept in the next room?
- Her bracelet was found in his house.
We have an eyewitness, a neighbor who saw
someone carry a body into
Bill's place that night...
Using this spare key.
It was left on the ledge
above the front door.
A very smart person could have watched
how the window repairman
entered Mr. George's house
while he was away.
Taking this key from above the front door.
And that's what our
witness says he saw happen.
He also says that he can
identify the person who did it.
I wish we actually had an eyewitness.
We do. If they think we do.
Who... who did this witness see?
Well, the physical description sounds
very much like your husband.
- What, like Chris?
- Mm-hmm.
Okay, are you joking?
We... Chris was with me.
Well, it's probably just a coincidence,
but because the description is so close,
we'd like to ask you, Mr. O'Hara,
to participate in a line-up.
Moment of truth, buddy.
If he walks out, we're screwed.
Right now?
If it's no trouble.
Yeah. Everyone is waiting.
W...
What's the big deal? Just go.
Chris.
Chris, why aren't you going?
Oh, my God, what did you do?
Oh! What did you do?
Look at me!
Oh, my... what... what did you do?!
What did you do to Annie? Oh, my...
What did you do? Damn it!
What did you do?! What did you do?!
Chris! She loved you!
Oh, my God! Chris!
You have the
right to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will be
used against you in a court of law.
You have the right to an attorney.
If you cannot afford one, one
will be appointed for you.
Do not get up without asking me!
- Julio.
- I'm just setting the ground rules, ma'am.
I'm not some helpless little girl, okay?
Is there anything you'd
like to tell us, Mr. O'Hara?
It was an accident.
It was an accident?
Annie was having a fit.
A really bad one. She was out of control,
and I tried calming her down, but...
I used the soft prone restraint
hold that they teach us,
but... but she just got
so aggressive, and...
I-I don't know what happened.
I mean, all of a sudden she
wasn't breathing, and...
It was an accident.
Then you accidentally moved her body
to your friendly neighborhood
sexual predator's house.
- I didn't know what to do.
- But you did know what to do.
You wanted it to look like
Mr. George committed this murder.
I improvised that in the moment.
No, you did not improvise!
- You tossed several rocks through Mr. George's windows!
- Believe what you want.
- So he would have to call a repairman!
- I did not throw rocks
- through George's window!
- And you could see how to gain entry
into his house!
Mr. O'Hara, did you wear gloves
when you threw the rocks through the window?
Because Mr. George saved the rocks,
and we're having them printed right now.
That's true. Guy holds on to everything.
If you don't want to tell us what happened,
maybe you would prefer a jury
to listen to how you crushed the ribs
of a special needs child
and then stuffed a blanket in her mouth.
She was not a special needs child!
She was a "no one else
can ever need anything
because it's all about her" kind of child.
The only life that Annie ever had
was the life she took from us!
And she was never gonna get better, but Jen,
no, she couldn't see that!
"Oh, I can't... I can't leave
my little girl in a prison,"
so now you want to throw me in prison?
Where do you think I've been living anyway?
Annie wasn't the one who was locked in!
I was!
God.
You have no idea how tired I am.
Oh...
That should put you over the top.
Yeah. Maybe Bill George can stop
- trying to kill himself now.
- Go ahead.
I'll say this.
It takes a special person to
see to the special needs
of a complicated kid.
Excuse me.
- Write it all down.
- Hey.
I'll see what we can do.
Impact statements come from victims.
I'm not a victim.
Stroh tried to kill you.
He hit you in the head with a shovel.
He pushed you into a canyon.
He sliced your leg open with a knife.
And that's all attempted murder.
Right. Right.
I see.
And you're saying that Emma wants me
to write about Stroh because...
She doesn't want the deal to go forward.
No matter what information
comes through the special master,
Emma still thinks Stroh should go to trial
for murder in the first
with special circumstances attached.
Did she ever actually tell you otherwise?
No. Um...
- I feel like such an idiot.
- Uh... Mh-mnh.
Lawyers are so...
- I'm sorry, I just, like...
- No.
Emma should have been clearer
with you about her intentions.
I'll talk to her about that.
But... deal or no deal,
sometime in the next two weeks,
this Phillip Stroh business
is coming to a head now.
Just so you know.
Thank you, Andrea.
Um, yeah, thank you. Thank you, Andrea.
I do appreciate the truth.
I do.
So what do you think?
I mean, sh-should I write
the impact statement or not?
It's a choice
between putting someone
in an institution for life,
or putting them to death
because they are in some way
a danger, and lack the
mental capacity for change.
It's an awful thing to have to consider.
But you've been given a voice here,
if not the last word.
If it were up to Rusty Beck,
what would happen
to someone like Phillip Stroh?
Synced by emmasan
www.addic7ed.com