[ Girl ]
Swords and staves.
Tough road you got this year.
Judgment, Death...
and Mr. Devil.
Glad it's your birthday readin'
and not mine.
Now here's your card, Fool.
See?
That's where I got your nickname.
[ Fool ] Don't remind me.
Here you go-- Thirteen today.
The golden-haired birthday boy
is settin' off on life's big adventure.
I ain't no
golden-haired nobody.
And all I'm
goin' off to
is seventh grade.
Well, you the Fool, and you can't escape that.
That ain't bad.
No?
No. Ain't the stupid
kind of fool.
Only the ignorant kind,
'cause you're just startin' out.
Well, that's better,
I guess. Ah, but look here.
Already he's got
a problem, see?
One step in front?
The drop off.
What about the dog?
That's Fool's companion.
See his spirit barking?
"Fool! Don't go marching
over that cliff, now."
Do the smart thing--
the high thing.
So what Fool gonna do
if he ain't gonna go
off the cliff? Fly?
He gonna do
what he have to, Fool--
Turn around and walk
the other way, right through the fire of the sun.
He get burned up
if he do that.
Just the boy part
get burned up.
Rest come out
the other side a man,
and no one
calls him Fool again.
[ Woman Coughing ]
[ Girl ]
Just try to sleep, Mama.
There's nothing you can do.
Shh.
[ Coughing Continues ]
Just rest, Mom.
[ Woman ]
I don't know what
to do with this, Ruby.
I didn't think the
landlord would do this--
Not now.
Fool, you shouldn't be here.
Fool, go back to
readin' your book.
What's wrong?
Nothin' you can do. Go on.
[ Lighter Flicking ]
Who are you?
Leroy, a friend of Ruby's.
You the little brother
she call Fool?
[ Sighs ]
My real name's Poindexter,
but Ruby hung up
on them tarot cards.
Why Mama cryin'?
Y'all been evicted.
You gotta be out tomorrow midnight.
I guess Ruby didn't see that one in the cards.
But why?
You're three days late
with your payment.
Fine print in the lease says
you gotta pay triple, else get out.
Only, your mama
and Ruby ain't got triple.
Well, don't
the landlord know that--
that Mama's sick
or Ruby got babies?
Yeah, sure, he knows.
He don't care.
He wants to tear down the building.
Y'all the last family in it.
You got some money
you can kick in?
[ Distant Siren ]
I know a way you can earn some.
You game?
[ Clearing Throat ]
One last family in
the Lennox Avenue building,
then it's clear to tear down.
[ Grunting ]
We build a nice,neat condominium.
We get clean people in there.
Lots of nice wood for my fireplace.
Lots of nice--
Money.
And money, mm-hmm.
For me.
Mama, what happens
to the people when you
make them leave their home?
I don't believe
I was speaking to you.
Speak when spoken to.
That's what good girls do.
You getting them out soon?
By tomorrow midnight.
Damn buckshot.
[ Chattering ]
[ Man ]
Hey, Fool!
Hey, I hear you're
gettin' evicted, man.[ Coughing ]
[ Man #2 ]
Yeah, then yo' ass
goin' be out on the street.
Hey, come back here!
[ Chattering ]
- [ Man Shouts, Indistinct ]
- [ Barking, Snarling ]
[ Girl ]
Hi, Fool.
[ Ruby ]
He don't need that kind
of opportunity.
He's a good kid.
Let's keep it that way.
He work for me, he do better
than the rest of ya.
Out of seven,
three's already dead.
And then there's you, baby--
Turnin' tricks on the strip.
Willy's a crack addict,
and what's the other one's name?
What's he in jail for? Assault?
Washington, and he didn't do nothin'.
He tried to put food
on the damn table.
That's what I'm tryin'
to teach the boy to do.
He wants to be a doctor.
You can't even afford
to pay rent!
How the hell you gonna
afford to send him to medical school?
- It ain't right anyway.
- Oh, that right?
You know your Mama got
a cancer in her...
she can't afford to have taken out?
Leroy!
Yeah, the thing any doctor
could take out just like that,
but you ain't got no money!
[ Muffled ]
And you ain't gonna
have no money unless-- Aah![ Kicks ]
You little snot--
Leroy, let go--
Don't touch me. Don't touch me!
You listen up, you little punk.
Listen up! Now, this is the big one,
and somebody deserve to be robbed.
Somebody who don't care nothin' about
Families or about the neighborhood.
He just wanna bring the wreckin' ball
In so he can line his pockets.
Who you talkin' about?
- The landlord, that's who.
- [ Siren Wailing ]
[ Ruby ] The landlord of this building?
Yeah.
I found a treasure map
last night in the back room...
of the liquor store
me and Spenser hit--
A letter addressed to the owner along
with the name of his company.
So?
So the name of the company...
is the same as the name
on your eviction notice.
Same guy who
owns the liquor store...
owns this building and half
the buildings in the ghetto.
I know where
your landlord lives.
No. Leave him alone.
I heard things about him.
Bad things.
You heard about the gold?
This is from the company...
that wants to buy the coins
the landlord collected--
Gold coins.
You wanna be stupid, Leroy?
You don't need Fool for that.
We got a plan for him, baby--
"Fool" proof.
Or you want your family
eatin' beans out in the street?
One day I'm gonna buy you a Cadillac
for each foot, Mama,
and you're gonna skate around town
looking so bad.
Just take care of the kids, Dexter.
You the man of the house now.
I'm tryin', Mama.
I'm tryin'.
[ Coughs ]
You didn't lick this, did you?
- No, ma'am.
- Stand up.
Hope this fits.
I worked all day.
Turn around. Stand still.
[ Zipping ]
Do you love your mother?
Yes, ma'am.
"Yes, ma'am," what?
Yes, ma'am, I love
you, Mother.
Good girl.
- Where's your fork?
- Fork?
I gave you a fork with this.
Where is your fork?
Well, it must've fallen--
- Somewhere on the floor maybe.
- You don't know?
No, I'm sure it's on the floor.
I mean, I know I dropped it.
You know the punishment
for losing silverware.
I'm sure it's right here.
[ Moans Softly ]
I knew it was there.
Some niggers  robbed the store.
Again?
May they burn in hell.
I'm very tense from this.
You have one of your headaches?
Ooh! Very, very,
tense about this.
Alice has been bad.
She's been feeding that thing
between the walls again.
- No.
- [ Faint Wailing ]
Remember not to bruise her face.
Bad girls... burn in hell.
[ Leroy ]
There.
[ Man ]
Jesus, it goes on forever.
No bars on the windows.
No car in the driveway. Maybe we lucked out.
Where's Fool?
He's goin' in.
Takin' it cool.
[ Creaks ]
[ Thuds ]
[ Bell Rings ]
May I help you?
Good afternoon, ma'am.
Sorry to bother you, but I'd just like
to show you...
some of these delicious cookies
we're selling.
I'm sorry.
We watch what we eat very carefully here.
I know it's a bother,
but so is cerebral palsy.
And if we don't do all we can--
I'm sorry.
Well, do you have, like,
a bathroom I could use?
They leave us
out here all day...
without anywhere to take a leak.
No. Sorry. No.
Sorry. Run along.
That's all right.
No. Run along.
That's okay.
Heavy wire screens
on the back windows.
They been hit before,
you think?
Uh, probably just
the neighborhood.
How are the screens held on?
Padlocks on the outside.
Padlocks on the outside? Geez.
What else? Any alarms?
That I don't know.
She wouldn't let me in.
I told you to tell her
you had to piss.
She wasn't buyin' that.
I wanna take a look.
Don't be stupid, Spenser.
The kid told us all there was to see.
We go in Sunday as we planned.
What if they got a remote alarm
to the police?
I'm not goin' in Sunday
without checkin' out the security.
Just look at the doors.The basement.
Maybe the connector boxes.
Now, how the hell are you
gonna get in there? She wouldn't
even let him up on the porch.
Well, you send a boy to do a man's job,
that's what you get.
Anyway, you thought
the Bear Scout disguise
was good, watch this.
Help you?
Gas company, ma'am.
Been an emergency.
Need to check your meter.
Passed it on your way up the drive.
Oh, that one we've already got.
There's one inside the house that I need to check.
There's none in the house.
I'm quite sure of that.
You're probably not even
aware of it, ma'am,
but it's on the master list,
and I'm gonna have to check it.
See, the situation is, we got a leak on
the block and it could be very dangerous.
- Identification?
- Oh, yeah.
Fact is, we do have
the legal right to come in,
even if we do have
to call the police--
Not that we ever have.
It's just there've been an awful lot
of robberies lately.
Neighborhood's changing.
Has us all a bit on edge.
I completely understand.
Better this little bother
than a chance of danger,though, right?
[ Fool ] I don't know how
he got past that woman.
She's got X-ray eyeballs.
[ Leroy ] Spenser's as slippery
as a snake.
I think he's up to somethin'.
Somethin' like what?
Like grabbin' that coin collection
for himself and cuttin' me out.
Cuttin' us out.
Spenser mess with you,
he gotta deal with me too.
[ Car Door Slams ]
[ Chuckles ] You somethin', Fool.
[ Car Engine Starts ]
She leave him alone in the place?
You gotta be kiddin'.
Has to be someone else in there—
Old folks, kids or somethin'.
Maybe Spenser should stick his
ugly head out and give us
some kind of a signal.
Maybe he lookin' around a little bit,
make sure it's safe.
Maybe the president is gonna
make me secretary of pussy.
Now, he's probably in there
hidin' the best for himself.
Come on. We goin' in.
No. Spenser said we gotta
stay out here, Leroy.
So he can get all
the good shit for himself?
Why not throw your mama out in the
street along with Ruby and the kids?
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Bell Rings ]
See?
[ Crowbar Clinking ]
[ Leroy Grunting ]
[ Grunts ]
They in Fort Knox or what?
Listen, Leroy.  This breakin'
and enterin' might not be so smart.
I mean, it's the first day
of my 13th birthday.
Could be unlucky.
Thirteenth birthday
is unlucky anyway.
Too old to get tit, too young to get ass.
Fucked either way!
Lord, now,
look at this.
The mother of all doors.
They ain't messin' around.
Spenser.
Spenser!
[ Creaking ]
Eh, so, Leroy, you think I got what
it takes to be a doctor?
Doctor of burglary maybe.
You're lucky I'm teachin' you
a trade, kid.
Ain't no door stands up
to Leroy.
I done busted this house's cherry.
It's opened right up now.
[ Snarling ]
- Get back!
- Get off him!
- Get off!
- [ Screaming ]
Hey, fuzzball!
Your mama sleeps with cats!
[ Grunting ]
Run, Fool!
That's one mean motherfucker!
You see that? He came at me
like an airplane or somethin'!
I saw it all right.
He gone?
He's waitin' right there.
Been trained to
wait there, probably.
He stay out there, and we stay
right in here.
[ Insect Buzzing ]
[ Leroy ]
This place is weird.
"See no evil, hear no evil,
speak no evil." [ Clears Throat ]
[ Leroy ]
Every cabinet has a lock on it.
Why do you think they do that?
Somebody need a bath bad.
[ Tapping ]
Heh! Nice to see
that rich folks got rats too.
Listen, Leroy. Let's just get outta here--
Out the front.
Let's first we find out
what's up with good old Spenser.
Man, the hell with Spenser!
Let's just get outta here!
Hell with those
gold coins too, huh?
Now, maybe you too stupid
for this kind of work,
or maybe you too chickenshit.
[ Thudding ]
Oh, there's
that bastard now.
He's upstairs.
We'll surprise him.
Come on.
Comin' or what?
I'm coming.
[ Clanking ]
[ Clock Tolling Hour ]
[ Gasps ]
I don't think we should
go up there, Leroy.
Oh, that's fine, girlfriend.
I'll tell you what. You stay down here,
and you keep an eye out.
You think you can do that?
[ Kissing Sound ]
[ Chuckles ]
Yeah. I can do that.
Man, there's enough room
for 10 families in here.
[ Leroy ]
Spenser! Spenser, you up here?
[ Rumbling ]
[ Rattling ]
Spenser!
- Spenser, you back in there?
- [ Breathy Voice, Indistinct ]
I ain't stupid.
"Or maybe you just too chickenshit
for this kind of work."
[ Male Voice Muttering ]
[ Lock Clicks ]
[ Ghostly Voice ]Fool.
Spenser?
[ Thud ]
Huh! Spenser?
[ Man ]
How can you say that of me?
I've never been unfaithful
to you, never even looked at another woman.
[ Woman ] I'm not talking about another woman, John.
I'm not talking about that at all.
[ John ]
What's that supposed to mean?
[ Woman ]
Connect the dots, John.
Everyone else has.
Ever since Paris.
Ever since Sybil killed herself.
[ Man ]Sybil's death was
a sailing accident.
[ Woman ]There are no accidents, John.
Only survivors.
And that's what I am--
A survivor. Tiffany!
I'm sorry, John.
Sorry for the both of us.
Sorry for the child that...
we never had, and never will!
Tiffany, don't get--
[ Man #2 Continues, Indistinct ]
[ Clanging ]
[ Man On TV ]
Oh, now, the antiaircraft battery!
- They're firing.
- Where?
I think it's the barracks.
They're over by the barracks.
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
We can hear
the staccato firing.
And now, here it comes.
Baghdad is lighting up!
Tracers flaring up
like angry hornets
from every rooftop now.
We cannot see the bombers,
but the fire of their munitions
is shaking the city.
It's shaking our hotel.
Oh, look! Look!
There's a cruise missile.
See it? Where?
There! Right over there!
It's flying just over
the rooftops!
Spenser,
you back in there?
[ Screams ]
[ Man Laughing ]
[ Indistinct Shout ]
Aah!
[ Grunting ]
Spenser.
[ Grunting Continues ]
You can't do that,
you miserable, stinkin' thief!
[ Gibberish ]
Come on, Spens.
I'm gonna get you outta here.
Man. This ain't right.
Who are you?
[ Shouting, Screaming ]
Leroy, we gotta get
out of this place! Oh, no!
Whoa!
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Grunting, Moaning ]
Ohh!
Let me go! Uh!
[ Panting ]
Hello? Miss?
[ Vehicle Rumbles ]
[ Barking ]
Leroy! Leroy!
Leroy?
- Leroy!
- Jesus!
- [ Screams ]
- You scared the shit out of me!
I thought you were dead, Leroy.
You was just layin' there.
A man ain't dead just 'cause
he's layin' on the floor.
I was listenin'.
Something's in there.
As a matter of fact,
why don't you crawl in there
and see what it is?
You turkey brain! You hittin'
on me, and I come up here
to save your ass!
Your gonna stick your dumb head
in there and lose it just like Spenser!
- What kind of shit you talkin'?
- I'm talkin' we gotta  get out of here, Leroy!
That X-ray lady's  back. She's out back
right now by the van.
She got a man with her
the size of Detroit!
- Damn. You seen Spenser?
- I seen Spenser all right.
- He find anything?
- Somethin' found him.
He's dead, Leroy--
I think scared to death.
You sure?
[ Scoffs ]You thought he was white before?
You should see that sucker now!
[ Door Opens, Shuts ]
[ Man ]
There is somebody in there.
The doors have been pried open.
I told you
there'd be another one.
Out the front.
Uh-oh!
[ Crackling ]
Wow! Uh!
Oh, shit.
Oh, my hand.
[ Fool Groaning ]
[ Woman ]Pry it open at the bottom--
enough so Prince can get in.
[ Snarling, Barking ]
Oh, God.
Come on, Fool!
Aah! What are you doing? Aah!
Stand right here, right in the open,
so the fuckin' dog can see you.
You think I'm crazy?
That mother got teeth he ain't even used yet!
Do like I say,
or I'm gonna take your head off.
I'm gonna nail that sucker.
Don't worry. I'm worried.
[ Growls ]
Kill! Get 'em!
Uh, uh-oh.
[ Whispers ]
Where'd he go?
[ Growls ]
Shit! Shit!
[ Screams ]
Get the fuck off me! Aah!
- Pull, Leroy!
- Fool! What the hell you doin', Fool?
Come on! Come on!
Fool!
Come on!
Aah!
[ Indistinct Shout ]
[ Pained Yelling ]
I'm gonna take
your fuckin' head off!
[ Both Blathering ]
[ Both Groaning ]
[ Woman ]I heard 'em yell!
I heard 'em go down!
[ Prince Growling ]
I told you, don't mess with me.
Man, I saved your life.
Are these people crazy or what?
You ask 'em!
Get in there, Daddy!
Get in there and get 'em!
Clear it out!
Make it safe for Mommy.
[ Grunting ]
[ Banging ]
Ow! Damn!
[ Woman ]Little doggy baby.
Someone is in here.
People under the stairs
got the so-called gas man.
Other one must be upstairs.
Princey! Daddy'll get 'em.
That's a big caliber automatic.
You ever see the holes they tear?
We can hide under the bed.
No, I ain't goin' in there, man.
There's somethin'
about that place.
No room. Find your own.
[ Distant Yelping ]
Ehh!
Aah!
[ Man Grunting ]
Aha!
Oh!
Aah! Run, Fool!
Uh!
Whoo. Yee-haw!
Got him!
[ Laughing ][ Whooping ]
Oh, Daddy!
Did you see that?
Yeah!
- He came at me like a bull.
- Just like a bull.
Big one!
Hear what he called me?
He called you a fool.
- He's the fool!
- Only good fool's a dead one.
Yeah!
[ Laughing ]
Ooh, better check upstairs.
Might be a mess.
Oh, no. Don't want a mess.
I better go look.
Might have to mop up a little.
Thought I heard somethin'.
Stay there.
Get back in the cellar,
you little bastard!
You little animal shit!
I'll get the dog up here.
You'll be sorry.
My-- My name is Fool.
What's yours?
Alice.
Don't be scared.
You never seen a brother before?
- Never had a brother.
- No, I mean a black dude.
There's black folks
in this neighborhood.
Neighborhood?
[ Prince Barking ]
A neighborhood.
You know-- outside?
Well, that's outside,
not in here.
So, you get outside, don't you?
- You sayin' never?
- Can't get out. No one ever has.
Well-- Well, I'm gonna get out.
I'm a whole other thing.
People have tried.
Y-- You mean the people
in the cellar?
Mmm, who are they?
Mommy and Daddy  looked a long time
to find the perfect boy child,
but each one they found
turned out bad.
Some saw things
they weren't supposed to.
Others heard too much.
Others talked back.
Daddy cut out the bad parts
and put the boys in the cellar,
one by one.
They get flashlights
and food of some kind.
I suppose they're happy
in their own way.
Yeah, right.
What about you?
How come they haven't
put you in the cellar?
I do not see...
or hear... or speak evil.
It's the only way.
[ Thud ]
[ Wailing, Moaning ]
- What is that?
- What?
- That yellin'. What is that?
- Well, that's Roach.
Roach?
That's who Daddy's hunting.
See, Daddy hates Roach
'cause he got out of the cellar
and into the walls,
and now Daddy can't find him.
[ Wailing Continues ]
[ Yells ]
There must be another way out.
Further into the house--
The only way. Here.
Papa's too big to follow,
and he's afraid of what's in there.
- I don't want in. I want out.
- Sometimes in is out.
[ Roach Wails ]
Forget it.
- [ Roars ]
- [ Roach Cackling ]
I hear ya! I hear ya!
[ Gunshot ]
Aha!
Yes. Aha.
Okay. I'll get in there.
[ Gunshot ]
[ Thud ]
[ Roach Cackling ]
Ah! Yeah? Aah! Hah!
Yeah! Ha, ha!
I'm gonna get ya!
Oh!
[ Gunshot ]
Yes!
[ Cackling Continues ]
[ Grunting ]
I got something for my Princey.
Yes. Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Good appetite.
Healthy Prince,
a secure home.
[ Brakes Screech ]
Stay.
[ Woman On Police Radio ]
We have a registration
that matches...
a description of a van
used in a 2-11 last night.
[ Gunshots Continue ]
[ Echoing, Feedback ]
Daddy, police out back.
Damn!
- [ Yelps ]
- [ Growls ]
Hey, police! Police!
[ Police Radio ]
514 respond, 2-11.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
Police! Police!
Hello. What can I do
for you, gentlemen?
Afternoon, ma'am.
Uh, is this your van?
Uh, goodness, no.
It was just standing here
when we got back from shopping.
You see anybody around
when you pulled in? Trouble?
Well, as a matter of fact, we did
see a couple of men--
one black, one white--
walking away as we approached.
We thought they were
service people of some sort.
- You know they're workin'
on your door, don't ya?
- No harm done.
Ah, we'll check the house.
Just checked it.
Even looked under the beds.
Clean as a whistle.
Well, let's recon the neighborhood.
There's still a chance.
You get a lot
of this sort of thing?
It's as if we're the prisoners,
and the criminals roam free.
I know what you mean.
You're lucky you're all right.
This van was usedin
a liquor-store robbery last night.
Well, goodness.
- Liquor store?
- I'd advise you to stay inside,
keep your doors
locked for a while.
You can count on it.
Hope you catch 'em.
- Catch 'em in hell.
- Oh, my God.
What?
There's not just the two.
There's a boy.
[ Sniffs ]
He's in there right now...
with our little angel.
[ Snarling ]
God, what are they feedin' you?
[ Belches ]
- [ Fool Yelps ]
- [ Prince Whines ]
[ Man ]
What is it, boy?
Huh?
[ Gunshots ]
Uh!
Oww!
Son of a bitch! Oh! Oh!
You come in here,
and I'm gonna kick your ass!
Aah! Come on!
Gonna kill you!
Uh! Aah!
[ Cackling ]
Kill. Git.
Ki-i-ill!
- [ Yelping ]
- [ Snarling ]
Go!
This your place?
[ Yelping ]
Aa-aa-aah!
What hit you?
The damn Bear Trooper.
Prince is after him.
He'll kill him
before he gets to Alice.
Let's do something!
[ Cackling ]
[ Howling ]
Do you hear something?
The boy's gotten to Alice.
- Thanks.
- [ Laughs ]
He doesn't talk much, does he?
H-His tongue's cut out.
Oh, man.
Mommy caught him trying
to call for help one day,
and Daddy had to teach him--
Speak no evil, right?
Your father's one sick mother,
you know that?
Actually, your mother's
one sick mother too.
Shh! [ Whispers ]
You're speaking evil.
They'd kill you if they
heard a word you just said.
Roach-- Roach is my friend.
Roach? I'm Poindexter.
[ Mutters ]
Everybody calls me Fool.
Fool?
We sure got the names, huh?
[ Laughs ]
This Leroy?
You did this?
Why you make these?
To hold the souls of burglars
when they died.
Or salesmen, workmen--
Other people who saw too much.
[ Indistinct Shout ]
Uh!
[ Indistinct Shouts ]
You viper in my bosom!
You little Judas!
- What do I do with him, Mommy?
- It is time to clean house.
Total spring cleaning.
Hey, let's move it!
Oh, you little piece of shit!
No, wait a minute--
Aah! Aah! Aah!
[ Woman ]
I am sick and tired
of your attitude!
You will do your chore now!
Clean it up, for God's sake!
What's a mother to do?
Lazy brat sits
in her room all day...
sewing dolls!
Children misbehaving
in the basement!
And one in the wall,
doing his business
God knows where.
You kids'll be
the death of me!
[ Whispering ]
The death of me.
[ People Chattering, Shouting ]
[ Shouting ]
I keep 'em real hungry.
I ask a simple thing.
Just clean up that
awful man's blood.
And what do you do?
You get it all over your nice, clean dress...
I worked so hard to make!
Now, get in that tub
and scrub yourself!
No!
[ Wailing ]
Don't want to get in, huh?
Well, let me help you!
You're gonna scrub yourself!
You scrub yourself!
It's hot, but the fires
of hell are hotter.
Come on.
No! Don't put me in there!
Don't put-- No!
No!
[ Whimpering ]
No! Don't put me in there!
Where's the Bear Trooper?
Dead meat.
I coulda killed him,
but I'll let the people
under the stairs do it.
Leave me alone!
Get away from me!
[ Moaning ]
[ All Gasping ]
[ Moaning Continues ]
Roach!
It's right there,
Roach.
[ Man ] I told you to keep it
quiet down there.
You're driving me nuts.
Pull it.
Guard 'em, Prince. Guard 'em.
[ Men Gasping ]
Noisy bastards.
If I have to come down there,
you're gonna be sorry.
Roach, you're shot.
We got to get you to a hospital.
[ Barking ]
The coin collection.
Leroy was right.
Thanks, Roach.
[ Whimpering ]
Alice is up there?
Roach!
[ Whispers ]
Roach.
[ Prince Barking, Snarling ]
[ Barking ]
[ Gasps ]
Get out of here!
Go!
[ Man ] What did he do to you?
I told you--
Hear me? Come here.
You answer me!
Did you tell him anything?
If you did,
you know what I'll do.
I killed your skinny friend
in the walls.
Now, what do you think of that?
Oh, and I got him good.
And the black one too.
[ Gasping ]
Shut the fuck up!
[ Shuddering ]
What the hell's wrong with him?
He said he killed you!
He exaggerated!
Come on! Stay.
Keep moving, Alice. He finds us, he gonna
shoot through the walls.
My dress is stuck on something.
Oh, great.
Uh-oh. We got to keep
going, Alice. Come on.
Burn in hell for gettin' free,
and burn in hell
for showin' the way!
Who turned on the heat?
[ Chuckling ]
Burn! Burn!
Burn in hell!
Burn!
Burn in hell.
[ Coughing ]
Alice, he's comin' closer.
We got to get out of here.
[ Coughing ]
Which way?
Only Roach knew the way
through the walls.
So we'll explore.
[ Rifle Cocking ] [ Man ]
Gonna find you!
I gotta sneeze!
Gonna kill ya!
[ Sneezes ]
[ Alice ]
Shh! If he can't hear us,
he can't shoot us.
[ Both Gasp ]
We got to be careful.
Real careful.
- You think you got him?
- We'll soon find out.
Come on, Prince. Come on, boy. Come on.
Kill. Kill. Kill.
[ Snarls ]
Kill. Kill 'em, Prince.
Kill 'em. Kill 'em!
Shh! I think I just
heard something.
- [ Snarling ]
- Oh! Come on!
- [ Fool ]   I'm not runnin' anymore.
- [ Prince Snarling ]
Come on!
[ Chuckling ]
[ Alice ]
Fool?
Alice!
Alice, get back!
[ Alice ] Get away from the wall!
Get away from the wall!
[ Fool Moaning ]
Gotcha.
Gotcha!
Jesus.
I got him! I got him!
I got him, I got him!
I got him. I got him.
I got him, I got him, I got him.
Got him, I got him.
Prove it.
Hey, hey, wait a minute.
It's light up there. Come on.
I know you're in there,
you little piece of shit.
- [ Snarling ]
- [ Woman Gasps ]
[ Body Thuds ]
Oh, shit.
You killed Prince!
[ Man, Woman Arguing ]
[ Fool ]
Look. You can see the lights
of the ghetto from here.
I never thought smog
could smell so good.
- Help!
- Shh!
We might have to climb down.
There's nothing to hold on to.
It's just a straight drop
off the roof.
Wait a minute.
What?
The water in the garden.
Think it's right
under this window.
If we jump off the edge,
we might be able to hit it.
- I don't know how deep it is.
- [ Man Knocking ]  I hear 'em.
Alice, come on.
We got to jump.
- I can't. I'm afraid.
- You upstairs, Alice?
- Alice!
- What's out there?
- [ Grunts ] - [ Gasps ]
- There he is!
Ah!
[ Alice Whimpering ]
What were you doing
with him? Come here.
Alice! Alice!
[ Gasps ]
Oh, no, no, no, no, no!
[ Shouting ]
Damn it.
[ Fool Gasps ]
[ Gun Cocks ]
I'll be back, Alice! Hang on!
- Bastard!
- I'll be back!
Daddy!
Never shoot your gun outside.
- He got away.
- Come back inside.
Damn it.
Bad boy! Go on.
Go straight to your room
and get into your suit.
If these had come
from anybody else,
I'd tan your hide and make you
take 'em straight back.
You know that?
Yes, sir.
Well, figuring
the rarity of these,
you do have enough
to pay your rent for a while.
Say, to the year 2000.
- Hey, and Mama's operation?
- And your mama's operation.
Keep hold of these
till tomorrow.
I'm gonna order
an ambulance for your mama.
Tomorrow we'll take those
to a good coin dealer,
and we'll all be smiling.
Meanwhile, you be careful.
That brother/sister act
you messed with are evil,
plain and simple.
- Wait a minute.
Brother and sister?
- Brother and sister.
Tail end of the craziest family
you ever heard of.
Every generation more insane
than the one before it.
Started out as a family
running a funeral home,
sellin' cheap coffins
for expensive prices.
Then they got their fingers
into real estate.
Started making a lot of money
taking over people's homes.
The more money they got,
the greedier they got.
The greedier they got,
the crazier they got.
All sorts of rumors about
what's gone on in that place.
Never proved it because the police
didn't take it serious.
But believe me, when I was a kid,
none of us ever walked past that house.
You okay, Fool?
I was just telling Mama
that I did something wrong.
Real wrong. And now I gotta do
something right.
I done the tarot cards
on you again.
They come up real scary.
Don't go messin' with them people again.
Somebody has to.
And maybe that means me.
Anyway, I made a promise
to Alice,
and I'm gonna keep it.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Woman ] 14th Precinct.
Hello. Police?
Yes. This is the police.
I'd like to report a case
of child abuse goin' on.
All right.
When did this happen?
Right now.
This real or what?
Bogus.
This place is clean.
People don't even have kids.
Got coffee though.
More coffee?
No, thank you. I've had plenty.
I'm so sorry you all had to
come out at such an hour...
for such a silly thing.
But you know, it's better there are
a few false calls...
if we can prevent just one child
from being abused.
Mm-hmm. Absolutely right.
Cream and sugar?
Nice furniture.
You didn't get that stuff
at Price Club, that's for sure.
No, it's been in the family for years.
Yeah?
It used to be,
the house was used for, uh,
business.
No kiddin'?
Sergeant, I think there's something here
you might want to see.
What?
Take a look.
Thought you said
you had no kids.
Alice left us
a long time ago, Sergeant.
The Lord saw fit
to come and take her.
Never touched the room since.
We're foolish, I suppose, but...
in a sense,
she still lives here.
And always will.
My apologies.
It must be
very painful for you.
I'm sorry about this.
This should have never happened.
No need to apologize.
We want to be helpful.
[ Policeman ] Thanks for the refreshments.
[ Man ] You're welcome.
Good night.
I don't want to see another cop...
or cookie in my life.
I don't know
which one makes me sicker.
May they burn in hell.
Forever and ever in hell.
The shelf worked.
Yep. Always does.
Simple works best.
We got to get
a new dog tomorrow.
A good, big one.
I was worried.
The police left the back door
open for so long.
So?
I couldn't watch it
all the time.
Think any of 'em got out?
Nah.
They were pretty out of it.
What'd you use?
Horse tranquilizers.
[ Man ] Tomorrow I'm gonna look
for the Bear Trooper.
[ Woman ] Where would you look?
The ghetto.
I'll find him.
And I'll kill him.
Night, Mama.
Night, Daddy.
Say your prayers like a good boy?
Oh. I forgot.
[ Woman ]
Now I lay me down to sleep.
[ Man ]
[ Together ] I pray the Lord
my soul to keep.
If I should kill before I wake,
[ Woman ] I pray the Lord
my soul to take.
[ Man ] I pray the Lord
[ Screams ]
You miserable little shit!
Shut up!
[ Screaming ]
Get him!
You hurt my baby!
[ Screaming ]
[ Woman ]
Get him! Get off! Get him!
[ Man, Woman Screaming ]
Get him! He's getting away!
[ Screaming Continues ]
Downstairs door.
[ Woman ]You get him?
He's fast, damn it.
Open the kitchen!
[ Groaning ]
Shit!
What happened?
Did he get out?
Burn in hell.
[ Woman ] What about Alice?
What'll we do with her?
[ Man ] Let her hang up there
all night.
[ Woman ] She's terrified of the attic.
I know.
It serves her right.
Alice.
Fool?
Are you okay?
Alice, can you get
any more of these bricks out?
- I can't. They've got me stuck.
- How?
I'm tied to a bolt
in the chimney.
This one?
Oh, yes.
Hi.
Let's see if we can get
some more of these bricks out.
Shh!
Get down.
Let me down, please.
[ Exhales Forcefully ]
Daddy!
Come down from there
and help me to bed!
Daddy!
I said now!
[ Lock Clicks ]
He's gone.
Fool? Fool?
Meet me at the window.
You know the one.
Okay.
You find him,bring him back to me.
I will.
Take him under the stairs
and do him like the others.
I'll kill him.
- Only it won't be his ears
I cut off.
- His balls!
Here, hold this.
Listen, Alice.
They're not your real parents.
What?
They're not. They're not
even husband and wife.
They stole you, like they did
Roach and all the others.
They're a bunch of
rotten baby snatchers.
You-You're just saying that.
My Grandfather Booker told me,
and he wouldn't lie to me.
What do we do now?
- Feel up to a little jump?
- Problem is,
first thing he did
when you escaped was drain it...
and put broken glass
and rocks in the bottom.
- That's a problem.
- The way we came up before
he's got fixed now.
Wait, Fool! Look!
[ Fool ] This place
is one big bomb.
[ Alice ] He's got 'em
all over the house.
Think you could climb the roof?
What's up there?
The only way out.
[ Woman ]
How dare he come
into our happy home?
He came back to get Alice.
You should have let me kill her.
You stay away from Alice!
She did it with him!
I know it!
Not my little girl!
She's a whore!
[ Clattering ]
What is that?
- [ Shot Fires ]
- [ Alice ]  Oh, God!
It hurts so bad!
[ Laughing ]
[ Shot Fires ]
See him?
I can't see shit.
Let me see the brick.
Hold it. I think
I hear something.
- Bombs away.
- No!
[ Thud ]
[ Groaning ]
- [ Woman ] That little bastard!
- This here's one of your smart bricks.
- You bastard!
- Come on. You can do it.
Just brace yourself
on the sides.
[ Groaning Continues ]
Oh, shit. Hang on.
You're mine now!
[ Screaming ]
Caca!
Okay, hold it here.
Why?
You know where we are?
Uh-uh.
There's the living room.
Get out the back door.
Well, come with me then.
I'm not finished with them yet.
- Fool--
- Go!
I'm goin' to get the shotgun,
set those kids free.
[ Voices Murmuring,
Faint ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Murmuring Continues ]
Food! Food!
Shh!
Hold it right there!
[ Gasping ]
Where is that little bastard?
Tell me!
I-I won't tell you.
We will get him out of our house!
He's filthy.
He's bad. He's awful!
[ Screams ]
Go to hell!
[ Man ]
Mommy! Oh!
[ Woman ]
Eldon! Oh, God.
He's turned my little girl
against me.
I told you. Those two--
Then she can burn
in hell.
Both of them.
She doesn't have a key.
She's still in here.
[ Voices Murmuring, Shouting ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Glass Shattering ]
[ Objects Clattering ]
She's in the cellar.
No way.
Then he is.
You know a prayer?
Say it.
Whoa!
Shoot her if you see her.
[ Man Chuckling ]
Come here!
[ All Shouting ]
- You see your friends?
- [ Flies Buzzing ]
- Get him?
- Oh, yeah.
[ Knocking ]
Shh! It may be
the police again. Hold on.
My name is Ruby Williams,
and I represent the Association
of People Who Have Been...
Unjustly Evicted, Exploited
and Generally Fucked Over.
What?
You and your brother are landlords of
over 50 buildings in this city,
all of which you've allowed to deteriorate
into rat-infested hellholes...
while you guys get rich
charging ridiculous rents.
Then you evict anyone
the minute they can't pay rent,
so you can tear down their home
and build more office buildings.
- Ain't that about right?
- None of your goddamn business!
Kill the little bugger!
Kiss your ass good-bye, boy.
[ People Shouting ]
[ All Shouting ]
- What the hell is going on?
- He's loose again! Damn it.
- [ Knocking ]
- [ Man ] Police! Open up!
- Shh!
- What?
[ Man ] Police! We have
reports of gunfire!
If you do not open this door,
we'll break it down!
Get off my property!
Just wanna finish saying our piece, ma'am.
Not only are you bad landlords,
but 10 times worse,
you've stolen the children
from our community
for your own sick needs.
There is no community here.
All I see are a couple of n--
[ Man ] Hey, Ruby, we're right here.
[ Woman ] You got that right.
Busted your ass, bitch. Yeah.
What are you gonna do?
Shoot us all?
- You'll do.
- [ Crashing ]
[ Ruby ]
Damn. You knocked
that bitch cold!
[ Man ]
Man, look at her. What are they
doin' to her in there?
[ People Shouting ]
Oh, shit.
I know you're in here.
You're not gettin' out.
Nobody gets out.
[ Gun Cocks ]
Nobody.
Fool?
[ Ruby ]
Fool, that you?
[ Shouting ]
Listen, there's a way out
for you guys if you can get past the man.
Huh?
The door to the outside cellar
got left open.
Now you can get outside--
to the sun,
to the birds, to the women.
You want to give me something?
[ Gasping ]
Shh!
Burglar alarm? No problem.
I studied with the best.
I can use these wires
to bridge it.
[ People Shouting ]
No wonder there's no money
in the ghetto.
Fool?
Fool! Fool!
[ Door Shuts, Lock Clicks ]
[ Ruby ]
Uh-oh. Your mama's gone.
Oh, shit. Where did that
crazy heifer go?
You guys see where she went?
Don't let her get away, hear?
- Wait a minute!
Let us help you! - [ Knocking ]
Please, open the door!
We want to help you!
Open the door!
[ Male Computer Voice ]
System remote override.
All doors locked.
[ Woman On Speaker ]
You know I wouldn't let you
get away that easy.
I see you.
And I see you, dearie.
[ Screaming ]
[ Shouting ]
[ Biting ]
You get back in there!
Get back in there!
Don't you touch me!
Don't you touch me! No!
[ Shouting ]
[ Flesh Tearing ]
[ Gasping, Sobbing ]
[ Growls ]
You hurt your mother.
You're not my mother.
Never were.
Then burn in hell!
[ Woman Screaming ]
[ People Shouting ]
Mommy!
[ All Chuckling ]
[ Coins Clattering ]
[ Man ]
Oh, no. No, no. Fool!
[ People Shouting "Fool" ]
[ Coin Clatters ]
[ Clattering Continues ]
I know what you're doing.
You're counting that money.
You're letting it
roll through your fingers.
I've done it myself...
a thousand times.
And I'll do it again.
But you won't!
- Hey.
- [ Gasps ]
You shoot me
and you die, too, man.
And you better believe it.
Don't be crazy, now.
Got enough dynamite back there
to blow you sky-high.
Not the best place to store it,
in my opinion.
But there it was.
Just put the gun down.
Put the gun down.
I don't want to kill you
but I will, 'cause
I don't like you much anyway.
I'm tired of fuckin' around!
So either put the gun down now,
or kiss your ass good-bye, boy.
- [ Shouting ]
- [ Gasps ]
Holy shit!
[ People Cheering ]
[ Cheering Continues ]
[ Groaning ]
All right.
[ All Clamoring ]
Fool?
Fool, you okay?
I feel like a million dollars.
[ People Whistling, Cheering ]
¶ Do the right thing
I'm not talking about
a black or white thing ¶
¶ 'Cause that would cause conflict
and make this thing legit ¶
¶ But your definition
of legit and illegitimate
is confusing ¶
¶ Now the Redhead One has said
to make things clearer ¶
¶ 'Cause in about a year
or two ¶
¶ What you do is take a look
up in the mirror ¶
¶ And what you see
is the image of hate ¶
¶ That you shed upon the others
of sisters and of brothers ¶
¶ Now, in my opinion
you need someone to teach ¶
¶ The whole world is actin'
like a giant out of reach ¶
¶ I asked my man Victor
what he used to do for fun ¶
¶ He said he learned to shoot
a gun before the age of 21 ¶
¶ Crime and abortion, all
kinds of mind distortion ¶
¶ This is very important
but just a little caution ¶
¶ Of what you can do, here's
a clue and it's true, yo ¶
¶ Don't wanna burn a sweater
Make your life better ¶
¶ And do the right thing
¶ Do the right thing
¶ You got to do the right thing ¶
¶ Do the right thing, yeah
¶ Brothers are stealin' and
dealin' and big wheelin' ¶
¶ And to a younger mind
that stuff is appealin' ¶
¶ So what do they do
They gather up a crew ¶
¶ Go out and steal and rob
instead of gettin' a job ¶
¶ Now your mother tried to bring
you up better than that ¶
¶ The same way she loved you
You loved her right back ¶
¶ But now you think you're grown
and you argue a lot ¶
¶ Over money you got from
dealin' stuff on the block ¶
¶ And do the right thing
¶ Do the right thing
¶ You got to do the right thing ¶
¶ Do the right thing, yeah
¶ You're not
the only one in the world
that has problems ¶
¶ Keep your head straight and
you can surely solve 'em ¶
¶ Be a fly guy
and reach sky high ¶
¶ And like the Jeffersons
you get a piece of the pie ¶
¶ I hope you take heed
to the message I brought ¶
¶ In other words
the lesson I taught ¶
¶ The Red'll kick a lyric
but I won't sing ¶
¶ And the F.B.I. crew
wants you and you
to do the right thing ¶
¶ Do the right thing
¶ You got to do the right thing ¶
¶ Do the right thing, yeah
¶ Gonna be counted off as
we go on something like this ¶
¶ One two, three Manhattan, you gotta
do the right thing ¶
¶ Brooklyn
You gotta do the right thing ¶
¶ And the Bronx
¶ Bruise Island
You gotta do the right thing ¶
¶ Long Island
¶ Staten Island
You gotta do the right thing ¶
¶ On the West Coast
¶ Everybody
Everybody in the world
You gotta do the right thing ¶
¶ Do the right thing
¶ You got to do the right thing ¶
¶ You got to do
the right thing ¶
¶ Do the right thing, yeah
¶ The Redhead One sendin' out a message
on a positive note ¶
¶ Try to make you all
see the light ¶
¶ When we supposed to be
in the dark ¶
¶ You know, this is goin' out
to my mother, to my brother ¶
¶ To the rest
of the F.B.I. tribe
you know what I'm sayin' ¶
¶ Everybody else in the world
I just want y'all to do one thing ¶
¶ And that's the right thing ¶
¶ Do the right thing
¶ You got to do
the right thing ¶
¶ Do the right thing
¶ You got to do the right thing ¶
¶ Do the right thing, yeah
¶ The right thing
¶ Do the right thing