(BINGOWINGZ)
Hey, yeah. The 1960's?
Happy times, heavy times.
All right, so you get
your daughter, right?
She might be Catholic,
Jewish, anything.
So you bring her up
in what they call...
the bourgeois,
American-type-society family.
Bring them up so they don't
screw until they get married.
You take them to church
on Sunday.
Teach them all you can
about bringing up a family...
how you should look and act...
then you send them to college.
You bust your hump.
No government subsidy.
Nobody's paying nothing.
You save your money,
or you borrow the money...
you work overtime,
you send her to college.
You want her
to get an education.
The first Easter
she comes home on a vacation...
she says, "Hey, Dad,
I'm living with some guy."
"You're living with some guy?
What do you mean?"
"This is the thing now.
Free love."
We're getting away
from the original point.
What we're trying to find is,
why are these bastards rioting?
Because they did dope.
Listen, you're going
in the wrong direction.
What of it?
What happens is, look,
I'm sending you to school...
I'm breaking my ass to send you
to college, right?
I expect you're going
to learn something.
Why be a janitor?
Learn something.
To justify my investment in you.
But some of these people
revel in the fact...
that their kids are leaders,
are rabble-rousers.
This son of a bitch
just started a riot.
These kids think
they're the first generation...
that ever screwed
before they got married.
We all did,
but we always had one girl.
She screwed...
that girl you took out.
It's better off
these kids don't get married...
because they haven't got
the guts to stick with it.
Hey, you fucking intellectuals
You think
you're so where it's at
Before you fill your minds
with any junk
Better listen to Fritz the Cat
'Cause writers and poets
and artists
It's your duty
to live life to the most
So fly out, brothers,
and check out the world
Give me a ride to the coast
Fritz the Cat
He fought many a good man
Laid many a good woman
Live life to the fullest
Cry out for more
until it bleeds
Help me,
help me help you, mother...
Love me,
I hate you, love me
I kill you, love me
I love you
What a mob in the park today.
God, the place
is crawling with phonies.
Yeah, high school punks.
Those creeps are always here
on weekends, man.
Most of them are total jackoffs.
So many people here
and nobody here.
-Dig that chick, man!
-Over there?
Man, look at that ass on her!
-What a baby carriage.
-So what, man?
If you hadn't showed up so late,
we'd be all right now.
Fritz always does it, man.
Everybody's here with
their guitars already.
Sixteen versions
of "Lemon Tree."
I just want someplace
where I can sleep.
I mean, I can cook.
I can sew and do housework
and things like that.
Get out the guitars.
Come on, get them out.
And one, two, three.
Once I had a little girl
Who was in love with me
Well, well, baby,
I know, I know
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah
Oh, mama, mama,
singing it, ho
Dumb chicks.
-Easily impressed by spades.
-lt's the thing, man.
Look, I'm gonna split.
I'll see you guys later.
Yeah, hang loose, Fritz.
I've read everything
James Baldwin's written.
He has a true sense of
the problems of black people.
I worked for Head Start
for free last summer.
Black kids
are so much groovier.
I went to a couple of
Black Panther meetings.
The time for
non-violent revolution is past.
More power to the people!
I'm taking a course
in African studies at school.
I had no idea you people
were so civilized.
Do you know
that property values...
actually go up when
a black family moves in?
Freud didn't write
for the black man.
Why does a great actor
like James Earl Jones...
always have to play black men?
Don't you hate it when people
say "Colored" or "Negro"...
and not "Black"?
Black is beautiful.
It's so great that black people
wear their hair natural...
not emulating
the image of beauty...
white people inflict upon them.
I had a black girlfriend once
who said that Jewish people...
were the closest
to black people.
I'm Jewish, you know.
I ain't no jive-ass
black nigger, honey.
Who do you think I am?
Geraldine?
Oh, God!
Oh, Jesus!
How awful.
My soul is tormented.
-Gee.
-Oh, no.
I've been up and down the four
corners of this big old world.
I've seen it all!
I've done it all!
-Gee.
-Wow.
I've fought many a good man,
laid many a good woman.
I've had riches and fame
and adventure.
Stood face to face with danger
and death countless times.
Are you somebody famous?
I think I saw you
in a movie once.
Try not to interrupt, huh?
I've tasted life
to the fullest...
and still my soul cries out...
in this hungry, tortured,
wrecked quest, "More!"
-Look at the good side of life.
-Things aren't all bad.
Gee, he's handsome.
You. You can help me.
You must save me.
By so doing, you, too,
will be saved.
I'd like to, but what can I do?
Lovely set of eyes there.
Little sweet one
with your heart of gold...
I know of a place
where we can be alone...
to join our souls
in sacred truth.
I want to be in on this thing.
What about my soul,
you fink?
Four in bed...that's a kick
I haven't tried yet.
What?
Yes. Together
we shall all learn...
the real existential essence
of the life force.
"Existential."
I heard that word once.
-What's it mean?
-"Cool," stupid.
You are a true genius, Fritz.
Wild, this is wild.
Oh, honey, I could go...
I'll get it. God damn it.
What's happening, man?
Fritz the Cat has become
the stud of the year.
We're having a session here now,
so I don't know.
Anybody using that room?
That's the john,
I mean...
if you're really
strung out, man.
We'll take it.
This way, group.
Come along, now,
step lively.
Watch your step.
That's a girl.
Rub-a-dub-a-dub.
OK.
A new world of experience
awaits us, my loves.
This bathtub
is now transformed...
into a space capsule
of truth and love.
Wow! This is wild!
Only in naked closeness
can we all know each other.
Yes! Right!
Very good, Winston, darling.
"Naked closeness," true.
You are a perceptive girl.
Closeness,
we must all get very close...
as close as possible,
as a matter of fact.
That's right.
Let's all get close together.
Oh, boy.
Closeness and fulfillment
of our hidden desires...
through which
we reach the truth.
Fulfillment is important.
Don't you think so, Winston?
Ooh, yes.
Very important.
Now I'm getting to the truth,
I think, yes.
It's all very clear now.
OK, Winston.
Here come the truth.
You got the word.
Oh, Fritzy.
You got such
an existential little body.
Jeez. Wow.
Oh, shit!
Maybe we better go, huh?
No! Not at all!
You get down over here.
And you down like that.
Right under here.
Watch the foot.
Ready, everyone.
Here we go.
Hey, Ralph,
I think this is the place...
we got the report on
with these kids upstairs...
doing the shit and smoking,
I think.
Tell me what to do.
I never went in before.
Because you're a rookie
and this is your first beat...
you just follow me.
We walk up the steps.
We don't make any noise.
You follow me slowly, got that?
I do. Like Dick Tracy.
No, it's like
Terry and the Pirates.
Dick Tracy's old hat.
Now, let's go inside.
Wait. Could I get
to search the girls?
Yeah.
I've done enough of that.
Here we go.
And watch me,
'cause I'm a natural in action.
Up the steps.
Hey, man.
What the hell's
going on in here?
For Christ's sake,
what do you want?
For Christ's sake...
Fritz is having his own
private little orgy.
Move over, man.
Will you get out of here?
We're seeking the truth!
It's my bathtub, man.
Don't pay attention
to that Fritz.
He got a Jesus complex.
Oh, I know it.
Have some joy puff,
sweet little bird.
Hello, New York.
Heard you're having
a hash session here.
Wow, this is where it's at.
Yes, man, come join us.
Good stuff and lots of it, man.
Only close the door.
We're modest.
Har har har.
The guy's a riot.
Oh, God, I'm there.
You really there?
How is it?
-lt's...
-How is it?
That's funny.
I'm not there anymore.
Oh, shit.
I'm a writer.
Let's talk about it.
Ever made it
with an aardvark before?
It's a rare opportunity.
We're scarce.
Really?
I can't tell
if I'm there or not.
How do you tell?
You'll know when you are.
Oh, balls.
lt doesn't work for me.
I'm a failure
as a pot smoker.
Don't be sad.
Someday you'll make it.
Really.
Shh. I think we're here.
Do you hear anything, Ralph?
It sounds like a bunch
of degenerates in there.
Now, listen, Ralph,
you got the deeper voice.
And I want you to yell,
"Open the fucking door."
Say the word "Fucking" because
that makes you sound tough.
When I say three,
you yell, "Open..."
I'm even gonna ad-lib.
No ad-libbing, Ralph.
Let me call them pre-verts.
What's a pre-vert?
A pre-vert is a degenerate,
didn't you know that?
A pre-vert's a degenerate?
Didn't you have no bringing up?
I got bar-mitzvahed.
You ain't supposed
to laugh, Ralph!
This is a serious job
and we're getting paid for it.
Cut the fucking shit out.
Let's go.
All right.
Open up in there!
It's the law! Hippie bastards!
Good, Ralph, do it again.
What the fuck's your problem?
Cut it out!
I won't laugh!
Open the door, you pre-verts!
Open up!
Law and order's here!
-Open up!
-All right in there!
Open up! Here we are!
Wow! I can do it!
Oh, baby, do I feel high!
I'm flying!
What a wonderful, wiggly world!
We're outside,
but we'll get in!
-Law and order's here!
-Open up!
All right in there!
Your fucking bath party's over!
-Over here!
-The cops!
Right in the mouth!
Yeah! I love it!
Take that!
Hey, you!
Get your hands out of my thing!
-Here we are!
-Where the fuck are you?
Over there! ln the head!
Get your hands
off of my dick!
In the head!
I love it! I love it!
Ralph, where are you?
Ralph, help! Gotcha!
Now I gotcha!
Here, take that!
That's my...
Gotcha! ln the heart!
In the head!
Over there!
Watch that thing!
Where's the cat?
Wow.
Hey, look at
this big fucking gun.
I killed the john!
Kill! Destroy!
Can you give him your glasses?
Because I can't.
I have to look.
-You can't see?
-l'll give them back.
A little bit...
Oh, boy, this is good for me.
Can you dig it in your eyes?
You're younger than me.
Forty-five, forty-eight.
I'm sixty-seven.
I wish I knew.
I would give you glasses.
I'd take another pair
from the house.
I didn't think
I would need the glasses.
I'm not so young no more,
remember.
You don't see nothing?
I'm older than you are,
I'll see.
I'll mention that I see.
You're doing fine.
You know something?
That you don't have to
look at the book, right?
So say it. Say it.
All right.
All right. Good.
-Good.
-Beautiful.
Thank you, thank you.
Just normal.
You know, nice and quiet.
Now, wait a minute.
Don't rush.
Mother of God,
I'm a fucking fugitive.
This is the place!
I saw him come in here!
Oh, my God, it's a synagogue.
What kind of a place is this?
A church?
Listen, I can hear them.
Don't sound like English.
Are they Puerto Ricans?
Ralph,
you're trying my patience.
You go down that aisle,
I'll go down this aisle.
It's about time
you said something bright.
Ralph, please be quiet.
It's my people.
-Excuse me, Rabbi.
-They all got long hair.
-Sorry, Rabbi.
-They all got long clothes.
-Excuse me.
-Must be a hippie church.
Hi, Rabbi.
Did you see him?
God.
Ralph,
would you please shut up?
I ain't talking loud.
Excuse me, Rabbi.
Hi, Ma.
Uncle Ben, how are you?
I'm catching a criminal.
Excuse me, Rabb...
It's you.
Did you find him?
No, he was over there, but...
-But I was just telling you...
-Cut it out!
But I was just...
I ain't talking loud!
What are you doing?
What's going on here?
You saved my life!
We interrupt
the lsraeli-Arab war...
for this special announcement.
The president,
after conferring...
with the lsraeli
prime minister Golda Meir...
has agreed to send more arms
and equipment to lsrael...
based on the return of
New York City and Los Angeles...
to the United States.
Mazel tov! Mazel tov!
Stop, you motherfucking cat!
Stop in the name of the law!
Stop!
Stupid, Ralph,
you're not supposed to dance.
But I didn't want
to break the circle!
-You're not supposed to dance.
-l got musical feet.
You dumb rookie.
Dumb rookie!
You dumb rookie!
You're not supposed
to dance, Ralph...
'cause you're not Jewish!
I had a great thing going till
the frigging fuzz showed up.
I wish that skinny broad
didn't turn on the shower, too.
I think I'm getting a cold.
Hello, men. Everybody studying
for their goddamn exams?
Hey, Buzz, how'd it go
with that Dee-Dee chick?
She's got some bod,
you have to admit.
Charlene isn't bad,
either, though, right?
Like wow!
Hines!
You swine, old buddy pig!
You groove behind Alvina,
get some kicks tonight?
Bastards.
You'd think the goddamn exams...
was the be-all and end-all
of existence...
cosmic life force
or something.
You'd think they were
the frigging fugitives.
Can't even get in
a few decent words to a guy.
Bastards.
What a bore,
they just sit there...
and take bennies
and stay up all night...
with their face stuck
in a bunch of books...
and their thumb up their ass.
Yes, yes,
I remember the time...
when it was all very inspiring
and enlightening...
all this history and literature
and sociology shit.
You think learning
is a really big thing...
and you become
this big fucking intellectual...
and sit around trying
to out-intellectual...
all the other big
fucking intellectuals.
You spend years and years...
with your nose buried
in these goddamn tomes...
while the world
is passing you by.
All the stuff to see...
and all the kicks...
and all the girls
are out there.
And me, a writer!
And a poet who should be
having adventures...
and experiencing
all the diversities...
and paradoxes
and ironies of life...
and passing over
all the roads of the world!
And digging all the cities
and towns and rivers...
and the oceans and...
making all of them chicks.
Oh, God.
As a writer and a poet...
it is my duty to get out there
and dig the world...
to swim in
the whole frigging scene...
while there is
still time, man.
My farting around days
are over, baby.
From this day on, I shall live
every day as if it was my last.
I must do it!
No more of the dreary,
boring classes...
dismal lectures,
sitting around bullshitting..
with pretentious
fat-ass hippies.
No more of the books...
the spoutings of
a bunch of old farts...
who think they know
the whole goddamn score.
Oh, my God, what have I done?
I set all my notes
and books on fire...
and now I can't study
for my exams.
I'll flunk out,
and my folks will be pissed off.
I'll get a blanket.
The blanket's on fire.
We better call
the fire department.
Bo Diddley buy his baby
a diamond ring
If that diamond ring
don't shine
He gonna take it
to a private eye
If that private eye
can't see
He better not take
that ring from me
Bo Diddley caught him
a nanny goat
To make his pretty baby
a Sunday coat
Bo Diddley caught him
a bear cat
To make his pretty baby
a Sunday hat
Maybe someday
You will fall in love
As I fell in love with you
Baby
The one you love
Just keep falling in love
with you
Then when
You all alone
You know it'd be best, baby
You can sing like that.
Little coquette, I love you
Sing, 'cause I want to...
if I get tired, I quit.
But you don't want to sing.
I want to sing, man.
I'm good.
You sing as good as you want.
If I get tired, I quit.
I went to school in Oakland...
and I had quite a few white-type
of school kids with me.
I'm forty-nine.
At that time, I had white kids
going to school with me.
I would have peanut butter.
I don't want it...
but I ate so much when
my mother gave it to me.
With apple butter.
I got two cans of it now.
That I don't eat because...
whitey was eating
ham sandwiches...
and I was eating
peanut butter sandwiches.
Sandwiches!
I got to get out of this town
for some Southern times.
Let me out of here.
That's right.
Suck! The bus only cost
$17 to New York.
I say, "l ain't made
$17 in two weeks."
Got air to live.
Riding a ship
coming out of Pearl Harbor.
And all my white friends...
then we drank water
out of the ditches.
If I had a K-ration,
I gave them some of it.
And...
I would ride this bus.
I couldn't sit with my friend
on this bus at Houston, Texas.
I had to ride
at the back end of this bus.
I'm about to get hot now.
As a matter of fact...
you couldn't even go no place
down South riding a bus.
Couldn't even get a soda...
walk in there
and get you a sandwich.
I don't give a damn
about who's racist.
I just want equality.
Be equal with the next guy,
because I'm paying my taxes.
That's a different thing now.
I'm a working man,
and I'm paying my taxes.
The money is what's happening.
See what I mean?
It all counts...
when is what's happening.
I'm talking about...
If you want
to be revolutionary...
you get some bread first,
and then you can talk trash.
Whitey blind us with religion.
If you fight
violence with violence...
like the late Malcolm did,
you'll get some results.
Right.
Because before
this rioting and shit...
you didn't have
no Head Start programs for kids.
You didn't have shit!
Really.
You didn't have
a goddamn thing.
Got you down in Harlem
selling horsemeat.
You know,
if one of them motherfuckers...
down and out selling
horsemeat, they dead.
Another civil war.
Civil war.
And I'm gonna be
standing back...
"Get 'em, baby!"
Hey, man, you in a bag?
Yeah, that's it.
I'm in a bag.
Just don't lose
your coolness, cat...
I mean,
don't lose your coolness.
Easy for you to talk.
You're a crow.
I wish I was a crow.
If I was a crow,
I'd fly away, man.
I'd fly away from
this miserable town for good.
You think being a crow
is a big motherfucking ball?
All you cats the same, man.
You don't know where it is.
There's nobody to tell you
where it's at.
And you come up here,
try to find out where it's at...
but you got to be up here, man,
to find out what's happening.
I know it isn't a ball, man.
I studied the race problems.
I know.
You don't know nothing
about the race problem.
Got to be a crow to know
You know what I mean?
Do you dig where I'm at?
You know what I'm talking about?
Man, this thing affects me
very deeply, fella.
As a cat, I have
a considerable guilt complex...
because my kind have always
brought suffering on your kind.
Yes, indeed, my soul
is tortured and tormented...
by this racial crisis.
No shit?
I kid you not, man.
Sometimes I really get
hung up about it.
You know, uptight.
-Strung out.
-ln a bag?
Yeah, in a bag!
I'm gonna buy you a drink, cat.
Just 'cause I think
you got coolness.
Great.
Hey, boy, can I have a drink?
Oh, man!
Hey, Duke!
They's blowing pot like mad
up in Mildred's pad!
I'm on my way, man.
Hey, cat, how would you
like to bug out now?
By God, man!
I'm gonna bug out!
Did he say bug out, baby?
Go ahead, baby, bug out.
Ain't no bug out.
-What kind of shit is that?
-lt's a bug out to him.
-lt's some kind of dance.
-Let's split.
Anybody looking our way?
Some stud
gone and left his keys.
What are you doing?
You stealing that car?
Shove over, Jack!
Let me drive this goddamn thing.
Move it out!
Hey, man,
you cats can't drive.
You don't know nothing
about nothing.
Can't you see that car go by?
Cool it, will you?
I drive like a crow.
-Man, look, slow down!
-l see the light.
Man, you'll get killed up here!
Bullshit, Ralph!
Would you please shut up?
It's bad enough
we got transferred up here...
without you bullshitting
all night.
Now, I gotta cover my beat...
and I'll meet you
back here in an hour.
One hour, Ralph.
And, Ralph...
please, be careful.
Yeah, but Harlem?
Come on, slow the car down!
Look out, man!
I ain't ready to die yet!
Harlem?
I know what I'm doing.
The only faces...
you can see in a crowd
up here is ours.
The way they look,
all you can see is their eyes.
I don't like it here.
I see the fucking fuzz.
Cool it, just cool it.
Right through the head
I'm gonna get you!
Throw that pig out!
Look out!
Cool it, man, will you?
I know what I'm doing.
Like hell you do.
Duke, you saved my life, man!
Shit!
Yesterdays
Days I knew as happy sweet
Sequestered days
Olden days
Golden days
Days of mad romance
And love
Then gay youth was mine
And truth was mine
Joyous free and flaming life
Them-sooth was mine
Sad am l
Glad am l
For today
I'm dreaming of
Yesterdays
That you, Sonny?
It's me, baby.
-How's the crowd tonight?
-Not bad.
We're pushing enough grass
to make our money.
Just enough.
But it sure ain't like
the good old days in Harlem...
when white money was boss...
and them fine, white cats
came up to Harlem...
spreading it all around
Big Bertha.
Oh, child.
That was before
all those peace marches...
sit-ins, riots, and 'dos.
Ain't nothing wrong
with no peace marches.
It's me, baby.
Who's that joker?
Friend of mine.
Cat, you ever been high on pot?
Are you kidding me, man?
Grass?
Who doesn't, you know?
What do you think,
I'm some kind of a hick?
Let's get that cat going on pot!
Take one.
That's what
I'm talking about, baby.
Nothing wrong, take two.
Come on, be a club member.
That's it!
Take three! Take four!
Five, six, seven!
That's it, baby!
He ain't losing now,
no, indeed.
Joint, Hilly! A joint!
Stay loose!
Fritz, come on, now, stop!
Yo, Fritz!
Fritz, come on, now,
stop it!
No, don't stop! Oh, yeah!
Oh, no, Fritz! Come on!
Hey, toro!
Hully gully cat!
Climb, sugar!
Right there! No, Fritz!
Come on, Fritz!
Aw, man, yeah!
Will you look at that?
You ain't black enough, hon.
That old black magic got me!
Oh, Fritz! That's right!
Right there, honey!
Wow, wow, wow!
Pump that thing!
Suddenly it's all very clear!
I must tell the people
about the revolution!
Revolt! Revolt!
Damn you! What the hell
you jabbering about now?
Revolt!
Revolt! Revolt!
Revolt,
you thick-skulled idiots!
You have carried heavy burdens
for the bosses!
You have sweat your lives away
The bosses!
They ride around in limousines!
Get the fuck off my car!
Bosses...they're eating
strawberries and cream !
That's funny!
Cats are real boss!
All right,
what's going on here?
Break it up!
Cool it, officer.
He's just blowing hot air.
No one's paying no mind.
Come the revolution,
there'll be no more limousines!
no more strawberries and cream !
Hey, Ralph, you know how
these dumb kids are.
They don't know what they doing.
Fucking "A" right.
There he is!
He's the one who keeps
the bosses in power!
He's the one
who's holding you down!
-Who, me?
-You!
-Not me. You.
-No, you!
-Me?!
-Not me!
You!
-Fuck you!
-You first!
The spiked Buddha Capitalism !
The iron thumb on the heads
of the proletariat!
They're gonna kill us.
Would you like to see
a picture of my kids?
Come on, man!
You'll get killed up here!
Get them, get them !
Kill them !
We shall overcome!
Group Commander to Formation B.
Don't give them
a chance to scatter.
Attack all congested areas.
I've got to find him.
Where could he be?
This is the alley behind
that place he was standing at.
It gives me the creeps.
Good evening, madam.
Oh, Fritz!
Thank God I found you.
Join me, Winston, my love.
It's not very pretty looking,
but it's cozy as a bitch.
Fritz, come out of there,
will you please?
The hell! With the fuzz
combing the city for me?
Has my picture
appeared on TV yet?
Have they broadcast an alarm?
Offered a reward for information
leading to my arrest?
Don't be so melodramatic.
You and your illusions
of grandeur.
I'm not getting in that filthy,
grimy garbage can with you.
Go fuck yourself.
You're such a child.
Such a self-centered,
egotistical child.
This is disgusting.
If you're gonna talk about
my garbage can that way...
just get the hell out.
Fritz, are you still going
to bug out or not?
Are you kidding, toots?
I got no choice at this point.
Listen to me, will you?
I've got a car and some money.
I can get
all the things we need...
and we can leave right away.
We can go out to the coast.
I'll get a good job
as a private secretary...
and you can work
on your poetry and all.
We can get married and rent
a nice little pad in Frisco...
and dig the scene out there.
It's supposed
to be a great town.
Frisco. Yeah, OK.
She makes men into boys
She makes giants into men
She'll have you feeling guilty
Before you can count to ten
Poor Winston
Sharp mind and a body to match
Fine fancy karma,
able, too, at that
Who is the girl
in the fiberglass shorts?
Well, it's got to be
Winston Schwartz
You can't outtalk her
'Cause she talks too fast
You can't outthink her,
she's a New York flash
She makes love to you
and tell you you're in love
You make love to her
She says you don't know
how to do it
Poor Winston
at last we're zooming down
that old lonesome highway.
It's wild.
Yeah. Marvelous.
Marvelous, my ass!
It's exalting. Elating.
The cool night wind
blowing past the window. Man!
I'm hungry.
Let's stop someplace.
The hell with stopping.
I just want to feel
those miles flying by.
I'm hungry!
Let's dig one of those
little greasy truck stops.
I'd like to talk with
those truck drivers, you know?
Hear what they got to say
about life on the road.
I bet they got
wild stories of the road.
Drivers, trucks, hijackers!
Fights! Let's do it.
Here's a good place.
I'll have your deluxe steak
with salad and coffee. Black.
All right.
What would you like, sir?
That was really a fine steak.
You can always depend
upon Howard Johnson's.
Let's get back on the road.
Goddamn.
Fritz! Wake up!
Huh? What?
The car is broken down...
and I can't get
the damned thing...
What? Where are we?
Fuck a duck.
We're out in the middle
of the frigging desert.
Jesus, it's great!
Exactly. You've been
sound asleep for two days.
-What?
-Two days.
You must've been dragged out
after your big binge.
Shit. I guess I was.
All that drinking and
blowing pot and screwing, man.
Man, I get horny
just thinking about it.
Like, wow!
Start thinking about
fixing this car, Fritz...
or we'll be sitting
here forever.
Look, is something
bugging you, pal?
The car won't go!
Well, let's have a look.
I knew that all the time.
The engine's not up here.
It's in the back.
Let's just check it out.
What's wrong?
Let me see, I'll just...
If I move that...no...
What's wrong, Fritz?
It's all very complicated,
Winston.
I couldn't begin
to explain it.
I think the piston rod's
stuck in the drive shaft.
Either that,
or the carburetor is rusted out.
Oh, good God.
Here comes a pickup truck.
Maybe he'll give us a push
to the next gas station.
What's the trouble, buddy?
Our car is busted down.
Could you give us a push
to the next gas station?
Let me look at it.
One thing I'm good at
is fixing things.
Shut up!
Please shut up, chickens!
Please shut up!
I mean, shut up!
One thing I'm good at...
is fixing things.
Dumb chickens.
Let me see now.
Ain't nothing the matter
with this car here.
Buddy, ain't you got
any sense at all?
You just let
your car run out of gas.
I swear, these motherfucking
hippies from New York.
There's a gas station
a couple of miles back.
I'm going this way.
You ought to stop for gas
once in a while, you stupid...
Gotta keep your engine fed.
Wise up, buddy.
Well, how do you like that?
New York hippies
come down here...
and they think they can...
I never, honest and true.
You think a thing
like that happens...
Son of a bitch.
You're so clever.
So clever.
Big mechanical genius.
Here's a bucket, smart guy.
Good luck.
Hey, this is for shit!
You made a big bourgeois deal
out of everything...
and ruined it completely.
I was gonna bug out and be free
from all this bullshit...
and roam around
and dig everything...
and really have a good time.
Your naivete is astounding.
You'd be completely lost
without me, Fritz...
and you know it.
You're a motherfucking bitch.
I see the hard facts of life.
I am realistic,
something you're incapable of.
You'd be better off with
one of those stupid morons...
like Charlene, who you could
sleep with and throw away.
You can't cope
with a mature woman.
You haven't the faintest idea
how lucky you are...
that an intelligent woman...
loves you and wants to
give you something of value...
something that will inflame
your creative potential!
Now, get going and hurry up!
We'll see who gets lost
without whom.
Fritz the Cat
I'm the envy of
each and every guy in town
She looks so sharp,
and the girl does, too
And everybody knows
what I'm gonna do
Gonna take a ride on my bike
Gonna take it
and drive all night
Tell my Chevy to take a hike
Take another ride on my bike
Blue, I'm crazy about you.
Penniless. A regular bum.
A hobo with no money
and no place to go.
Hey, you old scroungy
old alley cat.
Get out of them garbage cans.
You talking to me, Jack?
What the hell
you doing there, anyway?
Man, here we are on the brink
of the apocalypse...
the eve of destruction,
so to speak...
and I can't think
of anything to do.
Offhand, son,
I'd say you have got a problem.
But at least you're honest.
The revolution
can use a man like you.
Hop on.
-Hello there.
-Hi.
-How are you?
-High.
I'll introduce you to the guys
at the cell meeting.
Blue!
Glad you could make it, man.
Howdy, John. I brought along
an old buddy of mine.
He's a bright lad
but bored with life.
Fritz...
this here is John...
former biker
and small-time hood...
turned fighter for the cause.
That cat was a beautiful head.
Glad to meet you, man.
Another castout
for the bourgeois view.
From the mold
of bankrupt sedentary.
What's the state of
his political consciousness?
Practically nil, I'm afraid.
Our shipment came in today.
Thirty-two survivors.
Go around.
Hey, chief.
Getting ready for a little
action planned for tonight.
We're gonna paralyze
the whole fucking city.
It's going to be great, man.
The shit is really
gonna come down tonight.
We've got everything we need...
for three synchronized
sabotage actions.
The city will be ours.
The machinery
of the establishment...
will be in ruins by morning.
The government will fall
without firing one goddamn shot.
The new mayor will resign...
and we'll move in
and set up a tribunal.
It's curtains.
Blue, honey,
talk to me a minute.
Don't bother me.
I want to talk to you, honey.
Let's go.
Leave me the hell alone.
We'll go and get some chinks.
I'm so hungry.
I ain't hungry.
Don't turn off on me.
Besides...
I don't need that garbage.
Every time you're with
your friends you don't pay...
You son of a bitch!
That hurt me, god damn it!
What do you think I am,
a boxing ball?
A punching bag!
Hit her! Hit her!
You know what you guys are?
You're a bunch of closet fags.
Shut up!
And when I leave this place...
you'll get together
and screw one another.
That's nice.
That is nice.
See, she loves it.
I love it, too.
We've got a lot
of lousy time to kill.
I think I'm gonna ride
that goddamn horse.
Then go on, have a go.
You'll love it.
Let me ride
that goddamn horse.
Get on with it.
You know what you are?
You're a bunch
of fucking Nazi fags!
Guys, that's uncool.
Don't do that.
Listen, you son of a bitch.
You lousy...
Cut it out.
You're hurting her!
You maniacs!
What are you doing to her?
Go ahead and hit me!
My God, my God!
I can't take it anymore!
This isn't working out, Blue.
Our relationship stinks.
Come on, Harriet.
Let's go inside. lt's cold.
I have to go to bed by day.
Come on inside, baby.
You'll get hurt out here.
Listen, I tried
to stop them, but l...
Come on, Fritz!
Wait a minute, huh?
John says
this night will mean...
a great leap forward
for America's social evolution.
I dig it.
We're gonna blow up
the power plant.
This will keep you warm.
I gotta go.
Hey, baby.
We all had a good time
and got our rocks off.
Now we must devote ourselves
to the great task before us.
What'd you have
to hit her so hard for?
She loved it.
Me and you have been assigned
to blow up the power plant.
That's all I care about.
The revolution.
You're full of shit!
All you care about...
is a reason to hurt,
to destroy, to blow up.
You don't know what
a real revolution is.
None of you sons of bitches do.
Harriet, well, she's good.
She's real. She loves.
She loves.
And when you get
right down to it...
that's where it's really at.
The love you give is equal
to the love you get.
Well, fuck it.
I ain't doing it.
So long, Fritz.
I ain't planting this bomb
for you schmucks.
Far out.
And though after my skin worms
destroy this body...
yet in my flesh
shall I see God...
whom I shall see
for myself.
You gotta
let us see our Fritz!
Where is he?
What have you done with him?
You can't go in there.
I'm sorry, girls.
He's under house arrest.
Let us see him ! Please!
-No one gets in.
-He's hurt.
Lord Jesus...
and shalt believe
in thine heart...
that God hath raised Him
from the dead.
I reckon he needed her.
He must be through.
Finished.
For with the heart...
man believeth
unto righteousness...
and with the mouth...
confession
is made unto salvation.
He that covereth his sins
shall not prosper...
but whoso confesseth
and forsaketh them...
shall have mercy.
Fritz, we're so sorry, baby.
He's trying to say something.
I've been up and down...
the four corners...
of this big old world.
I've...seen it all...
and I've done it all.
I've fought many a good man...
and I've laid many a good woman.
And...
if there's one thing
I've learned...
it's...it's...
you get over here...
and you get
down there like that...
Poor cat.
He was a...
he was a tough kid
at that, wasn't he?
Down the lane
They're strolling
Two by two
Holding hands
They smile like we used to do
Here with their one and only
I'd forgotten I was lonely
Oh, how I wish
That here were there with you
All the days of sadness
They seem so needless now
Yes, it's taken me
This long, long time
To see
It's clear
And my dreams
Keep drifting back to me
And our strolls
Beneath these same stars above
And when the leaves
Are falling
My heart will be recalling
You're the only girl
I ever really loved
THAT's ALL FOLK's...