Oh, the Full Moon Scimitar...
The full moon, the smooth scimitar
the moon would become crescent
the scimitar would face many challenges
The full moon, the smooth scimitar
the moon knows my heart's desire
The scimitar would join two loving hearts
Tears drop as the wind laments
Success draws lovers apart
Love will soon be forgotten;
the wife abandoned!
The full moon, the smooth scimitar
the moon comes full circle,
gone is enmity & hatred
The scimitar dispels evil...
Excellent
You're too kind
Almost half of the great martial artists
are defeated by him
Guess who he would challenge next
I hear it would be
the best fighter of the Wu Dang
called Liu Ruo Song
"Zhang Song Villa"
Who is Ding Peng?
Ding Peng
He is merely a security chief's son
No one knows where he has learnt
the deadly technique called Shooting Star
He has defeated Sung Yang Swordsman,
head of the Iron Sword Clan
and Bao Ding Swordsman
in the last 6 months
Of late I have heard that he is the
most popular hero
in the martial arts world
I wonder what he wants with me
It's obvious
You are the chief of Wu Dang
If he defeats you
he'll top the martial arts world
He seeks to defeat me? Where is he?
Xiang Si Forest
Help...
What is it?
Save me
She's there, get her
What are you doing?
What do you think?
To get our woman of course
No, please, they are robbers
They robbed me and want to rape me
Fear not, as long as I am here
nobody dares touch you
Such insolence
Let's go
Who are you?
You want to know who I am
I too am eager to know who you are
Alright then
Take the gold hairpin to the Lee residence
and you will know
Please follow me, sir
Please wait here
Do you know who I am?
No
What? It's you
Yes, it's me
Please come in
Please
Why have you asked me to come here?
To repay you for saving my life
but I was worried you might not come
that's why I did this
Please...
Master Ding, if someone saves your life
what would you do to thank him?
What do you suggest?
There is only one way
in such a case
I'll give myself to him
Where's my sword manual?
"Zhang Song Villa"
Please
Master Ding, you really are a young hero
You flatter me
There are heroes from every clan
gathered here
If you win this fight
your name will rank supreme
Please show me some mercy then
I have heard your famous technique
is the Shooting Star
But how come you haven't
used it yet?!
That's because
I haven't fathomed your strength
Besides, I don't want to defeat you yet
Shooting Star...
So deadly...
Master Ding
Was that the Shooting Star?
When have you seen it?
Otherwise you couldn't have
thwarted my attack
Who taught you this technique?
My dad
Where's your dad?
He has passed away
That's strange
Masters, hero Ding says
he inherited the Shooting Star
from his family
However it greatly ensembles the
technique I invented, as documented in the
...Qing Song Sword Manual
Do you have the manual?
Of course
My father stumbled onto this by chance
and he gave it to me when he died
but I lost it along the way
Really?
Liu Fu, ask madam to take out my manual
Madam, please
What? Your wife?
Dear, the manual
Thank you
Is this the technique?
That's it
That's right then
Now the matter is clear
This page was lost from the manual
ten years ago
and we only found it recently
Master Ding's father
must have stolen my manual
Later he'd have practised in secret
and passed it on to his son
No, my father didn't steal it from you
She stole it from me
What are you doing?
Hero Ding you must be mistaken
We haven't even met
how could I have stolen from you?
You...
If I messed with you
I would be promiscuous
and you would be guilty of fornication
Right
What? What would you say...
Master Ding, I thought
you were a rising star
But you are merely the son of a thief
Dad, on your deathbed
you asked me to glorify your name
such that people would know
our Ding family has a remarkable son
But I am useless
What is this place?
Not bad if I could die here
Why would you want to die?
Who are you?
July the fifteenth is a day of the ghosts
I have come from hell
What? You're a ghost?
Fox ghost
Fox ghost?
What place is this?
This is where man and God meet
God will turn into a human here
and for a mortal, the other way around
What are you laughing at?
Because I have come to the right place
I want to be a ghost
What? Why do you want to die
at such young age?
Why should I tell you?
What's your name?
Why do you want to know?
When you die and become a ghost
we might see each other often
so that's why I want to know your name
So tell me your name first
I am Qing Qing
Qing Qing
I am Ding Peng
Alright, return the sword to me and leave
Why do you want me to go?
A dying person would not look good
Why are you still looking at me?
I haven't seen anyone die
would you let me?
What's there to look at?
I know a kind of death
that's interesting to watch
There is a flower
called the Oblivion in here
When one eats it
the person's all cares
will sink into oblivion
and die slowly
This is an interesting way to die
Who are you? Why do you want to kill me?
Who wants to kill me?
Only two people are
eligible to be killed by me
Who?
One is her
Is that a scimitar in your floral basket?
How did you know that?
So this is the scimitar
I've searched it for twenty years
at last I've found it
Kid, you want to die
I am really... dying
No, that fellow's Deadly Palm
only hit you unconscious
Grand dad has cleared your pressure points
so you should be okay now
What is this place?
A place where nobody would come
a ghostly place
What?
No human comes here
this place is separated
from the secular world
Anyone coming here
can never return to the living world
They are not human
they are like me, a fox
You seem to regret it
No, I wanted to die
why would I regret?
Nonetheless
let him recuperate here
You are awake
This is a beautiful place, you live here?
No
this place was originally my aunt's
Who is she?
Look
Listening to the Spring rain
in a small attic all night
It's said that when my aunt was young
she went to the human world
with the scimitar
and fell in love with a great kung fu hero
But being from different worlds
they had to part
On the night they separated
they sat in the rain till dawn
While parting, the young hero used
his inner powers and wrote on the scimitar
these characters
And hence when the aunt returned
she wrote these
words everywhere
Then what happened?
Then she waited here
hoping to see him once
She eventually died last year
The hero never came?
Didn’t my grand dad say so that
this place is totally detached
from the human world
why would any person come here?
One day when you are gone
I don't think even you'd ever return
Would you?
No, I wouldn't
but I wouldn't leave here
Is it love? Or could it be termed as fate?
A human and a fox shielded from the world
Every man has passions and desires
Ding Peng is a man after all
One day he would go back
No, he won't
Your parents died early
and you're all I've got
I can't keep you with me
the rest of your life
forget it, nobody knows
what the future will bring
If what I guess is right
it would be your destiny
Then you do endorse their marriage?
In the secular world
I have never seen
a beautiful place like this
Thanks
You always carry it with you
when you go out, why?
It's a present from grand dad
but he doesn't allow me to use it
Why?
Because anyone who sees
the scimitar drawn out
is sure to die
What a deadly sword!
Here, catch it
You want to practise in secret?
Could I?
It's mine and I'm yours
so why not?
This is "scimitar catching the cicada"
This is the
"Full Moon returning the pearl"
Lethal Scimitar
This move is called
"Double moon pierces the rainbow"
Great technique;
But, the user must be sincere
because the scimitar has its own spirit
If the user has evil thoughts
he'll never perfect the art
Try it and see if you have evil thoughts
This scimitar
Ding Peng...
I'm here
Haven’t you practised enough all day?
Right, Qing Qing
How has my practice been?
Not bad, you're better than me
What if I returned to the human world?
Then you will be invincible
What's the matter?
Nothing, I feel it's a shame
Man prides himself
because of his aspirations all along
but presently...
you still ponder over
Liu Ruo Song's matter
I was framed by him
and the guilt wouldn't be absolved
my whole life
Qing Qing, let's go to the human world
After I have had my revenge I'll return
Is revenge that important?
When my father died
he wanted me to glorify my ancestors
this is for my late father
Qing Qing, please just help me this once
You humans
have much regard for fame and glory
but I fear grand dad would not allow it
We could sneak out
Who are you? What are you doing here?
We're here to skin you alive
The scimitar
Did you think your petty skills
could beat me?
This is fox territory
Today I only kill foxes, not humans;
Be on your way
Why should I leave?
You're young and capable
go back to the living world
and you'll rank supreme
This sort of fame
doesn't just come to anybody
Well? Go now if you want to go
before I change my mind and kill you
If you want to kill her, kill me first
Grand dad?
Yes, it's me
When you married
I knew this day would come
Ding Peng is a man after all;
But I had to know
if he really loves you
before I could let you leave with him
Here are two boxes of jewellery
for your use
Thank you
Full Moon Villa?
Yes, after you left home half a year ago
they started building it
The master is mysterious
no one has seen him
Master
The Full Moon Villa has sent an invitation
for you to go and have a drink tomorrow
What's the name of the master?
Ding Peng
Pardon? Ding Peng?
Thank you for coming
Master Lau is here
Welcome
Master Ding, we haven't met for a while
Why have you brought the coffin?
What's happening?
The Full Moon Villa
is meeting its neighbours today
Guess you must be at the wrong place
Absolutely not
This coffin is not necessarily
for dead people
Just fill it with jewellery and treasure
and you won't be carried out in it
It won't be carried out empty after all
It's a new way to rob
Where did the pine shoots come from?
I have jewellery and treasure
but even if I consent
The one up there wouldn't agree
Pine shoots...
Who dares to ambush me?
Come out if you have guts
Big brother
Let me show them what we're capable of
Attack
Your big brother
didn't want this coffin removed empty;
Now that someone's in it
you could move it
Go
Yes...
Those scumbags just now
bothered you
I am sorry for that
No big deal...
Master Lau
There's unfinished business between us
Next month is the
Lunar Mid-January Festival
I'd like to invite you to my home
for a chat
and ascertain as to
from where was the
Shooting Star technique inherited
That Ding Peng?
That's him
Strange, I never thought
a poor kid like him
could suddenly be so rich
And he hinted he'll come after you
Come after me?
Why doesn't he come now
and be done with it?
Why build a big house
in front of ours?
What does he have in mind?
It's hard to tell what he has in mind
How could we know
what an alive human being has in mind?
For someone dead it'd be different though
Right, when someone's dead
he wouldn't have ideas
But it won't be easy to want him dead now
It won't be easy but
not too difficult either I'd say
Do you still remember Xiao Song?
You mean Song Zhong?
Yes, Death by Sword Song Zhong
You are Song Zhong?
Yes, I am Song Zhong, death by Sword
Why have you brought us six together?
Because I have received money
from six people
who want you all dead
I gathered you all here
to save time
What a boast, I'll teach you a lesson
Tastes no good
Who are you?
These two cases of gold are for you
Why?
How did you get in here?
The wind blew me in
What do you want?
For the gold given to me
I'll kill somebody
What a nerve
Who are you?
Let me deal with him
Don't kill me...
I won't kill you.
You're already a dead man
Leave
Disaster...
What is it?
A coffin jumped in by itself
What?
Song Zhong is dead?
No, I have not died
Who said I died?
Did you kill Ding Peng?
Ding Peng...
He is Qing Qing's husband
Qing Qing's here...
Don't come near...
Song Zhong, you haven't died yet
There's no Qing Qing here
Song Zhong...
Miss Qing Qing, spare me please
I have already died, don't kill me again
Have mercy
Song Zhong...
I know... you said
you'll not let me go if you saw me again
Alright, I'll go and kill myself
Right, I also want to tell you
you'd better run
Qing Qing said she'll be here tomorrow
and slaughter you all
Slaughter you all...
Rats
Help...
There are many dead rats in the kitchen
Come and look, quick
What happen?
The wine has all been spoilt
It stinks...
What are you doing?
Someone stole our clothes
Fire...
He must know about Song Zhong
and has come to take revenge
Damn, of all time
the thunder should come now
Is this their doing too?
Nonsense, how could this be?
Did you think he was a fairy?
Shut up
I am really frightened
Nuisance, shut up, go to sleep
What about you?
I'll sit here
I want to see what they could do to me
Ke Xiao...
Ke Xiao
How did I get to sleep on the tree?
They must have immobilized you
and carried you out
Let's get out of here quickly
Let's go, quick
Ghost...
Where do you think you're going?
Don't go
Let me go
You are from hell
you want to take my life
Ke Xiao...
Even couples in times of danger,
go separate ways
Who?
Who are you?
I am a beautiful woman
I am behind you
Where? Where are you?
Aren’t you afraid
you might be mesmerised by me?
Alright, I'll appear to you
Am I beautiful?
Have you seen enough?
You are...
I am here to save you
In this world
I am the only one
who could deal with Qing Qing
But she is a ghost
So am I
What? You are a ghost too?
Right,
only a human could deal with a human
and a ghost with a ghost
Would you like to see
how I'll deal with Qing Qing?
What?
Follow me
What is this place?
A dilapidated hall
where fox ghosts gather
What? Fox ghost?
She's coming,
hide behind and don't come out
Qing Qing...
You have the guts to come here
I didn't think you'd come here either
Of course, I want to kill you
Stop talking and grab your sword
Sister
you still remember
what happened a thousand years ago?
Naturally
If you hadn’t stolen my potion
I would have achieved
spiritual progress 500 years ago
would I have to wait till now?
So they had a grudge because of the potion
Your kung fu is really good
You now understand why I saved you
My only enemy is Qing Qing
precisely because she wants to kill you
I have saved you
Two days after when I fight with Ding Peng
Could you help me again?
Of course
"Full Moon Villa"
If I remember correctly
today will determine which of us wins
Lunar Mid-January Festival
Right
This duel
will be judged
by masters of the martial arts world
I invited
You seem confident
This is...
This is my new wife
Would you be
using the Shooting Star technique
you stole as before
or have you stolen other techniques?
I am not using the sword this time
but the scimitar
Fear not
use the techniques
I taught you yesterday to attack him
I'll help you from behind
Brother Lau,
your kung fu has improved a lot
your swordsmanship is deadly
You're too kind...
What next?
Challenge him officially,
limited to ten moves
Opponent drops his weapons
and have his clothes damaged
The loser has to admit as a bastard
and loses his whole residence
Right
If he loses everything is finished
Right, I hereby
challenge Ding Peng to a duel officially
in front of all senior masters
Ten exchanges are the basis of the duel
the opponent must drop his weapons
and have his clothes damaged
The loser, for whole life
must admit he's a bastard
and loses the whole residence
Are you really that confident?
I wouldn't have come otherwise
Alright, let all be witness then
and see who is the bastard
First move
second exchange
third exchange
fourth exchange
Lan Lan, why haven't you used
magic to help me yet
I've to see his moves
before I deal a deadly blow
Go quickly
The fifth exchange
He's lost his clothes
That was the sixth exchange
The seventh exchange
The next is the eighth
and your sword would be gone
Two more moves,
would you need your wife to help you
Lan Lan, what are you waiting for?
What are you up to?
You are mad again, he is mad again
I was a prostitute with Moon Heung Yuen
He looked me up suddenly one day
and wanted me to be his wife
in fact at that time
he was a cuckold
Then he wanted me to dress up as a heroine
and come here to see him fight
He said he'll kill master Ding
in three moves
Don't you think he's nuts?
Don't move
I thought
Ron Song is a great swordsman
he is in fact a mad man
So you...
What about us?
Two years ago
I was also defeated by this trick
The ninth and tenth moves
You've good manners indeed!
You've lost and still got to kneel to me
Lan Lan, you...
I suppose you want to know
what this is all about
I tell you frankly
This is a trap by Ding Peng and Qing Qing
she paid me to set you up in your home
then to put on a show
at the dilapidated temple
You fell for it and
embarrassed yourself here
Your pupil at your service
What? You regard me as your teacher?
No
You can't take him as your pupil
Why not?
It is out of his good intention
Just think
The greatest swordsman
the leader of Wu Dang is my student
I am so proud
You once said when you left
you came back to avenge your shame
and take back your glory
You also said the world is cold
and you wanted to return
No, Qing Qing
I only saw one side of the human world
There are indeed good people in the world
Look, these people here today are not bad
They are totally different from what I was
As long as I love you
it doesn't matter where we are
This is a glamorous place
and is packed with people
they live like kings
Everything is better than
living in the mountains
He is a regular here
The son of Loong Moors chief
He just returned from the border
Loong Moon clan is the
greatest in the martial world
this place has been booked for the night
Right?
Yes... no...
Yes or no, speak
What difference will it make?
You have to go anyway
Why?
Because the girl Tsui Hung is mine
As long as I am here
I don't want to see anyone
Teacher, stop, you can't hurt him
Why?
Haven’t you seen the iron medal
he is carrying?
This is an icon of immunity given by
the sixteen clans
His father has done great deeds
in the martial arts world
If the owner of the badge is harmed
he will be the enemy
of the sixteen clans
and would surely die within 7 days
Says who?
The third master of the Mighty Sword Villa
He is the master of all
I heard this long before I returned
You have risen quickly
in the martial arts world
but then your efforts
would be useless because
everyone acknowledges
third master to be the best
What do you want?
I want to kill you
because you dare not kill me
Tell third master
I'll look for him in 7 days
He is known as a saint
and they say
he is No.1 in the martial arts world
why do you look for him?
Precisely because he is the best
Why?
Because I deem
I should be the best
You have changed
Don't you think you are too arrogant?
No
With kung fu like mine
they say I should be the leader of all
with my current status
they say
I should rule the martial arts world
But then I haven't done this
am I not humble enough?
Why do you still look for third master?
Because being in the martial arts world
I have to know
if he or I am the best
Is it worth it?
Is it worth going this way
for empty fame? And...
You are a nuisance
Do you know
how important fame is to human beings
not being one yourself?
You are not human
so you'll never understand
Do you appreciate how I feel about
getting everything I want
They have to listen to me
and agree with me on everything
Just think;
With me like this
could I accommodate someone
as 3rd master in my world?
Immunity badge my ass
As long as I have the scimitar
see who could defeat me
Teacher
Yonder shore is the Mighty Sword Villa?
Right
That's where you'll be crowned
the best of the best
What are those people
gathered on the shore looking at?
They are here to look at you
and pay respects
besides, with your status today
dare they not come?
Really?
Who is she?
She is daughter of
the wealthiest family of Nan Gong
her name is Nan Gong Fen Yan
She has come out of admiration for you
This is a toast from our lady
wishing you every success
and to achieve great fame
Thank you
If I return triumphant
I will notify you straight away
Thank you
With your level of kung fu
you should be invincible
I'll await you here with a feast
Thank you
See you later
This is a place for my master's practice
please have tea outside
I am not a guest
I am here to fight with your master
My master would not
fight with anyone anymore
Is this coming from you or your master
From me naturally
You are not the master
and what you say is not valid
If it does not count
and as such it is rubbish
Step down
Who are you?
Ding Peng
So you are the
famous Ding Peng
causing all the current noise
You flatter me
Right, what are your names?
Here only the master and squire
have names, others don't
This place is for storing swords
not duels
Then why are you clasping swords
in your hands
They are not swords
Man is the sword
We're called Sword's Slaves
Sword's Slave?
Our duty is to keep out intruders
Please leave at once
What if I don't?
Then you'll be forced out
This Eighteenth formation is not bad
but wait till you see
the power of the scimitar
Rainbow Scimitar
Thank you
You live up to your fame
Please come in
Of all martial artists
you are the only one who could
thwart the formation
Really? Thank you
When they use the swords
they apply their hearts, not hands
You are ambitious
and your sword follows your heart's desire
Using one's heart
is the highest form of martial arts
Please sit
Sorry, there are only two cushions here
Do you know why I invited you in?
Why?
I want to ask you if your
scimitar has 7 characters on it?
Listening to Spring rain
in a small attic all night
How did you know that?
Actually I need not ask
there's only one scimitar in the world
You've seen it?
This is not our issue today
Right, you want to have a duel with me
but I have not held a sword in 20 years
Besides,
the sword at the Mighty Sword Villa
is at the bottom of the lake after the
duel with Yin
Yes, but the name of
the Mighty Sword Villa sill exists
that's why I've come here
How old are you?
Twenty three
You're very young
and as yet still place
too much importance on fame
What will you do if you defeat me?
What if I lose?
The best fighter in the martial arts world
may not be the best fighter in the world
because many have departed
Your skills have attained
the highest level
but you are still human
and so you pursue fame
and are a slave of the sword
Have you ever thought
what you'd become if
you were without the scimitar?
Well?
You'll have nothing
you'll be reduced to being
a commoner
like the ones who brought you here
But you said just now
the sword might have been lost
but my name still exists
that is to say though I am without a sword
the sword's spirit is in me
I have attained the highest level
A sword is not a sword,
and I am not what I am
Young man, I have no sword
to fight with you
nor do I have the reason
It'll be up to you advise them
if you have won or not
in any case
no one knows what's happened here
But real victory and defeat
lies inside you
not by what you say
Teacher, what is the result?
I have won
Thank you
Please
Master Ding, sorry you had to see me home
It's alright
The night is damp and robbers abound
It's best I saw you home
Help... save me
What's the matter?
Someone over there
killed all six of my brothers
and he's coming this way
You killed these six people?
Yes, we live by killing and robbing
and we met earlier at Full Moon Villa
Kill
Run... quickly
Don't run...
Miss Nan Gong
you are all alone now
What? You haven't died?
Not only that,
but my brothers have not died
This is a trap set by our brother
You...
Our aim is to abduct
Miss Nan Gong
and ask your dad for a ransom
You underestimated me
When you were dying I held your hand
and felt your pulse beating
So I knew it was a set-up
Kill...
Let me toast you
for saving my daughter's life
Thank you, please
Please
I heard you defeated
third master at the Mighty Sword Villa
It seems that the best of the best
should be your title now
You're right
Master Ding is really a young hero
Master...
About the favour I asked of you...
I know
Master Ding
you are now the best martial artist
in the martial arts world
In terms of power
none equals
the Nan Gong family
If your two families
could be united by marriage
it would be a grand event
You mean to say...
I am the go-between representing Nan Gong
Master Ding, I have only one daughter
and we owe you her life
If you are willing to accept her
I pledge everything of 108 sub-clans
in 18 provinces
and those of the 36 societies as her dowry
You would not only be the best by then
but you could become
the king of the martial arts world
But I...
Teacher...
Don't let this opportunity go
One's aim in life is either fame or money
Now you can have both
after you marry her
you could immediately be
the leader of martial world
and become king
Besides, she's a beauty
But what about Qing Qing...
Qing Qing, I still love you
but I am only human
and you're a fox
Just think
I would be a leader
and by then if people knew my wife
is a fox spirit
I could be embarrassed
When we first met
you knew I am not human
Yes, but then
I did not have this position
I know you love me
would you have me embarrassed
in front of everyone?
Why don't you move back
to the mountain first
and I'll look you up when I have time
Why do I have to move back
to the mountains?
Because you need this place
to get married with
that Nan Gong lady
You love her a lot?
No, I still love you
but she has a family which
could support me
as leader of the martial arts world
and she could be presented to the world
however if you don't like it
you could stay
I'll build her another house
No, I'll go
Ding Peng, you'll die soon
Lau Fu...
When will my teacher
the Invincible Eagle arrive?
I hear the best fighters of the 16 schools
have arrived at the lake side
In about 3 days
they'll be at that place
Mr Suen, because Ding Peng has injured you
the sixteen schools are offended
They are all after Ding Peng now
You could have your revenge soon
of cutting off your arm soon
Invincible Eagle, my respects
Greetings
Have all the schools arrived?
Yes
Good
Let's go and get Ding Peng now
Listening to the Spring rain
in a small attic all night
Who are you?
You are...
I live here
Who wrote these characters?
Why do you ask?
I once wrote them
on a scimitar
So you are that young hero
Unfortunately you are late
my aunt died a few years ago
Old friends have departed,
an empty house remains
Bid farewell on a rainy night
Old sorrows flow endlessly as the river
My sadness is like the clouds
You attend the former reunion now
The place is still pretty
but who will appreciate it!
May I ask...
Aunt and me are both lovelorn
I felt strange
that the scimitar should end up
in Ding Peng's hands
He is the father of the child?
Not anymore
He is the new star
of the martial arts world
son-in-law of the Nan Gong family
Quick... the guests are here
As per Ron Song
the sixteen schools are on their way
they might be coming to congratulate me
that's why we need a good place
to entertain our guests
Yes
I little expect our family
would have such a distinguished son-in-law
Master, someone outside wants to see you
Why have you come here?
I came to tell you
Qing Qing raised a son for you
and is waiting in the hills for you
When did third master
start meddling with
these petty matters?
A hero should never
be an ungrateful person
I fear you will regret it one day
You dare speak nonsense here
Who do you think you are?
Do you really want to have a taste
of the deadly scimitar?
There must be a reason
for a sword to become invincible
With people like you
even the most treasured sword
shall become like scrap iron
Bring the best sword to third master
Yes
What for?
I don't want to kill an unarmed man
Please
Thanks, no need
Evil cannot win over good,
that's the law of nature
even with thousands of swords
you can't defeat my righteous spirit
Bull shit
Ding Peng, are you mad?
What if I am?
Wait, I've come here
to speak a few words with Ding Peng
That's none of your business
You needn’t fight
I am taking this scimitar away
because you are unworthy of it
Simply nuts
With the skill I have
do I care for that scimitar?
Master, the sixteen schools are all here
Straighten my clothes
We are honoured by your presence
Welcome
I wonder what I could do
for you all?
You are mistaken; they're here to
avenge the damage done
to my immunity badge
Injuring me infers
challenging the whole martial world
The Invincible Eagle
has come to adjudicate the case
What do you want then?
I want to see how good you are
Father-in-law,
please send the men from the
all the divisions to deal with them
Master Nan Gong
for our old friendship's sake
I will not pursue this matter with you
if you are smart you'd better leave
Or else
you'll taste the deadly
onslaught of the sixteen schools
and me
Father-in-law you can't leave
Dad, you must save him, I love him
That's your lookout
but it's my life that's at stake
Let go
- Father-in-law...
- Dad...
Go and save yourself first
Father-in-law, Fen Yan
Ron Song, please gather
all your friends here
to avenge for your teacher
My teacher? He's here
I tell you frankly
I have arranged for the
sixteen schools to seek revenge today
Why?
To take revenge on you
Wait
To kill his kind
would be to smear dirt on one's sword
Get out if you want to live
Teacher, why don't you kill him?
Because I have use for him
Qing Qing where are you?
Qing Qing...
Qing Qing
As I expected
the Evil Clan still exists
Black Evil Clan?
20 years ago righteous heroes
tried to kill evil in the Black Evil Lake
but they escaped
we haven't heard of them since
The others thought they were all dead
only I tracked them down
I then heard my pupil say
Ding Peng had an invincible scimitar
which led me to think
20 years ago I too was injured
by a scimitar of the Evil clans
Tung Fang Bu Bai
which was also invincible
So I let you escape
in the hope you would find them
So you're not a fox
I belong to the evil clan
but I pretended to be a fox
to escape killing
You admit it
Get his sword
Run
Chase
Where's your grand dad?
They left long ago
Get the old rogue and settle our score
You're late unfortunately
My grand dad left six months ago
Don't worry
What I've owed people,
I'll surely return it in person
Invincible Eagle
20 years ago when we fought
both our only child died
We should be even
Could you still be chasing me for 20 years
for a scar on your face?
You are a plague to the martial arts world
Every righteous hero ought to
rid you off
You put it in a nice way
It's actually you who is after fame
Qing Qing, Invincible Eagle
when I became a leader
I have since become good
and have not done anything bad
Besides I have been a hermit
for the last 20 years
Could I be a plague to others?
You are still the Black Evil Clan
Teacher, take care
Give me the baby
Everyone, stop
I'll kill the baby
if whoever moves
Drop your weapons
I forgot to say one thing
If you all die he would still die
because we must ensure we get rid of him
Stop, are you a human being?
No, he isn't
he is a beast in disguise
Who are you? Where are you?
Third master?
Commoners focus on hatred and neglect love
why can't you let your hatred go
and live in peace?
The Black Evil Clan kill people
for no reason
there'll be no peace
as long as they still exist
You must be wrong
they have been living as hermits
for 20 years
and have never used any weapons
And to kill them
you have already killed many wrong people
in the last 20 years
You are in fact the
cold blooded murderer
Besides, your pupil is treacherous
and wants to kill even this baby
he is in fact the scum bag
So it seems
we should discern
who are the really evil ones
Xie Xiao Feng, who are you
to lecture me
I only want to
ask you to live and let live
and turn your quarrels into peace
Ask my sword first
Liu Ruo Song
Time to settle our score
Teacher, I am your pupil
how would I dare to fight with you
Ding Peng
Qing Qing, are you alright?
Yes
The ones who killed many people
in the martial world
are those scumbags and
hypocrites like him
Guess it's the inborn nature of everyone
One often does
all sorts of things for glory
Only some manage to conceal it
and some don't