Come on! Come on, kid!
The fuck?
Look at me. Fuck!
Come on, Oleg, stay with me.
Come on. Come on!
Come on, kid.
We're going to make it.
We're going to crash!
Yeah, mon.
Sweet like cola wine.
Come on,
we count the hundreds only.
Jeez.
Why don't they finish it?
We're good.
What you have there?
It's all looking very good.
Nobody fucking move!
- Eat the floor, fucker!
- Down on the ground!
- Get down!
- Now, you cocksuckers!
You heard him! Get down!
You're making the biggest
fucking mistake--
Shut up!
Down, motherfuckers, down!
Everybody,
eat the fucking floor!
Fucker!
Now, very fucking carefully,
reach into your jackets...
and take out whatever you're packing
and slide it under the bed!
Fuck you.
Come on, all of you!
Move it! Come on, fuckheads!
Keep it moving! Now!
You better spend it
real quick, shitbags.
You ain't long
for this fucking world.
Yeah, right. I will be sure
to have a mai tai on you.
All of you goombah fucks.
Come on.
I will have one on you, too.
Go, go! Come on!
Come on! Move, move, move!
- Hurry!
- Fucking move!
Get going! Move!
Let's go, let's go,
let's go! Come on!
Come on! Now!
Motherfucker!
No, man.
You fuckers!
You motherfuckers!
We don't give a fuck
about these niggers.
Now, you spill Perello blood...
you're deep-6 invested.
Walk clean.
Piss on Perello blood!
Fuck him!
Shit!
God damn it!
I don't think so.
Son of a bitch!
Motherfucker! Fuck you!
Fuck!
Come on!
Get up, you fuck!
Guys, let's blow this cunt!
What a fucking pussy!
What? Where you going,
you fuck?
We can work this out!
Let's talk!
Fuck you!
Shut the fuck up!
Where the fuck you reaching?
- Please--
- Tell you what...
have a mai tai on me...
Fuck me. He's a cop.
A fucking cop?!
Motherfucker!
Get the shit,
and let's go! Now!
Hurry the fuck up!
Fucking dirty mooks.
Cocksuckers!
Is there one fucking honest cop
in this fucking city?
Joey.
Give me your gat.
Take this shit
and get rid of it.
And do me a favor--
don't fuck it up.
No!
Give, loser punk!
Never...dickwad!
Sorry. You OK?
Shit.
I didn't mean to do that.
Call now.
Hey, boss.
What are you doing there?
Whacking off
to the E! Channel again?
I just want to smell you.
Stay just like that.
You didn't call,
you son of a bitch.
Let me guess.
Those are my pearls
you have been promising?
No. No, it's nothing.
Just a little recycling.
Joey, come on.
You are looking for trouble...
because if Tommy ever found out
about that--
Just remember it's just our little
insurance policy, all right?
because there's no way in hell
I am going to be thinking
about getting
some of this right here...
looking at you through
some glass window.
There's no fucking way.
No, Joey, come on.
No, no, no...
No. No!
Come on, baby.
Baby, look. Look at me.
- What?
- Nicky's around.
No, Nicky's busy.
Come on, I will be quick
and real quiet. Come on.
Quiet? I don't think so.
Quick, I can believe.
You know something, Mrs. G?
- What?
- You're bad.
Yeah, yeah... Sure.
- I got a rep.
- Yeah? You got a rep.
- Yeah, some things--
- You got a crazy rep.
Teresa likes to make it
on washing machines.
On select occasions, yeah.
- No, no.
- What?
My sauce! My sauce is bubbling!
Wait, that's how I like it!
Yeah.
Fuck! Come on!
Hey! You use language
like that...
you ain't getting
no after-dinner dessert.
Go find Nicky.
I think he's up
in the bedroom with Oleg.
Why's he always
with that Russkie kid?
Don't he have no other friends?
Joey, you know, they get along.
It's fine. What do you want?
I don't want him going over there
no more, that's what I want.
I know. He knows.
He knows.
I will go get him.
Yo, Nick.
Dinner.
Shit.
Come on.
Get down.
Dinner.
Can Oleg stay?
Babe, it's already been
3 times this week.
I am sure his mom would like
to have him home for a change.
It's OK. I am not even hungry.
I will see you tomorrow.
Go Razors.
You, go wash up.
Those hands are scary.
- Good night, Oleg.
- Good night, Mrs. Gazelle.
He's not even up there.
They turned the damn basement
into a sports complex again.
Well...
Come on, T, how many times
am I supposed to tell him?
Joe, what do you want?
They're just boys. They--
Dad, I won't do it again,
I swear.
Don't you expect me
to make book on that.
Now go get your grandfather.
I just washed my hands.
All right.
Hey, Nick.
Razors and Blues Friday night?
120 yellow, pal.
No way!
It's going to be a total deathmatch
between Chester and Erlich.
- They're going home in body bags!
- Red ice!
Hey... can Oleg come?
He's never been to one game, and--
No. No, not this time.
Sal can only score me
a pair of tickets.
Maybe next time, though.
Go get your grandfather.
Get up.
Come on.
Come on, man.
Make it different this time.
Get up.
I said, get up!
What is this?
Wolfgang Puck.
It's your favorite.
It's thick-crust...
you damn blyad.
I cut off crust for you.
It will be better.
Bring me another Moskova.
Hey.
Come here.
Come.
Watch this.
John Wayne in The Cowboys.
I don't like cowboys.
Come on.
It's the Duke.
Come. Sit.
When I was growing up
in Kishinev...
we had no VHS,
no DVD back then.
I remember...
I did a job for
this friend of my father.
I pickpocketed a key
off this apparatchik.
The man gave me as a reward...
this children's projector.
It came with 3 films--
Speedy Gonzales,
Tarzan of the Apes...
and John Wayne in The Cowboys.
I watched that thing...
a thousand times.
Anzor, it's getting cold.
I was 9 years old.
I didn't know how long
movies were supposed to be.
My version of The Cowboys,
it was only 10 minutes long.
No John Wayne getting shot.
Because it was for kids,
they left that part out.
I didn't know this...
until I arrive in America...
and see it on TV
for the first time.
I hate it.
I want my 8-millimeter back.
Because on that one,
the Duke lives.
Some things were better
in the old place.
Not too many. Some things.
Let me show you
from the beginning.
No, no...
Go forward.
This part's better.
Without the Duke?
Where are you going?!
You don't walk out on the Duke!
She said he's always distracted
and he never finishes his work...
and she wants to get him tested.
Wait, she wants to get him tested?
Tested for what?
I think maybe...
attention disorder or something.
I am not fucking A.D.D.
Hey! You don't use that word
in front of your mother.
What's wrong with "A.D.D."?
The other one, smart-ass!
And he don't use that word, period!
I don't want to be on medication.
You can't make me take it,
because I won't.
No, no, Nick. You know what?
Don't even worry about.
There's no way in hell anybody's
going to put you on meds, OK?
T, why don't you tell
that teacher...
to come down to the rink
and watch him wax that puck?
That's perfect concentration
every time.
That's different, Joe.
We're just--we're just trying
to find out what's going on with you.
OK? Buddy, she said
some great things, too.
She said--she said
that he's very bright.
She said he's very creative.
You left that part out before.
I like that part.
I got potential.
What are you doing?
You taking a collection
down there?
He must eat.
The little prick...
insults the Duke.
He don't eat in this house.
You hear me,
you little snotface?!
Stay in your room!
Jerk off to your fucking Razors!
Faggot!
He's a growing boy.
What did I fucking say, suka?
He has to eat, Anzor.
Please.
Who puts food
on this fucking table?
Not you, blyad.
I am the big man of this house.
When I say the little shit
don't eat, he don't eat.
Anzor.
John Wayne was a faggot.
So, Vicki Goletto
told me she saw you...
walking hand-in-hand
with Jeannie's daughter.
The fat one?
That sounded like a gun.
Hey, Nick, throw me some bread.
Shit! Get down!
Get down! You OK? You OK?!
Jesus, Joe. What the hell?
Stay here. Motherfucker.
Motherfucker!
I am going to kill
that fucking piece of shit!
- Where are you going?
- You Russian piece of shit!
Gun.
Shoot my fucking house.
I am going to fucking kill you.
Dad, wait!
Get back in the house.
Get back in the house!
Get back in now! Go!
Stay right here.
Don't you move, son, OK?
You fucking piece of shit.
I am going to fucking kill you!
- Nicky, get inside.
- Fucking piece of shit!
Joe! Joe!
What's the matter with you?
I just called 911.
Leave it for the cops!
Get the kid and take him
back in the house!
You fucking piece of shit!
I am going to kill you!
Open the fucking door!
- Oleg's my friend!
- I will kick it in!
- He's my friend!
- Open the door!
Joey, don't be a damn hero!
Open up! It's Joey Gazelle
from next door! Open up!
Open up!
Get back! Get back!
Where is he? Is he upstairs?
He's in--
- What?
- He's--
Listen, get down.
What the fuck?
Where's the kid?
Fuck him.
I am the one who's shot.
Who is he?
Is he still in the house?
The little snotfuck
ran out back.
Oleg?
Oleg? What are you trying to say?
Oleg shot you?
What are you...
a fucking idiot?
I didn't do this to myself.
The little prick
put a gun to me, too.
Look at him.
She used to fucking make--
Where'd he get the piece?
Where'd he get the fucking piece?!
- Fuck should I know?!
- What, it wasn't yours?
No! No way!
I got a .357
in the safe out back.
He had some fucking
snub-nosed thing.
Silver. Chrome.
This is bullshit, Nick!
Now you tell me!
I am not playing around!
We saw where you put the gun,
but he didn't take anything--
not with me.
Well, he went back, Nicky.
Well, I didn't know.
I swear I didn't know.
Come here. Listen to me.
Listen to me. That piece,
that's not just any hot piece.
Tommy used it
to burn a dirty cop.
- No. Joe.
- Yeah.
Yeah. No, no. Listen, listen.
On top of it...
that kid's out there right now.
The cops are on their way.
If they find the gun
or they find the kid...
and he talks, I am dead.
Fuck!
Calm down! Calm down.
- Yeah.
- Calm down.
We can get to him.
You can get to the gun
before the cops do.
Shit.
Hey.
Hey, so where you
going to take him?
Grimley Memorial.
Hey, Mila, you know, I think
you should go with him, OK?
Nyet. Ya padazhdu.
Yeah, no, you should go with him.
I am going to go look for Oleg.
Me and Nicky are going to
go find him, OK?
And I will get Teresa to stay here
in case he comes back, all right?
- All right, you should go.
- OK. Thank you, Joey.
- Yeah, no problem.
- I am sorry.
Yeah, no problem.
Yeah, we're going to find him.
Don't worry about it.
Fuck.
Come on.
Police officers.
Sir, you live here?
No, no. Actually, I live next door.
I heard some gunshots...
so I came over, you know,
to see what's going on.
What did you see?
I saw Anzor, my neighbor.
He was in the kitchen.
He--he's been shot.
He say who did it?
Nah. He was screaming
in Russian.
His wife, she asked me
to stick around for the kid.
He's out somewhere.
- You don't know who shot him?
- No.
I am going to need to take
a statement outside.
I can't have you
messing up the scene, OK?
All right.
Hey, check it out.
I don't see nothing inside.
Maybe all the way back.
Got it.
Leave it for forensics.
Sir, I need for you
to wait outside.
All right. No problem.
Fucking having a heart attack.
- I can't--I can't--
- Breathe.
I got to find this kid, T.
I got to find this kid tonight.
Nick, I need to know places,
all right?
I need to know hideouts.
Go to your room right now...
and make a list.
Nick, make a list!
OK.
I am not fucking around, Nick.
Joe, just--
just take it easy.
There's no fucking time!
All right,
I want you to wait next door...
and the second he shows up,
call me.
I got to fucking
do something about this.
I can't have the kid
fucking talking to the cops.
You understand me?
The fucking gun is on the street.
This whole fucking goddamn thing
is about to fucking blow up.
If fucking Tommy
or any of those fucking guys...
find out about it,
I am a dead man.
You got to fucking help me.
If I fucking have to.
Hey, grab your jacket, Nick.
We're going for a ride.
All right, Nick.
I want you to stay in the car,
all right?
Don't get out for anything...
and if I am not back in one hour,
I want you to call your mother.
She will come and get you, OK?
Excuse me.
OK, take her to burn now.
You're going to be fine.
Dr. Gutierrez, 745.
Excuse me.
Who's in the other room?
Is that Yugorsky, gunshot victim?
Teenager, DUI car wreck.
I think they just lost a GSW in 3.
Lost? He--he's dead?
Yeah.
No, wait.
He took a bullet right here.
No, a major trauma to chest.
Been in surgery all day.
Guy was a cop.
Wait. No. Yeah,
they did bring someone in...
about 40 minutes ago.
O.R. number 2. I think
he's gone upstairs already.
That's this way?
Can I help you...
Dr. Donaldson?
Yeah. The cops
are waiting outside...
and they need to run a match
on this bullet ASAP.
Well, I will make sure
they get it right away.
Excuse me.
You looking for this?
Yugorsky, GSW, shoulder?
You got to help me
find him, Nick.
What are you going to do to him?
I am not going to do nothing.
I just need to get my gun back
and bring him home.
You sure?
Talk to me, Nick.
It's this old abandoned
rec center in the park.
Me and Oleg would hang out
there sometimes, read comics.
He might be there.
Nice gun.
Lo Chan to Admitting.
Detective Rydell, Narcotics.
I already made a statement.
I don't know
who the shooter was.
Fucking niggers
all look the same.
Yeah.
Anzor Yugorsky.
Any relation to Ivan Yugorsky?
My uncle.
The Czar of Brighton Beach.
I been to his club
a couple of times.
Nice joint.
He even sang a few songs.
He sings like a fucking toad.
Well, Sinatra he's not...
but he's a man
with a serious reputation.
- He has a lot of enemies.
- Bullshit.
I told you. It was just
some fucking crackhead.
Yeah, well, I spoke
to the officers on the scene.
There was no sign
of forced entry...
but they did find some
interesting shit out back--
6 cases of NyQuil,
and it ain't even cold season.
Now, what do you think a search warrant
is going to turn up?
Dr. Cookson,
call Imaging Services.
- Come on, where?
- It's this way.
Let's go.
Quick, come on.
Come on.
Go, go, go.
This way.
Be cool...
and let me do all the talking.
I am going to get you out of here.
Help you?
- Yeah.
- How much you got?
I got a lot.
Yes.
Oleg, it's Nicky.
Are you in there?
- Is this the spot?
- Yeah.
Now, where's the stash?
Last stall, motherfucker.
Go. Find the stash.
Find it.
Go on.
Find it!
Fuck.
We're going to search
this entire fucking park.
He might still be around.
What the fuck do you think
you're doing, white boy?
All right, drop it, man,
or I will fucking waste the midget!
Come on!
He's just a tagalong.
Plug them, Dale!
Plug the motherfucker!
Fuck him up!
I will fuck you up, man!
Just let my boy go!
Pop a cap in his ass!
Wait, motherfucker, wait!
Man, shoot this motherfucker!
Shoot that--
All right, stay right by me.
Here. Against the wall.
You stay right there. Don't you move.
You stay right there.
Fuck.
Hey, hey,
I didn't do nothing, officer.
I--I--I just came--
You put your fucking hands
against the stall now!
Put your fucking head down!
Oleg.
I--I told you to stay outside.
- Did you find him?
- Get the fuck outside!
Get out of here!
I am fucking talking to you!
Turn around. What'd you see?
Did you find the gun?
Did you find the silver gun?
Did you find
that fucking silver gun?
I--I--I don't know.
You want to study
for your G.E.D.? Here.
Look what you done
to my fucking ride, bitch.
It's just 6 weeks, baby.
Please?
I only been taking 1 class--
1 class, 2 hours a week.
I still got time
to be pulling tricks.
3 fucking Gs I find you
for these fucking airbags...
and what do I get in return?
Fucking night school?
I will quit.
I am super-proud of you
for showing some initiative.
Maybe I will even come
to your graduation.
But first you're going to give me
back my fucking property!
You learn how to use that
watching Sesame Street?
You ain't even holding it right.
What's the matter, kid?
You got the shakes?
Now I am going to put a smile
on your face, boy--
cheek to cheek.
You're going to be the happiest
little brat in school.
Say cheese.
Who's laughing now, you fucking
gray meat limp dick motherfucker?
Mack daddy!
Who's macking now, bitch?
Puñeta!
You got some cojones, kid.
Let me see your fingers, son.
Is this--
Hey, hey. Is this your son?
I am taking care of him
tonight, OK?
Well, unless you have the name
and number of his doctor...
and I can get a prescription
over the phone...
you're going to have
to take him to emergency, OK?
Now, if you want me
to call you a cab--
I don't need no fucking cab.
I need some spray shit for him.
Well, that spray shit happens to be
a controlled substance, ma'am...
so what can I tell you?
Keep the change.
I can't--This is stupid.
I can't do this.
Listen, why don't we
go out in the back...
and we talk about it, OK?
- Look, lady--
- I will take care of you.
There's nothing I can do, lady.
There's nothing you can do?
Take him to emergency.
OK.
Nothing you can fucking do?
Get what he needs...now.
- It's Beclovent.
- Yeah, I know.
Beclovent, bitch!
Come on, let's just go back.
No. No. If he turns up,
your mom's going to call.
T.
Sal.
Yeah.
Do girls really
get naked in there?
You will find out when you're 21.
I have seen Mom naked.
It's no big deal.
Trust me on this one.
It's always a big deal.
Stay here.
Put your hands together
for the sexy redhead...
Galaxy.
What?
It's taken care of.
Lucky us.
Guys, sit down. Have a seat.
Don't be shy.
They make a good mai tai
for a twat bar...
but seriously overpriced--
$2 million
for a round of drinks...
and the pussy
ain't even that hot.
Hey, baby.
Jodi, I am doing business here.
Jodi...
come on.
Get the fuck out of here.
$2 million.
Suck a dick, you prick bastard.
You don't have shit on us.
What do you think of this?
The cops never found these
at the scene...
just 2 dead narcs
and 3 dead Jamaicans.
Ballistics is going to reveal...
that the slugs
that killed my partners...
didn't come from the Jamaicans,
so there were others involved.
As for myself...
I was never there.
Well, dead guys tell no tales.
Yeah. Why don't you ask
your pal here?
What the fuck you talking about?
You blew my partner
Stevie's balls off...
with a .38 snub nose,
a real distinctive piece--
stainless, polished up
like a spic's hubcap.
Now, let me take
a wild guess here.
I think that you gave him
the gun to dump in the river.
Now, I am assuming that
he never got around to it...
because 2 hours ago...
his next-door neighbor
took a slug in the shoulder.
The shooter was the guy's
10-year-old stepson...
who was over at Gazelle's house
2 hours earlier.
What the fuck
you trying to do here?
You trying to fucking play us?
Because you're wasting
our fucking time.
This is goddamn
fucking bullshit.
Bullshit? Bullshit?
This punk Anzor Yugorsky...
he describes the gun to me
in vivid detail.
Makes mention it's a snub nose
with a serious shine to it.
What the fuck is this guy
talking about, Joey?
He's talking about a fucking shiny gun.
Big fucking deal.
There's a thousand of them
on the street.
It ain't the fucking piece.
Yeah? What were you doing
at the hospital...
when they brought Yugorsky in?
Sniffing around emergency?
You know what I figure?
I figure you were there
to pull a switch...
on the slug
they took out of him.
My wife asked me to go
to the hospital.
She was concerned--you know,
in a neighborly way.
She wanted me to go to see--
All right, you know what?
Enough bullshit.
I expect to find a bag
in this locker...
at Dominic Station by midnight.
If the bag is not there
one minute after...
I am taking you all down
any fucking way I can...
even if I have to
manufacture the case.
And you know I will, because I got
the toughest mob in the world.
I am the law.
All right, stay put.
I am going to grab you a burger.
I am not hungry.
Yeah, but you didn't finish dinner,
so I am going to grab you something to eat.
Stay here.
Dad?
Don't go in there.
Let's just go home.
It's going to be all right.
No, it's not.
Hey, Frankie, how you doing?
- Hey, how are you?
- Yeah, it's good to see you.
Sit, Joe.
How you doing, guys?
- Hi, Joey.
- How you doing, man?
- Joey.
- I am fine.
You want some coffee,
something to eat?
Nah, I am good. But, listen...
I got my boy,
he's waiting out in the car.
I want to get him a burger
or something.
Tony, go and take care
of that, yeah?
Yeah, Tony, get him some fries
and a strawberry shake.
And don't scare him.
He don't know you're coming.
So, Joe...
I just got off the phone
with Ivan Yugorsky...
about this thing
with his nephew.
I told you.
It's not the fucking piece.
Look, everybody knows the nephew
is a brain-fried retrobate.
Yeah, whatever.
He's a fucking tweaker piece of shit.
And he's cooking meth
in his backyard.
I know I told you this already,
but it's just a matter of time...
before he blows up the whole
fucking neighborhood.
We notice, but it's a sensitive issue
with me and you.
Now, I am in bed with Yugorsky
on this gasoline deal.
Hey, it's a good deal.
I don't want to rock the boat.
Fuck that.
Fuck those Russian cunts!
Pa, it's the fucking narc
that's got his dick in our ass.
Hey...
calm down, Tommy.
You see, Joe, the tweaker's
got it in his head...
that maybe you were looking...
to knock him out
of the cooking business...
and help the boy out.
Made a piece available to him.
I would never use a kid
to do something like that.
Never.
All right, all right, look.
I made a personal reassurance
to Yugorsky...
that I would have
my entire crew in the street...
out looking for that kid.
Now, in the interest
of professional harmony...
I think we all want
to get our stories straight.
You agree, don't you, Joe?
One hamburger,
and you're out of my life.
That's it.
Oleg.
Shit.
Hey, kid...
how you doing?
Your old man sent this stuff
out for you.
Thanks.
Ain't it a little late
for you to be out?
I got twins your age.
They're in bed by now.
What are you, like, 9?
10...
and a half.
I got to go to the bathroom.
Hey, Joey...
looks like your kid
don't listen too well.
It must run in the family.
Hey, Nicky, get over here.
Get over here.
What the hell you doing?
I thought I told you to wait in the car.
I had to go to the bathroom.
How you doing, Nicky? You want
you want some gummy bears?
Hey, Nicky,
you wouldn't by chance...
know where your friend
got that gun, would you?
No.
I have to go to the bathroom.
OK.
Nicky, you go to the bathroom.
Have you decided yet?
I have a bus to catch in--
Cuando?
I will have a cheeseburger
and a coke.
I got to go to the bathroom.
Don't worry. We're going to
take care of the cop, OK?
- I know.
- OK.
Where is it?
Hey, Nicky.
- Where the hell are you?
- I am almost done.
Well, hurry up in there.
Come on, we got to go.
- Razors.
Get over there
and wash your hands.
We got to get out of here.
Come on.
Fuck.
Hey, sweetie, how you doing?
Good, hon.
All right, Nick, listen to me.
I want you to think really hard...
about where your friend
might be right now...
because the others,
they're looking for him...
and if they
find him first, I am--
- They won't find the gun.
- What did you say?
What did you say?
Don't you mess with me, Nicky.
I want you
to fucking talk to me now.
Just promise me
you won't hurt him.
Nick, I don't have time
for this shit right now.
- Now fucking tell me.
- Promise!
Promise you what? What, what?
I promise. I swear to God.
I am not going to fucking
hurt your friend.
Now, just come on. Just tell me.
Just tell me what you know.
Come on.
This one here?
Man.
Come on, where is it, Nick?
I thought you said
you put it in there.
Well, I did.
I put it right there.
Then where is it? I thought
you said you put it in the tank.
I put it in here.
Shit. Which one
did you put it in, Nick?
Which one did you put it in?
God damn it, Nicky.
Why'd you lie to me?
Why did you lie to me?
I didn't.
Why did you lie to me?!
I am not fucking lying!
I put it in there!
You just fucking
killed me, Nick.
You just fucking killed me.
You come here.
Now, I want you to keep
an eye open, right?
If you see anybody come...
I want you to cough really loud,
all right?
You're like a broken record.
I am telling you.
You got to see this.
You better not be
jerking my chain.
What are you doing here, kid?
I was looking for the bathroom.
See? Even the kid thinks
it's a shithole back here.
Shut up, Ralphie.
All right, just...
you go on out
through that door there...
turn left, go all the way
down to the end...
turn left again,
and you're there.
You got it?
Which door?
Come here, kid. I will show you.
Come here, kid.
Hey, Yolanda.
- Come on.
- Wait up.
Where you going
with my cheesecake?
No, this is for
paying customers, not you.
Manny.
Where are you? Here.
There. I got your number, fucker.
Forget it. I ain't dragging
your butt across no state lines.
Look, papa,
why don't you just go home?
I bet you things are not as bad
as you think they are.
Come on, papa.
Motherfucker!
Be careful what you say!
Get down! Over here.
Run! Run, little man, run!
Hey!
Let go!
Get off! Get off!
Get off!
Do you know these guys?
Yeah.
Baby?
Where the hell are you?
Taking care of things.
Well, forget about it...
because they picked up Oleg at
a bus station with some hooker.
Who picked him up? The cops?
Yeah.
Jesus Christ.
This is fucking bullshit.
- Hey...
- Fuck!
Hey! You got Nicky with you?
Yeah, he's right here.
Then stop using your mouth
around him...
and bring my son home now.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's what I am doing.
I am bringing him home right now.
Do you mind?
I am feeling kind of parched.
Big game Friday night.
I bet you're excited about that.
It's going to be red ice...
and plenty of
blue shirt body bags.
Am I right?
Look...
I could help you, kid--
you and your mom, if need be.
Now, I could get that prick
out of your life, lock him up.
I could do that. I am a cop.
All you have to do is tell me
where you found the gun...
and where you stashed it.
That's it. What do you say?
You let me help you.
Get out of here, Mila.
You know, go to a shelter.
I mean,
I can get you an address.
You don't understand.
I belong to him.
No. No...
I don't understand.
I was prostitute in Moscow.
Yugorsky Escort Service
offered to bring girls over...
with promise of big bucks.
We would owe $50,000--
you know, pay back through work.
I take offer...
not tell them I am pregnant.
When they find out...
they insist I have an abortion.
I told them no.
They sent Anzor to kill me.
Anzor's not a killer.
He's not hard man...
like big Yugorsky.
He thinks...
he thinks he's,
you know, John Wayne.
Must do right thing.
He goes against his uncle.
He tells big man Yugorsky
he will pay off my debt.
His uncle refuses...
tells him...
he will send others to kill me
to set example.
So, Anzor make me wife.
Big man Yugorsky
can't kill his nephew's wife.
But he tells Anzor
to leave Little Odessa.
He's no longer...
working for Yugorsky family.
Yeah.
I am going to get you
the name of a shelter.
You OK?
This ain't right, Joe.
He don't need to be
put through this.
Nick, I am proud of you.
You done good, all right?
Look, I am going to head up
to Community Hills.
The cops don't got
the gun yet...
but I may have a line on it,
so I am going to go over there.
I am scared, Joe.
I am pissed at you,
and I am scared--
equal measures.
Be careful.
- Hey.
Just got word.
The cops picked up the kid.
Anything you still
want to tell us?
Tell you what?
There's nothing to tell.
Where you headed, Joe?
I was supposed to head to the store
and pick up some milk and eggs.
In all the excitement,
I forgot to do it, so...
Yugorsky's going to call us
when he talks to the kid.
Don't go too far.
Later, Joe.
Yeah, see you.
Hey, T...
looking fucking good.
He keeps giving me
this bullshit story...
about finding the gun in some
abandoned locker in school.
What do you want me to do?
The little fucker shot me.
He ain't going to
spill dick to you.
You know, I don't think
I am being clear enough here.
You know what I mean?
Let me be crystal clear.
You get the boy
to give up Gazelle...
or I am closing shop
on your tweaker ass...
and I am taking you down
fucking hard.
Understand me?
Hey, cowboy.
Want to go get some ice cream?
Yo, we got good shit, daddy.
Get the fuck away from my car.
Hey. Hey,
I am looking for Manny Perez.
He--he's not here. No!
Manny? Where the fuck is he?
- He's not here.
- Where is he?
Where is he?!
He's not here!
You better not
fucking lie to me!
Where the fuck is he?
Where is he?
- OK, OK.
- Where is he?
He's at Armando's.
Armando's.
- He's at Armando's.
- Yes. He's at--
Get the hell out of the way.
You stay right there.
What's your name?
Conchita.
Now, you listen to me, Conchita.
You listen to me real good.
- I don't want to hurt Manny.
- OK.
All right?
I don't want to hurt him...
but he has something
that belongs to me--a gun.
Do you know anything
about a gun?
- No, no.
- No.
No. It's block 5, number 602.
That's where he is.
OK. Now, listen to me.
We are now on what we call
the honor system.
You comprende?
You understand what I am saying?
- Sí.
- OK.
- You don't call Manny.
You don't tell Manny I am coming.
You don't warn him for anything...
because if you do,
I am going to come back here!
I can be an asshole.
You have made your point.
You showed some balls.
I like that.
But now it's time to be smart.
You tell me
what I want to know...
and I am going to reward you--
Razors season tickets.
I am sorry.
It's OK.
I told you, we're cool.
Just tell me.
I am sorry I missed.
You little shit.
Tell me where
the fucking gun is.
You tell me,
or I will fucking kill you.
Fuck!
Oleg!
Where are you?
You little shit!
Oleg!
I will find you!
I am going to kill you, you...
You're only making it
worse on yourself!
Do you hear me?
Jeez, Edele,
I think we picked up a stray.
Indeed.
Hello there.
Hi.
And who might you be?
You know, I think we should get
another ice cream cone.
I think you're right, Papa Bear.
Hey.
Hey, are you Manny?
Manny? Nah. He's upstairs.
What you want with him?
Business.
If he owes you any money,
forget about it.
I just cleaned the cabron out.
Yeah? Who is it?
It's Conchita.
- Conchita.
- La Conchita.
Faces on the fucking table!
Heads down and fucking hands
behind your head!
You move,
and I will fuck you up!
I will fuck you up!
Don't you move, partner.
Don't you fucking move.
I will fuck you up.
Which one of you is fucking Manny?
Who's Manny?
Are you done?
- You mother--
- Pendejo!
You Manny? You motherfucker!
Don't call me pendejo,
you fuck!
I want my fucking gun!
I want my fucking snub nose!
You lifted it from
the fucking Arlington!
Now, where the fuck is it?
Where the fuck is it?
Fuck you!
Where the fuck is my gun?
* Stressed out,
but I am going to hold out
* For the whole 9,
that's no doubt
* Till I get what's mine
I am throwing no doubt...
Fuck!
Fuck! Motherfucker!
- Look at that.
- That's a good smile.
Look at those braces.
- There's a little dimple there.
- They are.
Yeah, that's super cute.
Isn't this cool?
Here, come on.
Look back in the camera.
Try it again.
And you push that.
Look in there and push--
My gosh. Yeah.
You can't see, right?
- Hey, Eric.
- That's very smart. Yeah.
- You want to hug your sister?
- Yeah. Come on.
Just a little bit.
Get a little closer.
Come on,
you guys love each other.
- You need a little hug.
- A little closer.
- Come on.
- Extend the arm.
Come on. Come on, Eric.
You can do it
a little better than that.
I mean,
that's your sister, right?
That's very good.
You love your sister, don't you?
What about you, Oleg?
You want to be in the film
as well, don't you?
My stomach hurts.
Can I go to the bathroom?
Sure.
I will just hold on to this.
You go outside,
you take a right...
and then a left.
Hurry up though.
You're missing out.
Who wants to play dress-up?
Good, dress-up.
We have the Burning Rocket
and the Volts.
There you are.
I thought you needed
to go to the bathroom.
I couldn't find it.
Silly boy.
I told you to take a right,
then a left.
Come.
I will show you.
Don't forget to wash your hands
when you're done.
Joe?
Mrs. Gazelle?
Who is this?
- Is this--
- Oleg.
I am sorry about taking the gun,
Mrs. Gazelle.
Oleg, where are you?
I think I am in trouble.
Sweetheart,
I know what happened, OK?
I need you to be
straight up with me.
Are the police listening
in on this call?
No, I am not with the police.
I am at Dez and Edele's apartment.
There's 2 other kids here.
What?
I--I think they are
going to hurt us.
Jesus.
Come on. No.
Is this some kind of a joke?
Oleg, you have caused
enough trouble today.
Where are you?
I don't know.
I was in the back of a van.
They brought us here.
They got this room
with all these toys in it.
They're making a video.
OK, OK. Oleg,
I need you to look around...
for an address for me, OK?
Is there any mail
laying around?
I am in the bathroom.
She's going to come back any minute.
Bathroom. Jesus,
I don't know, I don't know.
I don't know.
Just call 911.
No. I don't want to go
back to the police.
Why?
They want me to say
I got the gun from Mr. Gazelle.
Do you need
some help in there?
I am OK.
It's my stomach.
I am almost done.
You poor thing.
Well, I am right outside.
- Oleg.
- I am still here.
OK.
OK, so look
in the medicine cabinet.
Do you see any bottles?
Prescription bottles usually have
the address on the front label.
Do you see anything?
Is there anything in there?
Oleg, what--
what's happening?
Oleg, it's Dez.
You want to open up, please?
Oleg.
OK. Oleg?
- Come on.
- Oleg?
- Oleg.
- Oleg!
What is--
what's going on?
Oleg!
Just open the door.
Mrs. Gazelle, I got a bottle.
So, now read me the address.
1456 Owens Park Lane, Hoboken.
Oleg! Let's go! Open the door!
- Oleg?
- Come on! Oleg!
Jesus!
Wake up, wake up.
We got to go get Oleg.
Come on, put your coat on.
I thought he was in jail.
Hey, homes.
I got a busted headlight.
Hey, Lester, my man.
Who got over on you, bro?
Some puta
who's forwarding address...
is going to be
in 10 different zip codes...
all of them dumpsters.
I got you covered
by tomorrow night.
Hey, check this out.
Is that sweet or what?
Hey, a royal flush
put her in my pocket.
300 cold puts her in mine.
No, man. She's a beauty.
Think I am going to hold on to her.
500.
I won't miss them--
not until Cinco de Mayo.
Oh, Joe. Shit!
I am under a lot of stress tonight,
so whatever I say don't count.
Do I still have to go
to school tomorrow?
I don't know. We will see.
Remember me?
Who in the fuck are you?
You got something that
belongs to me, a snub nose .38.
You just scored it
off of Manny in a card game.
I need it back.
Fuck.
I want my fucking gun!
Where the fuck are you?
Don't be fucking stupid.
Fuck!
You fuck!
Where's my fucking gat!
Help me!
Where's my gat?
You going to fucking tell me
where my gun is now?
Tell me where I can find it,
or in about thirty seconds...
you're going to have third degree burns.
You know what that means?
No cock, asshole! You're going to
have a fucking melted dick!
I--I sold it to a pimp, Lester!
Say, what you waiting on?
Where the fuck can I find him?
Where can I find him?
I need to fucking know now!
Buckhill Cab, Union Street!
Ask them!
Stay here. Do not move.
I am not touching it.
Get away from me.
Fuck you!
The little shit!
He just bit me!
Who the hell is that?
I will go see. Throw me my robe.
Take the kids into the bedroom.
- May I help you?
- I am looking for Oleg.
Oleg? You must have
the wrong address.
No. He's a 10-year-old boy.
He's pale. He never smiles.
He's my neighbor's kid.
He called me
from this apartment.
Owens Park Lane, apartment 303.
Well, he must have given you
the wrong address...
or maybe you heard wrong.
There's no Oleg here.
He also said that he was
being held against his will.
That is ridiculous.
There's only my husband...
and my 2 children inside--
no one else. And it's late.
Well, I'd like to take
a little look inside...
just to satisfy my curiosity.
This is absurd.
What are you suggesting?
That I kidnapped Oleg?
Or you know what?
I am just going to call the police...
and I am going to stand here
for the next half-hour...
waiting for them to arrive...
when all's you got to do
is just let me in.
If you must.
Do you mind?
Go right ahead.
The children's room
is on the right.
They are asleep.
Please, go right in.
Hello.
Don't even ask.
It's too ridiculous.
Sorry. I am really embarrassed.
Excuse me, but I seriously doubt
he's hiding in there.
What's through here?
The playroom.
You guys got your own
little Disneyland in here.
Well, it's all about
the children...
and as you can see,
there's no Oleg.
I really hope that you find him.
You hear too many stories
these days.
God only knows
if it were our children.
Where are your children
photographs?
- Excuse me?
- Photographs.
No photographs.
If they were your children...
you would have
at least one photograph...
somewhere in this apartment.
This is ridiculous. We only
just moved into this place.
Everything's in storage.
Now, I really must
ask you to leave.
I insist!
Oleg?
What the hell
do you want me to do?
You let this bitch in here
in the first place.
All right? Right. OK.
Man. This is too much.
It's too much.
It's like some kind of a lure.
- You're making a mistake.
- Tell her to leave, Dez.
Ma'am, if you don't leave right now,
I am calling the police.
Call them. Call them.
And be sure to mention...
that you got 2 abducted
children in the next room.
2 children who don't appear in
any photographs in this house.
- This is insane.
- Where is Oleg?
How dare you suggest that we--
Where's the boy?
Where is he?!
God.
You better pray he's not dead.
Back off, you sick fuck.
Jesus. God help me.
Come on, come on...
I said back the fuck up...
you sick, twisted,
motherfucking cunt!
Holy God.
That's right.
That's right. Breathe.
You're going to be OK.
You're going to breathe now, Oleg.
I am right here. I am right here.
Just breathe. That's right.
OK.
Just cutting through wire.
Back off!
I said back off!
I will blow you away!
OK. OK, get up.
OK.
Go to the bedroom,
get the 2 kids.
Bring them downstairs.
Nicky's there.
All right? Wait with them. OK?
Move over.
Get out of his way.
No, I have got a safe
in the bedroom.
There's 100,000 cash
in there in diamonds.
All you got to do
is take the boy and walk away.
My God.
God.
No.
My God.
You sick fucks.
You're right. We're--we're sick.
We are. We're sick.
This is really great.
This is going to help us--
- Give me your phone.
- Please. Yeah.
- What are you doing?
- She wants the phone--
Who are you calling?
911. What is the nature
of your emergency?
I just heard shooting
across the hall.
1456 Owens Park Lane.
What is your name, ma'am?
You're not serious.
OK.
Hey. Hey, listen,
one of your cabs...
just picked up my brother
at Al's Automotive.
Yeah, well, listen--
listen to me.
I was supposed to pick him up,
but there's been a family emergency.
So what I need you to do
is I need you to find out...
where the cab
dropped him off at.
Yeah. Call me back.
My phone number's 555-7556.
Hello? Yeah.
Hey, wait, wait, wait.
Hey, calm down.
What happened to your face?
It's nothing.
I need to talk to you, Joe.
- Later.
- No. Now!
Why couldn't you just have
taken the kid and left?
taken the kid and left?!
I have never seen evil
before tonight, Joe.
Real fucking evil.
OK?
And I know that's not what I see
when I look in your eyes.
That's a lot, T.
I am trying to make a point here!
No, I know the point
you're trying to make!
I did not marry an evil man, OK?
I did not marry an evil man.
Shady, sleazy, mixed up with
the wrong kind of people...
but definitely not evil.
I know what you're
trying to say, T.
Do you?!
I hope so.
I have turned my back...
on a lot of things
since we have been married.
My eyes are wide open
on this one.
Nicky, go home with your ma.
Oleg, let's go take a ride.
What kind of music
do you listen to?
You listen to that techno shit?
You listen to rap music?
You like rap music?
They don't have
what I listen to on the radio.
Yeah, what's that?
Kvasha.
It's my mother's tape
from Russia.
What the fuck? Kvasha?
You're an American.
You weren't born in Russia.
What are you listening
to that shit for?
My mother said I started
in her belly in Russia.
So I am Russian.
You're not a fucking Russian.
You're an American. You know that.
because you were born
in the United States of America.
You're an American.
Say, "I am an American."
You say it.
I am an American.
You're an American. You were born
in the fucking United States of America.
That makes you an American.
Listen to this.
This guy right here is going to be
warming up the back seat for you...
when you're ready to get laid.
You mark my words.
* Oh, I know
that it's getting late...
Fucking Kvasha. Jesus Christ.
You put me through
the ringer tonight.
You know that, don't you?
I won't say nothing.
Yeah, and what about the cops?
What'd you say to them?
What did you say to them?
I told them I got the gun
from Steven Monroe's locker.
He doesn't go there no more.
Nicky told me to say that.
Nicky told you to say that?
Smart kid.
He's my best friend.
We're both going to play for the Razors.
Yeah. Hello?
Yeah, that was me.
The Royal Towers?
How long ago?
All right, thanks.
All right, kid. Hold on.
We're going to reclaim
some stolen property here.
Don't worry about it.
We're just going to sit tight
for a while.
You know...
I used to know this kid.
His old man was
a real fucking piece of shit.
Always drunk.
Always smacking him
and his mom around.
This kid, he takes his licks...
and he waits
this old fucking prick out.
And on the morning
of his 14th birthday...
he walks into his old man's room
with a baseball bat...
and he Mark McGwires the fucking
living shit out of him.
After that, the old man...
he can't even hold a spoon
without shaking.
He don't remember things
too good, either.
He's neutralized.
Which is a good thing.
4 more years max.
Maybe 3.
If you get some size early on...
you will be all right.
You just got to hang in there.
because it's more money.
It's lonely at the top.
I am telling you,
this corporation...
Get your hands off
of Lester's property.
- That's my property.
- I am sorry.
All right, you stay right there.
Don't you move.
Stay just like that.
Fuck.
Jesus Christ. Not now.
All right, let's get in the car.
I can hide it for you.
No, give it to me.
They're going to think you got the .38.
They're going to frisk you.
Come on, give me the fucking gun.
Yo, Joe.
Who you got there?
He's one of them
Christmas elves.
I found him hitching a ride
on Broad Street.
Joey's a funny fucking guy...
Let me take a guess, Joey--
you were just about to call us.
That's pretty good. You must
have telepathy or something.
Must. Give me your piece.
Think I am fucking around
with you?
How about that?
Cocked and ready to go.
What are you,
fucking nervous, tough guy?
You're going to follow us, Joey.
The kid will ride with us.
Stay the fuck in the car.
Yeah.
Nah, nah.
I am with him right now.
Yeah, 100%.
I fucking knew it.
Nah, don't worry about it.
I am taking care
of this motherfucker right now.
Come on, what the fuck?
What, are you going to
fucking whack me?
Come on, man,
I fucking told you.
You got any fucking doubts,
I am fucking telling you--
Shut your mouth.
Shut your fucking mouth now.
You see, my old man...
he says to me, "Nobody...
knows nobody."
Man, you fucking put
that piece of shit away.
I fucking told you,
on my fucking family--
Fucking family? When I leave here,
I am going to fuck Teresa in the ass.
That's how much I give a fuck
about your fucking family.
On my fucking family,
it ain't the fucking piece!
Now, how fucking far
do we go back?
How fucking long
have we known each other?
Come on, what the fuck?!
This is bullshit!
Like I said, nobody...
knows nobody.
You fucking take
that shit off me--
- Not in front of the fucking kid.
- What kid?
Not in front of the fucking--
You grab this fucking gun
out of my hand one more time...
I am going to blow your fucking brains
all over this fucking place...
and I will fuck that kid up
right in front of you!
You got that, nigger?!
Nobody knows nobody! You got that?!
Shit! What the fuck?!
Shit.
You see, Pop reached out
to a friend of ours in the department...
had him pull the paper
on Rydell's recent busts.
Turns out our friend Sal here...
was running his own little thing
on the side.
Hey, Sal.
How's fucking business?
A few weeks back,
Sal gets bagged...
by Rydell and his partners.
They let him walk...
as a situated informant.
We just got confirmation
10 minutes ago.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Get the fuck up.
Yeah.
He's alone?
Good. Give me
the fucking number.
Have a mai tai on me, guys.
One Nike gym bag--
60 bucks.
You motherfucking
guinea cocksuckers.
One Nokia cell phone--
100 bucks.
You have just fucked yourselves!
One ounce Semtex--
500 bucks.
Getting rid of a dirty cop--
Fucking priceless.
Now...
the jury's still out on you,
pal, so do me a favor.
Get your ass in that car
and follow me.
And hey, hey.
Don't get lost.
Where the fuck we going?
Come on down, come on down.
Let him go.
So, Oleg...
you want to see
something really cool?
It's called a jet ice.
Black light paint.
You got to do crazy shit
like this to fill the seats.
Now, Oleg,
this is very serious matter.
This man--
he give you the gun
to shoot Anzor?
Bullshit! He gave it to you!
He told you to whack me!
Stop fucking protecting him!
You shut the fuck up.
Oleg, you listen to me.
Where did you get gun?
At school.
I found it in a locker.
Don't you fucking touch him!
You don't fucking touch him!
I will fucking kill you!
You shut the fuck up!
Your turn is coming.
Yeah?
Well, fucking eat me!
You fucking vor cocksucking bitch!
Fuck you!
What you call me?
Nah, you fucking heard me.
Fuck you, you fucking bitch!
I am impressed. You know vor.
Vor v'zakoni.
The Brotherhood.
If you were smart man...
you would learn
to fear this symbol.
Yeah, well, fuck you, and fuck
your brotherhood, Boris...
because I don't have
to fucking answer to you!
Fuck you!
You going to let him muscle me around
like this, Frankie?
Well, we're just trying to
establish some truth here, Joe.
I mean, to be honest...
I think the man's got
some grounds for inquiry.
No, that's fucking bullshit.
I told you...
I didn't give the kid
the fucking piece.
Come on, Frankie!
Come on!
What the fuck, Frankie?!
I told you, I didn't give him
the fucking piece!
Don't you let them hurt
the fucking kid, Anzor!
Don't you fucking hurt the kid!
You fucks!
You fucking motherfuckers!
I am going to fucking kill you!
How's that feel, Joey?
Fuck you, Tommy!
Don't you do this, Frankie.
Don't you do it!
Don't you fucking
let them do this!
I am not fucking lying!
Fuck!
Just tell them
what they want to know!
Fuck! I told you
I didn't know anything, Frankie!
Fuck!
Shit, it's a fucking
human hockey puck.
I am going to fucking kill you!
You're going to kill me?
You're going to fucking kill me?
Give Anzor the gun.
Frankie, don't you fucking
let them do this!
Kill the kid.
Christ.
I am going to fucking kill you!
Don't you let them do this,
Frankie!
What do you want me to do?
You brought it on your goddamn self!
No. No. Wait, no!
Don't do it!
Joey...
I will fucking talk!
I will fucking tell you...
whatever you want
to fucking hear!
No, my friend!
First you will see
that I am serious.
Then afterwards, believe me,
you will talk!
No, come on!
Jesus Christ! I am fucking--
Don't you--
I will fucking talk!
I will tell you whatever
the fuck you want to hear...
you fucking motherfuckers!
Finish it!
Do it right this time!
No, Anzor!
Anzor, look at me!
Don't fucking do it!
Shut up!
I said finish it.
He's not your blood!
Don't fucking do it.
If you do it, I swear to God...
you better fucking
swallow a bullet.
There's no fucking way you're going to
be able to live with yourself!
Trust me, Anzor. Don't do it!
Say something bad about the Duke.
Let me hear you call him a faggot.
Come on.
Don't do it!
Say it.
Shoot him!
What are you fucking doing?!
Pick up the fucking gun.
You pick it up.
You do it.
Gutless piece of faggot shit!
Come on, faggot!
I said finish it!
Pick it up and use it.
Pick it up and do it.
Don't you fucking
walk away from me!
Get up...
you fuck.
Fucking bullshit.
Frank! Frank!
Fuck you, Frankie!
I ain't taking the fucking heat
for you no more!
It wasn't supposed
to go down this way!
What are you talking about?
The Czar of Brighton.
Vor whatever the fuck you are.
Fucking Perello
didn't like it...
that your nephew was cooking
a dealer in the neighborhood.
So he said--
he said, "Well,
let's send him a message."
He said, "Let's use the kid."
Yogi, would I put
our thing in jeopardy...
for some 2-bit fucking meth lab?
Think about it, OK?
That's number 1.
Number 2--I don't even live
in that fucking neighborhood!
What do I care if it blows up?
The gun--
it was Tommy's!
You fuck!
Tommy. Tommy, don't get involved
in their goddamn jackpot!
It's all bullshit!
He fucking put it
in my right hand!
A fucking snub nose .38,
stainless steel.
It was Tommy's gun!
You motherfucker.
I told you to get rid
of that fucking piece.
Yeah, well,
not to my fucking recollection!
He said...
"Interest the tweaker's kid
in the piece."
That's what he said.
"Interest the tweaker's kid
in the piece."
Ask the kid!
Ask the kid.
Mister, because he--
he gave me the gun.
He said I'd get to go to the game if--
if I shot Anzor...
and it would make
his friends happy.
I am sorry, kid.
OK. OK.
Fuck this bullshit.
Fuck you, Joey!
You fucking bastard!
You're fucking dead, nigger!
I am fucking shot!
You dancing bear motherfucker!
Fucking vor!
Scumbag!
You Russian cocksucker.
You son of a bitch!
Die, you fucker!
You die, motherfucker!
Where's the fucking gun?
Mr. Gazelle!
Fuck you.
Get off him, you fuck.
Do you know you got my son killed,
you fucking scumbag?!
Frankie, I am glad it's you
because there's something I have been--
I have really been meaning
to get off my chest.
You rat cocksucker.
All this fucking time?!
Yeah, this whole fucking time!
This whole fucking time!
And the only thing
we don't have...
is your finger on the trigger,
so fucking do me!
And it's one more nail
in your coffin.
You got all that, do you?
How come it took you
so fucking long, tough guy?
How come so fucking long?!
Tell me!
You had to climb in bed
with Yugorsky, didn't you?
I was all but out...
and you had to go mix up
with the fucking Russians.
12 years undercover...
and my own wife
don't even fucking know!
You cocksucker.
You don't have to worry.
She ain't never going to hear it
from your fucking lips anyhow...
you fucking scumbag!
I will tell her all about it
while she sucks my fucking dick!
Come on. Come on!
Are you fucking kidding me?
What are you going to do with that,
little boy?
Do you know that
I had a little boy?
My Tommy.
At one time, he was your age.
What are you going to do
with that, kid?
What are you going to do with that?
What are you going to do
with that...
you Cheerio-bred
little motherfucker?!
Let's go home.
In position!
All right, Johnny!
On the other side! Let's go!
Jesus Christ, Joey.
We got shorted out.
We lost you back at Newark.
Last thing we heard, you were
headed for Little Odessa.
Air support
finally made your Mustang.
I am taking the kid home
to his mom.
Joey, where you going?
You're hurt.
We got to get you to a hospital.
I am going home.
What are you thinking?
I don't want to go home.
Well, I am next door to you,
remember...
and I am going to be
keeping my eye on you.
Why don't we get
some breakfast...
before we have to start making
with the heavy explaining.
Get ourselves cleaned up a bit.
Hey, listen.
I am taking Nick to the game
on Friday night.
Maybe we could find you
another ticket.
If you'd like to go, that is.
All right, that's good.
You want to get some more
orange juice or something?
Right.
Well...
what do you say
we get out of here?
Well, lookie, lookie...
if it ain't
little Charlie Bronson.
One thing about Lester...
he always makes good
on a promise.
Hey, asshole.
Motherfucker!
Shoot that fuck!
Fuck him up!
Fucking piece of shit!
- Plug that asshole!
- Cocksucker!
Shit!
In your face, motherfucker!
Say hello to my little friend.
That's real fucking original.
What are you, a fucking cartoon?
I am a mack daddy pimp.
You know that.
And now I am going to cap your ass.
And when I am finished with you...
I am going to take
your little punk friend...
and I am going to put him
in my posse...
and I am going to pimp him out
for a couple of months.
And then I am going to take
that knife of yours...
and I am going to cut him
from ear to ear...
just like I should have done
yesterday, you fuck!
I am sure that sounds great to you all
in your fucking pimp world and all...
but, listen, right now...
that's not the fucking thing
you want to do!
You want to put down
that fucking gun...
and you want to walk away,
because I swear to fucking God...
I will fucking kill you,
you stupid fucking pimp bitch!
Wrong! Only one of us
is walking out of here.
- Guess who?
- Oleg, get behind me.
Oleg, get behind me!
Come on.
Oleg, talk to me. Come on.
OK, got to make it home now.
got to make it home.
Joey, please. You're bleeding.
I got some, see? I got some.
Come on! Fuck!
Fuck!
Look out!
Mr. Gazelle, stop the car.
We need to get some help.
Come on. Got to meet T.
- Please, Mr. Gazelle!
- I am coming home!
Mr. Gazelle, please,
stop the car.
We need to get some help.
- What's happened?
- You're hurt!
- We're going to make it home.
- Stop the car.
You're bleeding!
God.
Oh, God.
Nicky, stay back, stay back!
Mila.
Joey!
Joey, please! Stop!
Mr. Gazelle, come on, wake up!
Mr. Gazelle, wake up! Come on!
Stop the car, stop the car!
Please! Stop!
Joe! Come on!
Something's wrong! Let's go!
Joe!
Oleg, wait, wait!
- God.
- Mom! Mom!
- Joe!
- Mom!
- Fuck!
- Nicky, call 911!
Don't do this to me, Joe.
Don't fucking do this to me.
Sweetheart...
I loved you, OK?
Just remember I was always
stuck with Joey. OK?
Only once did I lie.
Shut up, shut up.
Look at me, look at me.
Hey, baby, look me in the eye.
Joey, look me in the eyes.
I don't care, OK?
It doesn't matter.
Whatever it is, I am going to
kick your ass over it later.
Stay with me, Joe.
Stay--look at me.
Look at me. I am right here.
I am right here for you.
Nicky! Nicky, come here!
Nicky! Nicky!
He's right here.
They're coming.
They're on their way.
OK.
We're still going to the game
Friday night, right, Dad?
I love you, Nick!
OK, he wants--he wants
to go to the game, baby.
Yeah. We're going to
go to the game.
We're going to fucking
kick their asses, right, Mom?
They are going down
big fucking time!
You--you have a bad mouth.
Yep. Yep.
It's not that bad. You will be OK.
Joe.
I am right here.
I am right here. I am right here.
Joe. Joe!
Joe?
Joe. God, no, don't!
God, no!
God! Joe!
Keep the kid outside.
I don't want him going in there.
Keep that boy over there.
We got to move in.
This guy's CPT.
Come on, let's move.
Subtitles: Arigon
Louise.
Good girl. How's it going?
George...
the alternator's in the car.
All right.
Don't ever ask me
to bury you again, Joe.
Hey.
So, what did they put
in that coffin really?
What?
- What did they put in that coffin?
- What'd they put in the coffin?
Yeah.
- Why? Did it seem kind of heavy?
- Yeah!
I don't know. I am thinking...
probably a couple of blue shirts.
Must have been Lashaub and McCall.
- That sound good?
- And Cavin.
And Cavin?
You want some of this, too?
For sure, Marishka.
Marishka?
You want some of this, too?
I am going to check
the both of you right now...
right in this house.
How about that?
Grab his head.