Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
Sue, don't misunderstand me, please.
I'm not complaining
about your work.
I have your latest piece,
and it's terrific.
But you were
due back yesterday.
But, Richard, there's one more
story I have to do.
There's always
one more story.
No, but listen to this.
Last month this guy
in the Northern Territory
was attacked by a crocodile.
It bit his leg off,
left him to die
100 miles from nowhere.
A week later,
he crawls away and disappears.
No interviews, no pictures.
So?
I tracked him down.
He runs a safari business
out of somewhere
called Walkabout Creek.
And his name-
Get this-
Michael J. "Crocodile" Dundee.
Even if it's for real,
it could take weeks
to nail him down.
Trust me.
I made arrangements
to meet him.
I've got a chopper meeting
the plane at Darwin tonight.
Well...
okay.
I really miss you, darling.
I miss you, too.
Take care now.
Don't worry.
I'm a New Yorker.
Hi. Walter Reilly,
Never- Never Safaris.
I'm Mr. Dundee's
business partner.
Nice meeting you, Mr. Reilly.
Oh, please, call me Walter.
We're pretty informal in the bush.
No, uh... Let me.
There you go.
You all right?
Yes.
I'm sorry Mr. Dundee
isn't here to meet you,
but he is here in town...
somewhere.
Welcome
to Walkabout Creek.
Oh, I took the liberty
of booking you into our hotel.
I trust that's in order?
Sounds just fine.
There's just
one other thing.
You did say that you were
prepared to pay the $2,500?
Absolutely.
I will see where he was
attacked and how he survived?
Miss, I assure you you'll spend
a few wonderful days here.
So tell me, what's
the side show all about?
That's just the boys
having fun and games.
Donk's never spilled a drop.
We're a pretty tough breed.
And your Mr. Dundee, does he -
No. He's very reserved.
He's a legend up here.
He was doing
a quiet spot of fishing,
when suddenly, bang-
This giant crocodile
came up,
turned him over,
bit half his leg off,
dragged him down under.
Killed it, of course.
Any normal man would have
turned up his toes and died.
But not our Mick.
Hundreds of miles...
snake- infested swamps...
on his hands and knees...
he crawled
right into Katherine.
Straight past the hospital
and into the first pub
for a beer.
That story's getting better
every time you tell it.
We handle ourselves pretty well
up here in the bush.
But if you're talking legend...
Oh, my God!
Two beers, Ida.
One for me,
one for me mate.
One for your mate,
you mad bugger.
Hang on.
I'm sorry if that
frightened you, Miss.
You see, it's stuffed.
Him and me both, Wal.
Michael J. "Crocodile" Dundee.
Never- Never Safaris.
Yeah. Never go out with us.
If you do, you'll never
come back. Right?
Sue Charlton, Newsday.
Yeah, I thought you might be.
Here, Wal. Mind Cyril for me
while I dance with
this charming young lady.
Legend has it a crocodile
took half your leg off.
A slight exaggeration.
Um...
more like a love bite really.
Enough about me leg.
Let me tell you
about the rest of me.
"Up north in the Never- Never,
"Where the land is harsh and bare,
"Lives a mighty hunter
named Mick Dundee
Who dances like Fred Astaire."
Smooth shag, eh?
Who did he say this clown was?
Mick Dundee.
He was grabbed
by a croc on the river.
Why was he there?
It's full of crocs.
What do you reckon
he was doing?
Just a bloody poacher, eh?
Listen, you do understand
I want you to take me out
where you were attacked,
show me how you survived.
Just the two of us
out there alone-
I've got me reputation
to consider.
Hey, you, Dundee.
Where can a man shoot
some crocs around here, eh?
How would I know,
shit - for - brains?
Just relax.
Now come on, Dundee.
Every man in the joint knows
you're a bloody croc poacher.
Oh, sorry about that.
I won't have anyone using
bad language in front of a lady.
Bad language?
Don't come back neither!
What was he saying
about you being a poacher?
He was just trying
to get a bite, that's all.
Donk, tonight's me lucky night.
Want a hit at the guts?
Here's a go, fellas.
Good on your Mick.
Give him
one of your kicks, Donk.
I'm sorry.
He's not normally like this.
I do apologize.
It's just the drink.
You mean there's
a serious side to him?
Hmm...
I can hardly wait.
Comfortable, Miss?
Wonderful country out here.
We think so.
I hope you're not going
to be the strong, silent type.
Me?
Reluctant to talk about yourself?
No. Favorite subject.
Why "Crocodile"?
Wal's idea.
He reckons it makes me more
colorful for the tourist business.
How old are you?
Don't know.
Uh, what year is this?
You don't know?
Time doesn't mean
much up here, Miss.
The aborigines
don't have calendars.
I was raised by the local tribe.
I asked a tribal elder
when I was born.
He said, "In the summertime."
Is there a Mrs. "Crocodile" Dundee?
I was sort of married once.
Nice girl. Good cook.
Big-
Mick!
I went off on walkabout.
When I came back, she'd gone.
A walkabout?
That's an aboriginal habit.
It means to wander around
and discover new places.
How long were you gone?
A couple of months.
Try 18.
And she didn't wait?
Strange girl.
Yeah.
Out of the way, Dopey!
Jesus.
That was amazing.
Mind over matter.
Old bushman's trick.
All right, Miss.
All ashore.
I'm going to leave you
in Mick's capable hands,
and I'll meet you at
the Echo Billabong on Wednesday.
2:20. We'd better get started.
2:20.
Yes. That's the way
we do it in the bush.
Don't worry. He's the best
bushman in the territory.
Best pupil I ever had.
You ready, lady?
Ready as I'll ever be.
Right, well, till Wednesday.
Cheerio.
Wednesday.
What's today, Wal?
Monday.
Doesn't know...
doesn't care.
Lucky bastard.
You okay, lady?
Oh, I'm fine.
It's only about another hour
to the river,
but you being a sheila,
it'll probably take two.
I'll do the best I can.
Yeah.
The water was running
20 foot up the bank
during the wet season.
Here's what's left of me boat.
You can see where
he sunk his teeth in.
My God.
How big was it?
Uh, 1 6, 1 8 foot, maybe.
You were out here
hunting crocodiles in that?
No. That's illegal.
I was just fishing.
How did you get away?
Crocs don't like fresh meat.
He wasn't trying to eat me.
He just wanted to take me
down for a death roll.
A croc will grab you,
take you down
to the bottom of the water,
and roll you over and over
till you stop kicking.
Then he'll take you
to his meat safe-
rock ledge, log-
down under the water,
jam you under it,
tenderize you a bit.
Good eating.
He let go to get
a better grip on me,
and I talked him out of it.
Talked?
And you were
just out here fishing?
Well, Barramundi's
a bloody big fish.
It'll be getting dark soon.
I'll take you to where
I camped the first night.
You married?
Was once...
to the original rebel.
What happened?
You name it, we marched-
Anti- Nuke, Women's Lib,
Save the Whales.
He's probably marching right now
for the Gay Nazis or something.
Sounds like a prize ratbag.
Oh, he meant well.
Haven't you ever protested anything?
Whenever I get
thrown out of the pub.
Come on. I'm serious.
Where would someone like you
stand on the nuclear debate?
What do you think
about the arms race?
None of my business.
None of your business?
How can you say that?
It's everybody's business.
Got to have an opinion.
Got to have a voice.
Who will hear it out here?
Okay.
Something closer to home.
The aborigines.
What do you think
about their claims
to get the land back?
Ah, well, you see...
aborigines don't own the land.
They belong to it.
It's like their mother.
See those rocks sticking up there?
Been standing up there
for 600 million years.
Still be there when you
and I are gone.
So arguing over
who owns them...
is like two fleas
arguing over who owns
the dog they live on.
You see, uh...
Uh...
Aborigines, well,
like all god's creatures,
want the right
to roam the earth
and be left in peace.
It's that si-
Oh, it's a King Brown.
Poisonous?
Oh, yeah. Deadly.
Not bad eating,
but they always give me gas.
Listen, are there any more
of those around?
Oh, maybe the odd one
late at night.
But stick close to me.
You'll be all right.
You're probably right.
A man should have an opinion.
Shh!
What?
Thought I heard something.
No. It's nothing.
Good night.
Mick?
It's only me.
Dangerous bastards.
It's those city cowboys.
What are you going to do?
Nothing. Why?
Why?
They're shooting these
poor kangaroos for fun.
There's no law against that.
Keep your head down.
Stay here.
Hang on. I need a piss.
Yeah, and a straighter rifle.
You're as useless
as tits on a bull.
Shh! Shut up, you guys.
Hey, Trevor.
Get the spotlight
over here, mate.
The spotlight!
Can't you see where
you're aiming?
Shut up!
Not on me, you silly bugger,
on the bushes.
Hey-
Hey, look at this
big, cheeky bugger.
It's got a gun!
Shit!
Good one, Skippy.
Despite the rugged beauty
of this land,
there's a sort
of strange emptiness about it,
a feeling of being so alone.
But you're not alone.
I'm here, aren't I?
Yeah, but I think I know
how you must have felt...
or how I'd feel
if I were out here alone.
You?
Out here alone?
That's a joke.
A city girl like you-
You wouldn't last five minutes.
This is a man's country
out here.
That's right.
I'm only a sheila.
We're heading for
that escarpment today, right?
Yeah.
Okay.
See you there this afternoon.
Hey!
Take the gun.
If you get into trouble,
fire a couple shots in the air.
That's the dangerous end.
So it is.
Hmm.
It's all right. It's over.
Hey. Hey.
I got you. I got you.
Is it dead?
Well, if it isn't,
it'll be hell
skinning the bastard.
Well, you were right.
Definitely no place
for a city girl.
From what Wal's told me,
living in the city can be
just as dangerous.
You've never lived in a city?
Never been to a city.
You're kidding.
No.
Cities are crowded, right?
If I lived in some city,
I'd only make it worse.
Here. Try this.
Want me to look at that?
It's just a scratch.
A scratch can turn septic
out here.
Shh.
Now what?
Oh, Christ.
It's like living with Davy Crockett.
Mick?
Mick.
Ah, Mick.
You frightened shit out of me.
I ought to.
Sneaking up on a man
rendering first aid to a lady.
Is that what you were doing?
It's a mate of mine.
Neville Bell, Sue Charlton.
G'day, Sue.
What are you doing
wandering around
in the scrub, Nev?
I'm going to a corroboree.
It's a bloody drag,
but my dad get angry
if I don't show up.
See, Nev's a real city boy,
but his dad's a tribal elder.
You can't take my photograph.
I'm sorry.
You believe it will take
your spirit away?
No. You got lens cap on.
Crikey, Mick.
I better get going.
Nice to meet you, Sue.
Bye, Nev.
I'll catch up with you.
What's happening?
I'll go with Nev
and have a chat
with the Pintinjarra.
Can I come?
No. Women are strictly taboo
at these turnouts.
How does he find
his way in the dark?
He thinks his way.
A lot of people believe
that they're telepathic.
Ooh!
God, I hate the bush.
How did you know?
Are you telepathic?
Nah.
Common sense.
You're a woman.
You're a reporter.
That makes you the biggest
busybody in the world.
I can live with that.
That croc was going
to eat me alive.
Oh, I wouldn't hold that
against him.
Same thought crossed
my mind once or twice.
Good night, Mick.
Mmm.
It took me a week
to crawl this far.
I thought I was a goner.
I said to meself,
"Mick, old son,
"find yourself
a comfortable spot
and lay down and die."
Weren't you afraid?
Dying? Nah.
I read the Bible once.
You know God and Jesus
and all them apostles?
They were all fishermen
just like me.
Yep. Straight to heaven
for Mick Dundee.
Yep.
Me and God...
we'd be mates.
This is Echo Lake.
I reckon this place saved me life.
That's mineral water.
Means no crocs.
More tucker here than you can
poke a stick at.
Tucker?
Food. You hungry?
I'm starving.
I'll get lunch.
How do you like your Goanna?
Medium? Well done?
You don't really expect me
to eat that.
Yeah. It's great.
Try those yams.
Try the grubs and ants.
Bite the end off.
They're sweet.
Black fellas love them.
What about you?
Aren't you having any?
Me?
Ah, well...
you can live on it...
but it tastes like shit.
Oh!
Mick, when I go back,
why don't you come along?
What for?
It would make a great wrap
to the story-
You in New York City.
Oh. For a minute there
I thought you were
making a pass at me.
Well, I might have been.
Would you mind?
Hoo- ooh!
Bloody Wally.
He's only been here
a dozen times.
He's probably lost.
Did you, uh...
You got wind
or something, Wally?
I want Mick to come to New York.
Mick? In a big city?
No chance.
Paper would pay.
Well, a man should
broaden his horizons.
Everything okay?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
No worries.
Jesus Christ!
Sue!
G'day, mate!
You look absolutely stunning.
Welcome home.
Thanks.
Here, let me get this.
Oh-
Where's the man
from the backwoods?
We got separated at customs.
He almost started a riot
when they wanted
to search his suitcase.
Ah, there he is.
So, that's Jungle Jim.
New York City, Mr. Dundee.
Home to seven million people.
That's incredible.
Imagine seven million people
all wanting
to live together.
Yep. New York must be
the friendliest place on earth.
Watch it.
G'day!
Mick Dundee from Australia.
How are you?
I'm fine. How are you?
Good. I'm down
for a couple of days.
Probably see you around.
Fine.
We went from there-
Thank you, Gus.
You'll take care of the luggage?
Yes, sir.
That's it.
Thanks for the lift, mate.
No problem.
What tribe are you, Gus?
Tribe?
Man, I ain't from no tribe.
You're a black fellow, aren't you?
Last time I looked.
Nobody in our tribe
has a car like this.
You must be doing
all right, eh?
I'll get a cab to the office.
Do you want to eat
somewhere special tonight?
I thought Tacano's
would be nice.
Tacano's. 7:30?
Mm- hmm. Great.
Bye.
O.K. Table for three.
Sir.
No worries.
Well, what do you think?
Oh, it's a bit rough,
but I'll manage.
Hey, how many of us staying here?
Just you.
I've got my own
apartment downtown.
Oh, sorry. Mick Dundee.
I didn't catch the name.
Angelo.
Pleased to meet you, Angelo.
I got it.
Here you go.
Got to pay for the room
in advance, eh?
You're in my town now.
Trust me.
Yeah.
Can I get the direct dialing
code for Australia?
You should be comfortable.
Everything's here.
There's a TV if you're bored.
Ah, television.
Yeah, I saw that at
Darkie Johnson's place years ago.
Yep. That's what I saw.
Right.
Okay. Thanks.
So, I'm writing down
Wally's number
and my office number.
Hey, Sue!
Come here. Look at this.
Some nitwit's put
two dunnies in here.
One dunny, one bidet.
Bidet?
Mmm. It's for, um...
After you - You, um -
You know.
You figure it out.
See you at 7:00.
Yeah.
For washing your backside, right?
G'day.
Hi.
Hello.
G'day.
Oops. Sorry.
Whoops.
Shit!
Take it easy, Mick.
Thanks, mate.
Ta.
Bye.
G'day.
Yes, sir.
Good evening.
Follow me, please.
Hello.
Sorry we're late.
Been waiting long?
I arrived early,
eager to spend time
with my girl.
What are we drinking?
Two vodka Martinis.
And what's yours, Crocodile?
Yeah, I'll have two of those
and a beer, thanks.
Could you send them through
to our table, man.
You have been here a while.
Let's eat.
This will be quite
a novelty for you,
eating something
without having to kill it first.
Shall we?
Ah, Roberto.
Good evening, Mr. Mason.
I see you've brought some friends.
Follow me, please.
Thank you.
I had almost forgotten
how sexy- looking you are.
I'll have to find a way
of keeping you in town.
We'll work something out.
Really? Yes, what?
Listen, uh- You two
should really be alone.
Sorry. We haven't seen
each other in six weeks.
All the more reason-
I wouldn't abandon you
your first night here.
Richard and I
want you with us.
Right. Absolutely.
New York is no place
for a country gent.
I mean, ain't no
crocodiles out there,
but a fast- moving Chevy
would sure make a mess of you.
What's your game?
Great. I'm starving.
Ha ha!
Grazie, Roberto.
Stato piacere rivederti.
Bravissimo. Lei parla
molto bene Italiano.
Thank you.
Um, perhaps I should
order for all of us.
I don't imagine
that they have any...
kangaroo steak or possum grits!
Don't worry about Mick.
He can make a gourmet meal
out of just about anything...
even medium- rare Goanna.
It was great, wasn't it, eh?
And what about the yams?
Oh, they were great.
Well, that's-
That's wonderful.
So, as he's our guest,
perhaps he'd like
to order for all of us.
Oh, wait a minute.
I'll do that.
No, it's- it's all right.
I'll have a lash.
Italian, eh?
Yes.
I don't know what you call it,
but I'd like that dish
the big fat sheila's eating.
Richard!
He okay?
Can't handle his drink, poor fella.
He said you hit him.
You're not in the
Walkabout Creek pub now.
He was being a pain.
That's beside the point.
You're not serious
about this lemon, are you?
Butt out, Dundee!
He had a little
too much to drink.
Richard is warm, caring,
and I love him.
Excuse me.
What?
I'm going to throw up.
God.
You want a hand?
No. I can handle it.
I'm fine.
We've got a busy day tomorrow,
so get some sleep.
I'll pick you up early.
Good night.
Night.
You better take me
to the boozer.
Boozer?
Don't know that one.
Pub. You know,
somewhere to get a drink.
Want to join me?
I just finished my shift.
Why not?
Fancy a drink, do you?
You kidding? I'm Italian.
I'd drink you under the table
any day, my friend.
Well, that could be interesting.
Now, I'm not putting down
your black widow spider,
but the funnel web spider
can kill a man
in eight seconds
just by looking at him.
Of course, the real danger
down there is the sharks-
The big ones,
you know, like Jaws?
I caught one three weeks ago,
opened it, and found
three Filipino fishermen,
still in their boat.
Hey, Buzzy!
Come on over.
Meet this guy from Australia.
Hey, my man,
what's happening?
Uh, where?
What's goin' down, bro'?
Goin' down?
Oh, yeah.
Just blowing the froth off a couple.
All right!
Hang loose, my man.
Flat out like
a lizard drinking.
Say what?
What?
He's cool.
Yeah. I'm cool. I'm cool.
All right!
He's a nice fella.
Here's me little
Italian mate Danny.
Just in time to buy
another round, mate.
What are you drinking,
Gwendoline?
No more.
I must be getting home.
Oh. Where's home, sweetie?
Just around the corner.
I have a little place
where I live all by my lonesome.
Not now.
Most of the time, that is.
Oh. Must get a bit lonely, eh?
Hanker for a bit of,
uh, male company?
Do I ever.
Hey, come here.
Uh, excuse me, Gwendoline.
Don't go away, love.
I been trying
to tell you all night.
That girl. She's a guy.
Huh?
A man dressed up as a girl.
Nah, nah.
A fag, for Christ sakes!
I swear.
Ooh!
That was a guy.
A guy dressed up like a sheila.
Hey, you all knew,
you pack of bastards.
Hey! Ahh!
Where the hell did
I leave the cab?
Don't know.
You wait here till
I go look for it.
Righto, mate.
Stay there.
G'day, girls.
Mick Dundee from Australia.
Looking for a good time, honey?
Always looking for a good time.
Are either of you, uh... ladies
attached or married
or anything?
No. We're both single ladies.
This is Karla. I'm Simone.
Where you from, honey?
I'm from Walkabout Creek
in the Northern Territory.
You probably don't know
where that is.
Hey, I do.
You're the guy I've been
reading about in the paper.
The crocodile man.
I've been reading
about him in the paper.
He's like a regular Tarzan-
Wrestles crocodiles,
eats snakes.
Is this your first trip
to New York?
First trip anywhere.
Well, hell.
We might just have
to give you one for free.
Yeah.
One what?
Ah, maybe we could
take in a movie
or go to a dance.
Hey, girls, girls.
Are we working tonight
or are we socializing?
Hey, pal.
I was talking to the ladies
and making progress.
Are you going to talk all night
or screw one of them?
I'm sorry about that,
but if you stand around
a place like this,
you'll hear that kind
of bad language.
I should've been home hours ago.
Nice chatting to you, ladies.
You're in no condition to drive.
Hop in, mate.
That's why you have
so many accidents over here-
The steering wheel's
on the wrong side of the car.
Get out of the way, Dopey!
Get on the right side
of the road, you pelican!
If I give my heart to you
Then I'll have none,
and you'll have two
Senor Mick?
The towels for Senor Mick.
Is that you, Rosita?
Just leave the spare towels
on the bed, will you?
Mucho gracias, love.
Si, Senor Mick.
'Struth!
Um... Hey, listen, uh...
Rosita, uh-
I was only being friendly.
You know, I didn't mean, um-
Your towels, Senor Mick.
Oh. Whew.
For a minute there,
room service took on
a whole new meaning.
Whew.
One dog, please.
With chili, onions, sauerkraut,
and some peppers.
There you go.
You eat that?
Well, you know,
you can live on it,
but it tastes like shit.
Ahh!
Aah! My bag!
Stop him!
Thief! Thief!
I can't believe that
you're alone in here
Let me warm your hands
against the cold
A close encounter
with a hardhearted man
Who never gave half
of what he got
Has made you wish that
you had never been born
That's a shame
'cause you've got a lot
Fate left you
with a sad face
Come up to my place
and give it up
You beside me
Hey, Mick!
How you doing, baby?
It's me- Simone!
Oh, yeah, Simone.
Having a good time?
As always.
Nice girl.
Thoughtful, too-
Dancing with her father.
Hmm.
We're going to have to overcome
this country boy shyness, Dundee.
Hi.
Yeah.
Oh, there's someone
I want you to meet.
Ah! Sue, darling!
You're back.
How wonderful.
Fran, how are you?
Couldn't be better.
Tell me.
Who's the new man?
This is the man I'm writing
about, Mick Dundee.
Something the matter, darling?
Oh!
Pleased to meet you.
It's okay.
He's Australian.
Maybe I'd better go there someday.
Oh, darling, I'm so glad
you could come.
Excuse me.
Ah.Just making sure.
Right.
I'll get us a drink.
How can you see
Looking through
those tears
Don't you know you're
worth your weight in gold
I can't believe
That you're alone in here
Let me warm your hands
against the cold
If you smile
You'll walk on out
On all the people
in this pickup joint
But if you laugh
You'll level this town
Hey, look, girl
That's just the point
Hey there,
beautiful sad face
Come up to my place
And give it up
It's good shit.
Let's get it on
It's a different world
But the heat's the same
Head of New York City
Do you know my name
What more could I ask for?
Don't make me ask
Don't
One day I might get there
I turned around
If you had looked
You'd know there's something
Bothering me
What's up, pal?
Got a blocked nose?
Blocked nose, right.
There's a better way
of doing it than that.
Better way, huh?
Yep.
It's the way we do it back home.
It really fixes us up.
Now. Boiling water.
Get the steam going right.
Get
your face right over there.
The old tea towel
right over your skull.
Put your head
right down onto that.
Breathe in real deep.
Ten minutes of that,
you'll be clear as a bell.
No worries.
Get into it.
You know, Mick,
that was probably
a couple hundred dollars
worth of cocaine.
What's that?
It's a drug.
You sniff it.
What for?
Well, to get a buzz.
What, like shoving
a blowfly up your nose?
Got the photo, Mick.
I look great.
Ha ha ha ha!
Ida sends love.
Wait a minute.
Donk wants a word to you.
Mick!
Get stuffed!
Ha ha ha.
Very good.
How you getting on
with the New Yorkers?
Oh, bonzer people.
Friendly, full of beans,
but, uh- a bit weird.
Well, that's the joys of traveling.
When are you
coming home, mate?
If you can manage,
I'll stay a while.
Oh, yeah.
No troubles at all.
Wouldn't have anything to do
with a certain lady writer,
would it?
To start with, she's
a better kisser than Donk.
You little beauty.
Keep in touch.
Yeah. No worries, Wal.
Ta ta.
What'd he say?
Well, he wants to stay there
a while longer.
Wants me to take
care of things here.
You got a light, buddy?
Yeah. Sure, kid.
There you go.
And your wallet.
Mick, give him your wallet.
What for?
He's got a knife.
Ha ha ha.
That's not a knife.
That's a knife.
Shit!
Just kids having fun.
Are you all right?
I'm always all right
when I'm with you, Dundee.
God, that sounds corny.
Why do you make me feel
like Jane in a Tarzan comic?
Ah! Ah!
That's what we ran
while you were Down Under.
Sorry. Can't seem
to get my mind in gear.
Sue, when you were away,
I, uh-
I did some thinking.
It's time I made
some concrete plans.
Are you building a freeway
or proposing to New York State's
finest catch?
Hello, young lady.
Been reading your articles.
It seems you've been
tripping all over the world
at our expense.
I'd like to think you're getting
your money's worth.
Hi, Dad.
You got a kiss
for the old man?
Thank God
you're home safe.
Have you told Sue about Sunday?
I was just about to.
You're coming to
the weekend house for dinner.
Right now, Richard
can explain
how he runs this newspaper
better than I do
when I'm away.
Bring along this
Crocodile Dundee.
Him, I've got to meet.
Thought you said
your dad sells newspapers.
Oh, well-
He sells a lot of newspapers.
Thank you, Gus.
Oh, hell.
The dogs are out.
Mick.
Nice to see you again, Miss.
Mr. Mason.
Good to see you
looking so fit and well.
Simpson, Mr. Dundee.
Nice to meet you, Simo.
Call me Mick.
Mick.
Your father's expecting you, Miss.
He's waiting with his guests
in the lounge.
And she was in great danger-
Oh, excuse me.
Hiya, pumpkin.
Hi, Dad.
Richard.
Good to see you.
This must be Mr. Dundee.
Yep.
I'm in your debt
for saving Sue's life.
Buy me a beer,
and we'll call it quits.
Nice joint you got.
Well, it keeps
the rain off our heads.
Come. I want you
to meet some people.
Patricia, a drink
for Mr. Dundee.
Oh, my God, look who's here.
My, uh- Dawn.
How are you?
Dorothy and Wendell Wainright.
From Australia.
Nice to meet you, Wendell.
Have a drink.
Thank you.
Are you involved in cattle?
Yeah. Mostly buffaloes.
Oh. Do you breed them?
No, just toss them.
And how are you finding New York?
Bit of a lunatic asylum, eh?
That's why I love it.
I fit right in.
If you'll excuse me,
I'd like to introduce Mick
to Senator Manly.
Nice meeting you.
See you later.
Seems like a personable fellow.
What a strange gentleman.
Nice people.
Dorothy's fine now,
but she used to be really uptight.
What happened?
She found a wonderful shrink.
Psychiatrist.
I shouldn't have made that crack
about the lunatic asylum.
Didn't know she was nuts.
Of course she's not nuts.
People go to a psychiatrist
to discuss problems.
She just needed
to unload them.
You know, bring them
out in the open.
Hasn't she got any mates?
You're right. We could
all use more mates.
You don't have shrinks
at Walkabout Creek?
If you got a problem,
you tell Wally.
He tells everyone in town,
brings it out in the open,
no more problem.
Richard!
Wendell, it's wonderful seeing you.
I don't believe I know your daughter.
Oh, stop it!
Oh, Richard!
Ladies and gentlemen...
friends.
Welcome home, Sue.
As you can see,
we're all glad
to have you back.
Of course, no one more than I.
I guess everyone in this room
knows how this beautiful lady and I
feel about each other.
Sue's come back to us,
delivered, literally,
out of the jaws of death
by our newfound friend,
Mr. Michael J. Dundee.
A man to whom
I am doubly indebted.
Not only did he bring back
the woman I love,
he increased
the newspaper's circulation.
Sam said to me earlier,
"You're her editor.
"Can't you stop her
from taking all these
dangerous assignments?"
Obviously, I haven't had
a great deal of success
influencing her as her editor.
Perhaps I'll have more success
as her husband.
If she'll have me.
Oh, Richard.
Congratulations.
It's a pleasure having you here.
Well done.
I couldn't have done it
without your help.
Sweetheart?
I'll get in the back, Gus.
The hotel, Mick?
Yeah, Gus.
By way of a liquor store.
For medicinal purposes.
Thanks, mate.
Hey, you take care now.
Hey, buddy.
Get it into you, Pop.
God bless you.
You saved my life, really.
Hey, Simone.
You want some action?
Uh, I thought you were
somebody else.
Well, if it ain't the man
who don't like bad fuckin'
language in front of ladies.
What's the matter, Aussie Boy?
You going to hop away
like a kangaroo?
Time for a little tap dance.
You okay, Mick?
Oh, yeah, Gus.
No worries.
I was just getting
on top of them.
You sure you're not
Pintinjarra tribe?
No, man.
Harlem Warlords.
I knew you were tribal.
Mick Dundee's room, please.
I'm sorry.
He's still not answering.
He said this morning
he was checking out today.
We're going to miss him
around here.
Thanks.
Thank you, sir.
G'day, Irving.
How are you, mate?
I wouldn't be dead for dollars.
Close.
Are you going back home?
Ah, no. I thought
I'd go walkabout.
Uh...
I'll wander around,
look at America.
For how long?
Long as it takes.
What's the quickest way
out of town?
If you're looking for adventure,
a subway two blocks that way
will take you
to Grand Central Station.
That'll do.
Have a nice day, "Oiving."
No worries, mate.
Morning, Miss.
Morning.
Are you sure you know
what you're doing?
No, but it will come to me.
If you're looking
for Crocodile Mick,
he's gone walkabout.
Do you know where?
He's headed for the subway
two blocks down.
You'd better hurry.
Mind this for me.
Oh, Christ!
Hey, lady, where you going?
If you want to play,
play with me.
Mick!
Mick Dundee!
Ooowweee!
What's up, lady?
I got to talk to that man
down the end.
The one in the black hat.
Hey!
Lady wants to talk
to the guy in the black hat!
Hey, fella!
You in the hat!
The lady down the end
wants to see you!
What does she want?
What do you want?
Tell him not to leave.
I'm not going to
marry Richard.
Tell him don't leave.
She's not going
to marry Richard.
Don't leave.
I'm not going to marry Richard.
Why not?
I don't know.
Tell him I love him.
I love you!
I love ya!
She loves me.
Well?
Um, tell her-
I'll tell her meself.
I'm coming through.
He's coming through!
It's too crowded.
We're jammed in like sheep.
Up, up, up.