We are never infinitely far from those whom we hate.
For the same reason,
we will never be quite close to those we love.
An atrocious principle
I already knew when I embarked.
But there are truths that deserve our attention,
and there are others that it is better to work around them.
We set sail 67 days ago.
September, 1914.
The matches are not much help on deck.
Thank you.
There you are their island.  Look, do you see it?
What is fleeing?
That was the first thing they asked me when I decided to get to the sea.
Prepare to lead anchors.
You can do a person, not two.
Do not listen, Russian.
Watch out for back there, not wet.
Careful with that.  That you can not drop anything.
C'mon C'mon.
No birds.
Or meteorologist to welcome him.
Captain, where did we leave things Officer airs and winds?
Here.
Tell the others not bring other supplies.
No, that they may bring.
With all due respect, it's my responsibility to get well
and this is not very reassuring.
You have already done their duty.
It should be understood as a kindness
Captain accompany me to the mainland.
Nothing forced him to it.
But throughout the trip, we started understanding
that sometimes arise between men of different generations.
The captain always treated me with courtesy of an executioner.
If I could do something for me, I would.
GRUNER OWNS THIS SOURCE
Guys, go back to the boat.
Is there someone?
¡Abra!
Can you hear me?
Hello!
Hello?
Hey!  Awakes.
Go for water, toadface.
Wake up!
Technician maritime signals,
I bring over from meteorologist, Aldor Vigeland.
Can you tell me where it is?
I said that is where the meteorologist.
Listen, I am the captain of a ship in transit,
I have digressed to bring it here
and take me to his predecessor.
Where is...?
Typhus.
Is dead?
You do snuff?  Vodka?
Where are his remains?
For God's sake, speak!
He left one day and already I have not seen him since.
For the love of God, is an island!
How much could have been removed?
Swimming ¿?
Your name?
Gruner.
Do you like Frazer?
The book is not mine.
You, you have snuff?
Above, no.
Sr. Gruner.
Captain,
I appreciate your concern but I will not return.
Take this.
Do not confuse stubbornness with stupidity.
I'll manage me.
Thank you for everything you have done.
Eat well.
I worked a lot.
Keep busy.
Good winds.
And best seas.
For twelve months would have to live there,
in a solitude of exile,
far from any civilized coast,
with such monotonous work as insignificant:
record the intensity and direction of winds.
HEIR TO THE THRONE THE AUSTRIAN, ASESlNADO
THE MURDER OF ARCHlDUQUE FERDlNAND FRANZ AND HIS WIFE
OFIClAL METEOROLOGICAL ALDOR VIGELAND
BOOK INClDENCIAS, GRAClA YEAR 1913
MARlNA REAL OF GREAT BRITAIN AND UNITED KINGDOM
MRS. VlGELAND LOVE, LOVE, LOVE
DARWlN WAS WRONG
Sr. Gruner.
Mr. Gruner, if this is your way to Init ...
Open the door!
Let me in.
¡Gruner!
- Please, let me in! - he should have stayed on the boat.
When fear overwhelms me that I can die,
without having my pen reaped the fruits of my soul
nor lift up my books stacked
as in the barn the mature grain.
When I look on the face starry night,
large cloud symbols of a high legend,
and I think I never live to trace their shadows
with maga hand of fate;
and when I feel, fair creature of an instant,
that I can never look at you
or enjoy the magical power of passionate love,
then, at the edge of the vast world I am alone
and I think until love and glory sink into nothingness.
Holy Virgin!
¡No!
- Do not shoot! - Put the gun down!
¡Bájela!
Behind!
What does he want?
Really I have to explain?
You said you had snuff?
Yes.
¿Café?
- Vodka? - Geneva.
And ammunition.
What caliber?
I have more.
- It's harmless. - lnofensiva?
They come here, come ... here.
Come on.
¿Lo ve?
I think I'll call Friend.
You've been bitten.
I've burned.
- How many killed? - I do not know.
The official meteorological old ...
It was not typhus.
He left lying here like me.
- counts as murder. - We have to go.
Come on!
Already it does not hurt?
- How long was I asleep? - I reckon a day or two.
It has been peed on.
1862.
That's what I call an arsenal.
That makes?
Petite stupid. He believes things will fly ...
- You can talk to the animals. - Speak not, order.
Do not try to escape?
¿Huye a dog in the most cruel master?
Is incredible.
I never imagined that something like this could exist.
We know it's a small island in the great ocean with something unknown.
I have read that there are atolls with unique and endemic fish species
which they have evolved completely freely.
The species that survived were in isolation.
They have been trapped in a sort of evolutionary stagnation.
Perhaps these beasts are well, not quite human
or amphibian or reptile or ictícolas.
She is not like the others, right?
This does not bite, that's all.
And what about that scar on your shoulder?
He did once, the only time.
He learned the lesson.
Remember,
Mansa below the current water is worse.
I have adjusted the mechanism to track the coast.
For all I know, the face of toads like all hell beasts
avoid light, human or divine.
- They are demons of Atlantis. - I believe in what I see.
The only thing I can not understand
It is that it could have run 4 days ago on the ship that brought me here.
- Run away where? - the civilized world.
Nice place that yours civilized world.
So why did he quit?
Here I am the master of my destiny against all odds.
Well, you can keep it. I will sign the first ship to pass.
Really?
This island is not in any commercial maritime route,
the next boat will bring his replacement.
Come on, Gruner.
The headlights are built where naval traffic.
And to balance the budgets of the Navy and divert funds.
You have to empty a bucket before filling it again.
It is the second time in a week that I am forced to rebuild my life.
All my belongings are burned.
I have nothing left of the person you used to be.
In this remote part of the world, I feel an irreparable loss.
I do not know if it is a manifestation of nostalgia for civilization,
SEPTEMBER 2, 1914
panic a prisoner or,
simply fear.
Do not! Do not eat it!
It is not edible.
It is a bird...
Friend,
take his rifle.
Do not fire until they reach the tower and do not waste bullets wounded.
Give them enough carrion and devour each other.
I see nothing.
And you learn what to look for.
Come on!
Shoot, man! Use your weapon!
Come on! Shoot!
You are welcome!
Nobody is an island.
What a stupid thing.
Gruner is an island.
Gruner does not need a charge.
As much chocolate and coffee that has brought miedica.
Go to water.
Last chance!
Companies.
Firm hold.
I waited.
Companies.
Prepared.
Behind him.
Wake up, man! Wake up! Shoot, dammit! Shoot!
It's your last chance!
Do not close, Gruner!
No, Gruner! I waited! Do not!
Let me go!
¡Gruner!
Let me go! Gruner!
Between Gruner and a curious coexistence prevailed
based on the routine.
The monsters always appear in packs at night
and they expand their attacks more and more every day.
The Japanese philosopher Musashi said
they are few who appreciate the art of war.
OCTOBER
Good fighter is not defined by the cause he defends,
but by the sense that knows how to extract the fight.
The days are always the same,
at daybreak drop guard on the balcony.
I sleep as much as I ask nature.
I have to accept the most thankless tasks
just to keep my place in the lighthouse.
I've been pondering the reason that brought me to this island.
He had been seeking peace of nowhere,
and instead of silence, I found a monster-ridden hell.
It smells funny.
- How do you know that are not weeds? - Herbs are like people.
They are neither good nor bad, are known or not, that's all.
Herbs not slaughtered him for money.
A farmer raises cows.
Cares for, feeds them, gives them endearing names
Margarita.
But then steals your milk
and kill their young.
Another riddle.
It is a matter of necessity.
Did not it occur to you that could be what attracts your bellowing beasts?
So why do they attack some nights and not others?
And why he would appeal to his blood to die on the rocks?
All you have to understand
It is that we are the invaders
and that make us the enemy.
Kill and conquer, that's what humans do.
Wants to conquer, is that it?
Oh, no, I destroy them.
We need more wood.
Why?
For weeks they have not attacked us.
He likes to sleep in my lighthouse.
Marchito.
In the distance.
Dissolved.
And quite forgotten.
My gaze has traveled a thousand times all surfaces.
We talk about Lighthouse domains as a province.
Every nook and cranny has its name.
Every rock,
each stone.
Perhaps like whales migrate in winter.
Or maybe the creatures have figured out that they can not defeat us.
They are beasts.
They are out there to multiply for your next attack.
It's up to guard.
Often, strange,
breaks between attacks are worse than the attacks themselves.
This parenthesis is accompanied by the change of attitude of the pet.
How could Gruner fornicate
with one of those same monsters that beset us every night?
How could justify the act
defying all obstacles established by civilization
and established by nature?
How could closer
and more
and not feel repulsed by her cold skin?
I decided to give it a name.
Aneri.
Down!
- When the potatoes are finished? - They were not finished, it's you're drinking.
Play?
What civilized man does not?
These beasts are fascinating species.
Blood, for example,
guessing they share properties
some Arctic fish
having as an antifreeze that helps them survive below zero.
Have you noticed that have two sets of eyelids?
The first is very similar to ours,
but the second is a transparent membrane
who is helpful when immersed, I imagine.
We could capture some specimens,
take them back to Britain or the United States,
present our discovery and we recognize ...
Okay, you've convinced me.
I have come to this damn world to become famous, okay?
Check! Shut up and play.
Checkmate.
No, it can not be.
- Can not be. - Calm down, Gruner, it's just a game.
- Reyes, peons ... - It can not be.
We have forgotten light. The upstairs balcony.
Come on, there are too many. There are too many.
So, what can we do now?
A Starry Night
While sleeping;
while she is lying in bed.
I dreamed I was listening
the wagon wheels screeching.
Molly Ban, darling,
come to bed.
Look at us, we can not survive another assault like that.
We are running out of supplies,
we're running out of ammo, we are running out of free will.
Where are you going?
What happen?
There is a boat.
¡No!
Gruner knows how to defend himself.
Gruner rules the world.
Gruner want what you have and only has what he wants.
Ungrateful little beast.
- Stay away. - Gruner, please.
No more people.
I see what you are.
A pitiful and ridiculous attempt failed misanthrope.
It is too scared to let go of his friends.
It is too scared to kill their enemies.
Scares you have no one to hate.
Do not you dare leave! Do you hear me?
Damn you, toadface.
Look.
What did you do this time?
Call
ship.
You see it?
What?
I found a boat.
Already knew.
Sorry, as it says? Why did you not tell me?
would not serve. Certainly I go out of my island,
but it would be attacked by hypothermia, hunger, a storm.
Most likely it ends up as food for frogs face,
but hey, who am I to deny the right to choose how you want to die?
- Where he came from? - It was the Portuguese.
- A wreck? - A big storm
It caused a disgrace overnight.
I'm sure he did everything he could to save them.
I did what I could.
Those who came ashore tried to reach the lighthouse.
There was nothing left of them in the morning. They were dragged back to the bottom.
What were you doing so far from trade routes?
It was an illegal boat. Bootleggers dynamite.
I found some boxes that were washed ashore.
But do not work, are flooded by water.
- He wants to dive to the ship. - and retrieve dynamite.
We repaired the boat and set off when the tide when it is safer.
He's an idiot.
What he does not like to blow a thousand toads face the air?
It's a suicide mission, I will not dive into that water.
He is afraid?
I will do.
- I just need to pump me air. - It will not work.
I'm talking about the extermination of frogs face.
No.
I've changed my mind.
We left right away.
Remember, a rope pull, everything goes well.
Two, cargo is subject.
Three...
Three reme with all his strength.
The second line is too close to the lighthouse.
At this distance, the toads will face tight,
like a can of sardines.
We end up perched on the Leaning Tower of Pisa
The austral summer is extinguished shyly, but with magnificence.
Now we move inexorably towards winter,
or rather, into the darkness.
Time is a relative idea.
Droplets suspended in a cobweb can take ages to fall.
Sometimes, however,
one week passes in a blink of an eye.
Between.
Three weeks. Three weeks and nothing.
- We can not eat that crap. - Gruner.
It was ratted. You are what you told your friends, huh?
You've warned them, right?
Toadface damn spy.
So you pay me, huh? Damn ungrateful!
How dare you leave me! How dare you!
Lnténtalo again!
They tend an ambush,
We leave the door open and we attract to come,
deals with them on the stairs
and triggered the detonator when they are close enough.
Gruner, Babel is open.
- And the lanterns? - Ignitions.
C'mon C'mon. ¡Sing!
Sing! ¡Canta cena para you! Sing!
Sing! Sing!
They're inside!
They are already here!
It does not work!
The connection!
Crouch!
¡No, Gruner...!
Gruner.
Gruner, can you hear me?
Under the vast starry sky,
Dig the grave and let me lie there.
I lived happily and gladly die,
I slept with one last wish.
Use your knife, do not waste ammunition.
Look what we've done.
It will do that for a while.
It will not stop mourn that way.
So I found,
He had been entangled.
They seem so cute like that, right?
But change.
I freed myself, I saved his life.
He'll come crawling back.
He always does.
They are mourning.
Look at this,
It is magnificent.
We have to keep up appearances with new and more powerful weapons.
We must continue metiéndoles fear.
I see you, king of the toads face!
Not hurt them, Gruner.
They just want a truce.
Gruner, lower the gun, show you do not want to hurt them.
We were wrong.
Gruner, we were wrong.
Go inside.
I've said in!
Do not leave Me.
Nobody leaves. Nobody leaves.
I am leaving. Nobody leaves Gruner.
Dont leave me,
do not let me, let me ... no.
Nobody leaves Gruner.
Gruner leaves, Gruner leaves.
Gruner leaves.
Nobody leaves Gruner, no. Gruner leaves.
No one Gruner Stop! Gruner leaves.
Wait.
¡Gruner!
Aldor Vigeland, is not a murderer!
Love,
love,
love...
Sr. Gruner.
Gruner technician maritime signals.
Come on, get up!
We have come to relieve the meteorologist with him.
You know where he is?
I talked!
Typhus.
This place is a pigsty.
¡Mírese!
It is not able to continue their work, we're at war.
Come here!
I think the poor are sick by isolation, sir.
- You know the saying, nobody is ... - We'll take care of it.
Register yourself the island!