(crowd cheering)
FA“
ANNOUNCER:
In this corner, Roberto Durén.
(crowd cheering, booing)
And in this corner,
Benny Huertas.
(crowd cheering)
(bell dings)
RAY:
Ring sense is an art.
A gift from God
that ﬂows out of a fighter
like a painting
ﬂows out of an artist.
You're either blessed with it
from the day you're born...
...or you're cursed without it
till you die.
In 66 seconds,
Roberto Durén changed my life.
(man shouting in Spanish)
(bell dinging)
(crowd cheering)
(man shouting in Spanish)
ELETA:
This is his
22nd knockout in 25 fights.
You can make him a champ.
I know it.
Well, I don't think
you need me, Carlos.
L-- the kid's got it all.
But he's wild.
Undisciplined.
You know,
he can't make this road
towards a world championship
by himself.
He grew up in the streets.
Fought everything, everybody.
Hates everything,
including the United States
of America.
Including the United States?
His father was an American
who abandoned his mother.
You can help him, Ray.
Listen, I want to train
the kid, I just...
I-I don't want... you know...
It's not easy.
I don't want to stir things up.
What, that thing
with the wiseguys?
That was 17 years ago.
- Well, you think
they still care? -Yeah, yeah.
I can pay you under the table.
Ah, they know all the tricks.
The only thing
I can think of is...
I'd have to train him for free.
That's not a bad idea.
-(door opens)
-(chuckles)
Cholo.
Hey.
Thirty-one flavors and I got them all!
I got somebody
very, very important
that I want you to meet.
The best trainer
in the history of boxing.
Ray Arcel.
He has trained
more world champs
than anyone else
in boxing history.
Relax. Don't look at me like that.
Where are you?
I told you I would bring you
to the Madison Square Garden.
Have I ever said anything
that didn't happen?
This man can make you world champ.
I don't need nobody
from America.
I know.
I got to go.
Hey, Ray, Ray, Ray, Ray-
RAY:
It's good to see you, Carlos,
after all these years.
We'll talk soon.
Thanks, Ray.
0K8)'-
Hey.
What's wrong with you guys?
That's Ray Arcel
Ray Arcel-- 18 championships
of the world.
Plomo Quifiones...
CGTO.
Now you got two trainers.
You got Panama. Our Panama.
And you got the man who knows...
You really have balls, Eleta.
I'm trying to make you world champ.
You don't wanna be world champ?
You gonna eat all that shit?
Of course! I bought it!
(crowd chanting, clamoring)
(chanting continues)
RAY:
Since 1903, the Canal Zone
was a U.S.-controlled territory
right in the heart of Panama.
♪ And the rockets'
red glare... ♪
By 1964, tension
was at an all-time high
as Panamanian students clashed
with the U.S. military over
the right to fly their ﬂag
in their own land.
Viva Panama!
(shouting) Panama!
CROWD (chanting):
Panama! Panama!
(chuckles)
(crowd gasping)
(shouting, clamoring)
AMERICANS (chanting):
USA! USA!
(crowd clamoring)
(rapid gunfire)
(birds cawing)
(gunshots)
SOLDIER:
Run! Run!
Get out there and swim!
Swim for your life!
(crowd shouting, clamoring)
RAY: The conﬂict
would last for three days,
and when it was done,
22 Panamanians
and four U.S. citizens
were dead.
Mom, got food!
Gun shots, Roberto, hide down here!
Uaughs)
What are you doing down there, you crazy?
Mangoes!
Wait!
Did you steal that?
Mom, you know me, I don't need to steal.
Where did you find that?
I got paid for my work.
Thanks, son.
RAY: Durén had
several teachers in his life.
One of the most important
was Chaflan.
(Speaking Spanish)
He was like the Pied Piper
of the neighborhood
who taught the kids
how to survive.
(shouting in Spanish)
(children laughing)
(shouts in Spanish)
Mangoes for everyone!
Now everyone say thanks for the mangoes.
Thanks for the mangoes.
If it's mine it's yours.
And if it's ours it's yours.
Thank you.
Left, Left, Left, Right, Left.
CHAFLAN".
Numero dos!
Numero tres!
Numero cuatro!
ALL:
Uno, dos, tres, cuatro!
Run! We are late!
(all clamoring)
(indistinct chatter,
clamoring)
(shouting in Spanish)
("Te Estan Buscando"
by Rubén Blades playing)
(man shouting in Spanish)
Use yourjab. Don't lower your guard.
Sir.
What's up, kid?
Would you train me?
Go to school. We are working here.
You gonna pay for school?
Just go, kid.
All good.
(crowd clamoring)
Shut up and box.
Boxing is fighting,
all you do is dance like my sisters.
Yeah!
Stand up you coward!
We are rich!
I didn't know you liked to fight!
You see? I'm gonna be world champ!
Then you gotta take me to NY.
Let's go eat!
Hide the money!
Give me that money, kid.
Give me the money.
I got no money.
He's just a kid!
(shouting in Spanish)
- Wassup, kid?
- Wassup.
- All good?
- Yes.
Clearly, all is great.
I can get you out.
But let me be clear...
If you are caught fighting or stealing...
I'll bring you back myself
and leave you here.
So you are gonna train me?
("Penas" by Ulpiano Vergara
y Lucho de Sedas playing)
(Speaking Spanish)
(crowd cheering)
They're not all gonna be this easy.
Sometimes...
You need to get points.
(crowd clamoring)
There's technique...
Rules.
Cheats.
Movement.
(counting in Spanish)
(crowd cheering, clamoring)
You learning everything I tell you?
I learn anything you want...
as long as you get me an ice cream...
every time I kill one of those fuckers.
(Speaks Spanish)
(crowd clamoring, cheering)
(Speaking Spanish)
(cheering)
Stand up you coward!
Hey.
Baby.
Turn around.
Hey, psst.
Blondie.
What's your name?
Did the mice eat your tongue?
You're not going to give me your name?
Huh?
You speak English?
You speak Spanish?
Happiness
You are kidding me, right?
Your name is happiness?
Let me guess. It's what you've
been looking for all your life?
The poor are born happy.
Only the rich know sadness.
And you still leave?
Come here!
Where are you taking me?
It's okay, I don't bite.
You are nuts.
Marry me!
I don't even know you!
Exactly!
We'll get the rest
of our lives to know each other.
You are really crazy.
Crazy for you.
I can't change who I am.
Then you need to forget about me.
You're going to leave me here?
You're the one who won't forget me!
You'll be drawing hearts in your notebook.
You are done, you turned...
And you fell in love.
You're crazy!
What's up? What's that spaceship?
Jeez. he's intense!
This is Carlos Eleta,
the richest man in Panama.
I've been looking for you for an hour!
Stop screaming in front of everyone.
I wanted to meet you.
I hear you are unbeatable.
When you fight clowns it's easy to win.
You wanna be world champ? I can help you.
(Plomo mouthing)
Yes
You speak English?
He's looking.
Yes, I speak English.
Gonna take you to Madison Square Garden.
Let's go right away.
This is your plane?
- Vamos, vamos, vamos.
-Robert, Robert, Robert,
Robert, Robert,
Robert.
Don't look, don't look.
RAY:
In the early '50s, I wanted
to take boxing
to every town in America,
but the New York City wiseguys
were not happy about that.
Boxing is
a New York City sport,
and that it's gonna remain.
But this national television
tour of yours
is taking the spotlight
off of the Garden.
And that we can't afford.
Well, I... (sighs)
I think it'll help you
in the long run... Frank.
If you can trust
what I'm saying.
TV will turn boxing
into a nationwide pastime
and you'll have talent and fans
from every part
of the country coming
to see championships
at the Garden.
I don't give a shit about
every part of the country.
New York is the heart
of the cow.
It's the prime meat.
If any boxing fan
wants to see a fight
in the flesh or in front
of your little dirty tube,
better understand
that all roads
go through New York.
RAY:
When they heard I survived,
we made a deal.
They would spare my life
as long as I never made
another dollar from boxing.
It's a familiar smell.
Where were you?
What, what are you
talking about?
Did you go there?
Where?
That's what I said-- where?
Please, you make it sound like
I've been with some woman
or something.
I would rather you were
with some woman.
Don't always be
a district attorney.
I was seeing an old friend.
You know, it's fine.
I'm blonde.
I look great in black.
I will be a very hot widow.
Is that what you want?
(sighs)
How many years do I have left?
R3)'-
These people will kill you.
Yeah, well.
I might as well
be dead already anyway.
Oh, what a lovely thing
to say to your wife.
I don't mean... you, honey.
I mean...
(sighs)
we are what we do.
And if you just make money,
you become money.
This thing that everybody wants
that everybody craves,
it's just symbolic.
It has no real value.
I have to do something
that I really care about.
I'm not an idiot.
I know you're miserable.
I get it, but those animals
run everything.
I'd rather live in fear.
("La Luna y el Toro"
by Gabino Pampini playing)
Pick it up a little,
pick it up.
You're gonna have
to learn to breathe.
And you're gonna learn
to pace yourself.
There's technique
and there's strategy.
Technique is your every move,
your every punch
covers all your short-term
decisions.
Strategy is your plan
for the whole fight.
It's your long term.
It defines how you
apply the technique
to achieve your major goal.
It's okay if your technique
fails for a beat
as long as you're
following the strategy.
Buchanan knows you're gonna try
to knock him out
in the first round.
And then he'll wait for you
to get tired and try
and catch you,
and that's his strategy.
ÉComprende?
He expect (rapid humming)
but if you slow down
and go (whooshing, sputtering)
slow, slow, slow, slow,
slow, slow, slow...
Buchanan no comprende.
Get off the fence.
Excuse me?
Ah, shut up, schmuck.
SOLDIER: Who do you
think you are, old man?
I'm Ray Arcel from Harlem, USA.
You know where that is?
And this is
the future world champion
you're talking to here.
Fuck off.
He's in a jail and he thinks
he's in charge.
- We in jail.
- No, he-he's in jail.
- They put jail here.
- No, no, he...
He's... It's all in the head.
Boxing is a mental sport, aqui.
What you do with your body
is one-third of the job.
You got to learn to be
the boss, which you are.
Say it, "He's in jail."
Say it.
"He's in jail."
- He's in jail.
See? In jail.
I thought I told you
to fuck off.
You in jail.
You don't know
when to stop, do you?
You in jail.
- Okay, okay.
- You, you in jail.
Get the fuck out of here.
- Is that the way you want this
to go? -DURAN: You in jail.
You are in jail.
I'm champion.
This is Panama.
RAY:
Nice.
Hook after the right.
Hook
Double up. Jab. Jab.
That's it,
that's it, there you go.
There you go.
("Plastico" by Rubén Blades
playing)
That's it. That's it!
-(bicycle bell tinkles)
- RAY: Nice, nice.
Ciao.
Hey, you are the boxer.
Yes.
And you are?
I heard you won.
Yeah, that was easy.
Now I'm going for the world championship.
That's good.
Can I walk with you?
What school did you go to?
I went to the Plomo Quifiones school.
Now I'm in the Ray Arcel.
Ray Arcel?
Uh-huh.
American school?
Yes, American school.
You didn't go to school, did you?
But you can read, right?
This is like a job interview.
I thought I was walking you home.
Yes.
I can continue alone.
Why?
We come from different worlds.
It's all in the head.
What?
Turn the right hand over,
turn the right hand over.
RAY: The first thing
a future world champ
needs to be taught
is to be lucky.
And luck is a woman
you must learn to seduce.
FA“
Be the host of the ring.
This is your temple,
and everyone does as you wish.
Be the master of time.
You and only you
should decide when to strike.
(thunder rolls)
(shouting in Spanish)
(rain pattering on roof)
Come See.
This is the kitchen.
Aqui.
My heavy b89-
Some perfumes.
Come see.
I'm looking at it.
FA“
You don't like it?
I'm just used to...
FA“
CARBO:
Hey, Ray.
How you doing, huh?
No worries.
You look good.
How's the wife?
She's good, thanks.
2O years since
your heroic mission
to expand boxing to the nation.
Boxing expanded.
I wasn't wrong.
Yes and no. But yes,
the sport makes
for fantastic television.
And now you're back.
Sort of.
I like you, Ray.
I feel really bad
for what they did to you.
I don't need to look
a gift horse up the ass
to know there's shit in there.
I thought we had a deal.
We do.
Maybe I'm confused
about what kind of deal
we're talking about.
You weren't meant to make money
from boxing again.
I'm training him for free.
You can check
with Carlos Eleta.
He's the fighter's manager.
You're a classy guy,
but you're not going to teach
me how to hide money.
Buchanan's favored 14 to three
against Duran, right?
That's right.
Except Durén's going to win.
Put all your money on Durén.
Make a bundle.
Leave me alone if he wins,
shoot me if he loses.
(chuckles)
You're a classy guy.
JOURNAUST".
Mr. Arcel,
why come back from retirement
with an unproven fighter?
I just turned 73.
You know,
seven decades and change.
And myself
and Freddy Brown here
have probably forgotten more
than most trainers
will ever learn.
But I remember well,
from the '20s to the '50s
we lived
the golden age of boxing.
Then television took over
and we all became... ambitious.
The sport turned
into a spectacle,
show business with blood.
And it was a good thing,
because we reached audiences
nobody thought we could reach.
The problem, inevitably,
is that the fighters
started doing it
for the fame, for greed,
for self-importance.
Independent promoters
faded away and, with them,
the true hungry fighters,
the lifeblood of this game.
Tonight, however, you'll meet
the best lightweight
New York has seen in 5O years.
Atrue, true hungry fighter.
Like in the old days.
He's got the soul, the rage,
the mental energy and
determination the sport needs,
and that's why I'm here.
Because a new
golden era for boxing
begins with Roberto Durén.
(cheering)
FA“
(crowd shouting)
CONDON:
With 28 wins, zero losses
and 24 knockouts...
from the slums
of El Chorrillo, Panama...
-(cheering loudly)
-...Roberto Durén.
The lightweight
champion of the world,
Ken Buchanan.
(cheering)
He's got a skirt?
He is wearing a skirt, Roberto!
A fuckin' skirt!
(laughing, whooping)
Take him to the movies.
Charm him.
Let him open up.
Then go to work on him.
Remember what we worked on.
Strategy.
Excuse me.
(conversing in Spanish)
Are they fighting yet?
It's about to start.
(bell clangs, crowd cheers)
DON DUNPHY: Durén is certainly
trying to improve on
his nine one-round
knockouts here.
He's throwing everything.
(grunts)
(cheering)
DUNPHY: Johnny scores it
as a knockdown.
(shouting indistinctly)
Find that body!
DUNPHY: The challenger
is a little over-anxious.
It was almost Buchanan
scoring the knockdown.
Kill him, cholo!
(bell clanging)
DUNPHY:
Durén may punch himself out.
Don't rush in. You got him.
Just keep on him.
Remember the strategy.
He wants you to get tired.
I don't care
about the strategy.
- I'll kill him.
- Listen to me.
If you don't go in
with a feint and a jab,
he's going to nail you
on the way in. He's tall.
He's-he's too tall for you.
Strategy.
Stick with the strategy.
- Fuck off.
- No, don't tell me that.
Don't say those things to me.
Fuck off. Yeah, yeah, he's tall
and he's gonna nail me.
What, you work for him or what?
- Are you out of your mind?
- Yeah, he's taller than me...
What am I doing here?
I don't need this.
Yeah, because he's gringo.
- Listen, you stupid
little schmuck. -Right?
You want me to leave here?
I can leave you in the corner
by yourself.
Now behave yourself,
act like a grown-up,
-and stop being a baby.
- I'm fucking with you.
- I'm nervous, okay? -I know you
are, I know you're nervous,
-but look at him.
- Don't make me worse, okay?
I'm... You're making
yourself worse.
- Okay, relax now.
- You're mak-- no, you relax.
You get out there and
you show me what you can do.
You pace yourself.
You be the boss.
(horn blows)
Keep the pressure on him
behind the jabs.
Start working on the body.
Keep the pressure on--
that's...
keep the pressure on him.
(bell clangs)
(speaks indistinctly)
What's going on?
(crowd cheering wildly)
DUNPHY: Durén's going
for that knockout.
That's a white bitch, Cholo!
Eso una perra blanca, Cholo!
DUNPHY:
Oh!
He really hurt him that time.
Buchanan's in trouble...
Make him shit his pants!
Buchanan's mouthpiece goes out!
(bell clangs)
Remember, Buchanan came
from a broken home.
(cheering)
Get him up against the ropes!
(announcer speaking Spanish)
(announcerconfinues
speaking Spanish)
(clangiﬂg)
(cheering)
(all shouting)
Chow'.!
-(crowd cheering wildly)
- RAY: Johnny. Johnny.
That was a clean shot.
You gotta know that.
We're in New York City,
don't forget, don't forget.
(whooping)
- I didn't hit him in the,
in the, in the balls. -No, no.
- I hit him in the gut.
- No, believe me, I know.
Durén! Durén!
(shouting)
(man Speaking Spanish)
TRAINER:
He's good.
- He's good.
- I can hear you.
I can hear you, I'm okay.
- I'm okay.
- He's good.
(cheering)
(whooping)
- Hey!
-(squealing gleefully)
(whoops)
(chanting): Durén, Durén,
Durén, Durén, Durén!
Hey!
We love you, Panama!
Durén, Durén, Duran...
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh-oh... ♪
FA“
Hey, Ray! Cheers.
- I got a question for you.
- Yeah.
Why you always brushed my hair
when we were in the corners?
Fighter punches you,
feels proud.
Bell sounds, next round starts,
you come out looking all fresh,
like you just
came out of the shower.
Drives him nuts.
He thinks he can't hurt you.
All psychological.
Oh...
- Strategy-
- Aha.
- Strategy.
Aha, you schmuck.
- Huh?
- Now you're speaking Yiddish.
- Yeah.
- Yes.
"Schmlendeck."
Schmendrick. Putz.
Yeah, son of a putz.
- Hey, watch my hair gel.
(laughs) -No, no, I just...
I just...
Yeah.
(Felicidad shrieks happily,
Durén speaks Spanish)
FA“
(Durén chuckles)
("El Desierto" by Lhasa de Sela
playing)
(Felicidad chuckles)
FA“
(screams)
(Felicidad panting)
(groans in pain)
Open my belly!
Don't open her belly!
Empuja.
How do we call him?
Roberto Duran
FA“
(cheering)
(groans)
It's a girl!
FA“
Another girl
Roberto Duran.
You can't name them all Roberto.
Let's name him Robin, then, like Robin Hood.
We fight the rich to give the poor.
FA“
Another boy and his name is Roberto Durén.
And I don't wanna hear it.
(children cheering)
(chatter in Spanish)
How are the girls? Did you eat?
Yes!
Get some sodas.
(Speaks Spanish)
What's wrong?
Papi, we've given away
100 grand already.
What's the problem?
We got money.
And it's good to give.
Look how happy everyone is.
Thanks for the food, Duran.
("Tiburon" by Rubén Blades
playing)
(chatter in Spanish)
Jump! Jump!
(cheering)
PRESIDENT CARTER (muffled):
We are here to participate in
the signing of treaties
which will assure
a peaceful and prosperous...
(clear):
...of the United States
to the belief that fairness
and not force
should lie at the heart
of our dealings
with the nations of the world.
Dear Mr. President Carter.
In the name of the truth of logic,
I would like to say,
that we will sign this treaty.
He's signing the treaty!
The treaty is signed! The Canal is ours!
Blondie!
They're gonna give us the canal!
General Torrijos signed the treaty!
See to believe the word of a Yankee.
(Durén speaks Spanish)
Come see what I got you.
But wait... this is important.
- Torrijos is good with the people.
- You wanna see the real Panama canal?
I've seen that tiny canal a million times.
You say that because all you have is a sail boat.
A sail boat? I got the Titanic here.
Sink it then.
All Panama is celebrating in the streets
and you are not even happy?
Happy about what?
About what?
You've obviously never been chased by a Marine.
Excuse me?
Rich girl.
Get off of me.
Now you gonna get mad?
Yes. You're talking shit.
Eh?
They offer to return your own territory in 1999.
In twenty years!
For fuck's sake, it's ours!
And it has nothing to do with being rich or poor.
It's common sense.
Now this is fucked.
I'm celebrating and you are pissed.
If you wanna make your people proud,
this is the guy to beat.
What does it say?
When are you gonna learn to read?
It says "Fighter of the year".
Fighter of the year? This clown?
He hasn't fought a man in his life.
He is the symbol of American sports.
My balls.
He's the symbol of American Sports.
(mimicking)
If you want your Torrijos-Carter treaty...
to mean anything for this country...
before 1999...
destroy their idol
and make them respect Panama.
That idol goes down in one round.
Let me see it.
For you I got 15 rounds or more.
("Bim Sala Bim"
by Hudson County playing)
FA“
RAY: Wow.
He's lightning fast, this guy.
DURAN: He's imitating Ali.
Punches like a girl.
Yeah, but he could run
away from you all night
and score dozens of points
with these punches.
He's jumping all over
the place. Look at him.
I mean, it's like, uh,
he's a different kind
of animal.
You gotta work on your speed.
Man, if you love him so much,
why don't you go train him?
I don't love him,
I respect him.
And you should do yourself
a favor and respect him, too.
- Look at him.
- No, but go, Ray,
go and massage the shoulders
you love so much.
- Oh, come on, stop it, come on.
- Huh? So now am I slow?
- I don't know, whatever,
stop it. -Now am I slow?
- No, go and massage
his shoulders. -I... you're...
- Go with your gringo, Ray.
- Oh...
Maybe you've been
training him already.
I don't know
where you go at night.
You, you've gotta be
kidding me. Roberto!
- Huh? No? -Come on, stop it.
Shut up. Grow up.
Not everything
revolves around you.
I have responsibilities.
Come on, look at this...
They must know that-that-that
I won't be able to beat...
to-to-to-to beat him.
I will beat him, you know?
I will beat him
because I'm a good boxer.
- And you know what? -Strategize
right now and sit down.
I will make him
fight like a man.
- Sit down so we can discuss
everything. -I'm done looking.
No go.
I will beat him.
With my strategy.
If you leave,
I'm packing my bags. I'm going.
- Leave.
- You leave, I'll leave.
- Be my guest.
- Ah...
(Durén speaks Spanish)
Goddamn schmendrick.
Goddamn you,
fucking schmendrick.
(door squeaks, closes)
LEONARD: And you tell your
father, root for me, okay?
Too cute.
(laughter)
Isn't that Durén?
Uh... yeah.
You know he was here?
Manos de Piedra!
Look at the rich kid.
He's a real fighter?
- Or a clown?
- WILFRED: Hey.
Respect, Durén. He's with his wife.
What, this son of a bitch here?
- Or are you talking
about the whore? -Hey, hey.
Hey, hey, you show
some respect, man.
You talking to me,
you piece of shit?
DURAN:
You know what you are?
Take that machismo bullshit
out of here.
All I see is
a golden spoon child
who thinks he can fight a man.
You can fight a man?
- Hey, shut up.
- You can fight a man?
ANGELO:
Let's get out of here, Ray.
- Come on.
- DURAN: You're a pussy, man.
You're a clown. All you do
is dance and jump around.
Jump around and sell soda.
He's gonna whip your ass.
- DURAN: You shut up, too,
bitch. -Oh, fuck you!
I'm gonna fuck your husband
in the ring
and when I'm done
with him, I'm gonna go
-and fuck you all night, baby.
- Oh, you...!
Gonna fuck them here, huh?
- What is wrong with you?
-(grunting)
(shouting indistinctly)
ANGELO: You wash your mouth
before you talk to a woman!
Right now, right now,
motherfucker.
(cheering)
I come all the way, all the way
from Panama to fight a man.
And all they give me is
a pretty boy. What the fuck?
And you see,
and you see his, um,
his diet cola commercial?
And he calls himself "Sugar"
-and he's selling you
sugar-free shit. -(laughter)
Or-or maybe, maybe that's what
we're gonna have.
A sugar-free fight.
(exclaiming)
Ah-ah, ah-ah, ah-ah!
I'm sorry, okay?
Sorry's not good enough.
How could you do that?
Insult a woman like that?
What's the matter with you?
Well, my country
felt insulted by yours.
And not only women.
Children.
What does your country
have to do
with the way
you talked to that woman?
The way you behaved?
You know how... you know how
it is to be hungry?
And I don't say,
"hungry" hungry.
To be hungry
that you have to go to...
to-to the garbage for food?
While the American army
is exploiting your country?
You know how it feels?
What does that have to do
with what you just did?
What are you...
what are you doing?
- Well, it has to do...
- You know, you want to be,
you want to be,
you want to be a warrior,
you want to avenge your people,
fine by me.
Avenge your people.
Be a warrior.
But real warriors
do not do what you did.
They don't mess with women
the way you just did.
And if you want me
in your corner,
you cannot do that again.
Well, well, okay,
okay, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
But I'm not gonna say
I'm sorry to him.
I say I'm sorry to you,
but I'm not gonna say
I'm sorry to him.
Let's forget it.
What's done is done.
Are you mad?
And let's just...
focus on the fight.
This anger you feel,
I understand that.
You don't want to become
a victim of your own mind game.
It's all in the head.
Robert.
Why are you here?
Huh?
If Ray finds out you are dead.
I can't sleep.
What's wrong?
I don't want to disappoint tomorrow.
Dad!
Hey!
My babies! Good morning!
Kisses for Daddy.
Can't wait to see you kill that coward!
Don't say that!
But Dad said it on TV.
It's my job to say those things.
So you're not gonna kill him?
Of course, I'm gonna kill that son of a bitch.
It's all a show.
He says that so the fight is more fun.
Come get dressed.
(muttering)
(cheering fades in)
HOWARD COSELL: Durén has turned
into the audience favorite
after a menacing training
process in town.
He has been so aggressive.
The referee tonight is Carlos
Padilla, who gloriously oversaw
the Thrilla in Manila
between Frazier and Ali.
You have to let them fight,
otherwise you're gonna see
two guys running all night.
To your corner.
Biggest ring I ever saw.
ANNOUNCER:
Sugar Ray Leonard!
-(booing)
- COSELL: The crowd
-is booing the champ,
ladies and gents... -Booing?
...in what must be
startling for Leonard,
who, in this very stadium
surprised the planet
by winning Olympic gold.
It's a wonderful day.
(booing continues)
JUANITA:
That's okay, baby!
It's your night tonight!
(booing continues)
You're dead meat, Durén!
- JUANITA: That's right.
- You're nothing.
Fuckin' Cholo!
JUANITA: Yeah.
Keep him close to your body.
Don't chase the lady.
Let her come to you.
Don't let her run.
Rather lose than run.
Look at him.
ANNOUNCER:
...15 rounds of boxing...
Strategy.
ANNOUNCER:
Presented by the promoter...
(announcer speaking Spanish)
COSELL: This Canadian crowd
has embraced
the underdog Roberto Duran.
ANNOUNCER 2:
Speculation has been rampant
over whether Leonard will turn
this into a street fight
or go back to the boxing
which brought him here.
-(bell clangs)
- Leonard and Durén!
(cheering)
Durén getting inside
the jab of Leonard.
At him!
Keep him on the ropes! At him!
ANNOUNCER 2: Two fighters
at the top of their game.
Jab! Jab! Jab!
Stay on him! Stay on him!
Get out of there,
get out of there!
(grunting)
(crowd cheering)
- Break it up. -ANNOUNCER 2:
That's not Leonard.
Leonard is short punches,
not wide ones.
Break it up.
(bell clanging)
COSELL:
The normally elusive Leonard
is staying flat-footed.
He wants to trade with Durén
and not back down.
He wants to prove he's a man.
Let him feel he's resisting.
Keep him hoping until he's
inspired and then kill him.
Look at me!
Who the fuck are you today?
Huh?
This is honor I'm fighting for.
ANGELO:
Fuck that shit!
-(clangs)
- Make him fight.
Go get him, champ!
- Run him around!
-(shouts indistinctly)
(cheering)
-(commentator speaking Spanish)
- Durén! Durén! Durén!
Durén! Durén!
(grunts)
COSELL: Durén lands
a left hook to the neck
that wobbles Leonard!
Ankles! Ankles!
(bell clangs)
Dale Chucha tu Madre!
COSELL:
This is not
the Leonard
we're used to seeing.
Can you believe he's trying
to match macho with macho?
ANNOUNCER 2:
Durén pushes back.
Leonard has some room now.
Good right hand by Leonard.
Break. Open. Open.
(whistle blows)
ANNOUNCER 2: The key to Leonard
is his left jab.
But it's also working in tandem
with those legs.
-(bell clangs) -Right now,
seems like he's flat-footed,
just trying to tee off
on Durén.
Go! Beat him!
(commentator speaking Spanish)
ANNOUNCER 2: Now, Sugar Ray
is fighting an inspired fight.
(bell clangs)
You gotta try
to knock him out, Cholo.
You never know
with these darn judges.
They can take
the fight away from us.
This has been your best fight.
But you're still human.
You could still lose.
I want you to focus.
Are we gonna be champions?
Tu eres mi campeén.
FA“
(whistle blows)
Against the ropes.
(speaks indistinctly)
Last round, champ!
- Now or never!
-(bell clangs)
ANNOUNCER 2:
Round 15!
Not many thought
it would come to this.
The crowd is on their feet.
And at the battle here
in Montreal.
- COSELL: We are in the waning
moments of this fight. -Go, go!
I cannot believe
what I'm seeing.
what is taking place.
To the very end,
these two warriors going at it.
Like they don't know
that a bell is going to ring.
This is what we are here for.
We are witnessing history.
- Cholo, knock him out!
-(yells in Spanish)
ANNOUNCER 2:
Who wants it more?
MAN:
Let's go, Cholo!
(commentators shouting)
ANNOUNCER 2:
An amazing battle!
And we're in the 15th round.
This fight is gonna go
all the way!
We are counting down.
Six, five,
four, three...
And the bell is going to ring!
-(bell clanging)
- Here they are!
Look at these two warriors!
(cheering)
Behave,behave,behave!
- We could get penalized,
behave. -You shit!
COSELL:
We've seen this before,
when a fight is close.
The decision
usually goes to the champion.
Who's the cunt now? Who's
the cunt now, motherfucker?
- Maricén!
- Fuck you!
- You are my bitch!
-(shouting)
Robbie!
You won, my love!
COSELL: Three judges
score the fight as follows:
OFFICIAL:
Judge Angelo Poletti
calls the match 147 to 147.
It is a draw.
(shouting in Spanish)
(booing)
Be calm, my love.
OFFICIAL: Judge Harry Gibbs
calls the match
145 to 144.
- You've proven yourself.
For Roberto Durén.
(cheering, whistling)
Attention. Attention.
Judge Raymond Baldeyrou
calls the match 146 to 144.
- The new welterweight...
- Yeah!
...champion of the world,
Roberto Durén!
(shouting, whooping)
FA“
(telephone ringing)
Hello.
WOMAN: I'm calling from
the Coney Island Hospital
in regards to a patient
with a heroin overdose.
- Yes?
- Patient's records
indicate she's the daughter
of Ray Arcel.
No, th-this is the wife
of Ray Arcel,
and my husband
does not have a daughter.
You must have the wrong number.
- Sorry, ma'am.
- Nope, no worries. Good night.
-(exhales)
- What happened?
Nothing.
It was just a wrong number.
What'd they say?
They said there's another guy
named Ray Arcel
and his daughter
is in the hospital.
What hospital?
What-what happened?
I don't know, but I know
I'm not gonna be able
to go back to sleep now.
What are you doing?
Aw, Jesus.
Thank you.
I understand
you're related to the patient.
Yes, I'm her father and, uh,
I'll, uh, be responsible
for anything that...
Why are you here?
All these years...
you come now?
Why?
You have no fighters
to-to nurture?
(crying):
What are you doing here?
I don't want
to be seen like this.
I'm not one of your fighters.
RAY".
Hazel and I couldn't have kids.
And we... wanted to adopt.
We adopted Adele
and when Adele was four,
Hazel passed away.
I didn't know what to do.
I had no money.
I couldn't take care of her.
I...
I-I thought she'd be better off
with my in-laws. I...
(sighs)
I was, uh...
-I-l know I should have
told you, I was... -Told me'?
What about her?
What about the girl
hanging onto her life
by a thread in a hospital bed?
FA“
DURAN (echoing):
Sure. Leonard.
You are my friend now.
(laughter)
Baby, I want to show...
I want to show you something.
Yeah?
What do you want to show me?
(mumbling)
- Uh...
- Want to go in there?
Yeah, we will.
But I-l want to show you
something before we do, okay?
Just... just let me...
let me...
COSELL: ...have respect
for Sugar Ray Leonard?
Sure.
Sure. Leonard.
You are my friend now.
(laughter)
Look at this.
DURAN:
Leonard.
You are my friend now.
All along, he's been
doing this on purpose.
He hurt you to drive me crazy.
To get me to be
in his macho tough guy war.
Ray, you're obsessed.
I'm telling you,
it's a strategy.
It's been a strategy...
I'm gonna fuck
your husband in the ring
and when I'm done with him,
I'm gonna go
and fuck you all night, baby.
From the moment
he insulted you,
he knew that he could
get in my head
and cause me to stand
toe-to-toe with him.
I've never lost.
I don't lose.
Angelo.
Talk to Don King.
Durén should fight
no one but me.
Set the rematch immediately.
KING: Tell you what
I'm gonna do, Carlos.
I'm gonna add a two
to that eight
and bring it up to ten.
$10 million, Carlos.
You're gonna have the highest
paid fighter in history.
Oh-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh, boy.
I know you like
the sound of that, Carlos.
the sound of that.
("Bonjour Madame"
by Camilo Azuquita playing)
Eva.
ELETA:
Hey, Show.
Cholo.
I'm exhausted.
ELETA: Hey.
I've been calling you for a week.
What's up, Beta'?
- I have great news, Cholo.
-¢' Que pasé?
They want a rematch.
Who?
What do you mean who? Leonard!
Leonard? What is he a masochist?
I got you the most money ever
-for a welterweight.
- How much? How much?
$8 million.
Hey, Boba.
$8 million for
a rematch with me.
He must be desperate.
No, the--
no, the man needs the money.
(laughing)
- Cholo. Cholo.
- What?
Look at me.
Pay attention.
Okay, 0K8)'-
I have to respond
to these people tonight.
In front of witnesses,
do you accept a rematch
with-with Leonard?
(Speaks Spanish)
I'd fight him, but
I'm not gonna
fucking marry a guy.
You're drinking.
You're getting fat.
You come to my house
and you call me fat?
You have mirrors in your house?
You're the one
who's getting fat.
You're getting fat from all
the food that you're eating
because of the money
that I'm making for you.
So what the fuck?
Parasite.
That's what you are,
you're a fucking parasite.
You call me fat,
I call you parasite.
Hey, hey.
Hey, hey, Eleta.
Now you are mad?
-(shrieking)
- Hey!
What the hell are you doing?
Can't you see you got us all wet?
You are a fuckin' parasite too!
I'm telling you to get out you idiot!
Rob, what are you doing?
He got me soaked.
Get out I said!
This is my fuckin' house, you moron.
Get out or I'll get in and break you.
It's Chaflan, Rob!
Stop it, it's Chaflan.
("Hot Stuff" by Donna Summer
playing)
Chivo, where's the Cholo?
Chow'.!
(whooping)
FA“
(indistinct chatter)
That's the man, talk to him.
How are you?
I saw you on TV.
I was in town and, uh...
said to myself, "Why not?"
Hey, listen. Uh...
I'm not proud of what I did.
But look:
you're the world champ.
She was 14.
No money.
Your son.
I was in the army.
And, uh,
when they say you gotta leave,
there's no ifs or buts.
What do you want?
Nothing.
Just, uh,
just thought I'd say hi.
Hi.
I thought you were American.
(man chuckles)
I am American.
You look Mexican to me.
Well, Mexican heritage.
You thought I was, uh, blond,
-blue eyes, eh?
- Yes.
I can't take back what I did.
All I can say is, uh,
I'm sorry.
And I'm...
I'm proud
that you're my son.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I bring you this show from Las Vegas.
Don't miss this international show
for all Panamanians.
(gasps theatrically)
Let's play a game.
Everyone look at the ball...
(shrieks)
Hold it right there!
I'm hungry, man.
Catch him!
(shouting in Spanish)
FA“
(shouting stops)
A bit salty...
but thank you.
FA“
(exhales)
(grunts)
Revolting!
FA“
"(Speaking Spanish)
FELICIDAD:
Fuck you!
While you were at your party...
What?
Chaflan was killed.
Who told you?
(Felicidad sobbing)
You can't discipline him by
forcing him to do something.
You have to let him live
his life in a certain way.
Stunned!
I was stunned!
And he will be stunned
when he hears what you did.
And I have to explain it
to him.
Yeah, explain to him
that I got him $8 million,
-which is the most money...
- He doesn't care.
-...that anyone has ever made.
- But he doesn't even know that.
He doesn't know that
even for himself.
That the money is
the least important thing.
He's a professional fighter.
He can lose that weight.
Three months to lose
almost 4O pounds.
You know what that does
to a fighter?
I want what's best for him.
I want us to do
-what is best for him.
- That's not best for him.
That's best for you
but not for him.
Well, that's your opinion.
Let me tell you this...
That's not my opinion.
That's a fact.
If he doesn't take this fight,
you know what's
going to end up happening? He's
going to go fight some nobody.
He's going to lose
and he will never,
in a million years,
get close to making the money
he's making right now.
He's Durén. He can't lose.
He's Durén. When he is focused,
he doesn't lose to a nobody.
You know that.
He won.
Let him enjoy it.
Let him party.
So what if he's partying?
So what if he's eating?
Let him eat.
Let him have a good time.
He never had anything.
He never ate anything.
And now he's finally
earned something.
He's earned it himself.
Nobody gave it to him.
And you just take it away.
I've been dealing with that
animal for the last ten years.
He's a, he's a, he's a,
he's a good kid...
He needs to be disciplined!
He will be disciplined!
That's my job.
If he loses, then we can sign
another rematch and...
You're a sick paskudnyak
wanting your fighter to lose.
No, what I said was, "if"...
- Carlos, you have the money.
- Ray.
- Family has the money.
He didn't have it.
He doesn't care.
The most important thing
for him is to win.
for me is to win.
To have the respect of winning.
Right.
What I said was,
if he loses,
he can have a rematch...
I'm done.
DURAN:
I met my father.
- RAY: Did you?
- Mm-hmm.
RAY:
What was he like?
He's Mexican.
I thought you said
he was American.
Um, he's American.
I mean, he was
born in America.
And I thought that he would
look like Paul Newman.
But he looks more like
Pancho Villa.
Think you look
like Paul Newman?
No, but Charles Bronson, maybe.
There's someone else
you're going to have
to learn to forgive.
Carlos.
Why?
He agreed to the rematch.
For when?
- Three months from now.
- Well, that's impossible.
We have to make it possible.
He already signed.
He can't sign
without my permission.
He said you gave him
your permission.
At your house, at a party.
In front of a lot of people.
Witnesses, he said.
(bat crashing against metal)
Hi!
ELETA:
Hi. They're insured.
So you can destroy them
if you want.
No matter what,
you're going to do the fight.
- You want me to call the
police? -Yeah, call the police!
They put me in jail and you
lose... you lose your fucking
$8 million!
Well, now, Cholo, now
you understand it's a business.
- I'm not a hooker!
- A hooker is cheaper
and it doesn't create
this much problems.
You should be
training right now.
I've been training
all my fucking life!
Go home, Roberto.
If you lose the fight,
we can have a rematch.
I don't lose!
ANNOUNCER (on TV): In Panama,
a nationalist demonstration...
RAY: We got 75 days
to lose 35 pounds.
You've got to keep working,
Cholo.
DURAN". I don't want to do this,
man, I want to rest.
- You want to rest?
- I'm tired, man.
- Yes.
To rest is to rust.
And you know that.
You're the kind of fighter
that's gotta stay on your toes
and if you don't
stay on your toes,
then you're gone, that's it.
And you can do this.
But you're going to have
to decide to do this.
Nobody can do it for you.
There's no such thing
as a reluctant hero.
You're going to have
to do it on your own.
I work all my life, man.
I work all my life.
I didn't have any food
when I was a kid.
I'm hungry, man, I'm hungry.
I don't want to be
hungry anymore.
I want to enjoy
what I have, Ray.
ANNOUNCER (on TV): The rioting
that followed was unexpected.
The Zone police used tear gas
and fire hoses
to drive off the demonstrators.
RAY:
I understand that.
I can try to convince Don King
to delay the fight.
But we got to be ready to fight
in case you have to.
0K8)'-
You still mad?
Don't know what to tell you.
Forgive me?
0K8)'-
I need you.
I don't want to fight.
Focus on your training.
Why don't you come with the kids?
I wanna see you.
You need to rest, Robert. Go to sleep.
Love you.
I love you.
Me too.
KING:
Do you realize I'm black?
Do you realize that I am
the only black promoter
in the business
and that if you pull out,
-they will fry me?
- RAY: We're not pulling out.
He can't make the weight.
It's impossible for him
to make the weight.
We got CBS.
We got the stadium.
We got the sponsors.
We got the tickets.
You can't go to them
and ask them?
Yeah, I can go to them
and ask them.
I'll say, "Excuse me, Mr. CBS,
I need another month."
They'll say,
"Black nigger, no."
That's what's going to happen.
Your boy either has
to make his weight
or he will be disqualified,
peﬂod.
Yeah, but you're making it
about yourself.
You're making it
about Bob Arum.
You're saying that
"I'm gonna look bad.
I'm the only black promoter."
With all due respect,
that doesn't mean anything.
You have a responsibility
to boxing.
Boxing?
Boxing has been run
by gangsters and criminals
and scoundrels
since the day it was born.
Come on, now.
Don't you put this on me.
- Don't you dare put this on me.
-It's a sloppy production
to start so soon
when he's not ready.
I happen to think
that Roberto Durén,
the man with the hands
of stone,
if you challenge him,
he will be ready.
He has got the spirit
of Panama in his heart.
You don't have
to tell me what he has.
I know him better
than anybody here.
All right, I'm sorry.
If we continue down
this road, Ray,
I'm gonna have to sue you
for breach of contract.
This is some mess
you got us into.
(door creaks)
("Heart in My Hand"
by Janelle Davidson playing)
Oh. Gosh, Ray, you scared me.
What are you doing here?
How did you even get in?
Hey. What...
Hey...
Ray, we can't do this.
Babe, baby, okay, come on.
Ray, look,
it's against the rules.
The fight's
just around the corner.
Come on, come on, babe.
No, no, no, no, no.
Shh, Shh, shh, shh.
It's my rules this time.
Okay?
FA“
(Leonard exhales)
You want to beat Duran,
you're going to have
to humiliate him.
You're going
to have to shame him,
right there,
in front of everyone.
FA“
It's not going to work.
Sorry.
Sorry, you have
to defend the title.
Or what they'll do is
they'll just take it away.
- What?
- They will take away the belt.
But I won the fight.
Everybody saw it.
They can just take away
my belt?
They-they... that's what
they can do.
They will take it away
if you don't defend it.
RAY: Roberto Durén had brought
us a new golden era for boxing.
Yet here we were, reminding him
that he didn't matter.
That decisions were made
in the back room
and he was only a circus animal
we needed for ticket sales.
OFFICIAL:
Approved.
(applause)
You're going to see
blood in this fight.
I don't like clowns.
When you come into the ring,
you come to fight,
not to dance or to clown.
He's imitating Ali all the
time, that's what he does.
He doesn't have any style.
I'm going to knock you out,
'cause imitators are losers.
And I don't like you.
Well, I think Durén
is a lovable guy.
And I want my son
to be just like him.
(audience laughs)
Listen.
I think Durén is a tough,
impressive,
intelligent fighter.
And we are in
for a serious fight.
You're gonna feel bad.
Stop it.
- Hand me that.
- You can't eat like this.
Pass me that yellow thing.
Why didn't I get wings when I asked?
You have plenty.
And why were you looking at Leonard?
Don't start with that.
You think I didn't see you?
Don't fool me.
- You think I'm stupid?
-Insane is what you are.
I saw him winking at you.
And you were all smiles.
FA“
ANNOUNCER: The former
champion of the world,
Sugar Ray Leonard!
COSELL: ...will be the rematch
of the century.
Here comes Leonard with his
entourage led by Angelo Dundee.
And here he is,
the challenger tonight,
Sugar Ray Leonard.
Looks very composed.
He looks very relaxed.
ANNOUNCER:
...world!
Roberto...
- Durén!
-(crowd booing)
COSELL: The man with
the hands of stone,
from Panama,
has to be regarded
as one of the greatest
fighters of all time.
And now Ray Charles,
in honor of whom
Sugar Ray Charles Leonard
was baptized,
will sing
"America the Beautiful."
(cheering, music begins)
♪ O beautiful ♪
♪ For purple mountain... ♪
♪ America ♪
♪ Sweet America ♪
♪ He done shed His grace ♪
IAnd you oughta
love Him for it ♪
♪ 'Cause He... ♪
♪ From sea to... ♪
Get out there and swim!
♪ Shining sea... ♪
-(cheering)
-Thank you, Ray.
Kick his ass, son.
- Oh, I will.
- Do it for me.
(cheering)
COSELL:
The action begins.
Leonard fighting
for pride tonight,
while Durén defends his place
in immortality.
CHILDREN (chanting):
Durén! Durén! Durén!
Durén! Durén!
COSELL:
There's Leonard.
That's what he wants
to do in this fight.
He says he did not
work his jab
efficiently
in the first fight.
RAY:
Stop following him!
Go after him!
Get him! Get him! After him!
COSELL: We have 2O seconds
left in the round.
RAY:
Suffocate him.
Up against the ropes!
No mercy!
Cut him off.
Get him up against the ropes.
Against the ropes!
COSELL: This is a much more
confident Leonard
we are seeing here tonight.
(bell clangs)
You gotta be the host.
You're acting like a guest.
You gotta pressure him, you
gotta put him on the ropes.
You gotta bang to the body.
It's your house.
Nobody else's. It's your house.
- You understand that, Cholo?
- I don't feel good.
You're letting this guy
run all over you.
He's running
in circles around you.
You know that he does,
-that's his defense.
- I don't feel good.
You don't feel good?
You ate too much.
Focus.
Don't let this guy run on you.
-(bell clangs) -Don't let him
run, don't let him run on you.
COSELL: Durén is falling
more and more,
-on his part... -Keep him
there, keep him there!
...into the pattern
of the first fight.
- Durén got in a good shot.
- Yeah!
- This is what Durén can do.
- That's it, that's it, Cholo.
Hey!
Durén is struggling
to contain Leonard.
You can see his anger
and frustration.
Cut him off!
COSELL:
Leonard is a moving target.
- And Durén is going...
- You get him! -(bell clangs)
(Speaking Spanish)
RAY: Get control of yourself.
Look at me! Look at me!
- Box, motherfucker!
- Listen.
- You gotta box him.
- Don't.
- You're letting him do that.
- I'm very fucking pissed.
COSELL:
Durén cannot get him
up against the ropes like
he did in the first fight.
Have you seen
the size of the ring?
They built the ring on purpose
so he can escape from me.
(crowd cheers)
COSELL:
The sneer is off his face.
Yes! Yes, Ray!
No, no, I'm a boxer.
I'm not a fucking ballerina...
I don't come here
to dance with a man.
(bell clangs)
COSELL:
And he's got Durén. Openly.
Not just furious but puzzled.
Durén troubled by the movement.
Dundee would be well advised,
I think,
to tell Leonard to stop that.
Leonard flaunting his skills.
(muttering)
And it is a vastly different
-human being...
- Stop following him around!
...that Durén is tonight.
(Juanita laughs)
That's right, baby!
Yeah!
Work on the body
and then up to the head.
- Everybody is laughing at me.
- No.
(laughing)
RAY:
Get out of your head.
I'm not a fucking clown in the,
-on the ring.
- Get, get out of your...
(bell clangs)
-(audience exclaims) -And he
caught him with the left!
Yes.
(bell clanging)
Calm down.
- You're let...
- I'm chasing the motherfucker.
You're let... L-Look at me.
You don't need to do that,
all right?
You're about to be
welterweight
champion of the world.
Get out of your head!
You're not doing
what you should be doing.
You know how to do it,
get out there.
I want to be proud of you.
I want you
to get out there
and I want you to...
Look at me'.
You're Roberto Duran.
Get in there and act like him.
(bell clanging)
Go to the body! Cut him off!
(cheering)
FA“
Hey.
RAY:
Cholo, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
-(cheering)
-COSELL: He... he quit!
Durén quit!
He said, "no més. "
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Cholo.
COSELL:
Roberto Durén has quit.
What are you doing?
You're going-- you can't.
The heck are you doing?
- You got to fight him.
- No. Fuck him.
- You've gotta fight him!
- No, no, he's a loser...
You can't. You've got to...
- Are you... What are you doing,
Cholo? -I'm not going to fight.
I didn't come here
to fight a clown.
- You gotta go fight.
- No, no, no, no, no.
They fuck me over.
- I've had enough.
- No, no!
I'm not a clown.
Listen, you have to go
in there and fight.
You can't do this.
- Why are you doing this?
-It's fucking bullshit.
JOURNALIST: Roberto.
Roberto, what happened?
I'm retiring from boxing.
COSELL: He, he said
he's retiring from boxing.
(quiet murmurs)
Suddenly, inexplicably,
the fight has ended.
Don't do it, Robbie!
Fight!
You have to fight!
(cheering, shouting)
FA“
(sobs)
Bullshit.
This is for America.
We did it! We did it!
Go.
FA“
RAY:
I don't care how much ability
you've got as a fighter.
(whooping)
If you can't think, you're
just another bum in the park.
Boxing is brain over brawn.
FA“
COMMISSIONER: Thousands
of people in the Super Dome
and millions more in
the closed circuit theaters
across the country
have been cheated
out of a fight
that they paid to see.
The commission and the public
deserve an explanation.
When a fighter loses
a fight in the ring,
it oftentimes
is the fighter's fault.
But when a fighter
loses a fight in his head,
it always is
the trainer's fault.
The cameras. The flashes.
The microphones.
The... hero worshipers.
Television can make anyone
think of himself as a god.
And I...
I probably failed at, uh,
keeping my fighter grounded.
But I can tell you this:
Roberto Duran 'vs no coward.
He did not leave the ring
out of fear of an opponent.
He left it out of pride.
COSELL: There is talk
of suspending Durén.
What would you say about that?
RAY:
I-l don't know what happened.
And if I don't,
then you don't.
But what I do know is
how Roberto Durén
began in life.
I know what
he willed himself to become.
I know the honor
he has brought this business,
which sometimes
doesn't deserve it.
And I know
you cannot suspend him.
He deserves better.
And if you don't
understand that
and you do this to him,
you will wake up tomorrow
and you will feel ashamed.
(shouting)
Faster, faster!
Get in there kids!
What's wrong with you?
Fuck you all!
FA“
PRESIDENT REAGAN:
We have no more right or reason
for giving away
the Panama Canal Zone
than we would
to now give away Alaska.
And I think that our
foreign policy should be one
and we, the people
who own the Canal,
should say to our government,
look, tell Mr. Torrijos
that we built that thing.
We bought the place.
We paid for it.
And we intend to keep it
from here on out.
(TV audience applauds)
(Speaks Spanish)
Come up here.
Get up.
Come.
Let's get out of here.
This is not life.
It's real life.
Your husband got fucked.
And everyone calls him a loser.
Show them wrong.
Why?
For money?
For the glory of Panama?
To hell with this nation of hypocrites.
Huh?
If life is such shit, why don't we stop it
like you stopped the fight?
NO! No!
-(screams)
-(Durén shouts in Spanish)
Cholo! No! No!
(glass breaks, Felicidad gasps)
I'm done.
Go find another woman.
I can have thousands of women.
I'm taking the kids.
Go to hell, but the kids stay here.
I'm leaving with my kids!
The kids are mine.
(pounding at door)
What?
(door shuts)
Speak for God's sake!
President Torrijos was killed.
FA“
(Durén sighs)
(bell tolling,
indistinct chatter)
MAN".
Chow:!
Get in the ring and I'll kill you.
Come have lunch with us, kid.
I don't need your food.
I earn my meals fighting.
You'll soon be begging for my autograph.
Well said, champ.
Who says well said?
You are not from El Chorrillo anymore.
"No Mas: shit from you.
I'll send you to the morgue
and make you quit again!
Ungrateful kid.
It's never enough!
Without Torrijos' leadership
this country will go to shit.
Let's go home, Robert.
(panting)
(birds singing, waves crashing)
They are right.
The hope of El Chorrillo walked away.
I walked away from the fight.
I walked away just like my father.
(faint voices shouting)
Yeah!
I let them down.
I let them down and I let you down.
I don't need to be the champion,
but I need to fight.
I'm going to fight.
(laughs softly)
DURAN: I need you to train me,
Dad. Please don't say no.
I'm sorry. I'm retired.
I can't.
You're my father, man.
You're the only one I have.
Listen. I-l can't.
L-I'm done with it.
And it has nothing
to do with you.
We're talking about me now.
I'm old. I'm tired.
You don't need me.
You never really did.
You're a naturally
great fighter.
You have great
fighter's instincts.
I was just there
to support you.
That's not true.
I need you in my corner, Ray.
Not anymore, you don't.
You're an adult now.
You have children of your own.
You don't need a father.
You need somebody to bring
the street back into you.
- Talk to Plomo.
- Plomo?
He knows you
better than anybody.
He's been with you
from the beginning.
I'll help you get a fight.
I'll be watching you
all the time.
But get Plomo
to bring you back.
That's who you need.
- Okay.
- And please,
always remember.
The American
you're talking to now?
He gave you
the best years of his life.
(dial tone)
(phone beeps)
Schmuck.
You have no reason
to feel guilty here.
Well, he's my fighter, so...
Yeah, well...
You need to do what you think
is best for everyone.
What do you think is best?
It depends.
You think that he's the one
that needs you the most
right now?
FA“
RAY: To prepare him
for his comeback,
the first thing Plomo did
was take Durén
to the spiritual heart
of Panama...
FA“
...the procession of
the Black Christ of Portobelo.
FA“
Plomo had promised Durén
when he was a kid
that if he went off track,
he'd take him back to jail.
So he did.
FA“
(grunting)
CARBO: I made a lot of money
on that fight.
Whatever you need,
the answer's already yes.
- Roberto Durén.
- Fuck no.
(crowd clamoring)
He's bad news, Ray.
You can do better
than that bum.
He needs a comeback.
He quit.
Understand? You can't do that.
Unless we tell you to.
No més.
No més, my ass.
Nobody's gonna pay
to see that spick.
How about Davey Moore?
Davey Moore?
I mean,
he's a 24-year-old monster.
You'll get Durén killed.
Isn't that what everybody
wants to see
-after what he did
in New Orleans? -Maybe.
I certainly would pay
to see Durén get a beating.
- I'll think about it.
- Okay.
I'm gonna think about it.
(clamoring continues)
(crowd cheering in distance)
(door creaks, closes)
(footsteps approaching)
(cheering continues)
You were the best fighter
in the world.
And I want to see that
back in the ring.
You're just happy
it will be another black guy
getting punched tonight.
No shit.
(chuckles)
Thank you.
(whispers):
Yeah, man.
And tell your wife...
I'm sorry.
I will.
(crowd cheering)
LEONARD:
Well, tonight happens to be
Roberto Durén's 32nd birthday,
and he's promised to turn
Madison Square Garden's fight
into a party
for he and his friends.
- Did Ray come?
- Why are you thinking about Ray?
I am Sugar Ray Leonard
reporting to you
on behalf of CBS Sports.
ANNOUNCER: Ray, I know
you respect your former rival,
but let's see if he even
finishes this one.
-(man speaking Spanish over TV)
-(kids shouting excitedly)
LEONARD: But Durén's experience
is sure to play
a great deal
in the fight tonight.
He started out
as a lightweight,
and now he's fighting
as a light middleweight.
Now, that's a tremendous jump
for any fighter.
(crowd continues cheering)
REFEREE: Okay, I gave
both of you instructions
in the dressing room.
I want to remind you.
Obey my commands at all times.
LEONARD:
He is younger, stronger,
with a far longer reach,
but I can tell you
from first, right
and left hand experience
why they call Manos de Piedra
Hands of Stone.
-(bell dings)
-(crowd cheering)
(camera clicks)
(grunting)
ANNOUNCER: Moore has power in
that right, and Durén felt it.
(grunting)
Moore wants to get Durén
out of here!
(bell dings)
FA“
Can Durén withstand
-the punishment he's taking?
-(bell dings)
We could be seeing the end
of Roberto Durén.
-(bell dings)
-(crowd continues cheering)
Duran is on the attack.
He is going all in.
How big a risk is this
against the younger Moore?
(cheering continues)
(bell dings)
How are you feeling?
I wanna take these gloves off and kill him!
That's the way to do it.
No mercy.
Focus on him.
He's yours. He's already dead.
Breathe...
That's it. Let's go.
I love you.
You know how much.
You are my son.
You are my hero.
(Plomo shouts in Spanish)
CROWD Qchanfing)".
Duran: Duran: Duran: Duran:!
-(bell dings)
-(Plomo shouts)
(crowd cheering)
FA“
ANNOUNCER: Durén has found
a home for that right hand!
He's landing it now.
FA“
(crowd cheering)
LEONARD:
And there's the towel!
Roberto Duran 'vs the new
super welterweight champion
of the world!
And it's his birthday.
-(crowd cheering)
- ♪ ♪
("Simbolo" by Rubén Blades
playing)
(Speaks Spanish)
You're back, my love.
(kids cheering)
(crowd chanting)
Ray!
(excited chatter)
FA“
Happy birthday, Papa!
(cheering continues)
Happy birthday!
Yeah! Thank you!
-(crowd cheering)
-(cameras clicking)
("Champions" by Usher
and Rubén Blades playing)
FA“
(man singing in Spanish)
("Bonjour Madame"
by Camilo Azuquita playing)
FA“
(song ends)
(music fades)