I would like to take the opportunity
to pay homage to the Gautama Buddha.
I am begging you
to forgive me for all of my sins.
Please rejoice in my merit.
And you have made great merit,
please share it with me.
Sadhu. I rejoice in your merit.
Fuck.
Shit.
Help!
THUMMANAKANIMIT TEMPLE
Hurry up.
The last bus to Bangkae and Tha Phra
is about to leave.
You better hurry.
Wait for us.
-Wait for us.
-Let's go.
Oh, my god.
-What's with your hat?
-Please speed up.
Shit.
Tell me beforehand next time
if you will dress up like this.
Just think of it as a trip to Milan.
Oh, my god. What kind of ride is that?
Stop acting like a princess, First.
Hey.
It's cold up here.
It's so easy to breathe.
Balloon.
I'm glad that
you won the lottery. However,
did you give your boyfriend the car
to drive to Bangkok when I was asleep?
Just because he forgot to feed the dog?
Guys,
my boyfriend's dog is pitiful.
If it doesn't get to eat...
Hey.
Is your boyfriend's dog
more important than your friends?
I told you to rent a private car,
but you wouldn't listen.
Is the car under your boyfriend's name?
Did you transfer the ownership to him?
No. Are you crazy?
I would never transfer
the ownership to him.
You bitch.
You already did, didn't you?
What's wrong?
What's wrong? Calm down.
I'm sorry.
Her epilepsy is acting up.
He's so handsome.
Over there.
Leave it to me.
-Guys.
-What?
-How is he?
-He's handsome.
Hello. My name is Balloon.
-Right.
-Guys, come here quick.
-Pongsit!
Yes, it's me.
BANGKOK TO NAKHON PATHOM
-What?
-Keep walking straight.
Have a safe trip.
Guys.
Keep it down.
Guys, I miss the time
when we were in university.
Do you remember?
I hadn't seen you for a long time though.
How have you been?
I was fine at first
but now that I'm here with you--
You must feel even better now.
So, can you tell me
where you work now?
I just got fired.
People say it's because of my unlucky age,
but I think it's nonsense.
Your unlucky age?
Are you 25 years old now?
Yes, I turned 25 years old today.
Guys.
It's his birthday today.
One, two, three.
-Happy birthday to you
-Poon.
-Yes?
-Keep it down.
Please tell them to shut it.
-Okay.
-Happy birthday
-To you
-Hey.
Happy birthday...
-Stop.
-Happy birthday to you
-Poon.
-Stop already.
Don't go yet. Come here.
-What is it?
-Look at it. Do you see it?
Happy birthday to you
-Do you?
-I don't see anything.
-Happy birthday to you
-You don't? What are you looking at?
-Look in the mirror, not the road.
-Happy birthday to you
-The mirror.
-Happy birthday...
I don't see anything.
-Then, let's look at it together.
-Happy birthday to you
-Okay.
Oh, my god. The driver fainted.
-Oh, no.
Oh, no. What should we do?
Got, it has to be you.
-What should we do?
-You can drive it, Got.
-I can't.
-Pull yourself together.
Go right now.
Calm down. Got...
-Does he even know how to drive?
-Fuck. Eyes on the road.
Right.
I'm trying.
-Got.
-Balloon, help me drive this thing.
Guys, I don't want to die today.
BANGKOK TO NAKHON PATHOM
The patient is safe now.
Nong.
How do you feel, Nong?
Got is dead.
Got.
Nong.
You can't say the accident
happened because of fate.
What about the people who died?
What did they have to do with it?
What about Balloon and First?
What did they do?
Why did this happen to them?
You can call me superstitious.
Or do you want to die like your friend?
So must I be ordained
to make my life better?
I won't get hit by a car
if I walk on the expressway.
I won't get burnt if I walk on fire.
Is that what you want?
Would I be a monk or an Avenger?
Nong.
Everyone.
Wait for me in there.
Did you see the person
who just went inside?
You know,
he isn't half
as lucky as you
because his parents
passed away before he could be ordained.
He has nothing to do with me.
I don't think getting ordained
is important at all.
Doesn't the importance
rely on the person getting ordained?
Would it have been important
if it was your mother
who asked you to get ordained?
THUMMANAKANIMIT TEMPLE
Who did you promise
to get ordained for?
Who did we promise?
We never promised anyone.
I did.
I made a vow
that I would get ordained
if I won the lottery.
That's your problem.
It doesn't concern me.
It does.
I vowed
that if I won the lottery,
all three of us would get ordained.
All three of us?
Balloon,
you're gay.
How could you vow to get ordained?
I wasn't thinking.
You should have.
Luang Loong.
Yes?
-Since he already made the vow,
-Yes.
what should we do now, Luang Loong?
Fulfill your vow
at the place you made it.
This is the shrine
where First and I made the vow.
PEE NAK SHRINE
Here.
Why are you giving it to me?
Keep it with you.
You will know
when the time comes.
Pee Nak,
I came to fulfill my vow.
We are here to get ordained
because this bitch made the vow.
Sadhu.
My god.
Hello, Luang Pee.
We are here to get ordained.
Balloon.
He's hot.
I don't mind being here for three phansa.
First.
You will never be lonely.
-Gosh.
Hell will get you.
Are you jealous, Nong?
You just had to pick this temple.
Will I have Internet here?
-What the hell?
-Oh, no.
What's with her?
We're sorry.
Why did I apologize?
Should we beat her up?
Before you beat her up,
you should wake Nong up first.
Nong.
Nong, pull yourself together.
-Let go.
-Fine.
Look at me, honey.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
So, that's the story.
That's why all three of us
decided to get ordained here.
Miss.
Call me mister.
You're gay, right?
We are all straight men here.
How could you think we're gay?
Right, First?
Yes.
Hey, guys.
Keep it down.
Are you sure you want to
get ordained at this temple?
Please don't discriminate us.
We will get ordained
at this temple no matter what.
That's not the case.
If that's not the case,
then what's the problem here?
The problem is you are gay.
Aod.
Did it hurt, baby?
Take these three to their sitter.
Bring chanting books too.
Yes, Luang Por.
Remove your nail color.
Your sitter
is very strict.
Aod, are we almost there?
Yes, we're here.
Are you the three people
who want to get ordained?
Luang Por
texted me just now.
So,
will you be our sitter?
Yes.
Will you be able to handle it?
Listen.
Can we get
a young and handsome monk?
Can we get the one we met at the shrine?
The monk with fair skin, huge biceps,
a high nose bridge, sweet eyes,
-and his face--
-Mister.
There isn't such a person.
In this temple,
Luang Por, the abbot,
is the only monk here.
Besides him, this novice and I
are the best looking ones.
-Then the person I met--
-Everyone,
I'll take you to your rooms.
Come on, Aod.
We have a ceremony in the evening.
What about the hot monk over there?
Just follow me.
I don't know anyone like that.
I knew it. It's so heavy.
I just had to bring so much.
Oh, my god. Help me!
Oh, no.
Shit.
Luang Por.
Gosh.
There is a coffin!
-A gecko!
-First.
My room has a coffin, First.
First, my room has a coffin.
Talk to me...
What kind of person eats a fucking gecko?
It bit my lip.
You shithead.
-It's dirty.
-Damn it.
Bitch.
Wait.
What are you doing?
I'll get that gecko out of your lip.
What about my face?
Help me.
Stay still.
Stay still, okay?
One, two,
three.
Nong.
Fuck.
-Shit.
-Nong.
First.
If you can get this snake off of me,
I'll let you touch my snake.
Are you serious?
Yes. Hurry up.
Gosh.
It's licking me. Hurry up.
All right.
First.
-Hurry.
-First, the head.
-I'll pee my pants.
-It's looking at you.
-Be careful.
-I'll pee my pants.
The tail, First. Watch its tail.
First.
-Hurry.
-I can't.
Please do it. I can't take it anymore.
It's a freaking snake!
Get out, Nong. Get out.
I'm leaving.
Nong.
Gosh.
Oh, my god.
What's going on?
-So long.
-Hey, wait.
Take this. Here.
Here's 500 baht for you.
Get us a new room. Let us sleep together.
Move my things to the new room too.
Hey, wait.
We need help at the temple.
Yes, I know. I'll be there.
Gosh.
My god.
I can't do this anymore.
-Please take it from me.
-Oh, no. Don't.
Gosh.
First!
This is it.
You guys can sleep here.
It's big enough
for the three of you.
Aod.
Why did you bring them here?
They will be ordained soon.
They shouldn't be involved with funerals.
It's inauspicious.
That's right.
Well...
Luang Por,
I invited the monks from Sai Temple.
And I informed them that you were sick
and won't be joining today.
Thank you so much.
Luang Por,
you should rest.
I'll take care of this end.
-Gosh.
-Thank you.
Gosh.
Wait.
Balloon.
-Come here.
-What now?
Come now.
He looks familiar.
Have we met him before?
Hang on.
How can he not look familiar?
He's lying right here.
Do you want to talk to him?
JAKKAPONG WONGWALLEE, 25 YEARS OLD
Jui doesn't have any relatives anymore.
Her parents recently passed away.
And now her brother too.
Hello, I'm Nong.
Let me help with the funeral.
Nong.
-What?
-Do you want a selfie stick?
You're sticking your face
all the way there.
Hey.
The monks are praying.
BORN
Do you want a piece of me?
Aren't you afraid of monks at all?
All right then.
THUMMANAKANIMIT TEMPLE SCHOOL
I don't hear anything.
What?
-Oh, my god.
-What happened?
Get the car ready. Get the car now.
Wait, Luang Pee.
The ceremony isn't complete yet.
-Let's leave it here today. I'm busy.
-What?
-We'll continue tomorrow.
-But...
-Wait.
-Why are you sitting there? Let's go.
-Wait for us.
Is it happening again?
PEE NAK SHRINE
Do you think
something's off about this temple?
Balloon.
Did you just realize this?
I think
since we stepped inside the temple,
nothing was normal,
especially
that old man over there.
First!
You're too loud.
Did you want him to hear you?
Keep it down.
First.
Balloon.
Thank you very much.
You are welcome.
What?
What are you thanking us for?
At first, I was going to stay
with the body alone tonight.
However, Nong said you guys volunteered
to stay here on my behalf
-What?
-because a girl staying here alone
may not be
appropriate.
Fuck you.
Of course.
We will
take the best care of him. Don't worry.
First, you...
-How can we sleep here?
-Thank you so much.
All right.
You idiot.
Why on earth did you agree
to stay with the body tonight, First?
It's Nong.
He sent me this sign.
You would do anything for a man.
Hello.
You are here with Balloon again.
We are live at a funeral.
So what? Who cares?
You're not even scared of your ugly face.
Those who are interested, please confirm.
We have a promotion today.
"You look prettier."
I'll give you a discount.
"Hey,
I see a hand from the coffin."
Where?
You guys are joking around
because you know I'm scared of ghosts.
I'm not scared even if I'm in a temple.
Don't try to fucking trick me.
You guys are at it.
Why are you typing so much?
I'm never scared of anything.
Let them come.
Let ten of them come.
Let's continue with our sales.
"It's even higher up now, sis."
Who's your sister?
Where?
Can it get any higher?
Stop trying to trick me.
Leave if you don't want to buy anything.
"The whole body is there."
He's here, isn't he?
First.
Nong.
What the fuck?
First, Nong, guys!
What the hell is wrong with you?
-Oh, my god.
-What's with you? You scared me.
The thought came to me.
What thought?
Look to my left.
This photo.
What photo?
This photo. Think about it.
At the shrine.
What shrine?
The shrine we were at this evening.
The handsome monk.
The handsome monk with the hot body.
The handsome monk?
Stop drooling, bitch.
First.
Then who's in the coffin?
It's him. You dumbass.
You're calling me dumb again.
You are dumb. You wouldn't listen to me.
You didn't explain it to me, First.
I tried, but you kept pointing at things.
You wouldn't listen.
I'm not the only dumb one here, idiot.
Did you call me an idiot? How could you?
You wouldn't explain it to me properly.
I explained it to you.
Shut up!
What have you done?
What the hell are you guys doing?
Hey. What the hell?
Hey, it's me.
It's me.
Damn it, Nong.
Why would you put on a face mask?
You put it on for me.
Why the fuck did you freak out then?
I'm sorry. I forgot.
Nong, we were haunted.
-It was so scary.
-What the hell have you done?
Put the coffin back right now,
or we'll be scolded by Luang Por.
Aren't you holding onto me too tightly?
I'm scared, Nong.
Shit.
-Shit.
-What?
The body is gone.
Are you sure, Nong?
Look carefully.
Look at it.
What should we do?
Look behind the curtain.
I'm not wearing my contact lens.
I can't see.
What?
Nong.
You left me.
First, you look at it.
My glasses are foggy. I can't see. Here.
What's wrong with you?
Guys, I can't see.
You're not blind.
Fuck.
I'm scared.
There's nothing to be scared of.
Balloon, how was it?
-What happened?
-Balloon.
Hey. Balloon.
Balloon, don't.
I'm leaving.
Hey. Balloon.
Balloon, wait.
What's going on here?
Luang Por.
The legend at this temple
is quite paranormal.
No one can never fully
become a monk at this temple.
-What?
In these past years,
people who came to get ordained
usually died at the stage of being a nak.
No one has successfully become a monk yet.
-Fuck.
You didn't swear at me, did you?
I did.
Hey.
Please continue. I wasn't swearing at you.
People say
that the person who died
would come to find someone
to take his place.
He would come to haunt
and kill the next person.
Sometimes at night,
you would see a nak parade
heading to the temple
but no one
would have a head.
And the cheering
would turn into a painful moaning instead.
Therefore, everyone concludes that
people who get ordained at this temple
will die mysteriously.
And they say the closer you are
to the ceremony,
the scarier it gets.
Oh, my god.
Balloon.
Did you not do a research
beforehand at all?
Bitch.
You would have found out
that the temple is really haunted.
Novice,
then please let the three of us
sleep with you tonight.
What?
Wait for me.
My eyebrows are getting ruined, bitch.
Is this the time?
Apply more powder.
Try it and you might be as pretty as me.
Hey.
Keep it down.
Do I not have enough makeup, Nong?
Nong said I didn't have enough.
Your face is as thick as a boxer's face.
First.
Did the wound that gecko left you
disappear already?
Don't tell me you had a plastic surgeon
to Netflix and chill at the temple.
It doesn't concern you.
I did things my way.
How do my eyebrows look right now?
Balloon.
Why would we need Arabica coffee
when we have
a hot guy like him to keep us awake?
Since we came,
I've only seen monks and ghosts.
I haven't seen any hot guys.
Which direction?
Your nine o'clock.
Nine o'clock.
Hottie.
How can gay men get ordained?
They are going wild
just seeing a man taking a shower.
It's inappropriate.
Balloon, First, let's go.
-Let's go.
-This one.
What's this can?
-Let's go.
-First.
First.
What?
What's wrong?
-What's wrong?
-First.
Wait. Hold me. My back hurts.
-Let's go.
-Don't go yet.
It might go back to sleep.
Come on. Let's go inside.
First.
Shall we kick their butts?
How dare you insult me?
Damn them.
Is this your Nak Prok pendant?
Yes, it's mine.
Aod found it
when he was moving your things,
but he forgot to give it back.
I've prepared your tuition fee.
Don't worry.
Did you transfer money to a guy again?
You're about to be ordained.
First,
I'm just here to fulfill my vow.
I'm not here to fucking get enlightened.
Can you stop fooling yourself?
You're gay. You don't have a uterus.
Shouldn't you save this money
for your future?
Think about your disabled mother.
First.
What?
My mom isn't disabled.
That was Got's mother.
I forgot.
By the way, what has gotten into you?
Don't tell me
that you haven't told your dad
about ordaining.
We'll only be ordained for a short while.
It's not a big deal.
First,
this ordainment
will make a military man like your father
proud of a beautiful gay son like you.
This yellow piece of cloth
will send your dad to heaven
faster than taking a jet plane.
My dad wouldn't even let me
wear a skirt.
Would he be able to take it?
You haven't even tried telling him though.
Do you have dermatophytosis?
-No, I don't.
Do you have bronchiectasis?
Do you have epilepsy?
-No, I don't.
Are you a human being?
-Yes, I am.
Look over there, human.
Hey, what's with that script?
Oh, shit.
What do you mean?
That ghost is out in daylight.
It's not afraid at all.
Do you see it?
That's a human, not a ghost, Balloon.
-Thief!
Balloon. Hey...
You old hag, you can't steal things
from the temple.
You can't do that.
Guys, what the hell?
-Guys, what's with her?
-What's wrong with her?
-Nong, what's wrong with her?
-What?
-Nong.
-Oh, my god.
What the hell?
-Nak.
-Nak?
Guys.
I'm not a nak.
Nong.
-Nak.
-Nong.
-What should we do?
-Guys.
-Nong.
-Hey.
-No.
-Nak.
-Help me.
-Let my friend go, you psycho.
-Nak.
Guys, help me.
He's mine.
Who said so?
-Oh, my god.
-Get out.
Hey, you!
-Hey.
-Let go, old hag.
-Let him go.
-First.
-Miss.
-Nong.
Who is she?
You don't need to know.
You should just worry about yourselves.
Nak.
-Let's go. That's not him.
-Nak.
-What?
-He's not a nak.
-He's not.
-Nak.
You psycho!
Who the hell is she?
Why does she act like she knows me?
Guys.
I wonder the same.
That old man too.
-He looks suspicious somehow.
-Guys.
Is this a temple
or a murder scene in Conan?
There are so many mysterious characters.
Will I get to ordain?
-Guys, it hurts.
-Are you all right?
Oh, no. It's all over you.
Farewell, Jak.
It will be okay.
Jak has gone to a better place.
Thank you so much for your help, Nong.
Please accept my condolences.
Try not to think too much.
-What's wrong, Nong?
-Nong.
-What?
-What's wrong?
-Calm down. What's wrong?
-Nong.
-What's wrong?
-What did you see?
-Say something.
-What's going on?
-Nothing.
-I'm fine.
-What?
-Is he fine?
-Jui.
-Nong.
-I'll see you later.
What's going on, Nong?
Nong.
What happened?
You looked troubled back there.
Nong.
Are you all right?
I think the ghost
that has been haunting us
isn't Jak's ghost.
Did you see its face?
Its arm
was full of tattoos.
And do you remember
that Jak's body
had no tattoos at all?
It could be a different ghost.
Jeez.
What the hell?
I almost went crazy because of one ghost.
And now there's a second one.
...unguents or adornments.
-...unguents or adornments.
I will not sleep in comfortable beds...
-I will not sleep in comfortable beds...
...with padding or cotton.
-...with padding or cotton.
I will not touch
or accept money...
-I will not touch
-or accept money...
...that will profit us.
-...that will profit us.
Can you cite it
without looking at the book?
I will
not
dance--
-It's "listen."
-Oh, my...
You scared me.
...listen to music
or watch any drama--
"Any dance"!
You keep wanting to watch dramas.
This is a religious chant,
not "Sabai Sabai" by Thongchai McIntyre
that I listened to since I was young.
Who could memorize all of these?
Exactly, and there are ten rules.
We can barely chant
the most basic prayer.
Aod, give us some time.
He's right.
How long do you need?
You're already behind schedule.
Let's do it again.
-I will not touch
-or accept money
-that will profit us.
I will not
listen
to music
or watch any dance.
I will not
decorate myself
with garlands,
perfumes,
unguents,
or adornments.
I will not sleep
in comfortable beds
with padding or cotton.
I will not touch...
What's next?
"Or accept money."
Oh, right.
That will profit us...
Balloon.
First.
Hey.
Balloon.
First.
Hey.
You can come out now.
Balloon.
First.
I'll seriously kick you guys.
Stop joking around.
Hey.
First.
Oh, my god. Aod!
Since when were you here?
Are you sure that you want
to get ordained?
It's not too late to change your mind.
What do you mean?
What's with you?
Your pendant looks nice.
Doesn't it make you uncomfortable?
I warned you.
No.
Hey.
Let me go.
I will kill everyone
who gets ordained.
What...
No.
No!
What's wrong?
Novice,
a ghost haunted me last night.
He said he would kill all of us
if we got ordained.
Why does the ghost
want to take revenge on naks?
Can we not become a nak, Novice?
Can we just skip it and become monks?
No.
Becoming a nak
is a very important process
because there's a story behind it.
Once, there was the Phaya Nak
who transformed himself into a human
because he believed in Buddhism.
He came to get ordained.
However, later,
the truth was revealed
that he wasn't human
but a nak who disguised himself.
Naks like him didn't deserve
to be born as a human.
He couldn't get ordained
because he would never be enlightened
if everyone found out he was a nak.
The nak was very disappointed when
he heard that he couldn't get ordained.
However, he left his name
with other humans
who were getting ordained,
to receive merit
that he couldn't do it himself.
As for him,
he vowed to serve Buddhism
in other ways.
And that is why
newly ordained people
are called "naga" or "nak" since then.
Keep in mind
that you deserved merit
enough to be born as human
with an opportunity to get ordained.
The nak didn't kill Jak, did he?
Well...
How are you feeling?
Are you okay?
At first, I wasn't okay.
But I'm starting to accept the truth.
Eventually,
people part ways.
It's just a matter of time.
Jui.
Well, Jui.
It's done.
You can collect his ashes.
-Okay.
Please excuse me then.
I'll talk to you next time.
Okay.
Where's the noise coming from?
My god.
Who's that?
Is that you, Nong?
Yes.
Oh, gosh.
Nong.
Why didn't you tell me
you were coming here?
You scared me, Nong.
Nong.
Are you farting lightly
or breathing really heavily?
Are you all right, Nong?
Oh, my god. Nong, the lights went off.
Where's my flashlight?
Nong, are you still there?
Why is this happening to me?
I need to shit.
Nong, you didn't wait for me.
Please, wait for me.
Nong!
Nong.
Are you in here, Nong?
Nong, is that you?
To be honest,
I like seeing you take a shower.
But isn't it a bit odd
to take shower
at this late hour?
Nong.
I'm scared, Nong.
Oh, my god.
Nong.
Please hurry up and finish your shower.
I'm scared, Nong.
I'm scared. Gosh!
Nong.
Why is your neck like that, Nong?
-Damn it, First. What's wrong?
-I'm scared.
First, it's me.
-No. Don't.
-It's me.
What's wrong?
Hey.
Don't possess me.
What? I'm human.
I don't believe you.
-Homage to the blessed...
-First, it's me.
I'm human, Mr. Chartchai.
Here. Touch me if you don't believe me.
Okay.
I'm still not certain though.
What the hell?
Hey.
That's enough.
Are you human?
Of course.
If you're really human,
then you must remember
the promise you gave me.
What promise?
That I could touch your snake.
Oh, my god. Fuck you.
First.
Fuck you.
Damn you.
Stop. I'm sorry. It hurts. Oh, my god.
What the hell was that?
It's really you.
Of course, it is.
I will kill everyone who gets in my way.
Hey.
Hang on, First.
What?
I hear a bell ringing.
Who would ring a bell at this hour?
-Balloon.
Let's go there now.
Oh, my god.
-Balloon.
-What are you doing?
-Help me, First.
Why are you banging your head on the bell?
What sort of crazy person rings their head
on a bell? I can't control it, dumbass.
-What? This isn't right, bitch.
-Help me.
Damn it.
-Nong.
-Hey.
What the hell, First?
-It's a ghost.
-Why aren't we helping him?
-Help me, you fucktards.
-You can't, Nong.
-He will die.
-We will die.
-Nong, don't.
-Hey.
-Move aside right now.
-No.
-Move.
First, Nong, help me.
-First, help me.
-Balloon.
Balloon.
-Help him.
Guys...
-Hang on, Balloon.
-Balloon, what's going on?
Shit.
Balloon.
First, hold this.
Stand on my shoulders.
Balloon, are you okay?
Put it down.
I'm doing it.
Climb up.
Cut it.
My God.
Balloon.
-How's he, Nong?
-Oh, no.
He's not breathing.
Balloon.
I must perform CPR on him.
Wait.
Nong.
You can't.
Leave it to me.
Balloon.
I'll save you.
Don't.
First.
Balloon.
Why did you hit me, bitch?
You can't kiss me, bitch. I'm your friend.
Guys.
What?
I heard the ghost say
he will kill everyone
who gets in his way.
Who will get in his way besides us
who want to get ordained?
Thus indeed
Is that blessed one
-He is the holy one
-Fully enlightened
Endowed with clear vision
-And virtuous conduct
-Sublime
-The knower of the worlds
-Knower of the worlds
The incomparable leader of men
To be tamed
The teacher of gods and men
Enlightened and blessed
If I don't get to be ordained,
then no one will.
Luang Por.
Normally, Luang Por
wakes up before everyone.
Why didn't he wake up today?
I wonder the same.
Is Luang Por sick?
Aod.
Oh, my...
What's going on?
Luang Por!
-What is it, Aod?
-Aod, open the door.
Aod, open the door.
Luang Por.
-Luang Por.
Aod, how is he?
Luang Por.
-Luang Por.
Novice,
the undertaker wants me to tell you
that Luang Por's relatives
will come to bring his body home.
Aod.
Luang Por isn't with us anymore.
How will we carry on?
Our temple has no monk.
Stay strong, Aod.
You'll have monks.
You have the three of us.
Thank you so much.
But I'm fine now.
Tomorrow,
I'll prepare for your ordainment.
Please excuse me.
I'll help Grandpa out.
That's okay, Aod.
I'll go.
I want to check on Novice too.
Oh, no.
What's wrong?
First.
Taohoo broke up with me.
He said he knocked up a girl.
It's okay.
If only I didn't make the damn vow,
all of this shit wouldn't have happened.
I would still be with him.
Luang Por would still be alive.
All of this didn't happen
because of your vow.
Balloon.
What will you do?
-Balloon.
-Wait.
What will you do, Balloon?
Everything started at the shrine.
Therefore, it must end at the shrine.
Move aside!
Why did Jui come?
Balloon.
Balloon, don't.
-What do you want?
-Don't do it.
What will you get
out of destroying the shrine?
You could die.
I've had enough with this fucking ghost.
Move aside!
Fuck you.
Fuck you. I can't take it anymore.
I made a vow,
and you wanted me to fulfill it.
Now that I'm here,
you wouldn't let me get ordained.
What do you want with me?
Calm down.
Stay out of it.
I have had enough with you, dumb ghost.
PEE NAK SHRINE
You decided to piss me off?
All right then.
You wanted to piss me off, right?
-Here you go.
-Hey.
Hey.
Jui.
Why didn't you say goodbye?
Nong.
Actually, I was going to leave
after Jak's ordainment.
But then he passed away,
so I asked my office
if I could stay here longer.
But you are the reason
that I'm staying here to get ordained.
Nong.
Why exactly did you come here
to get ordained?
You were just like me.
We were heartbroken.
Something bad happened to us,
so we needed someone to rely on.
You may think
that you have feelings for me.
But actually, you don't really love me.
You're just afraid of being alone.
I felt the same way.
I didn't want to be alone.
I'm sorry.
The only thing you should be thinking
about right now is your ordainment.
Do it for yourself
and your father.
Nong.
Something bad has happened.
What is it, Novice?
Aod called and said
that Balloon went to destroy the shrine.
What?
That's enough.
-Balloon, enough.
-Stop.
There comes the alms bowl.
That's enough.
-Nong, let's go.
-Balloon.
-Nong, hurry.
What the hell are you doing? Get out.
Balloon, what the hell are you doing?
-There.
-Oh, my god.
What are you doing? You will kill us all.
Look at what he did.
Show yourself.
Balloon.
Don't just make a sound.
Hello.
I'm selling ice-cream.
Here. I have black bean
and coconut milk flavors.
Do you want one?
Damn it, you old man!
-Hey.
-Balloon.
-Calm down.
-Hey.
Damn it.
Look.
Nak.
Where did Nak go?
Nak, where did you go?
-Go away.
-What do you want?
Get out.
My child.
-Let's help her out.
-My child.
-My child!
-Oh, my...
My child!
My child.
Nak.
Miss,
I'm sorry.
I got carried away.
Go away.
-Go away.
-It's okay.
-It will be okay.
-My friend didn't mean it.
-Go away.
-Please calm down.
-I'm sorry.
-Go away.
I said, go away!
-Oh, my god.
-Go away.
-Miss.
-Wait, miss.
What should we do, Novice?
What the hell have you done, Balloon?
Why didn't you think before you did it?
Guys.
This photo.
What?
Look, Nong.
We must find out
who this nak is
and how he's related to this woman.
Who can we ask about this?
Guys.
You could ask my grandpa.
Grandpa,
I know
that you know who this guy is
and how he's related to Pee Nak's ghost.
It's been a long time already.
I, myself,
tried to forget about Non, the Nak.
I think it was seven years ago.
There was a woman
named Phorn.
She brought her son, Non, to this temple
to get ordained.
Non, the Nak,
used to be a gangster.
He went to prison many times.
And he was also arrested for murder.
But then one day,
he wanted to get ordained
for his mother.
However, on the day of his ordainment,
he passed away.
THUMMANAKANIMIT TEMPLE
-What?
-Nak? Where?
Move aside.
Move aside. Make way.
-No.
-Hurry.
Nak!
Nak Non!
Nak Non.
Non.
Non, here's the lotus. Hold the lotus.
Let's head in the chapel.
It's almost time.
Phorn was devastated.
She became crazy.
She told everyone
to not touch
-her son's body.
-Don't touch him. He's not dead.
You can't take him away.
As we are speaking, his body
is being kept in the old chapel
behind the temple.
Stay away from my child.
So that's what happened.
Damn it, Balloon.
Balloon, enough.
Why did I have to be that hot-headed?
Why does Nak Non's pendant
look exactly like Nong's pendant?
Nong, look at this picture.
That's Luang Loong.
He's Luang Loong
that we met in the hospital, right?
Why are you giving it to me?
Keep it with you.
You will know when the time comes.
-Nak, my child.
-Nong.
Can I see the pendant you're wearing?
This is the same Nak Prok pendant
that Non, the Nak,
gave to this monk before he passed away.
It's this pendant.
Phorn.
Go away.
Miss, I'm sorry.
They are here to apologize, Phorn.
Phorn, it's okay.
-Miss, I'm sorry.
-It's okay.
Miss, I didn't mean to do it.
It's okay.
I'll fix the shrine for you.
PEE NAK SHRINE
It's fixed.
Tomorrow,
the three of us will be ordained.
I would like to dedicate
my ordainment to Phorn
on your behalf.
He will be ordained for you.
We would like you
to forgive us
for everything we've done in the past.
-Mister.
-Yes.
I would like to return
this Nak Prok pendant to Nak Non.
I see. Okay.
I'll hold it for you.
Do you feel better now?
That's good.
You should get some rest.
Your ordainment is tomorrow, isn't it?
As for Phorn,
I'll take care of her.
-I respectfully request the sangha
-for the third time to ordain me
-as a monk.
-I beg the sangha out of compassion
-to lift me up from the status
-of a nak.
We finally got it right.
It will finally be over soon.
I can't wait for tomorrow.
Listen.
If we get ordained,
the curse that has been going on here
will end.
Oh, right.
Balloon.
Nong.
I have something to tell you.
My dad will come tomorrow.
Did your dad finally accept who you are?
I guess so.
This ordainment
is the only thing
that makes my dad proud of me.
What about you?
You people have daddy issues.
I don't know.
I didn't invite him.
But he knows that I came to get ordained.
If he wants to come, he'll show up.
Where's the bell ringing coming from?
Oh, I know.
It must be that ice-cream man.
Let me scold him once
before I get ordained.
Let me enjoy this moment scolding him.
Wait.
Isn't it too late for anyone
to be selling ice-cream?
What's he looking at?
Look at him.
Balloon.
What's wrong?
Are you okay?
Did you fall asleep?
Oh, my god.
What the hell is going on? Oh, my god.
Fuck. What now?
It's the Nak Prok pendant.
Take it back. It's yours.
Do you think I would let you go so easily?
Nak Non.
What is it that you want?
Please tell us.
You can't give it to me.
I don't care.
You must die.
I told you.
-Nong.
-Shit.
Nong. Oh, no.
-The ghost is here.
-Shit.
I'm sorry. Gosh!
Nong, what's going on?
It won't open.
I will kill you all.
Hello.
Hello, my ass. This isn't the time.
-Oh, my god.
-Help us, Novice.
Come here.
-Help.
-What is it?
What happened?
Novice, do you know
how to perform an exorcism?
No, I don't.
We're screwed.
You must do it. Balloon's possessed.
You're our only hope. Go and face him.
-Help us.
-Oh, my god.
I'm a novice, not one of the X-Men.
Is this time to fucking joke around?
I'm sorry.
-Novice, go in there.
-You're our only hope.
That's enough.
Stop.
Fine.
I'm sorry.
Shit.
How dare you throw up in my face?
I'll beat you up when you wake up.
If what Nak Non wants is to get ordained,
why don't we do it for him?
Right, First?
It's already weird enough that a gay man
like me wants to get ordained.
Will you ordain a ghost too now?
Yes.
Novice.
As we are speaking, his body
is being kept in the old chapel
behind the temple.
Oh, my god.
Nong.
Shit.
-Aod.
-Yes.
Bring the ordaining equipment
from the shrine.
You and I will bring Balloon here.
Let's go.
Let's go, Nong.
Wait, everyone.
I'm sorry.
But what about me?
You can watch the body.
What?
Balloon.
-Balloon.
-Do we pick him up?
-What the fuck did you tie me with?
-Let's do it.
Gosh.
Pick him up.
Hold still, Nak Non.
I'm trying to help you.
Nak Non, my butt. It's me, Balloon.
What? Is that you, Balloon?
-Balloon.
-Let me go.
When did Nak Non's spirit leave your body?
What?
Was I possessed?
-Yes.
-Can you just untie me now?
-Okay.
Hurry up.
-God.
-Ouch.
-Get me up.
-Who the hell was that?
-Aod, watch where you're going.
-I'm very fragile.
-Untie me. What the hell is this?
Shit. Guys.
Did you get scared again?
The body is gone.
What body?
What? Where did Novice go?
You're right.
Novice.
-Novice.
-Where did he go?
-I'm here!
Novice, I told you to watch the body.
What are you doing over there?
Well, the body isn't over there,
but it's here.
What the hell?
Shit.
-Novice.
-What?
-What's going on, Novice?
-Novice.
Guys.
Help me.
I can't breathe.
Where are you dragging me to?
Oh, shit.
Guys.
-Guys.
-Oh, no.
-What should we do?
Hurry and help him.
-Aod.
-Nong.
Guys.
Nong, help him.
Say something.
Tell him to let Novice go, Nong.
-Guys.
-What do you want me to say?
Nong, say what the fuck you want.
Just say something. Hurry.
Let me think.
-Hurry.
-Hurry. Novice is dying, Nong.
He is dying.
I know. Just let me think.
Can you think any faster?
-Hurry, Nong.
-Novice, are you okay?
Ordainment...
Nak Non.
Let him go
if you want to get ordained.
If you don't keep your word,
you die.
Nong.
Are you negotiating with him
or challenging him?
-Novice.
Novice.
Please get it done for us. Do it.
-Wait.
-Novice.
What do you want me to do?
What?
Ordain him.
Guys, I'm a novice, not a monk.
I can't ordain anybody.
Nong.
What were you thinking?
A novice ordaining someone as a monk?
We are fucked. I already gave him my word.
You go, then.
No.
His legs...
Do something. First, think of something.
First, think of something.
Do something, First.
I figured out a way!
You guys came to the right person.
Don't worry.
I'll take care of him.
Are you sure this will work?
We will have to roll with it.
Is this the ghost
that scared me the other day?
Novice.
Back up, Novice.
He's coming closer. Back up.
Stay right there.
Can you ordain me?
His tone...
Is this a favor or a threat?
All right.
Where's the equipment?
Here.
These are Nak Non's alms bowl
and talipot fan.
Where's the robe?
Here's the robe.
-Oh, no.
-What?
Where's the robe?
-Aod!
-Aod, where did it go?
-Where did it go?
-I don't know.
If you don't have the robe, then I'm out.
Come on. Don't leave, Luang Na.
Luang Na.
Aod!
Where did you put it? Find it right now.
The robe.
The robe is here.
Here's the robe.
Here.
Here's your robe.
I will finally get ordained for you.
All right.
Do you know
how to cite the chant?
Yes.
In that case,
please cite a few lines for me.
Okay.
Do you have bronchiectasis?
No, I don't.
Do you have epilepsy?
Are you a human being?
I'm not human.
But I would like to be ordained
if you would be kind enough...
If you would be kind...
I cannot ordain you.
What?
Because you are not human.
Those who can be ordained
must be human.
If I don't get to be ordained,
then nobody will.
Oh, no.
Nak.
Nak, please calm down. Luang Na!
Luang Na.
-Is he possessed?
-Oh, my god. Luang Na!
Well, no...
He's not possessed.
I...
I'm sorry.
-I...
-What is it, Novice?
I ran out of data.
-What?
-Gosh?
-Why didn't you buy extra data?
-What's your problem?
What's your problem?
-First.
-What?
Shit!
Non.
Non, please don't.
If I don't get to be ordained,
they must die.
That's enough, Non.
Please don't hurt people anymore.
Non.
Nak Non.
You believe in the Phaya Nak, right?
Then please be like the nak.
Please accept the fact
that you cannot get ordained.
Enough already, Non.
I let it go.
Your yellow robe
isn't as important
as you leaving in peace.
Do you hear me, son?
Non.
Nong, come here.
Did the ghost listen?
My poor Non.
My child.
If I get to be reincarnated as a human,
can I be born as your child again?
Of course, you can.
My child.
Could I have Non's robe?
I will get ordained on his behalf.
First,
this ordainment
will make a military man like your father
proud of a beautiful gay son like you.
This yellow piece of cloth
will send your dad to heaven
faster than taking a jet plane.
Can you stop fooling yourself?
You're gay. You don't have a uterus.
Shouldn't you save this money
for your future?
To be honest, I came here to get ordained
for my mother.
I want to do something for her
even though she isn't with me anymore.
Do you have dermatophytosis?
-No, I don't.
Do you have bronchiectasis?
Do you have epilepsy?
-No, I don't.
Are you a human being?
-Yes, I am.
Let's make some merit.
Shall we make some merit?
We're already here. We must.
Wow. Look at those yellow robes.
All three of them got ordained together.
Give it to him.
Nak.
-My dear.
-All right. Everything turned out okay.
My dear.
The curse of Nak Non is finally over.
By the way, Luang Pee,
Luang Loong said
Luang Por wasn't harmed by Nak Non.
He died of natural causes.
Oh, right. Aod.
Yes.
I want you to keep this.
Keep it as a reminder that one day,
you will get ordained for your grandpa.
Thank you.
Stay as a monk for three phansa like us.
What?
You...
What did you just say? Three phansa?
Three phansa means three months.
Three phansa isn't three months! I...
One phansa is three months.
But three phansa means three years!
Look.
I thought we were here to fulfill the vow,
not to get enlightened.
Please calm down.
Stop the car.
-Aod.
-Yes.
Where's your grandpa?
He's at the crematory. What's going on?
This is Luang Ta Gorn's body.
He used to stay at this temple.
He passed away.
By the way, did you know
he passed away one day
before leaving the monkhood?
I'll send him to your grandpa then.
Let's go.
Could it be the curse?
What curse now?
In this temple,
besides the curse of the nak
who can never become a monk,
there's also another curse that
monks can never leave the monkhood.
Those who want to leave the monkhood
all end up dead.
Jeez!
Why didn't you tell us earlier?
Come on, Luang Pee.
You saw it.
I was busy running away
from ghosts with you.
Who would have thought about this?
Novice.
Can no one help us at all?
Luang Pee.
The whole Marvel team
wouldn't even be able to help you.
Well,
you will be here for three phansa.
You have a lot of time to solve this case.
Stay here with me for a long time.
Here we go again.
-Oh, no.
-Aod.
Aod.
What are you smiling at?
After you.
You're not so pretty.
Don't look at me, honey. Just let me go.
So that's what happened.
What?
He just wants to hit you.
Have you said cut yet?
-It's making noise.
-Guys.
Hurry up.
Oh, no.
Shit.
Didn't you research
how scary this place was?
You bitch.
Go!
Oh, no. He fell.
He's safe. It's okay.
Take a look at him.
-I can't. It's too hot.
-Bring a fan.
-Okay.
-That's enough.
-Don't gather around.
-Come.
Jui.
-Why didn't--
-Help.
I know...
Oh, my god.
-Help!
-Won't you say cut?
If I don't get to be ordained,
then no one will.
Cut. Luang Por.
Luang Por, you are not dead yet.
Wait until I finish talking.
I see.
Subtitle translation by
Pet-chompoo Sa-ngarmangkang