Man: HEY, HERE'S SOME
FRESH TRACKS.
THEY'RE HEADING
THAT WAY. COME ON!
HEY, HOLD UP, BOYS.
Man: FIND HIM YET?
WHERE?
I FOUND SOMETHING.
SOME KIND OF SCALP.
THAT AIN'T HIM.
HE AIN'T APACHE.
I DON'T EVEN THINK
HE'S AN INDIAN.
WELL, HE'S A BREED.
THAT'S FOR SURE.
CHINESE.
HEY, BACK TO TOWN!
YOU KNOW, BREED,
YOU CAN GET SCALPED
IN THESE MOUNTAINS?
NOW, WHERE'S
THAT APACHE HIDDEN?
APACHE?
PARTNER OF THE ONE
WE SHOT.
HIS TRAIL RAN OUT
DOWN THERE BY THE ROCK,
SO HE GOTTA BE IN HERE.
AND YOU GOTTA
KNOW WHERE.
I AIN'T GONNA
ASK YOU AGAIN.
Master Kan: YOUR TREAD
MUST BE LIGHT AND SURE,
AS THOUGH YOUR PATH
WERE UPON RICE PAPER.
IT IS SAID A SHAOLIN PRIEST
CAN WALK THROUGH WALLS.
LOOK FOR, HE CANNOT BE SEEN.
LISTENED FOR,
HE CANNOT BE HEARD.
TOUCHED, HE CANNOT BE FELT.
THIS RICE PAPER IS THE TEST.
FRAGILE AS THE WINGS
OF THE DRAGONFLY.
CLINGING AS A COCOON
OF THE SILKWORM.
WHEN YOU CAN WALK ITS LENGTH
AND LEAVE NO TRACE,
YOU WILL HAVE LEARNED.
THIS IS YOUR LAST
CHANCE, BREED.
I SEE NO APACHE.
BOO!
OK, BOYS, COME ON.
WE'RE JUST STANDING AROUND HERE,
AND THAT APACHE'S
GAINING GROUND.
LET'S MOVE!
YOUR SKIN IS NOT
LIKE THEIRS.
I AM FROM CHINA.
I HAVE SEEN OTHERS
FROM THAT LAND.
YOU ARE DIFFERENT.
MY FATHER WAS FROM HERE.
HE WAS A WHITE MAN?
YES.
NO.
YES, IT IS SO.
HE WOULD NOT HAVE STOOD
BEFORE A GUN FOR ME.
YOU DO NOT KNOW THAT.
I KNOW WHITE MEN.
THERE IS NO WHITE
IN YOU.
IT IS NOT THERE.
HOSKAY GREETS YOU
AS A BROTHER.
I ASK YOU
STAND WITH ME.
TAKE UP THE CAUSE
OF JUSTICE.
WE SHALL TRIUMPH
OVER THE MANDARINS
AND THE PEOPLE
SHALL BE FREE!
YOUR WORDS ARE VAIN,
TEH-SOONG.
Teh-Soong: LISTEN TO ME,
HEAR ME, MY BROTHERS!
ALL MY BROTHERS,
HEAR ME!
THIS IS A HOLY CAUSE!
VICTORY AWAITS US.
WE STAND TOGETHER,
VICTORY, TRIUMPH!
Young Caine: MASTER?
YOU DO NOT INTRUDE.
COME. SPEAK.
Teh-Soong:
WE WILL PREVAIL!
PLEDGE WITH ME.
PICK UP THIS HOLY CAUSE--
I HAVE LONG ADMIRED
OUR BROTHER TEH-SOONG.
THERE IS MUCH IN HIM
TO BE ADMIRED.
I FEAR HE GROWS
APART FROM US.
FROM OUR WAY.
HE IS FIRED BY
A DEEP CONVICTION.
WOULD YOU HAVE HIM
DENY THIS TRUTH...
HE FEELS SO DEEPLY?
BUT IF WE ARE BROTHERS,
SHOULD NOT OUR BELIEFS
BE ONE?
THAT IS WHAT
TEH-SOONG
DESIRES MOST
FERVENTLY.
HE WOULD HAVE US
DENY OUR TRUTH
AND ACCEPT HIS.
WHO IS RIGHT?
THERE CAN BE NO WAY
BUT THE WAY OF THE TAO.
SO WE BELIEVE.
WHAT THEN?
DO WE RENOUNCE
TEH-SOONG
AS OUR BROTHER?
MASTER? WHEREIN
DOES BROTHERHOOD LIE?
YOUR QUESTION IS
MOST WORTH ASKING.
MOST WORTH
CONSIDERING.
BEFORE MY 12th SUMMER,
I WENT ON A HIGH HILL.
I FASTED FOR DAYS
AND NIGHTS.
A VISION CAME TO ME.
I SAT ON A GRAY HORSE,
I RODE OVER THE CLOUDS,
AND MY BROTHER RODE
BEHIND ME.
WHITE MEN FELL
FROM THE CLOUDS
INTO THE DARKNESS.
AND THEIR BULLETS
DID NOT STRIKE US.
IT WAS...TO BE THAT WAY.
BUT MY BROTHER RIDES
NO MORE.
HIS SCALP HANGS IN
THE WHITE MAN'S CAMP.
SCALP HUNTERS.
THEY HUNT APACHE SCALPS.
THERE IS ONE CALLED RAFE.
THEIR LEADER.
I MUST KILL HIM FIRST.
YOU WILL ANSWER DEATH
WITH DEATH?
IT IS THE MISSION
FOR WHICH THE SPIRITS
CHOSE ME,
MY BROTHER, ALL HIS
FALLEN BROTHERS.
I MUST AVENGE THEM.
MASTER?
TEH-SOONG IS READY
TO LEAVE.
LET HIM ENTER.
YOU WILL NOT
BE DISSUADED?
NEVER.
I WILL NOT WASTE
ANOTHER DAY WITHIN
THESE WALLS.
WASTE?
THE PEOPLE
ARE LIKE SLAVES.
THEY STARVE, AND STILL
THE MANDARINS
DEMAND TRIBUTE
FOR THE EMPEROR.
WE PRAY.
WE MEDITATE. WE--
WE DO NOTHING.
HOW CAN YOU GO
ON BEING BLIND
TO THE MISERY
AROUND YOU?
I SEE IT.
AND DO NOTHING.
WHAT WILL YOU DO?
EVERYTHING!
I WILL TAKE
UP THE CAUSE
OF THE PEOPLE.
I WILL LEAD THEM.
SPEAK FOR THEM.
FIGHT FOR THEM.
AN AWESOME TASK.
YOU WILL BE
IN OUR THOUGHTS.
ALL HAS BEEN SAID.
WE WISH YOU LIFE.
HE WAS TAUGHT
TO BE ONE
WITH THE TAO.
TO FLOW. NOW HE STANDS
AGAINST THE CURRENT.
HE BELIEVES IT IS
THE WILL OF DESTINY.
COULD IT BE SO?
CAN ANY MAN
BE ASKED
TO BE MORE
THAN A MAN?
WELL, WOULD YOU LOOK
AT WHAT'S FALLEN
IN ON US?
EASY BOYS, EASY.
NOW, MAYBE HE JUST CAUGHT WIND
OF THAT APACHE.
IS THAT WHAT YOU'RE
HERE TO TELL US?
I CAME TO TELL YOU
NOTHING.
I AM LOOKING FOR RAFE.
RAFE WHO?
AIN'T NO ONE AROUND HERE
BY THE NAME RAFE.
Man: YOU'RE ALL
MIXED UP, BOY.
WHAT YOU CALL YOURSELF,
CHINAMAN?
I AM CAINE.
YEAH, I THOUGHT YOU WAS.
HOW COME YOUR NECK
AIN'T BROKE?
I WAS NOT HANGED.
WELL, THEY WAS FIXING
THE GALLOW
WHEN I WAS RIDING OUT.
WHAT MADE THEM CHANGE
THEIR MINDS?
I DID NOT CHOOSE
TO STAY.
YEAH?
THIS HEATHEN'S WANTED
BACK IN TEMESCAL.
WHAT FOR?
PUTTING A KNIFE
THROUGH SHERIFF AMES.
ALL THE WAY THROUGH?
FAR ENOUGH.
WELL, THAT'S
THE BEST NEWS I HEARD
IN A LONG TIME.
YOU WERE THERE.
YOU SAW.
YOU KNOW IT WAS
ANOTHER MAN
WHO KILLED
THE SHERIFF.
YEAH. AND I KNOW
WHO IT WAS.
BAILEY SEWARD.
THEN YOU WILL GO
BACK WITH ME,
AND TELL THIS
TO THE JUDGE?
UH, NO, HALF-BREED.
THAT'S NOT WHAT
YOU'D CALL
A PRACTICAL IDEA.
YOU SEE, THIS
BAILEY SEWARD
WE'VE BEEN
TALKING ABOUT,
UH, HE'S THE MAN
WE WORK FOR,
AND IT JUST DON'T
MAKE SENSE
TO, UH, CHOP OFF
THE HAND THAT PAYS YOU,
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
IF YOU DO NOT
COME BACK
AND TELL THE TRUTH,
JUSTICE WILL NOT
BE SERVED.
WELL.
NOW THAT'S GOING TO CAUSE ME
A FRIGHTFUL LACK OF SLEEP.
YOU GOT YOUR ANSWER,
BREED.
WHAT YOU WAITING ON?
I WILL NOT LEAVE
WITHOUT YOU.
YOU KNOW
SOMETHING,
CHINAMAN?
YOU'RE A REAL
CAUTION.
I DON'T THINK HE
KNOWS WHAT WE DO
FOR A LIVING.
YOU KILL MEN.
WE COLLECT SCALPS
FOR A BOUNTY.
AND MEN DIE.
APACHES DIE.
YOU KILL INNOCENT
MEN FOR PROFIT.
THERE IS NO
GREATER EVIL.
Man: HEY, YOU
KNOW SOMETHING,
BREED?
I THINK YOU JUST
BIT IT OFF.
YOU KNOW, KIRBY HERE
HAD A NOTION
THAT, UH, HIS SCALP
WOULDN'T GO MUCH
NOTICED
THEN WITH ALL
THEM OTHERS.
THAT SOUNDS
ABOUT RIGHT.
IT'LL MAKE UP
FOR THE ONE
THAT GOT PAST US.
WHAT, UH, WHAT DO YOU
SMOKE IN THIS THING?
I DO NOT SMOKE IT.
WELL, IT SURE IS
A FUNNY-LOOKING BANJO.
GIVE US, UM,
TEXAS LULLABY.
WHAT IS THAT?
THAT'S MUSIC.
IT'S THE ONLY KIND
WORTH LISTENING TO.
HEY, ANSEL, COME ON,
TICKLE SOMETHING OUT OF THAT.
YEAH, GO ON, ANSEL.
COME ON, ANSEL!
ALRIGHT, NOW
HOLD IT, BOYS.
SOMETHING'S GOING
TO HAPPEN.
ATTABOY, ANSEL!
PLAYS THAT BEAUTIFUL.
Young Caine: MASTER, WHEREIN
DOES BROTHERHOOD LIE?
Master Po: YOUR QUESTION
IS MOST WORTH ASKING.
MOST WORTH CONSIDERING.
Rafe: HEY, HEATHEN.
I WANT YOU TO MEET
SOMEONE.
NAME'S MUTALA.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
WE WOULD HAVE DONE
WITHOUT HIM.
IF, UH, YOU GOT
SOMETHING YOU WANT
TO SAY TO HIM,
JUST, UH, SPEAK
RIGHT UP.
LET ME TAKE THOSE
FROM YOU, CHINEY.
I'LL TAKE REAL GOOD
CARE OF THEM.
HE KNOWS WHAT
YOU'RE THINKING,
CHINAMAN.
HE DON'T LIKE IT.
UH-OH.
WELL, LOOK AT IT
THIS WAY, CHINAMAN.
YOU WERE QUITS
ANYWAY.
COME ON, MU!
COME ON, BOY!
CUT HIS EARS OFF!
COME ON,
GET HIM, MUTALA!
PRETTY GOOD, CHINEY.
STICK IT
IN HIS EAR!
GIVE HIM A BLOW
UPSIDE THE HEAD!
CUT HIS FACE!
GET HIM!
Ansel: RAFE! WATCH OUT!
NO, DON'T SHOOT!
YOU'RE LIABLE TO HIT RAFE.
RAFE! GET
OUT OF THE WAY!
COME ON, LET'S GET
DOWN THERE!
AAH!
HYAH.
THE SOLDIERS.
I COULD NOT STOP
THEM ALL.
THERE WERE
SO MANY OF THEM.
BATHE HIM.
TEND TO HIS WOUNDS.
CALL MASTER LI NU.
HE WAS BESET
BY SOLDIERS.
YES. THE WORD CAME
WHILE WE WERE EATING.
HE LED A REVOLT
IN A VILLAGE TO THE NORTH.
NOW THE VILLAGE
IS DESTROYED
AND TEH-SOONG IS MARKED
FOR DEATH.
WILL HE BE SAFE
HERE?
YES.
BUT WILL HE
BE CONTENT TO STAY?
IS YOUR BROTHER
AVENGED?
DIE OF YOUR WOUND,
WHO WILL AVENGE YOU?
OTHERS WILL FOLLOW.
TO LEAVE THEIR
SCALPS ON HIS LINE?
WHERE WILL
IT ALL END?
WHEN HE AND ALL LIKE HIM
ARE DEAD.
IT IS YOU WHO
WILL DIE IF
THE OTHERS RETURN.
WHERE IS YOUR LODGE?
A DAY'S RIDE.
WHERE THE CANYON BEGINS.
I NEVER SEEN
YOU SO INTENT.
THE WAY HE LOOKED AT ME.
WELL, YOU GET US
ANOTHER SHOT
AT HIM, OK?
THE RIVER WILL BRING
HIM OUT ABOVE THE CANYON.
HE MUST GO DOWN
INTO THE CANYON TO CROSS.
3 DAY'S JOURNEY ON FOOT.
YEAH. WE CAN COUNT
ON RAFE TO SLOW
HIM DOWN A BIT.
ANY OTHER WAY
OUT OF THAT CANYON?
THERE IS NO OTHER WAY.
THEN WE GOT HIM.
LET HIM LAY,
CHINAMAN.
ONE WAY
OR THE OTHER
HE'S DEAD.
YOU TRY
TO TAKE HIM
OUT OF HERE,
YOU'RE DEAD,
TOO.
HE'LL SLOW
YOU DOWN.
WHY SHOULD YOU CARE?
I'M THINKIN'
ABOUT MY
OWN NECK.
YOU GOT
ME LYIN'
HELPLESS.
MINUTE YOU TURN AROUND,
HE STICKS A KNIFE IN ME.
YOU'LL NEVER
GET ME
TO TEMESCAL.
THERE WILL BE
NO KILLING.
I MUST HAVE
YOUR WORD.
IT IS MY MISSION.
IT IS YOUR BURDEN.
YOU CALLED ME
BROTHER.
I ASK YOU
AS A BROTHER.
NO, I CANNOT.
YOUR WORD.
NO KILLING...FOR NOW.
I PROMISE NO MORE.
YOU ARE BOUND.
WE CANNOT DELAY.
I'M READY.
MORE PAIN?
MY PAIN IS
FOR MY BROTHERS.
WHAT'S YOUR
PLAN, HEATHEN?
IT HAS NOT CHANGED.
WE RETURN TO TEMESCAL.
WHATEVER YOU
SAY.
YOU FIGURE YOU
CAN FIND
YOUR WAY OUT
OF HERE, HUH?
WE HAVE NO CHOICE.
THE WAY OUT IS THE WAY IN.
NOW, THAT'S A FACT.
GET UP.
NOW, HOW AM
I GONNA DO THAT?
YOU GOT ME LASHED
HERE LIKE I WAS
FIXED FOR BRANDIN'.
YOU ARE UNTIED.
WHEN YOU REGAIN YOUR
STRENGTH, YOU FEED YOURSELF.
HUH?
HEY.
AIN'T THAT
SOMETHIN'?
IF I TIE YOU
TO THIS HORSE,
YOU WILL BE MOST
UNCOMFORTABLE.
IF YOU SWEAR NOT
TO TRY TO RUN AWAY,
I WILL CAST THIS
ROPE ASIDE.
WHAT DO I SWEAR ON?
ONLY GIVE ME YOUR
HONOR AS A MAN.
SURE.
I'LL GIVE YOU
MY WORD.
MY WORD AIN'T WORTH
NOTHIN', CHINAMAN.
WHAT YOU THINK
OF THAT?
YOU ARE WITHOUT HONOR?
UH-HUH.
HOW DOES TEH-SOONG
PROGRESS?
HIS WOUNDS COOL.
HIS ANGER DOES NOT.
HE SPEAKS
AGAINST YOU, MASTER.
I KNOW.
HE HAS DONE SO
TO MY FACE.
I HAVE LOST
ALL RESPECT FOR HIM.
THE SAGE SAYS, "A
SOUND MAN'S HEART
"IS NOT SHUT
WITHIN ITSELF,
BUT IT IS OPEN
TO OTHER PEOPLE'S
HEARTS."
TEH-SOONG ACCEPTS
YOUR KINDNESS,
AND AT THE SAME TIME
DEFIES YOU.
WOULD YOU HAVE HIM
HIDE HIS DEFIANCE?
IS THERE HONOR
IN SUCH DECEPTION?
I UNDERSTAND
YOUR THOUGHTS, MASTER.
BUT WHAT?
THIS PARTICULAR VIRTUE
YOU FIND IN TEH-SOONG,
IS IT MOST LIMITING?
STILL IT IS THERE,
AND IT IS FOR US
TO ACKNOWLEDGE.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT HONOR IS.
I CANNOT BELIEVE THAT.
COME.
I WILL HELP YOU UP.
WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA RIDE?
I WILL WALK.
WELL, SUITS ME.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
UHH.
I'LL TELL YOU...
THAT'S PRETTY GOOD,
CHINAMAN.
YOU, UH, WANNA TAKE
MY WORD AGAIN?
HEY. WAIT A MINUTE,
HEATHEN.
I WANT THAT APACHE
WHERE I CAN SEE HIM.
HE HAS GIVEN HIS WORD.
YOU BELIEVE THAT?
HIS WORD'S NO BETTER
THAN MINE.
JUMP ME THE FIRST
CHANCE HE GETS.
ONLY IF YOU BREAK
YOUR WORD.
CHINAMAN,
HE'S AN APACHE!
YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND THEM.
I KNOW MEN.
I TRUST THIS ONE.
AND WITH HIM,
I TRUST YOU.
HORSES.
HOW CAN YOU BE SURE
THEY'RE NOT OURS?
WE JUST RODE THROUGH
HERE A COUPLE DAYS AGO.
NO. TRACKS
ARE FRESH.
I NEVER FIGURED
THAT CHINAMAN WOULD
HAVE HORSES HID.
RIGHT HERE.
BLOOD.
THAT'S THAT
CHINAMAN'S BLOOD.
YEAH. WELL, I WOULDN'T
BE TOO SURE.
WELL, I AIN'T EVER
SEEN NOBODY GET
THE BEST OF RAFE YET.
NOW, LOOK. IF HE HAD WON,
WHY WOULD HE BE SITTIN'
HERE WAITIN' FOR US?
Mutala: 3 MEN
FIGHT HERE.
THE APACHE.
THAT'S THE ONE
THAT GOT AWAY.
YEAH.
WELL, IT ALL WON'T
BE FOR NOTHING.
WE'RE GONNA GET
THAT SCALP YET.
HOW LONG AGO THEY LEAVE?
NOT LONG.
WE CATCH 'EM.
WHOA. WHOA. WAIT. WHOA.
WE'RE LIABLE TO LOSE THEM
BECAUSE OF THE DARK,
BUT THEY GOTTA CLIMB
OUT OF THAT CANYON.
WHEN THEY DO...
WE'RE GONNA BE WAITING
FOR THEM RIGHT THERE.
IT WILL BE DARK SOON.
DARK OR LIGHT. DON'T MAKE
NO DIFFERENCE TO MUTALA.
HE'LL FIND A TRAIL
BLINDFOLDED.
COUNT THE MINUTES, HEATHEN.
HEY, WHY DON'T
YOU SAVE SOME
OF THAT?
WE'LL GET MORE.
YEAH? WHERE?
I WILL FIND SOME.
YOU MEAN YOU'RE GONNA WALK OUT
OF HERE AND LEAVE US?
YES.
JUST WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
I'M GONNA BE HERE
WHEN YOU GET BACK?
I HAVE YOUR PROMISE.
I TOLD YOU, CHINAMAN,
MY PROMISE DON'T MEAN NOTHIN'.
THEN YOU FORCE ME
TO TIE YOU.
OK.
YOU CAN SURE
COME AHEAD
AND TRY.
LET ME TELL
YOU SOMETHING,
CHINAMAN.
I AIN'T
HALF DROWNED NOW.
YOU MIGHT
WANNA KEEP
THAT IN MIND.
GO AHEAD.
LET YOU TAKE
THE FIRST SWING.
Jess: ANY CHANCE
THEY GOT HERE
'FORE US?
NO.
YOU REALLY WANT THAT
CHINAMAN, DON'T YOU?
HE PASSED
JUDGMENT ON ME.
OH, NO DENYIN' THAT.
I SEEN IT
IN HIS EYES.
HE DOES NOT KNOW
WHAT THE APACHE DID
TO MY PEOPLE.
I RECKON YOU BETTER
TEACH HIM A LESSON,
HUH?
HE WILL REMEMBER.
HEY, INJUN.
YOU KNOW MY MEN ARE
GONNA COME RIDIN'
IN HERE ANY MINUTE.
CHINAMAN
KNOWS IT, TOO.
THAT'S HOW COME
HE TOOK OFF.
AND HE AIN'T
COMIN' BACK,
SO, UH, WHY DON'T
YOU AND ME MAKE
A DEAL, HUH?
YOU CUT ME LOOSE,
YOU GO YOUR WAY,
I GO MINE.
I KEEP MY MEN
FROM CHASING YOU.
HUH?
YOU KNOW WHAT'S
GONNA HAPPEN IF THEY
FIND US LIKE THIS.
YOUR HANDS ARE RED
WITH APACHE BLOOD.
AHH.
IT'S OUR LIVIN'.
YOU THIRST NOT FOR WATER,
BUT FOR BLOOD.
I'D SETTLE
FOR WATER RIGHT NOW.
SCALP HUNTER.
WE LEARNED
FROM EXPERTS.
APACHES NEVER KILL
FOR MONEY.
WELL, YOU TAKE
THE GLORY, INJUN,
AND I'LL SETTLE
FOR THE CASH.
I GAVE HIM MY WORD.
Caine: AND YOU
KEPT IT.
I WILL KILL HIM YET.
PARASITES.
LEECHES.
HAVE YOU NO FEELING?
NO PASSION?
LEAVE HERE.
COME WITH ME.
TOGETHER WE CAN BRING
JUSTICE TO THE PEOPLE.
HOW?
WE'LL LEAD THEM
AGAINST THE MANDARINS
AND THE SOLDIERS.
WE WILL KILL THEM ALL.
VIOLENCE GIVES RISE
TO VIOLENCE,
NOT TO JUSTICE.
YOU'VE JUST SEEN
THAT FOR YOURSELF,
TEH-SOONG.
MY BELIEF HAS ONLY
BEEN STRENGTHENED.
MY ANGER SHARPENED.
WILL YOU COME?
Young Caine: MASTER, WHEREIN
DOES BROTHERHOOD LIE?
Master Kan: YOUR QUESTION
IS MOST WORTH ASKING,
MOST WORTH CONSIDERING.
WE MUST GO THROUGH
THE PATH.
WE WILL WAIT UNTIL DARK.
I DIDN'T HEAR NOTHIN'.
Jess: NOW, GET
THAT CHINEY.
STRAW.
THEY'RE GONE.
WE AIN'T NEVER GONNA PICK UP
THEIR TRAIL BEFORE DAYLIGHT.
YEAH. BUT THEY'RE
ON FOOT NOW.
AND WE STILL GOT
A SHOT AT THEM.
WELL, LET'S GO!
OH.
YOU ARE NOT KEEPING PACE.
I'M DOING
THE BEST I CAN.
I DO NOT THINK SO.
THERE IS HOSKAY.
HE DOES NOT LAG BEHIND.
HE IS SUFFERING
FROM A WOUND.
LISTEN, WHY DON'T,
UH, YOU AND HIM
GO ON WITHOUT ME?
I WOULDN'T WANNA
HOLD YOU UP.
HOW FAR IS YOUR VILLAGE
FROM HERE?
THERE'S A MOUNTAIN...
BEYOND THE ONE
THAT YOU SEE.
MY PEOPLE LIVE
ABOVE THE MOUNTAIN.
OH, THAT'S A LONG
STRETCH OF DAYLIGHT.
BETTER LOOK FORWARD
TO MEETIN' MY BOYS
SOMEWHERE ALONG
THE WAY.
YOU WISH TO REST?
NO.
COME.
HUMPH.
CAN YOU REACH YOUR
PEOPLE WITHOUT HELP?
YES.
WILL YOU STAND?
UH-UH.
THEN...
GOOD-BYE...
MY BROTHER.
YOU RELEASE ME
FROM THE PROMISE I GAVE YOU?
NO.
HEY, CHINAMAN.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
JUST LEAVE ME
HERE, ARE YOU?
IT DOES NOT PROFIT
ME TO STAY.
THEN COME CUT
ME LOOSE.
WHY?
HE HAS GIVEN HIS WORD.
I'M DEAD THE
MINUTE YOU GO
OVER THAT RISE.
YOU DO NOT LIKE
THE IDEA OF DYING?
I DON'T LIKE
THE IDEA OF
BEING HELPLESS.
IS THAT YOU, TEH-SOONG?
IT IS I, MASTER.
YOU RETURN
ONCE MORE TO US...
ALIVE, UNHARMED.
YOU WEAR THE RAGS
OF A BEGGAR?
A LOWLIER GARMENT
I COULD NOT FIND.
YOU RETURN FROM YOUR CAUSE?
IT WAS FALSE.
YOU SOUGHT TO RELIEVE
THE BURDENS OF THE PEOPLE.
MY CONCERN ONLY
VISITED GREATER
SUFFERING UPON THEM.
I FAILED.
FOR IN THEIR NAME
THOU LEAD,
PROCLAIMING I SOUGHT
MY OWN GLORY.
IT HAS BEEN SAID,
"BE UTTERLY HUMBLE
AND YOU SHALL HOLD
TO THE FOUNDATION OF PEACE.
"BE AT ONE WITH ALL
THESE LIVING THINGS
"WHICH HAVING ARISEN
AND FLOURISHED,
RETURN TO THE QUIET
WHENCE THEY CAME."
WILL YOU...
ABIDE WITH US?
YOU WILL ALLOW ME?
OUR HEARTS ARE OPEN.
I BEG YOUR
FORGIVENESS, MASTER.
YOU HAVE MY LOVE.
FORGIVENESS?
IF YOU WILL FIND THAT,
IT MUST COME
FROM THE ONE WHO HAS
CONDEMNED YOU, TEH-SOONG.
I WOULD HOPE HE WOULD
BE GENEROUS.
SURELY.
THERE HAS BEEN
ENOUGH DESTRUCTION.
WHAT YOU DO NOT LIKE IS
THAT YOUR LIFE DEPENDS
ON THE PROMISE
OF AN APACHE,
THE SCRUPLES
OF A CHINAMAN
WHICH YOU DO NOT
UNDERSTAND.
IT IS NOT HARD
TO UNDERSTAND.
THIS IS NOT AN INDIAN,
NOT AN APACHE,
BUT A MAN
WHOSE NAME IS HOSKAY.
I AM NOT A CHINAMAN...
OR A BREED.
I AM A MAN.
MY NAME IS
KWAI CHANG CAINE.
COME ON! LET'S GO!
COME ON, GUYS!
GOOD LUCK, RAFE.
COME ON.
MY VISION WAS TRUE.
I SAT ON A GRAY HORSE.
MY BROTHER RODE BEHIND ME.
AND NOW, WHITE MAN
WILL FALL INTO DARKNESS.
EVEN NOW, YOU HOLD ME
TO MY PROMISE?
THIS MAN IS A BUTCHER
TO ALL MY PEOPLE.
YOUR VISION
OF VENGEANCE
WILL DESTROY YOU...
AND ALL YOUR PEOPLE.
AAH!
UHH.
HE TRIED TO KILL YOU.
HOW COME YOU BOTHER
WITH HIM?
HEY, TELL ME SOMETHING,
CHINAMAN.
WHY'D YOU STOP HOSKAY?
WORD OF AN APACHE
AND SCRUPLES
OF A CHINAMAN, HUH?
WELL, HOW AM I
SUPPOSED TO HOLD ON TO THAT?
HEY, CHINAMAN,
WAIT A MINUTE.
NOW, WHERE YOU GOING?
TEMESCAL.
TEMESCAL?!
UM.
WELL...
MAYBE I'LL COME
WITH YOU.
HEY!
KWAI CHANG CAINE.
WILL YOU WAIT A MINUTE?
LET US RENEW THE
WORDS OF THE SAGE.
MAN AT HIS BEST...
LIKE WATER...
SERVES
AS HE GOES ALONG...
LIKE WATER.
HE SEEKS
HIS OWN LEVEL...
THE COMMON LEVEL OF LIFE.
WHAT HE MUST DO,
HE DOES...
BUT NOT FOR GLORY.
WHAT HE MUST DO,
HE DOES...
BUT NOT FOR SHOW.
WHAT HE MUST DO,
HE DOES...
BUT NOT FOR SELF.
A SOUND MAN NOT
ADVANCING HIMSELF...
HE ENDLESSLY
BECOMES HIMSELF.
YES.
HE IS ONE
WITH US AGAIN.
AND WITH HIMSELF.
EVERY MAN HAS HIS
YES AND HIS NO.
FROM MOMENT TO MOMENT,
ALWAYS HIS YES AND HIS NO.