English Subtitles by MeGustaVerano C.X.
2022-03-08
Captain.
Oders from Headquarters, Sir
The orders...
are to attack the bridge.
We can expect heavy casualties.
No-one will reach that bridge alive.
Find your nerve, men.
We risk our lives.
but we can take back our home!
For centuries, poets have dreamt fo dying for love.
I suppose we shall be the lucky ones.
The orders are to wait three hours for the wind to turn east.
then fire every gas canister we have.
There is an alternative, Captain.
What is it, Poirot?
We attack right now.
Now?
Yes.
Within the next seven minutes.
Perhaps eight.
Every morning,
the petrels take flight
just before the wind turns east.
You see?
This morning
they fly early.
The wind conditions are ideal now.
to hide our advance.
Hidden by the gas
we will cross 200 metres of no man's land without being seen.
Before the enemy even knows
that we attack!
If your're wrong, the wind will blow the gas back on the rest of our army.
We gas ourselves ... that you want
##
It's an ambush.
I can't see them.
Retreat!
You were right!
You are too sharp to be a farmer, Poirot.
No, Captain!
I asked you not to come.
I am a nurse too.
I heard there was a wounded soldier,
his instinct on the battlefield saved the entile company.
I did not save my captain.
And you agreeded to marry me before all of this.
Katherine,
you should go.
Do you have any idea how love works?
When you love someone, you love them...
through all their moods and changes all the time.
Their worst qualities pick your sense.
Their flaws become freckles.
And then happens...
I love you.
What about this?
Come here.
Simple.
You grow mustache.
DEATH ON THE NILE
AD TIME 30sec
LONDON
Poirot, where have you been?
The Arundell mistery? Are you with case?
No, I'm with hunger.
Monsieur Blondin.
Monsieur Poirot, you solved the case in Egypt.
It's good success, but I must come.
And tonight it's going to be.
Merci, Monsieur.
Want every desserts on the menu, thought it right?
Anything else, Mr. Poirot you want, just ask.
The whole house is wondering why there's no music.
There's no music becasue no money has been paid.
I'll pay for it at the end of the night.
On the my experience,
Man who run such upright quality establishments like yours,
lose their wallet when the bill comes.
I'm betting you really forgot my name.
Rosalie Otterbourne
I'm not just Salome Otterbourne's manager and her niece.
She'll retire wealthy and I'll seat that.
And we get paid in front.
So if you want a little music,
but so I want to see a stack of green
whatever color money in your country.
You remember my name now.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Salome Otterbourne !
Miss Ridgeway!
Linnet!
Wish a smile!
Miss Ridgeway!
Stand by! Leave a way for Miss Ridgeway.
Miss Linnet Ridgeway, I can't tell you what honor need.
Merci.
We have the  ... They're seven.
Indeed. Seven for they find, sir.
I do not want seven. I want to need six.
I can't have the...the uneven number of.
now we have the even number of.  This is good.
Which I should take away? I do not know.
No! No! My little fun. Please. Thank you for much little...
Get fun I will...
This is...you see, my little fun.
Linnet!
It's not fair looking like that and getting to be you.
I will ask Louise to pick something special to see my Jacks.
it's been ages.
Engaged?
I know.
But who?
He is big and square, and boyish and beautifully simple.
And that's it. He is called Simon, strike the point.
Simon Doyle.
We're just between marriage as soon as possible.
That's why I want to see you.
You are not...
What? No, No.
But we have sex a lot.
Constantly.
Jackie!
Sorry. It's true.
Honestly, I will die if I can't be Mrs. Doyle.
It's love.
If it's money you need,
call it a wedding gift.
No. Not money.
A job.
You bought that new estate.
You need someone to fix it for you and run it.
You can give that job to Simon.
He is unemployed. This country chewing through.
And he knows all about estates , I swear.
If he doesn't make good, at him on the spot.
But he will. He is too spectacular to fail.
Oh, darling,
you got it so bad.
Be careful.
It's too late.
Jackie, darling.
Here he is.
That was naughty of me.
Hello.
I hope you don't mind. Took liberty.
Simon, darling. Meet the golden girl, as I advertised.
The divine Linnet Ridgeway
Pleased to meet my new land agent.
Do you really mean that?
Of course she does.
Take to the dance floor, silly.
Going thank her properly.
Let's cheerly..one more triumph..for Salome Otterbourne!
THE RIVER NILE
SIX WEEKS LATER
Monsieur?
Monsieur !  ## ! Monsieur !
You're defiling one of the wonders on the world!
And tells by the way you've ruined a supreme Jaffa cake.
Monsieur!
You lovely kite!
What?
Poirot!
Bouc!
What are you doing here?
What do you think about my kite?
I come down. Stay there.
Be careful.
Among the piramids in all the world,
you after all come to mine.
What a small world!
Poirot ami, Bouc!
Why would you fly a kite on the piramids?
Because no one has!
Thousands of years, right here, I'm the first!
You are the first.
Poirot, it's good to see you.
Are you on that sort of holiday or on that sort of case?
Guess I am hiding from cases.
What? If you want to hide, come and hide with us.
In <i>Assouan</i> we're on a wearing tour.
Still the constant traveler.
Sadly no.
Uncle set me off the train.
when he founded out for that I did nothing.
I tried jobs at office.
I can manage the work just couldn't find the mornings.
But I made and meat as a catman.
Come!
Come. I shall introduce you to Euphemia.
But who is Euphemia?
While you'll find out.
The new young lady is like Bouc? A new name really.
Well, behind every kite flying man there is a woman.
Here she is.
The only woman I've ever loved...mother.
Mother, you must meet Hercule Poirot.
Why?
He must be amid the greatest detective of life.
He exagerates.
No, he is quite correct actually.
You're quite the most ludicrous man I have ever seen.
Not the first I'm heard this.
And you're in my view.
Stepping aside.
Be kind, mother. Poirot is my friend. And he is famous.
And he is joining our dinner tonight.
Is he?
I can not intrude.
Oh, not at all. You bump my stock at the table.
It‘s not mother and I on holiday.
We celebrate with friends.
It's a wedding party.
Is that me?
Might be.
Be nice.
FIRST CATARACT HOTEL 一号瀑布大酒店
ASSOUAN 阿斯旺
Should have entile situation managed,
then back to business as usual.
Do you have a plat? Good.
Now please see this telegram sent off as soon as able.
And...
Not another soul sees it.
No! I'll do it.
It is bad enough we have to
stay in this bourgeois nightmare of the hotel.
But I..I won't  be party to the oppression of the working fines.
Unless it's me, of course.
Then she is perfectly fine with that.
I am calm, capable and coony.
Dignity.
Marie Van Schuyler
And I don't need a suite.
just me and my nurse Bowers.
I'm Mrs. Doyle's godmother.
We do have a reservation.
And all this area be clear through the party then?
####
It's very expensive.
Merci.
Ladies and gentlemen,
...close the reception area for a wedding party...
Everything fine, madam?
It's perfect.
The cost of this party could feed a village for years.
Swinish for elegant.
I know. Wonderful, isn't it?
Is it true you donated your entire fortune to the Socialist Party?
Communist.
Money is the alienated essence of eventual labour and life.
Money is the only friend a woman can rely.
Look this.
Ladies and gentlemen, and mother.
It is my honor to introduce out hosts,
please welcome the newlyweds,
Mr. and Mrs. Simon Doyle.
Oh, here they are!
Mlle must be madame!
Fantastic Linnet!
Beautiful!
Ah, love...
It is not safe.
So beautiful.
I do a witness to a small drama some weeks ago.
Clearly I caught only the first act.
...like the angel really.
Lucky devil.
Fancy finding the one heiress about at noise and flat feet.
Elope just fast as they could.
Convention be damned.
Married for love then got money by chance.
That's the lightning strike.
Three cheers and a tiger for me.
How do I look?
Like a million dollars.
Make that two million.
Oh, my wedding gift from Simon.
Paid for with her account, so hardly.
Her gift to her, fire me.
I was sure Bouc was failing
when he said he knew D. Hercules Poirot.
Bonjour, then see you.
My congratulations and my gratitude, madame.
Merci.
Ladies, godmother,
Cousin Andrew!
Simon,
Cousin Andres my trustee for
all Ridgeway affairs abroad and domestic.
He is practically family.
I made him come so he take a vacation for once.
I only head for the Champagne.
Sacred honor.
And...
for this.
It's so sweet tonight.
Attention please.
Doyle.
Friends,
I know you all thinking there's a mystery I played.
The case of why in the hell would Linnet Ridgeway marry him?
I honestly can't say why.
I'm not smart at all, romantic,
don't have the words, or the money, or the pedigree.
But I do love you.
And now,
I don't even want to say it.
Let the thief come and steal you away.
To the Bride and groom.
Bride and groom.
- Three cheers!  - Three cheers!
Salome Otterbourne sang at the night we met.
So I beg your pal Rosalie to beg her to travel with us.
I wouldn't have missed it.
I haven't tasted caviar in ten years.
What a decay in displaying wealth.
Alright, Linnet, let's dance!
Ah, the bereaved.
As one as every wedding party.
The good Dr. Windlesham proposed Ms. Ridgeway
when she was still Miss Ridgeway.
He and papers both had deales as good as done.
Then came the engorge starlet and now makes Mrs. Doyle.
If I were to wish,
I do only come here to put a bullet in the groom.
Who our other guests,
Linnet's godmother who dispises Linnet's wealth.
and godmother's nurse maid Bowers who covers it.
as does Linnet's own maid, poor old Louise.
Oh, his cousin Andrew, he is a slippery fish.
No one except Linnet trust him.
We find mother and are the only sane deportable.
The only one who seems to like Linnet at all
is her own school mate Rosalie.
And she is Salome Otterbourne's niece.
no range but come to play for them.
Mr. Poirot, come dance.
Good luck!
Looking good, Simon.
Come everyone, let's go.
She's followed us again.
I'm sorry.
Oh, gentlemen.
At last, Act Three.
Total there's two bereaved at every party.
How is Linnet?
No, thank you very much, thank you. they're very nice.
Try this one.
Oh, very nice.
All these boxes in there.
He is here.
Who?
Poirot.
Alright, let's speak to him.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
This snake is your pet?
My best friend.
Monsieur Poirot.
Sorry about high drama last night.
Do think about giving us a gate?
You're much too kind to strangers.
Careful! Careful!
Thank you.
Madam.
So sorry!  I go. I go.
You're alright?
Mr. and Mrs. Doyle , so sorry.
Actually, Poirot, we wanted to ask for your help.
It's a Jackie De Bellefort.
She's followed us every step of our honeymoon.
She and I...
we were engaged. You see.
Has she made any specific threats?
No, she doesn't say a thing.
She only showes up, and sits and stares.
Pardon, I want know,
There's always no case for me to recept she has commited all right.
It's indecent what she's doing.
And maladroit mad, and she is making ass of herself a toilet.
See, I was with Jackie, I liked her.
I did.
Then I met Linnet.
Jackie just doesn't exist for anyone.
From hello I just...
got much more near the past by her side.
Lucky me, she feels the same.
I could punch the sun.
Instead, you broke your engagement.
Does he have to spend rest of his life
with someone he doesn't love to spare her feelings?
It's love.
It's not game play fair. There's no rules.
Now maybe she hasn't commited a crime yet.
But I know Jackie.
She will.
She always settles for her course.
Do think about it.
Hello, Mlle,
Do I know you?
If you would tell..make me a little moment to talk with you?
Of course.
Here comes.
Linnet paid the detective buttered money to no mile for tail.
She tenderly offered, I politely declined.
Oh huh.
Madame is used to get what she wants.
Her father was half to a gangster.
You've known Madam Doyle for some time.
We met during school play.
Antony and Cleopatra.
I was Cleopatra.
Until the teacher came one week before the opening,
he decided to give my part to Linnet.
I was stuck Charmian handmaid.
You have our newly wedding in the twist.
First I'd just to be near.
Then I go bold,
Let them see me.
I saw her smile fade.
Her lines crack cross her forehead.
Mlle De Bellefort , you must give it up.
What he's done is done between us , will not undo it
he is married and he loved his wife.
Simon loves me.
I know it.
Even he is forgotten, dazzled by her,
Love that fierce, doesn't vanish.
I love him.
I love him madly.
badly in every minute.
It's psychic, can't switch off.
There is a reason the heart is the organ giving love, you know.
If it stop to rest, we die.
and I won't die alone.
I can assure that.
It's a .22 caliber.
It's practically toy.
Maybe it fix a broken heart,
only takes a single bullet.
Damn her.
Alright then. What you have us to do?
Try police?
Would he find me a handily advice?
I'm sure Mrs. Doyle has a fine home.
Go to it now.
Building your nestle, beginning your lives together.
We could.
Simon.
We can go home and shut the gates.
We could be happy.
What? Just pack it in?
What about our honeymoon?
Consider it...
the cost of love.
and it bargain, and that?
## (Good night.)
Merci.
This way. Don't dawdle.
What's the scam here, Simon?
Thought we will sight seeing today.
Yes, I...
I know I invited you for another ten days.
Sight seeing in <i>Assouan Di Philae</i>.
But,
Circumstances invited the inspiration.
So, like Moses, not far from here,
We have made a surprise turn at water.
After all,
I couldn't refuse...
What?
the Queen of the Nile.
I have a mortal longing in me.
##
Fantastic!
Cheers!
...When we have a boat like that?
That is too much money, Linnet, no enought sense.
It's a great taste in boats.
See?
I told you we would be fine.
Jackie wouldn't be following us anymore.
Let's go.
Alright, everybody aboard.
Captain permission, coming aboard.
Oh, wow!
You're so happy. You deserve.
We have the <i>Karnak</i> all to ourselves until <i>Abu Simbel</i>.
Don't worry about your things
Darling Louise will go back...
and pack up all your rooms for you and meet <i>Di Shella</i>.
Happy to, Miss.
Thank you.
We have a piano tuned.
a chefs stolen from Sheperds of Cairo
and enough champagne...
to fill the Nile.
Champagne
It's no even half ten.
Then we're behind.
So we await one more a band. upstairs.
Hello. Egypt.
All the luggages from the hotel is going to the Karnak.
Monsieur Doyle,
I need his three cases sent to...
I shall strike this like Joe Di Maggio.
Oh. Completely useless.
Five, officer.
Make it Bowers.
Five points.
Bowers my love.
I'm winning by fat margin.
Well done!
Impressive, you did like Joe...
what's that there?
It is a grebe, isn't it? It is beautiful.
You just moved my part.
Foul shot. That was a foul shot, you know it. Take it again.
You cheat. The spin...
Linnet, four cheats on your boat.
Bowers & Van Schuyler are cheats too, just like these two.
Katherine, monamour.
Monsieur Poirot.
I hope you can forgive my hijacking your holiday.
Good glad you miss the friend.
It is an honor.
And this is convienient to my own plans.
Although travel by water doesn't naturally waver me.
Oh, I can tell you,
while I shouldn't tell you actually,
But I suspect you,
perhaps may enclosing me for reasons other than the fun.
I wish we can go home like you said.
and I don't feel safe here.
Not me, not Simon.
Even with Jackie gone.
but you have a lot friends.
When you have money,
No one is ever really your friends.
Now I remember your old jealousies and...
...fights.
I take some pill to get to sleep.
I don't feel safe with any of them.
I hope you might watch for us.
Thank you.
Well?
And now.
Think picky normal
I'm so hot.
Yeah, sure. You're in Egypt.
It's malaria.
You don't have malaria.
You know I have a temprature.
That thermometer is broken.
Perfectly normal.
No, no. It's broken.
No, it's not broken.
Oh, so hot.
I know, I know.
Tactless to talk business with bride on honeymoon.
Bad lawyer. You promised.
Just only a few quick signitures.
Fair enough. My marriage just made difference for sure.
You'd list one notice next time.
It's all quite straight format.
The Ceylon land consession.
The obvious changes if new will.
The lease of the London property.
It is all quite straight format.
Sorry, cousin, you know me.
Never met a contract they couldn't find some corrections.
Papa taught me too well.
Not me. It's not my way.
I haven't read contract in my life.
Any deal they can't make with a handshake, just isn't for me.
Go on, Linnet. Sign it.
Soon you do, soon we get bed.
You're the first girl who ever told me
that a woman can run her affairs as well as a man or better.
Don't tell me that girl changed for a little husband.
Go get ready for the party, Simon.
I promise I won't be too long.
I've been rude.
No rush.
Take it to tomorrow.
Come down, Poirot.
##
Bravisimo!
Wonderful as ever!
Thank you.
My La Reine, I'm so moved.
Your bluesy music has joy and done for the dancing,
and there's tragedy in there too.
Writing tragedy is easier.
I just imagined someone I want to punish.
Then I imagined them in love.
Eva!
Taking quite keen interest in Salome Otterbourne,
I thought Poirot was impervious to love's fever.
I was sick a little once.
It left me within the full liberty for a life time.
There are many fine detectives, what is not true,
there're many average detectives.
But to be what I am,
It require six centredness of mind,
The little grey cents pampered, indulged,
Giving newly oxygen in my blood,
Minutes on my clock.
No, I leave the temper storm of love to you.
But what of the niece?
A beguiling lady, no?
Is she?
A cool, methodical brain of the highest totals.
She sings well too.
I'm not. I haven't noticed. She is...
a school mate of Linnet?
You tried to keep secrets for me?
For me?
What?
Rosalie Otterbourne is overtly beautiful woman...
and Bouc hasn't spoken to her once?
It's not that she's have God smack love.
I've been bursting to tell you...
Linnet introduced her months ago
Since that there hasn't been another women I wanted to look at.
Except there's...a nanny to our children.
She is the...
cleverest merchant,
shocking most, alive woman I ever met.
I'm out class in the breath.
She loves me anyway, missed the only bad mark against her.
Mon ami, Bouc, l'amour,
shouting from the roof ?
Mon a...no where mother can hear.
Madame...Bouc doesn't support the motion?
She's never cared for anyone I ever brought home.
Unless was care that they're only staying one night.
Being...American doesn't our abide.
mother doesn't approve the people been born outside of <i>Mayfair</i>.
She is furious at Linnet making us as a pair.
And your whole opinion doesn't matter?
Money matters.
My income is monthly from Euphemia Bouc.
I've tried to earn enough,
So I don't need her permission to marry her, only her blessing.
I'm just rotten mattered.
All my life,
I never want to be anything to anyone but an amusement.
But for Rosalie, I...
I want to be good.
Everyone,
ship's crew ready for departure, returning 5 a.m.
Remember, we have new guests arriving at <i>Abu Simbel</i>.
- Good night  - Good night.
We're nearly there.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we're approaching <i>Abu Simbel</i>.
We're all going.
No strugglers. You too, Louise. You with us.
I have the pressing to do.
We're in ancient Egypt.
Was your idea for a honeymoon when you are engaged.
Caffe, Mrs. Doyle?
Thank you, Claire.
What's that?
The sandstorm is miles away, madam.
No need to worry.
I can't find my tube of carmine red.
can't be expected to capture these horizons without red.
Rushs down, mother. It's the temple of <i>Abu Simbel</i>.
Ramesses the Great awaits.
Ramesses II...
Married Nefertari first and favorate of his eight wives.
On the wall of the queen's burial #<i>Machitaba</i>#
he wrote a poet to her to respect...
Sir, may I look this?
Oh, Yes.
Thank you.
My love is like no them.
Just by passing, she has stolen my heart.
She is the one throne the sunshine...
He is a man in love.
He murdered half of Nubia.
Gratuitous blocks makes him put up ministry
the egoism of despotic bloody king.
I really like that hats.
Fancinating story.
It's bad enough to be married for one life time.
To be side by side for eternity is inhumane.
Why you must be so cynical, mother?
People build towers to love and song in stone.
As it's cooling over, a pair of dark eyes
is were saved them from pain.
If anything you will double it.
Go on.
Think you and then.
Beautiful girl would be an exception.
Not every love turns to a misery.
No.
The lucky ones die in child birth.
It's my job to protect you.
You think I don't know what you're after?
You....
You want my blessing...
to marry that girl while you can't have it.
Rosalie.
Everything alright?
Yes.
No more hiding.
We make it on our own.
Yes.
New passage are coming aboard.
Got to so much in my shoes.
How is that?
You approve of them?
First man she ever brought home,
A wealthy lawyer.
Straight, narrow,
on his way to make a Missouri senator.
Then was a baron who own islands,
manners of a king.
Now is this. This panelist Bouc...
who drinks too much, laughs too loud
always at wrong fair.
I like him best.
Do you have a husband, madam?
I had a handful husbands.
Each one is handful.
Are you married, Mr. Poirot?
I haven't that felicity.
Which felictity do you have?
I...
I have my cases.
I have my books.
In fact, I have my eye on ...
a cottage, well.
I hope...
eventually to retirement...
gardener.
I...
hope to perfect...
a new...
strain of other vegetable marrows.
They are magnificent vegetable...
they neglect the flavour which is..
I prefer more flavoursome vegetables.
Madam.
What are you really doing way out here, Mr. Poirot?
You do realize we've barely had hands past Cairo.
I haven't been myself.
Well, who shall  you be like?
Cleopatra, of course.
Come with me.
Come on.
The rulers of two kingdoms.
What would Cleopatra think?
Oh, Charmian.
Everybody inside quickly!
Bouc, inside!
Inside!
There is a balcony up the cliff of work out platform,
but no saw of anyone.
You think someone did that on purpose?
Let's get you safe, darling.
Small world.
The captain just swore that
Jackie got here when we left for the temple.
It couldn't be her.
I know she try to kill us. I want her off the ship now.
She already had a ticket to aboard! Put ahead!
There's nothing we can do!
I don't care! She always does this!
Just tell me what the cost to get away from me.
Name a price!
I'll buy the whole damn boat if I have to.
I'll buy the whole damn country!
Madame
Thank you, Louise. Thank you.
Louise,
Have you see my scarf ? I swear I had it earlier.
No. No, Miss Marie.
I'll be sure to look.
Okay. Yeah
You don't take your meal with us?
Miss Linnet prefer me not to.
I love that girl Linnet.
But when the revolution come, she will be the first.
Blindfold, last cigarette, against the wall,
Bang!
Some detective, my ledger?
You've taken my book.
J’ai fait des bêtises, Pardonnez-moi l’erreur.
I did stupid thing, pardon me please.
I confused it with...
...my Edwin Drood in the parlour.
I can see by your penmanship.
You're Dickens every precision.
Monsieur Poirot,
I want do to note you won't have to look out for us any longer.
Jackie might prob be up this reason.
But we can't.
We're going home.
We'll get a car to <i>Khartoum</i> first thing in the morning.
and dockey to rail, to ship to <i>Wode Hall</i>...
then familiar beds for ever.
The hell with Jackie De Bellefort.
God dear!
One last cork, though?
Why not?
I do not normally take alcohol.
But...
for this...
Darling.
Monsieur.
- Yes.  - Yes.
To going home.
Thank you.
You're not built for boats.
Or champagne.
Did you know the wives of the dead pharaohs buried alive with them?
It must be locked in screaming.
But I bet there is one who is willing.
and couldn't bear departed.
You're sorry to see me.
Like it or not, Simon stills.
Simon is afraid of me.
Mlle, You have a choice, still.
You can ruin his life or begin a new one.
It may not be the life that you imagined.
But perhaps it would be the life that God intended.
Love is far too important to trust God.
For the moment I met Simon, I knew one thing for absolute.
I will die...
if we're parted.
I once felt as you do.
I love so much.
but I thought if I lost her, I should die.
I lost her.
To another man?
A mortar shell.
Visiting me in hospital.
It was to be...discharge in a month.
But I...beg for her to come in Christmas...to be together.
She came, but the train...
was...hit.
After Katherine...
I became...
what I desire am now.
I was going to be a farmer.
Forgive me, the Champagne...
It loosens the...
..memory and mouth.
Ship's crew, ready for departure.
It's after twelve.
The crew left the boat.
All I want is a cocktail.
I'm done with today.
No. No.
Time for bed, my love, Yes.
I'll take pill.
So don't worry about waking me.
You not join her, Simon?
Oh, we have made love today.
Twice.
Three times.
Sleep well,
La reine Linnet.
Jackie,
I wish you well.
I do.
I'm not sorry for what we did,
but I'm so sorry for what did to you.
So we wish we could stay friends.
You're the only one who never care about the money.
Good night, Jacks.
AD TIME 30sec
This is the last time you see either of us.
You can't disappear.
Let's call it a night, Jackie.
Yeah.
No. Stay for a bit.
She is working for a scene.
God, I feel so free.
And so farted for not turning around sooner.
You can't be leaving me that easy, Simon.
We were bound.
Heart and body I gave you all of me.
A few months of good times?
Would even that good?
I swear looking at you now makes all fond memories go sour.
It's like trying to remember a party after you been sick.
Simon, Don't be cruel.
I've run dry of sympathy.
Did you anything still stunt of yours bring me back to you?
You're fool if you thought I could love you again.
I don't think I ever did.
Simon, that's enough.
You didn't mean that?
You don't.
Say you love me!
Simon.
Sorry!
No!
Rosalie, take her to Bowers.
Now.
Simon.
No. No. No. No.
I get the doctor.
Rosalie.
Bowers!
Nurse Bowers!
Simon.
Bowers!
No. No. Hey! It's alright.
So sorry!
I'm sorry.
Dr. Windlesham!
What's going on?
It's Simon. In the parlour. He looks bad.
Rosalie, stay there. I'll find nurse Bowers.
Bowers?
Bowers!
Who?
What's going on out there?
What's the matter?
It's Jackie. Bring your bag.
What happen?
which one?
This way.
I don't know.
Jackie.
Come straight in.
Alright?
Yes. Go!
And she shot me!
No. No. No I can't. I can't move my leg.
Bouc, help me.
Help me move him.
Ok.
Follow me.
Get him out.
Ok.
Alright.
I give something to easy pain.
Are you sure vague will make hurt more, doctor,...
for settle score?
Bone shattered. We need hospital.
Oh. So stupid of me. Truly riled Jacks like that.
You're right boy now.
You just might deserve that bullet.
Don't leave her alone. She...
She didn't...
She didn't.
She could hurt herself.
She won't.
I give her something to calm her down.
I'll stay with her.
Good.
Come on. Get him to bed.
Careful.
Just almost there.
Come in.
Sit.  Steady.  Steady.
That's good.
This could help you to sleep.
Oh, God!
Time of death?
Six hours ago.
Eight at most.
Sometime between midnight to 2 a.m.
No evidence struggle.
She died in her sleep.
At least that.
Gun held at temple.
Scorch tracks there.
God!
One bullet.
Small caliber.
Over be a .22 .
Pratically a toy.
Ah, good. I was hoping you with day shift.
Is someone ill?
Someone is dead.
Linnet Doyle.
Linnet?
Stop. What you mean? How?
I am afraid Jacqueline De Bellefort answer me good on threat.
That is impossible. I was with her all night.
She slept right here.
Eyes close.
Could she left, even for a moment?
Did yo leave her side or sleep at all?
I'm not a minute. No.
No wink. Can't even if I had?
I was scared she might hurt on sorry.
So sorry I gave her enough morphia to fallen an elephant.
Was there a single moment when Mlle De Bellefort leave your sight?
Never no.
so Jackie couldn't murder Linnet?
Just she could not push the boulder on Simon Doyle.
What did you do after bringing her to Miss Bowers?
We came back and picked the gun, locked away.
I kicked under the couch.
we..we came back could not find it.
I wanted to wake you.
I said not to .
You didn't want my assistance.
Louise stopped that. She was Linnet's friend.
So right, he is bloodhound, let him snoop.
Simon was with doctor, Jackie was with nurse,
I just figured it was awful lover's quarrel, not a case for the detective.
But the mysterious case of the vanishing pistol,
someone located..
in the moment between you bringing..
Mr. Doyle to the Dr. and you return.
and then presumedly use it...
to commit murder of Linnet Doyle...
and part two lovers forever.
Bouc, tell the captain to search the river around the ship.
Simon Doyle must be told.
No!
Oh, God!
It was... Jackie!
God damn her!
I could kill her.
Jackie De Bellefort was not the killer.
She shot me!
She has a complete alibi for the entile night
from the moment she fire a gun at you.
No!
Oh, God!
Linnet.
You have to help me.
Please!
You have to find out who killed my wife.
Did you suspect any other?
Everyone love Linnet.
Yet your wife confessed* she didn't feel safe with them.
There happened ...
petty things.
I... was crazy about her old bob in on the ship
moaning hold her in the entile time.
She mentioned something about Salome.
Something stupid happened years ago.
She didn't say what exactly.
What of your maid, Louise Bourget?
They're have any disagreement , no?
It was just Louise left something in the hotel.
Theft things. Nail varnish.
She has been with Linnet for years.
She've had charging Linnet's necklace.
Check on the necklace.
It's by the bed.
Thank you, Bouc.
It's not here.
So did you see the necklace when you came this morning?
I saw Miss Linnet there.
Dead.
I dropped tray and ran out.
What did she mean arrival on the way to <i>Abu Simbel</i>...
when she said that travel in Egypt is your idea...
for your own honeymoon?
Perhaps Miss Bourget would prefer
a privacy for this intermittence.
So could you please take Mr. Doyle...
But, No. If you please...I prefer Mr. Doyle hear me,
so he doesn't accused me of secret.
Accused you of secret?
Oui.
She ended my engagement.
Miss Linnet gave a party last year.
A man spoke to me.
And found me after.
When he propose, I give notice.
Miss Linnet was suspect his intention on me.
Just a maid, she had him investigated.
He had debts.
She offer to pay them all, if he would throw me.
To make...a test...of his affection.
He throw me.
For my benefit, she said.
That sum money hand to me as dowry could give me a life.
What did you do last night after you left Miss Linnet?
I went to my cabin on the bow.
Did you go any where else?
See or hear anything else?
Forgive me, sir.
If I had come outside my cabin to smoke,
I might have seen her killer and out or in of cabin.
But you did not or you did? What is this?
Oh, No, I...
I did...I did have a cigarette inside.
All you staring at me...it give me...
please...
You know, we keep confidences
I was childish times, but that's all.
Tell them, I'll never hurt Miss Linnet.
Yes, of course. Easy, easy, keep sit.
And no one here accusing you anything.
I know you always take good care of Linnet.
And I'll be certain... to take care of you.
That can be enough account.
Sure we can let the poor girl go.
You do think someone kill Linnet, stealing her necklace?
I've seen people poison for less.
Range the river.
Please be careful, Please.
Ow.
This is a few private possession I have,
I just sure you'll be sensitive.
Mortal money in the world.
She isn't frozen with the hams.
This is amongst the defiances we can not afford the dead...
in this circumstances.
Doctor, before you go,
you joined this wedding party,
despite your obvious affection.
You are now resolved* to see her with another?
Some people you can't say no.
She asked me...
If I may ask you a question, here about your passport?
You called by Dr. Windlesham,
but this is not your natural title.
No.
Lord Windlesham.
Born to,
not end.
Right as Lord Windlesham, belongs to the betroth tradition.
Right as doctor, is mine.
And Dr. Windlesham travels wide?
India, Africa.
Much of the world lack access to modern medicine
we take for grant to, Poirot.
Most nobility enjoy their nobility more.
Linnet used to tease me for that.
Said I shouldn't expect her the honeymoon in a mud hut.
Your thought to her world is standard.
What the husband?
I don't know him well.
Through I to know, I can't recommand.
This is appropriate.
Mr. Doyle would have us focus all suspision on you.
Me?
I was with him all last night.
Indeed. You gave him strong opiate thing injection.
He was asleep.
You could left him at the time not be observed.
Did he ask for the drug?
He was in pain.
Your analgesic* for pain medications in your bag which was suffice.
You created for yourself an oppertunity.
Look. I can create, but...
She was unkind, no?
She flaunted her new love...
it's called you like the puppy dog.
Seeing that pained you...
and like the strong opiate injection...
you could end your pain with a bullet.
Lord demand to get what they want.
You're still a Lord.
What you want me to say?
Run out ridiculous?
I'm not fool.
I knew she was sadly for me.
I didn't mind.
When she married Simon,
I actually thought about ending my own life.
They all thought our engagement was for families.
The papers, for the damnassed critical theatrics at all.
The shame it is...
I loved her.
Little Linnet and cousin Andrew.
I know her since we were...children.
Were you aware any grudges against family?
More than many.
Her father got rich making rich people poor.
Linnet continued the practice.
Did you hear anyting of the commotion last night?
I was all sound by 11.
And contracts you wish her to sign, they are very important?
They are. Were.
Linnet gone, the...
statements have to be redraw.
May I see them?
Forgive me. These are confidential.
I must insist.
Respect the deceased.
No matter, I know what it contain.
I doubt that very much.
I believe they stand your stewardship of Madame Doyle's state,
despite her marriage, no?
Who told you?
I am Hercule Poirot.
I don't need to be told.
I have eyes on the see, a brain on the thinks.
Now I think some pully of you.
You think I killed her?
Did you kill her?
No benefit a dime from her dead, Mr. Poirot.
You can look at the will I revise.
Godmother stands her inherit.
Her husband legally against the rest.
You won't see my name anywhere.
Perhaps the intention was not to inherit, but to conceal.
You, executed the control of her vast fortune.
Not concern, so long as there is no impropriety.
No speculation by loyal cousin Andrew...
in the time of market decline.
This is not kind of thing you can prove on boat.
You endeavor to obtain a signiture...
by trickery...
from little Linnet.
And you failed.
You knew a dozen matter of time...
before her keen eyes on coverage on thievery...
unless her eyes were closed forever.
See, in my position,
Mr. Poirot,
I often after transport items,
such as artworks worth of millions.
And they need security.
So, if I wanted to kill her,
I would've used this.
.45
Yes.
You may go.
.45
Why would he risk going back for Jack's gun of here?
That he would not.
Miss Bowers, if I may trouble you.
He wants to speak to me?
I'm laying down the corner.
There's nothings fear. You might know something value.
That would be the shocking twist.
If you wouldn't mind her coming alone.
I do, I would.
I want me served my funeral.
When you kept vigil with Mlle De Bellefort,
did she make threats against Linnet Doyle?
No, her threats were against herself.
She wanted to pitch herself into the drain, can not come out.
That's why I gave her the morphia.
How fortunate did we had you with this.
You have been nurse companion for how long?
Well, coming along 10 years.
All with Mrs. Van Schuyler, so...
feels like 20.
The job came to me late in life.
After you lost your great wealth.
Wealth?
Acquired taste require acquisition.
Here you moon over truffle and king crabs.
So to your gown Channel,
your luggage LV, your shoes Perugia,
or the pick of chic ten years, past one and patched over.
How many years since you have caviar, did you say?
Many lost fortunes in the crash.
Many of them due to papa Ridgeway...
and his unscrupulous business practices.
Perhaps that explains your reaction to...
the lease of Linnet London property, hm?
It was once called <i>The Bowers Building</i>.
We employed over a thousand people,
Good wages.
We spent our wealth when we had it.
So many...
like family.
Some never found work again.
So yes.
I miss caviar.
But I miss them more.
And you feeling as you do,
with your charge Mlle De Bellefort,
drug into slumber.
You're free to move about ship,
to find the gun, to shoot Linnet Doyle...
No!
when she sleep...
Mrs. Van Schuyler !
Stop the query.
A visitor.
She cannot be without Miss Bowers for even a moment.
Please, please join us to tea.
He just accused me of shooting Linnet!
No. No. No. I only...
suggest...
..a possibility.
I don't approve of this interrogation.
Have been who you to question us?
I am the working man.
The skilled labourer,
the hero of your own economical fairy tales.
Well, I don't care for it.
Or for you.
You are meant to find the killer...
of my goddaughter.
I never had...
children of my own.
I had Linnet.
You are aware ,of course, that you...
are the key beneficiary Linnet Doyle's will.
You accuse me of murder?
Oh, No. He accuse everyone of murder.
It is a problem I've made.
That I would kill...
my own goddaughter for money?
I already gave a well fortune.
I don't give a figure for money.
I see no reason to continue this conversation.
Come, Bowers.
The steward on the ship keep excellant all.
Have you noticed a truly first rate housekeeping staff?
He's out of his brains.
Beds made everyday.
Sheets folded in mattress precise 45 degree
Hospital corner, I must say,
Unlike, for example,
other day we departed when the beds were made in the...
flowing edged bed spoiled style.
But until when I saw, Mlle De Bellefort...
are sleeping Miss Bowers' room on their third aboard.
The bed was as it had been on our first,
as yet ... unslepting.
Bouc.
Where did you find Miss Bowers when you sought her aid?
In Miss Van Schuyler's room.
My mind asks...
here's a woman,
for hold the fire against class and materialism bould so hot,
And she keeps a servant?
No.
Her servant is not servant.
No nurse.
Only companion.
Let us name raw reason.
Love.
Don't worry.
and I know this.
It's alright.
People...
kill...
for love.
They found something!
What?
Monsieur Poirot.
Well done, young man. Get yourself cleaned up.
Yes, sir.
It's your scarf.
But It was missing.
I've been looking for since the temple.
It's true. we couldn't find anywhere.
It has another adventure in your absence.
Your scarf, complete with bullet holes.
Used to dampen the noise of the shot.
Also a boody handkerchief and...
the 22 derringer belonging to Jacqueline De Bellefort.
Two bullets fired.
We return immediately to <i>Assouan</i>.
Ooh, I like this.
the foe force of his forward attention,
the great mind, all mine.
Flirtation of our delightful will no effect.
A woman shows you a dribble of the interest,
and you're assuming it gonna be the hide guilt.
whoever she was,
must done a number on you.
That mask covers your whole face, doesn't it?
You knew Linnet Doyle before you came to entertainment, yes?
Pass cross.
You didn't like her?
I still polite.
Monsieur Doyle mention an incident with the victim long ago.
A reason for possible animosity.
Poolside Kennebunkport.
Summer 1924, before I was someone.
I paid a show at hotel and...
thought to take Rosie for a swim before packing.
A young girl complaint to her Papa...
about having to share the pool with the colored.
We were told to leave and...
while I didn't abide.
I was meant to.
I wasn't sure she didn't remember it.
I do.
It was1925.
So do she.
Mlle.
She shamed you in front of your world.
Monsieur Poirot,
If I put a bullet everyone to come bashing at me
for not keeping to my place,
The world would be laid with dead white ladies.
And Linnet was just a kid by then,
taught by a bad daddy.
But she became my friend in boarding school,
gave the other girls license to do the same.
Truth to tell,
Linnet was... easy to hate as love.
I might doubles.
That is a very honest reply.
Thank you move for your time, madam.
Oh, there's...one final question,
It's just curiosity I crane.
Your hat,
in the turban style,
many times I've seen you.
You're wearing just when would like.
but it is out of fashion, no?
Not when I wear it.
If you would...
indulge me please to...
remove it?
Oh, it's alright, Rosie.
He's drived an answer, he already knows.
.22 caliber, like the one that killed Linnet Doyle.
I've used it if you want to ask.
Twice in defense, once in anger.
Last night was not that once.
You tell me if I'm lying.
Mr. Poirot!
Monsieur,
You interrupted in poor time, madam.
You're meant to be the detective yet.
I found...
...this.
It was there,
right in my vanity drawer,
face up like yolk.
No, I didn't take it.
No, it's why our killer has reminded to your custody to return , thank you.
Unless...
Poirot.
Unless what?
Unless you took the necklace to steal the suspision away from you.
Evidence is easily disposed of over the ship's railing.
Whoever did this may the show of discovering.
Why would my mother murder Linnet?
Bouc, you said your mother was furious with Linnet for making you pair.
Madam, it was Linnet Doyle
introduced your son to the woman you distrust, you know?
Rest assure. If I had a bullet in my pocket,
correct my son's poor taste,
I would not spend it on Mrs. Doyle.
Mother, please, that is no helping.
Perhaps. But I've seen your excellent landscapes.
You're a patient woman...
who achieves every effect sheer and tens in time.
who so deligently planed to have me aboard the ship
Yet, with my suspisions directed in another direction.
That is a private affair.
That is a concluded affair, madam.
Enough.
Enough indeed.
I'm now prepare to present the conclusions...
of my another more secret case,
and put it to rest.
What secret case? What?
What does he mean?
Mother?
Monsieur.
Mlle.
Madam, thank you for join us.
Bouc.
I really make my own confession.
When we met in Giza ,
I told you I was on vacations for my detective work quit.
In fact,
I was...and have been on a case.
What case?
You.
At the request of your mother,
Madam Bouc cabled me in distress some weeks ago.
My mother? And distress?
I was bidden to follow the Otterbourne's
to determine the character and fitness
of the show business woman who has stolen your heart.
You did this to me?
I'm your mother of done far worse.
To observe them,
I had to consume many doses of the bluesy music
which I...confess I didn't expect enjoy,
but in fact I enjoy much...
as performed by Madam Otterbourne.
It was very..sound motional for me. It was very nice.
That's why you were in Giza.
How we met accidently?
I'm sorry.
I had to make you see what she is.
Tell him, detective.
I will tell you, Bouc.
Having observed Rosalie Otterbourne.
Having inspected her book of accounting.
Yes, I know, please forgive me, madam.
What?
I can tell you. She gambles frequently though, frequently wins.
She drinks little, she tips well.
She pays on employees and taxes on time to the dime.
She is diligent. She is forthright.
In business perhaps even virtuosic.
Though at piano, sadly amateur.
As far her adopted mother,
She drinks at excess twice a week more.
She smokes cigarettes of various compositions.
And I believe that two of her marriages were not...
I think it strickly legally ended.
But she is a magnificant personality.
I do not yet know who...
murdered Linnet Doyle.
But I do know this.
Rosalie Otterbourne is irrevocably in love with your son.
and this is better in virtue.
She is more than fit, she is a fined.
It wasn't enough than we happy.
I didn't trust her. Despite the detective, I still don't.
I love her.
That has to count for something.
Why should it?
<i>Corinthians</i> had it wrong in every point.
Love isn't patient and kind.
It envys and boasts, doesn't care who gets mown down.
And angers this irritably,
it keeps record of every transgression against it.
and good got it fails.
Sure, the face ages love fails.
He really wants your permission, but he doesn't need.
Any more than I need to meet your standard.
Or yours.
Having had chance to observe you.
Wanna know what I make of your character?
He's obsessive.
He's vain.
He's smug.
He's lonely for reason.
A detestable,
tiresome, bombastic,
egocentric little freak!
How dare you?
Get out in my way.
Mlle, wait for me.
Miss Otterbourne, I owe you an explanation.
Please.
Allow me to apologize.
Have you ever met a man
who said as my name as many times as Hercule Poirot...
Confirmed.
It is Louise Bourget.
Isn't a sign drowning.
He threw the body in after.
She must got caught up in the paddle.
She was murdered on board...
within the last hour.
Money...
covered in blood.
Louise Bourget...
hinted that she might have seen the killer make the escape.
# If in this he has, he might have...#
or felt her silence for ask on the money of blackmail.
Only the killer believes on her silence of silent.
Her throat cut clean.
The blade...
short.
very shawer,
Like...
Like scalpel.
You!
You killed them.
It was...It was his scalpel.
He killed Louise.
and she saw him leaving Linnet's cabin.
You've been lying ever since.
You're the one Linnet should've never trusted.
I always told your firm was bilking half a millions.
You murder.
I am killing you.
Stop it!
...behind...
Hey!
Act you much match!
How many have to die before you do something?
A further cut while you run me of the close.
He's trying.
Well he'd better try harder.
Or all would happy end in the Egyptian jail cell.
If you won't name the killer,
I will.
No.
He loved Linnet too much.
That's motive right there.
That all of you just keep quiet and let Poirot work.
And any case we reach the port by morning,
For now it's the safest way,
we just keep to own cabins with door locked.
She was engaged for a time.
I have to write, let him know that she is...
gone.
They broken off. But he'd want to know.
That's good to hear.
That's horribe. All of it horrible.
Who can do such a thing?
You must have some theory, Monsieur Poirot?
Don't you?
I'll have one final interview to conduct.
Whole speed.
As I have a lot affection,
to color the cloudy in my thoughts in your investigation,
I must ask you to remain this witness to listen in front of you.
How long did you know Linnet Doyle?
I'm a suspect now?
I know your tricks.
I've seen this play before for other side of the table.
A long time.
We weren't close, just familiar.
My parents considered her parents they're equal, so we...
grow up the same party's wonder.
Kissing each other's friends.
You can't catch me anything, cause I haven't done anything.
So ask whatever you like.
Where's your coat?
Why did you not wake Linnet Doyle when Simon was shot?
Poirot.
Don't...
Her husband was shot.
You have such sympathy for the former fiance of Louise Bourget.
You wish to inform him of her fate.
You didn't express the same sympathy for Linnet.
I thought she would be asleep.
She..She said that she's taken sleeping pill.
Rubbish!
How had I thought happy to see you , Bouc.
But you lie to me.
You lie in my face.
I know you make yourself my prey.
What happened?
Did he kill Linnet?
Was you and Rosalie together?
No, she is honest too. Proudly won't for theft.
You alone did this.
No, I didn't.
You returned to the parlour alone to find the gun and you did.
You then went to the Doyle's cabin to inform Linnet about Simon.
She was sleeping. You saw the necklace.You saw it by temptation.
But she woke catching you, so you shot her.
No, I didn't.
But Louise Bourget saw you leaving and demanding the money.
instead you brought her a blade.
No, I didn't.
Two murders. All to secure the stolen fortunes.
So you would not need her permission to marry, only her blessing.
I didn't kill anyone.
I never found the gun. That's not what happened.
No, you did not kill anyone.
Linnet Doyle's murder was premeditated.
It require exact timing, a stolen scarf.
You did not kill her, but...
You did go to Doyle's cabin...
and found Linnet...
already dead.
You knew she had been killed before all of us.
But instead of calling for help,
You took the necklace.
After I told you the cabin search, you intended to return it.
But you came upon Louise Bourget arguing with someone,
demanding money.
You saw her throat cut.
You saw her murdered.
You know who killed Louise?
But you could not say know, but it admitting you stole so.
You hid it in your mother's room,
but you didn't sure catch all the blame...
while you remain silent.
Only you have Louise Bourget's blood on your coat.
If...
If I admit this...
If I say it,
You'll face punishment for theft. You'll face prison.
I'll...I'll lose Rosalie.
She loves you.
I can't.
You can not let the killer go free to protect yourself.
I wanted to tell you.
All I thought was how ha...
All I thought was how happy to be.
We could run off and get married.
No obligations, we'll be free.
Stupid!
I was so stupid. I know.
Who did you see her with?
You are a terrible friend, Poirot.
Why did you have to teach me to be good?
Who?
You could never understand...
what people will do...
for love.
Come on!
No.
Mo...Mon ami, Bouc.
Bouc?
I heard a gunshot.
I heard a shot.
What's going on?
Did you catch him?
Poirot, did you catch whether or not?
What is it?
Was someone hurt?
I have never seen anyone so happy...
as he...
when he was with you.
He told me how much he hoped you would be happy one day too.
that you get tired of being just pure cold detective.
Be human instead.
I don't want you happy.
I want you to find who did this.
It was your gun shot him.
It was his gun.
I was in here!
His gun!
I was in here.
No, I don't believe you.
You were there, you saw me, tell her.
It's true. He's in here.
No. I don't.
My pistol was in my suitcase in my cabin.
Why did you leave your gun, with...with a killer on boat.
Because...
we'll be at port by sunrise,
there's local police saw a dark man holding a gun,
they'll shoot me before I ever saw a news.
You have failed...
your every duty,
his friend.
I did fail.
Linnet Doyle,
Louise Bourget,
Bouc.
I will not fail him now.
The murderer is here.
And will stay here.
Mrs.Otterbourne is right.
I love to talk, and audience.
I am vain you see.
I love people to hear me bring the solution to a crime scene.
See, Clever! Hercule Poirot.
While all I want now...
would give anything for...
with one conversation...
with Bouc.
I'll stomp about and say,
around the person like Linnet Doyle...
there're so many conflicting hates and jealousies.
It is like the cloud of flies, buzzing buzzing
and he will laugh at me.
<i>Then play your clever games,</i> he will say.
Ask you questions till the right one comes.
Who would want to kill her?
Who could have it?
Then I would ask, I would see. yes.
Bouc showed me too late.
A person in love will do anything.
Love make us to do reckless things, rush things.
A bolder falls, rush.
Louis murdered, wild.
Bouc, shot.
I had believed the identity of Madam Dole's killer was obvious.
Cousin Andrew Katchadourian.
Doing as he did at the Temple of Abu Simbel,
while he wandered for alone, despaired.
When he saw an opportunity,
hoping to hide his sins under a rock,
He pushed as one.
I don't know what I was thinking.
I...
I wasn't... I wasn't thinking.
I saw them below.
And...
And thank God, I missed.
And you must all know, I...
I didn't kill her.
I will never do that.
I loved her.
I didn't kill her.
No, he did not.
Linnet Doyle's murder was not wild.
It was methodical plan.
The details, the time, the bullets, the alibis.
But planed by who?
I turned to Bouc once more.
Why did you paint him in a green jacket
he wore in red on the piramid?
My red paint went missing.
It was stolen...
by Linnet Doyle's murderer,
by her husband,
Simon Doyle.
Me?
That's ridiculous!
How could he? He was shot.
Yes. He was shot. We know this for centain.
What we do not know for centain is when he was shot.
Or what he did in the moments after we believed that he was.
Consider, Madam Doyle reported...
her husband was cross with Louise for some nail polish left at hotel.
Why should he care?
Because Madem Doyle wore blood red nail polish,
which had for him an intended use.
This gone. Madam Bouc's paint would have to do.
He was something not expected his wife invited a detective to the party.
So to be safe, he puts me to sleep a single glass of Champagne.
At his insistance,
sends me to my bed with my head spinning,
druged for his performance.
Miss Otterbourne, you saw a gun fired.
You saw Simon collapse on an blood soaked handkerchief with his leg,
at which piont you left him,
busy with Jackie and finding the doctor.
This gives the murderer for moments alone,
moments alone he needs.
He picks up the pistol,
He runs to his wife's cabin,
Simon...
and he shoot self to the temple.
There were scorch much on Linnet Doyle's wounds
The missing scarf would eliminate it.
but this wasn't used on her.
It was instead used here to muffle the sound of another shot.
What's the matter, Bouc?
Been mattered.
He returns here,
to retrieve the scarf which he previously hidden.
With he took the gun one more time and fired towards the leg.
After which he replaces one bullet to the gun.
So if it was found,
we can count not three, but two shots that we believe have been fired.
He then wraps the handkerchief, the scarf and the gun,
and throws them into the water of the Nile.
Then let himself ready for the arrival of Dr. Windlesham.
She shot me.
I can't move my leg.
Your alibi secured you avoid suspision...
and you assure the multitude of the suspects.
Encouraging a guestlist not from your friends or family,
but exclusively those groaning, grudges, grievance against your wife,
even our entertainment.
All passing as a new husband thoughtful
as blending flecked in every direction except at you.
You are mad.
I would shoot myself...
and somehow kill Louise and Bouc.
He's right. (He...)
He couldn't have killed them.
He did not kill them.
The second and third murders were...
commited by his accomplice in the first and...
I believe by the master mind behind is the entile ingenious plot.
Jacqueline De Bellefort.
His lover once, his lover still.
Introducing the couple,
stalking and finding them aboard the ship,
shooting Simon with a blank.
All to create two unassailable alibis,
the grieving husband left to inherit wife's fortune,
then he turn to marry the woman he loves,
has always loved.
When I ask Louise Bourget has she seen anything,
she give a curious answer.
If I come outside my cabin, I might have seen the killer.
Not yes not no. But they threat to Lennet's killer...
who was present in the room...
Simon Doyle.
well then, assure her that Louise will be taken care. Indeed she was.
As soon as he was able,
Simon note out to send a message to Jacqueline...
warning her of the new danger...
telling her where to find the weapon.
And then when Bouc...
When Bouc...
detected who killed Louise,
Simon shouted,
Come on!
a warning...
to execute on it.
for shot Bouc through the throat...
before he could reveal...
Jacqueline De Bellefort.
You killed my son?
I'll see you die for this.
Rosie, please.
I swear.
You can't all believe him.
He has no proof.
True.
I have only a sinking gun away the fingerprints. Yes.
But it came with a gift.
The handkerchief.
The warm water of the Nile in spring time
will set the color of blood to dark brown.
In those same mysterious waters,
carmine red paint will fade...
to pink.
Oh, how clever is Hercule Poirot.
Was the ambition his or yours?
He needed things.
I needed him.
You never care for money.
but you could deny him nothing on even the plan...
when he could not devise on his own.
Simon, what could we do?
Let's leave.
No, taken in prison we'll be separated.
We get off boat now. I'll be around.
Come on.
It's alright, Simon.
Give it to me.
Listen to me.
We can make it.
We ought to go now. and we ought to be strong.
We can be strong.
I love you...
I'm sorry you have become so wealthy.
Nothing I can fix.
We might just keep some.
Come.
Or they'll arrest me, huh?
No.
So long as you settle her affairs honestly...
and pay by what you owed.
You return to London, doctor?
There's nothing for me in London anymore.
West Africa.
Perhaps I can do some good there.
I wish I have never got to see you work.
Perhaps.
LONDON
SIX MONTHS LATER
See you soon, Sid.
Thanks for tonight.
See you in a few days.
Tell the band one more song and they have to finish their rehearsal.
Watch you, Mister.
We close, man.
English Subtitles by MeGustaVerano C.X.