Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Who do we know
in Berwick-upon-Tweed?
We don't.
That's north, isn't it?
Careful.
Oh, good Lord.
It's from Queenie Hennessy.
Who?
She was at the brewery
years ago.
Gave her a lift sometimes.
Harold?
She's in a hospice.
She's just saying goodbye.
It's a nice day.
Why don't you get out
the patio chairs?
Are you still sitting there?
I'm writing Queenie a note.
Only nothing feels right.
I don't see why you can't email
like any normal person.
Do you want to do it?
Why would I do it?
I don't know. You're good
at this sort of thing.
You're the one
that worked with her.
Say something you mean.
I'm off.
Will you be long?
I'm only going to the post box.
- Morning, Harold.
- Morning, Rex.
- Lovely day.
- Yeah.
Off for a walk?
- Post box.
- I don't get letters.
Since Elizabeth passed,
- I only get circulars.
Thank you.
Want me to take that?
It's okay.
I'm going to the post office.
Harold?
Fuel?
No, thank you.
- Is that a letter?
- For a friend.
Aw, cute.
She has cancer.
Better go and post it now, huh?
And go home.
My aunt had cancer.
Do you want a bag?
- Sorry?
- For the milk.
- No, it's okay.
- But you can't give up.
It's not about the medicine
and that.
It's about what's in here.
Gotta have faith.
- Am I talking crap?
- Not at all.
I'm afraid religion's
not something
I ever quite got the hang of.
I don't mean, like, religious.
I mean, like, believing
you can make a difference.
And your aunt got better?
- Because you believed she could?
- Yeah.
She said it gave her hope
when everything else had gone.
St. Bernadine's Hospice.
I'd like to speak to a patient,
please. Queenie Hennessy.
I need to tell her something.
I'm afraid that's not possible.
Am I too late?
Queenie's asleep right now.
But I can take a message.
Tell her Harold Fry...
is on his way.
His what?
- His way.
All she has to do is wait.
Because I'm going to save her,
you see.
I'll keep walking,
and she must keep living.
It's a terrible line.
What are you doing?
- I'm walking.
Oh, right. Okay.
I'll tell her. You're walking?
From South Devon
to Berwick-upon-Tweed.
- I'm setting off right now.
As long as I walk,
she must live.
Please tell her this time,
I won't let her down.
Well, then.
You always do this.
You say you're ready,
then you fetch more crap.
Cheerio.
Hello.
Whoo-hoo!
Oh.
Who knew?
I'm walking
to Berwick-upon-Tweed.
You're what?
I'm going to save
Queenie Hennessy.
Have you been drinking?
There was a girl in the garage.
She had blue hair.
She saved her aunt, she told me.
You can't save people
with cancer,
not unless you're a surgeon.
And you never walk!
You've never walked
in your life!
The only time you walk
is to get to the car.
I know.
This is ridiculous. Come home.
It isn't enough
to post a letter.
Please.
I need to do this, Maureen.
Well... if that's what you need.
I had no idea.
Walk. Why not?
Walk to Berwick-upon-Tweed.
It can only be about 500 miles!
Harold?
You will not die.
Die you will not.
- You'll not die, will you not.
You will not die.
Not die you will.
Will you not die.
Die you will not.
Not, not, not.
I walked eight miles today.
You stink.
- Everything all right, Maureen?
- Yes, thank you.
Why isn't Harold doing the bins?
- He's in bed.
- Is he poorly?
- It's nothing. He slipped.
Oh, no! That's terrible.
- Can I do anything?
- It's fine, Rex.
He just needs to rest.
See any hedgehogs today?
Sorry.
Die will you not.
Not will you die.
Not will you...
Not. Not. Not, not, not.
You all right?
I don't suppose I could ask
for a glass of water.
I had no idea water was so nice.
You sure you're all right?
I'm walking a long way,
but I haven't quite
got the hang of it yet.
Why don't you sit down
for a minute?
Oh.
You'd have thought walking
would be the simplest thing.
It never ceases to amaze me
how difficult
the things that are supposed
to be instinctive really are.
Like eating.
Some people have problems
with that.
Sleeping, you know?
Even children.
Did you have any yourself?
- One.
- Ah.
- A son?
- Yeah.
A man needs a son.
Without a son,
he's the end of the line.
Not, not, not.
So...
- you're still...
Yes.
You?
I'm still here.
If that's what you mean.
I haven't gone anywhere.
Harold, when I said
you should go,
I didn't mean you should go.
I meant you should come back.
Harold?
I made a promise.
I suppose you've worked out
how much this is costing.
I'll stick to a budget.
It's not as if we had plans.
Is it okay?
Okay?
- Well, that I'm doing this.
That I'm walking.
I hardly notice you've gone.
Oh.
Excuse me, is this seat free?
Of course.
Goodbyes are always hard.
They are.
Would you like half?
- No, I couldn't. No.
- No, no, please.
I won't eat it all.
- We'll share.
- Thank you.
Mm.
Can I ask a question?
You seem like
a decent sort of man.
If you like.
I come to Exeter every Thursday.
I meet a young man, we...
do things. No one else knows.
Can I go on?
Mm-hmm.
His English is not so good.
I believe he had polio
as a child.
Sometimes causes him to limp.
He moves me, this young man.
He moves me beyond words. But...
I lick his trainers.
It's part of what we do.
But I noticed today
that he had a hole at the toe.
I want to buy him another pair,
but I don't want to offend him.
Equally, I...
can't bear the thought
of him walking the streets
with a hole in his trainers.
His foot will get wet.
What should I do?
I think I'd buy him
new trainers.
Thank you.
- Oh!
Do you need a lift?
- No, it's all right, thank you.
- You sure?
I've made a promise.
What do you know
of drift velocity?
Well...
Nothing.
Who was Milton?
Milton...?
I don't know.
For God's sake.
I hear from your mother
you got into Cambridge.
I hate you!
Fuck you!
No! No! No.
Thank you.
I'll be off in a minute.
But you're fucked.
Your shoes are fucked,
so is your body.
Every way you look at it,
you're fucked.
How do you think
you can make it to Berwick?
I don't know.
I failed Queenie once,
I can't do it again.
I have a spare room.
You can stay the night.
My son wanted a dog.
It's not my dog.
It's my partner's.
Harold?
- Yeah?
- For your feet.
- You can't wash my feet.
You're walking funny.
I need to look.
There's no problem.
Yeah? So how do you
take care of them?
- I put on plasters.
- Hmm.
Show me your leg.
- That's okay.
- Show me.
I know what I'm doing,
I'm fully trained.
You're a nurse?
A doctor.
They let women do it these days.
Hmm!
Give me your foot.
I won't send you home, Harold.
If you continue to walk,
this will get worse.
Your blisters are infected.
They need treating.
Why don't you have proper boots?
These are my shoes.
My partner likes walking.
He has all the gear.
You must be a good doctor.
I only get cleaning work
in England.
You think your feet are bad?
You should see the toilets
I clean.
Oh!
So... did your son get his dog?
I'm afraid I failed my son
very badly.
Your son and Queenie?
You failed them both?
It isn't good enough.
Never will be.
So it's not about you?
My husband.
But he's not here.
- He's walking.
To the surgery?
- To Berwick-upon-Tweed.
He believes he can save
a former colleague.
She has cancer.
And how does he mean
to save her?
He seems to think
the walk will do it.
He left 11 days ago.
A girl in a garage
gave him the idea.
Harold doesn't walk.
He could cause an accident.
He needs to be stopped.
And he has Alzheimer's.
I see. Uh...
What medication is he on?
Well, I mean,
it isn't diagnosed,
not as such. But he forgets
things all the time.
I mean,
he even forgot his phone.
- He has no phone?
- Exactly.
He's walking
the length of England
and he hasn't got a phone.
Mrs. Fry...
just because your husband
forgot his phone,
doesn't mean he has Alzheimer's.
It's good to walk.
It's good for the body,
and the mind too.
What he's doing, it may seem
a little unusual, but...
he's not hurting anyone.
It's beautiful.
You need to rest another day.
Ah, I have to get back
on the road.
You must tell me
what I owe for the room.
Here.
Thank you!
I'm sorry not to meet
your partner.
You can stay
as long as you like,
you still won't meet him.
Why?
He's gone, Harold.
He doesn't live here anymore.
I bet you think
I'm freaking crazy.
No, I don't.
We came here for a better life.
A few months later,
this woman shows up with a baby.
I didn't know about the woman.
I didn't know about the kid.
I thought he was going
to boot them out,
but when he picked up the baby,
it was like...
seeing a man I didn't know.
I went for a walk.
When I got back, they'd left.
He might come home.
It was a year ago.
And here you are walking
to Berwick-upon-Tweed.
If only I had a shred
of your faith, Harold.
- But you do.
- No.
I'm waiting for something
that can never happen.
- Yes?
Here.
Are you sure?
Go well, Harold.
And you owe me nothing
for the room.
You were my guest.
Maureen.
I wonder, do you have any milk?
Of course.
Do you want to come in?
Oh, it's all right, thank you.
I'll wait.
There you are.
- How's the patient?
- Good.
He's not at home, Rex.
I've been lying.
Did you think I don't know?
It was me.
It was always me
who talked of going.
But I never did. I stayed.
Because when it came to
walking away, I couldn't do it.
Even though it was...
so terrible.
I said things once...
I can't bear to think
about the things I said.
The world without Harold
would have been worse.
And now he's done it.
He's walking to Queenie.
And I'm frightened
he won't come back.
We could drive to find him,
if you like.
It would only take a few hours.
Maybe.
No, I can't.
Supposing he doesn't
want to see me.
To tell you the truth,
it hasn't been a marriage
for 25 years.
- Did you know her?
- Who?
- Queenie.
- No.
- I met her once.
Oh?
She came to the house
with a message for Harold.
I sent her away.
He never saw her again.
Harold hasn't walked out on you, Maureen.
That's not what this is about.
But, Rex...
I never gave him the message.
You'll not die.
Will you not die.
You will not die.
Oh, that's tough.
But it's good
your friend's comfortable.
She's in the best place.
Do you know someone
in a hospice?
Er, I'm a surgeon.
I treat people with cancer.
I met a Slovakian lady.
She's a doctor.
She can only get cleaning work.
So, this walk for your friend,
it's a sponsored event?
- She's waiting.
Excuse me?
I'll keep walking,
she'll keep living.
I'm going to save her.
Oh, I see. Yeah.
Uh, so, you're a religious man?
No.
I am. My wife and I,
we go to church every week.
But cancer isn't about belief,
it's about medicine.
And when someone
goes to a hospice,
it's because there's nothing
more we can do.
It means it's the end.
- When did your friend write?
- Three weeks ago.
And you've been on the road
ever since?
If I may say, you look tired.
Is it really necessary
to do all this?
Look, I'm sorry.
I should have kept quiet.
My wife always says I interfere.
It's fine.
Look,
you keep walking.
Good luck!
David?
Sorry.
St Bernadine's Hospice.
Could I leave a message
for Queenie Hennessy?
Are you the gentleman
who's travelling by foot?
I was.
Sister Philomena
was hoping you'd call.
- She has news.
Mr. Fry?
- HAROLD; Hmm?
I'm going to be frank with you.
Queenie has no family.
When people have no one,
they tend to pass quickly.
I see.
So, the change is remarkable.
To be honest,
I don't know how to explain.
I... I'm sorry?
She shows off your postcards!
Some days she even sits up!
She's waiting?
Yes, Mr. Fry.
- Just as you asked.
I must admit,
when you first rang,
I was afraid
you'd misunderstood
the gravity of things.
But I was wrong.
Maybe it's what the world
needs right now.
A little less sense
and a bit more faith.
- Yes!
When should we expect you?
In three weeks.
Possibly more, maybe less.
Goodness!
I'll tell Queenie.
And tell her not to give up.
Tell her I will keep walking.
I will.
Even when she doubts,
she must not give in.
She must keep living.
I believe she will.
God bless you, Mr. Fry.
Hello?
♪ We sowed the seeds of love ♪
♪ We showed them how to sing ♪
♪ Grown with a knowing
Of something in their blood ♪
♪ Where ceremony begins
Begins ♪
♪ When the apron string
Unpinned ♪
♪ My garden was forsook ♪
♪ To weigh in on industry ♪
♪ Raised behind the altar
Under oak and ash ♪
♪ I grew to a bonny rowan
Tree, tree, tree... ♪
♪ Freely in my own country ♪
Thank you!
♪ We sowed the seeds of love ♪
♪ We showed them how to sing ♪
♪ Grown with a knowing
Of wildness in their blood ♪
♪ More than the sum
Of the everything ♪
♪ The old wow never wears thin ♪
Here's to the walk.
Are you sure
you don't want a beer?
Lemonade's perfect.
Do you really believe
you can do it?
If I keep putting one foot
in front of the other,
it stands to reason
I'll get there.
What you're doing, man,
it's awesome.
I don't suppose I could
trouble you for a crisp.
Yeah, of course.
And you're in love
with the woman in Berwick?
I'm in love with my wife.
Could I take your photo?
Just to remember ya.
Hmm! Oh.
I wish you could see.
Harold Fry?
- Yes?
- Amazing.
Ooh! What can I give you?
No! Nothing.
Here.
Thank you.
It's so lovely to meet you.
It's lovely to meet you too.
...and a few showers coming in
overnight from the west.
And now, we have the amazing
story of a retired local man
who is walking from South Devon
to Berwick-upon-Tweed.
I take care
not to upset anything.
Oh.
I never force a lock.
No.
How about you, Maureen?
Oh, well, you know.
I've nothing, really.
I'm just at home.
Harold?
Have you seen the news?
No, why? What is it?
It's you, Harold.
You and Queenie.
You're everywhere.
Mr. Fry!
Harold! Yeah!
It's Wilf.
- Sorry?
- Wilf.
It's my name. I've come
to be a pilgrim, Mr. Fry.
- A what?
- I'm gonna save Queenie too.
I've got my sleeping bag
and everything.
I'm sorry, what are you doing?
I said,
"If I should go to Mr. Fry,
"give me a sign."
- And guess what.
- I don't know.
He gave me a dove.
- Who?
- The Lord!
The Lord gave you a dove?
Yeah, kind of. It had wings.
The point is, it was a sign,
you know?
If you ask the way,
He'll guide you.
And He could get you
a parking space as well.
I'm not really in need
of a parking space.
Mr. Fry, I didn't know
- you had a dog.
- I don't.
Whose is it, then?
I don't know.
Hey, look. Come on.
See? It likes us.
Come on.
The Lord loves me, you know.
And you too, Mr. Fry.
And Queenie, as well.
And the dog, as well.
He loves us all.
You just gotta open your heart.
You know, and I never
knew this before,
but I do now,
and sometimes...
I feel His light.
You know, and it's warm, and...
I know He's gonna guide me.
And it's...
- Hang on a minute.
- You all right?
Yeah, man. Yeah.
I'm coming.
Do we stop soon?
Can you light a fire, Wilf?
Can I shit, Mr. Fry.
- Where's your petrol?
I just need a match.
Wow.
-  Can I do that?
- If you want.
Yeah.
How old are you, Wilf?
Twenty-five.
I'm twenty.
Eighteen.
Do your parents know
where you are?
They don't give a shit.
Wilf, you can't walk with me
to Berwick-on-Tweed.
I just wanna do something
with my life.
You know,
most kids I know are on pills.
Are you?
I quit.
And I quit the booze too.
I'm clean.
Please let me walk with you,
Mr. Fry.
Do I know this isn't poisonous?
I'm eating it. Look at me.
Yuck!
It's not that bad.
Don't you get scared?
I used to sleep badly.
But since I've been in the open,
it seems there's less
to be afraid of.
Can we pray?
- Do you want to?
Yeah.
You can if you like.
What was that?
Foxes.
Dogs, maybe.
Sheep.
We didn't pass any sheep.
It's full-on freaky.
- Come here. It's all right.
It's all right.
Nothing will hurt you.
You see it?
Yeah, it's cool.
Don't take more
than we need, Wilf.
Okay.
One... two...
...four... six.
And we leave you with an update
on a local man, Harold Fry,
who left his home
in Kingsbridge
to walk over 470 miles
to Berwick-upon-Tweed.
Harold! When do you
hope to get to Queenie?
About two weeks.
Two or three weeks.
We'll get there.
Me and him. Together.
We caught up
with him in Sheffield
where he's been recognized and
warmly welcomed by well-wishers
encouraging him on his journey.
Thank you very much.
Very nice. Look.
- I'll take that.
- Hang on to that. Here we go.
Keep walking, Harold.
But I'm not doing anything!
I'm just here, day in, day out.
Staring at the same four walls!
You're waiting for Harold.
- Queenie's waiting!
You have to believe in him.
Yes, but who believes in me?
I see him on the television,
and everyone's clapping him.
And he looks... so happy.
And now he's got
this young man with him,
and I don't know who he is.
It would be easier
if he were dead!
At least I'd I know
where I stood.
That's a terrible thing to say.
You know what I most regret?
No.
- That I didn't fight it.
But how could you?
When the doctors said
Elizabeth was dying,
I gave up. We both did.
I know it wouldn't have made
any difference,
but I wish I'd let her see
how much I wanted to keep her.
I should have raged, Maureen.
I should have raged.
Go, Fry, go! Go, Fry, go!
Come on, Mr. Fry. Come on.
Go, Fry, go!
Go, Fry, go! Go, Fry, go!
This way!
- Go, Fry, go! Go, Fry, go!
- Good morning.
So, I was thinking,
we could all wear T-shirts.
- Oh?
- That way, people
will know who we are.
- Oh, okay.
- Obviously it's your call.
But I've got a mate who can sort
this. He can do it in a day.
- Do what?
- Well, the T-shirts.
Oh. Oh, I see. Yes.
Harold Fry?
- Yes?
On the house.
- Really?
- Is all that for free?
Here you are.
Guys, I got pizza!
Who wants some?
- Good night, Harold.
- Good night, Kate.
Oh, yes!
Coming your way.
Yes! Again, and again.
- How does it look?
Good.
Pilgrim?
- Yeah, pilgrim.
- Mr. Fry's pilgrimage!
I think this is wrong.
- What?
- All this.
These people
don't even know Queenie.
Maybe I should go.
- Go where?
- I don't know, on ahead.
What, without us?
You can't go. We need you,
that's why we're here.
Go, Fry, go!
Go, Fry, go! Go, Fry, go!
Queenie! Queenie! Here we come.
- Three, two, one. Pilgrims!
Pilgrims!
And once more over here.
Three, two, one.
- Pilgrims!
Pilgrims!
Everyone point to Harold
and shout, "Harold!"
Harold!
That's great. Give yourselves
a round of applause, everyone.
Maureen. What brings you
all the way here?
Rex and I just fancied a drive.
Oh, Rex is here too?
Yes, he's just gone to WH Smith.
Oh.
Don't suppose
you've got time for a cuppa?
Yeah.
There's so much choice.
Are you sure you
don't mind paying, Maureen?
What'll you have?
A strawberry milkshake
and one of those, please.
- And I'll have a coffee.
- Er, what kind?
Just normal.
Wait, you're that guy
off the news.
The one who's walking.
Yeah.
Can you sign?
Well...
My mum thinks you're awesome.
- That's nice.
- Lovely.
- After you.
- No, no, don't.
Do you often get recognised,
Harold?
What gets me
is everyone's so nice.
- Do you mind if I start?
- Go ahead.
Where did you sleep last night?
In a field.
I don't smell?
No.
I washed in a stream.
But I don't have soap.
I don't have a razor either.
Well, I guessed about the razor.
I could get you some soap.
I think I passed a Body Shop.
Thank you. I don't want
to travel with too much stuff.
Of course.
Oh.
Here.
I'm sorry.
It's just seeing you
again and...
you look so well.
You look well too, Maureen.
No, I don't Harold. I look like
someone who's left behind.
I miss you.
I wish you'd come home.
I miss you too.
But, Maureen, I've spent my life
not doing anything,
and now at last, I am.
I have to finish my walk.
Queenie is waiting.
She believes in me. You see?
Well, yes, I do see.
Of course I do. I-- I just...
Harold,
I don't know where I fit in.
I understand that
you're a pilgrim now
and everything.
It's just that...
I can't help thinking
about myself.
I'm not as selfless as you,
I'm sorry.
Anyone can do what I'm doing.
But you have to let go.
You have to let go of the things
you think you need.
Got a dog now.
Oh. I think he sort of has me.
- David wanted a dog.
- I know.
Maureen.
I saw him.
I think I saw him.
I should go.
You know you could walk with us.
You could do this too.
I can't.
I haven't got my things.
You don't need your things.
I do!
I do need them.
Oh, and um...
Rex says hello.
I brought you these.
Unless pilgrims
don't use plasters.
I love plasters.
It was selfish of me
to ask you to give up your walk.
Forgive me, Harold.
I'm the one
who needs forgiveness.
Harold Fry! He's our guy!
Harold Fry!
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
- Have you got something?
- No.
Have you taken something
out of my bag?
No!
- Is that a quartz?
- It's mine.
Wilf, it isn't.
That's for Queenie.
That's her present.
- You can't take it.
- It fell out. You dropped it.
I was helping you,
for God's sake!
What? I get hay fever.
Here, have it.
It's just a bit of glass.
Wilf. Please don't take pills.
The pills aren't good for you.
It's just a bit of glass.
Wilf?
Wilf!
Have you seen Wilf?
Have you seen him?
Wilf!
Has anyone seen Wilf?
♪ Old man, your horse is dead ♪
♪ And we say so
And we know so ♪
♪ They say, "Old man
Your horse is dead..." ♪
♪ Poor old man ♪
♪ The moon shines bright ♪
♪ And the stars give a light ♪
He reminded me of my son.
My son was so clever.
He got into Cambridge.
It didn't work out.
He was out of his depth.
He came home...
but he had started
mixing alcohol with pills.
He'd do anything
to be not like me.
I didn't know what to say.
I didn't know what to do.
I used to talk about him
with Queenie.
We often talked about him.
We covered barely a mile today.
Yesterday was worse.
You were right, Harold.
You have to leave us behind.
♪ The moon shines bright ♪
♪ And the stars give a light ♪
♪ In a little while
It will be day ♪
♪ The voice of love ♪
♪ It calls upon us all ♪
♪ And bids us awake ♪
♪ And pray ♪
♪ Arise, arise
Wake thee arise ♪
♪ For life
She is calling thee ♪
♪ For it might be the mothering
Of your sweet soul ♪
♪ If you open your eyes
And see ♪
♪ That the life of a man ♪
♪ It comes with little plan ♪
♪ It flourishes like a flower ♪
♪ As tender in the heart
Into which you're born ♪
♪ So cherish your every hour ♪
Go on.
Not long now, Queenie.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, aren't you...
No, sorry.
On we go.
Dog? It's the last push.
No.
No. No!
Where's David?
Harold, is that you?
- I want to come home.
You were right. I can't do this.
Where are you, Harold?
- I don't know.
Well, do you know
where you've been?
I don't even know
what day it is.
It's Tuesday, Harold.
You've been gone 62 days.
Ask someone.
- I can't.
People are kind.
On the whole, people are kind.
Ask someone.
I'm going to open the map.
Excuse me?
Yes.
- Where am I?
Adderstone.
- Where?
Well, wait.
Don't hang up.
You're nearly there!
Eighteen miles. That's nothing.
We can see it.
Who's with you?
Rex. We had supper.
I can't do it, Maureen.
Harold.
Before Queenie left,
she came here.
She asked me to tell you
not to blame yourself
for what happened.
You were her friend.
But I couldn't bear for you
to have comfort when I had none.
I didn't give you her message.
Oh.
You told him?
If he stops now,
he'll never forgive himself.
Please could I ask
for a glass of water?
- Here.
- Thank you.
Be quick.
Do you think someone
might lend me a comb?
And a razor.
Could you not read?
I'm gonna have
to ask you to leave,
or I'll call the police.
- Of course.
I want my son.
I want him.
Your son? Where is he?
Do you see your son here?
Is he in Berwick-upon-Tweed?
Excuse me, sir.
Are you the gentleman
who's been walking?
Well, who's your son, now?
What's his name?
Can I help you look?
His name's...
He's my son.
Dear girl in the garage,
I owe you the full story.
Twenty-five years ago,
I buried my son.
It is not something
a father should have to do.
He hanged himself.
My wife took it terribly.
It is too much
for a mother to bear.
We fought for a time.
And then we stopped talking.
Call yourself a man!
You never did anything!
You never held him!
You couldn't even say goodbye!
I couldn't forgive myself.
I drank too much.
But that wasn't enough,
so I did something stupid.
All I wanted
was to be punished.
Queenie was my friend.
She knew about my son.
She took the blame for what
I had done to protect me
and got fired.
I let it happen.
People think I'm walking
because there was a romance
between Queenie and myself,
but it isn't true.
I'm walking because
she saved me once,
and I did nothing.
And this is why
I'm writing to you now.
I want you to know how much you
helped me all those weeks ago
when you told me about
your faith and your aunt,
though I fear my courage
has never matched yours.
With best wishes
and my humble thanks, Harold,
brackets Fry.
Thank you.
Is he okay?
I don't know.
Oh, God.
I feel such a fraud.
Why?
You inspired his journey.
- It all happened because of you.
- But that's just it.
My aunt passed.
She passed years ago.
She's dead?
I wish I'd never said anything.
But what about your faith?
I thought your faith saved her.
I thought that was the point.
How could I do that?
She was dying.
Of course.
Oh, Harold.
I'm Harold Fry.
I've walked a very long way
to save Queenie Hennessy.
Welcome, Harold Fry.
- Queenie? We have a visitor.
Queenie is confused
and in some pain,
but she waited,
as you said she should.
She can't speak,
but she can hear.
Why can't she speak?
Take the weight off your feet.
You must be exhausted.
Hello, Queenie.
It's Harold. Harold Fry.
I must say,
you're doing very well.
Maureen, I...
I don't know if you remember
my wife, Maureen,
She sends her regards.
I brought you a souvenir.
It's here. It's here somewhere.
I just need to find it.
Ah! Here we go.
See?
I can put it up for you
if you'd like.
I can hang it
up in the window, maybe.
There we go.
Oh, Queenie.
Hello, stranger.
Do you mind if I...
- If I...?
- Sure.
How far do you think
those waves have travelled?
All that way,
just to finish here.
I don't know.
Harold, what I did was wrong.
I'm sorry.
Did you see her?
I did.
- Did you talk?
- Talk?
Yes, what did you say?
Not much.
I didn't stay long.
What did I think?
I'd travel the length of England
to save a woman from dying?
I couldn't even save my own son.
You dear man.
You got up,
you went out into the world.
In blind faith, you did it.
And if trying to find your way
when you don't even know
you can get there
isn't a miracle,
I don't know what is.
I love you, Harold Fry.
That's what you did.
Are you all right, Harold?
Yes, Maureen.
Let's go home.
♪ Oh, sweet girl McCree ♪
♪ I would love to be ♪
♪ Down on Banna's lonely shore ♪
♪ And to watch
As those ships went sailing ♪
♪ We'll watch them
Come in galore ♪
♪ But oh, sweet girl McCree ♪
♪ I would love to be ♪
♪ Down on Banna's lonely shore ♪
♪ All those birds that fly ♪
♪ Up in the sky ♪
♪ Their sweet notes do cry ♪
♪ For they'd fly
As those ships went sailing ♪
♪ They lead them to the shore ♪
♪ But oh, sweet girl McCree ♪
♪ I would love to be ♪
♪ Down on Banna's ♪
♪ Lonely shore ♪
♪ Where England's mist ♪
♪ Lifts from ♪
♪ Her greening ♪
♪ A curlew croons ♪
♪ In delight ♪
♪ Of this revealing ♪
♪ But my ♪
♪ Brown eyes ♪
♪ In awe ♪
♪ Are gleaming ♪
♪ For what soon ♪
♪ Shall return ♪
♪ To ♪
♪ The beginning ♪
♪ In awe ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ War turns to peace ♪
♪ All is forgiven ♪
♪ In awe once more ♪
♪ To this great ♪
♪ Endeavour ♪
♪ Love ne'er ♪
♪ Grows cold ♪
♪ When ♪
♪ Believing ♪
♪ Footprints in the road ♪
♪ Will guide our seeking ♪
♪ The meadow's tune ♪
♪ Will aid ♪
♪ Our healing ♪
♪ For these old eyes ♪
♪ Can't see ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ But'll adore ♪
♪ This land ♪
♪ That keeps us ♪
♪ Feeling ♪