HUNTER: Hey, kiddo, what are you doing?
I buy you a fancy Mexican meal and you're feeding it to a mutt.
Real fancy.
You have any idea what that is?
What?
Tree chicken.
What? That's what the locals call it.
Colds, headaches, hangovers, cures anything.
Iguana. That's what they say.
What about indigestion?
Fuckin' iguana taco.
Yeah, well, you had it in Salvador.
Yeah, and that was shit.
What about Angola? The food was good there, right?
Shit.
Yeah, Rhodesia?
Hamburg? Shit.
So if it's not New York, it's...
You got it. Shit.
Look at you wasting away.
We got to get a job in New York.
That won't be a problem. Plenty of assholes there.
Time to move, kiddo.
MEIER: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Fuck!
Stay down!
HUNTER: Stay down, kid.
What happened?
There was a kid in the car.What?
There was a kid in the car.
Go, go, go, go!
Fuck!
I'm done with this. I'm finished.
I can't do this anymore.
I can't do this.
Oh, shit!
Shit!
AGENT: Danny, get in.
These camel jockeys have got diseases I don't wanna think about.
Where is he?
The client still has him.
What client?
We're going there now.
Okay, drive.
AGENT: So the client's an oil sheikh, no less.
He used to rule some huge stretch of desert till his tribe kicked him out.
Been living here in exile ever since.
Anyway, Sheikhy was loaded and he wanted a job done.
Hunter took the contract, then he ran.
They caught him at the airport.
And?
You know the rest. You got the package.
Yeah, I got it.
What's the job? Just came with a price tag, no details. Hunter took it cold.
Why would he do that?
Six million dollars. A big score, Danny.
Too bloody big for Hunter.
Yeah. Why'd you offer it to him?
He wanted the money. And you were out, remember?
Yeah. Still am.
I'm done with killing.
Yeah, well, maybe killing ain't done with you.
Hunter needs the old Danny, the best in the biz.
The one with balls of steel. You remember him, right?
Look, it comes down to this.
You don't do this job, Hunter's a dead man.
They're waiting for you.
This way.
SHEIKH AMR: He's waiting for his eyes to adjust.
Be careful around this one, boy.
My son forgets the ways of the desert.
Since our war against the Sultan, all he has had of his homeland
is this paint. Plaster.
My first son, Hussain, was slaughtered here.
Shot before his children.
And here, at the Battle of Mirbat,
his brother, Salim, was wounded and then killed. Murdered.
And then my third son was taken from me. Ali.
Hunted down and slaughtered.
The law of the desert says the blood of the victim
must be washed away by the blood of the Killers.
But I refused revenge
and saved my last son, Bakhait, from the war.
So I was exiled to this desert.
I have wealth, power.
But rich men die, too.
When I die,
I want Bakhait to go home to my tribe.
But for that to happen,
the killers of my sons must be killed.
You don't need me or Hunter for this.
You got all the men you need.
What use would my men be in England?
England?
The English sent their fiercest
dogs to kill for the Sultan's oil.
The SAS?
Yes. Their glorious special forces.
It was a war. It was not England's war.
They came to my land, murdered my sons,
now they will face my law.
The doctors say I have six months left to live.
You must avenge my sons before I die
or your friend will die with me.
I don't care how you kill the Killers.
But they will admit their guilt on tape,
and their deaths must look like accidents.
This must not lead back to my son.
So go, show the English
a war isn't over till both sides say it is.
I wanna see Hunter.
Oh, Danny! No, Danny. No, no, no, no. No.
What are you doing here? Get out of here.
You all right?
Am I all right? Yeah, I'm all right.
You gotta go. Get away from here. Go, go, go, go.
I'm not here for you anyway. I was thinking about the girls and Celine.
Me, too. Me, too.
(CHUCKLES) What's that supposed to mean?
It's tough putting food on the table.
What you feeding 'em? Six million, no questions?
Well.
So you must've known that was a bullshit job.
Yeah, I knew. Fuckin' SAS, a one-way ticket for sure.
Well, you took the job, and I'm not leaving you here.
Give this man a drink.
I missed you.
I didn't miss you.
Every day you were out of this game was a good day for me.
I was proud of you when you got out.
Stay out.
Too late.
You should have stayed away.
Or run faster.
Son of a bitch!
What are you doing? Let me get my watch back.
Go, go!
Go, go, get the door!
Get the door!
Give me the gun.
Bravo! Bravo!
If you need to be shot, I'll happily oblige.
I'm sorry, kiddo.
My father needs him alive.
Nice try.
You know they'd have found you.
Everybody gets found.
You knew.
My gut tells me you knew the target and you knew Hunter wouldn't take it.
You used him as bait.
That's a lot of angles, Danny.
Do you think I'm that smart?
Get out.
And you. Out.
ANNE: We missed you at the dance last night.
DANNY: I'm not much of a dancer.
Besides, I'm still trying to find out how much house is under this.
Right, big plans.
Yeah, maybe too big.
You don't remember me, do you?
Yeah, well, it's been a while.
I'm Anne Frazer.
Anne Frazer?
Anne had red hair full of grass.
(LAUGHS) Yeah.
And weird red gumboots.
With eyes on them. (LAUGHS) Oh, my God!
Oi! You owe me 50 quid.
Told you he'd be back, didn't I?
We missed you. Yeah?
Here I am.
DAVIES: All right, then, you want some?
Yeah, mate, you still got it. Still got that edge.
You're a real killer.
DANNY: Come on, let's talk. (GROANS)
DAVIES: While you were away, you didn't start a family, did you?
No.
So no one's depending on you?
Only Hunter.
'Cause one,
you're going after the SAS.
They're a paranoid bunch. They always got their back up.
Two, you need info on Oman.
No one talks about Oman.
They went in there as advisors and ended up fighting the fucking war. Real hush-hush,
semi-mercenary stuff.
Three, you need confessions.
They're trained to resist torture
so no matter what you say or do, they'll say nothing.
And four, Danny,
this is the best special forces regiment in the world.
They make the Navy Seals look like a bunch of cupcakes.
And not only that,
you're trying to take down three of their geezers
and make it look like an accident.
All I'm asking is give it some thought.
Take a day, more if you want. I'm going anyway.
Of course I'm in, you silly bastard.
It's what we do, right?
Anyway, I've got a score to settle with them.
Tried out for them when I was in the Paras.
Did Hereford, the whole fucking lot.
MEIER: What, and they wouldn't have you?
(SIGHS) You want this bottle shoved up your arse?
Are you upset? Would you like a lolly?
I'd love a lolly.
MEIER: Strawberry or fuck you?
Meier.
In.
Why?
Ah, six million reasons.
So what's the split?
After the Agent takes his slice, 50-50 between you two.
50-50? How about you?
I'm in this for Hunter.
How wonderfully touching.
Touching, but fuckin' stupid.
The Sheikh could only ID one of the killers.
I need you to come up with the names on the other two.
Start with the one they killed at Mirbat.
So the one target we do have is Steven Douglas Harris.
Stayed on in Oman after the war.
Ended up flying choppers for the Sultan's armed forces.
Great. A juice junkie.
Me and Meier'll head there to track him down.
Boys? Danny.
Meier.
MAN: What the fuck!
MAN: Harris!
Harris, you prick! Fuck off!
Well, I hope the buggers like sand in their burgers, huh?
White Range Rover coming your way. It's Harris.
SANDY: What are you doing?
Come on, have a go. No.
Come on. I'm not.
Have a go. Look.
Just aim and shoot. Go! Here we go!
Oh, you horny git! Come on.
No. Come on. (LAUGHS) Come on.
DAVIES: All right, ladies, you can throw your knickers if you want.
Go on, you cheeky bugger!
MAN: You serve in Oman? At Mirbat.
That was a day, wasn't it?
What about Mirbat? That was a right mess, eh?
Wasn't good.
I had a mate there.
DIANE: Spike, get that quick. Yeah, all right, all right.
Bollocks.
Hello?
Spikey, it's Bazza.
God's sake! I'm unplugging that bloody thing next time, and I mean it.
Yeah, I'm onto this bloke here, right.
He was in the Bear earlier pumping some SAS lads for info on Mirbat.
Mirbat. And?
He says he's Welsh. But he don't sound it.
I don't know. Maybe I'm being a bit paranoid, but...
Hey, just 'cause you're being paranoid, doesn't mean to say they're not out to get you.
All right, mate, give me what you've got.
Okay.
Put one of my Locals onto him.
SPIKE: The Omani Embassy.
Our Local followed him into the visa section.
Says he's Welsh, calls himself Mr. Jones.
We lost him after he left.
FITZ: Lost him? How come?
He never came back to his car. Stolen.
Anyhow, he flies to Oman in four days.
I'd like permission to send one of my boys out there to tail him.
This was definitely some kind of recce.
That was a dirty war. What we did there was questionable.
Oman is a bloody hornet's nest.
Right. And if this bugger is poking at it,
I want to know who he is. I say we send a Local.
Any objections?
Noted.
We'll leave you to choose the right man.
I'd also like it noted that we are ex-SAS.
The men we protect are ex-SAS.
And you, Spike,
though you hate to admit it, are ex-SAS.
JUSTICE: Remember, we're businessmen and bankers now.
What we do here is illegal.
We can leave no trace of our activities.
That's why we're called The Feather Men,
'cause our touch is light.
THE DON: Now, Spike's a good man.
Day the SAS lost him, they lost a good soldier.
COMMANDER B: Yes, but the problem is he thinks he's still in the SAS.
Well, someone has to do the dirty work.
None of us want blood on our pinstripes.
Listen, I've got no problem with blood.
What worries me is ink.
Make sure he keeps us out of the newspapers.
MARTIN: What's doing, boss?
Your Arabic's still good, right?
Good enough. You're going to Oman.
I've got a bloke I want you to tail out there.
You lucky bastard!
You know what? You're gorgeous.
Where are you staying?
I'm staying at the Hilton.
As a matter of fact, so am I. What room are you in?
Why? Would you like to know?
Love to.
AIR HOSTESS: You are smooth.
DAVIES: What are we doing out here, then, in the middle of nowhere?
MEIER: Well, I ask him to go hide it, he hides it.
Could've been your asshole, consider yourself lucky.
Shut it, Meier.
Appreciate it, thank you.
These tiles are an exact match to the shower step?
Hundred percent.
Harris comes home, parks the car. It's been a hard day.
I'll have a shower. Whoops.
He slips on the shampoo,
hits the corner of the step with his occiput.
Case closed. Get out of it.
You boys are going about this all wrong. That bird he's screwing is married.
Why don't we just pop 'em both and
make it look like her husband did it.
Pop 'em both? What's she ever done?
It's Harris we're after.
Poor bastard.
Ten years after the war, he cops it for doing something he was ordered to do.
He knew what he was doing when he joined the club.
Yeah, what club?
The killing club.
It could be you or me. Yeah, but it's not...
I'm just glad I never killed a raghead.
No offense, my son.
Let's get this done.
MEIER: Excuse my friend. He's a royal asshole.
Shit!
DAVIES: Where's he gonna run? It's the middle of the fuckin' desert.
Son of a...
Meier,
cut him off at the next shaft!
Let's go, let's go.
Where is he?
Shh.
DAVIES: Let's get out here. Fuckin' hell!
MEIER: So what, now somebody's on our ass?
DANNY: We should move right away.
We'll set up Harris' interview for tomorrow.
Davies, you make sure his girl doesn't show.
She has nothing to do with this.
Wanker!
DANNY: We're military historians. I'll do the talking, all right?
Well, it's 5:00 somewhere, isn't it?
So where's this documentary gonna be shown, then?
On the telly?
The chair.
Those bastards in C Company put this together. Hmm?
HARRIS: What's the matter?
They didn't like sand in their burgers?
Eh? Hello, boys. I'm not saying a word
till I see my lawyer.
Think back. The village of Qum.
You killed a guerilla commander.
His name was Hussain bin Amr. Do you admit it?
Fuck off! You're kidding, right?
You commanded a company there.
Yeah, I led a company on that op, sure.
And you assassinated Hussain bin Amr.
There were witnesses.
You dropped him in front of his family.
All right, you got me. I did it. Hmm?
Fuck you!
Good one. Now untie me.
Get up.
Hey! Piss off!
We have what we need.
What if I told you somebody else dropped your guerilla commander?
His name is...
I can't remember.
But he's writing a book about the whole Oman gig.
You might find it in there.
If you could read. (LAUGHS)
To the bathroom.
No, no, no, no. Wait, wait, wait.
It's coming back to me, looking at your fucking face.
His name is Captain R. Sole! A-R-S-E H-O-L-E.
Shut up.
You're fucking dead, yeah?
On your knees.
Fucking queers! Serves you fucking right!
Head down. Get your fuckin' hands off me, you queer!
You're fuckin' kidding me.
DANNY: Hold him still.
If I find you, I'll put your fuckin' head in the toilet bowl.
Poor fucker.
Jay!
I need money for the taxi. I had to take a taxi. I had a flat.
HARRIS: Fuck you! (SCREAMS)
Case closed.
Thank you.
WOMAN OVER RADIO: ... tells of a dramatic 12-hour rescue operation
to save the crew of Radio Caroline.
The pirate radio ship sank the...
It seems your friend did what you couldn't.
Wouldn't.
Wouldn't, couldn't. He's avenged Hussain.
Good news for the old man, not for you.
What do you mean?
Three brothers dead. Rotting in the sand.
You didn't wanna get revenge yourself?
Scared of getting your hands dirty?
Better get used to it.
No palace where you're going.
A tent and a hole to shit in.
He's your worst nightmare and he's gonna do it.
And when he does, you're out of here.
When I find you in that desert,
I pray God keeps my aim...
...true.
Well, what do you think?
Yeah, it's coming along.
What are you doing for New Year's Eve dinner?
Oh, shit!
DANNY: Bollocks!
Strangers are a bit of an
exotic thing around here.
Oh, come on, I didn't think I was a stranger.
I know, but you're still exotic.
Danny, something tells me you've got a story to tell.
Yeah. Mmm.
Come on, what are you waiting for? Party's outside.
MAN: Happy New Year!
Happy New Year!
It's a tradition around here.
Shit!
Mirbat. The artist's name is on the back.
Have them talk to him.
One more thing. My boys had some trouble in Oman.
Somebody was tailing them.
We'll have to have a look into that, won't we?
Yeah.
Ah, that's how you get it so lifelike, then.
Sorry?
Photos of the lads. Isn't that like cheating?
I'm recreating an historical event. Accuracy is everything.
That Mirbat painting stopped me cold when I saw it.
You were at Mirbat?
Had a mate there. I was hoping you might have an address for him.
You're with the SAS?
Was.
Then your best bet for an address would be Regimental Association...
They won't talk to me.
Spent the last few years plying my trade overseas. Angola and that.
I come to you unofficial like.
Well, I might have something somewhere.
Just give me a few minutes.
Be my guest.
I got a bullshitter askin' about Mirbat.
Yeah. He claims he's with the regiment.
No, there's no way he was SAS.
Yeah, I can smell it off him. Ah, he's a bloody fake.
My contact says the call was cut off,
but Gowling said that there was somebody there asking about Mirbat. It has to be our guy.
And what would you have us do about it?
Find him.
If we don't, there's gonna be another murder and it will be one of our Mirbat boys.
Then who are they?
Well, they're pros for sure.
If these guys are going after the SAS,
they're gonna be top-class professional assassins.
They must have a string of hits behind them
but they're completely under the radar.
All we've got is Oman.
Oman?
We all know our people went too far.
Oman, Mirbat. It all needs to be left alone.
You should try telling that to the Welshman.
He's right.
We have to find this phony Welshman and his group.
DAVIES: The file says an SAS officer
killed the Sheikh's son at the Battle of Mirbat.
Warrick Steven Cregg.
He was the only officer there that night. Killed everything that moved.
He's our worst nightmare. A real hotshot.
Paintings of him, the lot.
Where did you get this?
The bloke who did the paintings.
Don't you worry about that, all right? He's shuffled off this mortal coil.
That wasn't part of the deal.
Come on, shit happens when you play in the deep end of the pool, Danny.
Why couldn't you two stick to the plan, huh?
You've been watching this Cregg, what's your next big idea?
His wife's in hospital.
When he's not training for the selection march, he spends most days there.
MEIER: So why don't we hit him there?
DANNY: No.
Not near his family.
Get me everything you know on that march.
We'll see where that goes.
there's
only four Mirbat survivors in Britain.
I've got Locals on the other three.
You get the celebrity.
Warrick Cregg? You're kidding.
Wish I was.
DAVIES: Welcome to hell, the SAS selection march.
Forty-one miles, fifty-five pounds of gear.
They lose someone every couple of years.
Don't you even think about it.
Why not?
During the march this place is crawling with SAS.
Yeah, you said it yourself. It's an accident waiting to happen.
How are you gonna catch him then?
He's been training for months, he's like a greyhound.
We'll just have to slow him down, won't we?
Insulin. Chlorpropamide. Initial here.
Anything doing?
No, Cregg's still in there with his missus.
Here, boss, this will keep you going.
Cheers.
Pennock.
I need you back here, mate. Pronto.
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
Get out of the fucking way!
WOMAN: Maniac!
You wouldn't fucking believe it,
somebody was watching Cregg.
What? Mmm.
You think he's from the same stable as the shooter in the desert?
Maybe. He was good. Whoever he is, he's too late.
Ah, good, good. Chroma slows him down.
Insulin sends him into shock.
Hypothermia to you.
And when were you planning on getting it to him?
Before the march.
How? It's an SAS base, Danny.
That you trained in.
So think back. The security layout, the lot.
You're nuts.
Are you gonna do it?
Man, you really are one crazy son of a bitch, Danny.
Clock's ticking. You've got under a minute, all right?
We've got company.
Lovely night.
You can't stop here, mate.
I didn't stop, the truck did.
If you don't fucking move it, we will.
All right, all right. But it's pissing oil, mate.
There's nothing I can do about it.
Turn off the bloody radio.
MAN: Where's your gear?
Right. On the trucks!
SERGEANT 1: I don't care what regiment you're from.
I don't care how great you think you are.
Let's see what you're made of, ladies.
On the trucks.
SERGEANT 2: Come on!
Get moving, you lot.
He only got half the dose.
Is it enough?
MEIER: Enough? He's a dead man walking. Stay on him, okay?
DANNY: His name was Salim bin Amr.
Do you remember the name?
Did you kill him?
Think back.
Did you kill him, Major? CREGG: Yeah, I did. I did the bastard. So bloody what?
Danny didn't want to do this.
DANNY: You did?
And your boy doesn't want to go back to the desert.
The Ministry of Defence today announced the death of an army officer during maneuvers.
Thirty-three-year-old, Major Warrick Steven Cregg,
died of exposure during an SAS exercise on the Brecon Beacons.
Weather conditions at the time were described as appalling, with...
Show a bit of respect, lads.
Top that.
I come bearing gifts.
Oi!
AGENT: From my boys in Angola.
I have no idea how you're meant to eat this.
Who's on our ass?
I'm on it. Don't worry.
Look, there's only one more to go.
After this is done, I'll get you boys a nice, cushy job in the sun.
There is no "after this."
I'm a vulture. I live off killers.
It gives me a unique perspective.
Have you heard of the two percent? That's you.
Davies, the SAS, all you lot.
Mercenaries, hit men, heroes.
You're all part of that two percent of men who are natural killers.
That's why you'll never get out.
You can't run away from who you are, Danny.
That's not who I am, that's what I've done.
And I can do something else.
Yeah, yeah.
That's all nice and good. But let's just take care of business first, shall we?
Your third target, Major Simon McCann,
Mad Simon McCann of late.
How'd you find him?
Asked around. It was easy.
These days, he's your basic "cash for trash" mercenary.
He's a sitting duck.
Now didn't I tell you I came bearing gifts?
You know where to find me.
DAVIES: You don't trust that snake, do you?
He's lying. Yeah? How do you know?
His lips were moving.
He just gave us a third target.
You've done nothing on that last file.
Someone's onto us.
I want Hunter out of there.
I want this finished. And I want to be around to enjoy the money when it is.
The first thing you should buy is a pair of balls.
We're going after McCann, all right?
ANNE: I miss you.
There's a lot I don't know about you, but I do know that much.
I convince myself that everything's okay
because when I'm with you I'm happy.
But then you go away
and I realize that I know nothing about you.
I don't know where you go and I don't know what you do,
I mean,
you've got a whole another life, Danny.
Is there someone else?
Come on, Anne.
Well, then, what is it?
I mean, Jesus, what are you not telling me?
What are you hiding?
Can we talk about this when I get back?
To hell with it.
Fuck.
What?
You show me a beautiful woman, I'll show you a bloke that's sick of her shit.
Shut up.
Roger that.
DANNY: That him?
DAVIES: That's him.
Major Simon McCann.
Served in the Sultan's forces till he was pensioned out four years ago.
And another.
Oi!
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
Piss off, grandpa. You want some?
DANNY: Doesn't look like an invalid.
Like I said, a bomb went off under his jeep,
scrambled his wiring.
He can't keep a job. He's a fucking psycho.
Jesus.
Come on, mate, that's enough.
What's he doing here?
That's the one I went head-to-head with at the hospital.
Right.
Wait, wait, wait.
Let's go.
Stick with him.
Mac, it's me. You okay?
McCANN: Oh, yeah, still scraping skinheads off my doorstep.
All right, mate. I was just checking in.
Bloke who drives that green Jag, what's his name?
AGENT: His name's Spike Logan. He's an ex-soldier of some kind.
He got his eye shot out playing a hero somewhere.
He's got no job and he keeps odd hours.
Don't you know who these guys are?
I mean, secrets being your bread and butter.
Don't worry about it.
I do worry about it. You should, too.
Every move my guys make, these lot are waiting.
You ask me, I think it's time you put those fancy shoes of yours on a few throats.
Yes. But no one is asking you.
DAVIES: You'll be interviewing for a security position, Mr. McCann.
McCANN: Right.
Actually we got your name from a mutual friend in the SAS.
Yeah, really?
So, we'll see you Tuesday the 17th, at 10:00.
Okay.
We look forward to it.
See you then.
All right, my son.
He'll be there.
Good.
I don't get it.
McCann lives here.
He'll be here for the interview, Tuesday at 10:00.
He'll take this road.
The Boston Brakes. Perfect.
They weren't perfect in Boston.
I wasn't at the controls.
We've got 10 days.
MEIER: Ten days?
The quicker we get this done, the better.
I'm going to need to bring in some help.
Okay. DAVIES: "Okay." Just like that?
McCann's being watched.
How are you gonna get a confession out of him?
We aren't. We'll fake it.
Bit of bad lighting and camera work, you could be him.
What we'll do is play back what he admitted to in the reports.
Who are you?
I'm the one they let fly around in an unmarked chopper
with a gun in my pocket.
You can call me MFWIC.
"MFWIC"?
Mother Fucker What's In Charge.
We have questions.
About this little illegal club of yours, The Feather Men.
Your attack dog, time to bring him to heel, eh?
And then we'll put that on the agenda.
Gentlemen.
We'll be with you in a minute.
I want to put Locals on Major McCann around the clock.
I realize McCann is an old friend of yours,
but what has it to do with us?
But this is our chance to get the bastards who killed Cregg and Harris.
The authorities found no evidence of foul play in either case.
What are you talking about, "No evidence?" I've got the evidence right here.
Everybody in this room knows that those men were killed.
Everybody knows that McCann is going to be next.
That's enough, Spike.
We have to do something.
THE DON: Well, we could put it to the vote.
Yes, but that would require the full committee.
And it will have to wait.
Spike. That was a set-up.
He sent him away. He knew there'd be a vote.
Spike, please. Look, listen.
This is getting big.
The powers that be are asking questions. Pressure's being applied.
They have their reputations to protect.
I'm not doing this to protect reputations.
You know, a light touch is one thing,
but no touch at all? I can't do this.
You realize this thing is set up for maximum deniability?
You're the only one who knows the Locals.
All their orders come through you.
So?
So? If this comes out, you're the one who takes the fall.
Fall? From where?
I am done with this whole committee thing.
I'm gonna find him.
MEIER: He's a good kid, don't worry. I'm shtupping his mom.
DAVIES: Does he know he can't bring his mom on the job?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DAVIES: Tell your mates in Oman I said hello.
Danny, is this what it was like when you were first starting?
This is your first job? Jesus.
My first time, I puked for a day afterwards.
I was young and dumb, just the way the army likes them. I could be good at this, man.
I mean, it's easy, yeah?
Killing's easy.
Living with it is the hard part.
PORTER: If I see him, I'll give you a bell.
Don't be shy about spreading the word.
There's a very tidy finder's fee.
I'll keep my eyes peeled.
One more and we'll call it a night.
JAKE: We're on.
MEIER: He's late.
Just keep me at 75 feet
and give me a clear line of sight. Yeah, okay.
Where'd you buy your license?
On his tail. Doing 60.
You'll have a visual on Danny in one minute.
Stay with him, Jake.
I got him.
DAVIES: We have target in sight.
JAKE: Gonna miss it.
Come on, get in. Get in behind him!
Just do it, get in! There's not enough room!
Push him!
I can't get in there.
Okay, then overtake him. Go! Pass him!
DAVIES: What the hell are you doing, Meier?
MEIER: I need a range countdown.
Meier: Don't screw this up.
I'll operate looking backwards.
Relax, Meier.
Davies will give you the countdown.
DAVIES: 400 meters.
MEIER: Okay, range me.
300 meters.
Outside lane, Meier.
200 meters.
Here he comes.
100 meters.
Now, now. Now, Meier! Shut up!
Now, Meier!
Fishtail! Fishtail!
JAKE: You fucking got him!
You got him, man. MEIER: Oh, fuck, he's dead. He's dead as Elvis.
You got him, man!
Stop the car.
We gotta be sure Elvis has left the building.
DAVIES: Target had a minder. Head to the exit point.
Bring him to me.
He had a fucking minder. Fuck!
You got him, man. You got him!
Shut up! Drive! Go! Go! Go!
Who is he?
I don't know. Give me an update, Davies.
Oh, man, he's coming fast!
Up here there's a yard. Take a left. Shit! Up here to the left. Keep going.
Hold on.
Come in, Davies.
Davies, where the fuck are you?
Got you, you bastards.
MEIER: Fuck this! Go! Go!
JAKE: Here he comes! Here he comes!
Get out of the car!
Where the fuck do you guys come from?
Step away from the car. Easy.
Jake. Yeah?
Take it easy. Check the car. Slowly.
No, no, no, no!
No!
He had no ID. Nothing.
Not a fucking thing.
Who the fuck is he?
This shouldn't have happened.
This should not have fucking happened! Take it easy, Danny.
Danny...
Take it easy?
We were out of there. Clean. Done.
PENNOCK: Look, I'm getting nothing. Campbell's not picking up.
Ls there anything at your end? Fuck.
Who are these bastards?
I don't know. But they're looking for their man and they're not legit.
Jake, call this number.
Tell the Agent we need a cleanup crew here ASAP.
And wire that radio into my car.
Gimme here.
That's it then.
Yeah.
Done.
I fly tonight.
You should get going, too. They're close.
What happens to Meier's cut?
There has to be somebody.
Poor sod. I'll have a hooker for him. He'd like that. (CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
Be safe.
You too, Davies.
PENNOCK: Sorry. We 're still looking for Campbell, but it looks bad.
Thank you, sir. If there's anything else...
Room service. Something exotic.
Yeah?
PORTER: I found your Welshman
You sure it's him?
I'm sure.
(SCREAMING) Fucking hell!
Get up. Get dressed. Move!
Look... Get up!
Don't say a word to anyone. Do you understand?
You killed Simon McCann, didn't you?
Yeah? And Campbell. Where is he, you fucker?
Never heard of him.
That all you got?
Yeah, Spike? We got the Welshman.
We 're bringing him to you now. Over.
SPIKE: Nice work, Pennock. Well done.
I'm looking forward to meeting the bastard.
Hey, Spike's gonna cut your dick off and shove it in your mouth. You like that?
I like the sound of that, yeah.
Do you? Yeah, I do.
Get in the van.
Get in. Come on, get in!
Fuck me. You're kidding. Come on. Get in!
There you are, you prick.
Open up.
Boss.
What am I meant to do with that?
He had this on him.
A phone number. Great work.
That pile of mincemeat was our best chance of finding out who these bastards are.
Print him and trace that bloody number.
You fucking idiots!
DANNY: Drop it.
Left hand. Put the gun on the floor.
Kick it to me.
The Welshman, they were bringing him to you. Where is he?
He didn't make it.
You? You do it?
A truck. He made a break for it.
He got lucky.
Would have been very slow otherwise.
Yeah, well that was my fucking friend.
Yeah, and McCann was mine. And what about fucking...
Campbell?
No.
Davies. Meier. Harris.
McCann. Cregg. Campbell. Too many names on that list.
Don't go adding yours, Spike.
Inside.
Who are you?
Doesn't matter.
After tonight, I don't exist.
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
It's over.
Done. You think so?
No uniform, no war, not special.
You don't know what to do with yourself.
Nobody knows what to do with you.
Right? Wrong.
You know my name but you don't know me.
You have no idea who you're fucking with.
Really?
Don't follow me.
Don't put your name on that list.
The third confession.
SHEIKH AMR: The killers have been killed,
now you can go home.
BAKHAIT: You can have your man.
You will get the money when it's been checked.
Bring him out.
Bring him out!
Let me put... I just wanna put my watch on.
What's the matter with you?
You all right? Yeah.
What's the plan?
Get out of here.
Okay, sounds good.
I was sure you were gonna get yourself killed, kiddo.
How in the hell did you do it? How'd you pull it off?
I don't want to talk about it.
I get it.
Thank you. Not from me, but from my kids
for having a dad.
I could never thank you enough for what you did. Never.
Yeah, you can.
You can get out of the business. Be done with this shit.
No more soldiering. No more mercenary work.
All right. Okay, okay.
I'm asking you, please. Tell me you're done.
I'm done. I'm out.
Good.Stay out.
Otherwise all this is for nothing.
So, how are the Yankees doing?
You could have called.
You wouldn't have answered.
No. Sorry about that.
You're sorry? It's me who should be sorry.
So it's over? You going back again?
No.
And you're ready to tell me everything?
Whatever you want to know.
Good.
Except I don't want to know. Not anymore.
I've missed you, Danny.
I don't really care about the past, I just care about now.
Hey, boss.
All right, Cal?
That phone number?
That was a business.
It's for some shit travel agent.
Runs mercenaries in and out of every shithole in the world.
Come in.
Hello?
AGENT: Hello, Danny.
How'd you get this number?
Please, Danny, don't insult my professionalism.
What do you want?
We got a problem with the job.
The job's done. No.
You killed the wrong guy.
There's one more to go.
I busted my nuts setting this job up
and I want my 10%.
No, I did what I had to do.
Tell that to the Sheikh. He wants a London meet with his son.
Check with your girlfriend before you make any rash decisions. Eh?
What are you doing? Come to bed.
Come with me, Anne.
What?
To Paris.
You can wait for me there while I'm in London.
Leave tomorrow. Nothing's keeping you here, right?
It's the middle of the night. Anne. Anne!
They know about you.
Who knows about me?
And about us.
When will this be over?
Soon.
If all goes well.
It will, won't it?
Danny.
Keep a good eye on her, huh?
Listen, don't do this on your own.
No other way.
Davies, Meier, all this heat on you.
Come on, let's just get in the car, we'll go to London,
be at the airport...
No. We have a deal, remember?
What do you mean? You think I can't cut this, is that it?
I mean, I'm not a babysitter, come on!
I need to know she's safe.
You're the only one I trust. This is bullshit. You could run, both of you just go, come on.
Everyone gets found. You know that.
You're gonna get yourself killed, kiddo.
Thanks for doing this.
You gotta be kidding me.
Welcome back to London, sir. Thank you, sir.
You tell the old man he threatens her again, I'll put it between his eyes.
Harris, the pilot, on his film he said
another soldier killed my brother.
He was winding us up. He thought it was some kind of a joke!
This was just published.
The author served with the SAS.
He describes an ambush where he killed a guerilla leader.
Harris did not kill Hussain.
You gave me his name. You said he was guilty.
Such is Allah's will.
Allah's will?
You had me kill an innocent man.
The book will be the real killer's confession.
My father...
I know what your father needs.
I need everything you can get on a Ranulph Fiennes.
Yeah, writer, ex-SAS.
What you got?
I got Fiennes.
He's still pushing his book on Oman.
He'll be doing a press bash on Tuesday.
Tuesday. I know it's a bit short notice,
but I'll be able to put a crew together. Nah.
I'll do this on my own.
Danny, are you sure? It's just a phone call.
I guess he's sure.
B-I-N-G fucking O.
I knew I'd find you, you bastard.
Do you mind if I sit down?
You look lonely.
You're Danny's friend.
The famous Hunter.
He say nice things?
What are you doing here?
Watching you.
You should be with him.
I tried. It didn't work.
He wanted me here to protect you.
And you look like you needed protecting.
From what?
You.
You're thinking about him not coming back. What happens then?
No, I...
I have a wife, I know the look.
We've known each other through thick and thin, Danny and I.
Celine, my wife, she loves him, my kids love him.
I mean, wild animals like Danny.
I know Danny's going to come back for you.
And when he does, you're going to steal him away. Huh?
I don't know what the plan is.
I have a woman to interrogate now.
PENNOCK: All right, look alive, lads.
Boys.
So this guy is good. Very good.
If he senses something's up,
he'll run until you corner him and then he fights.
But now the gloves are off.
This all fucking ends today.
MARTIN: All right, everybody knows the rules.
MAN: There are no rules.
MAN: Boss, he's out front. I think we're on.
This could be him. Black leathers.
Roger that.
He just took the service stairs. It has to be him.
Just hold your positions. We'll know soon enough.
He's down, boss. We got him! He stays alive.
Pennock, don't you touch him until I'm there.
Stay here.
Stay there, you fucker.
Get his helmet off before he chokes.
Shit.
Hands high, against the wall.
Okay, easy with that.
Guys, our man's down. Head for the roof.
Pennock, head for the roof.
We're on our way up now, boss.
Come on, move!
He jumped! He jumped!
PENNOCK: Come on, come on, he's on the move. Let's go!
SPIKE: Pennock?
Don't you do it.
PENNOCK: There's no sign of him up here, boss.
I can see all the way to the river. He's gone.
Shit.
Move and you're dead.
Right, let's go, let's go.
Get in.
What is this?
PENNOCK: That's for Campbell.
And that's for Cregg.
SPIKE: You finished?
We haven't even started.
Take the hood off.
Wait outside, boys.
Save a little bit for us, boss.
So why is he still alive? Why didn't you kill him?
Is that what you would have done?
I thought you were the good guys.
Who are you? Who do you work for?
You and I got a lot in common.
Really? You think so?
So, you're sitting there, tied to a chair
and I'm standing here with a gun in my hand.
Now you tell me what the fuck this was all about.
"Was?"
You think this is over?
There'll be somebody else.
Your boy, Fiennes, is gonna die.
Go on, pull the trigger. Kill me and you kill Fiennes.
They won't stop till they get him.
I stopped you, I'll stop them.
I didn't want to kill him. They will.
You put that in the right hands, this thing's over.
The camera? Why?
Proof. Evidence that he's dead.
It's the only way you'll save him.
You tell me I'll walk, I'll tell you who's behind this and where to find him.
Okay. You walk.
Sheikh Amr bin Issa.
You'll find him in Oman.
Why?
The war.
They killed three of his sons.
No.
Some good guy, eh?
Drop it.
Inside.
Beside him. On your knees.
You were set up.
That's what we love about you lot.
You only care about the action.
Never think about what you might really be fighting for. Or who.
Never see the big picture.
You're the one that was set up. He just wouldn't get out of the way.
Her Majesty's government doesn't like secret societies.
Particularly when they get in the way of our interests.
Do you know how much oil that pathetic crust of desert is floating on?
Do you know what those contracts are worth?
Three men's lives.
That's right.
We deliver the killers.
Son Number 4 goes home
and when Sheikhy re-ups the contracts, we get favorable consideration.
A bargain. You bastard, you're a...
Patriot.
Who serves his country as those three men did with their deaths.
As you will with yours.
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
AGENT: There she is.
Danny might've dropped off the radar,
but one thing's for sure. He'll come back for her.
He'll come through that door with $6 million
and she won't be there.
Who don't you screw out of his 10%? Yours truly.
Boss.
Deal with him.
It wasn't personal. Just business.
You played us. I don't care why.
But if ever a lying piece of shit needed killing, it was you.
Game's over.
You know, I wouldn't have hurt her.
I just wanted my cut. She was only collateral.
If you go after them,
I'll find you. Remember, everybody gets found.
Even you.
HUNTER: You gotta get those photos to that old bastard
to finish this thing for good, you hear, kiddo?
That's why I'm here. What about you?
Babysitting's over, kiddo.
Who says? I say.
She's safe. You're the one taking the chances now.
Come on. "Come on?"
You walked into a trap last time.
You think I'm going to let you do that again?
I told your girl you were going to be coming back to her.
You want to make a liar out of me?
You know, you were supposed to be guarding her, not interviewing her.
Well, I was always a sucker for a pretty face, no denying that.
She's a keeper, that's for sure.
She doesn't know, does she?
Some. Yeah.
It's going to be tough. My old man used to say,
"Life's like licking honey from a thorn."
Yeah, what does that mean?
Something about good times and bad times.
Seems like it's been all thorns for us lately. Both of us.
All right, let's finish this.
I'll be top cover.
Anything goes wrong,
I'm coming in. Hey, look, the Sheikh wants this over. It's in, hand over the photos, and out.
Yeah? Yeah.
There isn't going to be a problem.
From your mouth to God's ears.
Don't move till I give the all-clear, okay?
BAKHAIT: Who are you? What do you want?
For the Sheikh.
I have to see it placed in his hands.
Take these to my people.
Show them what I have done.
I have a message for the Sheikh.
He's still alive.
They're fakes.
But this is going to end.
I don't care.
What'll I do in that godforsaken desert?
Haven't you forgotten something?
HUNTER: Hold it, hold it, stay where you are.
Something's not right here.
You seeing this?
Yeah, I see it.
So we're in the wrong place.
HUNTER: Let's go! Let's go!
Relax, I only killed the car.
You again!
Back at the palace, what happened in there?
He was there, waiting for a message from you.
I was the messenger.
And?
What do you think?
His boy in there didn't give a shit.
He's not going back to the desert, so there'll be no oil contracts.
It was all for nothing.
Is that right?
And the winner is.
So that's what this is all about.
Yeah, it's all hookers and blow from here on in.
You just don't get it, do you?
Ditch it.
You sure?
I gotta cover my expenses.
You can't go back to England.
Not after killing that spook.
Who the fuck are you?
Who, me? The voice of experience.
Where are you going to go?
What are you going to do?
You're going to need this.
New name, new face, new papers.
Expensive. You'll see.
Damn shame.
You think you get to just walk away?
Nobody walks away.
Not me or you, none of us.
The old man you just killed,
he told me a war isn't over
until both sides say it is.
Well, I'm telling you now, this is over for me.
Really? And what? You want me to say, "Me, too," and then it's happy ever after?
Your choice.
You know, when I got this, they told me my war was over.
I told them they were full of shit. Now I'm telling it to you.
Let it go.
So where are you going?
What, are you planning a visit?
You never know.
You come. I'll be waiting.
We'll call you a cab from the airport.
Aren't you Anne Frazer? The girl with those weird gumboots?
Are you Danny Bryce, the boy who went away?
Yeah. I'm back.
Where you headed?
I don't know.
Me, neither. Want to come along?