Its true that the Hittites army has 60,000 troops camped outside Kadesh, whats less clear is why
The Heittites had tried to cross the border, what else have you found out?
they are anticipating an invasion by us,
They think we are preparing an attack
But i dont want to do, and wont do is sit here and wait until the Hittites armies are outside our palace walls
What do the entails say?, its doesnt say anything, they imply
And thats open to interpretation, so interpret them if we will or wont do an pre emptive attack, is that a yes or no?
And its not clear
But something else is, in a battle a leader will be saved, and his saviour will someday lead
And does the entrails say that we will abandon reason and be guided by yours?
Great Gods, Pharaoh drinks in your name and pray for victory over the Hittites and delivery
Your first order of business when the time comes, you retire her, i will, but i dont know why my father wont
But just in case, if you see me in any real danger, ride the other way...im serious
When i look at you i still see the two boys who grew up together close as brothers
If for any reason you ever forget that, that these will remind you
Small enough to fit in the horse pack and not so long that you will trip over
This is yours, you've got mine, thats right, thats how i want it, you have each others, to keep each other safe. Promise me you will do that, always
(( Discussing about battle tacticts to leave Moses out of danger ))
We should concentrate our strengh to the second
You should concentrate yours and fight, leave the rest to me
(( Warning about the Egyptians coming to attack ))
Take Ramsees..Go!
Moses, what happened out there?, nothing. I asked the commanders the same thing, they too lied, and im tired of it
He thinks something happened, but it didnt, meaning?, the high priestess, the prophecy, she said she couldnt see who would win, the other
You saved my sons life?, yes
Sit, thank you is most efficient, thank you
I know you dont believe in the priestess's prophecies...but i do believe, and i respect that
But this doesnt make any sense, because you are not my blood
Its true you cant succeed me, not the usual way, not in anyway
The people trust you more than him to lead
The hettites chariot troops crash through our defense and began its attack, i found myself surrounded by the enemy..no soldier, no shield bearer facing a desperate fight for my life.
Only with help of the Gods did i defeat our attackers and rejoin our divisions, stop there!
Anything you like to rephrase? No,
shall i go on, no for the rest its fine, whats next?
a situation, the slaves, Ramsees..what?...go up there meet with the vice roy, look around and make a report
Me?, it will be yours someday, to get interested in....what else?
I'll go see the vice roy, no, i'll do it, but its beneath you?, its beneath any general, i'll do it, Ramsees can we forget what happened on the battlefield?, if our positions have been reversed i would have saved
your life 2 weeks ago, i know
Welcome to Python, you'll get used to this land
The vice roy seems to be enjoying a good share of his resources, this is not a job everyone wants to do my lord, a certain degree of comfort is necessary to keep up with spirits
You know what the problem is?, people live too long these days, every year the death rate lacks further behind than the birth right..and these people reproduce like its a sport, is this a problem in growing
work force?, oh no..of course not, its good for production, of course it is but only to a point.
And that population wants you dead...yes its a problem, and so i deploy more troops to maintain it
You start slaughtering people for no reason other than this theory, you will provoke the very thing you say, fine then give me the troops
Lets go down and talk to them, why on earth?, you are worried about sedition, lets find out if that worry is real, by you talking?, by looking at them when im talking to them, you can tell a lot about somebody..looking them in the
eye
Well let me tell you something about hebrews, they are conniving combative people, do you know what Israelite means in their own language?, he who fights with God, he who wrestles with God, there is a difference
Look im not as educated as you, but i have to deal with them everyday, i know what im talking about, you dont have to come, ill go down myself
Why is he being punished?, persistent follow maker my lord, why is he smiling?, he says he feels no pain my lord, they why whip him?
You were not gathered up at random, i asked to see the elders
Come on what do you pray for?, we pray to see canaan again, canaan again? you'll never see it
ive seen canaan, ive seen that its inhabited by tribes fiercer than the egypt's military so you want me returning to it or if you do from?
God says otherwise, which God?, your God?, The God of Abraham?, the God that said that you are special, that you are chosen, let me tell you...come here, come, come here
He is wrong
I can see that you are unconvinced, and thats a problem, this beliefs are from fanatics and they set out sedition when/and they still have revolution and it all starts with the elders, whats your name?, whats yours?
I'll tell you, im Moses, im son of (***)
Record this ones name and the rest of them and bring in the next group
My name is (***)
They sent me out to tell you (to meet at one of the Israelites house)
I see you've survived (meeting with the Israelites), sorry to make you wait again, im not waiting
How was your trip to the quary?, fine, you saw what im up against, hmm..
Tell me is there anymore of my records i could get for you before you leave?, you can tell me has all of this been reported to memphis? was it approved? do you have a writing?, of course...on the record,
then you dont mind if i check
Of course i dont mind, but i dont understand whats gone wrong?, have i done something to displease you? and if so is there anyway i could please you?
You could stop living like a king, you are no one
To a land filled with milk and honey
Can they at least wait outside? we are not dangerous, wait by the horses
Do you believe in conincidence?, as much as anything else, i dont think this is one, what is it?, you..coming to python..why did you come?, business
Sit
Who is your father?, i know you dont know his name, you were told he is a general in pharaoh's army, unnamed by your mother, i can see this is making you uncomfortable
This will interest you, there is no general
Your mother whom you called mother has no children, you were born of the slaves, dont go, dont go..
Its better for you that i do, im leaving, if you leave now, just come back because you know something is wrong, you have always felt it....please
Everybody out, out..
The year of your birth, there was a prophecy, that our leader would be born to liberate us from our bondage, so there was an order from memphis to kill every first born hebrew boy
Your parents didnt wait for that to happen, any chance of your survival was barely no chance, they handed you to your sister, she took you in a basket to the banks of the river
And she floated you to where ramsees daughter was bathing, she took you and your sister Miriam as a maid who raised you as her own, she probably loved you but she never told you or anyone else the truth..you are Hebrew..true
The truth is its only a story, you people are only good at story telling
You...slave!
You!!
Do you expect a reward for this information?, our reward is to be in service to you, that said if it were some token you have in mind or beyond that?..you wont refuse it, why am i to accept, what if im going to kill you, that
would be sufficient payment, you people
Please..leave
How did it go?, we'll talk about that another time, we can talk about it now,
Sit
I took a thorough look at the city records, the man is clearly a thief,
Whats wrong Moses?, you are sick, something else is troubling you, i can tell, no..nothing is
May you be rejuvinated and protected by the gods every moment of your eternal life
To your left, no your left, good
It is..tall, monuments are monuments for a reason its inspiring, inspire what in this case? in this and in every case..power
Say it out loud whatever it is, the vice roy of python is outside (***) i dont know if we should deal with this, bring him in..
if you came here to beg for  the king's forgiveness it wont work, arrest him, ah..wait, please, may i at least respond?, i beg you, its in your interest, then make it short, i will, to the king alone
My advise is that he and the other generals also leave the room,
Great, thats real nice, well you are not his advisor, oh thats right..you are, thats right
Moses..Moses..
Everybody but the vice roy..out
Terrible news..
There you are
So..the vice roy..you didnt arrest him, you didnt take your chief's advices?, advice?
Oh he cant..uhh..(***) one who survived the attack and i told him i did not care, and then he told me the most unbelievable story
He told me my sources were unreliable, he admitted that there were Hebrew spies, you know what im talking about
And what do you make of it?, i think its offensive and i think its ridiculous, yes..you of all people are hebrew
How could i believe such a story?
What if i take the chance of believing him?..what am i to do?
Mother..the man is a thief, my son discovers this, not you, and he reports it to your father who would have hand this thief if he hadnt been dying himself, you believe his nonsense
All i want to know is if its true, i didnt ask for (***), you talk about this any longer we are dignified and i wont do that, answer the question..yes or no? was i talking to you?
Bring her in..bring her in..now!
Miriam..come sit..sit down
Now..im going to ask you some questions and i want you to answer me truthfully
How did you know Moses?, you know how i know him, i helped raised you both, so you are not his sister then?, of course not, and you are not a Hebrew?, no..
Put your arm on the table
Ramsees..dont be stupid, Ramsees!, im not talking to you, im talking to her
Your whole arm on the table, thank you
Ramsees..dont take this any further, dont take this any further or what?, do not take this any further, get your hand off or i'll use it..now
Perhaps you would like to answer the question?
Miriam im going to ask you again and if your answer is again no..i apologize for what happens next
Are you his sister?
No
Yes!!....Yes!!
You dont need a reason to kill him, but you have one, this was treason, i wasnt treasoning, he just admitted he knew, that wasnt an admission, he simply didnt want her arm chopped off
I saw it in his eyes, he doesnt (***) believe the story, i dont want to believe it, you want to believe it because its up (***) to get rid of him, i didnt say exiled..i said dead
That im sure will follow..where he is going
Allow me to talk to my mother, yes sir..yes
Come Miriam
it isnt every man who would protect his servant who is nothing more to him than that
Certainly no one else in this family including me
I wouldnt have said what you wanted to hear
And neither would she
thats how much we love you
Its not true, yes its true, you were wearing this when i brought you to the river, i took it of for obvious reasons, (***) the connection between you and all of them
Your sister saved your life, now you have saved hers
Miriam
Sorry sir
I have nothing to steal, my horse is dead, we are not here for your horse..Moses
What are you doing?, dont stop keep working, you..get water for our goats
You, wait your turn
Move your animals away from the well
Where are you from?, west from here
Where are you going?, east
What did you do?, what do you mean?
You comitted some crime?, i respect your daughters inviting me for some food, i did not know that there would be an interrogation, im sorry..im just curious
You are welcome to get cleaned up before dinner if that appeals to you, you can stay a night if you want, before continuing on..to where ever it is, thank you
Describe to me what its like where you come from
Its..i wouldnt say civilized..because i wouldnt want to offend the villages here, theres more than..sheep and goat there
There is more here than that, really?..where?
Im sorry that was rude..that was rude, im not ignorant just because i live here, i can see that
I can tell you one thing..this is by far the nicest place..between here and there
And so you are leaving?, of course..there is nothing here for someone like me
When?..today?
Remember this moment in time, for after these vows, you shall say to the world, this is my husband..this is my wife
(( Exchanging Vows ))
What makes you happy?
You know
Whats the most important thing in your life?
You are
Where would you rather be?, no where
And when would you leave me?, never
Proceed
I said per se..i dont want to discuss my tomb per se
I want to discuss why you want to discuss it before time, respectfully it should have been your first construction
Is there a problem with the palace?, its gone down, it wont be long now, set up months ago meanwhile im asked for my burial
Get it done!..faster!, do i have to kill someone?
Just aim a little higher,
Almost
Have you ever been to the top?
No, would you like to?, mother says its forbidden, by who?, our God
Our God?..stops us from climbing mountains?, not every mountain, just that one, its God's mountain
You are not fierce with him
Im not trying to, is it good for our boy to grow up living in nothing?, its bad to God believing in yourself
Its my faith, i know, and its his too, i understand, he can make up his mind when he is older, just like you, now he is a lot like me already
Moses
Help me, i think my leg is broken
More than that
What did you say?
Who are you?
Im a sheperd, i thought you were a general?
I need a general
Why?, to fight.. or else
Fight who?..for what?
I think you know
I think you should go and see whats happening to your people now, you wont be at peace until you do
Who are you?
I AM
You fell, Anything you saw..or think you saw afterwards was an effect of that, the storm..the storm started before
It was something else, but the boy was all in your head, how do you know?, because God isnt a boy
I have to tell you something.. i have to tell you something, i havent been completely honest with you
About what?, about who i am, about what ive done, and who i was, and how i feel
What do you feel about me? (***), rest, rest
What are you doing here?, nothing..i cant sleep
Are you worried about me?, yes, dont..ill be fine
What does it look like?
Come inside...come inside!
What are you going to do with all that?, make sure i see you again, are you doubting you cant see me forever?
What does this mean?, its someone i used to know
This is not forever..i will see you again..do you believe me?
Dont ever..just say what people want to hear..but i will..i will see you again
will you keep this for me?, please look at me,
What kind of God tells a man to leave his family?, if you understand it..i'll understand it, i dont..im sorry i cant answer that question
If thats what faith means..i'll trade mine to keep you
Dont touch me, go..go!
Father, have you some water to spare?, yes, where did you come from?, i come from the sea..its a narrow and dangerous path
Thank you father
I remember you, you used to feel no pain
Welcome back brother
Here is the man, he was once a prince of Egypt
Im fine, everybody is fine
You sleep so well, because you know you are loved, ive never slept so well
Im told that i should address you as Ramsees the great..now..
Moses..you are alive, i am glad you are alive, is that why you only sent two assassins to kill me?
Your mother, dont blame her, she wanted you dead, who do you think hid your sword where you would find it?
Moses
You are not here to take your throne, its not about the prophecy that worries you so much its just something else
I have been told, that things here have become much worse, things are better than ever have been Moses
We have order, order?..order?, the slaves..their bodies burn..night and day now ive seen it with my own eyes, you call that order?
They are slaves, what do you expect?, they should be treated like Egyptians, they should have the same rights, they should be paid for their work or..you must
set them free
They are not Egyptians..they are slaves..what else would you expect?, they wouldnt know what to do (***) to fend for themselves like animals
Do not call them animals !!
This..from a economic stand point alone..what you are asking is problematic to say the least
I didnt expect to hear..a simple yes..but i do not want to hear..a simple no, is that what you are telling me? are you saying no?, im not saying no
Im saying time, time, you listened to Hebrews, i listen to Hebrews, who were you talking to?
GOD....GOD
Which God?
Are you seriously considering his proposal?, well is it a proposal if a man is holding a dagger to your throat?
I understand correctly thats um..demand
He has lost his mind..he has found a God..this God..or one of ours, i would like Moses
I want Moses dead, did you hear me?, yes, then..go
And..his family too
Moses?..where is Moses?
Moses?..his family..where?
This is not Moses, this is not his family
This is a man..his wife and his child who would ask the simple question..where is he?..answered..we dont know
Carry this image..home with you tonight, and discuss why you would protect him..knowing that tommorow..at this time, there will be another family..and another day after
..and the day after that, dare i say more
You are not going to do anything?, i didnt say that
Where have you been?, watching you fail, at this rate it will take years..a generation
I thought you were making progress..now you are impatient, (***) for 400 years of slavery
Am i the only one sitting who has done nothing about it till now?, i do know a few things about military actions, still if you are not going to listen to me then why
did you take me away from my family!
I didnt..you did, you dont need me?, maybe not, so do i do nothing?, for now..you are going to watch
Divine (GODS), i humbly call on you to purify the waters of our life giving river
How long?, not long
But longer than that
The Nile as we know carries muds of clay, this year there is much more of it than usual..drifting in on the currents..settling in the river banks..kicked up by the wild
thrashing of the crocodiles
This thrashing not only dramatically changed the color of the water but it was to point of killing the fish, but frogs as we know..can get out of the water when they have too
But frogs still need water and when they cant find it in the streets or the city..which they wont, and they die?..they die!
And then the rats come, and the maggots come, and the flies come..and then..and then what!?, the flies die
Speak up!, its in Hebrew, Hebrew?, read it, this catastrophes are the work of God and they have not finished, they will get worse, we need to reach a settlement with
Moses
So..the words of God
Here is my settlement to you, workload shall be doubled and you will get no straw to make your bricks, perhaps your God will provide it you
I was impressed at first..not anymore, this is affecting everyone, so who are you punishing?
What is this?, did you do this?, not me..not me, is this you?, no no, whats happened to you?
Move!, move!, move
And we have among ourselves a few hidden diseases that we dont clearly understand, the animals?..they are not exact and there is some conjecture that these disease can migrate
from the smallest creature..like um..a fly?
Have you been out to the river banks? im here to come ask help again..from 6 more gods
Is that it?, are you done?
Are you going to say something with your actions!?, did you meant to humble me!?, because it will not!
Initial reports suggests more than 10 million square cubits of crops have been lost
I suggest we return a portion of the supplement to the civil grainary an act of mercy..your people are starving, are you suggesting that i should starve too?, no
People have plenty of water
Is that you?..Moses?..brother
Have you come to negotiate?, because im ready, because ive had enough of you
One more thing happens, and i will bring my own plague to you
You see every Hebrew child, not yet walking, and none shall, because i will drown them in the nile, like you should have been
Oh you say that you didnt cause all this, your God did?
I am god...i am god
So lets just see..who is more effective at killing..you?..this God?..or me?
Nice of you to come, is he giving you what you asked?
Not yet, but his own people are turning against him, and his army?, it will, i disagree
Something worse has to happen, i disagree, anything more would be, would be what?..what are you about to say?..cruel?..inhuman?
its not easy to see the people who i grew up with suffering this much, what about the people you didnt grew up with? what thought did you give to them?
you still dont think of them as yours do you?, as long as ramsees has an army behind him nothing will change, anything more is just revenge, revenge?
After 400 years of brutal subjugation, these pharaohs imagine they are living gods, they are nothing more than flesh and blood, i want to see them on their knees begging
for it to stop!
Im tired of talking with a messenger!
General!, ive heard ramsees's final threats, so let me tell you whats going to happen next
No..no, you cannot do this..i want no part of this!
Leave him
Moses
I can have you killed, i dont think so, unless you do it yourself, your own soldiers let me in
Im not negotiating anymore, thats not why im here, i came to tell you..that something is coming, that is out of my control
Something that will affect thousands and thousands of citizens and it will affect you very personally Ramsees unless you accept what ive asked for and annouce it publicy before
the sun goes down
Ramsees do not..do not turn your back on me!
This has nothing to do..with you and i, this is far beyond that, this is about Egypts survival do you understand?
Sunset..after that it will be too late, what will be too late?, to protect your child, to protect your child tonight, is that a threat?
Is that a threat?, Moses!, Moses!
Tell everyone, to slaughter a lamb and mark their doors and their doors post tonight with its blood
Why?, pitty the lambs if im wrong, but if im right..we will bless them for eternity
Ramsees?..Ramsees?, Ramsees?
Did the children die last nite? as did mine?
Is this your God?, killing children?, what kinds of fanatics worships such a God?
No Hebrew child died last night
Get..out, go, everyone of you!, go!
Go to canaan if thats what you want, back to the homeland of your dreams, go!
As you command
This is the route i took, from here we move south to the Red Sea..the straights are here, at low tide we cross on foot
Now i know why you sleep so well at night, because you know you were loved
With respect if we are going to recapture 400,000 slaves we need more than 3 divisions, we will not be capturing anyone
We should rest, no..we wont be safe until we cross the sea
Ramsees and 4000 men, 1000 chariots, how far more it is? 4 days..less if they dont rest the horses
We need to rest the horses
The straights are that way, the longest easiest route is there at the western coast..or we go through the mountains
The mountains? why?, why dont we take that route? you can but so can Ramsees, the mountain pass is a dangerous place but they are too narrow for Ramsees's chariots, he
couldnt follow and that would give us a lead in time
What does God tell you?
The mountains
Can we make it?
I need your help
I dont know where i am
You wont help me, you wont help them
This way!
Move out!
This way, are you sure?
I mean are you sure we can make it across with our equipments, our chariots, they didnt think they could make it with theirs
How do they know?, they have never been here, Moses you mean?
Is this high tide or low tide?, doesnt matter, this isnt the straights is it?, no
Do you even know where we are? yes, we are on a point on the earth where there is a sea and an army behind, so now what?, we have to rest
Ive mislead all of them, i have abondon my family, i have failed you, im not what i thought i was
What is it?, the current, its strong
We need to cross here, we need to cross now
We cross here, we cross here, ready yourselves!, we cross here!, go tell them, go!
Your orders are like the last of the Egyptian wimp, we are no longer slaves
Then you are..you are free, you have lost sight of canaan?
You have honored me with your trust, now i honor you with my faith, follow me and you will be free, stay..and you will perish
Do not be afraid, GOD is with us, go!..ready yourselves!, go!, GOD is with us!, we cross here!
Joshua!, Aaron!
We must leave!
Halt!, turn around!, turn around!
Leave!, brother?, leave now! thats an order!
Come on!, you'll never make it back!
Its just me here
Sit
My family..may be not far from here, your family?, i have a family a wife and a son
I was thinking, maybe i could convince them..convince them to join us, perhaps thats..perhaps thats not wise, of course they should come, we have a long way to go..a lot can happen
And then when we get there..if we get there.., you dont think we will settle on canaan?, this place is a maze, what are our choices?
We are big as a nation tribe and that concerns people more, why?
But we all are in the same boat, we are now, but what happens when we start running?
Ramsees..the great
Did you know what you said?, when did i say it?, that you would trade your faith to keep me, no
You may need it more than ever now
Who are they?, they are my people
What makes you happy?, you do, what is the most important thing in your life?, you are, you are
Will i leave you?, never
May i proceed?, proceed
What do you think of this?, no one will do it, if they didnt agree? (***)
These laws will guide them, if you disagree..you should put down the hammer