Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
♪♪
- Okay, but this is
just this Thursday?
This isn't every week?
Mm-hmm.
Great.
Then, can you just stay three
extra minutes into closing?
And you'll do
a five-and-a-half-hour?
Yeah, it's cool.
Great, thank you.
♪♪
No.
♪ Happy birthday dear Tina ♪
And do they use Resy
or Clover?
I think it was Resy.
Yeah, Resy.
Great, we use Resy here,
so that should be easy.
♪♪
Hey, how's it going?
Hey.
Good, good.
I need you
to do me a big favor.
Uh, gather
all the troops around
before dinner service
kicks in.
Sure, yeah.
Is everything okay?
Yeah.
Everything's okay.
Okay.
Alright, everybody's here.
Look, uh, I have
a big announcement.
We're closing?
Jake, why would you say that?
I don't know.
Intuition?
Anyway, look, guys,
now, a while back,
I heard there was a program
that Tuscan Grove sponsored
where they take all
the top managers from franchises
all over the country
on a all-expense paid trip
to the Tuscan Grove
Institute in Italy.
Uh, you learn about
Italian cuisine and culture.
Uh, you stay in a villa.
It's a opportunity
of a lifetime.
Now, Amber, you've been here
for nine years.
Matter of fact, I hope
she's here for nine more years.
Yeah...
You've shown grace
under pressure.
You've ran this place
like a perfectly run ship.
Amber...
pack your bags.
You're going to Italy
next month.
What?!
Congratulations.
Wha-- I --
Are you being serious?
Oh, my God!
I mean, I've never been
to Europe before or anything.
Paul, I'm -- I'm so grateful
to you for this, really.
Hey, look,
this is an honor.
Like, this is not
an easy program to get into.
Matter of fact, I had to
write you a two-page essay.
That's how much
I believe in you.
But seriously,
get out of Bakersfield.
Go have some fun.
Recharge, relax.
Have a little adventure.
And, look, don't worry
about us here.
We'll manage.
I don't know about that.
Whatever.
Come here, give me a hug.
Aww.
- Damn, dude,
this is the shit.
Wait, and you're gonna be
staying in the villa?
Yeah.
Oh!
I know.
What?
I have a feeling.
You know what?
Nope, never mind.
Oh, my God, tell me.
You're gonna fucking
fall in love.
Okay, I was kind
of thinking that, too,
but it sounds so stupid.
No, it's not stupid.
Welcome to our table!
Hey, look, look.
Oh, my God.
Enjoy oodles of noodles
with our famous
classic spaghetti
and meatballs,
our juicy
and tender chicken parmesan,
or go succulent with
my personal favorite,
creamy fettuccini Alfredo.
Plus, soup or salad.
And finish strong
with our irresistible desserts.
Three full courses
for just $13.95.
Best of all, all our pastas
are all-you-can-eat.
Mama, don't stop there.
He's a growing boy!
Tuscan Grove.
Pull up a chair
and mangia.
Whoa.
Mm, maybe it's a sign.
Of what?
How is that a sign?
Of synchronicity.
♪♪
Okay.
I am gonna miss you, too.
♪ Ooh-ahh-ooh ♪
♪ Ooh-ahh-ooooooooooh ♪
I don't understand.
They can't just lose my bags.
I mean, I hope they'll be able
to get them to me.
♪ Ooh-ahh-ooh ♪
Hi, I'm Amber Ruffman.
Benvenuta, signorina.
Ciao.
Sono Craig e saro
la vostra guida
per la prossima settimana
presso l'istituto
del bosco toscano.
Mettete tutto
qui per favore.
Oh, n-- Um,
I-I don't speak Italian.
Were we supposed
to learn Italian?
Ah.
No, I'm just kidding.
I'm Craig.
I'm your program supervisor.
But don't worry, I'm cool.
O-Okay.
Hop in.
Thanks.
Yeah.
Hi, I'm Jen.
Hi.
Amber.
Did Craig do that thing
where he was talking
in Italian to you, too?
Yeah.
That was so funny!
I totally thought he was a real,
authentic Italian guy
'cause of the beard and stuff,
but I should have known,
'cause his name's Craig.
And, like,
what Italian's named Craig?
Totally.
I'm Deb.
Hey, I'm sorry
about your bag.
I overheard.
I'm Amber.
Oh, nice
to meet you, Amber.
I had so many important things
in my bag,
and now it's just --
I'm sure
they'll find them.
Really?
You think so?
Okay, ladies,
before I forget,
if you could just hand me
your passports,
I'll hold onto them before
it's time to head home.
Yes, sir.
Grazie.
Now you're mine.
He's so fun.
We're getting kidnapped.
♪ Ooh-ahh-ooh ♪
♪ Ooh-ahh-ooooooooooh
♪ Ooh-ahh-ooooooooooh ♪
I am having so much fun.
This van is really great.
I just really need my stuff,
you know?
And all the cars here
are so boxy.
Well, anything you need,
you can borrow from me.
I over-packed.
I can?
Yeah.
Really?
You would do that for me?
Of course.
It's no biggie.
Gonna be fine.
I just really need to get
my sleep or else I --
Oh, oh, I will be sleeping,
too, when I --
Oh, my God,
you guys, look.
it's so beautiful.
No way.
The villa.
It looks like
a fairy tale.
It's even more magical
in person.
It is.
Holy cannoli, right?
I feel like I'm in a movie.
Oh, wait.
Where are we going?
I thought
we're staying there?
Uh, yeah, no.
It says in the brochure --
We have a hotel
where our managers stay.
Don't worry, it's really nice.
Oh.
Oh, wow.
That -- It --
So much brick.
♪♪
Okay.
Buon giorno, party people.
-  Buon giorno.
It's so great to be with you.
Welcome here to giorno uno.
That's day one
of the Tuscan Grove
Institute Exemplary
Managers' Program.
You should all be
very proud of yourselves.
We're gonna have
a lot of fun here --
eat a lot of great food,
learn about Italian culture,
and most importantly,
grow as people.
But first, everyone
introduce yourselves.
Tell us your name,
where you're from,
and a fun fact
about yourself.
Okay, that's dry.
I'll start.
I'm Craig.
I, uh, come from Cincinnati, Ohio.
But,
uh, I've been living
that ex-pat life
for eight years.
And, uh, let's see --
my -- my great uncle
invented skorts.
"Sports"?
Skorts.
Okay.
Um, my name's Fran,
and you all probably
recognize me
from "Chef's Challenge."
And, uh --
Well, anyways,
I think of myself
as more than
just a manager.
I guess
I'm a bit of a foodie.
I've been dabbling
in molecular gastronomy
and, I don't know,
just happy to be here
to share
my expertise with y'all.
Oh.
Um, I'm Dana, and, um,
I've loved Tuscan Grove
since I was a kid.
And I guess you could say
that Nick Martucci's
kind of my idol.
Just the way he, um --
he built this business
from scratch.
And he stars in those
beautiful commercials.
Um, I don't know --
I-I'm just really psyched
to be here.
I don't know.
I'm Jen.
Uh, I'm from Oakland,
California,
and I am very --
- Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry, I forgot.
I'm from Tenafly,
New Jersey.
Please continue.
Did you --
Sorry, no, no.
You can go.
Um, I am really over
the moon to be here.
I feel very connected to all
of you guys already, like,
in this cosmic way.
Like we met in a past life
or something,
and that's, like,
very exciting.
And -- Oh, fun fact about me is,
I used to be a twin.
Uh, almost, because
my sister died in utero.
Cool.
That's not really a fun fact,
but, okay.
Hi, everybody.
My name is Deb.
I lost my bags at the airport,
and I had all these really
important things in my suitcase.
I called this woman with
the airlines and I spoke to her,
and she was very rude to me.
And she has no idea when
I'm gonna get my bags back,
or if they'll ever
find them again.
So, I just feel like
I'm not being very fun.
Mm.
But, um, I really
appreciated Amber.
She was so kind, and you told me
that you could lend me clothes,
and I really appreciate that.
You seem like a nice person.
Thank you.
W-W-Well, I'm Amber.
I'm from Bakersfield,
California.
Um, this is my first time
traveling outside the U.S.
I've worked at Tuscan Grove
for nine years.
I technically took a year off
to open a restaurant, um,
with tablets
at every table,
but my ex put all the debt
on my credit cards
and killed my credit,
and it went under, so I'm back.
And...
now I'm here.
Alright. Well, okay --
Okay, so I'm Susie.
Oh, sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Um, I'm from San Antonio,
Texas, so, "Go, Spurs."
Um, yeah, I don't know --
I've been at Tuscan Grove
for, like, ever --
since I was a little kid, like,
I've been working there.
I mean, not, like,
for real-for real.
Just for fun.
It's not like child labor.
Um, but, like, my parents
and my, like, aunt and uncle,
they all have a franchise,
and they've had it forever.
So, it's like all of us
work there -- my cousins --
There's 23 of us,
like, all together.
We're just,
like, a big family,
but we're all, like,
really close.
They're, like,
my best friends.
Oh, I love family.
Yeah, no,
I mean, family rips.
- Great.
So, now that we got the fun
stuff out of the way,
I gotta --
I have to put on my serious hat.
Italy's a magnificent country,
but, uh,
it can also be dangerous.
That's why we have
a strict curfew.
How is Italy
dangerous, Craig?
Uh, well, you know, there's
a lot of unpaved roads here,
so you could slip and fall.
You could, uh --
You could get lost.
There are boars.
Boars?
Yeah.
There's no leaving the TG
Institute while you're here,
except for official field trips,
which are so fun.
Yeah, okay, now I can take
the serious hat off
and I can put my fun
hat back on
and introduce
a very special guest.
Uh, please welcome one of
the most important members
of the Tuscan Grove family.
She is personally responsible
for designing
the official TG menu.
No way.
Liz Bence is here?
Lizzie Bence.
Oh, holy shit.
Uh, I'm gonna faint.
- Oh, please don't do that.
That's way too much pressure.
Welcome, everyone.
Congratulations
on making the cut.
And speaking of cutting,
you all look hungry.
Let's get to the kitchen.
Come on.
Ooh!
Alright, this is interesting.
What is the different
between a ragu and a Bolognese?
You don't have to
raise your hand.
Sorry, um, a Bolognese
is from Bologne?
Yes. What else?
What else?
Ingredients?
Yes, but, uh, specifically.
Sauce?
Well, you're gonna use a red
wine for ragu and white wine...
Uh, and white wine
for Bolognese.
...for Bolognese.
- That's so interesting.
Ooh, I love this.
This is fun.
Would that look cute?
Yeah, you can take it --
sure.
I think it would be so cute
with my jeans, you know?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, and there's some sweats
to sleep in, if you want.
Thank you so much.
I really like you, Amber.
Yeah. So, do you have
a boyfriend back home?
No, definitely not.
Oh, that's okay.
You're still young, you know?
You got plenty of time.
You should just have fun
while you're here
and sow your wild oats,
'cause that's what
I'm gonna do.
But I'm actually married,
though.
Oh.
My husband, Hank,
is wonderful.
He's --
He's really good for me.
We actually have a really
good relationship -- very solid.
You're gonna find love, Amber.
I can feel it.
A lot of my friends say
I'm really intuitive.
And you're my friend
now, so, mm.
Oh, I just need to get this.
Are you good?
Oh, yeah,
I'll just finish up.
Hi.
Hi!
Oh, my God, how is it?
Tell me everything.
It's r-really great.
"Really great"?
Come on, that's it?
Come on, i-i-is it insane?
How are the people?
Are there any assholes?
Have you hooked up with
anybody? Come on!
Oh, my God,
I've been here one day.
Hold on.
Hey, do you have
everything you need?
Oh, yeah.
This is so cute.
My husband actually loves
when I wear
really revealing
and sexy stuff.
Not that I would ever
do anything while I'm here,
but, you know...
Uh, d-d-d-do you
need anything else?
'Cause I'm just gonna talk
to my friend right now.
No, it's fine.
Oh.
It's actually really good
for my self-esteem, though,
because I love
getting attention from men,
and it's like that kind
of sexual energy, flirty --
Just makes
my body feel good.
And then
you kind of, like,
bring that energy back
to the marriage.
So it's --
it's, like, healthy.
Totally.
S-Sorry, so,
it's just that my friend
is calling long-distance.
Oh, sorry.
Oh, yeah, okay.
Oh, sure, sure.
I'll get out of here.
Okay.
Just want this.
Sorry.
It's okay.
Here.
Let me get my purse.
Would you care
if I take a few hangers?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
They didn't put any hangers
in my room, so --
It's so annoying.
This is so cute.
Can I take it?
Ooh, i-it's just
my only jacket.
Oh, okay, no problem.
Okay.
Okay, bye.
Okay, good night.
I'll see you in the van
tomorrow morning.
I'll see you then.
Okay.
Oh, it doesn't lock.
Huh?
It doesn't lock.
You can just open it.
That's so weird.
I know.
Okay.
Good night, Amber.
Good night.
Bye.
What was that?
Jesus.
♪♪
I know, yeah.
Hey, little guy.
- Right, so you wear
the ring to sleep,
and then it just tracks,
like, how much
REM sleep you get,
how much deep sleep you get.
And you're supposed to get
like an hour and a half of REM
or whatever, but --
- Amber, I saved
a seat for you.
♪♪
Can you just get one more?
I just want to make sure
you get my good side.
- Yeah.
Okay.
That look good?
Natural?
Yeah.
I just want one good one.
Does that look okay?
- It says, "Medieval times,
a piazza had served
as a central social
and economic meeting place
in Italian cities and towns.
Farmer's markets are
the traditional way
that townspeople purchased
all their produce.
Hmm, that's just
so interesting, isn't it?
I didn't know any of that.
No.
All the fruits and vegetables
that you see --
I think I'm gonna go.
Are you okay here?
Yeah.
-Okay.
-Local farmers and growers.
And you know, th--
the reason that Italian food
always tastes so good,
it's not --
it's not just the fresh
ingredients that they use.
It's also the soil.
Here,
just take one of me.
The soil imparts...
From low --
from a low angle.
Oh, my God, is it --
it's just us?
Mm.
Um --
Uh, the soil really imparts
this really distinctive,
very rich flavors.
Eh, I'm Karl Marx.
You wanna go to, like,
a flea market
or a thrift store
or something?
Uh, yeah.
And really quick, like,
why don't we ask around
and see if there's
anything cool to do?
♪♪
Yeah,
this took a lot of work.
This detail here,
the hooves, snout --
it's like
a 4-hour procedure.
Wow, you must
really like pigs.
Yeah -- to eat.
It's the best.
I mean, aren't they supposed
to be, like, really smart?
Yeah, I heard
they're really smart.
- Yeah, supposedly,
they're as smart as dogs.
-So, what?
-Sorry, sorry, sorry.
Craig, I'm so sorry.
Oh, my God,
what's in all those bags?
Well, I bought
some new clothes
so I don't have
to keep wearing yours.
Boom. Let's hit it.
Andiamo.
- Fashion show.
Most of our classic TG
chicken dishes like a Milanese,
a parmigiana, include
traditional Italian seasonings,
which is made up of rosemary,
basil, marjoram, sage, thyme.
But our Crazy Calabrese lasagna
has red pepper flakes, right?
'Cause that gives it that kick
that we all love so much.
Do you wanna, um,
try the marjoram,
or whatever it's called?
Yeah, sure.
When she first said it,
I thought she meant "margarine."
Just 'cause it --
Yeah, me, too.
I was literally like,
"Wait, is margarine
an Italian spice?"
"Yeah, here's this cool
Italian herb.
It's called butter."
-Shh.
Uh...
Sorry.
And, of course,
at our stateside locations,
we exclusively use
the prepackaged...
Ladies. Ladies,
just respect the herbs.
- You know, speaking
of respecting the herbs,
um, do you mind
if I take the stage?
Or the, uh, sage?
Okay.
Listen, gang,
I-I want to apologize
if I've come across as aloof.
I don't know, it's the jet lag
or something.
But I-I want to try to be
more available for you guys.
And -- And, Liz, I love
what you're doing,
but maybe we should try
thinking outside the box.
Let's take bruschetta.
Um, why don't we try
flipping it on its ear?
Do you have a, uh, --
a chinoise for the foam?
And gelatin --
I need to bloom the gelatin.
No, I don't have that.
Okay, well, we can use
some egg whites
to give it some more body.
Beautiful six-pack here.
Where's my plate?
Okay.
Actually, you know what?
We'll just use the whole egg.
Get some of that protein
from the yolk.
Oop, okay.
Get this working here.
And what about some
liquid nitrogen?
Do you have some
some liquid nitrogen here?
It's really not
that kind of kitchen.
Alright, let's use
some milk, then.
And, okay.
We're mixing.
You gotta get a real,
real quick mix going.
-What?
-Is this really happening?
Oh, I know it's, uh --
it's not pretty,
but we're improvising.
We're making it work.
Fran, you maybe want
to stop macerating right now.
I would like to introduce to you
a very special guest.
He is our C.E.O.
and our founder...
Oh, Jesus.
...and my dear,
dear friend.
Nick Martucci.
Ciao, amici!
-Ciao.
-Whoo!
Hey, don't stop on my account.
Oh, okay.
I'm just, uh, whipping up
a little foam here.
More of an emulsion,
actually.
I'm sure it'll be amazing.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Well, I was in the neighborhood.
I figured I'd drop in.
Isn't this so cool?
I mean, normally, I'm not here
in the off-season,
but I figured, for this group,
I'd make an exception.
Oh, hey.
Hey, Nick.
What's up?
I'm Susie.
Susie?
Mm-hmm.
That's a beautiful name.
Alright.
I'm Nick.
I'm -- I'm Jen.
Your name is Nick.
Hi, Nick.
You have exquisite hands.
Thank you.
Uh...
I-I love you.
Thank you.
Oh, I'm sorry.
No, it's an honest mistake.
I've never been
to Europe before.
No need to apologize.
She looks so much
like Connie, huh?
I'm Amber.
Well, it's nice
to meet you.
Hey, Amber.
Hey.
I'm, uh, Fran.
Thank you all for coming
all the way over here.
We're so appreciative
of everything
that you've done for our family.
Turns out, I'm gonna be around
a little bit this week,
so I'm excited to get to know
you a little better.
This is my assistant, Kat.
If you need anything,
feel free to approach her
and let her know.
She handles all my business.
How about a group shot?
Yeah, let's do it.
Come on.
-Yes.
-Gnocchi.
Okay, everyone say "formaggi."
-Formaggi.
Mwah. Bene.
Okay, now, if you'll excuse me,
I'm gonna catch up
with you guys in the A.M.
-Alright.
-Thank you, Nick.
Bye.
- Ooh, well...
That was a lot, huh?
Is everybody okay?
So, Nick.
Boy, he was definitely
feeling a little
something extra, hmm?
-Well, I --
-Ah.
- Oh.
Who's Connie?
I don't know.
I kissed him
right on the lips.
You did.
Hey, you're Amber, right?
Yeah.
Cool. Do you want
to take a smoke break?
Oh, um --
Just come with me.
Okay.
- Now, um, one of the things
that is --
There you go.
That I love about
the red pepper is that --
Oh, I don't really smoke.
Don't inhale, then.
Okay.
I t--
I only ever smoked
for, like,
two weeks in high school,
and I smoked cloves
'cause I thought it was so cool.
And I would just, like,
drive around in my car
with my cigarette
hanging out the window
but, like, so nauseous.
And then, my mom found
the cigarettes in my purse
and, like, asked
if I was smoking.
And I said no, and then I just,
like, burst into tears.
I felt so bad about lying.
Just --
That's cool.
Me crying is cool?
No, sorry.
I'm just kind of out of it
right now.
Oh, from traveling.
No. Nope, all we
fuckin' do is travel.
Yeah, like, I can't even
remember the last time
we were in one place
for more than a week.
That sounds fun.
Yeah, it can be.
It can also suck --
majorly.
I'm sorry, I'm, like,
dumping all my shit on you,
and we just met.
Oh, my God,
you can dump shit on me.
Yeah?
What are you doing
tonight?
Do you have plans?
No.
I mean, I don't know.
I don't think we're allowed to,
like, plan our own stuff.
No, fuck that.
You're with me.
I actually know this really
cool spot in Lucca.
Okay, great.
I wanna go to a cool spot
in Lucca.
Plus, Craig says we should
all stick together, right?
Can I bum a square?
- Here we go --
first one.
Okay.
There we go.
Uh...
Marjoram?
No.
Mint?
Pine?
Mm, no.
Hey, everybody.
Amber, Kat, and I are gonna go
to a really cool bar in Lucca
tonight if anybody wants
to come with us.
Okay, no.
That's not gonna happen.
So, to be crystal clear,
none of us are going to leave
the TG campus except the --
Oh, Craig, it'll be fun!
You gotta live
a little, baby.
-I'm trying to go.
-Uh, no.
It's the birth place
of Puccini.
Deb.
Deb, that's not permitted.
What's not permitted?
Smoking.
What?
Deb?
Put it out.
Oh, my God, so serious.
Craig, we're in Europe,
if you didn't know,
and you need to lighten up
a little bit, please.
This is a working kitchen.
Put it out.
Fine.
-Cool, so, Lucca?
-Yeah, can we go?
Alright, guys,
I'll make you a deal.
We can go...
-Yes!
-Let's go.
...to the bar right here.
What the fuck, Craig?
What kind of deal
is that, Craig?
I don't know what to tell you.
We're not going to Lucca.
Them's the rules, alright?
I brought some molly,
and Jen and I
are gonna roll tonight.
I don't know
if you wanna...
We'll just see.
Okay.
Yeah, no pressure.
What are you guys
talking about?
Oh, my God, look at them.
...my eyes.
We have the same face!
Ugh, they are
so annoying.
It's so depressing.
When I first got to Italy,
I had men that were, like,
chasing me down the streets.
You know, th-they would --
they would cat-call me.
They -- They would just,
like, reach out
and take big ol' handfuls
of my ass.
Oh, no.
No, it was great.
It was great.
I walk down the street now,
I'm completely invisible.
People, like, settin' drinks
on my head like I'm a table.
I don't even get whistled
at anymore.
Or that thing, you know --
I don't -- With the --
You know, the fingers
and the tongue?
This thing?
I never get that.
Ew, they did that?
Yeah.
Oh, my God.
God, I miss that.
Sucks we're not
going to Lucca.
You know, Lucca's
the porn capital of Italy?
Except they wear masks
to hide their identities.
Why do you know that?
I'm sorry your plan
got all fucked up.
I really do want to check out
that bar you were talking about.
No, it's totally fine.
We'll go another time.
Totally.
Um, tell me more about
your -- your traveling.
What's your all-time
favorite place?
Mm...
been so many places.
Oh, this one time, I was living
abroad in the Andes,
and I hiked up the cape
to Pachamama high on coca.
Coca?
Yeah, you need the coca
to survive the soroche.
What's that?
Altitude sickness.
We were at 3,200 meters,
so you definitely
need the coca.
Anyway, it was
the solstice, right?
So it was like the one day
out of the entire year
where the sunlight hits both
of the ovary rooms
at the same time.
Yeah, I've been on a real
Latin American kick.
Totally.
Have you read
García Márquez?
Mnh-mnh.
Don't think so.
Well, I've been reading
"News of a Kidnapping."
It's about
all these people
that were kidnapped
by Pablo Escobar.
It's brutal.
It's not like any of his other
magical, realist shit.
It's like
totally fucked up.
Whoa.
Sounds fucked up.
Yeah.
It's wild how much better
the food is here, right?
Fran, this olive,
these chips --
it is like I've never had
an olive before.
It's like -- it's like
I've never had chips before.
Yeah,
but in my younger days,
I was definitely rougher
around the edges,
you know what I mean?
Mm-hmm.
Like, you know, I got
in some trouble all the time,
did some stuff
I'm not proud of.
Yeah, yeah.
So, Bakersfield.
Yeah.
It's, uh --
It's pretty lame.
I don't know, it sounds
kind of exotic to me.
Mm, there's no...
ovary rooms.
It's Nick.
I gotta go.
Everything okay?
Yeah, just the usual shit.
Well, this was really fun.
Sorry it was co-opted by...
Yeah, it's cool.
But how about next time,
we keep it just us?
For sure.
Bye.
♪♪
- What's your
favorite pasta?
Because mine has been
spaghetti my whole life.
- Spaghetti?
Eh, no, it's not spaghetti.
You've never heard
of my favorite pasta.
Wait, look, guys.
Nick's in
the study working.
That must be important.
The study?
What is this, "Clue"?
He's killing Colonel Mustard
with the, uh, lead pipe?
Yeah, no,
I just know a lot
about the layout of his
house because I'm a big --
You know a lot about
the layout of his house?
Yeah, I've done a bunch
of searches
and look at pictures.
Okay, well, that's not creepy.
Is it creepy?
Get dressed.
W-Why?
What are you --
Shh. We don't want
to wake the others.
Just get dressed
and come with me.
Am I in trouble?
No.
I thought you said
you weren't reading anything?
Wow.
♪♪
Should I have brought
my bathing suit?
No, you'll be cool.
Yeah,
so, this is Liguria,
so if someone offers you pesto,
just fucking take it.
♪♪
Hi.
Buon giorno.
Welcome aboard
my humble abode.
Oh, no.
No, I'm sorry.
That was so stupid.
Wow.
Alright, so, I'll see you
back here same spot tonight?
Oh, yeah.
You're not gonna come?
Nah.
Have fun, though.
Ok-- Oh.
Must be so exciting
for you.
Oh, my God, yes.
This is awesome.
Oh, you gotta
take your shoes off.
Unless they're new.
Oh, yeah.
♪♪
This is amazing.
So, how's the program
treating you?
Are you having fun?
Um, it's awesome.
It's so awesome.
Honestly, it's just so nice
to be in another country.
Right, it must be
strange for you,
never having been outside
of the States, huh?
Yeah.
I sometimes
take it for granted.
Bakersfield, huh?
Yeah.
This is...much better.
I'm glad
you're enjoying it.
I am -- I really am.
I-I want to see
and do everything.
I just want to, like,
appreciate every moment --
even though I know that
sounds dumb or whatever.
I don't think
that sounds dumb.
Take it all in.
Maybe I could show you
the Amalfi Coast sometime.
That'll really blow
your mind.
Hey, I want to show
you something.
I got these from a fisherman
friend of mine
this morning
in La Spezia.
Oh.
Amber...
tell me --
why are you here?
Your boat?
You invited me.
No, why are you here?
On this trip?
I'm confused.
I-I mean, my boss at home
recommended me.
Why are you so guarded?
I don't think I'm guarded.
Do you think I'm guarded?
If you could be famous,
would you?
Um, no.
What a random question.
Why not?
I don't know, I-I mean,
I don't really have
any special talents or anything.
But I don't think that
makes me guarded.
Before you make a call,
do you rehearse
what you're gonna say?
S-Sometimes, yeah.
Pr-- I mean, I guess, if --
if it's an important call.
Mm.
What roles do love and affection
play in your life?
Wow.
S-Sorry,
w-where is this going?
I mean, you know,
I don't know.
I love my family.
I love my cat, Stevie.
She's rea--
No, I mean romantically.
I-I don't really have that
in my life right now.
I-I-I kind of went through
a bad break-up
a few months ago.
He was really controlling
and, like --
I don't know,
he just made me feel,
like, really bad
about myself a lot.
Um, and I don't think
I was great for him, either.
I was, like, always trying to
break up with him,
and he was constantly,
like,
talking me back
into the relationship.
It just made me feel like
love is supposed to be
really hard work
and, like, that no one
would ever love me
without makeup on, and...
Wow,
that's really horrible.
You didn't deserve that.
Yeah, so, I guess I'm just --
I'm kind of glad
not to have love
in my life right now, you know?
I get to just be myself
and have fun.
So, there's been
nobody else?
Oh, God, no.
I mean, you know, if anything
like that's come up,
I've kind of just
shut it down.
Um...so maybe
I am a little guarded.
I don't know.
Yeah, that's really hard.
No -- I mean, it's fine.
Like, I'm okay.
It happens.
I'm -- I'm here.
Hmm.
I mean, what about you?
Right after
my sister died...
Oh, my God, I'm so sorry.
I-I --
It was the hardest thing
that I've ever been through.
Everything else pales
in comparison --
meeting prime ministers,
dignitaries;
pitching VCs;
filming commercials.
Nothing phases me anymore.
Sorry, I-I d-- I don't --
I don't ever...
It's okay.
♪♪
Um, I was in a --
a bad place.
I was really searching
for something deeper --
something less lonely.
I wanted to open myself up
and not feel limited
by conventional
attitudes and moorings.
And I found myself,
one night,
uh, in a group situation...
Feeling I was rising up
out of my body...
All this,
like, intertwining...
Beautiful skin.
♪♪
You know, you start...
I don't know what...
♪♪
Such an amazing way
to sustain bliss,
you know?
♪♪
Maybe I could show you.
Yeah, totally.
I'm really happy
you're here, Amber.
♪♪
I guess Kat's gotta
get you back.
This was incredible.
Wow.
It was.
Thank you so much.
My pleasure.
Okay, okay!
Jesus.
Hey, listen, um,
my friend Ricky's
having this
little party tomorrow night.
He's a sculptor --
super talented.
Maybe you'd want to join?
If it's not too much.
No, yeah.
Amazing.
I-I'd love to.
Great.
So...
it's a date?
Yes.
Great.
Oh, wait, one more thing.
It's probably best if we
keep this to ourselves,
'cause I don't want
the other managers
thinking you're getting
special treatment.
Of course.
Okay.
Oh.
That was so amazing.
I can't even believe it.
Yeah.
Just make sure to keep it
on the DL.
Right.
Totally.
Yeah, and he, like, asked me
all these intimate questions,
and he really
opened up to me
about his family
and his pain.
Wait, wait, his pain?
Yes, it was crazy.
Like, don't tell anyone,
but he told me about his sister
who died, and then we kissed.
And then, he invited me
to this artist party
tomorrow night as his date.
Wait, what the fuck?
So you're just, like,
riding on yachts
and you're, like,
his girlfriend now?
Okay, no,
I'm not his girlfriend.
We just had
an amazing day.
Oh, my God, is he
as hot in person?
Um, yeah.
Oh, my God,
I'm so jealous of you.
You're just gonna be, like,
flying all over the world
with your rich boyfriend,
meeting famous artists
on yachts and shit.
I told you this shit
was gonna happen.
He's not my boyfriend.
Okay,
that's your boyfriend.
How is that, Jen?
It's a little hard.
Well, that's what we refer
to as al dente.
It's actually the ideal
texture and doneness.
It's actually kind of gross,
this texture.
Yeah, it's really gross.
It's just, like, too bouncy.
But it's ideal.
Yeah, like, it's supposed
to be mushier.
Warm cat food
or something.
Yeah, like, right.
Well, not like -- It's like --
You know when you chew or eat,
like, an eraser,
it kind of tastes like --
Yeah.
Who would ever have pasta
like this?
Alright, you guys
can take your seats now.
Okay.
Amber,
how you feeling today?
Uh, great.
You sure?
You still don't have
that migraine?
Oh, yeah.
I-I do.
Okay, hmm.
Well, maybe you should go back
to your room and get some rest.
Yeah, that sounds great.
To, like -- to get rest.
Mm-hmm.
Glad she's getting some rest.
- Hey, Craig, when is
Ms. Bence coming back?
Oh, she won't be coming back.
- She gone.
Now, who knows what to do
with the water?
Do we pour out the water,
or do we use it for later?
I could show you
a better way to boil.
Oh.
Hey.
Jesus.
Nick sent me to escort you
to Ricky's party.
Great.
Um, let me just, I think,
run to my room and change,
and I'll meet you outside?
Nah,
don't worry about that.
We got you.
We need to be discreet.
Totally.
♪♪
I don't know.
Is it too much?
E assolutamente
fighissima, vero?
Si, si, si.
Yeah, si, si.
No, that's the one.
We're getting that.
Oh, Kat, I can't afford this.
Oh, don't worry.
It's Nick's treat.
Che romantico.
"Pretty Woman," no?
Tranne che non
è una prostituta.
-What?
Okay.
We're good.
♪♪
You want a drink?
Yes, please.
♪♪
La mia tartarughina...
Hi.
Oh, you look so beautiful.
Been thinking about you
non-stop.
Me, too.
I had so much fun.
♪♪
Here.
Come here, I want to introduce
you to some of my friends.
Okay.
There he is.
Amber, Amber, this is Ricky.
Oh, hi.
This is his party.
Oh, whoa.
We've been pals
for a long time now.
Mm-hmm.
He's almost
as good at sculpting
as he is at throwing parties.
I'm also a repository
for Nicky's dirty secrets.
Easy.
T-Thank you so much
for having me.
Your place is unreal.
Well, thanks for crashing
the party.
Just fucking with you.
Oh.
Nicky,
you were not kidding.
Her skin is so luminous.
Look at this.
Oh.
Wow, do you model?
N-- Oh, no, never.
Never?
That's such a shame.
You seem very open-minded.
Open to new experiences,
am I right?
Well, I was open
to coming on this trip.
She's funny, too.
Amber, uh, this is Danny,
Marcello, Wendy, Frank.
Ciao.
And this is my son, Giorgio,
and his lover, Vale.
Ciao.
Oh.
So nice to meet you.
It's my pleasure.
And, uh, these here
are my first loves.
No offense to Giorgio.
This is my early work.
Oh, wow.
Would you like
a little tour?
Yes.
That okay with you?
You don't mind sharing?
So, this piece
was made to honor
the victims of Amatrice.
God, what a tragedy.
Mm.
Ah, the fragility
of, uh, flesh.
This piece here,
this is from a series
that was commissioned
by Sir Richard Branson.
Cool.
Yeah.
He's a great guy --
really down to earth.
This one's my favorite.
You have great taste, Nicky.
This was three weeks
after giving birth to Giorgio.
I mean, it's amazing how
resilient our bodies are, hmm?
Oh, Amber, uh,
this is my wife, Sofia.
Oh, hi.
Come, let's go and sit.
Yeah, go.
I'll find you.
Got it.
Okay.
Have fun.
Oh.
Oh, no, no, no,
no, no, no.
Stay. Hmm.
Nicky speaks
so highly of you.
It's adorable.
He never speaks highly
of anyone, it's so strange.
Really?
Well, he's been really sweet
and -- and so generous.
Yeah, he's like that.
You seem so open-minded.
Why does everyone
keep telling me that?
Oh, G-- Oh, m--
There you are.
I was looking
all over for you.
Uh-oh.
Stage-one clinger.
Oh, no, I'm -- I'm not --
Oh, you're just
a little turtle
being forced out
of your shell?
I --
No, I'm k--
I'm totally kidding.
Oh, my God, I'm --
Okay.
Oh, you look so beautiful.
Thank you.
Come on, baby turtle,
I wanna show you something.
♪ Never seen so many men ask
you if you wanted to dance ♪
♪ And looking for
a little romance ♪
♪ Given half a chance ♪
I requested this
just for you.
Oh, 'cause of my dress?
♪ Or the highlights
in your hair ♪
Yeah.
♪ That catch your eyes ♪
♪ I have been blinded ♪
♪ The lady in red ♪
♪ Is dancing with me ♪
♪ Cheek to cheek ♪
Fuck.
♪ There's nobody here ♪
You look
so much like her.
Like who?
♪ It's just you and me ♪
My sister. Connie.
It's uncanny.
Right, I'm sorry.
No.
I'm sorry.
♪ This beauty by my side ♪
You just captivate me.
♪ I'll never forget ♪
It scares me.
Bri-- Brings up all these --
all these feelings --
Hey, may I?
♪ Oooooh oooooh ♪
You smell so good.
♪ I've never seen you
looking so gorgeous ♪
♪ As you did tonight ♪
♪ I've never seen you shine
so bright ♪
♪ You were amazing ♪
♪ Never seen so many people ♪
Excuse me, Ricky,
I'd like to cut in, alright?
♪ And when you turn to me
and smile ♪
♪ Took my breath away ♪
You know, your name
in Italian would be "Ambra."
Really? That's cool.
♪ I have never had
such a feeling ♪
- Hey.
♪ Such a feeling
of complete... ♪
Don't worry, I --
Na puttana!
Oh --
Puttana!
♪ Is dancing with me ♪
Hey, follow me.
Vale! Vale!
- Where's Nick?
Just keep it moving.
Okay.
You okay?
I don't know.
Vale, Vale, Vale.
Vale, Vale --
I'm so, so sorry.
I really fucked this up.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I think so.
I'm such a fucking --
I had such a lovely time
with you.
I really, really don't
want that to scare you.
Did it scare you?
Are you scared?
Uh, please don't be scared.
It's okay, I'm okay.
Oh, we're good, Nick.
We gotta get
a move on, okay?
I-I'll see you soon,
okay?
-Vale!
-Go, go, go, go.
♪ Lady in red ♪
What a shit show.
Are you hungry?
I don't know what I am.
Do you want
to get a nightcap?
I know
a really good place.
- This used to be
the number-one restaurant
in the world.
Now it's number three.
Oh.
It's still just as good.
Alright, just go along
with whatever I say, okay?
It'll be cool.
Cool.
-  Vivo.
Pretend to pour a salt shaker
onto your tongue.
Really?
Yeah.
Grazie.
I told him we were
really hungry.
Eh, voilà.
Wow, this looks
incredible.
There you go.
Told you.
Oh, my God.
Mm-hmm.
It's so good.
I know.
Just hurry up and eat
before he gets back.
Why?
You don't want to have
to pay for this.
I thought it was free.
Don't you know that guy?
Yeah,
he's a fucking scumbag.
Just eat.
Come on, let's go.
Come on.
♪♪
No, no, no.
Hey.
Ah! Ah!
♪♪
That was fucking badass.
I wanna fucking
kill that guy.
Let's get out of here.
Move!
You're really...
kind of intense.
Does it scare you?
Kind of.
♪♪
Wait, wait, wait.
Oh, I don't know --
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry,
I'm a little confused.
I just --
All that shit
with Nick earlier, you know?
It just fucking --
just kind of threw me.
Are you for real? Nick?
I don't know.
I don't -- you know --
Can I, like --
We have, like, a thing.
I-I don't --
Yeah, no,
Nick's a fucking baby.
He's incapable of caring
about anyone but himself.
He's just, like,
tripping on you
because of his sister.
But --
I-I mean...you're not there.
I don't --
No, Amber,
he does this with everyone.
You're not special.
It's, like, his M.O.
Look, I'm sorry.
Maybe we should just head back.
Okay, cool.
Kat --
No, it's cool.
Let's get you back.
- It's bullshit, man.
What does this have to do
with cooking?
-Just fucking do it, Fran.
-Hey, guys.
- Um, we're doing trust
falls. If you want, I can --
Sorry, I guess I overslept.
Glad you're
feeling better.
Hey, where's Susie?
She wasn't feeling well,
so I said she could
take the day off.
She seemed all right to me
last night,
if you know what I mean.
What do you mean?
Nothing, I just, you know,
mean she didn't seem sick --
literally.
Mm-hmm.
What?
♪♪
Susie.
- Amber?
Oh. You scared me.
Can we talk?
Sure.
Why aren't we as close
as we used to be?
What do you mean?
You didn't tell me
you weren't feeling well.
any of that.
And where were you coming
from before?
You should tell me
these things.
We're friends.
We used to be close.
We would tell each other
everything. Remember that?
You weren't with Jen
and Susie, were you?
No.
Don't lie.
If you're fucking lying,
I will find out in one minute.
I just overslept, is all.
And let me tell you
something else --
it gets back to me
that you're going around
snitching, gossiping,
and telling everyone that I need
what's in my suitcase.
I'm doing fine
with my new pills, okay?
So stop gossiping about me,
you little bitch.
I'm sorry.
Say it again.
What are you sorry for?
Everything?
Good.
Okay, fine.
Apology accepted, bitch.
-So we had the mice infestation.
-Yeah.
Vermin are a big no-no
with the health inspectors.
Hey.
It was raining so much,
we had black mold.
Hey, where's Susie?
I think she's really sick,
right?
Mm, mm.
It's sad.
You know, I thought I saw
her leave yesterday with Kat.
With Kat?
Mm --
Mm, yeah, I don't know.
Really? You don't know
anything about that?
Not, like, maybe --
She's sick.
Chill, okay?
- Morning, bambini.
- Morning.
So, we're gonna watch
a video today --
"Life is Beautiful."
You couldn't find that
on laser disc, there, Craig?
It stars Roberto Benini.
Anyone seen it?
I have, Craig.
Okay, yeah, I haven't seen it,
either, but it got some Oscars.
It's supposed to be a banger.
Craig,
I feel really sick.
I just f--
I don't feel good.
Oh, no.
You need to excuse yourself?
Uh, yeah, I'm sorry.
Is that okay?
I mean, I don't want you
to miss out.
This is supposed
to be hysterical.
I just think I need to,
like, rest, you know?
Are they telling you
to say this?
Just fucking drop it.
I gotcha.
Feel better, Jen.
Okay.
Bye, guys.
I'll miss you guys.
Ugh, don't worry about me.
I'm okay.
- Boy, they're really
dropping like flies, huh?
Hey, maybe we should go
whip up
some wellness shots
or something, you know?
Like, in the kitchen?
Like, make something, Craig?
Can I talk to you
outside for a second?
Showing a movie
to kill some time?
Okay.
This is some substitute
teacher bullshit, Craig.
Here.
Oh, I-I don't really smoke.
It was subterfuge.
Just don't inhale.
Okay, um...
Listen...
I think something weird
might be going on.
What do you mean?
Well, don't you think
it's weird that Liz Bence
suddenly disappeared
with no explanation?
I guess.
Is it weird?
And then, like, we haven't
seen Susie in two days.
And, like, Jen is suddenly
acting so strange,
and she's not feeling well.
Like, you had a bad migraine
for two days,
and I looked it up,
'cause I was worried.
And --
And I found, normally,
they only last
for four hours.
Why are all the women
in this program
suddenly getting sick?
I mean, have you talked
to Deb recently?
Something is definitely
going on with her.
So, maybe
it wasn't a migraine.
Maybe it was
something else.
Like what?
Poison.
Poison?
Think about it.
Liz Bence was making
all our food, right?
Mm-hmm.
Then, she disappears.
All of a sudden,
all of the women in the program
are dropping like flies.
Okay, I didn't actually
have a migraine.
That was just something
I said to cover
what was really going on.
Okay, well, what was
really going on?
Remember Kat?
Nick's assistant?
Of course.
Well, she secretly took me
to Nick's boat.
What?
Yeah.
She, like, made up
this whole scenario
so I could spend
the day with Nick,
and we went out
on his huge yacht.
And, like, then she drove me
back here afterwards,
and they both told me
not to tell anybody.
But, like,
Kat is kinda sketchy.
Like, she and Nick have
a super volatile relationship.
Like,
she kind of hates him.
You spent the day on Nick's
yacht, just the two of you?
Y-Yeah, and --
and what I'm saying is...
Wow. Yeah.
...Kat...
Yeah, yeah, that's fun.
A boat day, that's cool.
Okay, Dana?
Listen to me.
What I'm trying to say is
that Kat is kind of shady.
The next time I saw Nick --
Wait, you saw Nick again?
Yes, and she was supposed
to bring me right back here
afterward, and instead,
she took me to Lucca.
Birthplace of Puccini.
And then, just yesterday,
I saw her taking Susie away.
And she got back last night,
and Susie was gone.
And she left me some book
about kidnapping.
I'm just saying, if something
sketchy is going on here,
maybe Kat has something
to do with it.
Hey, uh, Craig.
I, uh -- I have to go
to the bathroom so bad.
Uh, is it okay if I go
to the bathroom?
'Cause I gotta go so bad.
Yeah.
Thanks. Oh, man.
♪♪
- So,
I got all these photos
from the other
manager trips.
Do you notice anything?
Um, there's regular ones
and there's crazy ones?
Like, they're -- they're
making silly faces and stuff?
Yeah, but look closer.
Almost all of the managers
are women,
and if you look at Kat,
she's next to the prettiest
girl in every single photo.
You think
I'm the prettiest girl?
Look, it's all women.
Fuck.
Oh, my God.
I made out with Kat.
Okay, yeah.
No, that's --
But now, it makes so much sense
why she was so upset
with Nick
this whole time.
Like -- Like, she was jealous
of him and me.
Maybe we -- we were ruining
her whole plan.
But jealous about what?
Him and I making
out and stuff.
She saw it when
she picked me up.
Wait, you made out
with Nick, too?
Y-- Why are our trips
so different?
Wait a second.
I just thought
of something.
Fran and I both have
unisex names.
They thought
we were women, too.
And that is why Nick
was so weird
when we first met,
right?
It's not just Kat --
it's Nick, too.
No, no, no, no, no.
I-I don't think it is Nick.
Like, I haven't even seen Nick
with any other women --
only Kat.
And Kat, she's been, like,
steering me to suspect him
this whole time.
Right.
Kat's the poisoner.
No, I don't think
there's poison.
I don't thi--
I feel like we moved on
from the poison thing.
I think that Kat
has developed
this whole program to,
like, hook up.
I don't know.
I mean, Nick is super rich.
He oversees everything
about the program.
There's no way something
like this could happen
without him
knowing about it.
I think Nick's
the mastermind.
No, I j--
What the fuck?
♪♪
Amber?
Amber!
♪♪
Amber?
I can see you.
Were you following me?
What are you doing?
I should ask you
the same question.
I wasn't following you.
No, not the following part.
What are you doing?
What do you mean?
The whole
yacht-seduction thing.
You do this
with all the managers?
Seduction?
Amber,
listen to yourself.
You sound
really disregulated.
Should I be worried
about you?
It's just, all these women
are acting so strange
and disappearing.
And Kat said --
Wait, I don't know anything
about any women disappearing.
Kat said that?
You need
to stay away from her.
She's a trickster.
I fired her.
What? When?
This morning.
It's been a long time
coming.
She's unstable.
She's a deeply unhappy person.
Don't be like her.
It didn't end well for her.
Didn't e--
Amber,
don't throw this away.
Do you have oysters
for Jen, too?
You're doing it again,
baby turtle.
You're pushing me away
like you always do
and going
in your little shell.
Why are you so afraid
of being loved?
Are you serious?
Why would you say that
to me?
You admitted you sabotaged
all your past relationships.
It's exactly
what you're doing now.
I can't believe you would
use that against me.
You're fucking
gaslighting me.
Gaslighting you?
I feel like I've been really
sensitive to you
and have had nothing
but the purest intentions.
Look, I'm hosting
a fete tomorrow night
and I thought maybe --
No!
Something shady is
going on here with you.
I know it.
Look, maybe take a moment
and realize you're in Italy.
Fuck Italy.
♪♪
Shit.
You're back.
You were right. It is Nick,
the fucking asshole.
Ugh, that creep.
I followed him and Jen.
He took her to the yacht.
He denied everything.
And Kat's gone.
Kat's gone?
Yeah,
he said she's fired.
But who knows
what's true?
He's trying to make me think
I'm crazy now.
He's using shit against me
from my past.
What does that mean?
Like, the other day
on the boat,
he was asking me all these
intimate questions, and --
and I told him some --
some really private stuff.
I'm such a fucking idiot.
Whoa.
Like, what private stuff?
It's private.
Sorry.
But, like,
it was really weird,
because it started out
super simply.
Like, "If you could be famous,
would you?"
But then, he got into shit
about, like,
"What roles do love and
affection play in your life?"
Like, who even talks
like that?
When did you last sing
to yourself?
Last week, why?
Look.
"'The New York Times' 36
Questions that Lead to Love."
Oh, my God.
Nick is the mastermind.
Okay, we gotta get the fuck
out of here.
Right. Well,
Craig has our passports.
We're American citizens,
and so we have a right
to demand
our passports back now.
And so,
we do demand that.
Furthermore, we want
to be flown out of here --
t-tonight, now.
Uh, well, yeah, that's --
that's not gonna happen.
Look, we know there's
something shady going on,
and we just want
to leave quietly.
So, just give us our passports,
and we won't report
any of this --
Wait, what?
What's that, now?
All these "women"
getting "sick"...
What are these
air quotes about?
I'm not following.
Where's Liz?
Where's Susie, huh?
We know they're not
just getting "sick," Craig.
So, Lizzie was only scheduled
to be here two days,
and she's left.
Well,
what about my migraine?
I didn't even have one.
Oh, you didn't?
Huh.
Why did you say you did?
Listen, guys,
tomorrow's the last day.
It's probably best
not to rock the boat.
I have a woman's name.
♪♪
So, I need to apologize
once again
for showing "Life is Beautiful."
Uh, my bad.
I'll be reading the synopses
from here on out.
I'd also like to, uh,
remind everyone that
you're very lucky to be here,
and you should be
very appreciative
of this opportunity.
So, keep it professional
and positive, okay?
So, in that spirit, let's do
some trust-building
exercises today.
This one's called
"Pass the Zuke."
Uh, share something personal
about yourselves, uh,
perhaps something you learned
on this trip. I'll start.
Um, I got
a better idea, Craig.
We should play Mafia.
It's really fun and it's
a great way to build trust.
Alright, so, I'm gonna hand
out these little cards.
They're gonna tell you
if you are a villager
or a member of the Mafia.
And then we're all
gonna close our eyes.
Mafia members will open them,
make eye contact,
and carefully choose
someone to kill.
- Hey, Nick.
-Hey, Nick.
-Ciao, amici.
Amber, could we have
a word outside, please?
I'm good.
She's good.
Hey, uh,
you want to play, Nick?
Uh, okay.
Sure.
What's the game?
Mafia.
Great.
-Awesome.
-Unreal.
Okay.
Shuffle these boys up.
Keep those close
to the vest.
Don't let anyone know
who you are.
Do you understand
the game, Deb?
- Yes. I think I do.
Here you go, my don.
Okay, everybody.
It's morningtime.
The sun is rising.
The birds are chirping.
You just had a restful sleep.
And in a second, everyone's
gonna open their eyes,
except for Dana.
Dana, you're dead, bro.
Okay.
Well, obviously,
it was Nick.
Right?
What'd you do with them?
Who?
Wait. Dana, you're not
allowed to talk.
You're dead.
Why would you think
that I did it?
Well, because
you know I know.
I mean, it's so obvious.
Know what, Dana?
Dana,
zip it up, dude, okay?
Were you Mafia
or were you a villager?
Yeah, maybe play it cool.
No, no.
He makes himself out to be
this amazing guy, right?
Mm-hmm.
With this amazing family.
And that
bringing all of us here
will let us be
a part of that.
And, instead,
he just totally snubs me,
and this program sucks!
It sucks.
I'm sorry.
You just fly a bunch
of white people out here.
You make a Bolognese.
You watch moves in this
dilapidated, low-rent shithole.
You have no other plan.
I hear trains go by
every fucking three seconds.
My room has silverfish in it,
and they really scare me,
but I don't want
to kill them,
so I'm just living
with fucking silverfish?!
Fuck this!
I'm Persian.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
But where is everyone
disappearing to?
Nick,
are you poisoning them?
-Whoa! Stop it.
-You're being a dick, Dana.
No, no, no.
It's okay.
You want to talk
about family?
You ever held your sister's hand
as she died
right in front of you?
No, I haven't.
That would be
an incredible coincidence.
I have.
Connie --
Connie was my everything.
I mean, this isn't
what I signed up for.
Tuscan Grove was supposed to be
a fine-dining experience,
so I didn't know
it was gonna snowball
into some fucking populist,
mass-produced,
fucking fast-food bullshit.
It was supposed
to be my Spago,
my Chez Panisse.
I've accepted what
it's become --
a massive success.
Great.
And now I try and create
a beautiful experience
for all of you,
inviting...
you into my home...
...my villa, my...
my life.
And you have the nerve
to accuse me?
I-I really put my heart
on the line this time.
Never again.
It hurt -- it hurts.
I'm sorry.
Thank you for inviting me
into your little game.
But I should go.
-No. No. No, no, no.
-Nick, come on, man.
Nico.
Way to go, Dana,
you pussy.
Hey, fuck you, Fran.
You're a fraud.
What'd you say?
I saw your episode
of "Chef's Challenge,"
and a fucking tween
beat you.
A twe-- a tween?!
Elliot is 13 1/2 years old.
That's not a tween.
And, furthermore, the rules
are fucking bullshit.
Think about it.
You know what?
They edited it to make me
look like an asshole.
You weren't even there.
Fuck you.
- Enough!
This is supposed to be
a team-building exercise.
Dana, cool out.
Ooh! Ooh! Fooh!
Big man Craig standing up!
You're a fucking fascist, okay?
You have no right to kidnap us
like this, alright?
I already apologized
about the video.
Sit down.
I'm not talking
about the video.
You're dead.
I'm talking about the fact
that you're a fucking patchouli
Charles Manson bitch
who I'm about to fuck up!
Oh, we got a hot shot here.
You're out
of your fucking mind.
Do you want to go back
to Teaneck?
- Hey, hey.
I'm from Tenafly.
Hey, Dana, come on.
Sit down now.
-Sit down now.
-Take off your shirt.
-I'm not gonna take my --
-Sit down!
-No!
-Hey! Sit -- Hey!
-I'm not about --
-Sit down!
Now you're fucked!
No, no, no, no.
Hey, come on, now.
Now my shirt's off,
and I can't stop
till I feel blood.
Sit down!
Okay!
Good.
We won't fight.
'Cause I'm starting to
feel sick anyway,
'cause I guess something
seems to be going around.
I'm gonna go drink
at the villa.
- What?
What?
What the hell?
I think Deb's the killer.
You bitch!
Oh!
You're all bitches!
All of you.
♪♪
Oh, my God!
Hey. Sorry.
It's okay.
Are you okay?
'Cause that was a lot before.
No, I had to create
a diversion.
Listen, you've got
to come with me.
There is something big
going on.
- All these people
are showing up
in fancy clothes.
Well, Nick told me
he was having a party tonight.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
But they have
machine guns.
Machine guns?!
Shh, shh.
♪♪
What the fuck?
Holy shit.
It's murder.
I knew it.
What the fuck?
♪♪
Okay. Okay.
I'm gonna tail her.
You stay here, okay?
And be careful.
Wait, wait.
Why?
What kind of plan is that?
Why do we keep putting
ourselves in danger?
I got this.
Sorry. Fuck.
♪♪
No!
Aah!
Aaaaah!
Fuck.
♪♪
Deb?
Just --
It happened so fast.
♪♪
Amber!
Fran, Fran, open up!
- Yeah?
One sec.
Come on, come on, come on,
come on, come on.
-Oh. Hey.
-We got to get out of here.
Dana's dead.
Deb's in on it.
Nick and Craig have
Liz tied up in the villa
for some kind of human sacrifice
or something.
I don't know.
But we got to go.
We got to go.
Is this a bit?
Dude, this is
really happening.
We got to get Jen and get
the fuck out of here.
Okay. Did you take
too much melatonin or what?
Dana is dead!
This is for real!
- Oh, my God.
She's coming.
Come on.
Who's coming?
-Oh, Jesus.
-Jen, Jen, Jen, Jen.
-Go, go!
-Jen.
- Jen. Jen. Jen.
She's fucking dead.
- I told you.
Shit!
Hide, hide, hide.
Shh, shh, shh.
Okay, wait.
So, what's happening?
Dana and I saw Liz
tied up in the villa.
We split up, and then
I found him dead
with Deb
standing over him.
They knew he knew.
Basically, Nick runs
this whole program
to get unsuspecting women here
and seduce them,
and now people
are getting murdered.
Why?
I don't know!
But, like, you know how everyone
keeps disappearing
and, like, how you have
a woman's name?
What? I-I --
Look, I keep trying 911,
but it's not working.
- Amber?
Shh!
Amber?
Amber.
Where are you?
♪♪
Fucking bitch.
Oh, my God.
Okay.
I'm trying 911, but I think
they have it jammed.
Yo!
Shh!
Where you been?
Wait. Who's that?
I'm Fran.
'Sup?
Shh. Listen.
We're being hunted,
and people have been murdered.
What the fuck?
Did you call 911?
It's not working.
I-I think they jammed it.
Shh, shh, shh.
Let's make a run for it.
♪♪
- Amber?
-  W-Wait. What -- what --
What just happened?
Is that the killer?
- Amber?
♪♪
Why are we running towards
the fucking villa?
I don't know.
Some fucking plan.
Help.
He's here.
Look -- he's alive.
-Who is alive?
-Help me.
Who was that?
-Hey, hey.
-Help.
Oh, and he's covered
in piss.
Oh, God.
Are you okay?
What did Deb do to you?
Not Deb, pigs.
Pigs?
That's some fucking Manson
hippie race-war bullshit.
You know,
helter-skelter, baby.
Guys.
Oh!
Oh! We got to go.
We got to run!
Come on!
♪♪
- What is this?
It's the atrium.
Dana, Dana,
don't fall asleep.
Don't fall asleep.
You know this place.
You got to tell us
where to go.
Where do we hide?
Study.
Study? Where is that?
Dana, Dana!
Is he okay?
I don't know.
What do we do?
Whoa, whoa.
I remember.
He -- he pointed it out.
Okay. Let's go that way.
My friend is in Italy,
and they're running away
from a serial killer.
Okay.
Italy, Italy, the country.
What -- Who do I call?
What do you mean
you don't know?
♪♪
Hey.
Welcome.
Guys, this is Amber.
She came.
Mama Martucci?
You brought friends.
That's great.
It's Lucca porn.
It's what I was telling you
about at the bar.
Isn't she gorgeous?
Oh.
Okay, this is not
what it looks like.
Wait.
This is not Lucca porn?
'Cause it looks exactly
like Lucca porn.
What the fuck?!
♪♪
Aah!
Sorry.
My alarm didn't go off.
I got it.
Italy -- it's not 911,
it's 112.
Uh, you guys...
Okay.
Okay, cool.
Alright.
There's nothing
you can do?
I can't fill in a police report
or anything?
It's a private...
- So, this is
kind of exciting.
I still have
my butt plug in.
So do I.
You do?
Oh, my God!
♪♪
Hey.
How you doin'?
Thanks.
Well, that wasn't really
how I saw that playing out.
Yeah.
But, I mean, we were kind of
right about the sex stuff.
Yeah.
And I got to see
Mama Martucci.
So, um, I guess
this is goodbye.
Yeah.
It was really nice to get
to know you a little.
Thanks for the adventure.
Uh, yeah, anytime.
Take care.
Hey.
Yeah, well, we really did it
this time, eh, kid?
Sure.
Feel better.
Is this the part
where we kiss?
Um --
Or --
Oh, no, I --
Okay.
♪♪
And then we were --
I tried to warn everyone.
I told them.
And then
there were the pigs.
Little pigs.
There were pigs.
I think the pills
my pharmacist gave me --
they were
the wrong pills.
♪♪
Ciao.
Oh, my God.
What happened?
Shit go down?
Where have you been?
I was in Genoa.
It was chill.
Miss me?
Yeah.
Aww.
I mean,
I don't know why...
Is that a dildo gun?
Yeah.
♪♪
♪ Now the ballroom's empty ♪
♪ Everybody I have known ♪
It's so creepy how
she can sleep like that.
♪ Has been and gone ♪
♪ With the music over ♪
Okay, well, ragazzi,
I guess this
is the end of the line.
I hope you cherish
these memories
for the rest of your lives.
It has been an honor.
And I also want to remind you
that you all signed NDAs,
which are legally
binding and actionable
and preclude you
from discussing any
and all details
from the trip.
-Jesus.
-Ciao, amici.
♪ Spin me 'round ♪
♪ Now there must be something ♪
♪ In what they say
of all things ♪
♪ Great and small ♪
♪ There's a dozen roses ♪
Hey.
♪ Lying almost dying ♪
Oh, my God.
If it logs you out, sometimes
it just needs to be reset,
which we do
with the admin password.
That's the bank?
Yeah.
Everything -- It should be
normal stuff looking,
like, breathtaking.
Yeah.
♪ Spin me 'round ♪
Oh, my God.
The man himself.
I'm such --
I can't believe you're here.
I can't believe you are --
Can I take a picture with you?
Come over here.
Could you take a picture?
Let's go now.
Hurry up.
What are you doing here?
I've been thinking a lot
about what happened.
That was no way
to say goodbye.
Yeah.
Look, I feel terrible.
My friends and I have been
having those kind of parties
for so long,
maybe I took it for granted.
I always invite managers
from the group,
and whoever comes comes.
Yikes.
No.
No, I just really want everyone
to have a good time,
and I guess I thought you were
into that kind of thing
because of what
we talked about.
When I told you about
my experiences with group sex
and sustained bliss
from Tantric techniques
and asked if you were
into that kind of thing
and you said "yes"?
Oka--
So, wow.
I didn't ca-- That's --
I wondered why you said
"sustained bliss."
That -- I-I-I must
have zoned out.
Hmm.
But I don't think that excuses
all of your behavior.
Oh, no, no, no.
No, I agree.
I've done
regrettable things.
And after everything
that happened,
I've been doing
a lot of soul-searching,
and I've realized
that it's best for me --
and for others -- if I swear off
any kind of physical intimacy
with anyone for a while.
I'm celibate now.
Look, baby turtle,
meeting you
genuinely opened me up.
I can't believe you came all
this way to tell me that.
I really needed to see you
again.
That's wild.
I guess I was hoping you'd
take me up on my offer
to sail
the Amalfi Coast together --
as my primary.
I want to be
with you only.
♪♪
Come on, baby turtle.
Say "yes."
♪♪
I -- You know what?
I-I don't think so.
I --
I think it's actually
kind of inappropriate,
since you're my boss.
Is that why you kept telling me
not to tell anybody?
Okay.
Uh, you sure?
I'm sure.
I'm good here.
But, you know, I hope
you have a safe trip
back to wherever.
Um...
I got you something.
I-I don't want this.
I'm not your baby turtle.
I think you should go.
Wow.
Okay.
'Cause I-I thought
maybe --
Bye, Nick.
Go.
Get the fuck out of here!
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear Alex ♪
♪ Happy birthday -- ♪
♪♪
♪ I'm not in love ♪
♪ So don't forget it ♪
♪ It's just a silly phase
I'm going through ♪
♪ And just because ♪
♪ I call you up ♪
♪ Don't get me wrong,
don't think you've got it made ♪
♪ I'm not in love ♪
♪ No, no ♪
♪ It's because ♪
♪ I like to see you ♪
♪ But then again ♪
♪ That doesn't mean you mean
that much to me ♪
♪ So if I call you ♪
♪ Don't make a fuss ♪
♪ Don't tell your friends
about the two of us ♪
♪ I'm not in love ♪
♪ No, no ♪
♪ It's because ♪
♪♪