If you are lucky,
a dog will come into your life
steal your heart and change everything
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
[DOGS BARK IN PANIC]
[THE GODFATHER PLAYING ON TV]
Can't believe that I made it.
Can't believe that I
made it this far at all.
Didn't mean to, but I had to.
Now I've got to, I must keep running on.
Overnight, I'm free.
In the morning, who knows where I'll be.
Oh my, I'm a little scared, but I'm free!
Run, run, run, for your life.
Leave it all behind you and fly.
Fast as you can, girl, no holding back.
Run, run, run, don't be scared.
Everything around you is brand new,
so take it in.
Who knows what you'll find.
[WOMAN SHOO THE DOG]
It's so bright outside,
not like when I was tied up inside.
This is amazing!
Run, run, run, for your life.
Leave it all behind you and fly.
Fast as you can, girl, no holding back.
Run, run, run, don't be scared.
Everything around you
is brand new, so take it in.
Who knows what you'll find.
Ooooh... I can't believe that I'm free.
Can't believe that I
made it this far at all.
[PEOPLE WHO LITTER HERE ARE DOGS]
Now all I have to do is keep on going.
Just keep on going.
Overnight, I'm free.
[DOGS BARKING]
In the morning, who knows where I'll be.
Oh my! I'm a little scared, but I'm free!
Hey, dog... stop!
Finally, I'm free.
Now I'm free.
Who knows where I'll be
[Chinmaya Colony (R) Mysore]
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
[TV plays in the background.]
Before bad luck strikes,
it apparently gives one a preview.
I am Dharma.
I wake up before the alarm rings.
[ALARM RINGS]
Yet, it strikes everyday.
And I strike back.
My mother would always say...
[ASTROLOGER ON TV] What you dream of at dawn,
comes true. Always.
In my opinion, I'm right.
It's people's perception of me that is wrong.
[PHONE RINGS]
[ Dharma] Hello.
[TELEMARKETER] Hello sir.
I'm calling from Spencer 4G Company.
We have some new
Internet offers on 4G. Can I..
[ Dharma] I already have it.
[Gate latch creaks]
[ONE MAN'S TRASH IS ANOTHER MAN'S TREASURE]
Damn! Flat tyre again!
What's up Krupakar sir?
Looks like there was trouble
at home last evening?
When you have a family,
these things are common. Isn't it?
The only way to be trouble free
is to lead a lonely existence.
Does he have a problem
because I have an easy life?
Or does he have a problem
because he has a family?
I still haven't understood.
Not because I'm incapable of it.
I just don't have the time.
I don't usually mingle with people.
Yet, there are always people behind me.
Dharma...
This is Uttam. Uttam, meet Mr. Dharma.
You'll be under him for training.
He is our best employee, okay?
Dharma, what will you start training him in?
I'll begin with training
him in punctuality.
Ah! Get used to Dharma, okay? All the best.
Sir, I had a flat tyre on the way here.
Nobody offered me a ride.
An idiot even showed me the finger!
My situation...
What? Him? Really?
How will you ever learn under him?
Why? Isn't that possible?
Murali sir said he is the best employee.
Just because he never takes leave and works 365 days,
he becomes the best employee?
No wife or kids. Never entertains anybody.
If not the factory,
where else will he go?
If he had a family,
he'd have known the reality.
Best employee, my foot!
Looks like they aren't
the best of friends. Right?
He has no friends here.
Quoting him as an example,
Krupakar's promotion has been
overdue since 3 years
That's why he's jealous of Dharma.
Like I said,
there are people behind me.
Always.
Only to speak ill of me.
[GRANDPA] Look Dharma is here.
[BATANI] Don't bother grandpa!
[GRANDPA] Hey Batani, you don't get it!
He's been absolutely useless!
Let him at least do this.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Hey Dharma!
Aren't you too from this colony?
Some idiot is distributing
TV sets in our colony ground!
How can I teach music
with his voice blaring on the speaker!
He is holding an orchestra
this evening. Come with us.
I have no interest in coming with you.
Hey! I'm not asking you
to attend the orchestra.
I'm asking you to join
us in confronting him.
Come, let's go thrash him!
[DOOR SLAMS]
[OPENS BEER BOTTLE]
When someone asks for my help,
I never send them empty handed.
I always give them an earful.
Aren't I leading a happy life
without anybody's help?
I am content.
[FIREWORKS]
[DOG BARKS]
[AN ORCHESTRA IN PROGRESS]
[PEOPLE SHOUT IN PANIC]
Get lost!
Ah!
Please come with us brother.
I don't want to, you carry on.
He is refusing to wake up mom!
Don't you know he doesn't want to come?
You get ready.
Have you taken all the
musical instruments dear?
[DHARMA'S FATHER] I have.
Dharani, please keep this in the car.
[COME SOON DEAR.
LOOKS LIKE IT'S GOING TO RAIN.]
I'm coming!
Dharma, I' ve kept breakfast
on the table. Have it soon.
Okay mom.
And don't drink cold water.
There's a flask of hot water for you.
Okay!
[SHARADA, HOW MUCH LONGER?]
I'm coming!
Don't forget to turn off
the TV when it thunders.
Come.
Brother! We'll have ice-cream on our way.
But we won't bring you any.
Bye!
[WAKES UP STARTLED]
Why have the kids littered all over?
It's not the kids.
It's the handiwork of a stray dog.
Oh god! Look at the mess it's created!
- [ADRIKA] Hey Rajat! I'm here!
- [ADRIKA'S MOTHER] Adi...
[BIKE APPROACHES]
[ADRIKA'S MOTHER] Come.
Have it.
No.
Adi, you better eat.
If not, Hitler uncle will take you.
[CHARLIE CHAPLIN'S SONG PLAYS]
[DHARMA HUMMING]
[TELEMARKETER] Hello sir.
I'm calling from Spencer 4G Company
[WE HAVE SOME NEW INTERNET OFFERS ON 4G.]
[LADY 1] Shantamma, my son passed his exams
only because of my prayers
[LADY 2] The Lord always gives
when you ask him earnestly.
What's the big deal about God
giving you something after asking for it?
There's no need to go begging to him.
After snatching everything,
how will he give it back?
[OLD MAN PRAYING]
Grandma, when your son calls from America,
ask him to send you a phone.
I'm sick of repairing this coin phone.
Yeah sure.
He doesn't have the
time to call his parents,
But I bet he will send us a phone!
Don't mind him.
Is it okay now?
Yes
Give me a pack of cigarettes.
Why son? Haven't you
seen the picture on the pack?
I asked you for a cigarette.
Not advice. Give me two idlis.
Do you intend to shut shop?
Shut up and give him what he wants.
My boy, stop arguing with my wife everyday.
Get married, you can argue with your wife.
Make it quick.
Wait son. I'll give you hot ones.
Dharma sir, are you
going to the bhajan tonight?
I want only two idlis.
[GATE CREAKS]
Good morning, sir
Only two idlis.
Sure son.
Home. Factory. Fights.
Idli. Cigarette. Beer.
That's what my life is all about.
Nothing interesting.
[CHARLIE CHAPLIN EPISODE ON TV]
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
Let's go faster.
Dharma is alone at home.
Damn these rains!
He'll be watching TV. Don't worry.
How is the ice-cream sweety?
Nice pappa!
We have 5 ice-creams.
One for you, one for my brother.
None for pappa.
And 3 for me, okay?
Promise?
Yes
Say it loud!
Promise...
[WAKES UP STARTLED]
[DOG WHINING]
Get lost!
Newspaper!
Out!
Uncle...
Ball.
[KID CRIES]
[BOY] Come let's go tell dad that
Hitler uncle burnt the ball.
[NARAYANA RAO HUMMING]
Hey Dharma,
there's warm breakfast at home. Come eat.
There's no greater tragedy than not finding
food when you're hungry.
Didn't I tell you about the
tragedy of not finding food?
Now there's a greater
tragedy that awaits me.
Why the hell is this dog following me?
If it comes inside the house,
I will not spare it!
[BIKE CRASHES]
[DOG SQUEALS IN PAIN]
[PAINFUL MOANS]
[LADY 1] Oh god!
Vicky has hurt himself!
[LADY 2] Come quickly!
[MAN] What happened Vicky?
[CHARLIE CHAPLIN VIDEO PLAYS]
[MURALI] Bikes are to
be rode on two wheels.
[VICKY] Yes, because it
has only two wheels uncle!
Exactly. Ride it on both wheels.
So if you do wheeling,
this is what happens.
Why are you scolding my son for it?
It's all this dog's fault!
[MAN] Okay. Should we
take him to the hospital?
[VICKY] No uncle.
Stray dogs have become a menace!
[LADY 1] This dog has
made a mess of this place.
[LADY 2] Yes.
[LADY 1] This was well deserved.
The kids always play here.
What if it had bitten them?
Call the civic authorities,
they'll take this dog away.
Let's go.
The dog is still breathing. Damn it.
Why are you taking it, son?
The local authorities will do it.
[KRUPAKAR] Let him take it.
[ADRIKA] Let's please take it
to the hospital. Please dad.
[ADRIKA'S MOM] Keep quiet!
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Let's go in.
[COMPOUNDER] Give a dose each
in the morning, noon and night.
- And this syrup twice a day.
- [LADY] Okay.
Bathe the dog with this shampoo
for silky, smooth fur.
[DR. ASHWIN] Today's generation are blind
when they're riding.
My boy, at least you should've been alert.
Always look to your left and right
when you cross the road.
[COMPOUNDER] Sir, he's here.
This guy?
Tell him I don't want to talk to him.
Not a word.
Sir, he doesn't want to speak to you.
He's angry.
Why should I?
He can't look after such a nice dog?
He only wants to show off!
This dog isn't mine.
What?
Lying to me?
I can identify the owner
just by looking at the dog.
Do you know how many
years of experience I have?
He doesn't know of my expertise!
I'll give it an injection.
And my job is done.
[CAJOLES THE DOG]
[DOG YELPS]
Look at how scared it is of the needle!
Has it been injected before?
Don't you get it?
This dog is not mine.
Nothing to worry.
The pictures have turned out great, right?
I have this thing for animals...
What is it called again?
Madness.
Ha
No
Passion
I'm just like you!
I can't bear to see any
animal suffering on the road.
I bring it here and treat it.
By the way, which road did I find you in?
Tablets.
He's irked!
Let's get to business now.
Give these tablets thrice a day.
Your dog will be fine in no time.
Hold on.
Didn't I tell you it's not mine?
What's the fee? I'm off.
What about the dog?
Keep it here with you.
How?
I'm unable to handle our own.
If the owner gets to know
I've got another dog, he'll kick up a fuss.
Sir
Try and understand
I can't look after it.
Why? Are you scared of dogs?
Doctor, looks like he has cynophobia.
Your brother-in-law had the same problem.
[DR. ASHWIN IN HIS NATIVE TONGUE]
Who is the doctor? You or me?
You.
Then shut up, will you?
Do one thing. Take the dog with you.
I get a lot of calls for adoption.
I'll set one up for you.
Just four days.
Dogs are not allowed in our colony.
What if someone gets to know?
How will anyone get to know
if you hide this pup in your home?
Then why don't you do it?
Hide it here.
And don't let the owner find out.
No way. It won't work.
He'll definitely get to know.
He is the owner.
[IN HIS NATIVE TONGUE] Did he ask you that?
Can't you shut up?
So what do we do now?
Abandon it on the street?
What if it dies under a vehicle?
Won't your good deed get wasted?
Just four days. That's all.
Give me your number now.
The good deed and the dog.
Keep them both.
[PETS NOT ALLOWED]
[MANJU] What do you take me for? A joker?
[KRUPAKAR] Please don't shout.
I'm due for a promotion.
[MANJU & KRUPAKAR'S ARGUMENT CONTINUES]
Puppy!
Okay!
[TV COMMERCIAL OF AN ICE-CREAM PLAYS]
Hey.. Shush!
Dharma was living a carefree life
But then came this spoiler
A barking drama
Causing inner fear
Everyone usually allow ants
unknowingly into their surroundings
Here this person allowed in a dog
that was wandering on the streets.
He is single and a recluse
Too rough with a very short fuse.
Repeat
Hi
What?
Puppy!
The puppy was in the park!
Really?
Yes!
It's still there, right?
Then?
It's here!
What can you do if your fate is twisted?
Even a dog can become your enemy
I have put up the dog on OLX for free
I'm done with feeding this dog
Tending it and fostering it round the clock
Oh god, this is such a notorious dog
Please save me my lord!
Repeat
Go in!
Uncle...
Ball.
Don't tell anybody that there's a dog here.
[NODS]
[NARAYAN RAO] What
are you kids doing there?
[KIDS] Nothing much.
Uncle's dog snatched our ball.
[NARAYAN RAO] A dog?
Despite tying a stick to the tail
it's still crooked.
Right now, I am the one feeling sour
A tail to wag, a mouth to create ruckus
A torture so impossible to bear
What do I do, I'm exasperated
I think, I am down with fever
This dog got me all weak and tired.
Ouch!
Yes, Dharma
Sir
You promised to find a home for the dog in 4 days.
It's been 2 weeks now.
Please find a solution soon.
I can't bear this torture!
Sure! By the way, give it good food.
The dog looks damn weak.
Only good-looking dogs get adopted.
Okay sir
[TV COMMERCIAL OF AN ICE-CREAM PLAYS]
Look this side!
Look how pretty she looks!
Now watch people queue up to adopt her!
Look!
She is a female dog. Be careful.
In addition to finding her a home,
we'll have to accommodate her pups, too.
Yes sir? Did you find her a home?
Of course! When I'm here, why fear!
At 4 pm today,
the interested party will meet you.
Okay sir.
Whatsapp your address.
[DHARMA] I will text you.
What is this Uttam?
How can you leave so early?
Learn from Dharma.
He has never asked for leave.
Nor has he asked to go home early.
[DHARMA] Murali sir,
I'm going home early today. Bye.
[DOOR BELL RINGS]
[A POPULAR KANNADA MOVIE DIALOGUE PLAYS]
[DOOR BELL CONTINUES TO RING]
[DOOR SWINGS OPEN]
- [BOY CRYING] Mummy!
- Ma'am, it's not the dog's fault.
It is a trained dog.
- Hey boy, don't you want the dog?
- I do!
Why do you need the dog
when we have your dad at home?
Poor boy wants the dog...
- Ma'am please.
- I want the dog!
Get inside the car.
Ma'am, it's not the dog's fault.
It is well trained.
Ma'am please!
[MAN 1] Looks like he has guests.
[MAN 2] How does that matter?
He'll get a fitting lesson.
[LADY 1] How dare he!
[BATANI] Even if he shouts,
we're not scared of him.
[I DIDN'T WANT TO GET INTO A FIGHT
TO MAINTAIN PEACE IN THE COLONY.]
[BUT TODAY, I'LL SHOW HIM MY TRUE COLOURS]
[LADY 1] Sure, let's see
[MAN 2] Call him out.
[LADY 2] Hello, excuse me!
Don't you know pets aren't allowed here?
You insist on following rules for all else.
[KRUPAKAR] It doesn't apply only to us.
It is for your dog and you as well.
[MAN 2] Acting smart with us?
If the cat shuts its eye and drinks milk,
you think nobody will know it?
[KRUPAKAR] How dare you keep a pet?
This is what happens when wayward
people like him live in this colony.
God alone knows what else he's up to?
[LADY 2] Look at the
way he's glaring at us!
[LADY 1] To hell with his glares!
Kids play here.
Imagine having a dog in the same place!
[KRUPAKAR] Why did you even bring it here?
You better get rid of it.
Or else, we'll have to throw you out.
[LOUD CLANG OF METAL]
This is my house.
I will live here.
This is my dog.
It will live here, too.
Let me see which b#st@%d
has the guts to throw us out.
Damn, I think I forgot to turn off the gas.
- [LADY 3] Let's go.
- [KRUPAKAR] I didn't get scared at all
- [KRUPAKAR WIFE]Let's go.
- [KRUPAKAR]Leave me.
- Hello. Did you arrive?
- I'm coming
Hey you.
Me?
If I see you wheeling on this road,
I'll pluck the parts
out and hand it to you.
Not of the bike, but of your body.
[KEATON]
You think I'm jobless?
I'm a dog doctor. Not a dog broker.
I didn't mean that.
But please understand my situation.
Okay, I'll put up a post on Facebook.
Send me the dog's
license number immediately.
License?
[TURNS OFF THE TV]
I haven't got it done.
You don't have one? Then do it right now.
If you have a license,
adoption gets easier.
Okay sir. Where do I get it done?
[DOG LICENSE CAMP 2020]
[KEMPRAJU] Next
Come Pammi.
Hi...
- [DEVIKA] Name?
- Pammi
What do you feed her?
Pedigree and milk. And fruits at night.
Good. Is she trained?
The milk she drinks is fetched by her!
Well groomed.
[LADY] My sugar plum!
- What happened sweety? Are you hungry?
- [BOY CRYING]
Mummy! Come soon. I'm hungry.
What's your problem?
- Not you sweety. Relax.
- [KEMPRAJU] Next.
Name?
Dharma.
Not yours. The dog's.
What do you call it?
[CLICKING OF THE TONGUE IN THE BACKGROUND]
[CLICKS TONGUE]
Sorry?
Its name is...[CLICKS TONGUE]
Really?
That's how I call it. Write it now.
Hmmm.
What do you feed it?
Idli.
What?
Only idli?
No, I give it chutney, too.
Look. Dogs have a special diet.
You should stick to that.
And maintain its hygiene, too.
So, take this.
Dog Essential Care Guide.
It mentions how to take care of one's pet.
You need it.
Don't teach me how to take care of my pet.
Keep that book with you.
Let's get down to business.
Give me the license.
[LICENSE NO: 0777]
[KEMPRAJU] Next...
[THROWS THE BOOK IN THE BIN]
Tell me.
Hi.
Hi. Can we come in?
No.
Hello, Mr. Dharma! Excuse me.
My name is Devika.
- Kempraju
- Pragati
We are from the Animal Welfare Board.
We've got a complaint that
your dog isn't being looked after well.
Who filed it?
She did.
Are you joking?
First you complain and
then come to check on me?
We have the authority.
So, can we come in?
Cigarette is harmful for dogs.
The dog doesn't smoke. I do.
Smoking is injurious to health.
Anybody's health.
Come to the point.
[CLICKS TONGUE]
Not you. Your dog. Where is it?
Hey dog!
Not you. My dog.
So, why is there only
one fish in the aquarium?
There were three. Now there's only one.
Animal cruelty is a punishable of fence.
The other day we caught an offender.
He was sentenced to 4 years in prison.
4 years.
But don't worry.
I'd like you to be well
informed, that's all.
What to do?
It's my job.
I have to do it.
[DEVIKA] Kempraju,
check if the dog is healthy.
Okay ma'am.
Hello Chu Chu!
Help! It'll bite me!
It's an extremely healthy dog ma'am!
Please call it sir! It'll bite me!
Sir! Please call it!
Oh god!
Your dog is really sharp!
Anyway, the Pedigree is over.
Buy a new one.
You eat the idlis.
Keep the cigarettes away from the dog.
So, we're off. For now.
Bye.
Dharma!
Yes, Dharma! All well?
You have two days.
Find someone by then.
If not, I'll plonk him on your desk.
Oh come on! This job
is snap of a finger for me!
What! He cut the call?
[MANJU] Don't say you want more time!
I can't wait any longer.
[KRUPAKAR] Don't create a fuss everyday.
You both go inside.
I need my money back!
I'm saying I have no money.
What are you saying?
I didn't borrow it for gambling, okay?
I'll give it when I get the promotion.
[MANJU] I can't wait that long.
[KRUPAKAR] Then I can't give it to you.
- [MANJU] If you don't, I won't budge from here.
- [KRUPAKAR] Do as you please.
Hey dog!
Come here!
What are you staring at?
Will you come or should I bash you up?
No, I'll leave.
So you've hired people to bash me up, huh?
I'll fetch the police.
I am not a coward.
Is there no one from the patient's family?
Coming right behind us.
Hey.. Hey..
[SECURITY GUARD] Hey dog!
Somebody catch it...
ECG is normal.
It's just a panic attack that you had.
Do you have anxiety issues?
Okay. Do you smoke?
[DOCTOR] Who the hell let that dog in?
Sir, it came running behind the ambulance.
[CHARLIE CHAPLIN: I'M SORRY, I DON'T WANT
TO BE AN EMPEROR.]
[THAT IS NOT MY BUSINESS.]
[I DON'T WANT TO RULE OR CONQUER ANYONE.]
[I SHALL LIKE TO HELP
EVERYONE IF POSSIBLE.]
[WE THINK TOO MUCH AND FEEL TOO LITTLE.]
[MORE THAN MACHINERY, WE NEED HUMANITY.]
[MORE THAN CLEVERNESS,
WE NEED KINDNESS AND GENTLENESS.]
[WITHOUT THESE QUALITIES,
LIFE WILL BE VIOLENT.]
[AND ALL WILL BE LOST.]
[TV COMMERCIAL OF AN ICE-CREAM PLAYS]
[DR. ASHWIN] Thank god you're at home!
Why can't you answer the phone?
I tried calling you so many times!
What are all these?
Feels like I've come to a bar.
What brings you here, sir?
What do you mean?
Didn't you call and blast me the other day?
That's why I've decided to
reduce your tension today.
[WHISTLES]
Come, come kids
Come
Who are these people, sir?
They're here to adopt the dog. What else?
Ma'am come. Sir, you too!
Please come in.
Come in.
That's the dog!
[IN HIS NATIVE TONGUE]
I want to kill this guy!
Ma'am, here. Take it for a trial.
- [KID 1] Give it to me
- [DR. ASHWIN] This way ma'am.
- [KID 2] I want to go first.
- [KID 1] No, I want to!
[COMPOUNDER] Careful kids.
Be gentle with the dog.
- [KID 1] Come here.
- [KID 2] Hey cutie. Come, come!
Don't be scared, come.
[KID 1] Come.
It looks so cute!
[KID 1] Yes.
Uncle, have you named it?
No, it's a new dog.
Name it once you take it home.
Hmmm.
Mom, I want a black dog.
Don't kid. It's easier to spot the dirt
in a black dog.
[KID 3] But I want one...
That's true
Has the dog been potty trained?
Of course!
It even flushes after doing its job!
[LADY] Hello... hi...!
Sir, I need to have a word with you.
What's the matter?
He's just concerned because
he's been with the dog so long.
Obviously, he'll miss it.
Don't worry. I think the kids
are already in love with the dog.
Happy? I'll leave now.
He will transfer the
license documents to you.
[LADY] Okay.
Let's go ma'am.
Drink little one...
Take son...
What happened son? You seem to be upset.
What nonsense is this! Brainless...
[DOG BARKING ON TV]
Don't keep barking...
Go eat your idli.
Doggy?
Is it sleeping?
Once it wakes up, please show this picture
and say Adrika made it.
Uncle, why don't you ever smile?
[ADRIKA'S MOTHER] Adrika!
Okay uncle, see you tomorrow. Bye.
[DR. ASHWIN] How long does it
take for you to transfer the license?
I'll get it done, sir.
No use of that now.
They've got the forms home already.
Take the documents and sign it for them.
Don't ruin my reputation.
That lady is repeatedly calling me saying
that the dog doesn't flush after its potty.
I'll send the address. Please go.
[SHANTI NIVASA - PEACEFUL HOUSE]
Come out! Now!
Mom, I want a black dog.
Shut up now!
The wind whispers something.
The world seems lively now!
There's a spring in the step,
in this new course of life.
Be with me, don't go anywhere.
Be around me... joyous as always.
In the path of life,
I have found a new turning point.
Join me in this journey and hug me tight.
Got a new dog son?
Adorable!
What have you named it?
Our path crosses again.
Like we were meant to be.
Now on, my routine shall be new.
Charlie!
I'll say without a doubt
that you're my best friend.
Charlie!
I'm reborn now and
you're the reason for it.
Charlie!
You're the sole focus of my life.
Charlie... Charlie!
Uncle, what are you up to?
- Surprise
- [ADRIKA'S MOTHER] Adi, don't be late.
Yes mom, I'm coming.
Oh Charlie!
In this journey,
you motivate me to proceed further.
I will never forget the
blows you've received.
Good morning Uttam.
- Good morning sir.
- Sit down.
I've collected every memory,
and preserved it in my pocket.
Dharma sir has changed so much!
Yet, there's so much to say.
Our emotions speak more than words.
Oh Charlie!
Oh Charlie, ask me a thousand times,
And I will say without a doubt,
you're my best friend forever.
Charlie!
I'm reborn now.
And you're the reason for it.
Charlie!
You're the sole focus of my life.
Charlie...
[ICE-CREAM COMMERCIAL PLAYS ON TV]
Hey.
Jumping in front of the TV
won't fetch you ice cream.
It's in the fridge, take it.
Now on, my routine shall be new.
I'll say without a doubt,
that you're my best friend.
Take.
I have quit smoking.
Huh?
I'm reborn now.
And you're the reason for it.
Charlie.
Ready?
You're the sole focus of my life.
Smile.
Charlie!
Sit! Charlie sit.
Sit, or else I won't give you this.
Charlie, please repeat the 'thanks'
what you showed me a while ago.
Uncle, I taught Charlie
the 'thanks' gesture.
Really?
Charlie, come here.
Uncle come. Quick.
Okay.
Charlie, show him...
Charlie do the 'thanks' gesture.
She did it a while ago uncle.
Charlie, please fold your hands and
show him what you did a while ago.
I promise she did it, uncle.
Please do it Charlie...
Adi, looks like Charlie is tired.
She'll do it later.
No uncle. She did it some time ago.
Please Charlie... show him.
If Charlie doesn't gesture 'thanks',
let's not give her the ice-cream.
Okay forget it! I'm leaving.
All you do is eat and sleep.
Can you do anything else?
Poor kid. She was in tears.
Take the helmet and ride by yourself.
Okay. Show Adrika what you've learnt
when she comes tomorrow.
Understood?
I'll be back home soon today.
I have a surprise for you this evening.
What's this new trick now? Move it!
Oh yeah! Charlie fetch!
Okay then...
I'll take you for a ride in the evening.
Okay? Bye.
[MANJU] You keep asking me to come to various places.
You take me for a cab?
- I'll thrash you!
- Please...
[MURALI SIR] Dharma, here's the
promotion list of your department.
Let me know who is eligible.
Okay sir.
[MURALI] I'll ask them to load it.
Sir.
Done? Okay.
Nothing is permanent in this wicked world.
Not even our troubles.
[COLLEAGUE] So Kruparkar has finally
got his promotion! Congratulations!
[DHARMA'S VOICEOVER]
Charlie Chaplin is right.
I had a limited view of life.
But Charlie came along and
changed it.
What happened? Still angry?
The house is full of paw prints.
Go to Adrika's house for a few days.
I'll begin painting the
house from tomorrow.
Hey! Why haven't you eaten anything?
Oh yeah?
Now?
Charlie.
Sorry doctor. I left the ball with Charlie.
I'll ensure it doesn't happen again.
Dharma, this isn't because
she swallowed the ball.
Okay. Then?
She has Hemangiosarcoma.
I hope there's no problem.
Please give her some medication.
I will. But it won't suffice.
Do you have to operate on her?
Dharma, she has cancer.
She has clots in her veins.
I suspected this when I saw her.
Blood test, CT scan is all done.
It's confirmed she has cancer.
But I've looked after her well, doctor.
How can she get cancer?
Like you suggested,
she's even got all her vaccinations.
You've looked after her well.
But that's not it.
I feel this is genetic mutation.
Some breeders mate
siblings and this happens.
This is called inbreeding.
Some breeders will do anything for money.
I found her on the road, doctor.
I didn't buy her from a breeder.
I agree. But you found a lost dog.
How else will you find
a labrador on the street?
I'll prescribe some medicines.
Take care of her.
[DR. ASHWIN] I know you're hurt.
But she's in pain, too. Remember that.
Dharma!
How much time does she have doctor?
Can't say Dharma.
She's in her final stage.
You can get chemotherapy done.
But you'd rather have her living a short
and sweet life than a long and painful one.
Happiness heals pain, they say.
Charlie has been my healing happiness.
But where do I seek the
happiness that will heal her pain?
[FILM SHOWCASING SNOW PLAYS]
SNOW!
I kept thinking that it was
the ice-cream that excited her.
Snow...
How do I bid farewell to you?
You're the apple of my eye.
You, who came to teach
me the meaning of love,
have become a piece of my own heart.
You have written the
foreword to a new journey.
Let's go Charlie.
Having lit up my life,
you've chosen to embrace the dark.
My past and my future is you my friend.
You are like a flower
entangled in a whirlpool.
How do I tolerate this pain?
Stuck in the clutches of time,
and endless pain.
Uncle, when will you both return?
As soon as possible.
Okay, come soon. I'll miss you guys.
Don't let Charlie play in the water.
She'll catch a cold.
Please bring Charlie back in time
for my fancy dress competition.
I'm going dressed as Charlie Chaplin.
Don't tell Charlie, it's a surprise.
Uncle...
She did the 'thanks' gesture the other day.
It's all right now.
No, it's not. Give it to me.
No way! What do you know?
I'm the one using it. I know...
It's nice.
Please keep your foot firmly.
Yes, I have - [CHARLIE BARKS]
Ah! Son!
When did you come?
New one. Got it from the city. Nice?
Conversations in silence convey
emotions far more powerful than words.
The bond that binds us as one,
goes beyond this lifetime.
A life that's writhing in pain.
How are you even handling this suffering?
The silent tears you shed,
have dried up without a trace.
You complete all my
yesterdays and tomorrows.
Oh god!
Come Charlie.
Dharma...
Sir...
The first time you brought Charlie to me,
she was petrified of the injection. Remember?
Yes...
Wait, let me share a video with
you on Whatsapp. Watch it right now.
[VIDEO ON PHONE]
[HEY COME ON KEATON.]
[COME ON!]
[THIS IS GOING TO BE FUN.]
[ARE YOU SCARED?]
[DR. ASHWIN] She's so scared of needles!
Has she been injected before this?
[VIDEO ON PHONE]
[YOU NAUGHTY BITCH!]
[YOU THINK YOU CAN ESCAPE FROM ME?
HUH? NO. NEVER.]
[NOW SEE WHAT I DO TO YOU.]
[VICIOUS LAUGH]
[NOW TASTE THIS CIGARETTE.]
[STUBS CIGARETTE ON THE PUPPY.]
[PUPPY MOANING IN PAIN.]
Keaton!
[DR. ASHWIN] I've got his address.
I will file a complaint with the police.
If you can, go say 'hi' to him.
Say it with a punch, okay?
[DOGS BARKING.]
[BELL RINGING.]
Who are you?
What do you want?
Do you have a spade?
What?
A pick axe?
[ANGRY BARKS]
I will do the talking. You keep quiet.
Do you remember her?
Keaton.
Syringe.
Cigarette.
[DHARMA] Sir, my job here is done.
He's safe here.
Go ahead and file the complaint.
Charlie!
Every dog has its day.
Today is Charlie's.
Didn't he mention where he's off to?
He doesn't bother
telling us all that. Moron!
Did he look after the dog well?
Would a man who tortures humans,
treat his dog well?
I pity that dog.
Wonder how it lived with him...
I always had my doubts about him.
Yes! He always tortured it.
You're showing so much
concern about the dog.
But there's a 'pets not
allowed' board outside.
Yes. But not anymore.
The rules have changed. I got it done.
We need pet lovers like you.
We have many rescue dogs.
You must adopt one.
Give me your number.
Sure! Next time.
I have to get my bike serviced.
[VICKY] Don't bother with that moron ma'am!
Vijayapura.
Hello ma'am. I've stepped out for a bit.
Is that so? Share the location.
I'll go right away.
Okay.
Same location!
[BREEDER] Hey let me go!
[BREEDER] Don't mess with me!
[BREEDER] You will pay for it!
[PRAGATI] Has it been given first aid, sir?
[BREEDER] Let me go!
[PRAGATI] Ma'am is here.
Hi ma'am.
How many dogs are here?
115 ma'am.
And puppies?
77.
Have you got their pictures?
Yes.
[GRUNTS]
Pictures?
I have them here.
Where is he off to?
[DEVIKA] Another criminal
has fled from the scene.
I will follow him.
[DEVIKA] I will share
the location, come there.
Okay ma'am.
As we journey on my bike,
with you my beloved companion.
In the intoxicating breeze,
let's spread our wings and fly.
Does a road without hurdles ever exist?
With you as my beloved companion,
let's spread our wings and fly.
Why didn't you tell me earlier
that the battery is empty?
[KEMPRAJU: I THOUGHT YOU'LL FIGURE WHEN
IT RUNS OUT OF CHARGE.]
My foot! I've shared the location with you
Go to hell!
[KEMPRAJU: OKAY MA'AM.]
Hi.
Do you have rooms?
Yes. Single or double?
We do sir, but...
Pets not allowed sir.
[HOTEL RECEPTIONIST] But if the dog barks,
it will disturb our guests.
Don't worry. She never barks.
[BARKS]
[YOU CAN KEEP YOUR TRUST IN US.
AND WE SHALL KEEP YOU ON THE RIGHT PATH]
[HOTEL RECEPTIONIST]
Excuse me sir?
Sir
Sorry sir, pets not allowed.
She's like a pair of eyes for me.
I can't budge without her.
Sorry sir. Hotel rules.
Sir, just imagine. A blind man. In this dark hour.
Where will he even go?
No mom. The office must
have booked a nice room...
Hotel Narayana!
As we journey on my bike,
with you as my beloved companion.
In the intoxicating breeze,
let's spread our wings and fly.
In search of my soul,
the path I've taken has been filled
by silence and loneliness.
Tired of being caged,
my spirit craves the
freedom of a flowing river.
Excuse me. Did someone by the name
Dharma check in here last night?
Yes ma'am. The blind man.
He had come with his dog.
Blind?
Yes.
Yes, blind.
Can you charge my mobile please?
Stay here. I'll be back.
For every small ripple of joy,
The heart rejoices like a child.
Hey Charlie!
Charlie! Stop!
Charlie!
Charlie...
Don't run. Wait!
Charlie!
Stay right there.
Charlie, stay.
Charlie...
[GLASS SHATTERS]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
I had never been to a police station.
You gave me that privilege, too.
Poor dog, sir. She's done it unknowingly
and you put her behind bars?
An owner should be responbile for his dog.
Ask him to give 10,000 bucks.
Okay sir.
[CONSTABLE] If you don't have cash,
then rot in there.
Okay, here take a look.
[BARKS]
I have only two thousand bucks.
I have to reach Himachal with this amount.
[CONSTABLE] Himachal?
This won't suffice even for the fuel.
This is all I have.
This amount won't do for us.
[DHARMA] Please understand, sir...
Sir, I want to file a complaint.
Tell me.
That dog is mine.
What?
The dog in the lock up is mine.
He's stolen it from me.
Oh!
Sir, he has only two thousand bucks.
It's okay. The dog's owner is here.
She will pay the rest of it. Isn't it dear?
Me?
Yes.
Why sir?
Your dog has broken the
windshield of our jeep. That's why.
Hey, let him go.
[CONSTABLE] Okay sir.
Sir, I'll give you the two thousand bucks.
But please don't release him.
Do you take this for a lodge to take
money and keep him inside?
Take his signature and release him.
Okay sir.
Pay up the money and take the dog.
Sir, you can't let him go.
I am an Animal Welfare Officer.
I have proof. This fellow...
[CONSTABLE] Ma'am, here's your dog.
Sir, this fellow is torturing the dog.
He's also partnered with a criminal
and is running an illegal breeding centre.
According to IPC 428 and 429, it's an of fence
to kill or hurt any animal including a stray dog.
This fellow and his boss have
been torturing so many animals.
It has all been captured on CCTV.
I will submit evidence.
You can't let him go
in exchange for money.
Don't release him until my team comes.
If you do that, I'll have to
take strict action against you.
Pay up and take your damn dog away!
What are you feeding her?
Get down.
Until my team comes, I will stay with her.
Get down right away.
You think I don't know
the sort of person you are?
I know where you're taking her...
[POLICE: BOTH OF YOU LEAVE
OR I'LL PUT YOU IN THE LOCK UP]
My lover is in my heart.
Lord Ram is in my heart.
Oh where, oh where
Where should I go to find you?
My lover is still in my heart..
I've seen Lord Brahma, seen Lord Vishnu
Don't bark! I'm here to save you.
I have seen Goddess Saraswati
My lover is in my heart.
Charlie...
I've been working for four years.
Just because you change her name,
you think I won't get to know?
On top of it, that blind
man act at the hotel.
That bald breeder is your boss, right?
Look. How cute she is!
How can you torture this poor soul?
I've never seen a zoo sadist like you!
Who said I torture her?
I mean...
[PHONE RINGS]
Wait.
[KEMPARAJU ON PHONE] Pragati, looks
like the rescuer has to be rescued!
Aye!
[KEMPRAJU] We've checked the CCTV footage.
Wait...
Tell me now.
[KEMPRAJU] Ma'am, it was Dharma
who thrashed the breeder like a hero!
Didn't I tell you he's a nice man?
Come back now.
Such a waste to have gone all the way...
Come Charlie...
Thank you for saving all those dogs.
I'm going back tomorrow.
I came here in a hurry without
even informing my mom.
I'd appreciate if you could
drop me to the airport.
You can go and sleep inside.
Thanks.
[KEMPRAJU] Ma'am, the direct flight
is only available tomorrow evening.
Shall I book it for you?
Okay.
She follows you everywhere!
That's how she is.
She doesn't believe strangers.
I've been to Ladakh.
On the bullet. That too, a solo ride.
So, how far are you planning to ride?
Hey, where to?
[EXCITED BARKS]
Excuse me sir.
Yes?
Can you take my dog for paragliding?
Dog? No.
Who takes the dog on paragliding?
Hi sir.
Yes madam!
She can. But the rule says
someone must accompany her.
They have a team.
Let one of them go with her.
One of us, is what he says.
Why don't you go?
Me? I can't.
Why? Scared?
No. I'm not interested, that's all.
Why don't you go?
Charlie will be happy, too.
Charlie doesn't trust strangers.
So you go. All will be well.
[EXCITED BARKS]
I'm focused.
I've been watching for the omens.
I've been listening to
everything you've said,
It's been running through my head
locked and loaded.
I've got the feeling that you've noticed.
Yeah I've only just begun
I won't stop until it's done
Till you're broken.
So welcome to the fire!
I'm the one who lit the night up.
See them running through your fame,
As we're walking through the flames,
getting higher!
So welcome to the fire!
Welcome to the fire!
See them running through your fame,
as we're walking through the flames,
getting higher!
So welcome to the fire!
I've been waiting for this moment.
The final battle of the chosen.
See I'm never gonna quit.
Got my legacy set in motion.
So welcome to the fire!
Welcome to the fire!
Charlie!
See them running through your fame,
as we're walking through the flames,
getting higher!
Welcome to the fire...
Welcome to the fire.
Someone was on Cloud 9 along with Charlie!
Can I tell you something?
The positons dogs sleep in
reveal a lot about their feelings.
They sleep like this only when they
feel safe and are attached to someone.
She trusts you a lot.
I'm so happy to be part of this event.
See you soon.
Charlie. From tomorrow,
the side cars is entirely yours.
What happened?
Wait, I'm coming.
Leave it.
How many times have I told you
not to roll in the mud...
Let's go? I have to be
at the airport by 7 pm.
[DEVIKA] Oh my god!
Are you crazy! Why don't you
keep a tab on these things? Move it.
It's a skin infection. It's dangerous.
Why have a dog if
you can't take care of it?
Poor Charlie...
This looks bad.
Cigarette.
Wait, I'll be back.
Lend your ear.
Let's spend some moments in happiness.
Hey... This gift of nature you and I have.
I've missed my flight mom.
Okay.
Do come. Come let's enjoy.
[ADRIKA MOM CALLING]
Do come.
Let's forget the burden of sorrows for now.
These flowing winds that come and go.
It's not just you whose luck is such;
Everyone has to face this.
I thought she was excited about ice-cream.
I realised it later it was the snow
that excited her.
Before something can go wrong,
I want her to see the snow.
Hey, don't worry. She'll be all right.
Your love will keep her strong.
Bear this in mind
things will not be like you intend.
Things are never the way they appear.
That's the rule of this journey.
This is the gift of life.
In all these tough times, there is
a sweet taste of happiness, too.
Do come...
These flowing winds that come and go,
Sometimes salty, sometimes fresh.
Do come...
This gift of nature,
that you and I have,
we have to accept it with love.
Finish it fast Charlie. We've to leave.
Hi Devika!
Hey...
You look nice. It's been a while since I've
seen you. How are you?
I'm good.
I finally get to meet you.
This must be Charlie. Hey Charlie!
Hey Dharma.
Hi.
I'm Karshan Roy.
I work with Travel Diaries.
It's an international travel magazine.
Devika has told me everything about you.
And I thought it's really interesting.
So this time we want to
feature you on the cover.
I mean, about Charlie.
So can you please tell
us about your journey?
Let's go.
Wow! Unbelievable!
I'm sure Charlie's wishes will come true.
I will pray for her and for you
And thank you very much for
your valuable time. Alright, let's go?
You carry on. I'll join you shortly.
Sure.
Lovely meeting you Dharma. Bye Charlie.
All right. Let's go.
He's a close friend.
We studied together in
Bengaluru. He lives here.
He forced me to come home
when he got to know I'm here.
I thought it'd be good for him to meet you.
I also have a program me to attend.
So I've to go.
It was really a memorable journey.
Charlie will be all right, don't worry.
If you need any help, feel free to call me.
Bye Charlie.
Bye.
Let's go?
Jump in.
What?
Okay enough.
Enough.
Don't be so sad Charlie.
It was the two of us
who started this journey.
So let's continue doing so.
Maybe when luck decides to chuck,
this is how it looks Charlie.
Where in Karnataka are you from?
Sir, Mysuru.
I'm from Tamil Nadu.
Do you know Tamil?
A little bit, sir.
Oh, nice!
Your name?
Dharma.
Myself Vamsi. Vamsinadhan.
This is my son. Karuppa.
Your son's name?
Daughter. She's Charlie.
Oh...
Hey, Karuppa, no!
Hi Charlie, welcome to my home!
These are Karuppa's medals
from various dog shows.
- Dharma right?
- Yes.
Do you want to eat now?
Or do you want to freshen up first?
I think I'll freshen up.
So you've set off to see the snow...
When people you love the most leave,
it hurts. Isn't it Karuppa?
Sir, your wife?
Oh.
I haven't told you about it yet!
Her name is Rani.
Our's is first sight at love!
But our parents didn't agree.
So we eloped and settled down here.
She worked at a bank near by.
We were so happy!
We led a wonderful life.
But we couldn't have kids.
We consulted many doctors.
They told us we could never have kids.
The problem was with me.
After that, I went into depression.
Then one day,
my wife gave me a wonderful gift!
Guess what?
My son, Karuppa!
My life transformed after he came.
Then Rani gave me another big surprise.
There was a letter on the table.
But I didn't open it.
My help Veluchami told me that...
she...
Aye, it's ok.
She eloped with her colleague. Anyway...
Leave it.
Poor girl, how long would she have
tolerated two fools like us!
She left
Karuppu, I hope you never leave me.
Should you even think about it, I'll kill you!
Come, let's dance.
Hey... Charlie...
Hey Dharma, morning!
Slept well?
Yes sir, slept well.
There's some fresh fish.
You freshen up and come.
Let's feast on it!
Veluchami!
Come with me there are miles to go.
Ain't nothing in our way at all.
Let seasons come,
the leaves may grow or fall.
Oh yeah.
Summer winds cool the way as we travel far.
Winter sun to keep us warm.
We follow the rainbow
to find a pot of gold.
Cheers!
Charlie...
[KARUPPA BARKS]
On the way we'll face the weather.
Hold my hands we'll roam together.
Don't let go for I can't walk alone.
Fallen leaves look pretty
when you're by my side.
Old paths feel fresh and fine.
The clouds all look like you
when they fall upon my eyes.
Hey Karuppa, the swing is broken.
Go play somewhere else.
I'll repair it later.
Veerji, that'll be 20,000 bucks.
20,000 bucks?
Yes sir.
Have you forgotten our horse trade?
Yes Veerji. Consider
that deal to be sealed.
Keep 15,000 bucks. Good day.
Okay Veerji. Good day.
Hey.. Come on Charlie.. Karuppa..here
Yes.. Made for each other.
Ah! Already love sick?
My Karuppa is already heart broken
because you're leaving.
So then? Leaving huh?
Yes, thank you so much.
Dharma, we may come from different states.
But the water we drink is the same!
No formality between us.
Dharma, I have something for you.
This is a participant pass to the
national-level dog show in Ludhiana next week.
This time I won't be participating.
If you have the time, go watch it.
It's a dog world. You and Charlie will
have the best experience. Trust me.
Sure.
Dharma, When you finish the trip,
come and meet us on your way home.
Bye.
This is hard!
Come let's go fishing, Karuppa.
Karuppa...
[ANCHOR 1] The Nobel laureate
Konrad Lorenz once said,
The bond with a true dog is as lasting
as the ties of this earth will ever be.
[ANCHOR 2] Welcome to the National
Agility Dog Championship 2020.
In association with the Animal Welfare
Association of India.
A warm welcome to all the participants who
have gathered at this event.
And have made this into a massive one.
[VOLUNTEER] Excuse me sir.
[ANCHOR 2] Today we have gathered
here at Ludhiana, Fields of Dreams stadium
- for this wonderful championship.
- [VOLUNTEER] Sir please.
We are truly overwhelmed with the amazing
response we have received for this event.
[VOLUNTEER] Sir, this way
Like we said, we have with us nationwide
best participants and their best dogs.
Also, first time particants who are
a little nervous and a little excited.
Relax and enjoy.
- This is what the Agility Championship is all about friends.
- [VOLUNTEER] All the best.
Fun for the dogs
[ANCHOR 1] fun for the handlers
[ANCHOR 2] and fun for the spectators
watching this show across the globe!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[ANCHOR 1] Without taking much of your
time, let's get the show started right away.
Welcome our Judges on
board for this year's show.
His pets have not only
saved people from danger
but also bravely stood by
the nation during war crisis.
Please welcome Mr. Pradham
Singh from Amritsar.
[ANCHOR 1] Welcome on board sir.
And from Kolkata we have our
dog psychologist Namratha Banerjee.
[ANCHOR 2] The founder of the Pets Care Foundation
& Adoption Centre, Mr. Vivan Sharma from Delhi.
[ANCHOR 1] And the most awarded Animal Welfare
Officer from Karnataka Ms. Devika Aaradhya.
Hello, hi.
When we have such prestigious judges here
with us today, what more can be asked for?
Let's give it up for our first
participants, Mr. Ashok Rathod and Sarama.
- Our three times championship winner here at NADC.
- [LADY]Come on Ashok!
They look pretty confident.
Let's see if they can the
trophy home this year.
[ANCHOR 2] That's a quick start with a
smooth double hurdle jump.
Moving past the tunnel.
Quickly through the dog walk.
A smooth ring jump.
Tricky yet amazingly past the wave pool.
There seems to be a bit of
a contact with the obstacle.
Swiftly through the long bar jump.
Inside the tunnel again.
Moving through the see-saw.
Leading to the A-frame.
And the final jump!
What a spectacular performance by Sarama,
a two and half year old Belgian Malinois.
[ANCHOR 1] And now, lets give a huge around of applause
for our second participant, Mr.Kashi from Lucknow
Hi.
Along with his 2 year old doberman who
was the first runner up of the 24th NADC.
What brings you here?
Participant?
All the best!
[ANCHOR 2] They take the
first jump over the hurdle.
Remarkable pace. Truly
tremendously through the tunnel.
Good connect with the dog over the ramp.
And nice smooth jump from the ring.
Nicely through the wavepools.
It's lovely to watch them perform together.
That's the highest jump any dog
has taken so far, ladies and gentlemen.
They seem to be doing
great for the first time.
That's the final jump that has been taken.
And they finish it.
[ANCHOR 1] So let's welcome our
next participant Dharma and Charlie.
A one and half year old female Labrador.
[ANCHOR 2] Look at the energy
and the enthusiasm of Charlie.
Looks like she wants to quickly finish
and take the trophy home.
Charlie...
[ANCHOR 1] Uh-oh.
That was bit of a
wrong start to the agility.
What's happening there?
[JUDGE] Must be for the food!
[ANCHOR 2] Well, she certainly seems to be entertaining
the spectators and the judges in a totally different way.
[JUDGE 1] Hello, excuse me!
What the hell is happening man?
You're unable to handle your own pet!
In addition, you're wasting all our time!
Sir actually we are not here
to participate - Oh really??
Do you even understand where
you are standing right now?
Do we look like buffoons?
That's what he thinks.
What's the name again?
[DEVIKA] Charlie.
Charlie.
Chaplin. Good combination.
In my 13 years of experience,
I have never seen anything like this.
[JUDGE 2] Ruined the show for us!
Looks like your dog is
more intelligent than you.
Shut up!
Just eat, roam and sleep!
Can you do anything else?
Never show me your face again!
Be with me.
In this classroom called life.
I shall be your friend and stay by you.
I shall follow you everywhere.
And share unspoken tales.
You're my life lesson.
You're my biggest trophy.
Hold my hand.
And take care my friend.
My dear friend.
Be like the nest that listens
to the chirping of the birds.
You're the peacock feather that
adorns the chapters of my life.
Come to me and I'll teach
you to make a paper boat.
I'll follow you and write a story.
That's dedicated to you but
hidden to the rest of the world.
When I'm with you, even the moon's
company seems insignificant.
Your smile is priceless.
And it's my privilege to spend
my days surrounded by it.
I will follow and join you.
And I'll sing you a song.
That I'll sing for none else but you.
You're my life lesson.
You're my biggest trophy.
Hold my hand.
And take care my friend.
My dear friend.
Camera 3, pan to the dog.
Yes fix.
You think she can make it?
Impossible.
[ANCHOR 1] Ladies and
gentlemen this is truly impressive.
Histroy has been made out here
with this performance at the 25th NADC.
I mean look at the audience around us.
All of them standing on their feet,
giving a fantastic standing ovation.
Watching this truly beautiful bond!
Love you Charlie!
[CROWD CHEERING]
Anyway, there are lots of
Charlies back home, too.
Mom called to say they're all missing me.
So I'm off.
The first time I came to your house,
I had fixed a tracker on Charlie.
I'll come looking for
her whenever I miss her.
Okay?
As someone who has always lived a confined life, I
discovered just how beautiful life is,
only when I stepped out into the world.
Life has been painted with new colours,
with new memories at every juncture.
My heart yearns for
this journey to never end!
[GLASS BOTTLE SHATTERS]
[DISTANT YELPING]
[DHARMA] Haven't I worked
without taking leave for so long?
No, I can't sir.
How can they hold my salary?
What should I have informed, sir?
Haven't I worked this long?
So I am entitled to my salary!
No need. I know how to get it!
Charlie...
Hello sir. I've come from Mysuru.
I've run out of money.
My dog hasn't eaten
anything since yesterday.
Please keep this mobile and give us food.
[HOTEL OWNER] Chotu...
[PETTY SHOP WOMAN] Hello...
[OLDMAN ON PHONE] Who is that, dear?
[NOBODY IS SPEAKING.]
[CHARLIE BARKS]
[SON?]
[DHARMA?]
Come Charlie, let's go.
It's not our's anymore, come let's go.
Charlie, please.
Smile at your child.
My feet and my prayers both wont work.
[BAUL INSTRUMENT PLAYING.]
Compassion my lord.
I'm setting out on this path.
Please allow me to come close to you.
Give me such companionship throughout.
That my forehead now only
bows at your sacred place.
There are a thousand
hinderances along the way.
But you can make it go away.
Give me such companionship throughout.
That my forehead now only
bows at your sacred place.
I ask you to watch over
and I ask for nothing else.
Turn your face to me
god and smile at your child.
If you stay oblivious
my feet and my prayers both wont work.
Turn your face to me
god and smile at your child.
Smile at your child.
[BUDDHIST CHANTS]
We can't guarantee you anything.
Nor are we sure how long you need to stay here.
She was pregnant, but
her puppies are no more.
Who is to be held responsible?
For this grievous and unforeseen end.
I curse this dreadful fate.
My luck has withered away.
Time has played its twisted game.
Eyes are moist, heart is shattered.
Every step forward is brimming with pain.
I place before you a humble prayer.
Show the path and save
us from this cruel suffering.
Shower your mercy oh Lord.
Put an end to my misery.
Charlie...
Charlie.
How much do you love me?
I love you too, Charlie.
A cloud of faith,
laid with prayers.
Is bringing hope into our deserted life.
I have long forgotten
the sound of laughter.
Baggage of sorrow is growing heavier.
Every door towards light seems shut.
My dearest is moving away from me.
Hear my prayers oh Lord!
Let my dear one live!
[KIDS] Hey cutie...
No. Don't touch.
[KIDS] Mom dog's name is Charlie.
Shower your mercy oh Lord.
Put an end to my misery.
Stop. Stop!
[DR. ASHWIN ON CALL] Dharma at this stage,
Charlie doesn't have much time.
[WHATEVER YOU WISH TO
DO FOR HER, DO IT SOON!]
Charlie.
There's been a landslide.
Roads are closed for now.
We request you to kindly co-operate.
[ARMY OFFICER] Do not let
any vehicles go ahead.
The convoy will be here in sometime.
I need the list of all the rescuers.
Sir, what happened?
There's a landslide ahead.
When will you permit movement?
I said you can't go.
There's been a landslide.
Sir, that's not possible.
I can't go back.
I have travel led too far.
I need to reach before it's too late.
Don't you get it?
There's a landslide ahead.
I don't care, sir! I have come from far!
I have a dog, too.
What is he blabbering?
Please take him away.
Sir, please sir!
[OFFICER BAKSHI] Let me
see how you'll go any further.
Please sir try to understand!
[OFFICER BAKSHI] I said go back!
[ARMY COMMANDER]
Mr.Bakshi, what's going on?
[OFFICER BAKSHI] Sir, this fellow is crazy.
Just doesn't get it despite telling him
that the roads are closed.
Sir, he's not letting me go to the other side.
Please help me.
My dog is unwell.
I need to show her snow at the earliest.
If I don't do it today,
it might be too late.
Please sir... I beg you!
Please sir...
So how's Charlie now?
She is okay.
When I got to know your story,
I was reminded of my army dogs.
Either they leave us, or we leave them.
The one who gets left behind,
is the one who suffers.
[TRANSCEIVER]
Listen Dharma, I know what this
journey means to you and Charlie.
But there's been a landslide and
the situation is really bad.
I don't know when the roads will open.
But there's a convoy that is
going to Kashmir tomorrow.
You will find the snow there too,
you can join them.
You can stay here for the night.
Sir.
How do you know about me and Charlie?
Oh! You are famous my friend!
Where is it?
Here.
"A Tale of Dharmaraj in Kaliyug."
The whole world knows your story.
Best wishes my friend.
Here the temperature drops steeply at night.
Take care.
Mr. Bakshi.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
I am told that if we travel towards Kashmir
tomorrow, we might be able to see the snow.
But time!
Charlie's every breath...
was a reminder that we didn't
have much time in our hands.
[HEAVY BREATHING]
Charlie, have you seen snow before this?
This is my first time ever.
I'm tired Charlie. You carry on.
Sir, it was a sight you missed!
She was so happy!
[ARMY OFFICER] Where were you?
Sir, just close by.
[ADRIKA] I miss you Charlie.
Adrika, she still hasn't showed 'thanks'.
Really Charlie? You haven't thanked yet?
Dharma as you said,
you should come visit me and Karuppu
before going back.
[DEVIKA ON PHONE] What is she up to now?
Sleeping.
[WE SHOULD MEET AS SOON AS YOU COME BACK.]
Sure.
[Good night]
Good night Devika.
Are you happy Charlie?
I know that,
this has been a memorable day for you.
It's the same for me too.
Let's take a flight home.
Everyone's waiting for you.
Good night, Charlie.
[AUTO ARRIVES]
Charlie!
[Giggles]
Charlie.
Charlie!
Sir, have you seen Charlie?
No.
Have you seen Charlie?
Charlie!
What happened?
Sir, have you seen Charlie?
No.
Charlie!
What happened?!
Why did you leave me
and come here Charlie?
Do you know how much
I searched for you?
I've lost everyone I've loved.
I thought I could somehow save you.
It's hurting me so much Charlie!
I don't know what to do.
I tried my best.
Doctors, prayers...
But I'm unable to save you.
[Thanks gesture]
[Charlie, you had shown the 'thanks' gesture.
Please do it again.]
How much do you love me, Charlie?
Charlie, have you seen snow before this?
This is my first time ever.
Sir, the dog came running
behind the ambulance.
He transformed my life.
Uncle, why don't you ever smile?
Charlie!
This is my dog.
Brother, please come with us.
I have quit smoking.
Dharma sir has changed so much!
Charlie!
Karuppa, you're in love, huh?
The way a dog sleeps,
reveals a lot about its feelings.
She trusts you a lot.
[A performance to remember out here.]
[Let's give it up for Dharma & Charlie
and that beautiful love they share.]
"A tale of Dharmaraj in Kaliyug"
[CRIES UNCONTROLLABLY]
I can't handle this pain...
[INDISTINCT CRY]
[PUPPY YELPING]
Charlie knew I'd be
unable to live without her.
That's why she left
me with a little Charlie.
Like I said earlier,
If you are lucky,
a Charlie will come into your life too.
But... only if you are lucky.
[CHARLIE'S ANIMAL RESCUE CENTRE]
[CROWD CHATTERING]
[CROWD CHEERING]
Towards the end, I realised that the past
is always tense and the future is perfect.
I opened an Animal Rescue Centre
in the loving memory of my Charlie.
Just like Charlie, many homeless souls
are waiting for a loving home.
You too can become the
Dharmaraya of Kaliyug,
But... only if you choose to.
Hey.. Charlie.
I'll be home soon from work. Take care.
[SNORING]
Your mother was way better than you!