Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
No, I can't, okay?
I have to finish this report.
JEFF: You can take
a couple hours off.
Well, I know its Sunday, Jeff,
but I'm evaluating
a shipping company
for this client
from Barcelona,
and he's flying in tomorrow.
No,
I'm not gonna change my mind.
I'll give you a back rub.
No!
Okay, you win.
We'll do it over the phone.
Jeff, don't do this to me.
So, what are you wearing?
I'm not gonna tell you.
Besides a thong and...
Maribel, come here.
Yeah?
I have a boyfriend emergency.
See that guy waiting for me?
The boy from
Ipanema over there.
You wanna bail on him?
He's a babe!
Come on, please?
Tell him I stayed home sick.
Spence is taking me sailing.
Come on. I'll owe you. Okay.
[SIGHS]
YOLANDA: Come on in.
What do you think?
I took the red out.
It's great!
Yolanda,
it makes you look younger.
Younger? Really?
Are you almost done?
Because I don't
want to be late.
Yeah. How was church?
[LAUGHS]
How was church?
Anyone interesting?
Yolanda,
church is not a pickup bar.
I'm not Catholic anymore,
remember?
I remember your dad trying
to understand the difference.
Catholics worship saints,
Christians worship Christ.
Christ was a Christian,
not Catholic.
Uh, honey, Christ was a Jew.
Really?
Yeah, and he had great hair.
[LAUGHING]
Speaking of which,
why don't we do something
different with your hair?
Me? No, I don't think so.
YOLANDA: Yeah.
We could snip it about here,
but the bangs need to grow.
YOLANDA: It would
accentuate your eyes.
What are you doing?
I don't want to do
anything with my hair.
Are you gonna come, or what?
Go ahead. I'll be fine.
Okay.
Tell your dad I'm
bringing April over.
[CARMEN AND JEFF LAUGHING]
Jeff, I don't know
if this is working.
Baby,
it's working, believe me.
I don't think
it's strong enough.
Believe me, Carmen.
Trust me on this,
it's strong enough.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Positive.
Are you sure?
[CREAKING]
Is that an earthquake?
What was that?
[SCREAMING]
[LAUGHING]
-Great chair, Jeff.
-I told you it
wasn't strong enough.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
You did not say that.
I know.
You don't miss it,
us being a couple?
We sucked as a couple.
I liked us as a couple.
Shit! I didn't realize it
was so late. I gotta go.
Jeff, let me up.
[BRAZILIAN MUSIC PLAYING]
Hey, music store girl.
You know someone named Eden?
Yeah. I'm gonna give
it to you straight.
Eden skipped out the back door
with some Ken doll.
Who is Ken doll?
I don't understand.
Oh, you're not from
this solar system, are you?
[LAUGHS]
She stood you up.
That means...
Yeah,
okay, I know what that means.
It's known to happen
in my solar system as well.
Which, I gather from the music
you're
listening to, is Brazil?
You know Brazilian music?
That's Bebel
Gilberto's composition,
Sem Contencao,
recorded in 1999.
-Released on Six
Degrees Records...
-Wow.
...and originally inspired by
the legendary bossa nova
artist, Joao Gilberto
who happens to be her father.
Hey, wait!
-Have a coffee with me.
-Mmm-mmm.
I can't. I'm late for dinner.
According to the theory
of relativity, time doesn't
exist as we know it.
Yeah, but my father does.
So you're going to
stand me up as well?
No. We didn't have a date.
How do you know, huh?
Maybe this all happened
for a purpose. Maybe you
had a date with destiny.
Oh, come on.
Come on.
There's a coffee shop
right across the street.
Does my destiny have a name?
Andre.
But you can call me Andy.
CARMEN: How long are we
gonna wait this time?
Maybe she got
stuck in traffic.
Tu sabes que Maribel
walks home from work.
English or Spanish,
one or the other.
[SIGHS]
All right. Soup isn't
meant to be served cold.
Leticia.
Dear Lord, thank you
for
the blessings of your bounty.
And help us, dear Jesus,
to commit
ourselves wholeheartedly
to the service of your name.
Amen.
Be our guide,
Lord Jesus Christ,
and show us your will.
Grant us
the privilege of dwelling
in the bosom of your love
for now and for all eternity.
Amen.
Amen?
Something wrong?
No, it's fine.
-What is it?
-[STUTTERING] She
said it was fine.
CARMEN: I don't know.
I think something's missing.
Serranos.
No, I put serranos in.
But you removed the seeds.
You would add seeds.
I respect tradition.
You made it better before, Pa.
-[OVEN BELL DINGING]
-I always make squash
flower soup this way.
He's getting worse.
He can't taste anything.
So? Do you have to rub it in?
[SIGHS]
-Hello?
-Mari, where the hell are you?
Sorry.
I'm here already!
Give me a break.
Jesus Christ! Sorry, Leti.
-Maribel,
do you know what time it is?
-MARIBEL: Gonna wash my hands.
I know, I know.
You don't have to say it.
Perdoname, Daddy.
Please cut the Spanglish.
I may have met
my destiny today.
I thought you
were mad at her.
Why don't you mind
your own business.
-When are you gonna grow up?
-When everybody
gets off my back.
Come on, now, come on.
This is not how we behave
for dinner. We honor dinner.
We have good manners,
and we have
pleasant conversation.
Well,
I have a little announcement.
You know the new luxury condos
going up in Playa del Rey?
MARTIN: Mmm-hmm.
Well, a friend of mine
who works for
the developer gave me a tip
and I was able to
get my bid in early.
You're moving out?
Not immediately, no.
It's still under construction.
Does it have a pool?
Can I come on weekends?
Dad, aren't you
gonna say anything?
Well, if you need a loan
for the down payment...
I'm covered.
I used my savings.
MARTIN: Oh!
What about the mortgage?
My agent handled everything,
and I even got him
to eat half his fee.
I understand.
If you wanted my advice,
you would've asked me before
making the decision.
I'm sorry, Dad, but you
would've told me not to do it.
[SIGHS]
I can't digest my food.
You did last week.
[DOORBELL RINGING]
Hey!
YOLANDA: Hi! Here she is.
Sorry for disturbing dinner.
Hi, Yoli.
You didn't miss
anything unusual.
Just the two
Aries butting heads.
MARTIN: Let's get her a chair.
Here we go. Try this.
What is it?
Nopales. I think
you're going to like it.
Go figure! I can't get her
to finish her cereal,
and you get her to eat cactus.
APRIL: Cactus?
Cool!
[ALL LAUGHING]
[PHONE RINGING]
Excuse me.
No, I'm not staying.
Soup?
Oh, that's me.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
-Hello?
-WOMAN: Yolanda,
where on earth are you?
It's my mom. I guess
her flight arrived early.
-I was just on my way.
-How could you
leave me stranded here?
MAN: There's nothing I can do!
But it's Sunday.
And I'm right in
the middle of dinner.
The governor's
dessert is burned up.
We need your help.
All right,
I'll come by if I have to.
If you're not here
in five minutes...
She thinks she belongs
at the hearing.
A single woman
living with her mother.
Looks better?
Here you go.
Oh, April.
[ALL LAUGHING]
I gotta go.
Thanks for baby-sitting.
My pleasure.
We're gonna have fun, right?
I'll see you later.
ALL: Bye.
See you. Bye.
Good night. Bye-bye.
I've got to put out a fire.
What happened to
"We honor dinnertime"?
Did you hear? Yolanda's mom
is moving into
the neighborhood.
Oh.
There's candied pumpkin
in the kitchen
for your ice cream.
Okay, bye-bye.
What?
MAN: This way, sir, over here.
Catering.
He's here!
Apron.
Toque.
[GOMEZ SPEAKING SPANISH]
No, they'll never do it again.
Don't fire them.
Tony,
the apples are still moist.
-How many bread
loaves do we have?
-We got plenty of loaves.
Remove the bread crusts
and save the apples.
Cut the baguettes into cubes,
coat them with melted butter
and bake them.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
I'll prepare the sugar syrup.
We'll call it
something French.
Belle melange.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
I want every little piece
of burned crust out of there.
I don't want to see one.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[LAUGHS]
-Belle melange?
-Belle melange.
It means a lovely mess.
[LAUGHING]
That's perfect for
this Hollywood crowd.
[HUMMING]
Leti, you have
papers to grade.
Why don't you let me
and Maribel finish?
How long you gonna give me
the silent treatment?
I don't know
what you expected.
We are three grown women.
[HUMMING]
Okay, make that two
grown women, living at home
with their daddy.
That might have worked
in Mexico, but he doesn't
realize things are different.
He needs to meet someone.
He's been alone for too long.
He only had one
true love in his life.
All they did was
bicker and fight.
That's how
they loved each other.
Please!
-What do you remember?
You were what?
-I was old enough to know.
Anyway, I have to get out.
And so do you.
When will you get it through
your head that I choose to
live my life this way?
Por favor,
you are lying to yourself.
Okay!
Somebody has to care
what happens to Dad.
I care, okay?
I care very much
what happens to him,
but I won't use
that as an excuse
not to live my life.
[HUMMING]
All you think about is you.
Stop pretending
you're mad at me.
You're mad because Carlos
showed you
the door a decade ago.
At least I don't sleep
with every guy I meet.
Don't make me out
to be a slut just because
I've had sex in this decade.
Why don't you wake
up and get a life?
I have a life.
[MIMICKING] I have a life.
You should've stayed Catholic
and joined a convent for
all the fun you're having.
MARIBEL: You're
aggravating her colitis.
CARMEN: What is wrong now?
Why do you always do that?
-Do what?
-Dismiss me
like I don't exist.
It is not just you.
She does it to everybody.
What are you talking about?
Don't play dumb, Carmen.
You can be a real bitch
when you want. No wonder
you don't have friends.
[FRIDGE SLAMMING]
What do you know?
You can't even show
up on time for dinner.
Oh, please! Why should I
when it always
ends up like this?
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
I can't take it anymore!
Is that a promise or a threat?
Jesus, you're pathetic.
Give it to me!
[ALL EXCLAIMING]
Oh, my... Are you crazy?
So fun!
No wonder the Greeks do it.
And they sing and dance.
Let's try that!
Maribel, wait.
* You won't admit you love me
* And so how am I
[ALL SCREAMING]
* To know
* You only tell me
* Perhaps, perhaps
* Perhaps
[LETICIA SCREAMING]
[CARMEN AND MARIBEL LAUGHING]
* A million times
I ask you and then
* I asked you over again
* You only answer
[SINGS IN SPANISH]
[SINGING IN SPANISH]
* So if you
really love me, say yes
* But if you don't,
dear, confess
* And please don't tell me
In Spanglish!
* Perhaps, quizas, perhaps
[ALL LAUGHING]
MARTIN: I just don't get it.
My three get
the best of everything.
The only thanks I
get is a daughter
who spends her last dime
on a cookie-cutter condo.
For what?
GOMEZ:
So it's not the moving part
that bothers you?
I want them to move out.
I want them to
get their own lives.
GOMEZ: You just wish
that they would ask
for your advice?
MARTIN:
So, what's wrong with that?
GOMEZ: Nothing, nothing.
But...
I mean, since you were the one
who pushed her to get her MBA,
I think you should trust that
she knows what she is doing.
I didn't push her.
Besides, I thought it
was for her own good.
Anyway,
I think the one that's going
to give you a lot of trouble
is that old maid Leticia.
She's gonna stick it to you
for the rest of your life.
-Now she's got
the perfect boyfriend.
-Who?
Jesus Christ.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[LAUGHING]
Speak for yourself.
[WHISTLING]
[DOORBELL RINGING]
[MUMBLING] Where's my shirt?
"Thanks for
ironing the shirt, Dad."
MARTIN: Hi.
Hi.
Hola.
I practically
had to beg Yolanda
to bring me over here.
-I heard so many
good things about you.
-Please.
My daughter's been so alone
during her terrible divorce.
She tells me that
you're a widower.
Martin, isn't it?
Yes. It's a pleasure.
I'm Hortensia.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
This is my oldest.
Leticia!
Of course.
The schoolteacher, right?
LETICIA: Let me
pour you a cup of coffee.
HORTENSIA:
You're still not married?
No.
I mean, yes, I'm not married.
And a nice girl like you.
You might want to try a little
Preparation H around the eyes.
It gets rid of those
nasty little lines.
Anyway, once you're past
the sex, marriage is
not all that interesting.
Especially if
you're crazy enough to marry
a real loser like Yolanda did.
Mother!
You wouldn't listen to me,
and now look where you are.
I left something in the car.
I'll be right back.
We all learn
from our mistakes.
Yes, of course.
It's just that,
as a parent,
it's so painful to watch
your child suffer needlessly.
You and I know a few things
about raising daughters.
I'm still learning. You see...
This is my...
Your youngest! Maribel.
Hi.
And what are you
rebelling against, dear?
People who can talk and talk
and talk and say nothing.
Careful, honey,
boys don't like smart-asses.
Yeah, they just like asses.
[MARTIN CALLS OUT]
It's hard to tell,
but I did teach her manners.
Just don't wait too
long like your big sister.
[WHISPERING] She's
already over the hill.
LETICIA: Sugar?
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
HORTENSIA:
Life is bitter enough.
Carmen.
-And you must be Carmencita.
-And you must be
Yolanda's mother.
Of course there's
no problem here.
Just remember, as pretty
as you are, a man is incapable
of telling the truth.
[LAUGHS]
I'm late for a meeting.
I'm sorry, but it was
very nice meeting you.
Me, too.
Just wait.
Just... [CLEARS THROAT]
Daughters.
And they say that
boys are harder to raise.
[EXCLAIMS]
What's this?
Oh, my!
It's not mine.
A man's work is never done.
Yolanda tells me you
make a coconut flan
that brings a woman to tears.
...Anything until
I get there, okay?
Hi. Thank you for
meeting me, Ms. Naranjo.
My pleasure.
I've been looking...
Don't worry.
I'll take care of it as soon
as I arrive, okay? Bye.
Sorry, but I'm flying
earlier than I expected.
No problem.
So?
So, according to my analysis,
Petersen's air,
rail and trucking links
are all very strong,
but those assets are far
outweighed by the company's
financial liabilities,
and a cargo fleet that
needs a lot more work than
their projections allow for.
Are you telling me
the company is a dog?
Bottom line? Yes.
Well, I could have
read that in the Journal.
Don't worry.
You'll be paid for it.
Why bother hiring
me if you're planning
to purchase Petersen anyway?
Excuse me?
I think you've already decided
to purchase the company.
How did you
arrive at that theory?
Last month's Wine
and Gourmet Magazine
had a picture of you dining
in San Francisco
with Harlan Richter,
the patent attorney.
So?
Petersen's ships and
trucks are all fitted
with their patented
satellite tracking devices.
I think you're interested
in acquiring the company
just to get the patent.
You mean
a classic bait and switch.
Exactly.
It could be a huge market.
They have the potential
to track all kinds
of consumer products,
including luggage, computers,
Palm Pilots,
cell phones, you name it.
Good effort.
But Harlan Richter
happens to be a friend of mine
and I'm really just
interested in the ships.
Bye.
Let's go.
[PLANE DOOR CLOSING]
The second type of
chemical reaction
is a composition reaction.
We all hate the smell
of ammonia, don't we?
Hmm?
So nitrogen and
hydrogen yield ammonia.
Who else can
give me an example
of a composition reaction?
What? No hands?
[THUD]
[GASPS]
[STUDENTS LAUGHING]
Who wants to return the ball?
ALL: I do.
Arms down. I'll do it.
I'm trying to teach up here.
I'm sorry. Look what
we did to your window.
Did anybody get hurt up there?
No, just humiliated.
Humiliated.
You ought to see
how my catcher feels.
I didn't know he
could throw that far.
So, uh...
[SIGHS]
You gonna keep that
ball as a souvenir?
I mean, you can. We got more.
[STUDENTS GIGGLING]
BOY:
Love is a chemical reaction,
Miss Naranjo.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Please tell me you
know what H2O is.
[STUDENTS GIGGLING]
[GIGGLES]
Waiting for Eden?
Waiting for you.
Come on.
[ENGINE STARTING]
Where do you want to go?
Brazil.
Brazil. Okay.
-What's this?
-It's a figa.
A good luck charm.
Has it brought you any luck?
I'm with you, aren't I?
Red lights are
such a waste of time,
don't you think?
You just sit and
wait with nothing to do.
[HORN HONKING]
Hi. We've never met up close.
I'm Orlando Castillo,
the new baseball coach.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
You teach science, right?
Chemistry.
Oh.
Um...
Nice biceps.
Pardon?
You work out?
No.
Oh, too bad.
'Cause you could
improve your triceps
if you would work out.
[MOTOR STARTING]
[MOUTHING]
JEFF: Surprise, surprise.
CARMEN: I felt like cooking.
[CARMEN LAUGHING]
JEFF: You cooked
enough for an army.
CARMEN: Try this.
Mmm.
That's delicious.
Is that one of your
dad's specialties?
It's my version.
It's tamarind-glazed lamb on
cumin cabbage with
a tangerine salsa.
The lamb is
French-South American,
the cabbage is pure Mexican
and the salsa is Caribbean.
JEFF:
What will they call this?
CARMEN: I don't know.
Dad calls my dishes mutts.
Well...
Nuevo latino.
Yeah.
I like that.
I bet if your dad
would just try it,
he would definitely be sold.
When I was little,
he used to bake me
bracelets out of cookie dough.
Then he'd make rings
and paint them with colored
sugar to make them sparkle.
Did you see that?
That's not stable.
I'm gonna go check this out.
It might be the leg.
It's the leg.
Yeah. Come here.
Hi.
[IN SEDUCTIVE TONE] Hi.
[SIGHS]
[PANTING]
[HORTENSIA SPEAKING
SPANISH]
Mind if I join you?
Of course.
What a beautiful day.
Yes, it is.
I need to stretch. Okay?
All right.
Yeah.
Ready?
And one,
and two...
All right.
Yep, and three.
...and three.
-I feel so much better.
Come on.
-Yeah!
[LAUGHING]
Uh-oh, red light.
[WHOOPING]
You need to review page 172.
Okay?
''Leticia, had we but
world enough, and time,
"this coyness,
lady, were no crime.
"We would sit down and think
which way to walk,
"and pass our
long love's day."
Long love's day.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
CARMEN: Hello?
WOMAN: Carmen, Mr. Urgell
flew back from San Francisco
today. He wants to meet now.
Did you change my appointment?
He asked
directions to the market.
You gave him the address?
He's coming there
to meet you.
What do you mean,
he's coming here?
That's what I said.
Carmen?
Thanks for
the advance notice, Sharon.
Hi.
Mr. Urgell.
Please, call me Antonio.
May I help you?
Sure.
Uh-huh.
So this is where you
get your great ideas.
You were wrong assuming
what I was
thinking the other day.
But your
instincts could be right,
and your timing is perfect.
So perfect, in fact...
That you're thinking
of buying Petersen?
Oh, just to get the patent.
[ANTONIO CLEARS THROAT]
[PEOPLE LAUGHING]
MARTIN: Pass the rice, please.
Am I hallucinating,
or are we having
a pleasant dinner?
Thank you.
I have some news.
Moving out?
Oh, well.
Did you close Escrow?
Not yet.
Yes. That's not what I was...
When are you moving?
Maribel, please.
Why can't I say anything?
I've been offered
a job in a new company.
Oh, congratulations.
In Barcelona.
Wow!
LETICIA: Spain?
MARIBEL: Yes.
That's far.
Not far enough for me.
MARTIN: I guess it doesn't
matter how far it is.
The distance isn't important.
What matters is...
Is it a good opportunity?
It's the kind of opportunity
you've always
wanted for me, Dad.
I would be running
a high-tech start-up company
and the money is more
than I ever dreamed.
What about the condo?
I'll rent it out.
It can pay for itself.
[DOORBELL RINGING]
[HORTENSIA CALLS OUT]
Excuse me.
HORTENSIA:
Look what I brought.
MARTIN: Music.
[SOOTHING MUSIC PLAYING]
For some reason,
I've never been able
to find the right man.
That's hard to believe.
My first husband,
Oscar, he was a womanizer.
He just couldn't keep
his cosita in his pants.
Then there was Gustavo.
He was a real artist.
Mmm-hmm.
Was he?
He liked
the opera and the ballet.
He also liked to
dress in tutus.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Then there was my
third husband, Pedro.
In the middle of making love,
he had a heart
attack and died.
I'm so sorry.
Just like that.
Sorry.
And your wife?
She passed away 15 years ago.
Oh.
And you never remarried.
No, not with working,
and raising
three girls, it's...
I like a macho con priorities.
The Spanglish will definitely
get on his nerves.
-It would be nice
if he found someone.
-Yeah. Someone else.
Oh, Martin!
MARTIN: Are you all right?
[HORTENSIA SPEAKING
SPANISH]
[LAUGHING]
Oh, Martin.
[BOTH EXCLAIMING]
HORTENSIA: I think I've had
too much to drink.
''Her face, her tongue,
"her wit, so fair, so sharp."
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Yours made it into my drawers.
Dad is getting worse
and worse. He should just
let us sort our own laundry.
I put your stuff in your room.
They're called thongs, Leti.
Come on.
You can say it. Thongs.
They're not the work
of the devil, you know.
They look
extremely uncomfortable.
On the contrary,
they kind of
massage you all day,
inspiring all
kinds of thoughts.
The only thing I need flossed
are my teeth, thank you.
[SCREAMING] No! No! No!
[CARMEN LAUGHING]
Too late. I already saw them.
So, who's the bard, huh?
Is it the drama teacher?
Social studies?
It's that security guard with
the broken nose
and cauliflower ears.
-He's always had
a thing for you.
-Very funny.
[LETICIA LAUGHS DRYLY]
Leti, what do you have...
You put Preparation
H around your eyes?
Get out! Get out!
[SIGHS]
[PANTING]
Miss April?
Hi.
Good morning. How are you?
Good.
Is that your breakfast?
Mom didn't have time
to make me anything.
They serve pizza
dogs in the cafeteria.
[EXCLAIMS]
Let me tell you. How would you
like it if I brought you
lunch once in a while?
A couple of main courses
and some porcupine cookies.
All right.
Yeah!
But my mom makes
me lunch sometimes.
Well, then we'll trade.
You give me yours.
That way, your mom
won't be embarrassed.
Okay.
Your bus.
Go on.
Good-bye. Thank you.
Good-bye now. Be careful.
MARIBEL: Wow!
So, French, Portuguese
and German and English?
What do you call that?
You're a...
What is that when somebody
speaks several languages?
Correct.
A polyglot.
-How about two languages?
-That's easy.
Bilingual, right?
One language?
I don't know. I don't
think I know that one.
American.
I'm just kidding.
I'm American and I speak two.
Both at the same time,
on top of it.
It drives my dad crazy.
He's a purist.
I love this!
[LAUGHING]
Contemporary Folk Songs.
-Okay, Mr.
Bossa Nova, what is that?
-I don't know.
It came like this...
Yeah.
"I never saw them before.
They came with the apartment."
Whatever.
[EXCLAIMS]
I love your place.
[SCREAMS]
Thank you.
What made you decide
to come to the States?
I didn't want to go
straight to college.
I mean, there's
a whole world out there,
and I had to see it, you know?
How long are you
planning on staying?
I don't know.
I think if you tell life
what it has to be,
you limit it.
But if you let it show
you what it wants to be
it will open doors
you never knew existed.
Yeah.
And your parents
are cool with that?
Totally.
Wow. Brazil must be
the opposite of Mexico.
[LAUGHING]
[GASPS]
"Gather ye
rosebud while ye may
"Old Time is still a-flying
"And this same
flower that smiles today
"Tomorrow will be dying?"
-Do you live
near a rain forest?
-No.
Where I'm from
is too far below
the equator to be tropical.
In fact, I hate July
because it's
our coldest month.
-July?
-Yeah, the seasons
are opposite there.
Wow. Seasons are opposite,
parents are opposite.
What else is
opposite below the equator?
[SCREAMS]
-I'd like to go to
this opposite world.
-Yeah?
Mmm-hmm.
[SCHOOL BELL RINGING]
You have 10 minutes
to solve the problem
before we move on to lab.
ORLANDO: All right, fellas,
gather around and sit.
Pay attention.
Now, young men,
what is our problem?
Here's what
happened in the last game.
You were using the bat
like it's a walking cane,
like you're rap...
You're not rappers!
You're not supposed to be
moving your legs up and down.
This is baseball!
It's more than a game.
It's about life.
It's about getting to
first base. It's an art form.
Do you know what
I'm telling you?
I'm telling you that...
Okay.
What I was trying to tell you
is you're doing a good job.
Done?
ALL: No.
[STUDENTS PROTESTING]
MARTIN:
Just like I promised you.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Green corn tamales. Huh?
Isn't that pretty?
Looks like a garden.
You're really
gonna like this one.
Tomatoes stuffed
with guacamole.
Little tomatitos,
stuffed with guacamole.
-Very special.
-Where are
the porcupine cookies?
I knew you were
gonna ask that. Here.
There they are. But this is
at the end. You can't eat
that first, all right?
Can I have a bite?
I'll trade you my Pokemon card
for the cookies.
APRIL:
You should open a restaurant.
I'll think about that.
That's a good idea.
[ALL CHATTERING]
Here. Here, taste this.
It's too salty? Hmm?
Too spicy? What?
Come on.
Don't make those faces.
Is it too salty?
Too spicy? What is...
MAN: What happened?
Gomez?
I just heard.
Imagine that, huh?
I almost got
killed by my own fart.
[LAUGHING IN RELIEF]
Look at her.
Seems like yesterday
she was a little girl
following me all
over the kitchen.
Yeah, until he kicked me out.
I wanted you to do something
significant with your life.
You didn't think a woman
would make a good chef.
I didn't send my daughter to
graduate school so she
could make tortillas.
You only make tortillas?
You wanna spend your life
in a kitchen like me?
Hello? I'm supposed to be
the center of
attention here, okay?
Sorry.
You know what I went through
to give her
opportunities I never had.
Here we go
with the immigrant story.
This is not
an immigrant story.
what I'm talking about.
Martin, please go
outside and...
-You know...
-Please go and
get me some ice.
Please, I need some ice.
All right. So you two
can just talk
behind my back, right?
Of course. What else?
Look, it's...
Get.
[LAUGHS]
He just wants to spare you
our kind of life,
baby, that's all.
What life, huh?
Doing what I love?
Listen, let me tell
you something. Look.
I remember when we
started our restaurant,
some of
the customers would complain
that the sauces were too hot
or that they wanted them
on the side, and your
father wouldn't budge.
He was, like, uncompromising
when people wanted
him to change anything.
I know. You're not
telling me anything new.
What I'm trying to tell you is
that things got
very difficult.
Okay? Very, very difficult.
The day your mother died,
so sudden like that,
he blamed himself,
he blamed the kitchen,
he blamed the restaurant.
I know, but I'm not like him.
I'm not afraid of change.
You know that.
Yeah. And look at you.
Your father's more proud
of you than anything
in the whole world.
He's just the type
that doesn't express his
feelings, that's all. Okay?
He's not like tio Gomez.
Tio Gomez is a guy who cries
when he watches telenovelas.
I know.
Look at me. I'm crying now.
I know you're crying now.
LETICIA: Dear Jesus,
thank you for the gifts.
[INHALES DEEPLY]
Dear, dear Lord, open our eyes
and be our guide
as we thank you
dear Lord, Lord Jesus Christ.
Amen.
-Maribel tells us
you're from Brazil?
-Yes.
Thank you.
Take this.
MARTIN: Well, the only
white Brazilians I know
are Nazi war criminals.
MARIBEL: Dad!
There probably were a few,
but most German immigrants
went to Brazil
between the wars,
mainly because of
the depression in Europe.
Andy's half-German,
half-Italian.
Oh!
Like the Argentineans.
They always like to brag
about their European heritage.
[ANDY MOANING]
This is amazing!
I can't even describe it.
It's really incredible.
So, you like pulpo
a la Veracruzana?
ANDY: Like it?
I love it.
Really. It's incredible.
Maribel told me
you were a chef,
but I'd say you are
more like an artist.
[CHUCKLING]
Artist.
That's very generous of you.
You're so lucky. Dinner
like this all the time.
[SPEAKING PORTUGESE]
No. But, tell me...
Tell me some more
about your country.
Is it true that there are
more Japanese women...
I have an announcement.
...than anywhere else,
outside of Japan?
It's overcooked.
It's not overcooked.
MARTIN: Do you know
Mexican cuisine?
ANDY: Mmm.
Not as much as I'd like.
But I do know that it's one
of the major
cuisines of the world.
Well, you should
come back next week...
I have an announcement.
...because I'm gonna make
something very, very special.
[LOUDLY] I decided
to postpone college.
Yeah... What? What was that?
I decided not to go
straight to college.
I want to take off
a year or two first.
Oh.
Well, may I ask why?
I want to find myself.
Find yourself. Well, you won't
have to look far. [CHUCKLING]
You know what I mean, Dad.
No, I don't.
You've applied,
you've been accepted,
you're going to college.
End of discussion.
No, I'm not.
Beginning of drama.
Now,
listen to me, young lady...
Why can't I decide
what to do with my life?
Because as long as
you're living under my roof,
you will do as I say.
You understand?
Fine. Fine. That's just fine!
'Cause I'm
moving in with Andy.
What?
Dad.
What? You sit at my table,
you make a fool of me,
while you're scheming
to take my daughter away?
-I wasn't scheming...
-I just want to
find out who I am.
Is that a crime?
You're Maribel Naranjo!
That's who you are!
I don't want you to tell me!
I want to find out for myself,
or else I'm gonna be who you
want me to be,
just like Carmen.
Whoa, whoa! What?
MARTIN: I never wanted you
to be anything, anybody.
MARIBEL: Why are you
so afraid to confront him?
You see what you're
doing to your sister?
She does it to herself, Dad!
I am not afraid, Maribel.
This is the first time I
ever hear of anything...
ANDY: Whoa!
[PLATE SHATTERING]
Stop it!
Way to go, Leti.
You okay?
Oh!
[CHUCKLING]
No wonder April's lunch box
is coming back empty.
Guilty.
What happens to
the lunches that I make her?
Well,
last Thursday's meat loaf
wasn't bad. It was...
Oh, my God.
I can't believe
you're eating my food.
No, don't worry.
I don't have much
in the way of taste anymore.
I hope not. [CHUCKLING]
Anyway,
it's the feeling that counts.
April's not going
to school today?
She's a little
under the weather.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Somebody else may
as well enjoy it.
Here.
Filete relleno de cabrilla.
Oh! Thank you.
Um...
Please don't tell her I know.
She must enjoy
her secret
encounters with you.
[PANTING]
Leti, did you know Dad
went to see a cardiologist?
In here.
Leti?
What are you doing?
I don't know.
I'm still in shock.
Our little sister.
I knew she was
going off to college
but that's not
the same as moving out.
Have you seen Dad?
Yeah.
He's catering some affair.
How'd he look?
Between Maribel and Gomez,
he's not
looking all that well.
Yeah.
You want some tea?
I know what
you're wondering about.
You think I'm overreacting?
"Overreacting?"
Yeah. I'm concerned
about how he is physically.
Is that all you
ever think about,
the physical part?
-No, I was just...
-I'm sure he's
fine physically.
He's the new baseball coach.
Played
professionally in the minors.
Never been married.
His name is Orlando.
I had his files checked
by a secretary in the office.
Oh! I love that you did that.
Mmm.
Do you?
Because I feel like such a...
A snoop?
Guess it runs in the family.
[GIGGLING]
How do you get
your hair to do that?
Oh, we are gonna bring
Orlando to his knees.
-No. You're not
gonna make me wear a...
-Mmm-hmm.
[LAUGHING]
[EXCLAIMS EXCITEDLY]
[LATINO MUSIC PLAYING]
[WHISTLES APPRECIATIVELY]
ORLANDO: Hi.
Hey, are you okay?
'Cause you're
walking a little funny.
You know, I could teach you
some exercises to
stretch out, if you want.
To give you better balance,
you know?
They're simple.
-You can do 'em on
a chair or on the table.
-[MUSIC GETS SOFT]
So, if you're interested,
you let me know. Okay?
On the table.
"I pray thee,
gentle mortal, sing again.
"And thy fair
virtue's force perforce
"doth move me
on the first view
to say, to swear,
"I love thee."
[SIGHS DREAMILY]
Okay, Billy, just like
we told you in practice.
Keep your eye on the ball
and make contact. Oh, yes!
That's contact!
That's what I
been talking about!
That's Billy boy!
That's my boy!
Hey, lady,
we're playing a game here!
Yes.
"Yes."
The poems.
I love you, too.
[SPECTATORS CHEERING]
What poems?
What were you thinking,
writing notes like that, huh?
You ought to be
ashamed of yourselves.
I'm sorry if those
jerks hurt your feelings.
I want you to know that if...
If I could think
of things like that,
if I were a kind of guy
who could write
things like that, I...
I would have written
those poems myself.
[SOBBING]
Please, please, don't cry.
My make-up's running.
That's okay.
I like you better without it.
But I have these
little wrinkles
around my eyes.
Where?
I don't see any wrinkles.
Hi.
Wow.
Well, what do you think?
Better, right?
Can you? Thank you.
You won't believe how gross
the laundry room was.
I ran the washer
with hot water
and bleach
for a whole cycle
just to disinfect it.
What papers?
Did you see my papers?
The ones that
were on the bed.
Yes. They're in
the organizer I bought.
[SIGHING] I had them
spread out for a reason.
You can't afford to do that
in a studio apartment.
There's not enough space.
[GRUMBLING]
[SOFTLY] There used to be.
What, sweetie?
Nothing.
[HUMMING]
HORTENSIA: Hope you like
your sangria fruity.
MARTIN: Oh, yes, I do.
But, tell me,
what are we celebrating?
Yolanda's getting
custody of April.
Her divorce
came through today.
Isn't that great?
Thank God I could
be here with her.
That's very good news.
Yes. I'm just
a little worried still.
She's a single mother now,
and she has absolutely
no professional skills.
She keeps telling me
that she's got
everything under control,
but I don't see
her doing anything.
Anyway, the worst is over.
Good.
It's all very good, then.
Here we are. All right.
So,
what are your plans, now that
you've accomplished everything
you came here to do?
[CHUCKLING]
I'm not at all
certain that I have
accomplished what I
came here to do, Martin.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Dear Lord Jesus,
please help me.
Please,
please, give me the strength
to make him understand just...
Please, just help me,
dear Lord Jesus Christ
almighty up in heaven.
My dear Jesus,
just give me strength...
Leticia,
why are you praying so hard?
Amen.
[MARTIN CLEARS THROAT]
I have an announcement.
Yes?
Well, I, um...
I, um...
We just couldn't wait.
I mean, he wanted to,
and I wanted to, too, and...
And we...
We really wanted to do
it properly, Dad, but...
It just wouldn't...
It was so...
Hold on.
Okay? Just one minute.
Where are you?
Psst.
Come on.
Do I look okay?
Yeah. You look great. Come on.
Dad?
Carmen, um...
I want you to meet
Orlando Castillo.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
My husband.
Your what?
Your husband?
Well, sir...
You see, Orlando and I...
I realize that
this is too late
but I would like to
take this opportunity
to ask for your
daughter's hand in marriage.
What's going on here?
Well, Orlando and I met and...
[BOTH STUTTERING]
Well, no, what it is, is that,
a couple of nights ago, sir,
we got ourselves
into this situation...
-No, I don't...
-...that I hope
you understand.
I don't think you
should tell him that part.
Please, please.
I'm just trying
to get to the place
where we went to Las Vegas.
Las Vegas?
Yeah, we had to get
married in a hurry.
I thought you went
on a retreat, Leti.
Well,
under those circumstances,
we really had no choice.
What circumstances?
That's what I've been trying
to explain to you, sir,
that we were,
a couple of nights ago,
we were together and...
I don't think he needs to...
All right, all right.
Here, have a seat.
[SIGHS LOUDLY]
So,
Orlando, are you a Christian?
He will be.
No, I...
Dad, may I?
I love toppings.
I've always liked toppings.
Sometimes I go to restaurants
and I just ask for toppings.
You know,
I say the more toppings,
the merrier.
That's what I say.
You like tortilla soup?
Yes, of course.
My mother used to make
it for us all the time.
She never made it like this.
This is the best
tortilla soup I've ever had.
Orlando was in
the Dodger farm league.
Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm.
Here.
Yes, I...
I used to catch for
Fernando Valenzuela
when he was in
the Sonora League in Mexico.
I still know some
people at Dodger Stadium.
I could probably
get us some box seats.
And we can sit
right over the dugout.
They're the best
seats in Dodger Stadium,
and we can sit
there and have hot dogs
and sodas.
Do you love her?
Excuse me?
Oh, yes, sir, I do.
I love Leticia very,
very much.
Hot dogs and sodas.
[SIGHS]
I'll tell you what.
You take care of the tickets,
I'll take care of the food.
All right. Provecho.
Congratulations.
We'll celebrate
some other time,
seriously, all right?
Try some stuffed chayote.
Thanks for everything, sis.
I'm so happy for you, Leti.
Whoa!
[SIGHS]
[SLURPING]
What?
You're leaning.
Towards the bowl.
Honey, spoon
the soup away from yourself,
and then bring it
up to your mouth.
Don't lean towards the bowl.
[EXHALES LOUDLY]
[LAUGHS] I can't
deal with this.
With what? Table manners?
No, baby, with you telling me
what to do every
second of the day.
With you rearranging
my entire apartment.
Making the bed every morning.
You're still mad
because I
misplaced your papers?
It's not just my papers.
I don't know where
anything is anymore.
Where's my hammock? Huh?
Your hammock?
Before I came here,
this place was
totally upside-down.
Yeah, okay, but I thought
you liked the opposite world.
How can you say that?
After all I've
done around here...
Who asked you to?
I never even asked
you to move in here.
You're right.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean it.
No, baby, come on.
No, you're right.
It's fine. No, don't worry.
No, no, baby.
-I'll put
everything back where it was.
-Baby, I'm sorry.
I mean,
I believe this belongs here.
Whoa!
-Let me see if I
remember correctly.
-I deserved that.
I believe that was over there.
That was there.
I live here, too.
Never made the bed.
What are these? Papers?
Hey, not the CDs.
Come on.
This was probably there.
I believe that was there,
if I remember correctly.
Maybe that was over there.
I don't know. Let me see.
This stuff.
ANDY: Can we talk
without you getting violent?
Violent?
How did you know
what you wanted to do?
That you wanted to go off
and see the world, anyway?
Were you born knowing?
Is everybody born knowing
exactly what they want to do
with their life,
except for me?
ANDY: Stop it.
Are you even listening to me?
Why doesn't
anybody listen to me?
Hello?
Are you... Am I invisible?
Look who's back.
Hiya.
No matter how much
Martin tries, he can't kill me
with his food, eh?
Come on. How are you? Hiya.
All right.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
No work for you.
Sit down and take it easy.
Sit down. Get him something
to drink or something.
Now, you stay there.
Behave yourself.
All right, hombre.
Let's go. We have
a very special
guest of honor today.
We must pay special attention.
Our captain is back.
Because of him, we will cook
like we've
never cooked before.
[GLASS SHATTERING]
Gomez?
He's gone.
[SPEAKS SPANISH]
No, I'll just have water.
You have to eat something.
It'll make you feel better.
Oh, no. My taste has died.
What's gonna happen to them
now that he's gone?
Some of these people have been
with me and Gomez for years.
Dad, you know,
ever since Mom died,
you have been looking out
for everybody
except for yourself.
I mean,
you need some time off.
Just slow down.
Slow down?
Why should I slow down?
This should be
a wake-up call for you.
Pa.
Isn't there something,
que me quieres decir?
English or Spanish.
What difference does it make
what language I'm speaking?
Take the job in Barcelona,
Carmen.
APRIL: Hi.
Hey!
Come here,
you little thing, you.
Come over here.
That's it. Right up here.
Come on, April. Mr. Naranjo
doesn't want to be
bothered right now.
No, it's all right.
She's just what
I need right now.
Just what I need.
Okay.
"Take the job in Barcelona."
Is that all you
can manage to say?
How about,
"How do you feel
about this, Carmen?
"Is this what you
really want to do?"
All right,
just calm down, Carmen.
You don't care.
Care about what?
How I feel.
What are you talking about?
How I feel, Dad.
Gomez knew.
He tried to tell you
but you wouldn't listen.
What's the use?
Jeff?
Please be home.
Carmen?
Jeff.
I'm sorry for barging in.
What's wrong?
Just hold me.
I have so much I want
to talk to you about.
Carmen, listen...
Jeff?
I didn't know we had company.
[CHUCKLES UNCOMFORTABLY]
[CLEARS THROAT]
Sorry.
Um... I guess I
should have called first.
Just give me a minute, okay?
Please? Carmen.
Carmen?
Stop, stop. Stop, stop, stop.
Okay? I'm sure I mentioned
Rachel to you before.
Maybe a couple of times,
or maybe not.
I don't remember.
But it wasn't that serious.
Until recently.
Congratulations.
Are you gonna be okay?
Yeah. Of course I'm
gonna be all right.
It's fine.
I really came by to tell you
that I just accepted
a new job in Barcelona.
I'm really
looking forward to it.
Great.
Thank you.
Here you go.
Hi.
I'll have the same.
So, what's up?
[LAUGHS] Nothing.
I was just thinking
about the trip because...
Well, I am going.
Yeah, I know.
I mean, it's perfect.
I speak the language,
and who wouldn't want to live
in a beautiful city
on the Mediterranean?
It's an incredible
business opportunity
that no one in
their right mind
would want to miss.
So, I have to pack.
But I have no
idea what to take.
So, what's
the weather like in Barcelona?
But we are not leaving
for at least another week.
I know.
But do I need a converter?
A converter?
What's the voltage like?
120? 240?
Are you okay?
Yeah. Of course I'm all right.
Do you know why
we clink glasses
before drinking?
I'm not sure.
I never thought about it.
It's so that all
the five senses are involved.
We touch the glass,
we smell the drink,
we see its color, we taste it.
Hearing is the only sense
that doesn't participate
unless we create a sound.
Temperate.
Typical Mediterranean weather.
You'll need a coat
in the winter, though.
Converter?
Definitely.
One or two of them, you know.
[KNOCKING]
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Can I come in?
Yeah.
Hi.
Did you find your papers?
Yeah. I forgot I'd
hidden them myself.
I didn't want
you to find them.
Why?
I applied to
the same college as you.
What?
In case you changed
your mind about going,
I wanted to be
able to go with you.
Did you get accepted?
Yeah.
What?
Are you kidding me?
No.
-Why didn't you tell me?
-What if I
didn't get accepted?
Then you would be an idiot.
But I am an idiot.
True.
[CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
I almost got him!
I don't think I
wanna eat that.
[LIVELY MUSIC PLAYING]
Dad?
[HORTENSIA HUMMING]
Let's go, April.
[SINGSONG] This is going to be
a memorable evening.
How do I look?
I wonder why
Martin didn't remarry.
He's not physically impaired
in any way, is he?
[STUTTERING] I don't know.
Anyway,
did you sign up for that
computer class, Yolanda?
You have to think
about your future.
You look great, Grandma.
ORLANDO: Mmm, chicken, pork
and lamb. Wow.
-What are we celebrating,
anyway?
-Fate.
We're
celebrating fate tonight.
That's why I
prepared this special meal.
To celebrate the fate
that has brought
us to this table.
I feel part of
the family already.
Well, you are, you are.
To family.
ALL: To family.
To family, my dear.
Dad, should you be drinking?
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
I can't think of
a better time to celebrate.
LETICIA:
Why don't we eat first?
That's a good idea.
APRIL: Yeah.
-Oh, Martin,
the food looks delicious.
-Thank you, Hortensia.
-Someday you'll have
to let me cook for you.
-Hmm?
I'm the one who taught Yolanda
her way around the kitchen.
I'd like to do a special toast
to my father-in-law.
To you, sir. Yes.
That's nice.
[ALL TOASTING IN SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Now, I have an announcement.
Leading our separate lives,
but under the same roof,
worrying and
caring for one another.
It's that caring,
it's what makes
us a familia, huh?
English or Spanish, Dad.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
And families
shouldn't keep secrets
from each other.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
But I've kept one.
Oh, dear.
Because I...
I didn't want to burden you
with my personal affairs.
But now I can't keep
it any longer, so...
We'll talk some more despues.
[ALL PROTESTING]
Please, Martin.
I can't eat a thing.
Just say what you
have to say, mi amor.
Every Sunday,
I have three
angels sit at my table,
in this casa full
of old memories.
And, now my angelitas
are gonna go
off into the world
and create
memories of their own.
And I can either
sit here by myself
or start a new life.
I've sold the house.
You sold the house?
You did what, Dad?
If I'm to start a new life...
I had to.
But I bought a new one.
Oh!
He bought a new house. Well!
There'll be plenty of
room for visitors, so...
Here's to the new house, then.
MARTIN: New house.
ALL: To the new house.
HORTENSIA: Is that it, dear?
ORLANDO: I hope that's it,
'cause I'm hungry.
-Haven't you
forgotten something?
-Hortensia.
I've gotten to know you
over the last few months.
LETICIA: Oh, my God, Carmen.
I finally have the confidence
to say what I feel.
Oh, si.
Excuse me.
Where's he going?
I had a complete physical.
That's the medical report.
MARIBEL: Leti, grab that.
HORTENSIA: Medical report?
Take a look at it.
Why don't you
look at it, Carmen?
-It says he's in
excellent health.
-Of course he is.
Why wouldn't he be?
[HORTENSIA CHUCKLING]
I'm glad to see
that you're still in
good working order.
And I promise you
that as long as I live,
I'll take good care of
your daughter and April.
I would expect nothing less
from a gentleman
like you, Martin.
And you will always
be welcome in our house.
Yes, of...
What are you
talking about, mi amor?
Hortensia,
will you do me the honor
of giving me
your daughter's
hand in marriage?
[ALL EXCLAIMING]
Dad! Stop drinking.
Martin,
just take a few deep breaths.
You got a little confused.
Start again.
Si, si, si. Yes, yes.
I was confused
but not anymore.
No. I forgot to ask
the woman in question.
What?
Yolanda, will you marry me?
[HORTENSIA GASPS]
HORTENSIA: What?
[ORLANDO EXCLAIMS]
No!
-Dad,
don't you mean Hortensia?
-Of course he does.
The hell I do. I mean Yolanda.
HORTENSIA: Yolanda,
what is he talking about?
Does this mean
you're gonna be my dad?
HORTENSIA: No!
That's up to your mom.
Well, I forbid you
to do this, Yolanda!
I'm a grown woman, Mother.
HORTENSIA:
I forbid it, I said.
[HORTENSIA STUTTERING]
Your father and I love
each other very much.
Yes, Martin, I will marry you.
[ALL EXCLAIMING]
ORLANDO: All right!
MARIBEL: To Dad and Yoli!
I can't believe you guys
never noticed them before.
MARIBEL: Yeah.
You knew?
Mom!
Grandma!
Somebody, pick that woman up.
Give her some air.
YOLANDA: Get her some air.
MARIBEL: Open the door.
-YOLANDA: It's okay.
Mom, you're all right.
-Unzip her dress.
-Don't you touch me,
you pervert!
-"Pervert?"
You should be ashamed
of yourself. All of you!
ORLANDO:
Let her catch her breath.
YOLANDA: Mom?
Are you all right?
What kind of
a family is this?
-Get away!
-ORLANDO:
Is anybody gonna eat?
Bravo.
[SQUEALS]
ANDY: Some water?
No.
I should take her home.
She gonna be all right?
She'll be fine.
Good.
Are you gonna be all right?
I'll be fine.
[GIGGLING]
* You won't admit you love me
* And so
* How am I ever
* To know
* You always tell me
* Perhaps, perhaps, perhaps
I should go.
MAN: Here, let me help you.
Here.
-Dad...
-It's a set of
some of my knives.
Some of them,
for your new kitchen.
-Thank you.
-You better put
'em in your bag
because you'll
never get past security.
If you need anything,
anything at all,
you call, hmm?
If you can't get
decent chipotles in Europe,
I'll send some air express.
Okay.
All right, go, go, Carmen.
You're gonna miss
your plane, go. Bye.
[BIDS FAREWELL IN
SPANISH]
[DISTANT LAUGHTER]
MARIBEL: Am I hallucinating,
or are we having
a pleasant dinner?
CARMEN: "How do you feel
about this, Carmen?
"Is this what you
really want to do?"
LETICIA: He wanted to,
and I wanted to, too,
and we really wanted
to do it properly, Dad, but...
CARMEN: Dad?
Dad?
Barcelona can wait.
Mmm-hmm.
All right?
Oh-ho! Chicken pibil.
Mmm-hmm.
But I wanted you
to taste my version.
MARTIN: All right.
Yeah?
MARTIN: Here we go.
It's, um...
It's exquisito!
[LAUGHING]
You're good.
You're very good, Carmen. Mmm!
Thank you.
Yeah, but, the serranos
is too sharp, too sharp.
Next time,
not so much zest, hmm?
I think that it's better.
It's a little
more interesting.
What? What's wrong?
I can taste.
I can... [SNIFFING]
I can smell and I can taste.
Wait, wait, wait.
One more thing.
There you go, Gavin.
Thank you.
-Hey,
Rock, how's it coming there?
-MAN: My table's waiting.
Table 22, you guys.
Extra special treatment,
please.
Very important people.
Looking good. All right.
All right, wait, wait. Okay.
There we go.
All right, you guys.
Careful on the lobster, okay?
Only two more minutes, please.
Hi. How are you doing?
It's good to see you.
Good. Everything okay?
[ALL CHEERING]
Tonight's lobster.
Oh, that looks so good.
What?
Carmen.
What, Dad?
The lobster.
Are you doing it in a...
You need to sit down,
have a bite,
and then you can criticize it.
All right, all right.
Can you believe him?
Attention, everybody.
I have an announcement.
It's a girl.
I'm so happy for you!
Wow! Nothing but girls!
You're the Dos Equis man.
Give me a high five.
[ PERHAPS,
PERHAPS, PERHAPS PLAYING]