You still need to fill the form out.
Really?
Thank you.
I don't have a pen.
There's a pen right there.
Good morning. Lacuna.
Oh, that offer expired
after the New Year.
Mister Barish?
How are we today?
Not too good, actually.
Oh my God! Stan!
Sorry. I was just
I'm working.
Here, Doctor.
Thank you.
You should not have seen this.
I apologize.
This is a hoax, right?
I mean, this is Clem's
I assure you, no.
There's no such thing as this.
Our files are confidential,
so I can't show you evidence.
Suffice it to say
that Miss Kruczynski was not happy...
and she wanted to move on.
We provide that possibility.
...was not happy,
and wanted to move on.
We provide that possibility.
What the hell is that?
I'm the nicest guy
she ever went out with.
Ah, fuck!
Rob, give it a rest!
It's okay.
I am making a birdhouse.
Joel, you know Clementine's
just like that.
So impulsive.
She decided to erase you as a lark
Alark?
Why did you do that?
Wait, wait!
I want it done. Now.
I told him pre-Valentine's Day
is our busy time -
That's okay, Mary.
But there are people waiting.
Mister Barish,
if you'd like to come inside.
Mary, if you'd take care of Mrs. Woo.
Goodbye, Mrs. Woo.
Of course.
The first thing we need you to do,
Mister Barish...
is to go home and collect everything
you own that has...
some association with Clementine.
Anything.
We'll use these items...
to create a map of Clementine
in your brain.
We'll need photos, clothing...
gifts,
books she may have bought you...
CD's you may have bought together,
journal entries...
We want to empty your home...
We want to empty your life
of Clementine.
After the mapping is done,
our technicians will do the erasing
in your home tonight.
That way, when you awake
in the morning,
you'll find yourself in your...
own bed, as if nothing has happened,
a new life awaiting you.
Wake up, buddy!
I'm sorry, Mrs. Sobel.
You can't have the procedure
done three times in one month.
It's just not our policy here.
How are you today, Mister Barish?
I know it's an emergency.
We'll do everything we can.
We can fit you in on March 1st.
Maybe you could talk to the Doctor.
What day would you like to come
in this week?
Mister Barish!
February is very busy for us because
of Valentine's Day.
This is Stan Fink,
one of our most experienced
and skilled technicians.
He'll be handling your case tonight.
Great to meet you, Mister Barish.
My name is Joel Barish...
and I'm here
to erase Clementine Kruczynski.
Very good.
Now tell me about Clementine.
I was living with this woman, Naomi...
a couple years ago, and my friends,
Rob and Carrie...
invited us to this party
at the beach.
I don't like parties.
And Naomi couldn't go,
but I went...
and I met Clementine.
I'm sorry.
We'll start with
your most recent memories,
and work backwards from there.
There's an emotional core
to each of our memories...
and when you eradicate that core,
it starts its degradation process.
By the time you wake up
in the morning,
all the memories we've targeted...
will have withered and disappeared.
As in a dream upon waking.
Is there any risk of brain damage?
Technically speaking,
the procedure is brain damage.
But it's on a par
with a night of heavy drinking.
Nothing you'll miss.
Comfortable?
What we're doing here is
actually creating a map of your brain.
Let's get started.
If we want to get
this procedure underway tonight,
we have some work to do.
I want you to react to these objects.
There's a good story behind that
I'll get a much better
emotional read-out...
if you refrain from any sort
of verbal description of the items.
Just please try to focus
on the memories.
Sorry.
Healthy activity up there again.
Healthy read-outs.
Very good.
Here's another object.
Next item.
Po-ta-to head.
Just focus on the memories.
Patrick, do me a favor, will you?
Can you check the voltage regulator?
Voltage looks fine.
Really?
I'm not wiping as clean as
I like here.
Technically,
the procedure is brain damage.
But it's on a par
with a night of heavy drinking.
Check the connections, please.
There you are.
I don't understand
what I'm looking at.
Why am I standing here and...
Oh, my God, deja vu.
This is so...
We should get started.
If we want to get the procedure...
underway tonight,
we have some work to do.
I'm in my head already, aren't I?
I suppose so.
This is what it would look like.
Very good.
We'll dispose of these mementos
when we're done here.
Then you won't be confused later
by their unexplainable presence
in your home.
Patrick?
Why are there so many wires?
Because we have a lot of equipment.
Does that help?
Are you sure
you set that thing up properly?
I don't know if I like this.
Ah, yourjournal.
That'll be invaluable.
I met someone tonight.
I don't know what to do.
Her name's Clementine
and she's amazing.
Whoa, Jesus!
What? What?
Careful Step back!
It's fine.
Let's not roach the guy.
Alright. We got that one.
This place is sort of a dump,
don't you think?
It's an apartment, Patrick
Patrick
Well, not a dump, but sort of plain.
Uninspired.
And there's sort of a stale smell.
Patrick Can we just get through this?
We've got a long night ahead of us.
This is the last time I saw you.
It's three o'clock
I kind of wrecked your car.
Driving drunk
It's pathetic.
I was a little tipsy.
Don't call me pathetic!
It is pathetic.
It's irresponsible.
You could have killed somebody.
Maybe you did kill somebody.
Should we turn on the news and see?
Should I check the grill to see
if there's children or small animals?
It's just a fucking dent.
You're like an old lady or something.
What are you like?
A wino?
Jesus.
Are you from the 50's or something?
A wino?
Face it.
You're freaked out because
I was out late without you...
and in your little, wormy brain,
you're trying to figure out...
Did she fuck someone tonight?
See, Clem, I assume
you fucked someone tonight.
Isn't that how
you get people to like you?
I'm sorry, okay?
I didn't mean it.
Your keys.
I won't need them anymore.
I was just angry or annoyed
or something.
Clem.
Got it.
Mary's coming over tonight.
Just thought you'd want to know.
I like when Mary comes to visit.
I just don't think she likes me.
She likes you okay.
So maybe I should invite
my girlfriend over.
I have a girlfriend now.
Do whatever you want.
Did I tell you
I have a new girlfriend?
We have to focus here.
The thing is,
my situation is a little weird.
My girlfriend situation.
I'm sure it is.
Clem, let me drive you home.
Get out of my face, faggot!
Look at it out here!
It's all falling apart!
I'm erasing you, and I'm happy!
You did it to me first!
I can't believe you did this to me!
Goddamnit!
Clem. Did you hear me?
By morning you'll be gone!
The perfect ending
to this piece of shit story!
Is there something wrong with
a girl being attracted to me?
No. I think it's funny.
Who do you think's better- looking,
me or this guy?
Patrick, let's focus.
Remember that girl we did last week?
The one with the potatoes?
That girl
That's this guy's girlfriend.
Was. We took care of that.
I kind of fell in love
with her that night.
What?
You little fucker.
She was unconscious.
She was beautiful, and I stole
a pair of her panties, too.
Jesus!
They were clean.
I don't want to hear this shit.
Stop. We've got work to do.
Okay. Fine.
There's more.
After we did her,
I kind of asked her out.
Jesus.
Do you know how unethical?
It's not really that bad.
Get that look off your face.
What's wrong?
You stole a girl' s panties.
There's someone here...
he stole your underwear.
I don't see anyone.
Joel, where are my boots?
I'm crawling out of my skin!
I should have left you
at the flea market.
Want to go?
I want to have a baby.
Let's talk about it later.
No. I want to have a baby.
I don't think we're ready.
You're not ready.
Do you really think
you could take care of a kid?
What?
I don't want to talk about it here.
I can't hear you.
I can never understand
what you're saying!
I said
I don't want to talk about this!
We're fucking gonna talk about it!
You can't just say you don't
want to talk about it!
I'm sorry.
I'd make a fucking good mother!
I love children.
I'm creative and I'm smart!
It's you, Joel.
It's you who can't commit to anything.
It's going! It's going.
You're lucky I'm interested in you.
I don't even know why I am.
Maybe I should end it right here!
It's over.
Leave you at the flea market,
with the costume jewelry!
Maybe you can find a nice
antique rocking chair to die in!
All the pain. Confusion...
Hi, Patrick
How's it going, Mary?
It's freezing outside.
Find us okay?
Yeah.
Hot.
Poor guy.
Do you have anything real to drink?
We haven't checked yet.
Patrick?
Let me do the honors.
Mary hates me.
Never really had much luck
with the ladies.
Maybe if you stopped stealing
their panties.
You didn't want any, did you, Patrick?
No. That's okay.
Wait.
Blessed are the forgetful,
for they get the better even
of their blunders.
That's Nietzsche.
Beyond Good and Evil.
I found it in my Bartlett's.
What's your Bartlett's?
It's a quote book
It's a book of quotations.
I think Howard
will be in Bartlett's one day.
Definitely.
Howard is pure Bartlett's.
Can you wake him up?
You can't wake him up.
You don't tell me things.
I'm an open book
I tell you everything.
Every damn embarrassing thing.
You don't trust me.
Constantly talking
isn't necessarily communicating.
I don't do that.
I want to know you.
I don't constantly talk.
Jesus.
People have to share things.
That's what intimacy is.
I'm really pissed that
you said that to me!
Sorry.
My life just really
isn't that interesting.
I want to read those journals
you're constantly scribbling in.
What do you write if you don't have
any thoughts or passions or love?
November 19th, Two thousand three.
Dinner at Kang's again.
Are we like those poor couples
you feel... sorry for in restaurants?
Are we the dining dead?
I can't stand the idea of us being
a couple people think that about.
I like that.
How's the chicken?
Good.
More?
No, thank you.
She's going to be drunk
and stupid now.
Would you do me a favor
and clean the goddamn hair...
off the soap
when you're done in the shower?
Yeah, it's gross.
I think it's just...
Repulsive.
It's repulsive.
Can we get through this?
Patrick?
Hey, Tangerine.
Patrick, it's you.
I'm so miserable right now.
What's wrong?
I don't know.
I'm just confused about everything.
What are you confused about?
Everything's fine.
Do you love me?
Of course I do.
Where's the self -help section?
Do you think I'm ugly?
No. You're beautiful.
Maybe I should come over.
Oh no. I'm a mess.
Just let me come over.
I'll cheer you up.
Okay.
Can I leave for a while?
My girlfriend's really upset.
We're right in the middle
of erasing this poor man's -
Let him go. I'll help.
How hard can it be?
She hates me.
She wants me to go.
Go.
Alright.
I'll be right over, Tangerine.
You like?
I matched my sweatshirt exactly.
I like it.
You look like a tangerine.
Clemen-teen the tangerine.
Juicy and seedless.
I like that.
I like tangerines.
Can you see me doing ducks?
Tangerine...
How does he know to call you that?
How did who know?
Oh my God. Clem?
That's what they called themselves.
The Clash,
the only band that mattered.
And they called themselves
that for a reason.
It's amazing, isn't it?
Like Social Justice.
Yeah, it's totally incredible.
What Howard gives to the world.
Yeah.
To let people begin again.
It's beautiful.
You look at a baby, and it's
so pure and so free and so...
clean and...
Adults are this mess
of sadness and...
phobias.
And Howard just makes it all go away.
Baby, what's going on?
I don't know.
I'm lost, I'm scared,
I feel like I'm disappearing.
My skin's coming off!
I'm getting old!
Nothing makes any sense to me!
You're not getting old.
Nothing makes any sense.
Tangerine...
It's okay.
Let's go out dancing.
You want to go out to Montauk with me?
Montauk?
Yeah. No!
Come up to Boston with me.
Sure.
We can go next weekend.
No. I have to go now.
I have to see the frozen Charles now.
Hi, it's Joel.
Leave me a message after the beep
and I'll get back to you.
Pick up.
Hello? What's up?
I got into a little situation
with the old lady.
Can you handle things tonight alone?
I'm really sorry.
Don't worry.
I've got it under control.
He's on auto-pilot now anyway.
Thanks. I owe you big-time.
I've got to go.
Look! You and me
on the Charles River.
I could die right now.
I'm just happy.
I've never felt that before.
I'm exactly where I want...
I'm so excited!
I'm excited, too.
Cool.
I got you this thing.
Happy early Valentine's Day.
Wow. What is it?
I don't know. Open it up.
It's gorgeous.
You like it?
It's just my taste, really.
I've never gone out with a guy
who bought me jewelry I liked.
Thank you.
Joely?
Yeah, Tangerine?
Am I ugly?
When I was a kid I thought I was.
Can't believe I'm crying already.
Sometimes
I think people don't understand
how lonely it is to be a kid.
Like you don't matter.
So, I'm eight...
and I have these toys, these dolls.
My favorite is this ugly girl doll
who I call Clementine.
And I keep yelling at her
You can't be ugly!
Be pretty!
It's weird.
Like if I can transform her...
I would magically change, too.
You're pretty.
Joely. Don't ever leave me.
Please let me keep this memory.
Just this one.
I want to hold your hand. Come on.
Stop it!