Watch this shot. Whoa!
Shoot, man. Go!
Yeah!
Heh-heh!
Huh!
Gee!
Hey, chickie! Chick, chick, chick!
Jet Boy! Hey, Jet Boy!
Jet, Jet, Jet!
Beat it!
Jets, get outta here!
Hey, Snowboy! Yeah!
Hey!
Come on.
Beat it!
Chico! Chico!
Olé, chico! Olé!
OK, here we go.
Jets! Hey, Jets!
Cracko, Indio!
Let's check him, come on!
Mío, mío, mío!
Hey, Jets!
Ándale, chico! Ándalelele!
Jets, come on!
Hey, Jets!
Hallo!
Jets, come on! Por aquí!
Come on!
Come on, boys, huh?
Hey, come on, huh?
Jets!
Jets! Jets!
Aagh!
Break it up, you punks!
Cut it out!
Come on, break it up, I said.
Come on. Break it up!
Come on!
How many times have I told you
punks to cut this stuff out?
- Why, if it ain't Lieutenant Schrank!
- Top o' the day, Lieutenant Schrank!
- And Officer Krupke!
- Top o' the day, Officer Krupke!
I'll give you the top o' the head!
Hey you! Get down.
But we're having such fun.
We enjoy the playground.
It keeps us deprived children
off the foul city streets.
- Shut up!
- And born like we was on the hot pavement!
You wanna get your skull broke?
Hey, Baby John, come here!
Come here!
All right.
Which one of these Puerto Ricans
bloodied you? Huh?
Well, sir...
Which one?
Excuse me, sir.
As a matter of fact, er...
we have suspicion
that the job was done by a cop.
- Two cops.
- At the very least.
Impossible.
In America, nothing is impossible.
All right, wise guys.
Now, you listen to me.
All of you!
You hoodlums
don't own these streets...
and I've had all the roughhouse I'm
gonna put up with around here!
You wanna kill each other?
Kill each other.
But you ain't gonna do it on my beat.
- Are there any questions?
- Yes, sir.
Would you mind
translating that into Spanish?
Get your friends out
of here, Bernardo...
and stay out.
Please.
OK, Sharks.
Vámonos.
Boy, oh, boy.
As if this neighbourhood
wasn't crummy enough.
Now, look, fellas. Fellas!
Look, let's be reasonable, huh?
If I don't get some law and order here...
I get busted down to a traffic corner.
Your friend don't like traffic corners.
So that means you're gonna start
making nice with the PRs from now on.
I said nice, get it?
Cos if you don't...
and I catch any of you
brawling again in my territory...
I'm gonna beat
the living crud out of each of you...
and see that you go
to the can and rot there!
Say goodbye to the nice boys, Krupke.
Goodbye, boys.
Jail? Gee!
You hoodlums don't own the streets.
- Go play in the park.
- Keep off of the grass.
- Get out of the house.
- Keep off the block.
Keep off the world.
A gang that don't own
the street is nothin'!
We do own it!
Come on, Jets. Round up.
Not you, Anybodys. Beat it!
Riff, you've gotta let me in the gang!
Didn't you just see me? I was smash!
I'm a killer, I wanna fight!
How else is she gonna
get a guy to touch her?
- You dirty rat!
- The road, little girl, the road!
Beat it!
Ah, beat it!
OK, come on.
OK, now, listen.
We fought hard for this turf
and we won't give it up.
The Emeralds claimed it
and we shut 'em out.
The Hawks tried
and we knocked 'em down the cellar.
- The PRs are different.
- They multiply.
They keep coming.
- They eat all the food.
- Breathe all the air!
Help, I'm drowning in tamales!
You heard Lieutenant Schrank.
We gotta make nice
with them Puerto Ricans, or else!
Are we gonna let 'em move in
and take it all away from us, or else?
You're damn right, no.
So what are we gonna do, buddy boys?
I'll tell you what we're gonna do.
We're gonna speed fast.
We're gonna move like lightning!
We're gonna clean them Sharks up
once and for all...
so they ain't never gonna
set foot on our turf again.
And we're gonna do it
in one all-out fight.
- A rumble!
- Now, cool, Action Boy.
The Sharks want
a piece of this world too.
And they're real down boys.
They might ask for er...
blades, zip guns.
Zip guns?
Well, gee!
I ain't finalisin' and saying they will,
Baby John.
I'm just saying that they might.
And we've gotta be prepared.
Now, what's your mood, Jets?
I say, go, go!
- I say mix!
- I say sock 'em!
- Tear 'em!
- Yeah!
But if they say blades or guns?
I say let's forget the whole thing.
- What?
- What do you say, Riff?
I say this turf is small...
but it's all we got, huh?
I want to hold it
like we always held it...
with skin!
But if they say blades...
I say blades.
If they say guns...
I say guns.
I say I want the Jets
to be the number one.
To sail!
To hold the sky!
Then rev us off! Voom va-voom!
- Cracko jacko!
- Diga diga dum.
OK, cats, we rumble.
Now!
Protocolity calls for a war council
with the Sharks to set it all up.
I will personally give
the bad news to Bernardo.
- You gotta take a lieutenant.
- That's me.
- That's Tony.
- Who needs Tony?
We need Tony.
His rep is bigger
than the whole West Side.
He don't belong no more.
Now, cut it, Action!
Me and Tony started the Jets.
So where is he?
How come he takes a lousy job?
Youth Board corrupted him.
- Temporary sickness!
- Wait and see.
Them fists when we beat the Emeralds!
- He saved my ever-Iovin' neck.
- He'll do it again.
He always came through for
us, and he always will.
♪ When you're a Jet ♪
♪ You're a Jet all the way ♪
♪ From your first cigarette
to your last dying day ♪
♪ When you're a Jet ♪
♪ Let 'em do what they can ♪
♪ You've got brothers around ♪
♪ You're a family man ♪
♪ You're never alone ♪
♪ You're never disconnected ♪
♪ You're home with your own ♪
♪ When company's expected ♪
♪ You're well protected ♪
♪ Then you are set with a capital J ♪
♪ Which you'll never forget
till they cart you away ♪
♪ When you're a Jet ♪
♪ You stay ♪
♪ A Jet ♪
I know Tony like I know me.
- And I guarentee you can count him in.
- Let's get cracking.
- Where will you find Bernardo?
- PR territory ain't safe.
- He'll be at the dance.
- That's neutral territory.
A-rab, I'm gonna make nice with him.
I'm only gonna challenge him.
Great, Daddy-O!
Everybody dress up sweet and sharp.
Meet Tony and me at the dance at 10.
- And walk tall!
- We always walk tall!
- We're Jets!
- The greatest!
♪ When you're a Jet ♪
♪ You're the top cat in town ♪
♪ You're the gold-medal kid ♪
♪ With the heavyweight crown ♪
♪ When you're a Jet ♪
♪ You're the swingingest thing ♪
♪ Little boy, you're a man ♪
♪ Little man, you're a king ♪
♪ The Jets are in gear ♪
♪ Our cylinders are clicking ♪
♪ The Sharks'll steer clear ♪
♪ Cos every Puerto Rican's
a lousy chicken ♪
♪ Here come the Jets
like a bat out of hell ♪
♪ Someone gets in our way ♪
♪ Someone don't feel so well ♪
♪ Here come the Jets ♪
♪ Little world step aside ♪
♪ Better go underground ♪
♪ Better run, better hide ♪
♪ We're drawing the line ♪
♪ So keep your noses hidden ♪
♪ We're hanging a sign ♪
♪ Says Visitors Forbidden ♪
♪ And we ain't kiddin' ♪
♪ Here come the Jets, yeah ♪
♪ And we're gonna beat ♪
♪ Every last buggin' gang
on the whole buggin' street ♪
♪ On the whole ♪
♪ Buggin' ♪
♪ Ever-Iovin' ♪
♪ Street... Yeah! ♪
- Tony, you're not listening.
- I hear you, Riff.
Then why don't you answer?
I don't want to hurt you.
You're my best friend.
Womb to tomb?
Birth to earth!
That's why you gotta come
to the dance tonight...
and stand up with me.
Come on, Tony. Just say yes.
Riff.
Do you ever stop to figure...
how many bubbles
are in one bottle of soda pop?
Tony, this is important.
Everything's important, Riff.
You. Me. The sweet guy I work for.
The Sharks walk bad. They bite hard.
If we don't stop 'em now, we'll never...
Here! Work for a living.
How do you like that?
Four years,
I live with a buddy and his family.
I think I'm digging a guy's character.
Boy, am I a victim
of disappointment in you.
End your suffering, little man.
Why don't you just
pack up your gear and move out?
Cos your ma's hot for me.
No! No, it's cos I hate
living with my buggin' uncle.
- Come on! Come on!
- Uncle! Uncle!
Now...
Go play games with the Jets.
Why not? They're the greatest.
Ain't they?
Were.
Were?
You found something better?
No. Not yet, but...
But what?
You won't dig it, Riff.
So try me.
Come on, Tony, try me.
OK.
Every single night,
for the last month...
I wake up, and I'm reaching out.
- For what?
- I don't know.
A dame?
It's right outside the door.
Just around the corner...
but it's coming.
What is?
I don't know!
It's like the kick
I used to get from being a Jet.
Well, now you're talking!
Man, without a gang, you're an orphan!
With a gang,
you walk in twos, threes, fours.
When your crew is the best,
when you're a Jet...
you're out in the sun,
you're home, free home.
Riff, I've had it.
Tony.
Tony, look at me, will you?
Come on, look at me.
I'm looking at you.
I never asked the time of day
from a clock, did I?
I never asked nothing from nobody.
But I'm asking you...
Come to the dance tonight.
I promised Doc
I'd clean up the store tonight.
Then do it after the dance.
Tony, I already told the guys
you'd be there.
If you don't show,
I'll be marked lousy.
What time did you tell 'em?
10.
For me, Tony. For Riff.
- 10 it is.
- Womb to tomb?
Birth to earth! I'll live to regret this.
What you're waiting for
may be twitching at the dance.
Yeah. Who knows?
Who knows?
♪ Could be ♪
♪ Who knows? ♪
♪ There's something due any day ♪
♪ I will know right away ♪
♪ Soon as it shows ♪
♪ It may come cannonballin'
down through the sky ♪
♪ Gleam in its eye, bright as a rose ♪
♪ Who knows? ♪
♪ It's only just out of reach ♪
♪ Down the block, on a beach ♪
♪ Under a tree ♪
♪ I got a feeling
there's a miracle due ♪
♪ Gonna come true ♪
♪ Coming to me ♪
♪ Could it be? ♪
♪ Yes, it could ♪
♪ Something's coming, something good ♪
♪ If I can wait ♪
♪ Something's coming ♪
♪ I don't know what it is ♪
♪ But it is gonna be great ♪
♪ With a click ♪
♪ With a shock ♪
♪ Phone will jingle ♪
♪ Door will knock ♪
♪ Open the latch ♪
♪ Something's coming ♪
♪ Don't know when, but it's soon ♪
♪ Catch the moon, one-handed catch ♪
♪ Around the corner ♪
♪ Or whistlin' down the river ♪
♪ Come on, deliver ♪
♪ To me ♪
♪ Will it be ♪
♪ Yes, it will ♪
♪ Maybe just by holding still ♪
♪ It'll be there ♪
♪ Come on, something ♪
♪ Come on in, don't be shy ♪
♪ Meet a guy, pull up a chair ♪
♪ The air is hummin' ♪
♪ And something great is coming ♪
♪ Who knows ♪
♪ It's only just out of reach ♪
♪ Down the block, on a beach ♪
♪ Maybe tonight ♪
Por favor, Anita. You are my friend.
You must make the neck lower.
Stop heckling me. We are working
on our time, not the old lady's.
One inch.
How much can one little inch do?
Too much.
Anita, it is now to be
a dress for dancing...
no longer for praying.
With those boys, you can start in
dancing and end up praying!
Querida. One little inch.
- Un poquitino.
- Bernardo made me promise.
Bernardo!
One month have I been in this country!
Do I ever touch excitement?
I sew here all day.
I sit at home all night.
Why did my brother bring me here?
To marry Chino.
Chino.
When I look at Chino, nothing happens.
What do you expect to happen?
I don't know. Something.
What happens
when you look at Bernardo?
It's when I don't look that it happens.
I think I will tell Mama and Papa...
about you and Nardo
in the balcony of the movies.
Oh! I will rip this to shreds!
No.
But if you perhaps could manage
to lower the neck...
Next year.
- I hate that dress!
- Then, don't wear it.
And don't come to the dance tonight.
- Don't come?
- Here!
Could we not dye it red?
No, we could not!
White is for babies.
I will be the only one there in a white...
Aaah!
- Oh, sí.
- Ah.
It is a beautiful dress.
I love you!
- Are you ready, ladies?
- Nardo, come in!
Is it not beautiful?
Ah, yes.
Very.
Er... I didn't quite hear.
Ah, very beautiful.
Come in, Chino. Do not be afraid.
But this is a shop for ladies!
We won't bite you...
till we know you better!
Chino...
keep both eyes on Maria tonight,
in case I cannot.
You too, Anita.
My brother is a silly watchdog.
Aah, my sister is a precious jewel.
What am I? Cut glass?
Nardo, it is most important
that I have a wonderful time tonight.
Because tonight
is the real beginning of my life...
as a young lady of America.
Get out of here!
Hey, Nardo, ¿ cómo estás?
Come on, guys.
Maria!
Hey, Maria.
- Hey, look what I got.
- Hi, Consuelo.
These are some of my friends
you have not met.
- Hey. Pick up.
- How are you?
This is Loco.
- Mucho gusto.
- Encantada.
Teresita.
- My sister, Maria.
- Good evening.
- Luis Arruza.
- Encantada.
- Rosalia, hi!
- Oye, Nardo.
All right, boys and girls, all right.
Attention, please.
Attention!
- Come here.
- Let's get on with it!
My, this is a fine turnout
we have here tonight.
It's all for you, Glad Hand.
I know.
I know you boys and girls are here...
because you want
to make new friends...
and get closer to old ones.
Tonight we're gonna do
something special.
We're gonna have a get-together dance.
Ginger-peachy!
All right. All right, now.
Kids, kids.
I want you to form two circles.
How many?
Two. Boys on the outside
and girls on the inside.
Where are you?
All right.
Now, er...
When the music stops...
each boy dances with
whichever girl is opposite.
OK?
OK.
Two circles, kids.
Well, it won't hurt you to try.
Oo-ooh, it hurts, it hurts!
Snowboy.
That's it, kids. Keep the ball rolling.
Around she goes, and where she stops...
nobody knows.
All right, here we go.
Boys to my right and girls to my left.
♪ "The Dance At The Gym" ♪
- Mambo!
Go!
Hey, Tony.
Mambo!
Baila! Baila!
You're not thinking I'm someone else?
I know you are not.
Or that we met before?
I know we have not.
I felt...
I knew something
was going to happen...
had to happen,
but this is so much more.
My hands are cold.
Yours, too.
So warm.
So beautiful.
Beautiful.
It's so much to believe.
You are not making a joke?
I have not yet learned
how to joke that way.
I think now I never will.
Get your hands off, American!
- Keep off my sister!
- Sister?
- Can't you see he's one of them?
- I saw only him.
They want only one thing
from a Puerto Rican girl.
- That's a lie!
- Later, Tony.
- Don't listen.
- She will listen to her brother first.
Please! Everything was going well.
- Come on, we're here to have fun!
- I want to talk to you.
Nardo!
Take her out of here, we're going home.
Nardo, it is my first dance.
Please, we are family. Now, go.
Come, Maria.
Maria.
I don't want you.
I want you, though.
I want you for a war council.
Jets and Sharks.
- The pleasure is mine.
- Let's go outside.
I would not leave ladies alone
with your kind around.
We will meet you at midnight.
- Doc's candy store?
- Mm-hm.
And no jazz before then.
I understand the rules...
native boy.
Ice.
Doc's at midnight. Spread the word.
Right, Daddy-O.
Maria.
Maria!
♪ The most beautiful sound I ever heard ♪
♪ Maria ♪
♪ Maria, Maria, Maria ♪
♪ All the beautiful sounds
of the world in a single word ♪
♪ Maria ♪
♪ Maria, Maria, Maria ♪
♪ Maria, Maria ♪
♪ Maria ♪
♪ I just met a girl named Maria ♪
♪ And suddenly that name ♪
♪ Will never be the same to me ♪
♪ Maria ♪
♪ I just kissed a girl named Maria ♪
♪ And suddenly I found ♪
♪ How wonderful a sound can be ♪
♪ Maria ♪
♪ Say it loud and there's music playing ♪
♪ Say it soft ♪
♪ And it's almost like praying ♪
♪ Maria ♪
♪ I'll never stop saying ♪
♪ Maria, Maria ♪
♪ Maria ♪
♪ Maria, Maria, Maria ♪
♪ Say it loud and
there's music playing ♪
♪ Say it soft ♪
♪ And it's almost like praying ♪
♪ Maria ♪
♪ I'll never stop saying ♪
♪ The most beautiful sound I ever heard ♪
♪ Maria ♪
I do not say these things
to spoil your evening...
or to hear myself talk.
- I am here longer than you.
- Sí, Nardo.
When you are old and married
with five children...
you can tell me what to do.
Now it is the other way round.
Now go to bed.
He's the old married woman.
You know, she has a mother.
Also a father.
They know this country even less.
You do not know it at all.
Girls here are free to have fun.
She is in America now.
Puerto Rico is in America now.
Sometimes I don't know
which is thicker...
your skull or your accent.
- Vámonos, muchachos.
- Let them wait.
Is Maria all right?
- I should be so all right.
- It will not happen again.
Pepe, Indio!
Tonight, things will be settled.
First, settle your stomach.
Never mind my stomach.
Well, I mind your nose
and your head broken.
- Broken?
- Sure.
They use Maria for an excuse
to start World War III.
It is more than that.
More than what? She was only dancing.
With an American...
who is really a Polack.
Says the Spic.
You are not so cute.
- That Tony is.
- And he works.
A delivery boy.
- And what are you?
- An assistant.
And Chino makes half
of what the Polack makes.
- The Polack is American.
- Here's the commercial.
Your mother's a Pole,
your father's a Swede.
You were born here,
that's all that you need.
You are an American. But us?
Foreigners!
Lice! Cockroaches!
Hey, but it's true.
When I think of how I
thought it would be here.
We came like children -
believing, trusting.
With our hearts open!
With our arms open!
You came with your mouth open.
You did
and you'll go back in handcuffs.
- I'll go in a Cadillac!
- Air-conditioned.
- Built-in bar.
- Telephone.
And television.
If you had all that here,
why would you go back to Puerto Rico?
Even if you didn't have all that here,
why go back?
It's so good here?
It's so good there?
We had nothing.
Ah, we still have nothing...
only more expensive.
- Anita Josefina... Beatriz...
- No, no. It's plain Anita now.
- Etcetera, etcetera.
- Leave me alone. At least I left.
Once an immigrant, always an immigrant.
Instead of a shampoo,
she was brainwashed.
- Stop it!
- She's given up Puerto Rico...
now she's queer for Uncle Sam.
Oh, no.
That's not true.
♪ Puerto Rico ♪
♪ My heart's devotion ♪
♪ Let it sink back in the ocean ♪
♪ Always the hurricanes blowing ♪
♪ Always the population growing ♪
♪ And the money owing ♪
♪ And the sunlight streaming ♪
♪ And the natives steaming ♪
♪ I like the island Manhattan ♪
I know you do!
♪ Smoke on your pipe ♪
♪ And put that in ♪
♪ I like to be in America ♪
♪ OK by me in America ♪
♪ Everything free in America ♪
♪ For a small fee in America ♪
Olé!
♪ Buying on credit is so nice ♪
♪ One look at us and they charge twice ♪
♪ I have my own washing machine ♪
♪ What will you have,
though, to keep clean? ♪
♪ Skyscrapers bloom in America ♪
♪ Cadillacs zoom in America ♪
♪ Industry boom in America ♪
♪ 12 in a room in America ♪
♪ Lots of new housing with more space ♪
♪ Lots of doors slamming in our face ♪
♪ I'll get a terrace apartment ♪
♪ Better get rid of your accent ♪
♪ Life can be bright in America ♪
♪ If you can fight in America ♪
♪ Life is all right in America ♪
♪ If you're all white in America ♪
♪ La la la la la America ♪
♪ America ♪
♪ Here you are free and you have pride ♪
♪ Long as you stay on your own side ♪
♪ Free to be anything you choose ♪
♪ Free to wait tables and shine shoes ♪
♪ Everywhere grime in America ♪
♪ Organised crime in America ♪
♪ Terrible time in America ♪
♪ You forget I'm in America ♪
♪ I think I go back to San Juan ♪
♪ I know a boat you can get on ♪
Bye-bye!
♪ Everyone there will give big cheer ♪
♪ Everyone there will have moved here ♪
Ow ow ow!
Ow ow oooow!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Hey, hey! Hey, muchachos!
Vamonos, muchachos. Es tarde ya.
Corre, es tarde! Come on!
Hey, Chino.
What are you doing?
- Meet me on the roof later.
- Meet me on the roof later!
- Will you or won't you?
Hey!
Well, will you?
You have your big important war council.
The council...
or me?
First one...
then the other.
No.
I'm an American girl now.
I don't wait.
Back home, women know their place.
Back home, little boys
don't have war councils.
Ah, but they do here.
You want me to be an American,
don't you?
Buenas noches, Anita.
Josefina...
Teresita... Beatriz del Carmen...
Margarita...
etcetera, etcetera.
Oh! Immigrant!
Buenas noches.
Ten cuidado.
- Buenas noches, Maria.
- Adios, Maria.
Goodnight, Maria.
Goodnight!
Maria!
- Maria!
- Ssh!
- Quiet.
Come down.
- No!
- Maria.
Please.
My mother and father will wake up.
Just for a minute.
A minute is not enough.
- For an hour, then.
- I cannot.
- Then forever.
- Ssh!
Then I'm coming up.
Maria!
Momentito, Papa.
Now see what you've done.
- Momentito, Maria.
- Cáilate.
- Ssh!
It is dangerous. If Bernardo knew...
Well, let him know.
I'm not one of 'em, Maria.
But you are not one of us...
and I am not one of you.
- To me, you're all the beautiful...
- Maruca.
Sí, ya vengo, Papa.
Maruca?
His pet name for me.
I like him... and he will like me.
No.
He is like Bernardo...
Afraid.
Imagine being afraid of you!
You see?
I see you.
Oh, Maria. See only me.
♪ Only you ♪
♪ You're the only thing
I'll see forever ♪
♪ In my eyes, in my words ♪
♪ And in everything I do ♪
♪ Nothing else but you, ever ♪
♪ And there's nothing for me but Maria ♪
♪ Every sight that I see is Maria. ♪
♪ Tony, Tony ♪
♪ Always you,
every thought I'll ever know ♪
♪ Everywhere I go, you'll be ♪
♪ All the world is only you and me ♪
♪ Tonight, tonight ♪
♪ It all began tonight ♪
♪ I saw you and the world went away ♪
♪ Tonight, tonight ♪
♪ There's only you tonight ♪
♪ What you are, what you do ♪
♪ What you say ♪
♪ Today ♪
♪ All day I had a feeling ♪
♪ A miracle would happen ♪
♪ I know now I was right ♪
♪ For here you are ♪
♪ And what was just a world ♪
♪ Is a star ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
♪ The world is full of light ♪
♪ With suns and moons
all over the place ♪
♪ Tonight, tonight ♪
♪ The world is wild and bright ♪
♪ Going mad ♪
♪ Shooting sparks into space ♪
♪ Today, the world was just an address ♪
♪ A place for me to live in ♪
♪ No better than all right ♪
♪ But here you are ♪
♪ And what was just a world ♪
♪ Is a star ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
Maruca! Es tarde.
I cannot stay. Go quickly.
I'm not afraid.
Please.
Goodnight.
Buenas noches.
I love you.
Yes.
Yes, hurry.
Tony?
- When will I see you?
- Tomorrow.
I work at the bridal shop
across the street... Madam Lucia's.
- I'll come there.
- At closing time, 6.00.
Yeah, yeah.
Goodnight.
- Tony!
- Sssh!
When you come, use the back door.
Sí.
Tony!
What does Tony stand for?
Anton.
Te adoro, Anton.
Te adoro, Maria.
♪ Goodnight ♪
♪ Sleep well and when you dream ♪
♪ Dream of me ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
Where are them Sharks?
Maybe they're too chicken to show.
A-rab, Riff and Ice ain't here yet.
- Come on.
- He don't use a switchblade.
He don't even use an atomic ray gun.
- Who don't?
- Captain Marvel.
Gee, I love him.
So marry him!
I ain't never gonna get married.
Too noisy!
You ain't never gonna get married.
Too ugly!
Pow! Pow!
Cracko jacko!
Down goes a teenage hoodlum.
Gee! C-could a real zip gun
make you do like that?
I know what it could make you do.
You'd better wear diapers.
Go walk the streets like your sister!
Listen, jailbait!
I licked you twice
and I can do it again!
Come on, Anybodys. Knock it off.
- Riff's here.
- Jets all present?
I'm proud of you.
You done good at the dance.
- So where are they?
- Unwind, Action.
- Any sign of Tony?
- The Invisible Man?
What are the Sharks gonna ask for?
- Mercy.
- Rubber hoses, maybe.
- Relax, little man.
- You tell him, Daddy-O.
- I'm ready.
- Easy! Cool!
- Chung chung!
- Cracko jacko!
Ooblee-oo.
Riff, in a tight spot,
you need every man you can get.
- No!
- An American tragedy.
- Pow!
- Oh, poo!
Ooblee-poo.
Look, when the Sharks come,
you chicks cut out.
We might. And then again, we might not.
This ain't kids' stuff, Graziella.
I and Velma ain't kids' stuff, neither.
Are we, Vel?
No, thank you.
Ooh! Ooblee-ooh!
And you can punctuate it.
Ooh!
What are we pooping around
with dumb broads?
I and Velma ain't dumb.
Hey, the bulls!
- Hey, you!
- Hey, who?
- Who, who?
- Who, me?
Who, her?
Top o' the evening, Officer Krupke.
You!
- Who? Me, sir?
- Yeah, you.
Didn't you hear me?
Yes, sir. I got 20-20 hearing.
Why didn't you answer?
His mother told him
not to answer back to a cop.
- You want me to run you in?
- Indeed not... sir.
I ought to run all yous punks in.
Why are you standing around
on the sidewalks?
You see, sir. We're afraid to go home.
Such a bad environment.
- We don't get no love there.
- Oh, it's awful.
If you don't leave us stay out here...
we're liable to turn into
juvenile delinquents.
I know yous was
cooking up something tonight.
Yous won't put nothing over on me.
Sergeant, come on. We've got a 10-13.
Go on! Get a move on, all of yous.
Don't let me catch
none of yous here when I get back.
See you around now.
Hey, hey, hey!
- You forgot to say goodbye.
- They ain't got no manners.
Don't let me catch you here
when I get back.
- They treat us like we ain't human.
- He was pretty mad.
So what happened? A big fat nothing.
Suppose he comes back
while we're having the war council?
We'll snow him some more.
Cops believe all they read
in the papers about us JDs.
So that's what we give 'em!
Something to believe in.
Hey, you!
- Who, me, Officer Krupke?
- Yeah, you!
Give me one good reason...
for not dragging you down
to the station, you punk!
♪ Dear, kindly Sergeant Krupke ♪
♪ You gotta understand ♪
♪ It's just our bringing up-ke ♪
♪ That gets us out of hand ♪
♪ Our mothers all are junkies ♪
♪ Our fathers all are drunks ♪
♪ Golly, Moses ♪
♪ Naturally, we're punks ♪
♪ Gee, Officer Krupke ♪
♪ We're very upset ♪
♪ We never had the love
that every child ought to get ♪
♪ We ain't no delinquents ♪
♪ We're misunderstood ♪
- ♪ Deep down inside us, there is good ♪
- ♪ There is good ♪
♪ There is good, there is good ♪
♪ There is untapped good ♪
♪ Like inside the worst of us is good ♪
That's a touching good story!
Let me tell it to the world!
Just tell it to the judge!
♪ Dear, kindly judge, Your Honour ♪
♪ My parents treat me rough ♪
♪ With all their marijuana,
they won't give me a puff ♪
♪ They didn't want to have me ♪
♪ But somehow I was had ♪
♪ Leapin' lizards ♪
♪ That's why I'm so bad ♪
♪ Right! Officer Krupke ♪
♪ You're really a square ♪
♪ This boy don't need a judge,
he needs an analyst's care ♪
♪ It's just his neurosis
that ought to be cured ♪
♪ He's psychologically disturbed ♪
I'm disturbed!
♪ We're disturbed, we're disturbed ♪
♪ We're the most disturbed ♪
♪ Like we're psychologically disturbed ♪
Hear ye! Hear ye!
In the opinion of this court,
this child is depraved...
on account he ain't had a normal home.
I'm depraved on account I'm deprived!
So, take him to a headshrinker.
- You!
- Who me?
♪ My daddy beats my mommy ♪
♪ My mommy clobbers me ♪
♪ My grandpa is a commie ♪
♪ My grandma pushes tea ♪
♪ My sister wears a moustache ♪
♪ My brother wears a dress ♪
♪ Goodness gracious ♪
♪ That's why I'm a mess ♪
♪ Yes! Officer Krupke ♪
♪ He shouldn't be here ♪
♪ This boy don't need a couch,
he needs a useful career ♪
♪ Society's played him
a terrible trick ♪
♪ And sociologically he's sick ♪
♪ I am sick! ♪
♪ We are sick, we are sick ♪
♪ We are sick, sick, sick ♪
♪ Like we're sociologically sick ♪
In my opinion...
this child does not need
to have his head shrunk at all.
Juvenile delinquency
is purely a social disease.
Hey, I got a social disease!
So take him to a social worker.
- Which way?
- That way.
♪ Dear, kindly social worker ♪
♪ They tell me, "Get a job" ♪
♪ Like be a soda jerker ♪
♪ Which means like be a slob ♪
♪ It's not I'm antisocial ♪
♪ I'm only anti-work ♪
♪ Gloryosky ♪
♪ That's why I'm a jerk ♪
♪ Officer Krupke ♪
♪ You've done it again ♪
♪ This boy don't need a job ♪
♪ He needs a year in the pen ♪
♪ It ain't just a question
of misunderstood ♪
- ♪ Deep down inside him, he's no good ♪
- ♪ I'm no good ♪
♪ We're no good, we're no good ♪
♪ We're no earthly good ♪
♪ Like the best of us is no damn good ♪
- ♪ The trouble is he's lazy ♪
- ♪ The trouble is he drinks ♪
- ♪ The trouble is he's crazy ♪
- ♪ The trouble is he stinks ♪
- ♪ The trouble is he's growing ♪
- ♪ The trouble is he's grown ♪
♪ Krupke, we've got troubles of our own ♪
♪ Gee, Officer Krupke ♪
♪ We're down on our knees ♪
♪ Cos no-one wants a fella
with a social disease ♪
♪ Gee, Officer Krupke ♪
♪ What are we to do? ♪
♪ Krup you! ♪
Curfew, gentlemen and ladies.
Aren't you up late, Baby John?
I got insomnia, Doc. Too many worries.
- Anyone seen Tony tonight?
- You bet you we did.
He was supposed to clean up the store.
Maybe he decided to clean up the PRs.
Tony?
Doc, you ain't gonna close up now?
I'm not?
- We got a war council here.
- A who?
To determine weapons.
We're gonna set up a mix with the PRs.
Weapons? You couldn't play basketball?
Get with it, buster.
You don't understand.
We got special business here.
Making trouble for the Puerto Ricans?
- They make trouble for us.
- For you, trouble is a relief.
We gotta stand up to 'em.
It's important.
Fightin' over a piece of street
is so important?
- To us it is!
- To hoodlums it is!
Who are you calling hoodlums?
- War councils...
- Don't start.
- When I was your age...
- When you was my age? ♪
When my old man was my age!
When my brother was my age!
You was never my age, none of you!
The sooner you creeps get hip to that,
the sooner you'll dig us.
I'll dig you an early grave,
that's what I'll dig.
Dig, dig, dig.
OK, Doc, set 'em up. Cokes all round.
Let's get down to business.
Bernardo hasn't learned
about gracious living.
I don't like you either... so cut it.
OK, kick it, Doc.
- Boys, couldn't you talk...
- Kick it!
We challenge you to a rumble.
All out, once and for all. Accept?
- On what terms?
- Whatever terms you're calling.
- You crossed the line once too often.
- You started it.
Who jumped Baby John today?
Who jumped me when I moved here?
Who asked you to move here?
- Move where you're wanted!
- Spics!
- Mick!
- Wop!
We accept.
- Time.
- Tomorrow?
After dark.
- Place.
- The park?
The river.
Under the highway.
Weapons.
Doc! Hey, Doc!
- Tony!
- Weapons.
Weapons! ♪
Weapons.
- You call.
- Your challenge.
Afraid to call?
Rocks.
- Belts.
- Pipes.
- Cans.
- Bricks.
- Bats!
- Clubs!
- Chains.
- Bottles, knives, guns!
- What a coop full of chickens.
- Who are you calling chicken?
- Every dog knows his own.
- I'm calling you all chicken.
Big tough buddy boys
gotta throw bricks?
Afraid to get in close and slug it out?
Afraid to use plain skin?
Not even garbage?
- That ain't a rumble!
- Who says!
You said call weapons.
It can be clinched by a fair fight...
if you've got the guts.
Best man from each gang to slug it out.
I would enjoy to risk that.
OK, fair fight.
Wait a minute!
The commanders say yes or no.
Fair fight.
When I get through,
you will be like a fish after skinning.
Your best man fights our best man...
and er... we pick him.
- I thought I would be fighting with...
- You shook on it!
Yes. I shook on it.
Bernardo,
if you want to change your mind...
- Bernardo, want a cigarette?
- No, thank you. I don't smoke.
Evening, Lieutenant.
I and Tony was just closing up.
Well! Now, this is more like it, fellas.
Warms me all over to see you this way.
And after only a couple of words
from me at the playground today.
Oh, do you mind?
I have no mind. I'm the village idiot.
Headquarters hears about this,
I may even get a promotion.
Good deal all around, huh, Bernardo?
I get a promotion...
you Puerto Ricans get
what you've been itching for.
Use of the playground,
use of the gym...
the streets, the candy store.
So what if they do turn
this town into a stinking pigsty?
Don't stop him!
He wants to get home...
write to San Juan,
tell them how he's got it made here.
What I mean is... clear out, you!
I said clear out!
Oh, yeah, sure. I know.
It's a free country,
and I ain't got the right.
But I got a badge.
What have you got?
Things are tough all over.
Beat it!
OK, fellas.
Where's the rumble gonna be?
Come on!
Americans don't rub with
the gold-teeth unless...
- Look, Lieutenant!
- You shut your mouth.
Come on, Baby John...
before your smooth little kisser
gets cut up for life.
Now, where's it gonna be?
The river?
The park?
Look, fellas! I'm for you!
I want this beat cleaned up
and you can do it for me.
I'll even lend a hand
if things get rough.
Now, where are you gonna rumble?
The playground?
Sweeney's lot?
Why don't you get smart,
you stupid hooligans?
I ought to throw you
in the can right now!
You and the tinhorn immigrant scum
you come from!
How's your old man's DTs, A-rab?
How's the action on your mother's
side of the street, Action?
One day,
there won't be anyone to hold you!
Get him out of here! Come on!
Don't worry.
I'll find out where it's gonna be.
Be sure to finish each other off...
because if you don't, I will.
Oh, yeah, sure.
Understand 'em.
That's what they keep telling me
at headquarters - understand.
You try keeping hoodlums in line
and see what it does to you.
It wouldn't give me a mouth like his.
Come on, Doc. Don't let it get you.
I'm sick.
You heard. It's gonna be a fair fight.
And that's gonna cure something?
From here on in,
everything's gonna be all right.
- I got a feeling.
- What have you been taking tonight?
A trip to the moon.
And I tell you a secret, Doc.
It ain't a man that's up there.
It's a girl.
A lady.
Buenas noches, señor.
Buenas noches.
So that's why you made it
a fair fight?
I'm seeing her tomorrow. I can't wait.
Tony!
Things aren't tough enough?
Tough? Doc, I'm in love.
- And you're not frightened?
- Should I be?
No.
No, I'm frightened enough
for the both of you.
♪ "Maria" ♪
♪ "I Feel Pretty" ♪
What has Chino done to her?
Chino? Why Chino?
Maybe she is just dolling up for us.
Gracias, querida.
Rosalia, Consuelo,
my adorable friends.
Can you keep a secret?
I'm hot for secrets!
No, I won't tell you.
- What?
The poor girl is out of her mind!
I am. Crazy!
She might be at that.
She looks somehow different.
- I do?
- And I think she is up to something.
I am?
"I do?" "I am?" She talks like a parrot.
What is going on with you, Maria?
♪ I feel pretty ♪
♪ Oh, so pretty ♪
♪ I feel pretty and witty and gay ♪
♪ And I pity any girl who isn't me today ♪
♪ I feel charming ♪
♪ Oh, so charming ♪
♪ It's alarming how charming I feel ♪
♪ And so pretty ♪
♪ That I hardly can believe I'm real ♪
♪ See the pretty girl
in that mirror there ♪
♪ Who can that attractive girl be? ♪
♪ Such a pretty face,
such a pretty dress ♪
♪ Such a pretty smile,
such a pretty me ♪
♪ I feel stunning ♪
♪ And entrancing ♪
♪ Feel like running and dancing for joy ♪
♪ For I'm loved ♪
♪ By a pretty wonderful boy ♪
♪ Have you met my good friend Maria? ♪
♪ The craziest girl on the block ♪
♪ You'll know her the
minute you see her ♪
♪ She's the one who is in
an advanced state of shock ♪
♪ She thinks she's in love ♪
- ♪ She thinks she's in Spain ♪
- ♪ La la la ♪
♪ She isn't in love,
she's merely insane ♪
♪ It must be the heat ♪
- ♪ Or some rare disease ♪
- ♪ La la la ♪
♪ Or too much to eat ♪
♪ Or maybe it's fleas ♪
♪ Keep away from her ♪
♪ Send for Chino ♪
♪ This is not the Maria we know ♪
♪ Modest and pure ♪
- ♪ Polite and refined ♪
- ♪ La la la ♪
♪ Well bred and mature ♪
♪ And out of her mind! ♪
Miss America!
Ay, qué linda que eres!
Miss America! Bravo! Speech!
Speech!
♪ I feel pretty ♪
♪ Oh, so pretty ♪
♪ That the city
should give me its key ♪
♪ A committee should be
organised to honour me ♪
♪ La la la la la la la-la ♪
♪ I feel dizzy ♪
♪ I feel sunny ♪
♪ I feel fizzy and funny and fine ♪
♪ And so pretty ♪
♪ Miss America can just resign ♪
♪ La la la la la la la-la ♪
♪ See the pretty girl
in that mirror there ♪
♪ What mirror where? ♪
♪ Who can that attractive girl be? ♪
- ♪ Which? What? ♪
- ♪ Where? Whom? ♪
♪ Such a pretty face,
such a pretty dress ♪
♪ Such a pretty smile,
such a pretty me ♪
- ♪ Such a pretty me ♪
- ♪ I feel stunning ♪
- ♪ And entrancing ♪
♪ Feel like running and dancing for joy ♪
♪ For I'm loved by a
pretty wonderful boy ♪
Cállense, por favor, muchachas!
You want to sing,
do it with the needles...
or you'll be singing for your supper.
What can you expect?
We use Singer sewing machines.
Sure. You make the bad joke
at home where I can't hear it.
Go now, go home.
It's closing time. Shoo!
Buenas noches, Madam Lucia!
You pull down the shades,
pick up the pins...
turn off the lights
and lock the doors.
Buenas noches, Anita.
Buenas noches.
Ay, the jail is open!
I thought she'd never leave.
It's hard to believe that old bag
was once a young bag like us.
Let's go before she changes her mind
and comes back.
You go, querida. I will lock up.
- Why?
- I have work.
- Do it tomorrow.
- I am in no hurry.
I am. I'm going home now
and take a nice long bubble bath.
Black orchid.
Black orchid?
Mm. All over.
I got a date with Nardo after the rumble.
What rumble?
Oh. Well, er...
Nardo's Sharks
and those boys at the dance.
They fight each other tonight?
They don't play potsy.
Why must they always fight?
You saw how they dance...
like they gotta get rid of something.
That's how they fight.
To get rid of what?
Too much feeling.
And they do get rid of it.
Boy, after a fight,
that brother of yours is so healthy.
Definitely. Black orchid.
Buenas noches.
"You go, querida. I will lock up."
It's too early for noches.
Buenas tardes.
Gracias.
He just came from the drugstore
to deliver aspirin.
- You'll need it.
- Not us.
We're fine. We're out of the world.
You're out of your heads.
We're 12 feet in the air.
Anita can see that.
You will not tell?
Tell what?
How can I know
what goes on 12 feet over my head?
You'd better be home in 15 minutes.
It's all right. She likes us.
But she is worried... and so am I.
- That's foolish.
- Are you going to the rumble?
- No!
- Yes.
Why?
- You must go and stop it.
- I have stopped it.
It'll only be a fist fight between two.
Any fight is no good for us!
Everything is good for us.
We've got magic.
Listen, and hear me.
You must go and stop it.
It means that much to you?
Yes.
All right, I will.
I believe you. You do have magic.
Of course.
I've got you.
Tonight, after I stop the rumble,
I'll come by for you.
I will wait for you on the roof.
No. Not the roof.
I'll come to your house.
You cannot. My mama...
Then, I'll take you to my house.
Your mama? ♪
She'll come running
from the kitchen to welcome you.
She lives in the kitchen.
Dressed so elegant?
I told her you were coming.
She'll look at your face -
try not to smile.
She'll say, "Skinny... but pretty!"
She is plump, no doubt?
Fat.
I take after my mama. Delicate-boned.
Oh!
Ooh! Not in front of Mama!
Oh! I would like to see Papa in this.
Mama will make him
ask about your prospects.
Many.
- If you go to church?
- Oh, always.
Yes. Papa might like you.
May I have your daughter's hand?
He says yes.
Gracias.
- And your mama?
- I'm afraid to ask her.
Tell her she's not getting a daughter.
She's getting rid of a son.
She says yes.
She has good taste.
Here. Maid of honour.
Oh, that colour is bad for Anita.
- The best man.
- That is my papa!
Sorry, Papa.
Here we go, Riff. Womb to tomb.
Now, you see, Anita.
There was nothing to worry about.
Look. Mama's crying already.
I, Anton...
take thee, Maria...
I, Maria...
take thee, Anton...
For richer, for poorer...
In sickness and in health...
To love and to honour...
To hold and to keep...
From each sun to each moon...
From tomorrow to tomorrow...
From now to forever...
Till death do us part.
With this ring...
I thee wed.
♪ Make of our hands ♪
♪ One hand ♪
♪ Make of our hearts ♪
♪ One heart ♪
♪ Make of our vows ♪
♪ One last vow ♪
♪ Only death will part us now ♪
♪ Make of our lives ♪
♪ One life ♪
♪ Day after day ♪
♪ Now it begins ♪
♪ Now we start ♪
♪ One hand ♪
♪ One heart ♪
♪ Even death won't part us now ♪
♪ The Jets are gonna
have their day tonight ♪
have their way tonight ♪
♪ The Puerto Ricans grumble,
"Fair fight" ♪
♪ But if they start a rumble ♪
♪ We'll rumble 'em right ♪
♪ We're gonna hand 'em
a surprise tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna cut 'em
down to size tonight ♪
♪ We said, "OK, no rumpus, no tricks" ♪
♪ But just in case they jump us ♪
♪ We're ready to mix tonight! ♪
♪ We're gonna rock it tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna jazz it up
and have us a ball ♪
♪ They're gonna get it tonight ♪
♪ The more they turn it on,
the harder they'll fall ♪
- ♪ Well, they began it. ♪
- ♪ Well, they began it ♪
♪ And we're the ones to stop 'em
once and for all ♪
♪ Tonight! ♪
♪ Anita's gonna get her kicks tonight ♪
♪ We'll have
our private little mix tonight ♪
♪ He'll walk in hot and tired,
poor dear ♪
♪ Don't matter if he's tired ♪
♪ As long as he's here ♪
♪ Tonight, tonight ♪
♪ Won't be just any night ♪
♪ Tonight there will be no morning star ♪
♪ Tonight, tonight ♪
♪ I'll see my love tonight ♪
♪ And for us ♪
♪ Stars will stop where they are ♪
♪ Today the minutes seem like hours ♪
♪ The hours go so slowly ♪
♪ And still the sky is light ♪
♪ Oh, moon, grow bright ♪
♪ And make this endless day ♪
♪ Endless night ♪
♪ The Jets are coming out
on top tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna watch
Bernardo drop tonight ♪
♪ The Puerto Rican punk'll go down ♪
♪ And when he's hollered, "Uncle" ♪
♪ We'll tear up the town ♪
- ♪ We'll be in back of you, boy. ♪
- ♪ Right ♪
- ♪ You're gonna flatten him good. ♪
♪ Tonight, there will
be no morning star ♪
♪ Tonight... ♪
♪ We're gonna rock it tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna jazz it tonight ♪
♪ Late tonight ♪
♪ We're gonna mix it tonight ♪
♪ Today the minutes seem like hours ♪
- ♪ The hours go so slowly. ♪
- ♪ They began it ♪
♪ We'll stop 'em once and for all ♪
♪ The Sharks are gonna have their way ♪
♪ The Jets are gonna have their day ♪
♪ We're gonna rock it tonight ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
- Ready.
Now er... move in and shake hands.
For what?
Well...
that's the way it's done, buddy boy.
Ah. More gracious living?
Every one of you
hates every one of us.
We hate you right back.
Let's get at it.
Sure.
Come on, Ice. Come on.
Hold it!
Tony! Get with the gang. It's all OK.
- No.
- Tony, what are you doing?
Maybe he has found the guts
to fight his own battles.
It don't take guts
if you've got a battle.
We ain't got one, none of us.
OK, Nardo?
Tony!
Hold it. Let's just cool it.
The deal is a fair fight
between you and Ice.
Get with the gang.
Mother hen protecting the baby.
I'll give you a battle, gallito!
- You've got one!
- I'll take pretty boy as a warm-up.
Afraid, pretty boy? Afraid, gutless?
Afraid, chicken?
- Cut it!
- No!
I don't want to, Bernardo.
- I'm sure!
- Now, listen to me!
There's nothing to fight about.
- The hell there ain't!
- You've got it wrong!
- Why can't you understand?
- What do you say, chicken?
Kill him, Tony.
- Come on, man.
- Afraid to fight?
- Come on!
- Let me see you fight!
Hey! He is chicken.
- Hey, pretty boy.
- Bernardo, listen.
Don't! Stop.
We've got nothing to fight about.
- Bernardo!
- You yellow-bellied chicken!
- Don't push me!
- You yellow-bellied Polack!
Riff! Riff, what are you doing?
Get out of here, Tony.
Riff, don't!
- Hold him.
- Ice, let me go!
Riff, don't!
Keep out of this!
Somebody stop him!
Let me go!
Ice! Tiger!
Riff! Riff!
- Come on, Nardo!
- Stop him!
Riff, don't!
Nardo! Corre!
Nardo, corre!
Get him!
MARIA!
Tony, come on! Come on, Tony.
You've gotta get out of here. Come on!
Come on, Tony.
Come on, get out of here!
Come on!
Come on, Tony!
Hey! Wait for me, Rosa!
♪ "Maria" ♪
Chino!
There was no-one downstairs.
My mother and father are at the store.
- I didn't expect you to come...
- Maria.
- You have been fighting, Chino?
- Yes.
I am sorry.
- That is not like you.
- No.
You must go home and wash up.
- Maria...
- I will see you tomorrow.
- At the rumble...
- There was no rumble.
- There was!
- You are wrong.
Nobody meant for it to happen!
Tell me.
It is bad.
Very bad?
You see...
It will be easier
if you say it very fast.
There was a fight.
And Nardo...
Somehow, a knife...
And Nardo and someone...
Tony. What happened to Tony?
Chino, tell me. Is Tony all right?
He killed your brother!
You are lying.
Chino! Why do you lie to me?
Chino!
Chino, you are lying! Lying!
Why do you lie? Chino! Chino!
Mama! Mama!
Bernardo está muerto!
Bernardo? Muerto?
No!
Santa Maria, make it not be true.
Please make it not be true.
Madre de Dios, I will do anything!
Make me die...
only please make it not be true.
Le suplico... no puede ser!
Make it not be...
Killer, killer, killer!
Killer, killer, killer...
I tried to stop it.
I did try. I don't know what went wrong.
I didn't mean to hurt him.
I didn't want to.
But Riff was like my brother.
When Bernardo killed him...
Bernardo didn't mean it either...
I thought you knew.
I didn't come to tell you that.
Just for you to forgive me
so I can go to the police.
No!
- It'll be easy now.
- I won't let you.
- I must.
- Stay. Stay with me.
- Maria, I love you so much.
- Don't leave me.
- Whatever you want, I'll do.
- Hold me.
- Oh, forever.
- Tighter.
We'll be all right, I know it.
We're really together now.
But it's not us.
It's everything around us.
Then, I'll take you away
where nothing can get to us.
Not anyone... or anything.
♪ There's a place for us ♪
♪ Somewhere a place for us ♪
♪ Peace and quiet and open air ♪
♪ Wait for us somewhere ♪
♪ There's a time for us ♪
♪ Someday a time for us ♪
♪ Time together with time to spare ♪
♪ Time to look ♪
♪ Time to care ♪
♪ Someday ♪
♪ Somewhere ♪
♪ We'll find a new way of living ♪
♪ We'll find a way of forgiving ♪
♪ Somewhere ♪
♪ There's a place for us ♪
♪ A time and place for us ♪
♪ Hold my hand and we're halfway there ♪
♪ Hold my hand and I'll take you there ♪
♪ Somehow ♪
♪ Someday ♪
♪ Somewhere. ♪
Baby John, what are you doing here?
Nothing.
What are you doing nothing here for?
Come on!
I don't want the guys to see me, A-rab.
Why not?
Well, I'm crying.
You are?
What for?
I don't know, I'm just...
Blow your nose.
A-rab?
Yeah?
Did you get a look at their faces?
- Which faces?
- You know.
At the rumble. Riff and Bernardo.
I wish it was yesterday.
Me too. I'm scared.
Cut it out, do you hear me?
A-rab, what are we gonna do?
Meet the other guys and form up.
Now, come on. Let's go.
Hey. Have you got a handkerchief first?
What's wrong with your sleeve?
- Where have you been?
- Where do you think? The Stork Club?
We thought they'd nabbed you.
- You didn't see Tony?
- No, nothing but coppers.
- What's wrong with him?
- Nothing, he's OK. Get it?
All right, all right.
- Maybe we ought to go home.
- For what?
- Bet you they got him.
- Not Tony.
He was great. Huh, Baby John?
Oh, yeah!
He really come through for the Jets.
Just like Riff said he...
Said he would.
Riff, I want Riff!
Come on, Graziella.
Gee. Nobody was supposed to get killed.
It just...
- They're gonna pay.
- Them stinkin' Sharks.
- Dirty fighting.
- They started it.
Let's finish it
and show 'em who's on top.
- The Jets!
- Let's do it now.
Ain't we had enough?
- Are you scared?
- Who are you calling scared?
- Lay off of him.
- Mind your own business.
Don't sound off on me! I'll hit you!
Knock it off!
Shut up, you bunch of good-for-nothings!
Go home where you belong!
Who are you calling good-for-nothing?
Come down, I'll put this
through your stupid face!
Get inside, all of you!
- Shut up!
- I don't have to take that from nobody!
The next creep who gets on my craw...
You'll laugh!
Yeah.
Now, you all better dig this,
and dig it good.
No matter who or what is eating you...
man, you show it, and you are dead!
You are cutting a hole in yourselves
for them to stick in a hot umbrella...
and open it wide.
Man, you wanna get past the cops
when they start asking about tonight?
You play it cool.
You wanna live in this lousy world?
Play it cool.
- I wanna get even!
- Get cool!
- I wanna bust!
- Bust cool!
- I wanna go!
- Go cool!
♪ Boy, boy ♪
♪ Crazy boy ♪
♪ Get cool, boy ♪
♪ Got a rocket in your pocket ♪
♪ Keep cooly-cool, boy ♪
♪ Don't get hot ♪
♪ Cos, man, you've got
some high times ahead ♪
♪ Take it slow ♪
♪ And Daddy-O ♪
♪ You can live it up and die in bed ♪
♪ Boy, boy ♪
♪ Crazy boy ♪
♪ Stay loose, boy ♪
♪ Breeze it, buzz it ♪
♪ Easy does it ♪
♪ Turn off the juice, boy ♪
♪ Go, man, go ♪
♪ But not like a yo-yo schoolboy ♪
♪ Just play it cool, boy ♪
♪ Real cool. ♪
Easy, Action.
Sssh.
Cool it, A-rab. Cool it, cool it.
Pow!
Cool!
- Go!
- Crazy!
- Cool!
- Go!
- Crazy!
Yeah!
♪ Boy, boy ♪
♪ Crazy boy ♪
♪ Stay loose, boy ♪
♪ Breeze it, buzz it ♪
♪ Easy does it ♪
♪ Turn off the juice, boy ♪
♪ Just play it cool, boy ♪
♪ Real cool. ♪
OK.
Let's go.
Pow!
Hey, where are we going?
If we lay low,
the coppers are gonna smell fish...
- Hey, buddy boys!
- Aw, go wear a skirt.
I got scabby knees. Listen.
We act like we've got nothing to hide.
Suppose they ask us about the rumble?
Suppose they ask you
who's looking for Tony...
with a gun?
You know something?
- I know I gotta go get a skirt.
- Come on, Anybodys.
- What's the freak know?
- Plenty.
I figured somebody should
infiltrate PR territory and spy.
I'm very large with shadows.
I slip in and out of 'em
like wind through a fence.
Is she making the most of it?!
- You bet your fat A I am.
- Spill it!
OK!
I hear Chino tell the Sharks something
about Tony and Bernardo's sister.
Then Chino says,
"It it's the last thing I do...
I'm gonna get that Polack."
Then he pulls out the bad news.
- Them PRs won't stop.
- Till we stop 'em.
Hold it!
Now, listen.
Tony come through for us.
We gotta do the same.
- We gotta find him before Chino does.
- And burns him.
You cover the river.
Snowboy, go to Doc's.
- I'll take the alleys.
- We'll take the streets.
- The park.
- The schoolyard.
- Let's go!
- Hey, what about me?
- You?
- Uh-huh.
Take the shadows.
Maybe you'll find Tony there.
Right!
Hey!
You done good, buddy boy.
Thanks... Daddy-O.
♪ "Somewhere" ♪
Who is...
Maria!
Maria, it's Anita. Are you in there?
- Maria?
- Yes!
Open the door. I need you.
No...
Now you are afraid too?
What?
I'll be right there.
- Together.
- But where?
The bus station. We'll go so far away,
they'll never find us.
- How can we?
- Doc'll help us with the money.
- You meet me at his store.
- At Doc's? Yes.
I'll wait for you there.
- Maria!
- Yes!
Hurry.
Maria!
Coming, Anita.
Anita.
Oh...
All right. Now you know.
And you still don't know.
- He is one of them!
- No, Anita.
Yes!
♪ A boy like that would
kill your brother ♪
♪ Forget that boy and find another ♪
♪ One of your own kind ♪
♪ Stick to your own kind ♪
♪ A boy like that will give you sorrow ♪
♪ You'll meet another boy tomorrow ♪
♪ One of your own kind ♪
♪ Stick to your own kind ♪
♪ A boy who kills cannot love ♪
♪ A boy who kills has no heart ♪
♪ And he's the boy who gets your love ♪
♪ And gets your heart ♪
♪ Very smart, Maria, very smart ♪
♪ A boy like that wants one thing only ♪
♪ And when he's done,
he'll leave you lonely ♪
♪ He'll murder your love ♪
♪ He murdered mine ♪
♪ Just wait and see ♪
♪ Just wait, Maria ♪
♪ Oh, no, Anita, no ♪
♪ Anita, no ♪
♪ It isn't true, not for me ♪
♪ It's true for you, not for me ♪
♪ I hear your words ♪
♪ And in my head, I know they're smart ♪
♪ But my heart, Anita ♪
♪ But my heart knows they're wrong ♪
♪ You should know better ♪
♪ You were in love ♪
♪ Or so you said ♪
♪ You should know better ♪
♪ I have a love ♪
♪ And it's all that I have ♪
♪ Right or wrong ♪
♪ What else can I do? ♪
♪ I love him ♪
♪ I'm his ♪
♪ And everything he is ♪
♪ I am too ♪
♪ I have a love ♪
♪ And it's all that I need ♪
♪ Right or wrong ♪
♪ And he needs me too ♪
♪ I love him ♪
♪ We're one ♪
♪ There's nothing to be done ♪
♪ Not a thing I can do ♪
♪ But hold him, hold him forever ♪
♪ Be with him now ♪
♪ Tomorrow ♪
♪ And all ♪
♪ Of my life ♪
♪ When love comes so strong ♪
♪ There is no right or wrong ♪
♪ Your love is ♪
♪ Your love. ♪
Chino has a gun.
I heard the boys talking.
He's hunting for Tony.
He's at Doc's store, waiting for me.
If Chino hurts him
or touches him, I swear I'II...
You'll do what Tony did to Bernardo?
I love Tony.
I know. I loved Bernardo.
- Anybody home?
- Yes.
Bernardo's sister, please.
She isn't feeling well.
Who is?
Hello, Miss. I'm Lieutenant Schrank.
I don't like to disturb you
just now...
Yes. A very bad time.
If you will excuse me, please.
- I have a couple of questions.
- Afterwards, please.
I must go to my brother now.
- Just one minute.
- Can't you wait?
No!
Now, you were at the dance
at the gym last night...
Will this take very long?
As long as it has to.
Excuse me.
Anita, my headache is much worse.
Will you go to Doc's store for me?
Don't you people keep aspirin around?
This is something special.
Will you go for me, Anita?
What shall I ask for?
Doc will know.
Tell him I have been detained...
and can't get there right away.
Or I would have picked it up myself.
Excuse me.
You were asking?
Yeah.
At the gym,
your brother got into an argument...
because you danced with the wrong boy.
Yes.
Who was the boy?
Another from my country.
And his name?
José.
- Can't find him.
- Down in the cellar.
- Tony?
- Safe and sound.
- I found him.
- Did you warn him about Chino?
- Why's he in the cellar?
- To keep the mice company.
No sign of Chino, huh?
- Nothing.
- His luck.
I'll slip out the back
and check the alleys again.
- You guys, hang here.
- OK.
Boy, I'm thirsty. Where's Doc?
Upstairs,
raising getaway money for Tony.
- Doc ain't got no money.
- His mattress has.
Cut the frabbajabba.
Grab some reading matter.
Some of you get outside.
If you see Chino, or those stinking PRs...
I'd like to see Doc.
He ain't here.
Where is he?
At the bank. They made
a mistake in his favour.
The banks are closed at night.
Where is he?
You know how skinny Doc is.
He slipped through
the night deposit slot.
And got stuck, halfway in.
So there's no telling when he'll be back.
Buenas noches, señorita.
Where are you going?
Downstairs.
Didn't I tell you? He ain't here.
I'd like to see for myself.
Please.
Por favor.
Will you let me pass?
She's too dark to pass.
- Oh, don't.
- Please don't.
Por favor!
- Gracias!
- De nada!
- Ay, ay! Hey, mambo!
- Listen, you!
Look, I gotta give
a friend of yours a message.
I gotta tell Tony...
- He ain't here.
- I know he is.
- Who's the message from?
- Never mind.
Could it be from Chino?
Don't you understand? I want to help.
Bernardo's girl wants to help?
Even a greaseball's got feelings.
- She wants to help get Tony.
- No!
Not much! Bernardo's tramp.
- Bernardo's pig.
- You lying Spic!
- Don't do that!
- Gold-tooth!
- Pierced ear!
- Garlic mouth!
Cha! Cha-cha!
Cha-cha-cha!
Olé! Olé!
♪ "America" ♪
Stop it!
What are you doing there?
Bernardo was right.
If one of you...
was lying in the street bleeding...
I'd walk by and spit on you.
Stop her!
She'll tell Chino Tony's in the cellar.
Don't you touch me.
I got a message for your American buddy.
You tell that murderer
that Maria's never going to meet him.
You tell him
Chino found out about them...
and shot her!
She's dead!
When do you kids stop?
You make this world lousy.
We didn't make it, Doc.
Get out of here.
Maria?
Doc, I though I heard... You got it!
Yeah, I got it.
You're a pal.
You're the best friend a guy ever had.
I'll pay you back as soon as I can,
I promise.
- Forget that.
- Never! I couldn't.
You know what we're gonna do
in the country, Maria and me?
We're gonna have lots of kids.
We'll name 'em all after you.
So when you come to visit...
Wake up!
Is this the only way
to get through to you?
Do just what you all do?
Bust like a hot water pipe?
What's got into you?
Why do you kids live
like there's a war on?
Why do you kill?
I told you how it happened.
Maria understands.
I thought you did too.
Maria understands nothing...
ever again.
There is no Maria, Tony.
What?
I can't.
No, no, Doc.
Now, tell me. What is it?
That was Anita upstairs.
Chino found out about you and Maria...
and he killed her.
No...
Maria.
Maria died?
Chino!
Come and get me too, Chino!
- Tony!
- Who's that?
- Anybodys. Come on!
- Get out of here.
Chino!
- Come and get me, damn you!
- What are you doing?
Get out of here!
- Chino!
- Come with me...
It ain't playing any more.
Can't anyone get that?
- But the gang!
- You're a girl!
Be a girl and beat it!
Chino!
Come on, Chino!
Get me too!
Chino!
Chino! I'm calling for you, Chino.
There's nobody here but me.
Come on!
Please, will you?
I'm waiting for you.
I want you to.
Maria!
Tony!
I... didn't believe hard enough.
Loving is enough.
Not here.
They won't let us be.
Then, we'll get away.
- Yeah. We can.
- Yes.
- We will.
♪ Hold my hand and we're halfway there ♪
♪ Hold my hand and I'll take you there ♪
♪ Somehow ♪
♪ Someday ♪
♪ Some... ♪
Stay back!
How do you fire this gun, Chino?
Just by pulling this little trigger?
How many bullets are left, Chino?
Enough for you?
And you?
All of you!
You all killed him!
And my brother. And Riff.
Not with bullets and guns.
With hate.
Well, I can kill too...
because now I have hate.
How many can I kill, Chino?
How many?
And still have one bullet left for me?
Don't you touch him!
Te adoro, Anton.
♪ "Somewhere" ♪