[CAR HORN HONKING]l
[CHILDREN GIGGLING]
BOY:
Whoa. Whoa!
[CHILDREN SHOUTING]
[GRUNTING]
[CHUCKLING THEN GRUNTING]
[BOTH LAUGHING]
BOY:
Huh?
Awesome.
Great use of your chin as a brake, honey.
Don't eat too much sand.
You'll spoil your dinner.
WOMAN 1 : Look, it's Superman.
WOMAN 2: Superman!
WOMAN 3:
It's the Man of Steel!
He's going to save us.
Whoo! Superman! Ha-ha-ha.
Wait, what is he saving us from? Lunch?
Yeah, it's a pretty nice day.
[BIZARRO GRUNTS]
[GROANING]
[BOTH SHOUTING]
Ha-ha-ha. Huh?
[CHILDREN CHEERING AND GIGGLING]
Huh?
[GIGGLING AND LAUGHING]
Bizarro save tiny people
from tentacle creature.
[GRUNTS]
[WHIMPERS]
Bizarro no like calamari.
[SCREAMING]
-Aah!
-My baby!
[BOTH CONTINUE SCREAMING]
[CHILDREN GIGGLING]
-Oh.
BOY: Mommy.
Don't worry. They're just fine.
But this one spit up a little sand
when I caught him.
Thank you, Superman.
You saved my child from your crazy brother.
Oh, no. No, no, no.
That's not my brother.
It-- I mean, he, was created when Lex Luthor
hit me with a duplicator ray...
...to make a clone of me he could control.
Excuse me.
[BIZARRO GRUNTING]
Bizarro, put that down.
Bizarro put down.
Down means up, up means down.
Why does everything
have to be backwards with you?
Bizarro help Superman save Metropolis
from tentacle creature.
Why is it every time you try to help,
Metropolis ends up destroyed?
-That octopus isn't a creature.
-Oh.
-It isn't even an octopus. It's not dangerous.
-Huh?
[GROANS]
[WHISTLING]
[ALL SCREAMING]
Ha-ha-ha. Boom.
My car! Do you know how long
it took me to assemble?
There were, like, so many bricks.
Can you take your identical twin
somewhere else?
Twins? Oh, no.
He's actually the opposite of me
in every way.
[CHILDREN SCREAMING]
Ha! Bizarro save Metropolis.
Bizarro save home.
MAN 1 :
Hey, who's gonna pay for this?
WOMAN 1 :
Someone might have gotten hurt in all of this.
-You sure did.
WOMAN 1 : This is ridiculous.
You know, I recently discovered a place that
needs your help even more than Metropolis.
[GASPS]
Let's not go.
Follow me.
I mean, don't follow me.
Bizarro spy with his little eye,
something start with letter S.
Space.
How Superman know?
[BEEPING]
SUPERMAN:
Should be around....
Ah! Right there.
[WHIRRING]
Aah! Oh.
[BIZARRO LAUGHING]
BIZARRO:
Pretty. Ha-ha-ha.
[GRUNTING]
Ugh!
[SHOUTING]
Ha-ha-ha. That tickled.
Where you take Bizarro?
Somewhere you can't get into trouble.
This planet's physics are a little backwards.
Just like you.
It's going to be the perfect home.
Home Metropolis.
How I save Daily Planet?
How I save people here?
Hmm....
Watch this.
The Daily Planet, just like the one on Earth.
What do you think?
Uh....
Ah!
Bizarro, that citizen is in trouble.
Ha!
Ah!
[GRUNTING AND CHUCKLING]
Ha!
You nothing to worry for, citizen.
Bizarro keep safe.
Aah!
I think I kill him.
I think I kill him. Aah!
No, no, he'll be just fine.
He just needs to rest at home.
Wait, he needs a home.
Can you build him a home, Bizarro?
Uh, Bizarro build.
I'd wish you good luck, Bizarro,
but I know you'd take it the wrong way.
[RUMBLING THEN ALL GASP]
[RUMBLING CONTINUES]
MAN 1 : It's Giganta!
MAN 2: Run, run, run!
MAN 3:
What is that thing?
[CAR ALARM BLARING]
Out of my way.
I don't wanna be pulling mini figs
out of my toes.
The Daily Planet news building.
Well, I got news for you.
Print is dead.
[GRUNTING]
[ALL SCREAMING]
[SCREAMING AND SHOUTING]
[SHOUTS]
[GRUNTING]
This skyscraper is heavier than you think.
[CHEERING AND LAUGHING]
Now Clark Kent doesn't have to look
for a new job.
[GRUNTING]
By the Golden Girdle of Gaea, Giganta,
this is no way for a lady to act.
Or dress. Animal prints are so last season.
Leopard spots are the new black.
And I'm gonna make you black and blue.
Get back here.
If you say so.
[GRUNTING]
The perfect distraction for the perfect plan.
[GIBBERING]
[WHIRRING]
The Justice League will never figure out
what I'm really up to.
BATMAN:
Let me take a shot at it, Gorilla Grodd.
You use your mind control helmet
to turn Giganta, Penguin...
...Deathstroke and Captain Cold
into henchmen.
So while Giganta wreaks havoc on Metropolis,
you go after your real prize.
[GRUNTS]
Pretty good guess,
and a lot of words on one breath.
[WHIRRING NEARBY]
[GRUNTS]
-Ugh.
-Booyah!
Bats knew you'd try that,
so he had me snatch your hypno-helmet.
He's just so smart.
[WHIRRING]
[GRUNTS]
[GROANS]
Ugh!
[GRUNTS]
Grodd had us under mind control.
DEATHSTROKE:
We're stealing for you?
That's cold, man.
This heist better be for something good.
-Huh?
-Aah!
Bananas?
Ha, ha. Bananas?
I like bananas? Ha-ha-ha.
DEATHSTROKE:
Nobody makes a monkey out of me.
Let's get out of here.
[GROWLING AND GRUNTING]
[CYBORG SHOUTING]
[CHUCKLES]
[QUACKING]
-They're getting away.
-Relax, Cyborg. They won't get far.
Hawkman, Operation Crop Duster.
Flash, I need you after Captain Cold.
I'm on it.
BATMAN: Green Arrow, see if you have anything
in your quiver to take down a flightless bird.
Copy that, Dark Knight.
BATMAN: Plastic Man, I need you
to wrap up Deathstroke.
Roger Dodger, Caped Crusader.
Hawkman delivers.
[HAWKMAN CAWING]
Just my size.
Gotcha.
[GROWLS]
Stay put, rookie.
Wish I had a jetpack.
[GRUNTING]
GUY:
Man, do I have to do everything around here?
Let me show you how a real hero does it.
Say hello to my little friend
who's really big, and it's me.
Wow, look, Superman...
...Guy Gardner finally made something
as big as his ego.
[GRUNTING]
Say hello to the agony of the feet.
[GROANING]
[SHOUTING]
Ow.
Flash to Batman,
I'm hot on the trail of Captain Cold.
Get it? Hot, cold, huh?
I don't like tailgaters.
Hmm.
[GRUNTS]
[SCREAMING]
All right.
Cool off in the icebox.
[GRUNTING]
[QUACKING THEN GASPS]
-Ha-ha-ha.
-My favorite time of year: Duck season.
[SCREAMING]
[GRUNTS]
Green Arrow to Batman.
This Penguin is poached.
Plastic Man versus Deathstroke?
That's a stretch.
[SHOUTS]
Whoo! That was close. Aah!
[PLASTIC MAN SHOUTING]
[CHUCKLES]
-Aah!
-Oh.
[GRUNTING]
Plas to Batman,
I've got mine all wrapped up. Hee-haw!
Wrapping things up here too.
Superman to Batman.
How's it going with that big gorilla?
-Need any help?
-I don't need any help from you.
BOY 1 :
Look, a monkey.
[GRODD CHUCKLES
THEN CHILDREN SHOUTING]
[GASPS]
[CHUCKLING AND CHEERING]
[LAUGHING]
[GASPS]
[SCREAMING]
[GRODD GRUNTING AND WHIMPERING]
[GRODD GRUNTING]
[ALL CHEERING]
[CHEERING STOPS]
Thanks, Batman.
Hey, now, great takedown.
But, you know, maybe next time, instead
of using children to stop supervillains...
...feel free to call on your friends.
I keep my friends close
and my enemies closer.
I hope not much closer than this.
Hey, you're not implying that--
[SINGING] We cauht Gorilla Groddy
And now we're gonna party
Villains going to prison
'Cause the Justice League is winning
Booyah, yeah
[BOYS LAUGHING
THEN CYBORG WHOOPS]
Great work out there, everyone.
Especially our two new recruits:
Cyborg and Guy.
The Man of Steel just said I did great.
Fist bump.
I don't fist bump.
Just glad I was there
to save Wonder Woman.
Was that before or after Giganta
laid you down for a nap, rookie?
-Hmm.
-Whoa.
When we join forces, no evil can match us.
That's why we formed the Justice League.
Together we fight for the liberties
of all living creatures, great and small.
BATMAN: I joined the league to keep an eye
on the most powerful being on Earth.
The hearts and minds of man
are no mystery to me.
But an alien Superman....
Good thing I have my "just in case" box
of kryptonite.
[SUPERMAN GASPS]
I'm okay.
Not sure what came over me there.
Must've eaten some bad buffalo wings.
Now, where was I? Oh, yes, yes.
Next order of business.
Flash is bored, again.
Any ideas on some new activities
to keep him busy?
-Archery.
-Ice sculpture.
North American duck calls?
-Ha, ha.
-Huh?
[DUCK CALLING]
[QUACKING]
Okay, what now? Ooh. Snack time.
SUPERMAN: A hero sandwich sounds good.
PLASTIC MAN: Let's eat.
GREEN ARROW: Race you.
HAWKMAN: Birdseed burrito time.
CYBORG:
Booyah!
BATMAN:
Hmm. Superman sure left in a big hurry.
[ALARM WAILING]
-Uh-oh. Trouble alert.
-Great Hera.
There are reports of Superman
attacking LexCorp in Metropolis?
Aha! I knew he would snap one day.
I tried to warn everyone,
but no one would listen.
CYBORG:
Uh....
We were just making sandwiches.
Don't think I won't check that alibi.
I have a pretty good idea
of who's behind this.
Why don't I just take care
of this one solo, guys?
I don't think so. Let's go.
[GROANS]
GUY:
What a mess.
I'd hate to be the guy
who's responsible for this.
[CYBORG GRUNTING]
Yeah, really, guys, I've totally got this.
And miss all the action? Uh-uh.
[GROANS]
Oh, look. Guns, guns, and more guns.
Is this a villain lair?
Oh, it's my first villain lair. Ha, ha.
It seems Lex has been busy
plotting our demise.
Even Superman's.
Hmm. Mm-hm.
All right.
Okay.
Ah.
Hmm.
Lex may be onto something with this one.
And the directions are very easy to follow.
Ah, Batman, leave it to you
to dispose of Lex's evil plans for me.
Yeah, that's what I was doing.
[DOOR OPENS]
Took you long enough.
My lab is practically destroyed.
Lex Luthor.
Do we really have to help this guy?
What's that supposed to mean?
Hello? Villain lair?
You spend all day creating weapons
to destroy us.
Hades himself would spurn you,
you treacherous snake.
How many times have you framed
one of us for a crime...
...and then run for president
on a platform to stop us?
That reminds me.
Vote for Lex.
[GUY GRUNTING]
That's going to look great on posters.
Now, stop him.
Bizarro.
BATMAN:
Another alien.
Whoa.
Are you twins?
Heh, heh. We are not twins.
[GROANS]
Great Scott,
the LexCorp duplicator ray that created you.
You broke in here to steal it? But why?
-Bizarro show you.
-Bizarro, don't!
[ALL GRUNTING]
[GRUNTING AND GROANING]
[GRUNTING]
Ugh!
[GROANING]
I Batzarro. World's worst detective.
I Greenzarro. And I scared.
I--
--Cyzarro.
I Bizarra. Pretty, pretty princess.
[CHUCKLING]
[GRUNTING]
Bizarro, give me that ray
before you do any more damage.
Nothing stop Bizarro.
Not even Superman.
Can we go? I scared.
Okay. Let's stay.
You heard Bizarro. Stay.
Hmm.
"B-O-M-B."
Boom.
[BELL DINGING]
[GROANING]
[GRUNTING]
That was weird.
Your twin brother was way out of line there,
Superman.
-The universe only needs one Guy Gardner.
-If that.
How do we know this wasn't always
part of your secret alien plan?
Because Bizarro can't keep secrets.
He can barely keep his pants up.
But why make duplicates of us?
Duplicates with terrible hair
and unplucked eyebrows?
I don't know, but if one Bizarro
can cause this much destruction...
...think of what an entire
Bizarro League could do.
And I think I know where they're going.
Bizarro World.
Let's go.
BATMAN: So you want us to follow you
to some distant planet, huh?
Well, I'll play your little game for now, alien.
LEX:
This is just great.
They destroy my lab
and Bizarro takes the kryptonite bomb...
...I was going to destroy Superman with.
[CHUCKLING]
[LAUGHING]
[SHOUTING]
Ow.
WONDER WOMAN:
Merciful Minerva.
Bizarro's planet's a cube?
Figures.
I should warn you,
things here behave a little--
Uh, Bizarro?
[CYBORG SCREAMING]
Ha! One Green Lantern rescue rocket
coming up.
[CHICKEN CLUCKS
THEN WONDER WOMAN GRUNTS]
A chicken?
Why does that not surprise me?
Hey, at least I can still fly,
Wonderless Woman.
CYBORG:
Ugh!
Chicken. How degrading.
Yeah, I call that use of power ring
a clear "foul."
Get it? Fowl? Ha, ha.
This strange planet shows no evidence
of animals or plants.
Well, there's a face-plant. Heh.
[WHIRRING]
These rocks are emitting
a weird form of radiation.
Ooh. We should call it weirdiation, then.
I like that name.
-It's this radiation--
-I do not know what you are talking about.
Radiation? There are so many kinds.
If only there was a way
to differentiate this particular--
Fine. It's this weirdiation
that created the planet...
...and is now interfering
with the team's powers and equipment.
Equipment? That's what I'm made of.
Oh, there goes my arm.
-Hey, why doesn't this place affect you?
-Well, not much does, I guess.
BATMAN: So the Kryptonian
has lured us to a planet...
...that renders our powers
and weapons useless...
...while he remains unaffected.
Well, I have something that will affect him.
Hmm.
Shh. We're being watched.
What do you want?
I think he wants to know
why you're talking to a rock.
It's a citizen.
A citizen?
[GUY CHUCKLES]
I tried to make this place
feel more like home for Bizarro.
But he seems
to have taken it to another level.
GUY:
It's a wacked-out Metropolis.
A Bizarrotropolis.
I like to make up funny names.
[THUMPING]
I hear something.
I'm going to investigate.
Not without me, you're not.
CYBORG:
That looks like fun.
Oh, man.
SUPERMAN:
Beautiful from up here, isn't it?
Oh, and unless you want us both to fall
and become super pancakes...
...I'd keep your lead box
full of kryptonite closed tight...
...Bruce Wayne. Ha, ha.
I knew you'd use your x-ray vision on me.
But how did you see...
-...through my lead-lined mask?
-I can't.
But I can see that somebody stitched your
name onto the elastic band of your underwear.
Alfred.
SUPERMAN:
Oh, come on.
You can trust me with your secret identity.
I'm Superman.
I don't trust anyone.
Also, you're an invulnerable alien...
...whose motives remain mysterious which
means I should especially not trust you...
...Clark Kent.
Hey, how did you know my secret identity?
I'm Batman.
That's the source of the sound
I heard earlier.
BOTH:
Darkseid.
[GRUNTING]
Must save citizens from big head machine.
[WHIMPERS]
[GRUNTS]
[WHIMPERING]
[BATZARRO GRUNTING
AND CYZARRO WHIMPERING]
CYBORG:
Oh, my doll.
Desaad, who is stealing my rocks?
Why, no one, Master Darkseid.
This is only a minor interference.
I'm taking care of it as we speak.
[GROANS]
This heinous host of hideous heroes
seems familiar.
No matter. Parademons, unleash the drones.
[SHRIEKING]
[BUZZING]
[SHOUTS AND GRUNTING]
[GASPING THEN LAUGHING]
It tickle. It tickle.
[LAUGHING]
[ALL LAUGHING]
-They're being tickled?
-Tickled to death.
[LAUGHING CONTINUES]
[ALL GASP]
[ALL GRUNTING]
Aah! Superman?
Superman is here?
DESAAD:
And Batman.
They have unexpectedly joined forces.
Aah! Oh, they must know our plan.
I didn't say anything, I swear. I know I can be
a gossip, but they didn't hear it from me.
Unless my mother said something.
Crush them.
As you wish, my lord.
Crushing them as we speak.
Crush, crush, crush.
[GASPS]
DESAAD:
Yes! We've crushed them.
We've squished them.
Squished them into jelly, master.
Ooh, jelly. Maybe I could spread them
on my toast.
[GIGGLING]
Huh?
Where's my jelly?
Huh. Hmm.
Master Darkseid, the jelly--
I mean, the heroes have vanished.
Vaporized. Pulverized.
Atomized. Victimized.
We'll probably never see them again.
Probably. Maybe. Definitely?
Then there are more stones to collect.
Yes.
More stones, more stones, more stones.
[CHUCKLING]
[GRUNTING AND GROANING]
[SQUEAKING]
[BATZARRO CHUCKLING]
BATMAN: Ugh.
BATZARRO: Hmm?
Good thinking. Creating a tunnel
for us to escape into saved us all.
Was that a compliment?
BATMAN: Aah! No. The alien clearly has some
sort of mind control power I'm unaware of.
Must keep my wits about me.
GUY:
Nice.
You managed to find
these Bizarro knuckleheads on your own.
Man.
Ugh.
Why does this planet keep tripping me up?
You am pretty, like Bizarra.
[BELCHES]
[WONDER WOMAN GRUNTS]
Ha! She is the spitting image of you, princess.
Ha-ha-ha.
Hey. Who--?
You make good hiding place for Greenzarro.
Oh, boy.
Huh? Me am help you. Ha-ha-ha.
Thanks, I got it.
Now that we've found them,
what are we gonna do with these Bizarros?
We're actually dealing with something
much bigger than Superma--
I mean, Bizarro now.
Darkseid.
Darkseid?
I'm guessing that's a bad thing.
Oh, he's just the most dangerous force
in the universe.
GREENZARRO:
Yipe!
Is that why you stole the Bizarro ray
and created your own league?
To stop Darkseid?
Bizarro wanted to protect his citizens
from big head machine.
Big head machine
already take many citizens.
You should have come to me first, Bizarro.
We can help you against Darkseid.
Whoa, whoa. Whoa, whoa.
Easy for you to say,
Mr. I've-Still-Got-My-Powers.
Are you sure you're not scared, Guy?
We're talking about rocks, princess.
Why risk our behinds
for meaningless rocks?
Rocks my only friends
after Superman send me away.
-I sent you here because--
-Because you embarrassed by Bizarro.
So you hide him.
No, I--
They may just be rocks...
...but I suspect Darkseid wants to harvest
their unique properties for a weapon.
-Weirdiation.
-Why make a weapon out of something...
...that messes up everything
it comes in contact with?
Because it messes up everything
it comes in contact with.
Harnessing the power of this weirdiation...
...could render Earth's defenses,
it's heroes, useless.
Just like Guy.
Hey.
If Darkseid's after these rocks...
...then he's headed
to the greatest concentration of them:
Bizarrotropolis.
I have a plan. I'm going to reconstruct
the blocks of these vehicles...
...to create a thermodynamic amplifier
of the Bizarro ray.
When fired at Darkseid's weirdiation supply,
it will create a new opposite form of matter...
...and the two will annihilate each other,
destroying his ship.
That make no sense.
All I hear is, "Blah, blah, blah...
...science, blah, big word."
I have better plan.
First, we take nap.
Yay! Nap.
[SNORING]
I think we should go with Batman's plan.
Thank you for meeting Bizarro for talk
in his special place.
You am excellent listener.
Bizarro not feel helpful to Justice League.
-Bizarro not helpful to anyone.
-Ahem.
Huh?
-Something bothering you?
-On Earth, I bad hero...
...on Bizarro world, I bad hero.
All I want is save day like Superman.
Oh. Oh, uh-- Ugh.
Sorry.
Uh. Aw.
The Justice League will save the day, Bizarro.
I promise.
No.
Bizarro save day.
Darkseid.
We've got to buy Batman some time.
Let's go.
Ha, ha.
This is gonna make you laugh.
Superman apparently was not crushed
when we were doing all that crushing.
Neither was anyone else.
Please don't hurt me.
I will deal with them myself.
[BUZZING]
[GRUMBLING AND GRUNTING]
By Athena's gray eyes, she is a dog of war.
Then why is my guy such a pussycat?
Why can't you be more like her?
[WHIMPERS]
Come on. You can do it.
I believe in you. You're a Lantern.
Ha!
[CLUCKS]
Still not working.
No!
[LAUGHING]
That's what I'm talking about.
They better watch out
for Darkseid's Omega Beams.
What are Omega Beams?
[CYBORG GASPS THEN SCREAMS]
Those are Omega Beams.
Got it.
Superman, we meet again.
[GRUNTING]
[SHOUTS]
You know, Darkseid,
my mother used to say:
"Heroes get the cake
and bullies get the rake."
I'm still not entirely sure
what that all meant...
...but we'll never let you harness
the power of this planet, you space bully.
I will.
And after Earth falls,
the entire universe will bow to me.
I don't think so.
Oh, the cape. Oh, the face.
[SCREAMING]
[SUPERMAN GRUNTS]
I need more time, Superman.
[SUPERMAN CHUCKLING]
Time?
Time is now purple o'clock. Heh, heh.
[GRUNTS]
I can break for you.
That's what we're worried about.
Aah.
[SQUEAKING]
[SHOUTING]
Go, Cyzarro, break now.
[GRUNTING]
BATMAN:
He did it.
He fixed it.
Of course. Only a Bizarro
can make technology work here.
Take this.
-Ugh!
-And this.
-And one of these too.
-Ugh.
Uh-oh.
Ugh! Not fun.
You're too late, Superman.
I now have enough of this bizarre energy
to rule the galaxy.
[GRUNTING]
Well, on Bizarro World,
rules are meant to be broken.
[PLANE WHIRRING]
Bizarro save day.
SUPERMAN:
Bizarro, stop!
[BATMAN GRUNTING THEN ALL GASP]
A kryptonite bomb.
Thank you.
[BEEPING]
[CHUCKLING]
Desaad, let us test our weapon on Earth.
[WHIRRING]
[HAWKMAN CAWING]
Hawkman and hawk jet, inbound.
Deploying hawk swords.
Pressing hawk button.
Hawk shield deployed.
[HAWKMAN CAWING]
[GRUNTING]
BATMAN [OVER RADIO]:
Hawkman, did you intercept the ray?
You could say that.
Hawkman is holding off the ray...
...but I suspect even his armor
will eventually fall to the weirdiation.
Bizarro tried to help.
Yeah, you helped, all right.
You helped Darkseid.
Thanks to you, we're done. Earth is toast.
Without Superman, we can't stop him.
Yes. Yes, you can.
Darkseid's ship is somehow
being protected from the weirdiation.
But if we overload the ship
with those crazy rocks....
-Huh?
-But that'll just make his weapon stronger.
So this is how you destroy us all.
You need to trust me, Batman.
Trust you?
[GRUNTING]
[GROANS]
Well, if there's one place I can try trusting you,
it's on a backwards world.
No. Those are Bizarro's people.
His friends.
I know, Bizarro,
but you have new friends now.
[CHUCKLING]
Huh? Ah.
-Heh.
SUPERMAN: And an old one too.
Superman Bizarro's friend?
Not just friends, Bizarro.
Brothers.
And I should've been a better one to you.
Twin brothers?
Fraternal, but, yes, twin.
[CHUCKLES]
Goodbye. Bizarro miss you.
[GRUNTING]
[CHICKEN CLUCKING]
[ALL GRUNTING]
[GRUNTING THEN CHUCKLING]
I miss you.
Especially you with pointy head.
What are they doing?
They're overloading the system.
Goodbye, special place.
[GRUNTS]
[BEEPING INCREASING
THEN ALARM BLARES]
[LAUGHING AND CHEERING]
We lose. Heh, heh.
Activate the boom tube.
Yes, sire!
Must keep pressing button.
So hard.
Huh?
[SIGHS]
Uh....
How attached are Earthlings
to a round moon?
Superman A-okay.
That's great.
He's gonna be all right, then?
No. Batzarro means we can't save him.
Goodbye, Kal.
Gonna miss you, pal.
Wish I could've learned more from you.
Superman live.
Stop with the opposite talk, man.
No. Superman live.
He's drawing the kryptonite radiation
from his body.
And because he's Bizarro,
it doesn't affect him.
[GRUNTING]
[BELCHES]
[SUPERMAN GROANS]
[GROANS THEN CHUCKLES]
You saved the day, Bizarro.
-Bad job.
-Terrible work.
You're a loser. Heh.
[CHUCKLES]
Thanks.
-You had me scared for a second, buddy.
-Scared?
Knew it.
Booyah!
Darkseid on the run and the Earth is safe.
Justice League does it again.
Fist bump.
[CHUCKLES]
I'm not wrong often, but I was about you.
You can be trusted.
Really? Wow.
Then I guess you won't need
that box of kryptonite anymore.
Let's not go crazy.
If we're gonna have a wild card
on the team...
...who can't stop keeping tabs on me,
I'm glad it's you.
Whoa. Look at this place.
Bizarro lost whole world.
Then we're just gonna
have to rebuild it together.
[CHUCKLES]
Hmm, great job.
In fact, the whole place looks wonderful.
I can't wait to walk through that front door.
Hmm. Front door.
So the heroes managed
to survive Bizarro World. Hooray.
But even the mighty Justice League
cannot hope to survive...
...Operation Doom.
[English - US - SDH]