The Empire is gone, Mando.
This asset
was of extreme importance to me.
I had to ensure its delivery.
He's not a local warlord.
He's Imperial.
I'm in.
Our secrecy is our survival.
Our survival is our strength.
Our strength was once in our numbers.
Now, we live in the shadows.
Our world was shattered by the Empire.
You're going
to have to relocate the covert.
This is the Way.
In the wake of your destruction,
it was left behind.
Is it still a hunter?
No. But it will protect.
You got a real thing for droids,
don't you?
I got a real thing for that droid.
Let me take the child to him...
Let's kill him and get out of here.
- We both need the client to be eliminated.
- He's right.
As long as the Imp lives,
he'll send hunters after the child.
It's a trap.
- Have they brought the child?
- Yes, they have.
You have something I want.
Kuiil? Are you there?
In a few moments...
Kuiil! Are you there?
...it will be mine.
Speeder bikes have arrived
at the checkpoint with the asset.
Awaiting confirmation.
Knock it off!
Waiting for confirmation
to continue into town.
That's a go to proceed,
but I advise you to double-check.
The Moff just touched down and already
took out a squad of local troopers.
Standing by.
Did he just say
that Gideon killed his own men?
Oh, who knows?
These guys like to lay down the law
when they first arrive into town.
You know how it is.
I said, shut up. Yeesh.
What is that thing, anyway?
Uh, I don't know.
Maybe Moff wants to eat it.
I don't ask questions.
Can I see it?
Did you not just hear
that Moff Gideon killed
a dozen of his own troopers
to make a point.
- Okay.
- I get that point.
- Do you get the point?
- Yes.
Okay.
Should we offer
that thing some water?
You just wanna look at it.
So what?
You got to see it!
Barely.
I mean, I grabbed it up off the ground
and I stuffed it in the sack.
It's more than I got to see it.
Look, I'm not taking it out of
this bag until I deliver it to the Moff.
- Fine.
- Okay. Stop asking.
Let me check on this thing. This is crazy.
Any update yet?
That's a negative.
Still waiting on confirmation.
He just killed an officer
for interrupting him,
so this might take a while.
Thank you.
Standing by still. Unbelievable.
Hey, how long has it been
since that thing moved?
I don't know,
like a minute or two. Don't worry.
Uh, it's been
way longer than a minute.
Oh, my God.
Shouldn't we check
and see if it's still alive?
You hit it pretty hard.
You just wanna see it.
We should check
and see if it's hurt.
The last thing that you want
is to give Gideon a bag
and have him open it
and find whatever is dead...
Okay. Okay, look.
Here you go. See?
Take a peek. Everything's fine.
What is that?
I don't know.
It's a pet or something.
A pet? I thought you...
Serves you right.
Stop that.
Identify yourself!
I am IG-11.
I am this child's nurse droid and require
that you remand him to me immediately.
A nurse droid?
I thought it was a hunter.
Aren't IGs usually hunters?
Yeah, well,
evidently this one's a nurse.
I'm sorry, nurse,
but you're gonna have to get out of here.
Are you refusing my request?
No.
I'm telling you to get out of here.
Hey.
That was unpleasant.
I'm sorry you had to see that.
Is there another way out?
No, that's it.
- What about the sewers?
- Sewers?
The Mandalorians
have a covert down in the sewers.
If we can get down there,
they can help us escape.
Yeah, sewers are good.
Checking for access points.
What the hell are they waiting for?
Hold up.
They're setting up an E-Web.
It's over.
I found the sewer vent.
Let's get the hell out of here.
It's assembled!
How long until that thing's cleared?
- Blow it.
- I'm out of charges.
Get out of the way!
Your astute panic suggests
that you understand your situation.
I would prefer to avoid
any further violence,
and encourage a moment of consideration.
Members of my escort
have completed assembly
of an E-Web heavy repeating blaster.
If you are unfamiliar with this weapon,
I am sure that Republican Shock Trooper
Carasynthia Dune of Alderaan
will advise you that she has witnessed
many of her ranks vaporize mid-descent
facing the predecessor
of this particular model.
Or perhaps the decommissioned
Mandalorian hunter, Din Djarin,
has heard the songs
of the Siege of Mandalore,
when gunships outfitted
with similar ordnance
laid waste to fields of Mandalorian
recruits in The Night of a Thousand Tears.
I advise disgraced Magistrate Greef Karga
to search the wisdom of his years
and urge you to lay down your arms
and come outside.
The structure you are trapped in
will be razed in short order
and your storied lives will come
to an unceremonious end.
What do you propose?
Reasonable negotiation.
What assurance do you offer?
If you're asking
if you can trust me, you cannot.
Just as you betrayed
our business arrangement,
I would gladly break any promise
and watch you die at my hand.
The assurance I give is this:
I will act in my own self-interest,
which at this time involves
your cooperation and benefit.
I will give you until nightfall, and then
I will have the E-Web cannon open fire.
I say we hear him out.
The minute we open that door, we're dead.
We're dead if we don't.
At least out there, we've got a shot.
That's easy for you to say.
I'm a Rebel Shock Trooper.
They'll upload me to a Mind Flayer.
Those aren't real.
That was just wartime propaganda.
I don't care to find out.
I'm shooting my way out of here.
What about you, Mando?
I know who he is.
It's Moff Gideon.
No.
Moff Gideon was executed for war crimes.
It's him.
He knew my name.
So? What does that prove?
I haven't heard that name
spoken since I was a child.
On Mandalore?
I was not born on Mandalore.
But you're a Mandalorian.
Mandalorian isn't a race.
It's a Creed.
I was a foundling.
They raised me in the Fighting Corps.
I was treated as one of their own.
When I came of age,
I was sworn to the Creed.
The only record of my family name
was in the registers of Mandalore.
Moff Gideon was an ISB Officer
during the purge.
That's how I know it's him.
That's how he knows who we all are.
He says he needs us,
which means the child got away safely.
I was worried when the Ugnaught
didn't respond,
but if they'd captured the kid,
we'd already be dead.
Hail them again.
Come in, Kuiil.
Kuiil?
- Nothing.
- They might have jammed the link.
Kuiil has been terminated.
What did you do?
I am fulfilling my base function.
Which is?
To nurse and protect.
What was that?
Look alive.
Look!
Cover me.
Burn them out.
Stay with me, buddy.
We're gonna get you out of here.
This is our only path out.
Can you clear it?
Stay with me.
If you go near this child,
I will no choice but to kill you.
I understand.
Can you do anything to move the grate?
Yes, of course.
Oh, I love IG units.
I'm not gonna make it. Go.
Shut up. You just got your bell rung.
You'll be fine.
Leave me.
- I'm gonna need to take this thing off.
- No. You leave me.
You make sure the child is safe.
Here.
When you get to the Mandalorian covert,
you show them that.
You tell them it's from Din Djarin.
You tell them the foundling was
in my protection, and they'll help you.
We can make it.
Come on! Let's go!
I'm not gonna make it and you know it.
You protect the child.
I can hold them back long enough
for you to escape.
Let me have a warrior's death.
I won't leave you.
This is the Way.
Come on! It's open, let's go!
Go. Go.
We have to move! Now!
Go.
Escape and protect this child.
I will stay with the Mandalorian.
Promise me you'll bring him.
You have my word.
Do it.
Do what?
Just get it over with.
I'd rather you kill me than some Imp.
I told you.
I am no longer a hunter.
I am a nurse droid.
IGs are all hunters.
Not this one. I was reprogrammed.
I need to remove your helmet
if I am to save you.
Try it and I'll kill you.
It is forbidden.
No living thing has seen me
without my helmet since I swore the Creed.
I am not a living thing.
This is a bacta spray.
It will heal you in a matter of hours.
You have suffered damage
to your central processing unit.
You mean my brain?
That was a joke.
It is meant to put you at ease.
I got you.
Do you know which way to go?
No. I don't know these tunnels.
I've only entered from the bazaar.
Well, if we get the smell
of sulfur and we follow it,
it'll lead us up to the plains
where the river flows.
And the Imps will
catch us before we make it to the ship.
We need the Mandalorians
to escort us to safety.
Ugh, this place is a maze.
Stop.
I can stand.
The bacta infusion is working.
I'll try to find tracks.
We're close.
Turn here.
We should go.
You go. Take the ship.
I can't leave it this way.
Did you know about this?
Is this the work of your bounty hunters?
No.
When you left the system
and took the prize, the fighting ended
and the hunters just melted away.
You know how it is.
They're mercenaries. They're not zealots.
Did you do this? Did you?
- No!
- It was not his fault.
We revealed ourselves.
We knew what could happen
if we left the covert.
The Imperials arrived shortly thereafter.
This is what resulted.
Did any survive?
I hope so.
Some may have escaped off-world.
Come with us.
No.
I will not abandon this place
until I have salvaged what remains.
Show me the one
whose safety deemed such destruction.
This is the one.
This is the one that you hunted,
then saved?
Yes. The one that saved me as well.
- From the mudhorn?
- Yes.
It looks helpless.
It's injured, but it is not helpless.
Its species can move objects
with its mind.
I know of such things.
The songs of eons past tell of battles
between Mandalore The Great,
and an order of sorcerers called Jedi
that fought with such powers.
It is an enemy?
No. Its kind were enemies,
but this individual is not.
What is it?
It is a foundling.
By Creed, it is in your care.
You wish me to train this thing?
It is too weak. It would die.
You have no choice.
You must reunite it with its own kind.
Where?
This, you must determine.
You expect me to search the galaxy
for the home of this creature
and deliver it to a race
of enemy sorcerers?
This is the Way.
Hey.
These tunnels will be lousy with Imps
in a matter of minutes.
We should at least discuss an escape plan.
If you follow
the descending tunnel,
it will lead you to the underground river.
It flows downstream toward the lava flats.
I think we should go.
I'm staying.
I need to help her and I need to heal.
You must go.
A foundling is in your care.
By Creed, until it is of age or reunited
with its own kind,
you are as its father.
This is the Way.
You have earned your Signet.
You are a clan of two.
Thank you.
I will wear this with honor.
We should go.
IG, please guard
the outer hallway.
A scouting party draws near.
Hang on.
I don't do the baby thing.
I have one more gift
for your journey.
Have you trained in the Rising Phoenix?
When I was a boy. Yes.
Then this will make you complete.
Thank you.
ARMORER When you have healed,
you will begin your drills.
Until you know it,
it will not listen to your commands.
I understand.
You are protected.
More will come. You must go.
Come with us.
My place is here.
Restock your munitions.
IG, carry this for Din Djarin
until he is well enough to wear it.
Now, go.
Down to the river and across the plains.
Be safe on your journey.
Thank you.
Hey, Mando.
Where are they?
I said, where are they?
This is the lava river.
The ferry droid is fried.
Yeah, but if we push the boat out,
we can get it to float downstream.
Come on.
Looks old. Will it take the heat?
You got a better idea?
Guess not.
Push!
Come on! What're you doing?
- Let's try this.
- Push!
You guys mind getting out of the way?
Oh!
Good job.
Watch your feet. It's molten lava.
No kidding.
I don't suppose anybody here speaks droid?
I believe he is asking
where we would like to go.
Down river. To the lava flat.
That's it. We're free!
No.
No, we're not.
Stormtroopers.
They're flanking the mouth of the tunnel.
It looks like an entire platoon.
They must know we're coming.
Stop the boat.
Hey, Droid, I said stop the boat.
Hey! I'm talking to you.
I said stop!
We're still moving.
Looks like we fight.
- There are too many.
- Then what do you suggest?
'Cause I can't surrender.
They will not be satisfied
with anything less than the child.
This is unacceptable.
I will eliminate the enemy
and you will escape.
You don't have
that kind of firepower, pal.
You wouldn't even get to daylight.
That is not my objective.
We're getting close. Saddle up.
I still have the security protocols
from my manufacturer.
If my designs are compromised,
I must self-destruct.
What're you talking about?
I am not permitted to be captured.
I must be destroyed.
Are we gonna keep talking,
or get out of here?
I can no longer carry this for you.
Nor can I watch over the child.
Wait. You can't self-destruct.
Your base command is to watch the child.
That supersedes
your manufacturer's protocol, right?
- Right?
- This is correct.
Good. Now, grab a blaster
and help us shoot our way out.
Victory through combat
is impossible.
We will be captured.
The child will be lost.
Sadly, there is no scenario where
the child is saved, in which I survive.
Listen, you're not going anywhere.
We need you. Let's just come up with a...
Please tell me the child
will be safe in your care.
If you do so,
I can default to my secondary command.
But you'll be destroyed.
And you will live,
and I will have served my purpose.
No. We need you.
There is nothing to be sad about.
I have never been alive.
I'm not sad.
Yes, you are. I'm a nurse droid.
I've analyzed your voice.
IG?
What're you doing?
Manufacturer's protocol dictates
I cannot be captured.
I must be destroyed.
Moff Gideon!
- He missed!
- He won't next time.
Our blasters are useless against him.
Let's make the baby do
the magic hand thing.
Come on, baby! Do the magic hand thing.
- I'm out of ideas.
- I'm not.
Here he comes!
No!
That was impressive, Mando.
Very impressive.
It looks like your Guild rates
have just gone up.
Any more stormtroopers?
I think we cleaned up the town.
I'm thinking of staying around
just to be sure.
- You're staying here?
- Well, why not?
Nevarro is a very fine planet.
And now that the scum and villainy
have been washed away,
it's very respectable again.
As a bounty hunter hive?
Some of my favorite people
are bounty hunters.
And perhaps, this specimen of soldier
might consider joining our ranks.
Yeah. I've got some clerical
concerns regarding my chain code.
And if you would agree
to become my enforcer,
clerical concerns would be
the least of your worries.
But you, my friend, you will be welcome
back into the Guild with open arms.
So, go off, enjoy yourself.
And when you're ready to return,
you will have the pick of all quarries.
I'm afraid I have
more pressing matters at hand.
Take care of this little one.
Or maybe, it'll take care of you.
What do you got there?
I didn't think I'd see this again.
Why don't you hang onto that?