[cheers and applause]
[indistinct chatter]
- LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
ILIZA SHLESINGER!
[upbeat music]
[cheers and applause]
- ALL RIGHT!
DALLAS, TEXAS!
[laughs]
THANK YOU.
[cheers and applause]
OH.
HOW ARE YOU GUYS DOING?
THANK YOU FOR COMING OUT, Y'ŐALL.
FANTASTIC.
I AM SO EXCITED AND HONORED
TO BE SHOOTING MY HOUR SPECIAL
IN MY HOMETOWN
OF DALLAS, TEXAS.
YES, MA'ŐAM.
[cheers and applause]
[laughs]
I'ŐM SO EXCITED
TO BE HERE.
NOT THRILLED
WITH GETTING HERE.
I HAVE TO BE HONEST.
I FLY ENOUGH THAT I FEEL
I HAVE THE RIGHT TO SAY THIS.
IF YOU WORK
FOR AN AIRLINE,
I HATE YOU.
OKAY?
AND I DON'ŐT WANT
TO HEAR,
"NO, MY COUSIN SHEILA'ŐS
A REAL SWEETHEART.
SHE WORKS FOR SOUTHWEST."
FUCK YOUR COUSIN SHEILA.
[laughter]
ALL RIGHT, YOUR COUSIN SHEILA'ŐS
A GODDAMN BITCH.
AND I'ŐLL TELL YOU
SOMETHING ELSE.
THE ONLY REASON
PEOPLE WORK FOR AIRLINES
IS BECAUSE THE NAZI PARTY
IS NO LONGER HIRING.
[laughter and applause]
I DON'ŐT HAVE AN ISSUE--
THANK YOU.
I DON'ŐT HAVE AN ISSUE
WITH FLYING.
MY ISSUE IS WITH THE BOARDING
OF THE PLANE.
HAS ANYONE ELSE HERE
EVER HAD THE MISFORTUNE
OF BEING STUCK
IN BOARDING ZONE FOUR?
LIKE, THAT'ŐS WHEN
YOU HAVE A SEAT--
YOU HAVE A TICKET
'ŐCAUSE YOU'ŐRE HOLDING IT--
BUT YOU'ŐRE SO LOW
ON THE FOOD CHAIN,
IT PRETTY MUCH GOES,
LIKE, FIRST-CLASS,
LUGGAGE, TERRORISTS,
MAYBE YOU.
[laughter]
AND THEY TAKE
SUCH PAINSTAKING CARE
TO BOARD ZONES
ONE THROUGH THREE.
AND IF YOU DON'ŐT FLY
THAT AIRLINE OFTEN ENOUGH,
YOU ARE S.O.L. IN TERMS
OF GETTING ON THAT PLANE
'ŐCAUSE THEY ARE BOARDING GROUPS
OF PEOPLE
THAT YOU DIDN'ŐT EVEN KNOW
YOU COULD APPLY
TO BE PART OF.
WE'ŐRE GONNA START BOARDING
FLIGHT 556 TO DALLAS/FORT WORTH.
ZONE ONE.
THESE ARE
OUR FIRST-CLASS PASSENGERS,
OUR FIRST MEMBERS,
OUR GOLD MEMBERS,
OUR GOLDEN SHOWER MEMBERS.
THERE YOU GO.
THANK YOU, THERE YOU GO.
RIGHT THIS WAY.
OUR GOLDEN EAGLE MEMBERS,
OUR EAGLE FACE MEMBERS.
IF YOU HAVE AN EAGLE FACE
INSTEAD OF A PERSON FACE
'ŐCAUSE YOU LOST
YOUR FACE
IN SOME SORT OF HORRIBLE HOLIDAY
TURKEY DEEP FRY ACCIDENT,
YOU DIDN'ŐT HAVE
ENOUGH BUTT FAT
TO GET A NOSE GRAFTED
ONTO YOUR FACE,
SO YOU HAD TO BORROW ONE
FROM AN EAGLE,
SO NOW YOU HAVE A BEAK,
AND YOU LIKE TO EAT MICE,
YOU CAN GET ON THE PLANE.
BOARDING ZONE TWO--
THESE ARE OUR SILVER MEMBERS,
OUR SILVER STAR MEMBERS,
OUR SILVER SURFER MEMBERS.
IF ANYBODY LIKES COMIC BOOKS,
YOU'ŐRE A FUCKIN'Ő NERD.
YOU CAN SIT IN THE BACK
OF THE PLANE.
SILVER HAIR, IF YOU'ŐRE OLD,
HURRY THE FUCK UP.
SILVER SPOONS, IF YOU LIKE
RICKY SCHRODER, 'Ő80s TV SHOWS,
YOU WERE BORN REALLY WEALTHY,
YOU CAN GET ON THE PLANE.
SILVER BULLET SUMMER--
NO, MA'ŐAM, YOU CANNOT BRING
YOUR COORS LIGHT
UP IN THIS, BITCH.
BOARDING ZONE THREE.
[cheering]
THESE ARE OUR...
[cheers and applause]
THESE ARE OUR COPPER MEMBERS,
OUR COPPER STAR MEMBERS,
OUR COPPER TOPPER MEMBERS.
IS ANYBODY USING
A DURACELL-OPERATED DEVICE?
I DON'ŐT GIVE A SHIT
IF IT'ŐS A PACEMAKER.
YOU TURN THAT OFF
FOR TAKEOFF.
COPPERHEAD.
IF YOU HAVE A COPPERHEAD SNAKE
AS A PET
INSTEAD OF A NORMAL GODDAMN PET
LIKE A DOG OR A CAT,
YOU'ŐRE LIKE, "FUCK IT,
I'ŐM GONNA GET ME A SNAKE.
"YEAH, FUCK YOU, DAD.
I'ŐM NOT GOING TO LAW SCHOOL.
"I'ŐM GONNA GO
TO ART SCHOOL ONLINE
"AND LEARN
HOW TO DRAW DRAGONS
"AND MANAGE A HOT TOPIC
IN MY SPARE TIME.
"I LOVE MY SNAKE.
"I'ŐM BRINGING HER
TO THANKSGIVING.
"HER NAME IS JUDY.
WE'ŐRE IN SNAKE LOVE.
"I LOVE HER SO MUCH.
DON'ŐT TOUCH ME, MOM."
YOU GET
ON THE PLANE.
AND BOARDING ZONE FOUR,
YOU CAN GO FUCK YOURSELF.
[cheers and applause]
NOW BOARDING ALL ZONES.
[laughter]
I SPEND
A LOT OF TIME TRAVELING.
SPEND A LOT OF TIME
IN HOTELS.
AND AS A RESULT OF IT,
I WATCH A LOT OF TV.
AND I THINK
THE SADDEST COMMERCIAL OUT THERE
HAS TO BE THE S.P.C.A.
SARAH MCLACHLAN AD.
SEEN IT?
WITH THE FUCKED UP ANIMALS?
CAN I TELL YOU A SECRET
ABOUT THIS COMMERCIAL?
IT KNOWS
WHEN YOU'ŐRE ALONE.
[laughter]
DO YOU EVER NOTICE
IT ONLY COMES ON
WHEN YOU'ŐRE BY YOURSELF,
MAYBE YOU'ŐRE DRUNK?
YOU'ŐRE VULNERABLE, RIGHT?
AND WHAT'ŐS CRAZY
IS AT FIRST,
YES, YOU ARE SAD
FOR THE ANIMALS.
BUT THE LONGER
YOU WATCH IT,
THE LONGER YOUR SADNESS
KIND OF BEGINS TO TURN ON YOU,
AND BY THE END OF IT,
SOMEHOW,
YOU JUST FEEL REALLY BAD
FOR YOURSELF?
YOU'ŐRE SITTING THERE,
LIKE, "OH, MY GOD.
THERE'ŐS--THAT CAT
DOESN'ŐT HAVE A FACE."
I DON'ŐT KNOW.
"I'ŐM SO SAD.
"I FEEL SO BAD
FOR HIM.
"AND I FEEL SO BAD
FOR HIS CAT FAMILY.
AND I FEEL SO BAD FOR...
ME."
[cries]
"OH, GOD.
WHAT AM I GONNA DO?
"WHAT SHOULD I DO?
I SHOULD--I SHOULD--
I SHOULD GET A CAT."
SO YOU GET A CAT.
BUT BECAUSE HE'ŐS
FROM THE S.P.C.A.,
LIKE, LET'ŐS BE HONEST, HE'ŐS ALL,
LIKE, FUCKED UP AND AUTISTIC.
JUST SHITS EVERYWHERE.
YOU'ŐRE LIKE, "OH, MY GOD.
WHAT DID YOU EAT?"
GOES THROUGH YOUR STUFF.
HE ONLY EATS THE BUTTONS
OFF YOUR GOOD SWEATERS.
YOU'ŐRE LIKE, "HOW DID YOU KNOW
TO GO TO FOR THE GOOD SWEATERS?
"WHY DIDN'ŐT YOU GO
FOR THE CRAPPY SWEATERS?
WHY DO YOU HAVE
SUCH EXQUISITE TASTE?"
GOTTA GET RID OF HIM
'ŐCAUSE HE'ŐS RUINING EVERYTHING.
BUT WHAT DO YOU DO?
YOU CAN'ŐT KILL HIM BECAUSE--
BECAUSE THAT'ŐS FUCKING INSANE,
I GUESS.
BUT YOU GOTTA GET RID OF HIM.
SO WHAT DO YOU DO?
I'ŐM GONNA TELL YOU.
YOU PUT KITTY
IN THE CAR.
YOU DRIVE HIM TO A NEIGHBORHOOD
HE DOESN'ŐT KNOW.
[laughter]
YOU LET HIM
OUT OF THE CAR.
DON'ŐT WORRY.
THE S.P.C.A.
WILL FIND THAT CAT.
I DON'ŐT KNOW
IF YOU'ŐVE NOTICED.
THEY'ŐRE IN THE BUSINESS
OF SECONDHAND CATTERY.
THEY FIND THE CAT.
THEY CLEAN HIM OFF.
THEY UPDATE HIS RESUME.
HE GETS A JOB MANAGING,
LIKE, A CHIPOTLE.
HE'ŐS FINE,
ALL RIGHT?
SO IN HONOR
OF THAT COMMERCIAL,
I HAVE A TREAT
FOR YOU GUYS.
[cheers and applause]
THIS IS MY CAT.
[laughter]
[cheers and applause]
THIS IS MY DOG BLANCHE,
AND I ADOPTED HER.
AND SOMETIMES WHEN YOU ADOPT
AN ANIMAL,
YOU DON'ŐT KNOW
THEIR BACK STORY.
SO FOR BLANCHE,
I MADE ONE UP.
IN MY HOUSE,
WE PRETEND THAT BLANCHE
USED TO BE
A DOG PROSTITUTE...
[laughter]
[cheers and applause]
WHICH MAKES SENSE,
BECAUSE AS YOU CAN TELL,
SHE'ŐS A LITTLE SAD
BEHIND THE EYES...
BUT SHE CLEARLY
HAS NO PROBLEM
WITH YOU STARING
AT HER DOG VAGINA.
[laughter]
MAKE IT RAIN.
SHAKE IT
FOR THE MONEY.
SO IN HONOR OF THAT COMMERCIAL,
SHE AND I ARE NOW GOING TO DO
OUR RENDITION OF IT
FOR YOU.
HERE WE GO.
[laughter]
[singing]
IN THE ARMS
OF THE ANGEL,
FAR AWAY
FROM HERE,
IN THIS DARK,
COLD HOTEL ROOM,
AND THE END,
DAH, DAH, DAH, DAH, DAH
YOU WERE PULLED--
[chuckles]
THAT'ŐS IT.
THAT'ŐS IT FOR BLANCHE.
[cheers and applause]
LET'ŐS GET SERIOUS.
MY DOG IS SO CUTE,
I WANT TO HURT HER.
DO YOU EVER GET THAT WAY?
WHEN SOMETHING IS SO CUTE,
IT MAKES YOU ANGRY.
I JUST WANT TO RIP ITS NOSE
AND--[growls]
YOU EVER GET THAT WAY
WHEN SOMETHING IS SO CUTE,
YOU DON'ŐT KNOW IF YOU CAN
TRUST YOURSELF AROUND IT?
I USED TO GET THAT WAY
WITH MY NANA.
SHE'ŐS, LIKE, THIS TALL,
AND YOU EVER HUG
YOUR GRANDPARENT,
AND YOU'ŐRE, LIKE, "OH, MY GOD,
I JUST WANNA PUSH YOU
DOWN THE STAIRS."
YOU EVER FEEL THAT WAY?
YOU EVER FEEL THE URGE,
JUST, "WHAT IF I JUST--"
[growls]
"JUST FEEL LIKE..."
HYPOTHETICALLY.
[sighs]
SOMETIMES, I GET THAT WAY
AROUND GARBAGE DISPOSALS.
YOU EVER JUST PUT YOUR HAND IN
JUST TO FEEL THE--FEEL THE FEAR?
[groans]
YOU REACH
THE OTHER HAND OVER.
YOU DON'ŐT TOUCH THE SWITCH,
BUT YOU HOVER AROUND IT?
YOU'ŐRE LIKE,
"WHAT IF I JUST..."
[groans]
"NO!"
[grunts]
I DON'ŐT DO THAT EITHER.
IT WAS JUST A JOKE.
SOMETIMES YOU GET THAT WAY
WITH CUTE THINGS, LIKE BABIES.
SOMETIMES BABIES
ARE SO CUTE.
ARE NOT SO CUTE.
BUT SOMETIMES BABIES--
SO CUTE,
YOU KNOW,
FAT, LITTLE, BABY CHEEK.
YOU JUST WANT
TO RIP HIS CHEEK OFF.
[laughter]
BUT YOU CAN'ŐT
'ŐCAUSE YOU WON'ŐT
BE ALLOWED
AROUND THE BABY ANYMORE.
THAT'ŐS FOR GODDAMN SURE.
THERE WAS ANOTHER VERSION
OF THAT COMMERCIAL.
WHAT HAPPENED WAS THEY AIRED
THAT COMMERCIAL.
AND IT WAS SUCH A HIT, SO MANY
PEOPLE WERE ADOPTING PETS,
SO MANY PEOPLE
WERE DONATING MONEY,
SO MANY PEOPLE WERE
GOING ON ANTIDEPRESSANTS.
AND THEY WERE LIKE,
"LET'ŐS DO ANOTHER ONE."
SO THEY TRIED TO RECREATE
THE MAGIC OF THAT ONE.
SO IN THIS COMMERCIAL,
THEY PLAY
ANOTHER SARAH MCLACHLAN SONG,
OKAY?
I DON'ŐT KNOW THE SONG,
BUT IT'ŐS SOME LESBIAN CHANT.
THAT'ŐS HAPPENING.
[laughter]
AND THEY ZOOM IN
ON THESE PICTURES
OF THESE JACKED UP ANIMALS.
AND AT THE BOTTOM
OF THE SCREEN,
THEY PUT A CAPTION
OF WHAT THE ANIMAL IS THINKING?
[laughter]
NOW, WHERE THEY GOT
THAT INFORMATION, I DON'ŐT KNOW.
THEY SHOW A DOG,
AND HE'ŐS ALL NO TEETH.
HE'ŐS JUST AWFUL-LOOKING,
LIKE, "NAH!"
"WHERE'ŐS MY FAMILY?"
"I DON'ŐT KNOW!"
[mouths words]
THEY SHOW ANOTHER DOG,
AND HE'ŐS ALL MUDDY AND GNARLY.
HE'ŐS JUST, "NAH!"
"I HOPE THEY COME BACK
FOR ME."
"NAH!
"DAD, YOU SAID YOU WAS
GOING FOR CIGARETTES.
"WHY?
IT'ŐS ME, SPOT."
AND THEN,
THEY SHOWED A CAT.
AND THIS CAT WAS,
LIKE, 45 POUNDS.
IT--IT HAD ONE EYE.
[all aw]
AND IT TURNED--
DO YOU KNOW HIM?
AND IT TURNED AROUND--
HE TURNED AROUND IN SLOW MOTION,
AND IT WASN'ŐT
A CAMERA TRICK.
HE'ŐS JUST, LIKE,
A 45-POUND CAT, I GUESS.
HE DOESN'ŐT HAVE,
LIKE, A MEETING TO RUSH TO.
SO HE'ŐS NOT...
[groaning]
[laughter]
"I'ŐM SORRY
FOR WHATEVER I DID WRONG."
NO, THAT'ŐS WHERE I STOPPED
BUYING THAT COMMERCIAL.
THERE'ŐS NO WAY
A CAT HAS REMORSE.
[laughter]
YOU EVER MET A CAT?
THERE'ŐS NO WAY
HE'ŐS APOLOGETIC.
WHATEVER THAT CAT DID
TO LAND HIM IN CAT JAIL,
HE'ŐS NOT SORRY
HE DID IT.
HE'ŐS SORRY
HE GOT CAUGHT.
THERE'ŐS A DIFFERENCE.
[cheers and applause]
THAT CAT'ŐS AS HARD AS THEY COME.
HE DOESN'ŐT GIVE A SHIT.
HE'ŐS SITTING THERE
IN HIS LITTLE CAT CELL.
HE'ŐS GOT "MEOW MIX FOR LIFE"
TATTOOED ON HIS LITTLE BELLY.
HE'ŐS GOT A LITTLE RAT
THAT HE'ŐS MADE HIS BITCH.
IT'ŐS CARVING A SHIV
OUT OF CHEESE IN THE CORNER.
HE'ŐS GOT
ONE SHARPENED CAT CLAW.
HE'ŐS JUST RUNNING IT
AGAINST THE BARS, LIKE, "BRR.
BRR."
OH, YEAH, HE'ŐS GOT ONE EYE.
I FORGOT.
"BRR.
BRR."
HE'ŐS LIKE, "HEAR ME?"
[spits]
"I DON'ŐT GIVE A FUCK."
[meowing]
"YOU THINK I CARE?
"OH, HELL, YEAH,
I SCRATCHED UP YOUR CURTAINS.
AND I'ŐD DO IT AGAIN.
FUCK YOU."
[laughter]
THIS IS A CAT PAW.
[laughter and applause]
THAT COMMERCIAL
IS SAD.
THE COMMERCIAL THAT MAKES ME
FEEL THE WORST ABOUT MYSELF,
I WOULD HAVE TO SAY, WOULD BE
THE P90X COMMERCIALS.
THAT COMMERCIAL ALWAYS COMES ON
WHEN I'ŐM EATING...
[laughter]
WHICH IS THE WORST TIME
FOR ANY FITNESS COMMERCIAL
COMES ON 'ŐCAUSE IT KNOWS
WHEN YOU'ŐRE SITTING THERE
BEING A LITTLE FATTY,
EATIN'Ő GRAHAM CRACKERS
WITH YOUR SHIRT OFF,
WATCHING "LAW & ORDER: SVU."
IT KNOWS.
AND IT COMES ON, AND IT GETS
YOU, YOU'ŐRE JUST SITTIN'Ő THERE.
YOU'ŐRE LIKE,
"I'ŐLL NEVER FIND LOVE.
I DON'ŐT KNOW.
I DON'ŐT--"
[mimics static]
"DO YOU WANT TO GET IN SHAPE?"
YOU'ŐRE LIKE...
[gasps]
[laughter]
AND BY THE WAY,
IT'ŐS NOT ASKING YOU
IF YOU WANT TO GET
IN REGULAR-PERSON SHAPE.
IT'ŐS NOT TALKING
TO NORMAL PEOPLE.
IT'ŐS TALKING
TO, LIKE, NAVY SEALS.
TO CRAZY PEOPLE.
IT'ŐS NOT ASKING YOU
IF YOU WANT TO LOOK MEDIOCRE
WHEN YOU GO TO THE POOL
THIS SUMMER, UH-UH.
IT'ŐS JUST FOR CRAZY--
IT'ŐS SAYING,
"HEY, FAGGOT, DO YOU WANT TO GET
IN SUCH FUCKING GOOD SHAPE
"SO FUCKING QUICKLY
THAT YOUR ARMS
"AND YOUR--
AND YOUR CHEST AND YOUR BACK
"GET TOO BIG TO FIT
THROUGH NORMAL DOORWAYS,
"SO EVERY TIME YOU COME THROUGH,
YOU SMASH INTO THE PLASTER,
"AND YOU'ŐRE COSTING YOUR MOTHER
THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS
"IN DRYWALL DAMAGE?
"IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT?
"DO YOU WANT YOUR FRIENDS
AND FAMILY TO FEAR YOU
"BECAUSE YOU DRINK
HORSE TESTOSTERONE
"AND CREATINE SHAKES,
AND THEY MAKE YOU SLEEP OUTSIDE?
"IS THAT WHAT
YOU FUCKIN'Ő WANT?
"DO YOU WANT TO GET SO HUGE
SO QUICKLY,
"SO UNNATURALLY,
THAT ALL YOUR CLOTHES
"SHRINK ON YOU,
AND THEY FIT LIKE BABY CLOTHES
"'ŐCAUSE YOU'ŐRE LIKE THE HULK
MID-TRANSFORMATION,
"AND YOU CAN'ŐT AFFORD
TO BUY NEW CLOTHES
'ŐCAUSE YOU SPENT ALL YOUR MONEY
ON THESE FUCKING P90X DVDs?"
[cheers and applause]
MY QUESTION IS WHY?
WHY WOULD
THE AVERAGE GUY
WANT TO GET THAT JACKED
THAT FAST?
WHY? SO YOU CAN, WHAT,
BE THE STRONGEST MANAGER
AT THE VERIZON STORE?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
WITH THAT MUSCLE?
YOU WORK IN SALES.
YOU'ŐRE NOT GUARDING SPARTA.
IT'ŐS FINE.
"THIS IS SMART PHONE."
[mimics thud]
[laughter]
I THINK P90X HAS
A SUBLIMINAL MESSAGE
THAT A LOT OF US
ARE MISSING
'ŐCAUSE I DON'ŐT THINK THEY'ŐRE
TALKING TO REGULAR PEOPLE.
I THINK THE COMMERCIAL NEEDS
TO BE HONEST AND COME CLEAN
AND SAY WHAT THEIR PRODUCT
IS REALLY MEANT FOR.
THE COMMERCIAL
SHOULD SOUND LIKE THIS.
"HEY, P90X GUY HERE.
WHAT'ŐS UP?
"SO DID YOU,
LIKE, RECENTLY COMMIT A CRIME,
"AND YOU'ŐVE BEEN SENTENCED
TO PRISON,
AND YOU HAVE TO REPORT THERE
IN 90 DAYS, SO..."
[laughter]
"YOU FIGURE
IN THE INTERIM,
"YOU'ŐLL JUST GET AS HUGE
AS POSSIBLE
"FOR FEAR OF THE SAFETY
OF YOUR BUTTHOLE?
P90X."
[laughter and applause]
YEAH.
IT'ŐS A PRISON WORKOUT.
THEY'ŐRE LIKE,
"YOU CAN DO IT
FROM THE COMFORT
OF YOUR OWN LIVING ROOM."
THAT'ŐS 'ŐCAUSE YOUR LIVING ROOM
AND A JAIL CELL
ARE ROUGHLY
THE SAME SQUARE FOOTAGE.
DO THE MATH.
THINK ABOUT IT.
"NO EQUIPMENT.
NO EXCUSES."
NO SHIT THERE'ŐS NO EQUIPMENT.
YOU'ŐLL GET RAPED
WITH EQUIPMENT IN PRISON.
YOU CAN'ŐT HAVE IT THERE.
"WE HERE AT P90X
WANT YOU TO GET CREATIVE
"WITH YOUR WORKOUT.
FUCK YOUR ANTIQUES, BRO.
"YOUR GIRLFRIEND'ŐS
GONNA BREAK UP WITH YOU
"WHEN YOU GO
TO JAIL ANYWAY.
"MAY AS WELL USE SHIT
AROUND YOUR HOUSE.
"TAKE YOUR DINING ROOM TABLE.
CUT OFF THE BACK LEGS.
"PUT IT AT AN ANGLE.
"NOW, YOU HAVE A BENCH
FOR INCLINE PRESSES.
"P90X.
"GO AHEAD.
GRAB YOUR OLD KENWOOD SPEAKERS.
"THAT'ŐS RIGHT.
TAKE 'ŐEM OFF THE FRONT LAWN.
"USE THOSE FOR WEIGHT.
"YOU CAN TAKE WATER BOTTLES.
DUMP THAT SHIT OUT.
"FILL 'ŐEM UP WITH SAND.
"USE THOSE
FOR BICEP CURLS
"'ŐCAUSE YOU'ŐRE TOO CHEAP
TO BUY A SHAKE WEIGHT.
"YOU'ŐRE GONNA GET ENOUGH OF THIS
IN PRISON.
P90X."
[laughter and applause]
THE PROBLEM WITH P90X
IS THAT IT WORKS.
LIKE, YES,
IT WILL CHANGE YOUR BODY,
BUT ONLY
FROM THE NECK DOWN.
THEY DON'ŐT TELL YOU
IN THE COMMERCIAL
YOUR FACE STAYS
EXACTLY THE SAME AS IT WAS.
"DO YOU WANT TO HAVE THE BODY
OF A 20-YEAR-OLD ADONIS,
"BUT GO AHEAD
AND KEEP THE FACE
"OF A BALDING,
MIDDLE-AGED ACCOUNTANT?
"P90X, DISAPPOINT YOUR WIFE
FROM THE CHIN UP
ON A NIGHTLY BASIS."
THESE GUYS AT P90X,
YOU WANT TO LOOK HOT,
JUST GET IN SHAPE.
I THINK WOMEN IN OUR COUNTRY
HAVE TOO MANY OPTIONS
FOR WEIGHT LOSS
TO THE POINT OF PARALYSIS.
THERE'ŐS SO MANY OPTIONS.
YOU GO ON TV, THE INTERNET,
WOMEN'ŐS MAGAZINES.
THERE'ŐS SO MANY,
YOU CAN'ŐT EVEN MAKE A CHOICE.
I WAS READING A WOMEN'ŐS MAGAZINE
THE OTHER DAY
'ŐCAUSE I WANTED
TO PUNISH MYSELF
AND JUST FEEL AWFUL,
AND THEY HAD
ALL THESE DIET TIPS.
DIET TIPS FOR LADIES.
I SAW THIS ONE
IN "COSMO."
THEY SUGGESTED THAT WOMEN,
IF YOU'ŐRE ON A DIET,
"NEXT TIME YOU'ŐRE ON A DIET
AND YOU'ŐRE HUNGRY,
DON'ŐT RUIN THE DAY--"
'ŐCAUSE YOUR WHOLE DAY IS RUINED
IF YOU EAT A DOUGHNUT,
BY THE WAY.
YOU HAVE
TO KILL YOURSELF IMMEDIATELY.
"DON'ŐT RUIN THE DAY
BY GRABBING A FRIED SNACK.
INSTEAD, JUST GRAB
A HANDFUL OF ALMONDS."
JUST GO OUT--JUST GO AND GRAB
A HANDFUL OF ALMONDS.
YOU EVER DO THIS?
WHEN YOU'ŐRE HUNGRY, YOU GET
A HANDFUL OF--YOU DON'ŐT DO THAT?
YOU DON'ŐT GO UP
TO THE NEAREST TREE
AND JUST
GIRAFFE YOURSELF LIKE--
[grunts]
[laughter and applause]
"CINDY, I'ŐLL BE RIGHT THERE."
[grunts]
HANDFUL OF ALMONDS.
"COSMO" SAYS GET A HANDFUL
OF ALMONDS.
JUST GO AHEAD, GET A HANDFUL
OF ALMONDS, AND GET A HAND--
WHY DON'ŐT YOU GO
FUCK YOURSELF
WITH A HANDFUL
OF ALMONDS, "COSMO"?
SEE HOW FULL
YOU GET OFF THAT.
I'ŐM A GROWN WOMAN,
NOT A SUGAR SQUIRREL.
ALMONDS.
JUICING.
THAT'ŐS A BIG THING.
"WHY DON'ŐT YOU JUST JUICE IT?
DO YOU WANT TO JUST JUICE?
"WE SHOULD DO JUICES
AND SMOOTHIES.
YOU WANNA MAKE
A SMOOTHIE?"
[high-pitched]
YOU PRONOUNCE SMOOTHIE LIKE THIS
'ŐCAUSE YOU ONLY NEED THIS MUCH
OF YOUR MOUTH OPEN TO DRINK IT.
[laughter]
SMOOTHIE.
[mimics bleating]
THEY WANT WOMEN
TO DO THIS.
TAKE ALL YOUR FOOD,
JUICE IT DOWN.
GO GET YOUR CARROTS.
GET YOUR KALE.
DON'ŐT FORGET THE KALE.
GET THE APPLES.
PUT IT IN THE JUICER.
GO AHEAD AND JUICE THE APPLE
AND THE CELERY.
PUT YOUR HAND IN THE JUICER.
JUICE YOUR HAND DOWN.
JUICE YOUR HAND
RIGHT DOWN TO THE NUB.
MAKE SURE YOU JUICE ALL OF IT.
YOU'ŐLL LOSE 2 OUNCES.
DRINK YOUR HAND, THERE'ŐS LOTS
OF NUTRIENTS IN YOUR HAND.
"COSMO" NEVER SAID
TO JUICE YOUR HAND.
I'ŐM JUST GONNA
PUT THAT OUT THERE.
MAKE A SMOOTHIE.
DO YOU HAVE TIME IN THE MORNING
TO MAKE A SMOOTHIE?
YOU HAVE TIME FOR THIS?
NO?
SHOCKING.
YOU DON'ŐT HAVE TIME
IN THE MORNING
TO GO OUT TO YOUR OWN
PERSONAL BOTANICAL GARDEN
AND CUT DOWN
A BRONTOSAURUS BRUNCH
WORTH OF BROCCOLI
AND ASPARAGUS,
JUICE IT DOWN
TO AN OUNCE,
SO YOU CAN SHIT GREEN
FOR A WEEK?
YOU DON'ŐT HAVE TIME?
[laughter]
I LOVE BEING
A STAND-UP COMEDIAN.
IT'ŐS PROBABLY
THE BEST JOB EVER.
UH, IF I COULD HAVE
ANY JOB--
IF I COULD HAVE ANY JOB,
I WOULD BE A CAT.
BUT THAT IS
NOT SOMETHING
I'ŐM SUPPOSED
TO TALK ABOUT IN PUBLIC.
IF I COULD HAVE ANY JOB
BESIDES THIS,
I KNOW THIS SOUNDS WEIRD,
BUT I WOULD BE A PHARMACIST
BECAUSE I WOULD BE--
LIKE, I WOULD ADD
SOMETHING COOL TO IT.
I WOULD BE, LIKE, A DIFFERENT
KIND OF PHARMACIST, OKAY?
SO I WOULD
DO IT DIFFERENTLY, OKAY?
SO--SO I WOULD LOOK
LIKE A PHARMACIST.
I WOULD WEAR
THE WHITE COAT,
'ŐCAUSE WITHOUT THE WHITE COAT,
YOU'ŐRE JUST A DRUG DEALER.
[chuckles]
I'ŐD WEAR THE WHITE COAT,
BUT UNDER IT,
I WOULD GO TO, LIKE,
A RENAISSANCE FAIR.
WE HAVE RENAISSANCE FAIRS HERE?
all: YEAH.
- YES! OF COURSE WE DO.
EVERY STATE'ŐS GOT WHITE TRASH.
OF COURSE WE DO.
SO I'ŐD GO TO A RENAISSANCE FAIR.
AND I WOULD GO TO, LIKE,
THE WITCH DOCTOR'ŐS TENT.
AND I WOULD GET ONE OF THOSE,
LIKE, MEDIEVAL WITCH WOMAN BELTS
THAT HAS,
LIKE, SOME LEATHER.
AND IT'ŐS GOT BELLS
AND RACCOON PELTS
AND A JUG
FOR YOUR ALE, WHATEVER.
AND IT'ŐD HAVE, LIKE, A JAR
OF PIGEON WHISPERERS.
I'ŐD HAVE ALL THESE THINGS,
ALL THE ACCOUTREMENT
OF A CREEPY WITCH
ON MY BELT.
AND I'ŐD PUT IT UNDER THE COAT
SO THAT WHEN I WALKED,
THE COAT WOULD FLARE OPEN,
AND YOU'ŐD GET GLIMPSES
OF MY MEDIEVAL TRICKERY
UNDER IT.
JUST--
[blows]
AND YOU'ŐD BE IN LINE
AT THE PHARMACY.
AND YOU'ŐD BE LIKE, "WHAT'ŐS UP
WITH THAT ONE PHARMACIST?
"IS SHE INTO THE DARK ARTS?
"IS SHE A SORCERESS?
MAGIC WITH A 'ŐK'Ő?
DOES SHE PLAY "SKYRIM" ALONE?
WHAT IS THAT?"
[blows]
AND I WOULDN'ŐT COME UP
TO THE COUNTER.
INSTEAD--INSTEAD OF A BELL
THAT YOU RING,
I WOULD GET--
I WOULD GET A RAVEN.
I WOULD STUFF A RAVEN.
AND I WOULD GIVE IT A BEARD.
I'ŐD GLUE ON THE BEARD.
I WOULD SPEND MY TIME
GLUING THE BEARD ON,
AND IT WOULD HAVE A BEARD, AND
I WOULD SIT HIM ON THE PERCH,
SO WHEN YOU CAME UP
TO THE COUNTER,
YOU'ŐD HAVE
TO PULL THE BEARD.
AND THEN THE RAVEN WILL GO...
[squawks]
THAT'ŐS MY CUE TO APPEAR.
AND THEN I'ŐD--PFFT.
YES?
SECRETLY, I WAS WAITING UNDER
THE COUNTER TO HEAR THE RAVEN.
AND THEN--PFFT.
YES?
I WAS RIGHT THERE.
THERE'ŐS NO MAGIC.
I'ŐM RIGHT THERE.
[in elderly woman voice]
YES, MY CHILD?
[normal voice]
I CALL YOU MY CHILD
'ŐCAUSE THAT'ŐS WHAT
CREEPY PEOPLE DO.
[in elderly woman voice]
YES?
[normal voice] AND YOU'ŐD HAND ME
YOUR PRESCRIPTION.
AND I'ŐD SAY,
"OKAY, ONE MOMENT."
AND I'ŐD HAVE A HUMP.
OH, YEAH, I HAVE A HUMP.
YOU GOTTA HAVE A HUMP.
IF YOU'ŐRE GONNA BE
MAKING MEDICINE,
YOU GOTTA HAVE A HUMP
'ŐCAUSE THE HUMP SAYS
THAT YOU'ŐRE SERIOUS.
A HUMP
IS YOUR CALLING CARD.
A HUMP SAYS,
"I'ŐM NOT OUT PARTYING.
"I'ŐM NOT OUT
GETTING DRUNK.
"I'ŐM DOWNSTAIRS
IN THE BASEMENT
"STUDYING ALCHEMY AND--
AND WITCHERY.
"AND I'ŐM LEARNING
HOW TO TURN
"NEWT THOUGHTS
INTO RAT EYEBALLS.
"I'ŐM DOING THINGS
LIKE THAT.
"I'ŐM LEARNING THE PROPER USE
FOR AN ERLENMEYER FLASK.
I'ŐM DOWN THERE
DOING THESE THINGS, OKAY?"
SO I HAVE THE HUMP,
AND THEN--
AND THEN, I'ŐD TAKE YOUR--
I'ŐD TAKE YOUR PRESCRIPTION.
AND--ONE MOMENT.
[groans]
I HAVE A LIMP TOO...
'ŐCAUSE THE LIMP
COMES WITH THE HUMP,
STANDARD.
[sighs]
AND THEN I WOULD SET TO WORK
MAKING YOUR MEDICINE.
SO I'ŐD BE BACK HERE,
AND I WOULD HAVE MY BACK TO YOU.
AND I'ŐD--I'ŐD HAVE
ALL THESE SOUND EFFECTS
ON, LIKE, A KEYBOARD READY,
SO YOU WOULD BE STANDING THERE.
AND YOU'ŐD HEAR LIKE...
[mimics bleating]
[mimics thud and bleating]
[mimics animals squealing]
[mimics thud]
"EH, ONE MOMENT."
[mimics bleating, thud,
and animals squealing]
AND I WOULD ALSO HAVE
A CLOSED-CIRCUIT TV RIGHT HERE,
SO I COULD WATCH EVERYTHING
IN THE PHARMACY, OKAY?
SO YOU WOULD GO TO,
LIKE, TOUCH SOMETHING,
AND I WOULD SEE YOU
ON THE TV.
AND I WOULD
JUST SAY THIS,
"I WOULDN'ŐT TOUCH THAT
IF I WERE YOU."
[chuckles]
BUT I'ŐM JUST WATCHING YOU.
AND I HAVE--
AND, LIKE, AN HOUR LATER,
I'ŐD EMERGE WITH YOUR MEDICINE
IN THE ORANGE BOTTLE.
LIKE, I DIDN'ŐT MAKE
YOUR SHIT.
I HAD IT READY TO GO.
I WAS JUST WASTING YOUR TIME...
'ŐCAUSE A HUMP SUGGESTS
THAT I'ŐM MAKING IT,
SO I WANT YOU
TO FOLLOW THAT FANTASY.
I DIDN'ŐT--I DON'ŐT KNOW HOW
TO MAKE MEDICINE OUT OF HERBS.
I'ŐM NOT CHINESE.
SO I HAVE IT.
AND I'ŐD COME UP
TO THE COUNTER.
AND I'ŐD SAY--
AND I'ŐD SET IT DOWN.
AND I'ŐD SAY, "WOULD YOU LIKE
A CONSULTATION?"
[laughter]
AND YOU'ŐD SAY, "SURE."
AND I'ŐD SAY, "OKAY."
AND I'ŐD HOLD UP YOUR PILL
TO THE LIGHT.
I SHOULDN'ŐT TOUCH YOUR MEDICINE,
BUT I'ŐM GOING TO.
I'ŐD HOLD IT UP, AND I'ŐD SAY,
"TAKE ONE!"
[mimicking echoes]
ONE, ONE.
AND I'ŐD HAVE ALL THE OTHER
PHARMACISTS FLIP THE LIGHTS
ON AND OFF TO MAKE IT...
AND THEY'ŐD PUT LIGHTERS UP
TO THE SPRINKLERS.
AND WE'ŐD GET
ONE OF THE FOG MACHINES
LEFT OVER
FROM OUR HALLOWEEN SALE.
AND PFFT,
AND IT WOULD
FILL THE ROOM.
AND WE'ŐD HAVE PEOPLE
WAFTING IT WITH CAR MATS
JUST TO MAKE IT GO
IN SOME SORT OF CIRCLE.
"TAKE ONE
ON THE SEVENTH SOLSTICE
OF THE THIRD
VERNAL EQUINOX."
IT'ŐS TWO DIFFERENT TIMES A YEAR,
BUT IT'ŐS JUST A BIT.
"TAKE ONE
IN THE PRESENCE--
"PRESENCE OF A RIGHTEOUS MAN
"WITH THE BLOOD
OF A VIRGIN.
"ALSO WITH CRACKERS,
SO YOU DON'ŐT UPSET
YOUR TUMMY."
I GIVE IT TO YOU,
AND AS YOU ARE GOING TO LEAVE,
YOU DIDN'ŐT
EVEN SAY ANYTHING.
I'ŐD SAY, "WAIT!"
I GRAB YOU...
GRAB YOU
WITH A GRABBING HAND.
WHAT'ŐS A GRABBING HAND?
I'ŐM GONNA TELL YOU.
YOU CAN'ŐT--
IF YOU'ŐRE GONNA GRAB SOMEONE
AND YOU WANT TO INSTILL FEAR
IN THEIR HEARTS,
YOU CAN'ŐT GRAB
WITH A WELL-MANICURED HAND
WITH, LIKE,
A PRETTY RING.
NO ONE'ŐS
GONNA BE AFRAID.
IF I GRAB YOU WITH THIS HAND,
YOU'ŐD BE LIKE, "WHAT?
THAT SOUNDS AWESOME."
IT'ŐS GOT
TO BE CREEPY, OKAY?
SOMEONE GRABS YOU
OUT OF A GRAVE.
WHAT DOES IT LOOK LIKE?
IT'ŐS SINEWY.
IT'ŐS GOT DIRTY NAILS.
IT'ŐS ALL "THRILLER"-LOOKING.
JUST NAH!
GONNA GRAB HIM.
HOW DO YOU MAKE
A GRABBING HAND?
I'ŐM GOING
TO TELL YOU.
YOU PUT YOUR HAND
OUTSIDE YOUR CAR
FOR TWO HOURS A DAY,
SO IT TANS QUICKER
THAN THE REST OF YOU.
YOU TAKE SPECIAL LIVER PILLS
THAT PREVENT YOUR LIVER
FROM FUNCTIONING
ON THIS SIDE.
SO YOU START TO GET LIVER SPOTS
ALL OVER, OKAY?
NOW, YOU GOTTA MAKE
YOUR FINGERS CREEPY.
SO MAYBE--
SO THIS FINGER--
YOU'ŐVE GOT, LIKE, A COKE NAIL
ON THAT FINGER.
THIS ONE'ŐS GOT, LIKE--LIKE,
A RACCOON EYEBALL FOR A RING.
MAYBE THIS--
YOU DON'ŐT NEED THIS FINGER.
YOU CUT THIS ONE OFF TOTALLY
'ŐCAUSE YOU LOST IT--
YOU LOST IT
IN THE HOBBIT BORE.
I DON'ŐT CARE.
AND THEN
YOU GET A BRACELET
MADE OF, LIKE, WHORE GYPSY
KARDASHIAN HAIR.
YOU WRAP YOUR HAND IN IT.
[laughter and applause]
AND JUST AS YOU'ŐRE--
I PULL OUT MY GRABBING HAND.
I HAVE IT SHEATHED.
IT'ŐS SHEATHED IN A SHEATH.
AND, UH...
JUST AS YOU WERE LEAVING,
I'ŐD GO, "WAIT!"
YOU'ŐD BE,
LIKE, "WHAT?"
AND I'ŐD SAY,
"THERE'ŐS ONE MORE THING."
AND I'ŐD PULL OUT A HAND
OF MAGIC DUST,
WHICH IS JUST SAND FROM THE
BEACH AISLE IN THE PHARMACY.
I'ŐD PULL--
I'ŐD PULL OUT A HAND OF DUST.
AND I WOULD JUST GO...
[blows into microphone]
[laughter]
"DO YOU HAVE
A CVS CARD?"
[laughter and applause]
I LOVE WALKING
AROUND PHARMACIES.
I LOVE DOING THAT.
I CAN'ŐT--I CAN'ŐT GO TO
A PHARMACY AND NOT SPEND MONEY.
ONE OF THE PRODUCTS
THAT CREEPS ME OUT--
THEY HAVE A PRODUCT
AT EVERY PHARMACY
CALLED "K-Y INTENSE."
YOU SEEN THE COMMERCIALS
FOR THIS THING?
THE COMMERCIAL FOR--
FIRST OF ALL,
THE COMMERCIAL FOR K-Y INTENSE
IS SUPER OFFENSIVE.
AND WE WILL TALK
ABOUT THAT.
IN THE C--
FIRST OF ALL,
IF YOU'ŐVE EVER USED
K-Y INTENSE,
YOU KNOW THAT IT'ŐS INTENSE
BECAUSE IT BURNS.
[laughter]
I WILL VOLUNTEER THAT.
I ACCIDENTALLY USED IT
ONE TIME THINKING, LIKE,
"THIS IS GONNA
BE MAGICAL."
AND IT BURNED.
AND I PROMISE YOU
GIRLS DON'ŐT WANT THAT.
IN MY LIFE,
I'ŐVE NEVER BEEN, LIKE,
"MAN, THAT SEX
WAS AWESOME.
"BUT YOU KNOW WHAT I WANTED
TO FEEL, LIKE, RIGHT AFTER?
FIRE."
[laughter]
OF COURSE,
THEY DON'ŐT BILL IT
AS A BURNING SENSATION
ON TV.
THEY CALL IT
"A TINGLING SENSATION."
[laughter]
AND THEY TRY TO, LIKE, TALK
TO THE GIRLS.
THEY'ŐRE LIKE,
"LADIES, DO YOU WANT
"MORE PLEASURE
OUT OF YOUR THREE MINUTES?
DO YOU WANT THAT?
OKAY."
[laughter]
"WELL, K-Y INTENSE
IS GREAT
"'ŐCAUSE IT'ŐS A TINGLING
SENSATION FOR HER
"AND HE GETS TO USE
HIS PENIS.
SO EVERYBODY WINS."
BUT EVEN IF IT--
EVEN IF IT WAS
A TINGLING SENSATION,
WE LIVE IN A SOCIETY
PRECONDITIONED TO NOT
WANT TINGLING.
WE DON'ŐT
LIKE TINGLING.
WE KNOW THAT TINGLING, IT MEANS
A BAD THING IS HAPPENING.
"HEY, EVERYONE, GRANDMA SAYS
HER ARM IS TINGLING."
"OH, SHE MUST BE HAVING
AN ORGASM."
[laughter and applause]
"YOU DON'ŐT HAVE TO RUSH HER
TO THE HOSPITAL.
"SHE'ŐS LAYING ON THE GROUND
"WITH HER EYES ROLLED BACK
IN HER HEAD.
SHE'ŐS CLEARLY
ENJOYING HERSELF."
TINGLING.
IT'ŐS HORRIBLE.
YOU EVER HIT YOUR FUNNY BONE
AND BEEN, LIKE...
[mimics thudding]
"AHH."
[laughter]
THE COMMERCIAL IS AWFUL
BECAUSE IT'ŐS TWO BRITISH PEOPLE.
AND THEY'ŐRE SITTING THERE
HAVING BREAKFAST.
AND THEY'ŐRE DISCUSSING
ALL THE SEX
THAT THEY HAD
THE NIGHT BEFORE...
[laughter]
'ŐCAUSE THEY USED
THE K-Y INTENSE.
BUT BECAUSE THE BRITS ARE VERY
TACIT ABOUT SEXUAL THINGS,
THEY'ŐRE NOT COMING RIGHT OUT
AND DISCUSSING IT.
THEY'ŐRE SPEAKING
IN CODE.
AND AT THE BOTTOM
OF THE SCREEN
ARE THE SUBTITLES
IN AMERICAN
SO WE CAN UNDERSTAND
WHAT THEY'ŐRE SAYING.
SO THEY'ŐRE SITTING THERE,
AND THEY'ŐRE EATING.
THEY'ŐRE HAVING
THEIR...PORRIDGE.
[laughter]
THEY'ŐRE EATING
THEIR CURDS AND WHEY.
I DON'ŐT CARE WHAT THE BRITS EAT.
WE WON THE WAR, SO THERE.
[cheering]
RIGHT?
SO THEY'ŐRE SITTING THERE.
AND THEY'ŐRE EATING IT.
AND IT'ŐS JUST VERY QUIET.
AND THEY'ŐRE JUST...
[laughter]
TEETH OUT TO HERE.
AND THE GIRL
LOOKS AT THE GUY.
"WONDERFUL DESSERT
LAST NIGHT, SIRE."
SHE DIDN'ŐT SAY "SIRE."
THEY DON'ŐT TALK
LIKE THAT ANYMORE.
SO SHE TALKS,
AND THERE'ŐS SUBTITLES.
"WONDERFUL DESSERT
LAST NIGHT."
"HEY! WHAT'ŐD YOU PUT
ON MY PUSS, NIGGA?"
AND THEN THE GUY...
RESPONDS IN KIND.
HE'ŐS LIKE,
"OH, YES, 'ŐTWAS--
"'ŐTWAS A BIT
OF A NEW RECIPE.
HOPED YOU LIKED IT."
"PUT SOME OF THAT K-Y SHIT
ON MY DICK, BITCH.
HOW YOU LIKE ME NOW?"
[mimics barking]
[laughter and applause]
AND THEN, THE GIRL IS,
LIKE, "OH, YES.
'ŐTWAS QUITE INVIGORATING.
DIDN'ŐT EXPECT THAT ONE."
"YOU FUCKING KIDDING ME
WITH THAT SHIT?
"WHAT'ŐD YOU PUT?
ANTS ON YOUR DICK?
IS THIS A JOKE?"
"YOU WANT
TO FUCKING DIE, MOTHERFUCKER?
"YOU WANT TO END UP ON SNAP?
I'ŐLL FUCKING KILL YOU.
THIS FUCKIN'Ő HURT."
THEN THE GUY, LIKE,
"OH, YES,
"TRIED A SPIN
ON AN OLD RECIPE.
TRIED A DASH
OF NUTMEG."
[laughter]
AND THERE WERE
NO SUBTITLES FOR THAT
BECAUSE I THINK
THEY FUCKING DO USE NUTMEG.
AND THAT'ŐS WHAT MAKES IT
BURN SO MUCH.
[laughter and applause]
I KNOW A LOT ABOUT SEX
AND DATING.
I KNOW A LOT
ABOUT DATING
BECAUSE I WATCH
A LOT OF DATES.
[laughter]
THAT SOUNDS CREEPY.
I HOST A DATING SHOW.
SO I'ŐVE LEARNED A LOT
ABOUT MEN AND WOMEN
AND THEIR INTERACTIONS.
AND ONE IMPORTANT THING
THAT I'ŐVE LEARNED
IS THAT WHEN YOU LIKE SOMEONE
AND YOU WANT TO IMPRESS THEM,
WHAT DO YOU DO?
YOU LIE.
YOU HAVE TO,
BECAUSE IF PEOPLE KNEW
HOW WEIRD YOU WERE
IN YOUR OFF TIME,
NO ONE WOULD HAVE YOU.
A GUY SAYS TO YOU, "WHAT DO
YOU LIKE TO DO FOR FUN?"
GIRLS, YOU CAN'ŐT
BE HONEST.
YOU CAN'ŐT BE HONEST
ABOUT THAT SHIT.
ABOUT WHAT YOU WERE DOING
10 MINUTES BEFORE YOU CAME
TO THE DOOR.
YOU HAVE TO LIE.
"WHAT DO YOU LIKE
TO DO FOR FUN?"
YOU CAN'ŐT TELL HIM.
YOU CAN'ŐT BE, LIKE,
"I REALLY ENJOY
"CHOREOGRAPHING NAKED
CHEERLEADING ROUTINES
"TO OLD
BRITNEY SPEARS CDs.
"AND THEN, I GOOGLE
A BUNCH OF HENTAI PORN,
"MASTURBATE, DON'ŐT WASH
MY HANDS,
"FACEBOOK STALK MY EX-BOYFRIEND
AND HIS EX-GIRLFRIENDS,
"JOT DOWN THEIR PLACE OF
EMPLOYMENT FOR FUTURE REFERENCE.
"AND THEN, I GO
BAKE SOME COOKIES.
"AND THEN,
I MOUTH-KISS MY DOG
AND PROMISE HER THAT ONE DAY
SHE'ŐLL BE MY WIFE."
YOU CAN'ŐT SAY THAT.
NINE TIMES OUT OF TEN,
A GUY ASKS A GIRL,
"WHAT DO YOU LIKE TO DO
FOR FUN?"
THE GIRL'ŐS ANSWER
WILL BE, "HIKING."
[laughter]
"I LOVE HIKING.
I DO.
I DO--DON'ŐT I?
I DO. I LOVE HIKING."
[laughter]
"I DO, HIKING'ŐS--"
[mimics baaing]
"I LOVE HIKING."
[laughter]
"I DO. I LOVE IT.
I LOVE HIKING."
"NO, YOU DON'ŐT.
STOP LYING.
"YOU DON'ŐT LIKE--REALLY, STACY?
YOU LIKE HIKING?
"WHERE ARE YOUR TRAIL SPIKES?
WHERE'ŐS YOUR WALKING STICK?
WHERE'ŐS YOUR LESBIAN
MOUNTAIN PARTNER?"
[laughter]
YOU DON'ŐT LIKE HIKING.
YOU DON'ŐT EVEN KNOW
WHAT HIKING IS.
MOST MODERN GIRLS DON'ŐT REALLY
KNOW WHAT HIKING IS, OKAY?
TO THE AVERAGE GIRL,
HIKING IS
YOU WAKE UP
WHENEVER YOU WANT,
YOU PUT ON
LULULEMON YOGA PANTS
'ŐCAUSE THEY MAKE YOUR BUTT
LOOK UNREASONABLY GOOD
AS THEY SHOULD
FOR 800 FUCKING DOLLARS.
AND YOU GO FOR A WALK
IN THE PARK
WITH YOUR BEST FRIEND
AND COMPLAIN
ABOUT HOW HUNG OVER
YOU ARE.
THAT'ŐS HIKING.
[laughter and applause]
YEAH.
I DO IT TOO.
PROMISE YOU THIS, GIRLS.
IT'ŐS NOT A SPORT
IF YOU CAN DRINK A STARBUCKS
AND HAVE A PITA
WHILE YOU'ŐRE DOING IT.
"DO YOU WANT
A PIECE OF PITA?"
[groans]
"I'ŐM HIKING."
BUT THERE'ŐS A METHOD
TO OUR MADNESS.
THERE'ŐS A REASON WOMEN
SAY "HIKING."
WE SAY HIKING BECAUSE WE THINK
GUYS LIKE HIKING.
THAT'ŐS WHY
WE'ŐRE DOING IT.
BE OUTSIDE
WHERE THE BUGS ARE?
NO!
WE THINK YOU LIKE THAT.
WE'ŐRE TAUGHT TO BELIEVE
THAT MEN ARE OUTDOORSY,
AND RUGGED,
AND THEY LIKE NATURE.
AS FAR
AS WE'ŐRE CONCERNED,
YOU'ŐRE THE CLOSEST THING
WE KNOW TO A BEAR.
[laughter]
SO WE SAY HIKING,
HOPING TO HAVE
SOMETHING IN COMMON
WITH YOU.
WE HONESTLY
SAY "HIKING"
HOPING THAT YOU'ŐLL BE,
LIKE, "YOU LIKE HIKING?
I LIKE HIKING.
MARRY ME."
IT'ŐS THE EASIEST THING
YOU CAN SAY THAT YOU DO.
IT'ŐS ONE OF THE ONLY
OUTDOOR ACTIVITIES
THAT YOU CAN LIE
AND SAY THAT YOU DO IT
HAVING NEVER
DONE IT BEFORE,
AND THEN DO IT AND PULL IT OFF
BECAUSE IT'ŐS WALKING.
YOU CAN'ŐT PULL
THAT OFF,
YOU SHOULDN'ŐT BE MATING
WITH ANYONE.
YOU CA--
MOST OUTDOOR ACTIVITIES
REQUIRE A DECENT AMOUNT
OF SKILL.
FOR EXAMPLE, YOU CAN'ŐT SAY
YOU LIKE ROCK CLIMBING
IF YOU'ŐVE NEVER BEEN
ROCK CLIMBING.
I MEAN, YOU CAN,
BUT I PROMISE YOU THIS.
YOU'ŐRE GONNA GO.
YOU'ŐRE GONNA SLIP.
YOU'ŐRE GONNA GET YOUR HAND
CAUGHT IN A ROCK.
127 HOURS LATER...
[laughter and applause]
STUMP'ŐS NOT GETTING YOU
A SECOND DATE.
I PROMISE YOU THAT.
I DON'ŐT KNOW IF GIRLS
WANNA HEAR THIS,
BUT THE TRUTH IS
90% OF THE ACTIVITIES
THAT WOMEN ENGAGE IN
REVOLVE AROUND GETTING
A GUY'ŐS ATTENTION, OKAY?
AND IT'ŐS JUST THE WAY
WE'ŐRE BUILT BIOLOGICALLY.
THIS IS JUST
SOMETHING WE DO.
WE LOVE TO GET
YOUR ATTENTION.
IT'ŐS PART OF THE SPORT OF IT,
ALL RIGHT?
YOU THINK
I GO TO A SPORTS BAR
BECAUSE I LIKE WARM BEER
AND STICKY BARSTOOLS?
NO. I GO 'ŐCAUSE THERE'ŐS
GUYS THERE.
YOU THINK I DO A PUB CRAWL
EVERY YEAR
'ŐCAUSE I LIKE IT
WHEN MY LIVER HURTS?
NO! I GO 'ŐCAUSE THERE'ŐS
GUYS THERE.
WE DON'ŐT WEAR HEELS
FOR OUR CIRCULATION.
WE DO IT
TO PROP UP OUR BUTT
SO YOU'ŐLL LOOK AT ME
AND WANT TO MATE WITH ME.
THAT'ŐS WHY WE DO IT.
THIS ISN'ŐT A FUCKING GAME,
ALL RIGHT?
THIS ISN'ŐT A PUSH-UP BRA.
IT'ŐS BODY ARMOR.
AND THIS AIN'ŐT
MAKEUP, SWEETHEART.
IT'ŐS WAR PAINT.
LET'ŐS MAKE A BABY.
[cheers and applause]
GIRLS KNOW EXACTLY
WHAT THEY'ŐRE DOING.
WE KNOW EXACTLY WHAT YOU LIKE,
WHAT YOU DON'ŐT LIKE.
WE DO OUR RESEARCH
WHEN WE LIKE A GUY.
AND BY RESEARCH,
I MEAN WE FACEBOOK STALK YOU.
WE DO IT.
I KNOW
YOUR FAVORITE FOODS.
WHERE YOU WENT ON VACATION.
I KNOW THAT YOUR FAVORITE TEAM
IS THE COWBOYS.
I KNOW ALL ABOUT THAT.
I'ŐM TOTALLY INTO YOU.
THAT'ŐS RIGHT.
THEY SAY MEN ARE HUNTERS
AND WOMEN ARE GATHERERS.
WELL, KIND OF.
WOMEN ARE GATHERERS.
WE LIKE TO GATHER INFORMATION
ABOUT YOU.
AND THEN WE HUNT YOU.
YOU THINK WHEN I BRING YOU HOME
TO MEET MOM ON CHRISTMAS
IT'ŐS 'ŐCAUSE I WANT HER
TO MEET YOU?
NO, IT'ŐS SO I CAN BE, LIKE,
"MOM, LOOK WHAT I CAUGHT."
[laughter and applause]
WE HAVE TO, BECAUSE GUYS
ARE KIND OF PASSIVE
WHEN IT COMES
TO MEETING WOMEN.
SURE, THEY GO OUT.
BUT GIRLS MAKE A SPORT OF IT.
MY GUY FRIENDS
DON'ŐT CARE.
IF THEY HAD THEIR WAY,
THEY'ŐD SPEND
EVERY SATURDAY NIGHT
WITH EACH OTHER--
WHICH IS WEIRD--
WATCHING "1000 WAYS TO DIE,"
EATING SANDWICHES,
RAGGING ON THEIR ONE FRIEND
THAT HAS A HUGE NUT SACK
FOR NO REASON.
LIKE, THAT'ŐS WHAT
THEY WOULD DO.
GOING OUT'ŐS
VERY IMPORTANT.
YOU GOT A REAL JOB, YOUR WEEKEND
IS VERY IMPORTANT TO YOU,
BECAUSE A WEEKEND REPRESENTS
48 HOURS
THAT YOU HAVE
TO FUCK UP THE LIFE
THAT YOU WORKED SO HARD FOR
ALL WEEK.
[laughter and applause]
THAT'ŐS WHAT
YOUR WEEKEND IS.
IF YOU'ŐRE
A REAL PROFESSIONAL,
YOUR WEEKEND STARTS THURSDAY
AT, LIKE, 5:00 P.M.
RIGHT?
YOU GO TO HAPPY HOUR.
HAPPY HOUR TRICKLES
INTO, LIKE, NIGHTTIME.
YOU'ŐRE DRINKING
A LITTLE BIT
'ŐCAUSE YOU CAN GO TO WORK
A LITTLE HUNG OVER, RIGHT?
NO ONE'ŐS DOING REAL WORK
ON FRIDAY.
NOBODY'ŐS WORKING
ON A FRIDAY.
NOBODY'ŐS WORKING ON A FRIDAY
'ŐCAUSE IT'ŐS WHAT?
SHABBAT. NO.
BECAUSE IT'ŐS FRIDAY
AND NOBODY CARES.
YOU EVER BEEN AT WORK, YOUR BOSS
IS NEVER GONNA BE, LIKE,
"LET'ŐS GET IN THOSE REPORTS
AND START BRAINSTORMING."
YOU'ŐRE, LIKE,
"OKAY, I'ŐLL BE THERE."
[chuckles]
"OH, YOU WERE SERIOUS?
OKAY, LITTLE HAND JOB.
I'ŐLL BE AT MY DESK.
THAT'ŐS FINE."
[laughter]
GIRLS TAKE GOING OUT
VERY SERIOUSLY
'ŐCAUSE THAT'ŐS
OUR HUNTING GROUNDS.
"GOING OUT.
LET'ŐS DO IT."
[laughter]
"DO YOU WANT TO DO,
LIKE, A GIRLS'Ő NIGHT?
DO YOU WANNA
DO THAT?"
EVERY WEEKEND, I GET CALLS
FROM MY GIRLFRIENDS.
"DO YOU WANT TO DO,
LIKE, JUST GIRLS?
LIKE, A FUN GIRLS'Ő NIGHT?
ILIZA, I'ŐM TALKING TO YOU.
ILIZA."
[mimics baaing]
"DO YOU WANT TO DO THAT?
[laughter]
[mimics baaing]
"DO YOU WANNA DO,
"LIKE, A GIRLS'Ő--
WE'ŐLL JUST DO--
"OH, WE'ŐLL ALL WEAR,
LIKE, FUN SHOES.
"AND WE'ŐLL ALL GET,
LIKE, APIS.
AND THEN, WE'ŐLL DO,
LIKE, A FUN GIRLS'Ő NIGHT."
"DO YOU WANNA
DO THAT?
"I WANNA DO
A GIRLS'Ő NIGHT.
I MADE AN EVITE
FOR THE FOUR OF US."
[laughter]
"YOU DIDN'ŐT ANSWER."
"'ŐCAUSE I'ŐM STANDING
RIGHT HERE."
"YOU'ŐRE SUCH A BITCH."
"LET'ŐS DO A GIRLS'Ő NIGHT.
LET'ŐS DO JUST GIRLS.
"NO BOYS.
LET'ŐS JUST ALL WEAR WEDGES
AND NO BOYS."
[laughter]
"LET'ŐS NOT DO BOYS, JUST GIRLS.
JUST THE GIRLS."
I'ŐM LIKE, "WHY?
WE HATE EACH OTHER."
GIRLS HATE
EACH OTHER.
ESP--SHE HATES YOU,
ESPECIALLY DURING THE DAY.
[laughter]
BUT WHEN THE MOON COMES UP
AND THERE'ŐS WHITE WINE INVOLVED,
"OH, MY GOD.
STACY, YOU LOOK AMAZING.
I FUCKING LOVE YOU."
AND YOU NOTICE
THE DRUNKER YOU GET,
THE MORE SPANISH
YOU START SPEAKING?
"OH, MY GOD.
MAMACITA, MUY CALIENTE.
WHOO!"
"FUCKING LOVE YOU, CHICA."
BUT THE MORE LOVE YOU GIVE
TO ONE GIRLFRIEND,
THE MORE LOVE YOU MUST TAKETH
AWAY FROM ANOTHER GIRLFRIEND.
IT'ŐS HOW WE KEEP BALANCE
IN THE GIRL UNIVERSE.
"I LOVE YOU.
CAN I JUST TELL YOU?"
[mimics baaing]
"I LOVE YOU, I DO.
"BUT YOU KNOW WHO I HATE?
[deep voice]
"BECKY.
"SHE'ŐS A BITCH."
"NO, I HATE HER
EVEN THOUGH SHE DROVE ME HERE
AND I'ŐM WEARING
HER TOP."
[laughter]
"CAN I JUST TELL YOU THAT?
"LIKE, FOR REAL,
LIKE, I HATE HER.
"WILL YOU NOT TELL HER?
DO YOU PROMISE?
"DO YOU--DO YOU PROM--
YOU WON'ŐT TELL HER?
"DO YOU PINKY SWEAR?
"DO YOU PINKY S--
DO YOU PINKY SWEAR?
"EVEN THOUGH
I'ŐM A GROWN FUCKING WOMAN
"THAT PAYS TAXES
AND VOTES,
DO YOU WANNA PINKY SWEAR?"
[laughter and applause]
"THIS IS IRONCLAD.
DO YOU PINKY SWEAR?
"OKAY, COME HERE.
NO, HERE, TAKE MY HAND.
"I WANNA TALK TO YOU.
COME HERE.
"NO, LIKE, EARLIER, LIKE--
HERE, COME HERE, COME HERE.
"LIKE, EARLIER, SHE WAS JUST,
LIKE, BEING, LIKE, A BITCH.
"AND I WAS, LIKE,
'ŐWHAT'ŐS YOUR PROBLEM?
I DON'ŐT EVEN UNDERSTAND.'Ő"
"NOW, SHE'ŐS LIKE, 'ŐWHY
ARE YOU BEING, LIKE, SO RUDE?
'ŐAND, LIKE--WHAT, ARE YOU, LIKE,
BIPOLAR OR, LIKE, MANIC?
'ŐLIKE I JUST FREELY USE
THESE PSYCHOLOGICAL TERMS
'Ő'ŐCAUSE I DON'ŐT KNOW
WHAT I'ŐM TALKING ABOUT.'Ő
"AND SHE WAS, LIKE, BEING,
LIKE--WAIT, WAIT.
"IS SHE LOOKING?
"DID SHE HEAR ME TALKING
ABOUT HER?
"IS SHE--PRETEND LIKE WE'ŐRE
NOT TALKING ABOUT HER.
[laughter]
"IS SHE GONE?
"NO, BUT,
LIKE, THAT'ŐS THE THING.
"LIKE, EARLIER, SHE WAS JUST,
LIKE, BEING,
"LIKE, PASSIVE-AGGRESSIVE
AND, LIKE, CRAZY.
"AND, LIKE..."
[mimics baaing]
"AND I WAS JUST, LIKE..."
"SHE WAS JUST BEING,
LIKE, A FREAK.
"AND SHE WAS JUST,
LIKE, DISRESPECTING ME.
"AND, LIKE--NO, NO, LIKE,
WHEN YOU DO IT, IT'ŐS FINE."
[laughter and applause]
"RIGHT?
BECAUSE WE GET EACH OTHER
'ŐCAUSE WE'ŐRE BOTH PISCES."
WHICH MEANS NOTHING.
"DO YOU WANNA DO THAT?
"DO YOU WANNA DO
A GIRLS NIGHT?
"FUCK YEAH.
WHY DON'ŐT YOU COME OVER?
"'ŐUS WEEKLY'Ő,
JENNIFER ANISTON, HANG OUT,
"'ŐLOVE ACTUALLY,'Ő
WATCH A MOVIE, BRAID OUR HAIR,
STIFF AS A BOARD, "LIGHT
AS A FEATHER, HAVE SOME CANDY,
"HAVE SOME CAKE,
HAVE SOME COOKIES,
"HAVE SOME BOX WINE,
HAVE SOME FUCKING MARTINIS,
"AND A LOW-FAT PIZZA.
HAVE A GODDAMN MUFFIN,
"HAVE A PIECE OF CAKE,
HAVE A PIECE OF BROWNIE,
'ŐFIFTY SHADES OF GREY.'Ő"
"SOUNDS GREAT, CINDY.
"CAN'ŐT WAIT TO BE SHIT-FACED
ON YOUR COUCH
"AT 2:00 A.M. WITH NO BOY
TO MAKE OUT WITH.
"YOU GOT 'ŐGREY'ŐS ANATOMY'Ő
ON DVD? AWESOME.
"POP IT IN. LET'ŐS LEZ OUT.
WHERE'ŐS YOUR BROTHER?"
YEAH.
LET'ŐS MAKE THAT HAPPEN.
TIRED OF FEELING
LIKE A SEXUAL DEVIANT
'ŐCAUSE I JUST ENJOY
A LITTLE BIT
OF MOUTH-KISSING
WITH MY RED WINE, OKAY?
LOOK, THAT'ŐS WHAT MOST GIRLS
WANT, BY THE WAY.
WE JUST WANNA MAKE OUT,
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
RIGHT AT THE BEGINNING
WHEN YOU FIRST MEET,
THEY WANT
TO MAKE OUT.
THAT'ŐS WHAT
MOST GIRLS WANT.
"I WANNA DO
SOME FUN SHOES,
RED WINE, MAKE OUT,
WEINER TOUCH, GO TO BED."
THAT'ŐS WHAT WE WANT...
WHEN YOU FIRST
MEET SOMEONE.
LOOK, LET'ŐS NOT
GET CRAZY, RIGHT?
JUST MAKE OUT, AND--
[mimics snoring]
AND THEN THAT'ŐS IT.
JUST REAL QUICK,
IN THAT ORDER.
YOU DON'ŐT WANT
TO HAVE DRUNK SEX.
THAT'ŐS A WHOLE MESS.
DRUNK SEX, THERE'ŐS EMOTIONS,
ANKLE SPRAINS, PAPER WORK.
THERE'ŐS, LIKE,
A WHOLE THING INVOLVED.
GIRLS LIKE MAKING OUT.
IT'ŐS A SENTIMENT
ECHOED BY ALMOST ANY GIRL
IN ANY BAR
ON ANY NIGHT.
YOU PICK ANY BAR
IN THE COUNTRY.
YOU FIND A GIRL,
SHE'ŐS GONNA BE DRUNK,
FACE ON SIDEWAYS,
JUST, LIKE--
[grunts]
[laughter]
"I JUST WANT TO MAKE OUT
WITH A BOY.
"I DO, I JUST WANT TO MAKE OUT
WITH SOME BOY.
THAT'ŐS ALL I WANT."
[mimics baaing]
"I DO.
I'ŐM PRETTY, RIGHT?"
[groans nervously]
"I JUST WANT--"
[laughter and applause]
"SAVED IT."
[laughter]
THAT'ŐS WHAT YOU HEAR.
YOU RARELY HEAR
A GIRL TALK
ABOUT HAVING SEX
WITH A STRANGER.
I UNDERSTAND
IT HAPPENS.
THAT THERE'ŐS ONE-NIGHT STANDS.
BUT RARELY DOES A GIRL
GO OUT
WITH THE INTENTION OF HAVING SEX
WITH A STRANGER.
RARELY DO YOU HEAR
A GIRL, LIKE,
"I JUST WANT TO, LIKE, GO OUT,
AND, LIKE, PARTY,
"AND, LIKE, MEET SOME DUDE,
AND GO HOME WITH HIM,
"AND THEN HAVE SEX WITH HIM,
AND THEN WAKE UP,
"AND REALIZE
I NEVER GOT HIS NAME.
"BUT HE'ŐS ALREADY GONE
TO THE GYM.
"SO I CAN'ŐT ASK HIM.
"SO I GO OVER
TO HIS COFFEE TABLE,
"AND I FIND A PHONE BILL
WITH HIS NAME ON IT.
"AND I PUT IT
IN MY POCKET,
AND I GO HOME
WITH THE PHONE BILL."
[laughs]
"AND I GET HOME TO MY COMPUTER,
AND I TAKE IT OUT.
"I'ŐM LIKE, 'ŐBRIAN WILLIAMSON.
THAT'ŐS A GENERIC FUCKING NAME.'Ő
"SO I LOOK UP ALL 90,000
BRIAN WILLIAMSONS ON FACEBOOK
"UNTIL I FIND THE ONE
THAT RESEMBLES HIM.
"AND THEN,
I SEND HIM A MESSAGE.
"BUT I HAVE
TO USE BAIT
"'ŐCAUSE I HAVE TO MAKE SURE
HE'ŐLL WRITE ME BACK.
"SO I'ŐM LIKE,
'ŐI THINK I'ŐM PREGNANT.'Ő
"HE WRITES BACK.
'ŐJ/K, MOTHER FUCKER.'Ő
'ŐBUT I GOT YOU NOW.'Ő
"NOW, WE BEGIN
THE DANCE OF SEDUCTION.
"NOW, I SAY THINGS,
LIKE, 'ŐI JUST WANNA BE FRIENDS.
'ŐYOU WERE SUPER FUN
TO HAVE SEX WITH.
'ŐLET'ŐS JUST BE FRIENDS
AND HAVE SEX.
'ŐFUCK A RELATIONSHIP
AND OXYTOCIN.
'ŐI NEVER WANNA HAVE
A FAMILY.
LET'ŐS JUST DO
WHAT YOU WANNA DO.'Ő
HE'ŐS INTO IT.
SO I GET YOUR NUMBER, RIGHT?
YOU HOLD ONTO THE NUMBER
UNTIL YOU HAVE AN OCCASION.
AND THEN,
IT'ŐS LIKE ST. PATRICK'ŐS DAY.
YOU SEND OUT A MASS TEXT,
BUT IT'ŐS JUST TO ONE PERSON.
YOU EVER DO THAT?
ME NEITHER.
IT WAS JUST A JOKE.
IT'ŐS THE BEST IDEA.
YOU FIND ONE GUY
THAT YOU LIKE.
AND YOU SEND OUT A TEXT
THAT'ŐS, LIKE, "HEY, EVERYONE."
MAKE SURE YOU WRITE
"EVERYONE" IN CAPS
SO IT'ŐS CLEAR THAT IT'ŐS
FOR, LIKE, A BUNCH OF PEOPLE.
"HEY, EVERYONE, L-O-L."
[spits into microphone]
"WHATEVER, SMILEY FACE,
I'ŐM GONNA HAVE A PARTY
"AT KELLY'ŐS BAR
AT 9:00 P.M.
EVERYBODY SHOULD COME,
YOU GUYS."
TRIPLE "Z"
SO HE KNOWS
THERE'ŐS A LOT OF PEOPLE
IN THIS TEXT.
"OKAY, SEE YOU LATER."
AND THEN YOU BRING
YOUR ONE FRIEND
THAT HAS NO ISSUE
WITH YOU DITCHING HER.
YOU GO TO THE BAR,
AND YOU POST UP,
AND YOU WAIT
UNTIL HE GETS THERE.
HE SHOWS UP.
YOU'ŐRE LIKE,
"I GUESS EVERYBODY PASSED OUT.
IT'ŐS JUST US STANDING."
[groans]
AND THEN,
YOU MAKE OUT.
AND HE'ŐS, LIKE,
"YOU SEEM LIKE A COOL CHICK."
YOU'ŐRE, LIKE,
"I'ŐM THE COOLEST CHICK.
I WANNA FUCKING
DO IT."
AND HE'ŐS, LIKE, "LET'ŐS GO OUT
TOMORROW NIGHT."
YOU'ŐRE LIKE,
"YEAH, A SECOND DATE.
"IT ONLY TOOK ME
SIX FUCKING MONTHS.
YEAH."
SO NOW, YOU'ŐRE EXCITED
'ŐCAUSE YOU HAVE A SECOND DATE.
AND GIRLS LOVE GETTING READY
FOR DATES.
EVEN THOUGH IT MAKES US
A LITTLE NAUSEOUS
AND ALL WE WANNA DO
IS STAY HOME AND EAT,
WE LOVE SECOND DATES
'ŐCAUSE YOU GOT TO GET READY
FOR YOUR SECOND DATE.
SO WHAT DO YOU DO?
YOU DO YOUR HAIR,
YOU DO YOUR MAKEUP,
YOU SHAVE YOUR BIG TOE.
YOU COME
TO PLAY, RIGHT?
GOTTA MAKE SURE
YOUR UNDERWEAR'ŐS CUTE.
DON'ŐT WANNA GO
TO VICTORIA'ŐS SECRET
'ŐCAUSE THAT'ŐS A BIT TOO MUCH
OF A COMMITMENT.
SO WHERE DO YOU GO FOR A CHEAP
BRA THAT'ŐS REALLY CUTE?
TARGET.
[laughter and applause]
THEY DON'ŐT FIT,
AND YOU'ŐRE LIKE, "FUCK IT.
"FOR $12.50,
I'ŐLL WEAR A BRA
"MADE OF CEILING INSULATION
AND BARBED WIRE.
THAT'ŐS FINE."
"IT DOESN'ŐT FIT
THIS BOOB,
"AND IT MAKES THIS NIPPLE
FALL ASLEEP.
BUT FOR 12 BUCKS,
I'ŐM GOOD."
YOU GET ALL EXCITED.
YOU PUT ON MAKEUP.
YOU PUT ON THE MAKEUP THAT
YOU'ŐRE OKAY WITH SLEEPING IN.
ALL GIRLS HAVE
TO MAKE THIS DECISION
'ŐCAUSE YOU KNOW YOU'ŐRE NOT
GONNA BE WASHING YOUR FACE
BECAUSE GIRLS ARE SO FUCKED UP
THAT WE THINK,
"I'ŐD RATHER FALL ASLEEP,
GET NIGHT ZITS,
"AND WAKE UP LOOKING
LIKE A MELTED CLOWN
THAN EVER WASH MY FACE AND SHOW
HIM THAT I'ŐM A HUMAN BEING."
SO YOU GO THERE.
YOU'ŐRE ALL EXCITED.
YOU GET TO HIS HOUSE.
YOU GUYS START DRINKING.
YOU GET SO FUCKING WASTED
IN THE FIRST TWO HOURS
THAT YOU HAVE SEX
FOR THREE MINUTES
BEFORE HE GOES
COMPLETELY SOFT.
AND THE NEXT THING
YOU KNOW,
YOU WAKE UP IN YOUR UNDERWEAR
ON HIS COUCH.
YOU LOOK OVER,
HE'ŐS EATING NOODLES,
WATCHING "HARRY POTTER."
IS THIS RELATABLE
TO ANYONE ELSE?
[cheering]
POPULAR MISCONCEPTION
ABOUT GIRLS
IS THAT WE GET DRUNK
AND WE WANNA HAVE SEX.
HERE'ŐS THE TRUTH.
WE DO.
HAVE A GOOD NIGHT.
NO.
WE DO FOR, LIKE, THE FIRST HOUR
OF BEING DRUNK, OKAY?
LET'ŐS TALK ABOUT THE FIRST HOUR
OF BEING DRUNK
MOSTLY BECAUSE MANY OF YOU
ARE IN THAT HOUR RIGHT NOW.
I CALL IT
"THE WITCHING HOUR."
THE FIRST HOUR
OF BEING DRUNK
IS THE BEST HOUR
OF THE NIGHT
BECAUSE YOUR BUZZ
IS FRESH.
YOU'ŐRE HAPPY.
YOU DON'ŐT FEEL FAT.
YOU HAVEN'ŐT CRIED YET.
YOU'ŐRE STILL SOMEWHAT
OF THE SELF YOU WERE
WHEN YOU WERE SOBER.
YOU STILL COULD OSTENSIBLY
OPERATE HEAVY MACHINERY
IF AN EMERGENCY
WERE TO ARISE, OKAY?
YOU'ŐRE IN THAT BUZZ.
YOU'ŐRE FEELING AWESOME.
YOUR SYNAPSES HAVEN'ŐT BEEN
SOAKED IN ALCOHOL.
SO YOU'ŐRE STILL ALERT.
YOU'ŐRE FEELING AWESOME.
YOU WALK INTO THAT BAR
LIKE YOU OWN IT.
YOU FUCKING KICK THAT DOOR OPEN
EVEN THOUGH IT'ŐS A PULL-IN DOOR.
YOU DON'ŐT CARE.
YOU'ŐRE JUST--
[mimics thudding]
WALK IN.
"LET'ŐS DO SHOTS, BITCHES."
[mimics baaing]
YOU AND YOUR AWFUL FRIENDS
LINE UP AT THE BAR.
LIKE, "LET'ŐS DO SHOTS."
YOU'ŐRE DOING SHOTS
YOU HAVE NO BUSINESS DOING.
"LET'ŐS GET JAGERMEISTER,
GOLDSCHLAGER,
"RUMPLE MINZE,
AFTERSHOCK.
"DO YOU HAVE
ANYTHING ELSE
THAT TASTES LIKE CHRISTMAS
AND VOMIT?"
[laughter and cheering]
YOU START DOING THEM.
YOU'ŐRE LIKE, "FUCK IT.
"IT'ŐS MY BACHELORETTE,
21ST BIRTHDAY,
"WEDDING EXTRAVAGANZA,
DONKEY PUNCH.
"I DON'ŐT KNOW WHAT THIS IS--
DO IT."
SHOT, SHOT.
[gags]
"WHAT IS THAT, HAND SOAP?
BUBBLES. I DON'ŐT CARE. AWESOME."
NOW, YOU'ŐRE ON
THE DANCE FLOOR.
YOU'ŐRE LIKE,
"THIS IS SO GOOD."
AND YOU'ŐRE FEELING SO GOOD,
RIGHT? YOU'ŐRE DANCING.
YOU'ŐRE ALL EXCITED 'ŐCAUSE
YOUR BUZZ HAS JUST HIT YOU.
YOU'ŐRE LIKE, "THIS IS GREAT.
I FUCKING LOVE IT."
YOU'ŐRE AMBITIOUS
ABOUT LIFE.
YOU EVER PLAN A WORKOUT
WHEN YOU'ŐRE DRUNK?
WHEN YOU'ŐRE DRUNK, YOU'ŐRE, LIKE,
"THIS IS WHEN I GET IN SHAPE.
"THIS IS
WHERE IT STARTS.
GOING TO START TOMORROW."
YOU TRY TO DRAG YOUR FRIENDS
INTO IT.
YOU'ŐRE LIKE,
"STACY! STA--"
[mimics baaing]
"STACY."
"DO YOU WANNA WORK OUT?
YOU DANCE LIKE AN ASSHOLE,
BY THE WAY.
I DON'ŐT KNOW
WHO DANCES LIKE THIS.
"DO YOU WANNA WORK OUT,
LIKE, TOMORROW?
"DO YOU WANNA
DO THAT?
"I'ŐM GONNA GET UP EARLY
AND WORK OUT.
"DO YOU WANNA GO
WITH ME?
"DO YOU WANT TO GO
AT, LIKE, 6:00?
IT'ŐS 5:00 NOW."
"DO YOU WANNA TAKE
A SPIN CLASS?"
"DO YOU WANNA SPIN?
"DO YOU WANNA--"
[mimics baaing]
"DO YOU WANT--
YOU DON'ŐT WANNA SPIN?
"YOU DON'ŐT
WANNA GO SPINNING?
"YOU DON'ŐT WANNA SIT
ON A STATIONARY BIKE
"AND TOLERATE GETTING POUNDED
IN THE RECTUM FOR AN HOUR
"WHILE SOME TWINKED-OUT
SPANDEX QUEEN YELLS AT YOU
"OVER A SHITTY REMIX OF U2'ŐS
'ŐIT'ŐS A BEAUTIFUL DAY'Ő
IN TOTAL DARKNESS?"
[laughter]
"YOU DON'ŐT
WANNA DO THAT?"
SO YOU'ŐRE FEELING GOOD
AND YOU'ŐRE DANCING.
YOU'ŐRE LIKE,
"I FEEL SO THIN.
"I'ŐVE NEVER BEEN HOTTER
IN MY LIFE.
I FEEL SO GOOD."
AND THEN, IT HITS YOU.
YOU'ŐRE LIKE, "OH, MY GOD.
I FEEL SO GOOD RIGHT NOW.
"I FEEL SO AWESOME
AND HAPPY.
"I WISH I COULD FEEL THIS WAY
ALL THE TIME.
I WISH I COULD FEEL THIS BUZZ
AND THIS HAPPY ALL THE TIME."
AND THAT'ŐS
WHEN YOU REALIZE
THAT'ŐS HOW
AN ALCOHOLIC THINKS.
BUT YOU'ŐRE, LIKE, "SCREW IT.
I'ŐM GONNA GIVE IT A SHOT.
I'ŐM GONNA SEE JUST HOW FAR
I CAN PUSH BEING DRUNK."
SO YOU DECIDE
TO DO SHOTS.
AND YOU DECIDE,
"THESE SHOTS AREN'ŐT GONNA GET ME
'ŐCAUSE TONIGHT'ŐS THE NIGHT
I OUTSMART THE LIQUOR."
"NOT GONNA HAPPEN TONIGHT
'ŐCAUSE I'ŐM GONNA DRINK WATER.
GOING TO DRINK A GLASS OF WATER
WITH EACH SHOT."
AND THIS IS
YOUR BRILLIANT IDEA.
NO ONE IN THE THOUSANDS OF YEARS
OF PEOPLE IMBIBING ALCOHOL
HAS EVER THOUGHT
OF THIS.
THIS IS
YOUR NIGHT, EINSTEIN.
IT'ŐS YOUR BIG PLAN.
"I'ŐM GONNA DO A SHOT
AND THEN HAVE A GLASS OF WATER,
"AND THEN A SHOT,
AND THEN A GLASS OF WATER.
"YOU CAN'ŐT BUY ME A SHOT NOW,
BUT THANK YOU.
I'ŐM JUST HAVING WATER."
[groans]
"I'ŐM JUST HAVING..."
"I'ŐM JUST DRINKING WATER,
BUT THANK YOU."
SHOT AND WATER,
BUT WHAT YOU DON'ŐT REALIZE
IS THAT FIVE SHOTS
IN AN HOUR
IS STILL FIVE FUCKING SHOTS
IN AN HOUR.
YOU WENT AND DRANK ALL
THAT WATER LIKE A CRAZY CAMEL.
YEAH, GOOD JOB.
NOW, YOU'ŐRE BLOATED.
AND YOU HAVE TO PEE.
WAY TO BE.
'ŐCAUSE WHEN A GIRL'ŐS
GOTTA PEE,
EVERYTHING HAS TO COME
TO A HALT.
EVERY GIRL'ŐS
GOTTA GO WITH HER.
"I HAVE TO PEE.
DO YOU HAVE TO PEE?"
[mimics baaing]
"I CAN'ŐT GO ALONE.
NO.
"WILL YOU STOP WHAT YOU'ŐRE DOING
AND COME WITH ME?
"I HAVE TO PEE.
DO YOU HAVE TO PEE?
I HAVE TO GO PEE."
CAN'ŐT GO
IN THE BATHROOM ALONE.
YOU MIGHT NOT COME BACK.
'ŐCAUSE NO GIRL'ŐS
EVER BEEN
TO THE BATHROOM ALONE
AND SURVIVED.
IT'ŐS TRUE.
THE LAST WOMAN
THAT ATTEMPTED IT,
IT WAS 1937...
AND HER NAME
WAS AMELIA EARHART.
[laughter and applause]
IT'ŐS A BIG EVENT.
"I HAVE TO PEE.
COME ON. LET'ŐS GO.
"EVERY GIRL, LET'ŐS GO,
YOU GIRLS.
"COME ON.
I HAVE TO PEE, COME ON.
"TAKE MY HAND.
LET'ŐS MAKE A CHAIN OF WHORES.
EVERYONE HOLDS HANDS."
AS THEY WALK
INTO THE BATHROOM.
FOR ME, WHEN I'ŐM WALKING
THROUGH A CROWDED BAR,
THE AMOUNT OF AGGRESSION
I WILL DISPLAY
TOWARD THE OTHER BAR PATRONS
IS IN DIRECT CORRELATION
WITH HOW MANY BOYS
I'ŐVE GOTTEN TO FLIRT WITH.
MEANING IF I HAVEN'ŐT GOTTEN
TO TALK TO ANY CUTE GUYS,
MAMA'ŐS GONNA BE
A LITTLE AGGRESSIVE
IN HER WALK
TO THE BATHROOM, OKAY?
GUYS, WHEN THEY GET DRUNK,
SOMETIMES PUNCH WALLS.
I LIKE TO MULE KICK OTHER GIRLS
IN THE SHIN.
IT'ŐS TOTALLY FINE.
EVERY GIRL'ŐS DONE THIS.
AND YOU KNOW WHY WE DO IT?
'ŐCAUSE WE CAN GET AWAY
WITH IT.
YOU CAN KNOCK INTO A GIRL
AND THEN BE, LIKE, "OOPS.
I DIDN'ŐT MEAN THAT."
[mimics baaing]
[laughter]
OUR SMILE
IS OUR JEDI MIND TRICK.
JUST, "THESE ARE NOT THE DROIDS
YOU'ŐRE LOOKING FOR."
YOU EVER DO THAT?
YOU EVER JUST CHECK A GIRL
INTO THE BOARDS 'ŐCAUSE YOU CAN?
YOU EVER JUST BEEN WALKING,
AND JUST BEEN, LIKE--
[mimics thudding]
"I LOVE YOUR SHOES. OOPS."
[laughter]
TAKES YOU FOREVER,
BUT YOU FINALLY GET THROUGH
THAT JUNGLE OF PEOPLE.
YOU GET TO THE BATHROOM.
FOR THOSE OF YOU
THAT HAVEN'ŐT BEEN
IN A WOMEN'ŐS RESTROOM
LATE NIGHT,
A WOMEN'ŐS RESTROOM
LATE NIGHT
LOOKS LIKE A SCENE OUT OF
"APOCALYPSE NOW."
[laughter]
THERE'ŐS GUNFIRE,
EXPLOSIONS,
BLOOD EVERYWHERE,
CHILDREN,
A LOT OF VIETNAMESE MEN,
WHICH I NEVER QUITE UNDERSTOOD,
LIKE, WHY THEY'ŐD BE THERE.
YOU'ŐRE WITH YOUR BUDDIES
JUST TRYING
TO GET THROUGH EVERYTHING.
YOU GO PEE.
YOU GET TO THE SINK.
AND THEN, YOUR NIGHT COMES
TO A SCREECHING HALT
'ŐCAUSE FOR THE FIRST TIME
IN, LIKE, FOUR HOURS,
YOU GET A LOOK AT YOURSELF
IN THE MIRROR.
[laughter and applause]
AND YOU SEE THE SWAMP WITCH
THAT YOU'ŐVE BECOME.
[laughter]
TEN MINUTES AGO, YOU THOUGHT
YOU LOOKED LIKE HEIDI KLUM.
IT TURNS OUT
YOU LOOK LIKE SEAL.
[laughter and applause]
IT HITS YOU LIKE A TON OF BRICKS
OUT OF NOWHERE.
AND YOU DON'ŐT KNOW
IT'ŐS COMING.
YOU'ŐRE SITTING THERE
TALKING TO YOUR FRIENDS.
YOU'ŐRE LIKE,
"THIS IS AWESOME.
"I'ŐM GONNA BE YOUNG FOREVER.
THIS IS--[screams]"
"NO! WHAT?
WHAT IS THIS?
I WAS ONCE
A GREAT BEAUTY."
"NO.
WHAT IS THIS?"
[babbles indistinctly]
YOU GO TO TOUCH IT.
IT DISAPPEARS.
YOU'ŐRE, LIKE--
[babbles indistinctly]
"IS IT A HOLOGRAM?
WHAT IS THAT?
I LOOK WEIRD."
ONE EYEBALL
HAS MIGRATED HERE.
[laughter]
YOU LOOK DOWN.
YOU'ŐRE JUST LEAKING VODKA.
[laughter]
NOW, YOU DON'ŐT WANNA HOOK UP
WITH ANYONE.
NOW, ALL YOU WANNA DO
IS EAT.
I'ŐM A RED-BLOODED
AMERICAN GIRL.
ABSOLUTELY, WHEN I GET DRUNK,
I WOULD RATHER EAT
THAN HOOK UP WITH YOU.
I'ŐM SORRY.
I DON'ŐT KNOW.
GIVE YOU A HAND JOB
OR GO GET FRIES?
[laughter and applause]
BOTH ARE SALTY.
ONE WILL GIVE ME CARPAL TUNNEL.
I'ŐLL GO WITH THE FRIES.
EVERY TIME.
[applause]
A POPULAR MISCONCEPTION
ABOUT GIRLS
IS THAT WE DON'ŐT
LIKE TO EAT.
GIRLS LOVE TO EAT.
YEAH.
WE JUST DON'ŐT LIKE TO EAT
IN FRONT OF A GUY THAT WE LIKE.
THAT'ŐS THE DIFFERENCE.
WHEN YOU FIRST MEET A GUY
THAT YOU LIKE,
YOU CAN'ŐT EAT THE WAY
YOU WANT TO ON A DATE.
YOU CAN'ŐT.
YOU CAN'ŐT HAVE THAT FOURTH PLATE
OF RIBS ON A DATE...
[laughter]
I FOUND OUT.
GOING ON A DATE,
SOCIETY DICTATES
THAT GUYS CAN DO
WHAT THEY WANT
AND WOMEN HAVE
TO BE DAINTY.
SO HE'ŐS GONNA GET FRIES,
A BURGER,
HALF A GAZELLE,
WHATEVER HE WANTS TO EAT.
GIRLS, YOU GET THE MENU,
WHAT ARE YOU ORDERING?
all: SALAD.
- SALAD.
LIKE HOT LITTLE ROBOTS.
SALAD.
AND IT'ŐS
AN EXCRUCIATING EXPERIENCE
'ŐCAUSE YOU'ŐRE TRYING TO JUST
LOOK PRETTY THE WHOLE TIME.
HE'ŐS SITTING THERE
ENJOYING HIS BURGER.
YOU'ŐRE EATING
YOUR LETTUCE.
YOU'ŐRE JUST SITTING THERE
GOING, "UGH."
YOU'ŐVE ABANDONED
THE UTENSILS.
YOU ORDERED, LIKE, A KOALA.
YOU MAY AS WELL EAT LIKE ONE.
YOU'ŐRE JUST, LIKE--
[groans]
[laughter]
HE'ŐS TALKING.
YOU CAN'ŐT FOCUS
'ŐCAUSE YOU'ŐRE STARVING, RIGHT?
HE'ŐS YAPPING.
YOU'ŐRE JUST, LIKE--[growls]
YOU FINISHED YOUR LETTUCE.
THERE'ŐS NO MORE WATERCRESS
ON THE PLATE.
YOU'ŐRE JUST--[groans]
YOU PULL ONE--
YOU'ŐRE LOOKING AT HIS FOOD.
YOU'ŐRE, LIKE,
"WHAT'ŐS THAT OVER THERE?
FRY."
[growls]
TALKING, TALKING. YOU CAN'ŐT
FOCUS. YOU CAN'ŐT FOCUS.
YOU'ŐRE NOT GETTING ANY
NUTRIENTS TO YOUR BRAIN.
YOU'ŐRE JUST KIND OF STARING OUT
THE WINDOW,
WONDERING WHAT BIRDS
TASTE LIKE.
YOU'ŐRE JUST, LIKE--
[pants]
YOU FINISHED YOUR LEMON WEDGE,
LIKE, AN HOUR AGO.
HE'ŐS STILL EATING.
HE'ŐS STILL TALKING.
AND YOU'ŐRE--YOU'ŐRE STARTING
TO GET COLD NOW.
YOU'ŐRE NOT GETTING ANY NUTRITION
INTO YOUR BLOODSTREAM.
YOUR SPINE IS STICKING OUT.
YOU'ŐRE SHIVERING.
YOU START--
YOU'ŐRE LIKE A LOST PUPPY.
YOU START SAYING THINGS
THAT YOU DON'ŐT MEAN.
HE'ŐS YAPPING. YOU START
JUST SAYING THINGS, LIKE,
"I WOULD LOVE TO SPEND
THE AFTERNOON WITH YOUR MOTHER.
"THAT SOUNDS GREAT.
AND NO, I TOTALLY CARED
"ABOUT THAT WHOLE REPLACEMENT
REFS THING.
IT REALLY ROCKED MY WORLD
AS WELL."
ONCE YOU'ŐRE
IN A RELATIONSHIP,
YOU CAN EAT THE WAY
YOU WANT TO.
ONCE HE LOVES YOU, YOU CAN ROLL
OUT A TROUGH AT MEALTIME.
IT DOESN'ŐT MATTER.
YOU CAN PUT YOUR HANDS BEHIND
YOUR BACK,
COUNTY FAIR
PIE-EATING-CONTEST-STYLE.
[growls]
"I LOVE YOU.
IS THAT THE HOUSE CAT?"
[mimics bone breaking]
[growls]
YEAH, YOU CAN LET IT ALL
HANG OUT WHEN HE LOVES YOU.
THEN, YOU CAN SHOW HIM
HOW YOU EAT.
ONCE YOU'ŐRE IN LOVE,
YOU CAN SHOW HIM
THE 12-FOOT MAN-EATING LIZARD
YOU ACTUALLY ARE.
[screeches,
mimics thudding]
[screeches]
[applause]
YOUR EYES LIGHT UP RED.
VWOOM, VWOOM.
[deep voice]
"LET'ŐS GET CHEESECAKE."
"OH, COOL, SWEETHEART.
YOU WANNA SHARE
A PIECE OF CHEESECAKE?"
"UH-UH."
TAIL SWIPE.
[blows into microphone]
"GET YOUR OWN."
[groans and snorts]
[blows into microphone]
[groans]
"ALL RIGHT, SWEETHEART.
DINNER'ŐS OVER.
DID YOU GET ENOUGH TO EAT?"
I LOVE WHEN THEY ASK THAT
'ŐCAUSE I'ŐVE ALWAYS WANTED
TO GIVE THIS ANSWER.
"DID YOU GET ENOUGH
TO EAT?"
[laughter]
"UH-UH."
"WHY?
WHAT ELSE DO YOU WANT?"
"YOUR SOUL!
FIRE!"
[laughter and applause]
[mimics thudding]
[blows into microphone]
CAN I ASK YOU--
CAN I ASK YOU A QUESTION?
[blows into microphone]
DOES THIS TAIL
MAKE MY BUTT LOOK BIG?
[laughter and applause]
GIRLS LOVE EATING.
WE DO.
WE WERE THE FIRST ONES
TO MAKE IT FUN.
HELLO? APPLE?
GARDEN OF EDEN.
MM-HMM.
GIRLS LOVE TO EAT.
I SAW A BACHELORETTE PARTY
TAKE DOWN A LIVE BUFFALO
AT 35 MILES AN HOUR
OFF THE FREEWAY.
IT WAS MAGNIFICENT.
THE GIRLS
RAN ALONGSIDE IT.
LIKE, "STACY PUT YOUR VEIL
OVER HIS SNOUT."
[laughter]
YOU EVER TRIED
TO GET A GROUP OF DRUNK GIRLS
TO WALK FROM A BAR
TO A RESTAURANT?
IT'ŐS LIKE HERDING DRUNK,
RETARDED SHEEP.
[laughter]
FIRST OF ALL, YES,
I LOVE BEING A WOMAN.
WE'ŐRE AMAZING.
I LOVE BEYONCE.
BUT WE HAVE NO IDEA
WHERE WE'ŐRE GOING.
OKAY?
WE'ŐRE WALKING AROUND.
ALL WE KNOW IS THAT WE GOT
LITTLE SHEEP HOOVES ON
AND WE'ŐRE FREEZING
BECAUSE NO ONE BROUGHT A JACKET.
[mimics baaing]
JUST WALKING FOREVER, NO CLUE.
"I'ŐM COLD.
I'ŐM COLD."
"WHY DIDN'ŐT
YOU BRING A JACKET?"
"'ŐCAUSE I'ŐM IN MY 20s
AND I'ŐM STUPID."
[mimics baaing]
"I'ŐM COLD."
"I HAVE TO PEE.
I'ŐM COLD."
I DON'ŐT HAVE SOLUTIONS.
JUST MORE PROBLEMS."
[mimics baaing]
[laughter and applause]
EVERYBODY'ŐS GOT
THAT ONE GIRLFRIEND
THAT'ŐS A LITTLE FILTHY.
SHE HAS NO ISSUE
WITH PEEING BEHIND A DUMPSTER.
IT HOLDS EVERYONE UP.
YOU'ŐRE ALL TRYING TO WALK
AND SHE'ŐS BACK THERE.
SHE'ŐS, LIKE...
"YOU GUYS!"
[like a sheep]
"WA-A-A-AIT."
[laughter]
"WAIT, NO, MAKE SURE
NOBODY'ŐS WATCHING."
[mimics baaing]
YOU'ŐRE SITTING THERE
RUNNING INTERFERENCE
FOR YOUR FRIEND, LIKE,
"DON'ŐT LOOK AT HER SHEEP VAGINA.
JUST MINE."
[mimics baaing]
I PROMISE YOU
NOBODY'ŐS WATCHING.
I PROMISE YOU.
I PROMISE YOU
NO GUY IS DRIVING BY,
LIKE, "UGH, WELL,
TONIGHT REALLY SUCKS.
"AND I--"
[mimics tires screeching]
"WHOA."
"IS THAT A DRUNK GIRL
PEEING ON HOT GARBAGE?"
[laughter]
"THAT'ŐS AWESOME."
"OH, WHAT AM I DOING?
I GOT TO GET
TO THE CRAFT STORE."
[mimics engine revving]
OH.
SO SHE'ŐS--SHE'ŐS DONE PEEING.
YOU'ŐRE ALL WANDERING.
NOW, YOU'ŐRE
INTO THE SECOND HOUR.
YOU'ŐRE STILL
DRUNK SOMEHOW.
YOU'ŐRE COLD, YOU'ŐRE HUNGRY,
AND YOU--
EVERYBODY'ŐS GOT
THAT ONE GIRLFRIEND
THAT HAS A POOR
MORAL BAROMETER.
SHE'ŐLL GET IN A CAR
WITH ANY GUY...
AS LONG AS IT LOOKS WARM.
AND SHE'ŐLL RATIONALIZE
WHY HE'ŐS NOT A RAPIST
BASED SOLELY ON THE WAY
THAT HE'ŐS DRESSED.
EVERY GIRL'ŐS
HAD TO DO THIS, RIGHT?
YOU HAVE TO MAKE THESE, LIKE,
GAME-TIME DECISIONS.
YOU'ŐRE, LIKE,
"HE'ŐS NOT GONNA RAPE ME.
HE'ŐS WEARING NIKE DUNKS."
"GUYS, COME OVER HERE."
YOUR FRIEND GOES OVER
TO THE GUY.
SHE BENDS DOWN
LIKE A STREETWALKER.
SHE'ŐS, LIKE,
"HI, WHAT'ŐS YOUR NAME?
"TODD?
OH, THAT'ŐS A FUN NAME.
"THAT'ŐS A REALLY EXOTIC NAME.
OH, YOU'ŐLL GIVE US A RIDE?
OKAY, THAT'ŐS REALLY FUN.
MY NAME IS CRYSTAL."
[chuckles]
"NICE TO MEET YOU.
"HOLD ON A SECOND.
YOU GUYS!
HE'ŐS GONNA GIVE US A RIDE."
[mimics baaing]
"HE'ŐS GONNA GIVE US A RIDE."
"DO YOU WANNA GO WITH HIM?"
YOUR FRIENDS KNOW BETTER.
THEY'ŐRE ON THE OTHER SIDE
OF THE STREET
HUDDLED TOGETHER,
LIKE, "CRYSTAL, GET AWAY."
[laughter]
"WE'ŐRE NOT--GET--HE'ŐS NOT--"
[mimics baaing]
[laughter and applause]
CRYSTAL'ŐS STUPID,
AND SHE'ŐS ALREADY--
SHE'ŐS, LIKE,
"HOLD ON ONE SECOND.
"THANK YOU SO MUCH.
I REALLY LIKE YOUR CHIN STRAP.
IT'ŐS REALLY ATTRACTIVE."
"HOLD ON ONE SECOND.
HOLD ON.
"LET ME--
YOU GUYS!
"HE'ŐS GONNA GIVE US
A RIDE.
"LIKE, DO YOU WANNA JUST
KEEP WALKING?
SARAH, YOU'ŐRE BEING A BITCH."
"YOU ARE--LIKE, WE TALKED
ABOUT THIS EARLIER
"WHEN YOU WERE
IN THE BATHROOM.
"YOU'ŐRE BEING--THIS IS,
LIKE, WHAT WE TALKED ABOUT.
"YOU'ŐRE BEING A--
DO YOU NOT WANNA--
"YOU DON'ŐT WANNA GO
WITH HIM?
"YOU GUY--
HOLD ON ONE SECOND.
"THANK YOU SO MUCH.
HOLD ON ONE--
"OKAY, HOLD ON.
HOLD ON A SEC.
"YOU GUYS, HE'ŐS GONNA GIVE US--
HE'ŐS BEING NICE.
"STOP IT.
STOP IT.
HE'ŐS NOT--HE'ŐS NOT--
HE'ŐS NOT GONNA RAPE US."
[laughter]
"HE'ŐS NOT GONNA RAPE US."
YOU HAVE TO WHISPER
THE RAPE PART.
JUST IN CASE
THAT WAS HIS INTENTION,
YOU DON'ŐT WANT TO OFFEND HIM
AHEAD OF TIME.
[laughter]
GOD FORBID YOU OFFEND HIM
AND HE LEAVES.
OH, NO.
THEN WHAT?
"HE'ŐS NOT GONNA RAPE US.
HE'ŐS WEARING SKECHERS."
THAT'ŐS FAIR.
NOW, YOU'ŐRE
INTO HOUR THREE.
YOU DIDN'ŐT TAKE THE RIDE
FROM CHIN STRAP.
SO YOU'ŐRE WALKING.
YOU'ŐRE COLD.
NO ONE KNOWS
WHERE THEY'ŐRE GOING
'ŐCAUSE YOU'ŐRE ALL RELYING
ON GIRL GPS.
FOR THOSE OF YOU
THAT DON'ŐT KNOW,
GIRL GPS PRETTY MUCH CONSISTS
OF ONE GIRL DOING THIS:
"UM..."
"I FEEL
LIKE IT'ŐS THIS WAY."
[laughter and applause]
GIRLS, WHEN YOU GET DRUNK,
WHO ARE YOU MOST LIKELY
TO PICK A FIGHT WITH?
YOUR BOYFRIEND.
DO YOU WANNA KNOW WHY?
'ŐCAUSE YOU KNOW
HE'ŐS NOT GONNA HIT YOU BACK.
[laughter]
EVERY GIRL IN HERE KNOWS
THAT YOUR BOYFRIEND
WILL TAKE A HEALTHY DOSE
OF YOUR DRUNK RANTING.
WHY?
'ŐCAUSE AT THE END OF THE NIGHT
WHEN YOU'ŐRE ALL TUCKERED OUT,
HE'ŐS GONNA WANT
TO MOUTH-KISS YOU
AND TOUCH YOUR SNOOTCH,
THAT'ŐS WHY.
I HATE TO TELL YOU
IT'ŐS WHY THEY DO EVERYTHING.
IT'ŐS WHY THEY PUT UP
WITH YOUR ATTITUDE.
IT'ŐS WHY THEY BUY YOU
EXPENSIVE DRINKS.
IT'ŐS WHY THEY LET YOU MAKE THEM
TURN THE GAME OFF
SO YOU CAN SHOW THEM
WHAT YOU DID ON PINTEREST.
OKAY?
FOR SNOOTCHES.
[laughter and applause]
"STEVE, COME HERE.
COME LOOK AT THIS.
"NO, LIKE, OFF.
LIKE, TURN IT OFF.
"DON'ŐT P--
JUST, LIKE, SHUT IT OFF.
"I WANNA SHOW YOU SOMETHING.
COME HERE.
COME HERE."
"LOOK, LOOK WHAT I HAVE.
LOOK WHAT I PINNED.
"LOOK AT THIS.
IT'ŐS AN ENTIRE WEDDING
MADE OF CHEESE."
"IT CAN BE OUR WEDDING."
"STEVEN?"
I CALL IT A "SNOOTCH"
'ŐCAUSE I DON'ŐT LIKE
THE WORD "VAGINA."
NO ONE SAYS "VAGINA."
LIKE, NO ONE SAYS THAT.
THAT'ŐS WEIRD.
NO ONE HERE HAS EVER BEEN
HOOKING UP WITH SOMEONE
AND BEEN, LIKE,
"THIS FEELS GREAT.
CONTINUE TO TOUCH
MY VAGINA."
[laughter]
VAGINA?
WHAT?
A VAGINA SOUNDS
LIKE AN INDIAN CASINO.
[laughter]
"THIS WEEKEND AT VAGINA..."
"WAYNE NEWTON AT VAGINA."
I MADE UP "SNOOTCH"
'ŐCAUSE IT'ŐS SO CUTE-SOUNDING.
[in high-pitched voice]
SNOOTCH.
MAYBE IT WOULD BE,
LIKE, A CARTOON CHARACTER.
LIKE, A CUTE, TINY,
FURRY...OBVIOUSLY...
CHARACTER.
IT'ŐS GOT A LITTLE
TOP HAT.
AND MAYBE BEFORE
YOU HAVE SEX,
YOU HAVE
TO SUMMON SNOOTCH
SO HE CAN BLESS
THE WHOLE THING.
YEAH, THAT'ŐS WHAT
YOU HAVE TO DO.
YOU'ŐRE HAVING--
YOU'ŐRE ABOUT TO HAVE SEX.
YOU HAVE TO GET OUT
A SNOOTCH FLUTE
WHICH YOU HAVE
TO PREORDER.
YOU HAVE
TO ORDER THEM ONLINE.
IT'ŐS A--
IT'ŐS A DOT-GOV SITE.
YOU PULL IT OUT.
YOU'ŐRE, LIKE,
"YOU READY TO HAVE SEX?"
"SURE, LET'ŐS--LET'ŐS--
LET'ŐS SUMMON SNOOTCH."
[singing]
"DOO, DOO, DOO, DOO, DOO, DOO.
SNOOTCH!"
[laughter and applause]
"HI, FOLKS."
"HI, SNOOTCH.
"WE WERE JUST ABOUT
TO HAVE SEX.
DO WE HAVE
YOUR BLESSING?"
"WELL, YOU SURELY DO.
"IT WAS NICE MEETING
BOTH OF YOU,
"BUT I BETTER BE
ON MY WAY.
[singing]
"DOO, DOO, DOO, DOO, DOO, DOO.
SNOOTCH!"
[laughter and applause]
SO CUTE.
I MADE UP "SNOOTCH"
'ŐCAUSE I DON'ŐT LIKE THE P-WORD.
I DON'ŐT LIKE SAYING IT.
IT'ŐS NOT A LADY WORD.
PUSSY.
IF I GOT TO SAY IT,
THERE'ŐS GONNA BE
AN INVOLUNTARY FACIAL SPASM
THAT COMES WITH IT.
YOU SHOULD
KNOW THAT.
I WILL RUIN
ANY SORT OF MOMENT
WE HAVE GOING
IN THE BEDROOM.
"ALL RIGHT, BABE.
THIS IS GREAT.
TELL ME WHERE YOU WANT ME
TO PUT IT."
"I'ŐLL SAY IT,
BUT YOU'ŐRE NOT GONNA LIKE IT."
[laughter]
"COME ON. WHERE DO YOU
WANT ME TO PUT IT?"
"WHY DON'ŐT YOU PUT IT
IN MY PUSSY!"
[screams]
"I CAN'ŐT."
"WHAT'ŐD YOU SAY?"
"NOTHING.
I'ŐM FINE, I'ŐM FINE."
[sighs]
"ALL RIGHT. LET'ŐS DO THIS."
"GREAT."
"ALL RIGHT, COME ON.
"LET'ŐS GET BACK TO IT.
ALL RIGHT, WHERE DO YOU
WANT ME TO PUT IT?"
"WHY DON'ŐT YOU PUT IT
IN MY PUSSY!"
[screams]
"NO!"
IT'ŐS NOT A LADY WORD.
LADIES DON'ŐT SAY THAT WORD.
LIKE, GROWING UP,
DID YOUR MOM EVER SAY,
"PUSSY, YOU NEED
TO SHOWER?"
NO, SHE DIDN'ŐT, RIGHT?
NO, AND IF SHE DID,
THEN YOUR MOM WAS WHITE TRASH.
[laughter]
IT'ŐS NOT A LADY WORD.
IT'ŐS NOT A WORD THAT WOMEN HEAR
INDEPENDENT OF MEN.
MOST WOMEN DON'ŐT HEAR THAT WORD,
LIKE, IN PROFESSIONAL ETHER.
NO WOMAN'ŐS LAYING THERE
AT THE GYNECOLOGIST.
DOCTOR WALKS IN, HE'ŐS, LIKE--
[snorts]
"WHAT'ŐS UP?"
[clears throat]
"HOW'ŐS IT HANGIN'Ő?
ALL RIGHT, LET'ŐS SEE.
PUSSY CHECKS OUT ALL RIGHT."
"GREAT TITS, BY THE WAY.
GOOD HUSTLE.
GET OUTTA HERE."
[laughter and applause]
IT'ŐS--IT'ŐS A GUY WORD.
I DON'ŐT CARE
THAT GUYS SAY IT.
BOYS ARE GROSS, AND THAT'ŐS
WHY WE LOVE THEM, OKAY?
BUT THAT'ŐS A GUY THING.
THAT'ŐS WHAT GUYS SAY
IN THE LOCKER ROOMS
WITH--WITH--
WITH ALL THEIR GROSSNESS.
I'ŐD IMAGINE THEY GO
TO THE LOCKER ROOM
AFTER A ROUSING GAME
OF TOUCH SOFTBALL,
AND THEY TALK
ABOUT THE P-WORD.
"HEY, WHAT'ŐS UP?
WHAT'ŐS UP, BRO?
"WHAT'ŐS UP?
DID YOU GET ANY--
DID YOU GET ANY PUSSY
LAST NIGHT?"
"YEAH, A WHOLE BUCKET."
I DON'ŐT KNOW
HOW YOU QUANTIFY IT.
I DON'ŐT KNOW IF IT GOES BUCKET,
MUG, RAMEKIN.
I DON'ŐT KNOW.
BUT THAT'ŐS WHAT GUYS DO
IN THE LOCKER ROOMS
WITH THE BUTT SLAPS
AND THE SWORD FIGHTING.
THAT'ŐS WHAT THEY DO.
WE KNOW ABOUT THAT.
WE KNOW YOU DO WEIRD THINGS
WITH EACH OTHER
WITH YOUR WIENERS
'ŐCAUSE YOU DO WEIRD THINGS
WITH US, AND YOU'ŐRE TRYING
TO IMPRESS US.
SO I CAN ONLY IMAGINE
WHAT CREEPINESS
GOES ON BEHIND CLOSED DOORS.
I'ŐVE SEEN IT FIRSTHAND.
EVERY GIRL HAS.
EVERY GIRL'ŐS
HAD THAT BOYFRIEND
WHERE YOU'ŐRE SITTING
ON THE BED
IN YOUR TARGET
UNDERWEAR WAITING.
HE COMES OUT
OF THE BATHROOM NAKED
EXCEPT FOR A T-SHIRT.
NO BOTTOMS,
DONALD DUCKING IT THE WHOLE WAY.
[laughter and applause]
HE'ŐS GOT THIS GRIN
ON HIS FACE.
AND HE'ŐS JUST, LIKE,
"HEY, BABE.
BABE, CHECK THIS OUT."
[laughter]
WHY ARE YOU DOING THAT?
ON BEHALF
OF ALL WOMEN, WHY?
IT'ŐS NEVER GONNA CHANGE
A GIRL'ŐS MIND, EVER.
YOU ARE NOT
HELPING YOURSELF.
NO WOMAN,
I PROMISE YOU, EVER--
YOU'ŐRE SITTING THERE
DOING THAT LIKE A CIRCUS MONKEY,
NO GIRL IS GONNA
TURN AROUND, LIKE...
[sighs]
"MY, MY, MY."
"YOU KNOW WHAT'ŐS CRAZY?
"UM...
"I DIDN'ŐT WANT TO HAVE SEX
WITH YOU BEFORE.
"BUT NOW...
"NOW THAT YOU'ŐVE DISPLAYED
THE AGILITY..."
"OF YOUR FLACCID PENIS...
"AS IT SLAPS
IN RHYTHMIC REPETITION...
"AGAINST EITHER ONE
"OF YOUR CLEARLY
NEVER-SEEN-BY-THE-SUN THIGHS,
NOW, SNOOTCH TIME."
[laughter and applause]
IN CLOSING, I WOULD...
[chuckles]
IN CLOSING,
I WOULD LIKE TO GIVE
THE GIRLS IN THIS ROOM
A BIT OF ADVICE, OKAY?
I HAVE A TIP FOR YOU,
BUT JUST THE TIP.
[laughter and applause]
LADIES, NEVER ORDER A LOBSTER
ON A DATE.
THE LOBSTER IS THE MOST
EXPENSIVE THING
ON THE MENU, OKAY?
SO JUST KNOW THAT IF YOU ORDER
AND CONSUME A LOBSTER,
YOU HAVE TO TOUCH
YOUR DATE'ŐS WEINER.
YOU HAVE TO, OKAY?
IT'ŐS LIKE A SEXUAL CONTRACT
FROM THE SEA.
[laughter]
IT'ŐS BINDING.
NOW, KEEP IN MIND HE WANTS YOU
TO GET THE LOBSTER.
HE'ŐS NOT GONNA
MAKE YOU GET IT,
BUT HE'ŐS HOPING YOU'ŐLL COME
TO THAT CONCLUSION ON YOUR OWN.
HE'ŐS HOPING YOU'ŐLL BE FLIPPING
THROUGH THE MENU,
AND YOU'ŐLL BE, LIKE,
"I DON'ŐT KNOW WHAT TO GET.
"LIKE, I'ŐM JUST--I DON'ŐT KNOW.
I'ŐM EATING FRESH THIS WEEK.
"I'ŐM EATING A LOT
OF FRESH THINGS.
"THAT'ŐS MY NEW THING, FRESH.
I'ŐM JUST GONNA DO FRESH FOOD."
[gasps]
"LOBSTER?
"SHOULD I--SHOULD I GET IT?
SHOULD I GET IT?
"SHOULD I GET
THE LOBSTER?
"SHOULD I CRACK IT OPEN
ON MY HEAD LIKE AN OTTER,
"EAT IT OFF
MY CHEST?
LOBSTER?"
"YEAH, 'ŐCAUSE THEN,
IT'ŐS WEINER TIME
THIS SUNDAY AT VAGINA."
[laughter and applause]
HERE'ŐS HOW IT'ŐS GONNA
GO DOWN, OKAY?
YOU'ŐRE GONNA BE
MAKING OUT LATER.
AND NOW, GUYS,
THIS IS FOR YOU TO KNOW.
JUST SO YOU KNOW,
AS GIRLS,
WE LIKE TO MAKE OUT WITH YOU
WHEN WE FIRST MEET YOU.
A COUPLE TIMES
AND THEN LEAVE
RIGHT WHEN YOU THINK
WE'ŐRE GONNA SLEEP
WITH YOU, OKAY?
WE DO IT TO MAKE SURE
THAT YOU LIKE US.
BUT IF YOU WANT TO KNOW
THE TRUTH,
THEY TEACH US THIS SHIT
IN HIGH SCHOOL.
WHILE YOU WERE OFF BUILDING
A BIRDHOUSE IN SHOP CLASS,
WE WERE OFF LEARNING
HOW TO BE ANNOYING.
HERE'ŐS HOW IT HAPPENS.
YOU'ŐRE GONNA BE
MAKING OUT.
AND YOU'ŐLL NOTICE
THAT WHEN A GIRL
MAKES OUT WITH YOU
AND LEAVES YOU,
WE ALWAYS LEAVE
IN A VERY SWEET WAY
BECAUSE WE WANT YOU
TO HAVE
A NICE IMPRESSION OF US
FOR LATER, RIGHT?
SO IT'ŐS ALWAYS, LIKE,
"OKAY, WELL, I GOTTA GO.
BYE." [mimics baaing]
NO, YOU DIDN'ŐT. NO.
"BYE. I LOVE YOU TOO.
STOP IT." [mimics baaing]
IT'ŐS ALWAYS
VERY SWEET, RIGHT?
I'ŐVE GONE AS FAR
AS TO SOMETIMES BRING
A LITTLE THING
OF VANILLA BODY SPRAY.
AND WHEN HE GETS UP
TO GO TO THE BATHROOM,
I SPRAY IT ON HIS PILLOW.
THAT WAY, LATER,
WHEN HE TEXTS ME,
HE'ŐS LIKE, "OH, MY GOD.
MY PILLOW STILL SMELLS
LIKE YOU."
I'ŐM LIKE, "THAT'ŐS AMAZING."
"I DON'ŐT KNOW WHY."
YOU CAN GET CREATIVE
WITH IT.
YOU CAN TAKE A HANDFUL
OF GLITTER ON YOUR DATE.
AND THEN AFTER YOU'ŐRE LEAVING,
JUST BE, LIKE,
"OKAY, I GOTTA GO."
[blows into microphone]
"BYE."
YOU CAN BRING A SMOKE BOMB...
[mimics exploding]
AND THEN, LIKE,
STILL BE STANDING THERE
'ŐCAUSE YOU DON'ŐT KNOW MAGIC.
GIRLS ALWAYS LEAVE
IN A SWEET WAY.
WE NEVER LEAVE
IN A HUFF.
IT'ŐS NEVER, LIKE,
"WELL, I GOT MINE.
EAT MY SHIT LATER, FUCK-TARD."
[mimics thudding]
NEVER DOING THAT.
SO WE'ŐRE GONNA BE
MAKING OUT LATER.
AND HERE'ŐS
HOW IT'ŐS GONNA GO.
WE'ŐRE GONNA BE
MAKING OUT, OKAY?
SO THIS IS
I'ŐM 12, THIS IS WHAT MAKING OUT
LOOKS LIKE.
AND THE GUY'ŐS
GONNA BE, LIKE,
"OH, I LIKE MAKING OUT WITH YOU
SO MUCH."
"I LIKE MAKING OUT
WITH YOU."
"TONIGHT WAS SO FUN."
"IT WAS REALLY FUN."
"YOU'ŐRE SO HOT."
"I KNOW."
"THIS IS SO FUN.
I REALLY LIKE YOU.
YOU'ŐRE SO PRETTY."
"I KNOW, THIS IS GREAT.
I AM PRETTY."
"OH, I LIKE YOU A LOT.
SO YOU WANNA KEEP GOING?"
GIRLS, THAT'ŐS YOUR CUE.
"ALL RIGHT, WELL, I GOTTA GO."
"WHAT?"
"I GOTTA GO, BYE."
"LATER."
[mimics baaing]
AND THE GUY
IS GONNA TRY
TO GET YOU TO STAY, RIGHT?
AS HE SHOULD.
YOU CAN'ŐT JUST WALK
OUT OF A SPIDER'ŐS WEB.
[laughter]
"YOU'ŐRE REALLY GONNA GO?
COME ON. COME ON.
"AMBER.
YOU REALLY GONNA GO?
YOU REALLY GONNA GO?"
"REALLY GONNA GO?"
[indistinct]
[trilling]
"REALLY JUST GO?
YOU'ŐRE JUST GONNA GO? HUH?"
[laughter and applause]
[laughter]
"YOU'ŐRE JUST GONNA LEAVE IT
LIKE THIS?"
"I'ŐM SORRY.
"WERE WE IN THE MIDDLE
OF OPEN HEART SURGERY?
"I'ŐM PRETTY SURE
YOU'ŐRE FINE.
"YEAH.
"I'ŐM NOT A DOCTOR PER SE,
BUT I'ŐM FAIRLY CONFIDENT
"THAT BLOOD WILL RETURN
TO YOUR SYSTEM.
WALK IT OFF, CHAMP."
[laughter and applause]
THAT MIGHT SOUND HARSH,
BUT IT TOOK TEN YEARS
OF ME DATING
TO LEARN THAT A BONER
ISN'ŐT A MEDICAL CONDITION.
SO I'ŐM PAYING YOU BACK
RIGHT NOW.
[laughter and applause]
NOW, HE'ŐS PISSED,
MOSTLY BECAUSE HE HAS
A RAGING ERECTION
AND YOU CALLED HIM "CHAMP."
NOW, HE'ŐS MAD.
"REALLY? YOU'ŐRE GONNA GO?
THAT'ŐS MESSED UP.
THAT'ŐS MESSED UP!"
[growls]
"IT'ŐS MESSED UP, AMBER.
YOU'ŐRE JUST GONNA GO.
"LET ME...
JUST GONNA GO?
"IT'ŐS FUNNY.
IT'ŐS FUNNY.
"YOU'ŐRE JUST GONNA GO
'ŐCAUSE, UH...HUH.
I DISTINCTLY REMEMBER
I BOUGHT YOU A LOBSTER."
[laughter and applause]
THE MAN'ŐS RIGHT.
TIME TO PAY THE PIPER.
GIRLS, YOU DO NOT HAVE
TO SLEEP WITH HIM.
IT'ŐS JUST A CRUSTACEAN.
THAT'ŐS RIDICULOUS, ALL RIGHT?
BUT YOU GOT
TO GIVE HIM SOMETHING.
I-I SUGGEST A BEEJ.
THAT'ŐS WHAT I SUGGEST.
[laughter]
THAT'ŐS PROPER.
DON'ŐT DO A HAND JOB.
THAT'ŐS RIDICULOUS.
THAT'ŐS CHILD'ŐS PLAY.
[laughter and applause]
HAND JOB?
A HANDY? REALLY?
AS A GROWN WOMAN, YOU'ŐRE NOT
DOING A HAND JOB, OKAY?
IF YOU VOTED,
YOU'ŐRE NOT DOING A HAND JOB.
[laughter]
LET'ŐS SEND SOME HAND JOBS
OVERSEAS TO CHINA.
[laughter and applause]
NOT DOING A HAND JOB.
A HAND JOB, WHO DOES--
THAT'ŐS WHAT KIDS DO
WHEN YOU'ŐRE,
LIKE, A TEENAGER.
YOU DO A HAND JOB.
YOU PUT ON YOUR PROMISE RING.
YOU REVEL IN YOUR VIRGINITY
FOR THE NEXT 10 TO 15 YEARS
DEPENDING ON YOUR INVOLVEMENT
WITH COMIC BOOKS.
THAT'ŐS WHAT A HAND JOB
IS FOR.
AS AN ADULT,
IT'ŐS NOT HAPPENING.
IT'ŐS AN INTERMEDIARY STEP
IN A SEXUAL EVOLUTION
THAT YOU'ŐVE
EVOLVED PAST, OKAY?
IT'ŐS LIKE A TAIL...
NECESSARY AT ONE POINT
FOR BALANCE,
BUT IF YOU BUSTED IT OUT
AT A HOUSE PARTY,
PEOPLE WOULD BE,
LIKE, WEIRDED OUT.
[laughter]
I WAS OUT WITH A GUY ONE TIME
WHO I WASN'ŐT EVEN INTO.
I DIDN'ŐT WANT TO DO ANYTHING.
AND HE DIDN'ŐT BUY ME A LOBSTER.
AND I WAS--
I EXPLAINED EVERYTHING.
AND AFTER TALKING
TO HIM,
HE'ŐS LIKE,
"I'ŐD LIKE A HAND JOB."
[laughter]
"I THINK
IT SOUNDS GREAT."
AND I GUESS
I WAS FRUSTRATED
'ŐCAUSE HE HADN'ŐT BEEN LISTENING
TO ME OR MY FEELINGS.
AND I WAS LIKE,
"ALL RIGHT.
"I'ŐLL TELL YOU WHAT, SON.
"I'ŐM GONNA GIVE YOU
A HAND JOB.
BUT IT'ŐS GONNA BE
ON MY TERMS."
[laughter]
"45 MINUTES LONG..."
"NO LOTION..."
[laughter and applause]
"AND YOU DON'ŐT BREAK
EYE CONTACT.
GO!"
[cheers and applause]
[coughs and sighs]
WHAT KILLS ME IS THAT YOU GET
THAT I'ŐM KIDDING.
HE DID NOT.
I SWEAR TO GOD HE GOES,
"AW, NO LOTION?"
[laughter]
"THAT DOESN'ŐT SOUND FUN."
LIKE THE 45-MINUTE PART
IS TOLERABLE?
[laughter]
"ILIZA, COME ON.
YOU GOTTA DO SOMETHING.
YOU GOTTA GIVE ME LOTION
OR DO SOMETHING CUTE."
IT THREW ME OFF
THAT HE SAID "CUTE"
BECAUSE THAT'ŐS NOT AN ADJECTIVE
I BELIEVE
BELONGS ANYWHERE
NEAR AN H.J.
IT SOUNDED CREEPY
IN A WAY.
I WAS LIKE,
"WHAT DO YOU MEAN 'ŐCUTE'Ő?
"WHAT--WHAT'ŐS CUTE?
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
WHAT DO YOU WANT,
KITTEN PAWS?"
[laughter]
IT'ŐS PROBABLY HOW THAT ONE CAT
LOST HIS EYE.
YOU GUYS ARE FANTASTIC.
THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR COMING OUT.
[cheers and applause]
[upbeat music]