- That's it.
- Not that l don't like the music.
l thought you weren't supposed
to talk about it too much.
- No, l guess we're not.
- l thought we were supposed to...
pan away from that sort of stuff,
get into something else.
Since the beginning,
since we started playing together,
just like we've all grown just a little bit,
so have the women.
- You know? And it's amazing.
- That's right. That's good.
l just wanna break even.
(cheering)
(' ''Coyote'')
' No regrets, coyote
' We just come from such
different sets of circumstance
' l'm up all night in the studios
and you're up early on your ranch
' You'll be brushing out a brood mare's
tail while the sun is ascending
' And l'll just be getting home
with my reel-to-reel
' There's no comprehending
' Just how close to the bone
and the skin and the eyes
' And the lips you can get
' And still feel so alone
' And still feel related
' Like stations in some relay
' You're not a hit-and-run driver, no, no
' Racing away
' You just picked up a hitcher
' A prisoner of the white lines
on the freeway
' We saw a farmhouse burning down
' ln the middle of nowhere
in the middle of the night
' And we rolled right past that tragedy
' until we pulled in
to some roadhouse lights
' Where a local band was playing
' Locals were up kicking
and shaking on the floor
' The next thing l know
' That coyote's at my door
' He pins me in the corner
and he won't take ''No!''
' He drags me out on the dance floor
and we're dancing close and slow
' Now he's got a woman at home
' He's got another woman down the hall
and he seems to want me anyway
' Why d'you have to get so drunk
and lead me on that way?
' You just picked up a hitcher
' A prisoner of the white lines
on the freeway
' l looked a coyote right in the face
' On the road to Baljennie,
near my old home town
' He went running through
the whisker wheat
' Chasing some prize down
' And a hawk was playing with him
' Coyote was jumping straight up
and making passes
' He had those same eyes, just like yours
' under your dark glasses
' Privately probing the public rooms
' And peeking through keyholes
in numbered doors
' Where the players lick their wounds
and take their temporary lovers
' And their pills and powders
to get them through this passion play
' No regrets, coyote
' l just get off up aways
' You just picked up a hitcher
' A prisoner of the white lines
on the freeway
' Coyote's in the coffee shop
' He's staring a hole
in his scrambled eggs
' He picks up my scent on his fingers
while he's watching the waitresses' legs
' He's too far from the Bay of Fundy
' From Appaloosas and eagles and tides
' And the air-conditioned cubicles
' And the carbon ribbon rides
are spelling it out so clear
' Either he's gonna
have to stand and fight
' Or take off out of here
' l've tried to run away myself
' To run away and wrestle with my ego
' And with this flame
you put here in this Eskimo
' ln this hitcher
' ln this prisoner
' Of the fine white lines
' Of the white lines
' On the free freeway
(cheering)
Levon's home town,
it's near West Helena.
One time we were there,
for some reason or another,
and we decided we were gonna look up
one of the legends of that town,
which was Sonny Boy Williamson.
ln my opinion, he's the best harp player,
that's like harmonica,
blues harmonica, that l've ever heard.
He's the big Daddy of 'em.
And he took us to a friend of his,
a woman's place,
who served food and corn liquor.
ln a southern booze can.
He would sit there
and he was playing for us.
And we were getting drunk
and trying to figure out where we were.
He was spitting in a can.
l thought he was dipping snuff.
l thought he had something in his lip.
And he kept spitting in this can and
playing, and we kept getting drunker.
Finally, l looked over in the can
and l realised it was blood.
He was getting pretty tired
and pretty drunk by then.
And we made big plans for the future
and all kinds of things we were gonna do.
And it was tremendous. A great night.
A couple of months later, we got a letter
from his manager, or whoever it was,
saying that he had passed away.
(' ''Mystery Train'')
' Train arrive
' 16 coaches long
' Train arrive, yeah
' Well, that long, black train
took my baby and gone
' Train, train
' Rolling round the bend
' Well, it took my baby
away from me again
' Heard that whistle blowing,
it was the middle of the night
' When l got down to the station
the train was pulling out of sight
' Mystery train
' Rolling round the bend
' Well, it took my baby
' Away from me again
(cheering)
(Robertson) Paul Butterfield!
Near Memphis,
cotton country, rice country,
the most interesting thing
is probably the music.
(Scorsese)
Levon, who came from around there?
Carl Perkins.
Muddy Waters, the king of country music.
(Robertson) Elvis Presley.
Johnny Cash. Bo Diddley.
That's kind of the middle
of the country back there.
So bluegrass or country music,
you know, if it comes down to that area
and if it mixes there with rhythm
and if it dances,
then you've got a combination
of all those different kinds of music.
Country, bluegrass, blues music.
- (Robertson) The melting pot.
- Show music.
- (Scorsese) And what's it called?
- Rock and roll!
(Scorsese) Yes. Exactly.
Whoa!
(' ''Mannish Boy'')
' When l was a young boy
' At the age of five
' My mother said l would be
' The greatest man alive
' But now l'm a man
' Way past 21
' l want you to believe me, woman
' l have lots of fun
' l'm a man
' l spell ''M''
' ''A'', chile
' ''N''
' My grandma says l'm grown
' No ''B''
' ''O'', chile
' ''Y''
' That mean mannish boy
' Man
' l'm a full-grown man
' l'm a natural-born lover's man
' Man
' l'm a rolling stone
' l'm a hoochie-coochie man
' Well
' Well, well, well
' The line l shoot
' l will never miss
' When l make love to a girl
' She can't resist
' l think l'll go down
' To old Kansas Stew
' l'm gonna bring back my second cousin
' That little Johnny Congeroo
' All you little girls
' Sitting out at that line
' l can make love to you, girl
' ln five minutes' time
' Ain't that a man?
' l spell ''M''
' ''A'', chile
' ''N''
' That represents man
' No ''B''
' ''O'', chile
' ''Y''
' That means mannish boy
' Man
' l'm a full-grown man
' l'm a natural-born lover's man
' Man
' l'm a rolling stone
' Man-child
' l'm a hoochie-coochie man
' Well
' Well, well, well, well, well, well, well
' Well, well, well, well, well
(cheering)
(Robertson)
Wasn't that a man! Muddy Waters!
On the guitar, Eric Clapton!
(cheering)
One, two, a-one, two, three...
(' ''Further on up the Road'')
' Further on up the road
' Someone's gonna hurt you
like you hurt me
' Further on up the road
' Someone's gonna hurt you
like you hurt me
' Further on up the road
' Baby, just you wait and see
' You gotta reap just what you sow
' That old saying is true
' Just like you mistreat someone
' Someone's gonna mistreat you
' Further up the road
' Someone's gonna hurt you
like you hurt me
' Further on up the road
' Someone's gonna hurt you
like you hurt me
' Further on up the road
' Baby, just you wait and see
' You been laughing, pretty baby
' Someday you're gonna be crying
' Further on up the road
' You'll find out l wasn't lying
(cheering)
OK. So, Rick, what is Shangri-La?
Maybe you could give us a little tour.
What is Shangri-La?
lt's a club house where we get together
and play. Make records.
Yeah.
Kind of better. lt's like an office, l guess.
lt used to be a bordello.
- A bordello?
- You can tell by the wallpaper.
That decadence,
that softness in the barroom.
l've heard a few funny stories, man.
- That's why all these rooms are here.
- You can't believe most of what you hear.
This was a master-control bedroom,
this is now a master-control music room.
Let me ask you, now that The Last
Waltz is over, what are you doing now?
- Eddie, why don't you...
- (' ''Sip the Wine'' intro)
Just making music, you know?
Oh, yeah.
Trying to stay busy, man.
(music grows louder)
' l want to lay down beside you
' l want to hold your body close to mine
' Like a grape that grows ripe...
lt's where the music took you. Otherwise
you would never go to such a situation.
Because of the music,
it took us everywhere.
lt took us to some strange places.
- (Scorsese) Physically and spiritually?
- Physically, spiritually and psychotically.
lt just always wasn't on the stage.
- Even though you were on the stage.
- Even though we were on the stage.
(' ''Evangeline'')
' She stands on the banks
of the mighty Mississippi
' Alone in the pale moonlight
' Waiting for a man, a riverboat gambler
' Said that he'd return tonight
' They used to waltz on the banks
of the mighty Mississippi
' Loving the whole night through
' Till the riverboat gambler
went off to make a killing
' And bring it on back to you
' Evangeline, Evangeline
' Curses the soul
of the Mississippi Queen
' That pulled her man away
' Bayou Sam from South Louisiana
' Had gambling in his veins
' Evangeline from the Maritimes
' Was slowly going insane
' High on the top of Hickory Hill
' She stands in the lightning and thunder
' Down on the river the boat was sinking
' She watched that Queen go under
' Evangeline, Evangeline
' Curses the soul
of the Mississippi Queen
' That pulled her man away
' Evangeline, Evangeline
' Curses the soul
of the Mississippi Queen
' That pulled her man away
(' ''Chest Fever'')
(Robertson) Garth was one of the most
amazing musicians that we knew.
He could play better
than anybody we ever heard.
And Garth joined The Band
if we would make him the music teacher.
We didn't know why but we said
''Sure. l mean, we're interested anyway.''
And we had to pay him $10 a week each
for these music lessons.
Then l was sure it was a riff.
But then l found out what it really was.
lt was that, where he was coming from
and his musical education,
to tell his parents at this point
that we was joining a rock-and-roll band
would have been like
pouring it down the drain.
So he justified it to his people and his
background by being a music teacher.
There is a view that jazz is evil
because it comes from evil people.
But, actually,
the greatest priests on 52nd Street
and on the streets of New York City
were the musicians.
They were doing
the greatest healing work.
And they knew how
to punch through music
which would cure
and make people feel good.
(' ''Ophelia'')
' Boards on the window
' Mail by the door
' Why would anybody leave
so quickly for?
' Ophelia
' Where have you gone?
' The old neighbourhood
just ain't the same
' Nobody knows just what became
' Of Ophelia
' Where have you gone?
' Was it something that somebody said?
' Mama, you know we broke the rules
' Was somebody up against the law?
' Honey, you know that l'd die for you
' They got your number
' They're scared and running
' But l'm just waiting for
the second coming
' Of Ophelia
' Please darken my door
' Was it something that somebody said?
' Mama, you know we broke the rules
' Was somebody up against the law?
' Oh, honey, you know that l'd die for you
' Ashes of laughter
' The ghost is clear
' Why do the best things
always disappear?
' Like Ophelia
' Oh, please, come back home
(cheering)
Most of the show stuff, though,
was like travelling shows, like tent shows.
One was Walcott's Rabbit Foot Minstrels.
- (Scorsese) What was that?
- Walcott's Rabbit Foot Minstrels. Yeah.
They used to have the show start, right?
They'd have the singers and the players
and the different parts of the show.
Then the master of ceremonies
would come out just before the finale
and explain that, after the kids go home,
they'd have the midnight ramble.
- (Scorsese) The midnight...?
- The midnight ramble.
The songs would get a little bit juicier
and the jokes'd get a little funnier.
And the prettiest dancer would really
get down and shake it a few times.
A lot of the rock-and-roll duck walks and
steps and moves came from a lot of that.
Everybody did it and so, when you would
see Elvis Presley or Jerry Lee Lewis
or Chuck Berry or Bo Diddley
really shaking it up,
it didn't come out of nowhere,
lt didn't come out of the air.
lt was like the local entertainment
everybody was going to see.
So when they exposed it
to the rest of the world,
it was like this unknown beast
that had come out,
the grotesque of music
that the devil had sent, you know?
Here we go.
(' ''Caravan'')
' And the caravan is on its way
' l can hear the merry gypsies play
' Mama, Mama, look at Emma Rose
' She's a-playing with the radio
' La la la-la la-la la
' And the caravan
is painted red and white
' That means everybody's
staying overnight
' And the barefoot gypsy boy
round the campfire sing and play
' And a woman tells us of her ways
' La la la-la la-la la
' Da da da-da da
' Turn up your radio
' And let me, let me, let me hear the song
' Switch on your electric light
' Now we can get down
to what's really wrong
' l long just to hold you in my arms
' So that l can, l can feel you
' Sweet lady of the night
' l shall reveal you
' Turn it up
' Little bit higher
' Radio
' Turn it up
' That's enough
' So you know it's got soul
' La la la-la la-la la
' Turn up your radio
' And let me, let me, let me,
let me hear the song
' Switch on your electric light
' Then we can get down to what's
really wrong, really wrong, really wrong
' l long just to hold you in my arms
' So that l can, l can feel you
' Sweet lady of the night
' l shall reveal you
' Turn it up
' Little bit higher
' Radio
' Turn it up
' That's enough
' So you know
' lt's got soul
' So you know it's got
' Soul, baby
' Yeah
' Zi boo ba boogie,
zi boo ba boogie, zi boo ba boogie
' So you know it's got soul
' So you know it's got nothin' but soul
' Turn it up now
' Yeah, yeah, yeah
' One more time
' Do that one more time
' So you know
' One more
' Do that one more time
Thank you.
Hey, Van the Man!
(cheering)
Lawrence Ferlinghetti!
Let us pray.
Our Father, whose art's in heaven
Hollow by thy name -
unless things change.
Thy wigdom come and gone.
Thy will, will be undone
on earth, as it isn't heaven.
Give us this day our daily dread,
at least three times a day.
And forgive us our trespasses
on love's territory.
For thine is the wigdom
and power and glory...
Oh, man!
(cheering)
(' ''Forever Young'')
' May God bless and keep you always
' May your wishes all come true
' May you always do for others
' And let others do for you
' May you build a ladder to the stars
' Climb on every rung
' And may you stay
' Forever young
' May you stay
' May your hands always be busy
' May your feet always be swift
' May you have a strong foundation
when the winds of changes shift
' May your heart always be joyful
' May your song always be sung
' And may you stay
' Forever young
' May you stay
(' ''Baby, Let Me Follow You Down'')
' Can l come home with you?
' Baby, can l come home with you?
' Well, l'll do anything
in this god-almighty world
' lf you'll just let me come home with you
' Baby, let me follow you down
' Well, l'll do anything
in this god-almighty world
' lf you'll just let me follow you down
' l'll buy you a diamond ring
' l'll buy you a wedding gown
' Well, l'll do anything
in this god-almighty world
' lf you'll just let me follow you down
- (cheering)
- Thank you.
We got Ringo and Ronnie Wood
gonna help us out on this one, too.
(' ''l Shall Be Released'')
' They say everything can be replaced
' They say every distance is not near
' So l remember every face
' Of every man who put me here
' l see my light come shining
' From the west down to the east
' Any day now
' l shall be released
' They say every man needs protection
' They say that every man must fall
' But l swear l see my reflection
' Somewhere so high above this wall
' l see my light come shining
' From the west down to the east
' Any day now
' l shall be released
' Down here in this lonely crowd
' There's a man who swears
he's not to blame
' All day long l hear him shouting loud
' Crying out that he been framed
' l see my light come shining
' From the west down to the east
' Any day now
' l shall be released
- Thank you.
- Thank you very much.
(Robertson) The road was our school.
lt gave us a sense of survival.
lt taught us all we know.
There's not much left
that we can really take from the road.
We've had our share of...
Or maybe it's just superstitious.
- (Scorsese) Superstitious in what way?
- (Robertson) You can press your luck.
The road has taken
a lot of the great ones.
Hank Williams. Buddy Holly.
Otis Redding.
Janis. Jimi Hendrix.
Elvis.
lt's a goddamn impossible way of life.
No question about it!
(cheering and clapping)
(' ''Theme from The Last Waltz'')
Thewildbunch22
synchro
tHe.b0dY