- Previously, on
"RuPaul's Drag Race UK."..
- We're holding
a general erection...
- Mmm!
- [gasps]
giving you the chance
to roast
your fellow candidates.
♪ ♪
- I thought the troubles
in Ireland ended
in the '90s, but it's clear
from looking at her face that
they have only just begun.
[laughter]
- I was worried when I
heard Danny was going
to be attending this roast,
but then I remembered
how much I love bacon.
[clears throat]
- [laughs]
- Cheddar Gorgeous is
so old, her first gig
was when I was born.
- Yes.
[laughter]
- Black Peppa.
- You've got it in your
head that you're not funny.
It's one of those
personal roadblocks
that you're going to have
to overcome at some point.
- Pixie Polite,
you are naturally funny,
and I didn't get any of that.
Danny Beard,
you just were so witty.
You took everyone down.
It was like a disaster movie.
No one got out alive.
- Condragulations,
you are the winner
of this week's challenge.
Black Peppa, shantay, you stay.
Pixie Polite, sashay away.
- Goodbye.
[chuckles]
- What an amazing cast.
[cheering]
[all chanting]
Season four!
Season four! Season four!
[dramatic music]
- It's Barry Jerry.
- The look is,
like, 50% of the mark.
- I'm ginger
and fagulous, baby.
- I just will
never be happy.
[laughter]
- No one puts Baby
in a corner.
- Take this umbrella,
and shove it up your ass.
♪ ♪
- I hate musicals.
- Bitch, I broke the curse.
[laughs]
♪ ♪
- My top four queens.
- [roars]
- Black Peppa.
- I have to win this crown.
They better watch out.
- [burps]
- Danny Beard.
- I don't like fighting,
but tonight,
hah, the fight's on, babe.
♪ ♪
- Brr!
- Jonbers Blonde.
- Bring on the final.
I'm feeling ready for battle.
- [laughs]
- Cheddar Gorgeous.
- One of us is going
to be the winner.
Let's do it.
♪ ♪
[all screaming]
- I have just survived
my fourth lip sync
and have secured
a spot in the top four.
Oh!
[screams]
- Final four!
- Ding dong, the witch is dead.
- Is that what she wrote?
- No, that's what I'm saying.
- Oh, and here she is.
- I've sent home a quarter
of the cast, by the way.
Do the math. It's 12 girls,
divide that by 4.
Got 3, see?
You're a fabulous top four,
but Pixie was robbed.
[laughter]
Very rude.
- Very rude.
- Oh, I love her so much.
- Aww.
- Honestly, what her growth
in this competition has been--
next level.
The Pixie I knew nine,
ten weeks ago
is not the Pixie
that has just written
that vile message with
that horrible handwriting
on the wall.
- She's an absolute dreamboat.
It is such a bittersweet
moment because I love Pixie
and as much as I want her
here, I want the top four.
And what a tough way to go.
Peppa, congrats, babe.
- Oh, my God.
I don't know what came over me.
The minute that song
played, I just--
I just fell straight into it.
- Oh, my God.
You literally
splitted into it.
- Literally.
- I--honestly, I--I hope
that no screws are
inside of my body right now.
[laughter]
- You bailed it.
- I deserve to be here.
I fought so hard to get here.
We are the top four.
- Say that again.
- We are the top four!
all: Yeah!
- Not only am I in the final
of "RuPaul's Drag Race UK,"
I am with some of the
most amazing and talented
people I've ever met.
- Should we have
a congratulations
for my fellow four-badge
Manchester Queen, Danny Beard?
- Girls, I am bustin'
my tats off.
- Though you should be.
- I've got four old badges.
That's a lot of metal to take
down to the conversion shop
and this is putting
me in a really good
place going into the finals.
Pinch me, Mary,
I'm I in a dream.
You better watch next week.
I'm doing what it takes.
- But--
all: It's not over yet!
- Ahh!
- Ohh!
- Unlock that door,
'cause there's one last fight.
- Ahh!
Listen, I'm no Carol Vorderman,
but the maths on this are this:
12 queens have become 4,
and there's only 1 winner.
So you go figure out
what needs to happen.
There's only one crown!
- Oh, no.
- Do you like my crown, ladies?
- I'm triggered.
I deserve my place in the final
because I am amazing.
[laughs]
- It's the duel of the horns.
- Ahh!
The crown needs to go on
this head immediately.
[shouting]
- No! Oh!
- Put it on me head.
- She left her dildo.
The only thing that she leaves.
How stiff is this competition?
It's very, very stiff.
- Honestly, doctor, I was
just doing the garden,
and I fell on it.
[laughter]
[upbeat music]
- The winner crowned the
UK's next Drag Race superstar
will receive an all-expenses
paid trip to Hollywood
to create their own digital
series with the producers
of "RuPaul's Drag Race."
Tonight, with Michelle Visage,
Alan Carr and Graham Norton.
- ♪ RuPaul's Drag Race ♪
♪ May the best drag queen
win ♪
♪ Best drag queen win ♪
[upbeat music]
- Yeah!
- [vocalizing]
- Final four!
- This bird, ladies,
had a glow-up.
- Krrrrr!
[laughter]
- It's a new day
in the werk room,
and it's the grand finale.
I'm here! It's real!
Touch me!
- Manchester's slaying.
My God.
- Right?
- Do you know what?
It's about time
we had some
Manchester talent and I,
I'm repping two cities
that don't get on.
And I am uniting them
in my art.
- Is that art? Fart?
- Well, no, not really.
- Art with an F.
[laughter]
- You know what guys?
We are at the point in
the competition where,
let's be honest,
it's gonna come down to how
you're performing this week.
- Yeah.
We're the top four
and we're four different forces
to be reckoned with
and really and truly,
looking around,
everyone has
different strengths,
so it's gonna be
a very interesting pick.
I am ready to give these
judges the shock of their life.
- Well, I feel like we've
all made a bit of an effort.
You've got feathers, you've
put stones on a joke shop suit,
you've got mohair.
I'm...
Pat Butcher.
[laughter]
[siren wailing]
[all screaming]
- Ooh, girl!
Her majesty done
already done had herses.
♪ ♪
My top kitty girls.
- Hi!
- This competition is on fire,
and the realness
just got realer.
So if you wanna
snatch that crown,
you better sissy that walk.
And don't call me mother unless
you say it
like you mean it, Tina.
[car engine roaring]
- Realness--
- That's all Ru songs.
both: "Sissy That Walk."
- Hello, hello, hello.
all: Ah!
♪ ♪
- My top four queens.
all: Hi!
- Condragulations for making
it to the grand finale
of "RuPaul's Drag Race UK."
[all cheering]
Well, this is it.
Your last chance to
show off your charisma,
uniqueness, nerve, and talent.
So for this week's
final maxi challenge,
you'll take turns
stealing the spotlight
as you perform a megamix
of "Drag Race" anthems.
- Ahh!
- Whoo!
- And by "Drag Race" anthems,
I mean, my songs.
[laughter]
- Obviously.
- Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, yes.
I have been waiting
for a challenge
where I can do something
that I am good at
and I can't wait to
light that stage up.
Come on, let's go.
- #DragRaceUK.
[ding]
[laughter]
- Ooh.
- Now is the time
to take total control
of your destiny, darling,
as you write and record
your own lyrics.
And then master the moves of
Choreographer Claudimar Neto.
all: Ooh!
- Now, Black Peppa, your
solo is "Sissy That Walk."
- Ahh!
- Cheddar Gorgeous,
"The Realness."
- Ohh.
It's so ironic
'cause there's
nothing real about me.
[laughter]
- Danny Beard,
your solo
is "Call Me Mother."
- ♪ Na na na na na na ♪
Yes, bitch.
Thanks.
- And Jonbers Blonde,
"Kitty Girl."
- Ahh!
Okay.
[laughter]
- And in between
the hustle and bustle,
you'll each sit down
and spill the tea
with Michelle Visage and me.
- Yay!
- And tomorrow on
the main stage,
we are going to crown
ourselves a winner, baby.
[laughter]
- This is our last moment
to grab the spotlight,
to say, "Look at me.
I want that crown."
Pressure's on.
- Racers,
start your engines
and may the best drag queen
win.
all: Yay!
[upbeat music]
- I've literally
got goosebumps. Ahh!
- Oh, my God.
I'm gonna eat this up.
- You're gonna be great.
- This is gonna be so good.
"Sissy That Walk" is such
a big RuPaul song,
so the fact that I get to have
my bit in, it's so exciting.
- This is gonna be insane.
- But this is, like,
a proper dancing routine.
Like, how are you--how are
you feeling about that?
- Made up, mate.
- [laughs]
This is a great song,
but, my God, it is fast.
If I'm in that rehearsal studio
doing boop, boop, boop, boop,
I'm gonna look a twat.
I'm probably the
shittest dancer,
but I've been pushed
out me comfort zone
in other challenges--
- Yeah.
- And surprised me self.
The only thing
in between me and doing
all right is in there.
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah.
Do you know what?
I'm not great with choreo
but I know--like,
I dance all the time,
like, in clubs and,
like, on nights out,
and, like,
having a fun time.
What are you laughing at?
- No, 'cause it's just funny.
You be like,
"I dance in the club."
Like, we all dance in the club.
- But we do.
- But we can't be like,
♪ Hey, kitty girl ♪
♪ It's your world ♪
- But you dance--like,
you know what I mean?
Like when you're dancing in
a club, and you just relaxed
and you get into a song.
- You let loose.
- The mindset.
- At the club.
- It's just gonna be
about relaxing into it for me.
-Yeah.
- I'm keen to just
see what they're
gonna make us do on this one.
I know this is
gonna be a bigger
challenge than "The Rusical."
- Let us go and
write our lyrics.
- Put the pens of the paper.
- Let's go.
♪ ♪
I already have some
ideas in my head
that I'm willing to
write down on paper,
so I just need to get
this out of my head.
- This is gonna be fresh.
I think Adele probably
will be giving me a call
after this for these lyrics.
I want it to be like--
You know?
- Oh, yeah.
- Hi, hello.
- Look who's here.
- Oh, Danny Beard.
- [laughs]
- Oh, I love that shirt.
- Thank you.
- That jumper.
- The bearded queen has
made it into the top four.
- Wow. Thank you, guys.
- What?
No, you did it.
You're the one who did it.
- That's the magic
of this show.
Like, it's pushed me
and it's exciting me.
- So here you are,
this bearded queen.
What's the story there?
- When I first started,
I was studying club kids.
And what I loved about their
drag is they did it their way.
- Sure.
- And I was like,
"I'm gonna do it my way."
- And now that you have
been wearing wigs and doing
different looks, does that open
your eyes to different ways
of how Danny Beard does drag?
- When I did that ruffles
runway,
I was feeling myself.
[laughter]
I was like--yeah, it's opened
my eyes is the answer--
short answer to the question.
- Right, good.
- I still feel very much me
throughout it, though.
- You have been.
- You know.
- You have confidence.
I think that's what it is.
- Yeah.
- You have a strong sense
of self, of who you are.
- Yeah.
- Where'd you get that?
- [sighs]
When I was younger,
I was really bullied,
and I--I wasn't me.
Like, year eight, I don't
know how old you are,
this guy made, um,
knuckle dusters with pins
and cut my face up.
- [gasps]
- And, um, my mom and dad
moved me from Liverpool
to the whirl
and then my mom sat me down and
said,
"This is a fresh start.
You can be anyone and
anything you wanna be now.'
And I went into that
school in year nine.
And the first kid that said
to me, "Hey, are you gay?"
I went, "Yeah, and what?"
And that was it, like--
- Aww.
- And that's when my
confidence started growing.
Not being afraid
to be flamboyant.
I remember me dad
screaming down the stairs,
"We're going to
a family barbecue.
Why are you orange?"
You know what I mean?
[laughter]
And I was like, "You don't like
me being gay."
And he was like, "No, I
don't like you being orange!"
[laughter]
You know?
- He wanted--you were
okay being gay,
just not orange.
- Yeah!
- And he's a big butch fireman.
- Aww.
- And listen, even in the
"The Roast" last week,
you did well because
you trusted yourself.
And that's because you have
confidence in yourself,
and you have done so well.
- Oh, yeah.
- What would it
mean to you to be
the UK's next drag superstar?
- There's never been--I don't
think a contestant like me,
let alone a winner like me.
I'm a really good
entertainer and I'm a--
I'm a really nice
person, actually,
and that's what a "Drag Race"
winner should be.
- Well, you have been a joy
throughout this competition,
- Thank you.
- And we will see what happens.
- Thank you, guys.
♪ ♪
- Hello!
- Look who's here.
- Darling, where to sit?
- There.
- Jonbers Blonde.
- Hello, darling.
- So you are in the top four.
- I know!
- Are you surprised by that?
- You know what?
I'm a huge believer
in visualization.
And if you visualize it,
you can manifest it.
And I knew I could do it as
long as I trusted in myself.
And I just wanna say a huge
thank you to both of you
for giving me the
opportunity to grow.
- You went for
every single thing.
Everything was listened to,
and you put it all to good use.
Here you are in the final four.
- Absolutely.
- Because you adapted.
- Mm-hmm.
- And that was amazing.
- Thank you so much.
- And that's really
why you're here.
And--and that philosophy will
carry you throughout life.
Now you--you love fashion.
Where'd you get your
sense of style?
- From when I was a kid,
I always loved the '70s.
My mom kept a lot of her
dresses from the '70s
and even though
my mom would always say
she isn't fashionable,
she was always in,
like, a full-length gown,
like, dress to the nines.
My mom is so strong
and so full of love.
- Mm.
- What's your relationship
like with her?
- Oh!
I just--I just
love her so much.
She's so amazing.
She always believed
in me as a kid
and always said, "You can
do whatever you want."
Even though she didn't--
we didn't see eye-to-eye
whenever I came out as gay--
- Mm.
- That didn't stop the love.
It was hard for
a couple of years,
but I always needed to
trust in the process,
and everything would be--
would work out eventually.
- And what would it mean
to you to be crowned
the UK's next drag superstar?
- It would--it would
mean everything to me.
Not a lot of people in my
life have ever believed in me.
It's only--I--I couldn't
even count on one hand
how many people that have.
- Yeah.
- I mean, my group of friends,
before I met them,
I was--
I could--I wouldn't
say voodoo ghost and I wouldn't
like, even fart talk
and--and poo talk
would really scare me.
Now, it's--
now, it's a poo party.
[laughter]
- Well, thank you, Jonbers.
- Thank you so much for this.
To have you believe
in me and to be
able to show what I can do, my
wildest dreams have come true.
And thank you so
much for making
it an amazing experience.
- Well, there's more to come.
- Yes.
Thank you so much.
- Thanks, Jonbers.
- Thank you, loves.
Lots of love.
♪ ♪
- Hey, White Salt.
- [gasps] Yes.
- You'll never guess
who just walked in.
- Oh, hey, Black Peppa.
It's your girl, White Salt.
- Hi! [laughs]
- Look at you up
in the top four.
- Yeah, look at that.
- How does it feel?
- It feels incredible,
and I fought to get here.
[laughter]
- You did.
You did, baby.
- Now, the first time I saw
you, we did a photo session.
- Yes.
- And you did not
stay inside the box.
And I thought, "Wow."
But what has kept
you from working
outside the box in terms
of humor and the acting?
You know what
I'm talking about.
- Absolutely.
It's just that child
in me has always
had that doubt because
my parents being like,
"No, you can't.
You're not allowed to do this.
You can't do that.
You can't do that."
And I feel like I still do
have that little doubt in me
whenever I'm faced
with a challenge.
Like, "Oh, I can't do this."
- And your family
in Saint Martin,
did you have to leave
when you came out?
- On the day when
I was leaving,
my mom had a chat with me.
She was like, "Akeem,
are you gay or not?"
And I was like," Yeah, I am."
She was like, "Have
you slept with boys?"
And I was like," Yes, I have."
Then I couldn't stand up for
myself the way that I am now.
So, took off in the plane that
day and never looked back
and I just felt liberated,
and I could be queer
and I can live my life
the way I wanna live it.
- Do you talk to them?
- We are kind of getting
somewhere now and--
and my sister, she's kept
me and held me together
in times when I
felt like I really
couldn't keep it together.
And I keep remembering, "You
have someone else on earth
that really depends
on you to be strong,
so you cannot let them down."
- Aww.
- Wow.
- She's lucky to have you.
- Well, listen, that same
love you have for her,
you have to care for your inner
child that exact same way.
Life is a dance and
once you connect
to that rhythm, which
you know how to do,
it's smooth sailing.
- What would it mean
to you to be crowned
the UK's next drag superstar?
- It--I've said before, this
competition is bigger than me.
Right now, as we speak,
there's so many
that can't even live
the life that they
want to live because
they can't be themselves.
I can inspire people that
you can come from a position
in your life where
you're not proud of,
but you can take it there
just by believing in yourself.
- I love that.
- Well, I think that this is
just the beginning for you.
I really do.
- Thank you so much.
- Good luck to you, my darling.
- Thank you.
Thank you, Black Peppa.
Paging Dr. Cheddar.
- What?
- Paging Dr. Cheddar.
- I see you've been
in the operating theater.
[laughter]
- Well, this was--
this was the
brutality of the competition
really, wasn't it,
you know what I mean?
- You know, we spent some time
in--in Manchester last year.
We fell in love
with Manchester.
What do you love
about Manchester?
- One of the things I've
always adored about it
is that we've always had
such an amazing range
of drag that happens
there, and we've
got an amazing history there.
Hacienda and all
that sort of stuff.
- Is the Hacienda still there?
- No, the Hacienda is
now an apartment block.
- Oh, really?
Because I'd performed
at the Hacienda many years ago.
- Wow.
- I think during
the Thatcher administration.
[laughter]
- Cheddar, you in
particular, when I saw you,
your name on the roster,
I was like, Cheddar?
In "RuPaul's Drag Race"?
Why now?
- I just got to this very
strange place with drag.
I didn't know whether I even
wanted to be in drag anymore.
- Mm.
- I actually didn't
expect to get a call back,
but when I got a rundown
of what was involved,
I felt excited.
And I haven't felt
excited about drag
for such a long time.
- You've proven you're
fucking phenomenal.
- Thank you.
- We've seen it.
- And that surprised me.
- What surprised you?
- I was surprised I've
done as well as I have.
My inner voice doesn't give
me love and praise very well.
- You don't give yourself
that pat on the back.
Where did you learn
that behavior?
- [sighs] That's growing
up a working-class kid
in Birmingham, I think.
I learned to think not to
raise my head too far up.
- Mustn't grumble,
mustn't grumble.
- Mustn't grumble.
Emotions are for other people.
I come from
a family of helpers.
Very wonderful people
full of their kind of love.
- The challenge is to
learn to parent yourself
in a way that is unapologetic.
Are you able to do that?
- Well, I'll give it a try.
[laughter]
I mean, I certainly do like
the sound of my own voice
sometimes, as you
may have noticed.
- What would it
mean to you to be
the UK's next drag superstar?
- At the risk of
sounding cocky,
regardless of whether I
take that crown or not, um,
I'm gonna do exactly
the same thing,
which is go out there and be
100%--150% totally myself
and keep doing it.
The crown would be added
validation to that.
- Well, thank you so much.
- Thank you so much.
- Thank you.
- Have a lovely day.
- Bye, darling.
- Bye bye.
all: Hello!
- Hello, hello, hello, hello!
My name is Claudimar.
I'll be choreographing the
"Ru Megamix" for this final.
I'm, like, super excited.
We're gonna go in.
Like, you--we're talking
about four iconic tracks.
We are going for gold.
But within saying that,
why not bring
some dancers out for you guys?
Come on out.
This is Brett and Logan.
Oh! Hi!
- Something's
telling me that I'm gonna
enjoy this a little
bit more than I thought.
- So Miss Peppa, we're
about to start with you.
So can anybody else just take
a seat and I'll get to you guys
shortly, right?
Let's get into this.
- Let's get into this.
Anyone who knows me knows that
I always have a show, okay?
She loves a production.
Having dancers to really
bring it together
it's just even better.
- This is quite intricate,
so I want you to take
your time to really understand
every single rhythm.
- Mm-hmm.
- So you're gonna go dum,
ti, ti,
and that's to the hip.
So we go dum,
ti, ti to the hip.
- Doom, ti, ti.
- This is what Peppa does.
- From the top.
And we go dum, ti, ti.
Dum, dum, dum, ti, ti.
- I am at home and
I'm in my element.
I am feeling everything.
Every single move I'm
getting and I'm like,
"This is--this is perfect.
I'm loving this."
- Ti, ti, ti, ca.
That's right, Peppa.
You are done, my lovely.
- Yes!
- Thank you so much.
- Thank you, thank you.
- Cheddar.
- Oh.
Oh, so you already have plans?
- Yeah, we do indeed.
- Oh, my, my.
- Oh, well, well, now I
feel suddenly at home.
I've been given choreo,
that's very sexy.
It's all a little bit sexy.
- And you look at him, and
then do two body ripple there.
Body and body.
There you go.
- Yes.
- Yeah.
- I've never danced
before in my life.
I don't know what you mean.
And, like--and I'm
all right with that.
I like that.
Like, I quite enjoy having
a little bit of a moment
of, you know, sexy dolphin.
Let's try and see if
I got all that in.
- Okay.
- There you go.
The innuendo potentials
when surrounded
by lovely, gorgeous dancers.
- [laughs]
- Thank you so much, Cheddar.
Let's have Danny up.
- You!
- Yes!
- Come and live in your truth.
- Go get 'em, girl.
- Ru says you've gotta be
able to master the moves.
I'm not gonna bow out now.
I'm gonna try me hardest.
- Hey, we go one,
two, we go look.
Look, we go up, down, shoulder,
sling goes shimmy, down, up.
Flick off the shoe.
There you go.
- No, I didn't do any of it.
I just did the end bit
when you turn around.
[laughter]
- Carrying on?
- There's more?
- There's more.
Not that it's too much more.
A little bit.
- I think Claudi baby thinks
I can do more than I can.
- Five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four, five--
- Fuck this.
[sighs]
Just give me a moment,
and let me process this
and I'll come back
with a product.
It's fast. It's fast,
but it's doable
'cause we've--we've done it and
I know you'll be able to do it.
I know that.
- You're fucking dancers.
[laughter]
- No, trust me,
I can get you to do it.
I guarantee you that.
- Thank you.
- Yeah?
Thank you, Danny.
- Jonbers,
you've got this right?
- Yeah!
What I'm not gonna do
is freak out.
I am going to breath,
I'm going to remember
what happened in
"Girl Group," and I'm not
gonna let that happen.
- Here we go.
One, two, three, shot,
look, ga, ga, ga.
And really sell that.
Dum, dum.
- I can dance.
I actually can dance.
Takes me a while,
but I can get there.
- One, two, and
three and four and--
- Sorry. Right.
- It's okay.
Just remember this--that
is going to the left.
- Oh, what am I doing?
- You're going to the right.
- I'm going to the--ahh!
So, uh--
- So sit on the left and you
wanna come up to go left.
There you go.
- No. [laughs]
What am I, like--
- You got it down.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'll get it. No, I'm--
I'm confident that I'll get it.
I am going to be the
best version of myself.
Get ready for my
redemption story, kids.
- I know it was a lot
that I've given you.
We're talking about a megamix.
There was no point of just
coming in and going, "Ooh."
We weren't
never gonna do that, okay?
But we are gonna make sure
that you have it down
and I know that you are gonna
look absolutely amazing.
- It is the big day
of big days tomorrow.
We better be ready.
♪ ♪
[upbeat music]
- Yes!
- Whoo-hoo!
[both shouting]
- Yes!
- It's the finals!
Ahh!
Someone's gonna
be crowned today.
Someone's gonna get that
crown and that scepter.
That's actually crazy.
- I am cream crack again.
- Over slay--yeah.
- I have to say I find it
tricky at first,
but I feel--I feel good now.
Now that it's
rehearsed and we've
done it a good few times,
I feel relaxed into it.
I've got this, kids.
I'm finally gonna show RUPAUL
that I can dance
and five, six, seven, eight.
- Girl, I can barely
speak English,
and now I can speak dancer.
[laughter]
Boom, black, boom,
whack-a-da-whack boom, boom.
The stench of competition
in the werk room
is stronger than one of my
farts
and they can be strong.
- So one of us
will be the winner.
- Will it be a first
ever no-badge winner?
- Nope.
- No.
[laughter]
- I might not have a badge,
but I've got gumption
and I've got
a catsuit to die for.
- Here we go, Kitty girls!
all: Let's go!
[screaming]
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
- Girls, has
anybody's experience
been anything different than
they thought it was gonna be?
- It was a lot harder than
I thought it would be.
- Yeah.
- Like, it's an intense
experience,
and not just the drag.
I feel like it's the
endurance you need for it.
- It's almost like a race.
- Yeah.
- Imagine that!
- Imagine that.
[laughter]
- Even though, yes,
it's been a pressure pot,
and at some points
it's boiling...
- Yeah.
- But I've just loved
every second of it.
It's just been so fun!
I wanted to come here to
prove that I could do it
to myself and to everybody
else that never believed in me,
or they said I'd never
make my dreams come true.
Ha!
- I know we joke about, you
know, having badges and stuff,
but you do deserve
to be here just as much
as the next--
- Thank you so much.
- Because you're you.
There's not another you.
- Yeah.
- And you've proved
time and time
that this is your stage.
- That's so nice.
Thank you so much.
- Do you know what I mean?
both: I love you.
- We're gonna smash tonight.
- What's that on my face?
- Oh, shit,
have you got ear!
- Ahh!
DANNY: Oh, fuck. Sorry.
- I'll join the clown--
I'll join the circus.
[laughter]
- What do you think
you've learned, Cheds?
- I'm learning how
to be more me again.
It's been a really
transformative experience.
It's reminded me of some stuff
that I'd forgotten I could do.
It has showed me some things
that I didn't know I could do,
and it's taught me some
things that I had no idea
I'd ever be able to do.
- I hope when you
watch this back,
you realize how
amazing you've done.
- Yeah.
- You've done amazing.
- You've done so
incredible, babe.
Like, you've really just
blown this whole situation
outta the park.
- I just--I just wanna do--
I wanna do my family proud,
and I wanna do--
- Well, you will, and you have.
- Definitely.
- I wanna feel like
I've put something here
that's meant to be here.
- Well, babe,
you absolutely have.
- My highlight for you,
Danny, is Caty man.
When Alan brought out that
laser pen and you just
went--and he said," What
would I do if I just put this
laser on the [babbles]?"
[laughter]
- Oh, it was just genius.
- Do you know what?
And I equally loved
your bird woman, love.
- Oh, thanks.
Ca-caw! Coo!
Cleh!
[coughs]
- I think that was your
real moment that you said...
- Yeah.
- I'm here and I'm not
going nowhere, bitch.
Do you know what I do think
will go down in history?
Your Lil Nas X, bitch.
[laughter]
- No, I think--I know it's
not funny, laugh anyway.
[laughter]
- Just laugh.
- That was comedy genius.
- Yeah.
- The moments I
have loved of yours
are probably the
ones that you like the least
in that I have enjoyed seeing
you survive, pull it out.
But in addition to that,
the way you walk a runway--
- Oh, yes.
- It's amazing.
- Wow, thank you.
I am living proof that you
can accomplish anything
you wanna accomplish in life,
and if you put up
a good fight, honey, you'll be
here in the finale, okay?
So don't ever doubt yourself.
Don't ever for one second think
you can't do what you can do.
I've learned that, you
know, coming on the show,
make sure you wear things
that you can lip sync in.
[laughter]
- Cheddar, I loved Rachelle.
both: La Cockroach!
Oui, oui, oui.
- [purrs]
- Moi Cherie, surely
it is good to be
a little dirty sometimes, no?
[laughs]
- Every time I look
at your station,
I see those cockroaches.
I'm just like, "What?"
- I'm keeping them.
They're my children now.
They're all my children.
- How about our Linda?
How's our Linda doing?
Linda the cockroach.
- Linda.
Oh, my God.
What happened to Linda?
God!
- Oh, sorry. I stood on her.
[laughter]
- I know that we've all done
had moments where we've gone,
I can't really do that.
And you know what?
We can.
- Yeah.
- We can.
Even if we do it badly,
we can still do it, right?
There is no such thing
as "I can't" anymore.
- Mm-hmm.
- Just, "I can badly."
- Just "I can badly."
[laughter]
[intense music]
- I know my moves,
I know my lyrics.
I'm ready.
♪ ♪
- I think it's anybody's
game right now.
It's anybody's game.
- I am ready to show
the judges why I should be
UK's next drag superstar.
I am ready to put a show on.
♪ ♪
- This hairy potato is gonna
look sweet with a crown on it.
[RuPaul's "Cover Girl"]
♪ ♪
[laughter]
- ♪ Cover girl, put
some bass in your walk ♪
♪ Head to toe,
let your whole body talk ♪
[applause]
And what?
- Welcome to the grand finale
of "RuPaul's Drag Race UK."
Tonight, the whole
family is together.
She's one red hot mama,
Michelle Visage.
- Hey, sis!
Thank you for such
an incredible,
another unbelievable season.
- National treasure,
Graham Norton.
- Ru, I love our
top four queens.
- Well, we love you, darling.
- Ohh, I bet you say that to
all the national treasures.
- No, just you and
Dame Shirley Bassey.
[laughter]
And the super specsy,
Alan Carr.
- I can't wait to see
how this turns out.
[laughter]
- You know, that would
make a really great meme.
- Wouldn't it just?
- So stupid.
- [laughs]
This week, we challenged
our final four
to take star turns performing
a new "Drag Race UK" megamix.
And tonight on the runway,
category is
Grand Finale Eleganza.
Racers, start your engines,
and may the best drag queen
win.
They're here to make
herstory performing
the "UK Grand Finale Megamix."
It's Black Peppa,
Cheddar Gorgeous,
Danny Beard, Jonbers Blonde,
and the queens of season four.
- Queens have been
cited stomping the runway.
Suspects are known
to be dangerously
fierce and sickening.
Calling on all civilians
to return to safety.
This is not a test.
♪ ♪
♪ In the disco heat ♪
♪ Real is what you feel ♪
♪ ♪
♪ The disco ♪
♪ Uh-oh,
now sissy that walk ♪
- ♪ Start this track off, DJ ♪
♪ Black Peppa's in the house
watch this ♪
♪ Let's go let's start this up
check it out watch this ♪
♪ A bad gal rhythm with
a Caribbean twist ♪
♪ Lip sync assassin
since I walked in ♪
♪ Softly spoken
but my body did the talking ♪
♪ Iconic runway
watch me strut ♪
♪ Tumbled many times
but I got back up ♪
- Whoo!
- ♪ Latex, baby ♪
♪ Taste this leather ♪
♪ Everybody's salty
but I'm just Peppa ♪
- ♪ And if I fly
or if I fall ♪
♪ Least I can say,
I gave it all ♪
♪ Fly, fly, fly, fly, uh-oh ♪
♪ Uh-oh
fly, fly, fly, fly ♪
♪ Uh-oh, now sissy that walk ♪
♪ ♪
- [laughs]
- It's me, Cheddar Gorgeous.
OG queen of versatility.
[purrs]
♪ Take me to your leader
I got some things to say ♪
♪ I've been down to
change the world ♪
♪ And things
won't be the same ♪
♪ Leave your doubt behind you ♪
♪ Believe you can be more ♪
♪ Learn to love the alien ♪
♪ Throw the rule book ♪
out the door ♪
♪ The realness,
the, the realness ♪
♪ Catch it, touch it,
touch it, catch it ♪
♪ Flavor of this fever ♪
♪ The realness,
the, the realness ♪
♪ Catch it, touch it,
touch it, catch it ♪
♪ Flavor of this fever ♪
♪ The realness ♪
♪ The, the realness ♪
♪ Catch it, touch it,
touch it, catch it ♪
♪ Flavor of this fever ♪
♪ The realness
the, the realness.
♪ Catch it, touch it,
touch it, catch it ♪
♪ Flavor of this fever ♪
♪ The realness ♪
- How we feelin'?
Let's go!
♪ Look at me girl,
I'm phenomenal ♪
♪ I'll cramp your style
and abdominals ♪
♪ Got you laughing so hard
over all these hoes ♪
♪ These queens going down
like dominoes ♪
♪ The Beard is here,
here to stay ♪
♪ Born to fly
and not for show ♪
♪ Just bring coffee
I'm here to slay ♪
♪ But I don't come cheap
so you gotta pay ♪
♪ I been that bitch,
yes, I love that drama ♪
♪ Flashy feminine
up-and-comer ♪
♪ From the Clintons
to the Obamas ♪
♪ I keep it tight,
now they call ♪
♪ Me ♪
♪ Mother, mother, mother ♪
♪ What, what, what, what,
what, what, what ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
♪ Brrat-at-at ♪
♪ Na, not now
giggity, giggity hop ♪
♪ Brrack get back, back, back ♪
♪ Bow, bow,
honey, honey, honey, honey ♪
♪ Count my money,
count my money with it ♪
♪ Big to the knick
the nick knacker ♪
♪ With the freaky money
click clack, ow ♪
[laughter]
- JB 's in the house y'all!
♪ Strut to the beat
come pose with me ♪
♪ This bird is flying high
shouting, cooey ♪
♪ People say blondes
have more fun ♪
♪ So bleach it up
make it fashion, hon ♪
♪ Watch for signs from the
universe we're on the BBC ♪
♪ Please don't curse ♪
♪ If I haven't already
then let me say ♪
♪ I'm Northern Irish, babe,
it's you're lucky gay ♪
- ♪ Hey kitty girl ♪
♪ It's your world ♪
♪ When you walk the street
steppin' to the beat ♪
♪ Hey, kitty girl
get your twirl ♪
♪ In the disco heat ♪
♪ You're the
boogie-body-rockin' queen ♪
♪ Boogie-body-rockin' queen ♪
♪ Pop, pop
boogie-body queen ♪
♪ Boogie queen,
boo, boo, boo, boo, queen ♪
♪ Boogie-body-rockin' queen ♪
♪ Hey, kitty girl
boogie-body-rockin' queen ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Boogie queen
boogie-body-rockin'♪
♪ Boogie-body-rockin'
boogie-body-rockin' queen ♪
- Whoo-hoo-hoo!
- Here we go, girls!
all: ♪ Hey hey hey ♪
♪ Kitty kitty
hey, ki-kitty kitty ♪
♪ Hey, kitty kitty girl ♪
♪ Girl, oh, girl
ohh, ohh, oh, kitty, kitty ♪
♪ Hey, ki-kitty kitty ♪
♪ Hey kitty, kitty girl ♪
♪ Hey hey, kitty girl ♪
[cheers and applause]
[laughter]
- Whoo!
- The "UK Grand Finale Megamix"
is available right now
to stream and download.
Portion of the proceeds will
be split equally between
Comic Relief
and Children in Need.
♪ Can you feel the love? ♪
Category is
Grand Finale Elaganza.
Up first, Black Peppa.
Hell must be missing an angel.
- [laughs]
- Instead of going for
the typical pretty gown--
because I could have, honey--
I decided to give
you upcycled look
that is quintessentially me
and a touch of "Drag Race."
- Honey, she is crackin'
that Black Peppa.
[laughter]
- Tonight, I feel like I am
Black Peppa in her full form.
I feel beautiful,
I feel elegant,
and I just feel like a winner.
- Burning rubber
down the runway.
- I hope she's unleaded.
[laughter]
- Cheddar Gorgeous.
- A mensa with a pensa.
[laughter]
- I am serving a H.R. Geiger-
inspired fantasy,
bringing amazing alien deity
energy to the runway.
- There's a fisting
accident waiting to happen.
[laughter]
- I am doing what I know best.
I am being my true
sci-fi inspirational
spectacular divaness.
- Ru, you remember
Paula Abdul's "Vibeology"?
- Yeah.
- This is Cheddar's
follow-up, "Entomology."
- [laughs]
- We got there.
[laughter]
- Yes, we did.
- Listen, babe,
you gotta try.
[laughter]
- Up next,
o, Danny Beard.
- What? This gold thing.
- [laughs]
- I'm playing homage
to Liverpool.
I'm a lively liver bird,
a phoenix rising from
the ashes.
Ethereal, stunning, body, gold.
- That's what I
call a flock destroyer.
- [laughs]
- RuPaul's got her
eyes all over me.
I, let me tell you,
am uncomfortable as fuck,
but I look gorgeous, so you
better gimme that crown.
- Get the flock outta here.
[laughter]
- Jonbers Blonde.
- That's what I
call a goldfinger.
- This look is my drag and
fashion dreams all come true.
I am giving
Schiaparelli realness.
I am giving Celtic Warrior--
where my dragons at?
- Fetch me some gruel,
fair maiden.
[laughter]
- This look is very inspired
by "Lord of the Rings,"
"Game of Thrones," and the
battle for the crown is on.
- Do you think that ring
is too big for her hand?
- No, if you liked it,
then you should've
put a shield on it.
[laughter]
- ♪ Can you feel the love? ♪
Welcome, my top four queens.
Tonight, we salute the power,
passion, and perseverance
that brought you here,
and on a personal note,
I just want to
applaud each of you.
You should be very
proud of yourselves.
I am so proud of each
and every one of you.
And now it's time for
your final critiques.
First up, Black Peppa.
- Hey, Black Peppa,
it's your girl, White Salt.
[laughter]
You know, watching
you in this competition
has been such a joy and as
you stand before me right now,
you just look evolved.
I thought the performance
was dynamic tonight.
I thought you
killed it out there.
- You were a dancer.
That dancing was off the chart.
From the beginning,
I loved your looks.
You present them
fantastically.
You have such a kind of
sense of your own body.
- You just pair these
amazing things together.
Leather, feathers,
feminine, masculine.
I just absolutely love it.
- Well, Black Peppa,
your story is so amazing,
and your courage
and perseverance is
really one for the storybooks.
- You have fought for
your place to be here.
Every time we thought
well, this might be it.
You were like,
"Hell, no not tonight."
There's nothing
you can't overcome
because look where you are.
- Can I be honest with you?
I know you were
heartbroken when you were
in the bottom two, but I used
to go, yes, 'cause I'm gonna
get an amazing performance.
[laughter]
- This experience here
has just been phenomenal.
Today, I just felt like
I could do anything
and I'm so happy that you
saw that on the stage.
I just felt electrified.
- Fantastic.
♪ ♪
Up next, Cheddar Gorgeous.
- Cheddar, I know
this may sound cheesy...
[laughter]
but for me, seeing you
in this vulnerable state--
being judged, being critiqued--
makes me look at you
in a different perspective.
And it's been refreshing
to see your journey
and your looks has
been unbelievable.
And tonight's is
quintessentially Cheddar,
quintessentially drag,
but beautiful.
- You've surprised me
because you have kept raising
your game, and yet you've
managed to stay true to both
the challenges and yourself.
And tonight, in the
challenge, you were sexy.
You know, we saw
some Cheddar crack.
[laughter]
- I think I saw
a Dairylea triangle.
[laughter]
Every week, you've just given
us something interesting.
It's weird, and it's crazy,
and it's avant garde,
but you let us in and
it's always accessible.
I love this look.
- It's so you.
You look gorgeous.
You're a pro, and I've
witnessed you navigate
not only the weekly
challenges but the challenges
in opening yourself up.
- I've done things I definitely
thought I'd never be doing
in drag, and I have
loved that freedom
and know that if I can do
those here in this environment.
I know I can do
anything in the world,
and it has been transformative.
- Thank you, Cheddar.
Up next, oh, Danny Beard.
- You have been so fun.
You are so filled with
personality and life,
and it's been so great to
see you accept who you are.
That performance was so fun.
When you did the fast-talking
in "Call Me Mother,"
that was great.
- Only you could rhyme
abdominals with phenomenal.
[laughter]
I didn't know all these
different facets to you.
We've been on a few bills
together doing things,
but I'm not here to talk about
my extensive charity work.
[laughter]
And I'm so pleased I just sat
here and watched you evolve.
- My God, you are funny--
- Thank you.
- I mean, in all
the comedy challenges,
you--oh, don't cry now.
- I know. Fuck's sake.
- [fake sobbing]
I'm funny.
[laughter]
- Thank you.
- What I didn't expect were
the looks and the beauty.
Absolute beauty.
- I envy this hair.
I mean, the hair
goes into the makeup.
It's pretty genius.
And I think that you
really are a genius.
- Thank you.
- When you're on stage,
eyes are drawn to you,
and that's something
you can't learn.
That's just something
you know how to use.
- I am so proud of
your journey here.
I know you get emotional.
- Oh, God, you're
all making me cry.
This is everything to me,
so I think this is why
I'm so emotional about it.
Like, my whole life
is drag, you know?
♪ ♪
Thanks.
- Thank you.
Up next, supermodel
Jonbers Blonde.
- Jonbers, you're like the
Pokémon of this competition.
Constantly evolving and
every week you are always
willing to not just listen,
but to apply
and you're gonna
continue to grow.
I know you will
because you're that bitch,
and it's so impressive.
- I think when people
struggle at the beginning.
Most people are
defeated by that.
That isn't what
happened to you.
- You're clearly a fighter,
and that's why I think
this look just sums you up.
I love it.
Joan of Arc with a toffy penny.
Love it.
[laughter]
- You look so beautiful.
- Thank you.
- This is the prettiest
you've looked in my eyes
for the whole competition.
- You have done
something to your face
that has opened it up.
It looks so good.
And I think probably your
eye for fashion, your eye
as a stylist has allowed
you to look for the bits
that everyone else
may have missed.
The performance was beautiful.
- You killed
that choreography.
You had such great energy.
I was like, "Oh, I didn't
know Jonbers had all that."
- Who knew you could
dance like that?
You knew you could
dance like that.
- Yes.
- I knew if I just
persisted with it,
I would get it and not to get
defeated because that's what
I'd done with the girl
group and I thought,
I'm not going back there.
I'm going forward.
I had the best time
on that stage today.
It was just electric.
- Thank you so much, Jonbers.
- Thank you so much.
- Ladies, a lot of young,
sweet, sensitive souls
watch this show.
Looking for clues as to how to
navigate their lives.
With them in mind I wanna
ask Black Peppa,
what advice would you give
to six-year-old Akeem?
- It's so hard to
watch that photo.
I remember taking this
picture, and I remember
being so unhappy that
I couldn't play outside
with other kids,
and I just always
was in this strict upbringing
that I just couldn't be free.
And the things that people said
to me that they probably don't
remember, it hurt me so much,
and I forgive them because I
had to move on with my life.
And I just wanna tell him
that you are amazing.
You have everything
inside yourself
to take you far in life,
and you're gonna have to make
sure that you do not give up.
No matter how hard things get,
you're gonna
be able to get out of
that island where you're from,
and you're gonna be able
to finally be free one day,
and you're gonna finally
understand why you feel
the way that you feel because
everything that you feel,
nothing's wrong with you.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
Cheddar Gorgeous,
what advice would you give
[crying]
to five-year-old Michael?
- Oh.
- From as early
as I can remember,
I always felt like a grown-up.
I don't know why you felt that
you had to grow up so fast.
But you are not as old,
and you are not as wise
as you like to think you are.
Be young, especially
when you grow up.
And just know that you
are surrounded by love,
and you're gonna be
surrounded by more love
than you possibly know,
and more love than you
could possibly accept.
You deserve it.
- You know, I don't know why,
but kids with glasses
always get me.
- [laughs]
- Oh, my God.
Danny Beard,
what advice would you give
to five-year-old Daniel?
- Ohh.
- Oh, God, don't let your
mom cut your hair, love.
[laughter]
You're gonna go through shit.
Everyone's gonna say--
ask you if you're a girl.
You're gonna go
through a moment
where you think
the bullies made you gay.
♪ ♪
You're gonna doubt yourself,
and then you're gonna have
big dreams
and you're gonna get
knocked back loads of times.
But keep going, because when
you keep going and you try,
you really will succeed.
♪ ♪
And listen to your dad when he
says you really look orange.
[laughter]
Because one day you're
gonna--gonna get to meet too
many amazing likeminded people,
and it's just gonna
be magical,
so to keep going.
I dunno if I'm laughing
or crying right now.
[laughter]
- Thank you.
- Jonbers Blonde,
what advice would you give
to two-year-old Andrew?
- Ah!
You're gonna go through a
lot and people are gonna laugh
at you for having--
for big dreams
and they're gonna
call you delusional
and you are delusional.
[laughter]
But just trust that even though
you think nobody likes you,
you will find
people that love you
and never stop fighting
and love your parents
a bit more
cause they're the
best things ever.
And just know that
you're amazing
even though that a lot
of people don't tell you
you are until you get
to repost Drag Race.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, ladies.
While you untuck
in the werk room,
the judges and I
will deliberate.
You may leave the stage.
all: Thank you.
[upbeat music]
- Oh, my God!
[all cheering]
- Hello!
- Yes!
- Wow, I thought I could
smell cheap perfume
from outside the werk room,
and look who's in here.
Only the winners of
"RuPaul's Drag Race UK."
- Yous look phenomenal.
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
- You guys look like
you've just fought in a battle.
I love it.
both: Yeah.
- We have, it's
called season four.
- I'm leading the battle.
- Yeah.
- I'm here, and I'm looking
at Krystal Versace,
Lawrence Chaney,
and The Vivienne,
and oh, my God, what royalty.
- First of all,
congratulations,
you've made it to the final!
[all cheering]
- Now, obviously, we are dying
to know
has it been amazing?
- It's been--it's been, like,
a literal dream come true.
As a fan of the show, it's just
been everything that I thought
and even more,
it's just been so fun.
Obviously, it's fuckin' tough.
[laughter]
- She's not a finalist,
by the way.
She's just paid
for meet and greet.
[laughter]
- I do promise you though,
even though
yous are knackered, it is worth
it if you win.
Even being in the final.
But looks better winning.
[laughter]
- The three winners
of this show
have gone on to do so much.
So to sit beside them
would mean so much
and what could be next?
- And do you know what?
It's so amazing
sitting here looking at four
such diverse queens, the best
piece of advice I could give
is don't get complacent now.
You have got the most amazing
future ahead of yous,
doing things you've
never dreamed of doing.
Whoever wins, the hard
work starts the minute
you leave "Drag Race."
- It is all about that
life after "Drag Race."
It's how you talk to your fans.
Never be disrespectful
to the people that are
literally paying your rent.
You know, we are living the
dream of people liking us.
How amazing is it?
People like us.
It's insane.
And just know that, you know,
you're fabulous,
but you're not Beyoncé.
You know, try and--
- I think I'm Beyoncé.
[laughter]
- Keep your shoes.
- Not Lil Nas X,
though, darling.
- Just you.
[laughter]
- I would also say, like,
for me personally,
I only just realized
that the pressure
wasn't coming from everyone
else, it was coming from me.
So just remember, like,
don't look at anyone else.
Follow your heart,
and this is the key
to do whatever you want.
- Are you ready
to crown the next?
- No.
[laughter]
- It's been long.
- My crown is at home
fully locked away,
no one's getting near it.
- Sod the crown, I'll have the
scepter, thank you very much.
Think of all the
amazing things you
could do with that scepter.
You could use it as a stick
to beat your friends politely.
You could use it for an
exceedingly, fabulously
camp game of cricket.
The possibilities are endless.
- Whatever happens, tonight
well done, all of you.
- Cheers.
- Congratulations.
- Cheers, ladies.
- Cheers, baby.
- No matter what
happens when we walk out
back that main stage,
I'm proud of us all,
and I'm super proud of me.
- To the new winner of
"Drag Race UK," cheers!
[all shouting]
all: Cheers!
- Whoo!
- Yay!
- Now, just between us girl
friends, what do you think?
Who should be crowned
the UK's next
"Drag Race" superstar?
Let's start with Black Peppa.
- She arrived here and
just took my breath away
and tonight back with a bang.
That was the performance
you give in a finale.
- That kid can perform.
The dancing, the look,
all of it, the body.
She was serving it.
- There was fire there,
there was fierceness,
and yet, she smiles
and after hearing
just a snippet
of her backstory,
she's here in the final,
that's amazing.
- She has persevered.
She's a fierce queen,
and she's earned her spot.
- She is a star.
- Will Black Pepper and
White Salt be going on tour?
- Yes, it's the reunion
of Salt-N-Pepa.
[laughter]
- The condiment sisters.
- Let's talk
about Cheddar.
- There's something very
refreshing about a queen
who knows who she is,
what she does, and what
she can deliver really great.
- In the beginning, I thought
I might get bored of
perfection,
but somehow, I didn't.
'Cause there was always a
twist in it, a quirk in it,
something to get
your teeth into.
- She's intelligent,
and most importantly,
she's, like, provocative
and sometimes
it provokes you to think.
- Looks-wise, I'm not sure
she faltered ever,
and tonight, I mean,
this look was dynamic.
- Not a centimeter of
it was unthought about.
- I'm sure there's
influences there
that I'm not clever
enough to get,
but she always has a message,
and it is always detailed
within an inch of its life.
- She is a real pro.
She has incredible.
- All right, let's
talk about Danny Beard.
- Tonight, in the
performance, you could
tell how proud Danny was.
Not only can Danny
turn a look,
Danny was also pushing himself.
He went for it and it
has been so much fun.
- That's the queen
I'm queuing up in the rain
to go and see--an entertainer,
a proper entertainer.
- He never disappointed
in any of the challenges.
And you know what?
He makes it look easy.
To be spontaneous like that,
it takes me weeks.
[laughter]
- The talent is there,
but also not afraid
to show the emotions,
which gives us
a fully-rounded human being.
- I would watch Danny
perform the phone book.
- If you can find a phone book.
- Do they even exist anymore?
- I don't know.
- I don't even think so.
[laughter]
- What's a phone?
- Exactly.
- All right, let's
talk about Jonbers Blonde.
- She has come
on such a journey
and tonight was a spectacular
night for Jonbers.
She came out here in
that incredible catsuit,
killed it with
the choreography,
and then that outfit tonight,
look how pretty she looked!
Like, who is this girl?
- I wish I could travel back
in time ten weeks and put a bet
on Jonbers being in the final,
'cause it would've been
about a hundred to one.
- Yeah.
- It was amazing to
see how far she's come,
and I think that's all happened
here in front of our eyes,
and what a joy.
- I don't think
in recent history,
I can remember
a queen who's been
able to apply these
critiques as well as she has.
- To me, she's a bit
like a wind turbine,
you know what I mean?
You can use that wind
and use it for good
and that's what
she did, it's true.
- Silence, I've
made my decision.
Bring back my girls.
People of the United Kingdom,
all hail your Crowned Queens.
From season one, The Vivienne.
♪ I'm a winner,
I'm a winner, baby ♪
Gorgeous.
♪ I'm a winner,
I'm a winner, baby ♪
- From season two,
Lawrence Chaney.
♪ I'm a winner,
I'm a winner, baby ♪
- Fuckin' bing, bang, boom.
[laughter]
- ♪ I'm a winner, baby ♪
♪ Don't give up ♪
Fabulous!
And from season three,
our reigning queen,
Krystal Versace.
♪ I'm a winner,
I'm a winner, baby ♪
Wow!
♪ I'm a winner,
I'm a winner, baby ♪
- And now welcome back
to the main stage
season four royalty, Just May.
♪ Bring back my girls ♪
♪ Bring back
my girls ♪
♪ Bring back my girls ♪
Starlet.
♪ Bring back my,
bring back my girls ♪
♪ Where they at?
Bring back, my girls ♪
♪ Get 'em back
bring back, my girls ♪
Copper Topp.
♪ Bring back my ladies,
bring back my girls ♪
♪ Bring back my,
bring back my ♪
♪ Bring back my ♪
- Sminty Drop.
♪ Bring back my
bring back my girls ♪
bring back my, bring back my ♪
♪ Bring back my, bring back my,
bring back my ♪
♪ Bring back my
bring back my girls♪
Le Fil.
♪ Bring back my girls ♪
♪ Bring back
my girls ♪
Dakota Schiffer.
♪ Bring back my ♪
♪ Bring back my girls ♪
♪ Where they at? Bring back my
girls, get 'em back ♪
♪ Bring back my girls
come on ♪
Pixie Polite.
♪ Bring back my girls ♪
♪ Bring back my, bring
back my, bring back my ♪
♪ Bring back my,
bring back my ♪
And finally, our top
four queens, Black Peppa.
♪ Bring back my, bring
back my, bring back my ♪
♪ Bring back my, bring back
my, bring back my girls ♪
Jonbers Blonde
♪ Bring back my ♪
♪ Bring back my,
bring back my ♪
♪ Bring back my, bring back
my, bring back my ♪
Cheddar Gorgeous.
♪ Bring back my girls, girls ♪
♪ Bring back my girls ♪
And Danny Beard.
♪ Bring back my girls,
bring back my girls ♪
♪ Bring back my girls ♪
♪ Bring back my ladies,
bring back my girls ♪
It's some queens
in this house.
♪ Bring back my girls ♪
Welcome back, ladies.
Based on your performances
this week
and throughout the competition,
I've made some decisions.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
Danny Beard,
Cheddar Gorgeous...
codragulations, you are the top
two queens of the season.
[exciting music]
[cheers and applause]
- Well done, Cheds.
Well done, girl, we did it.
- We did.
- It's really amazing that's
standing up there
with me is Danny,
Regardless
of what happens now,
either me or my friend
takes this home.
- Thank you.
- Jonbers Blonde, Black Peppa,
I'm sorry, my dears,
but this is not your time.
Thank you both for making
this a truly sickening season.
You may join the other girls.
both: Thank you so much.
- For everything.
Thank you, thank you.
I love you all.
I love you.
- I love you so much.
Well done, love.
Well done.
It should have been me!
[laughter]
♪ ♪
- I have so much
admiration for Cheddar
and I couldn't think of
anyone better to be in the top
of the competition with.
- The winner of "RuPaul's
Drag Race UK" will receive
a spectacular crown
and scepter, courtesy of Fierce
Drag Jeweles
plus an all-expenses paid trip
to Hollywood
to create and star in
your own series
with the producers
of "RuPaul's Drag Race."
Two queens stand
before me.
I've consulted with the judges,
but the final decision
is mine to make.
Prior to tonight, you were
asked to prepare a lip sync
performance of
"This is My life"
by the iconic
Dame Shirley Bassey.
Ladies, this is
your last chance
to impress me
and prove to the world
that you are the UK's next
"Drag Race" superstar.
♪ ♪
The time has come for you
to lip-synch
for the crown!
♪ ♪
- This is it.
It is time to leave all
of it out on the stage
and go for that crown.
- The fight's on, mate.
I'm ready to throw everything
at this and the kitchen sink.
I'm gonna show
RuPaul why I should
be a winner for the show.
♪ ♪
- Good luck...
and don't fuck it up.
♪ ♪
- ♪ Funny how a lonely day ♪
♪ Can make a person say
what good is my life? ♪
- ♪ Funny how a breaking heart
can make me start ♪
♪ To say,
what good is my life? ♪
♪ Till I look around and
see this great big world ♪
♪ Is part of me ♪
♪ And my life ♪
♪ This is my life
today, tomorrow ♪
♪ Love will come
and find me ♪
♪ But that's the way
that I was born to be ♪
♪ Let me live, let me live ♪
- ♪ Sometimes
when I feel afraid ♪
♪ I think of what mess
I've made of my life ♪
- ♪ I was put on earth to be ♪
♪ A part of this great world
is me and my life ♪
♪ Guess I'll just
add up the score ♪
♪ And count the things
I'm grateful for ♪
♪ In my life ♪
♪ This Is my life ♪
♪ And I don't give
a damn for lost emotions ♪
[cheering]
♪ I've such a lot of love
I've got to give ♪
♪ Let me live, let me live ♪
♪ This is my life ♪
♪ This is
♪ My life ♪
[cheers and applause]
- Amazing.
- Ladies,
I've made my decision.
[tense music]
The time has come
to crown our queen.
♪ ♪
The U.K.'s next "Drag Race"
superstar is...
- Danny Beard.
[cheers and applause]
♪ ♪
- Whoo.
- Condragulations.
Is there anything you'd
like to say, my queen?
- Yeah, love, have you
got the receipt for this?
[laughter]
Jokes aside, honestly, thank
you for believing in me.
I've had the wildest
dream here meeting
the most amazing people.
I never thought
anyone who did drag
like me would be a Ru girl,
so this is for all them kids
out there that are different.
Thank you.
- I love it.
Now prance, my Queen, prance.
[cheers and applause]
♪ ♪
- Yes, bitches!
[cheering]
I can't believe
I am the winner.
I just can't wait to let
the world know exactly
what Danny Beard is all about.
Honestly, I made up.
- Condragulations
and remember,
if you can't love yourself,
how the hell
you gonna love
somebody else?
Can I get an amen up in here?
all: Amen!
- Now, let the music play.
♪ To, to, to the Moon ♪
♪ To the Moon, baby ♪
♪ To the Moon ♪
♪ Come on and take me away ♪
♪ To, to, to,
to the Moon ♪