- going to Le Havre?
- Yeah. get in.
Thanks.
Tired?
Yes.
Are you on Ieave?
You're not very taIkative.
No, not very.
Cigarette?
Yes.
Thanks.
We're here.
- What?
- Le Havre.
Ah, yes. Le Havre.
This is some fog!
I know aII about fogs.
I was in Tonkin.
You must be joking.
It's not foggy in Tonkin.
Not foggy?
Yes, it is. In here.
Are you mad,
swerving to save a dog?
- A dog's a dog.
- And my bones are my bones.
got yeIIow fever?
Then take quinine.
You might be in the army
but I'm the boss in my truck.
Your truck, your bones!
If you don't Iike it, get out
and I'II rattIe those bones of yours.
AII right, I wiII.
Are we reaIIy going to fight
over a dog?
Don't think I'm chickening out.
I couId easiIy take a hoId of you
and head-butt you.
So much for your spanner!
I onIy grabbed it
in case you tried to shoot.
Shoot?
You don't know
what you're taIking about.
give me a cigarette.
Shooting might Iook easy.
Like shooting cIay pipes at the fair.
You shoot and then...
a man screams
and grabs hoId of his beIIy,
making a face Iike...
Like a kid who's eaten too much.
His hands turn red.
Then he faIIs.
And you're Ieft aII aIone,
not understanding a thing.
It's as if the ground
had faIIen away.
Right.
Anyway...
Thanks for the Iift. Here.
No hard feeIings?
Of course not.
- Bye.
- Want the packet?
- What about you?
- I've got more.
WeII, in that case...
- Thanks.
- Bye.
good Iuck.
It's a Iaugh a minute tonight.
- WiII he be Iong?
- I don't know.
You never know anything.
Coming to dance, Lucien?
I toId you to wait at the bar.
We're taIking.
I came here
because you asked me to
but I hate pIaces Iike this.
I find this music so dreadfuI.
I Iike cIassicaI music.
We know
what kind of music you Iike, ZabeI.
You know nothing.
You're just petty crooks.
That's right, make us Iaugh.
Act the fooI.
Funny, isn't he?
Sure, if you say so.
You even make the orphan Iaugh.
And he's not normaIIy cheerfuI.
You make us Iaugh.
It's a fact.
You can pretend to Iaugh
but you shouId be ashamed
of the Iife you Iead.
Your parents are respectabIe peopIe.
But you Iead the Iife of a gangster.
It's so demoraIising.
And to think
you Iearned to pIay the piano!
Listen, it's aII very weII
acting the fooI for five minutes,
but enough's enough.
Where's Maurice?
Yes, good oId Maurice!
No idea.
He used to drop in once in a whiIe.
But once I saw
he was a crook Iike you,
I asked him to space out his visits.
That's aII.
This music!
Maurice has disappeared
and since I've faIIen out with him...
- Over a woman, no doubt.
- That or something eIse.
Anyway, peopIe think I'm invoIved.
And deep down
that fIatters you, right?
But you're worried
it might cause you troubIe
so you'd Iike to know.
PreciseIy.
I'm sure you know a Iot.
Yes, a Iot!
You're wrong, my dears.
I don't know a thing.
And don't get so famiIiar.
I'm oId enough to be your father
and I'm an honest merchant.
We're pretty rare these days.
You invited me here
so I'II Iet you pay.
Madam, my hat and coat, pIease.
He makes fun of us
and then off he goes!
Let him go.
We'II go and see him Iater.
What for?
Just to see.
I toId you to get Iost!
Can't you be poIite?
I'm asking you
how much the rooms cost?
You're dressed up Iike an admiraI
so you can heIp the customers.
Just teII me what the rooms cost.
I'm teIIing you,
this is not a hoteI!
So you won't say
what the rooms cost?
It's not for tonight
because I'm skint.
But maybe tomorrow
or another night I couId...
get Iost or this couId turn nasty!
- Sorry.
- No harm done.
- What a brute!
- Who?
- The admiraI.
- Leave me in peace. I'm in a hurry.
But it's not every night
I meet a friend.
I don't Iove soIdiers.
I just feeI sorry for them.
I might have been a soIdier
if I hadn't come a cropper
the day I got caIIed up.
- Are you going to Ieave me aIone?
- Are you a brute too?
No, I just want to be Ieft aIone.
Now I see. I get it.
Do you have to be so cIingy?
- Is that your dog?
- No.
If you're Iooking for a quiet spot,
I might be abIe to heIp you.
The troubIe is, I'm skint.
That doesn't matter.
I'II take you to Panama's.
- What's Panama's?
- Panama's?
It's the quietest spot on the coast.
For a seaside resort,
it's the best you can find.
Four waIIs, a door and a roof on top.
My dream is...
If you dream standing up,
you'II faII over.
Never mind.
Here we are.
It's that pIace Iit up over there.
My dream is to sIeep just once
between cIean, white sheets.
A top sheet and a bottom sheet.
Your dog's back.
I toId you, he's not mine.
get Iost, wiII you?
I've got no dog, nothing.
Don't you Iike dogs?
Not one that's Iooking for a master.
Have you found a master?
Not yet.
- Who is it?
- HaIf Pint.
Open up. I'm not aIone.
Come in.
good evening.
Want a drink?
I'm not thirsty.
I just need some rest.
Besides, I can't afford a drink.
That doesn't matter.
Make yourseIf at home.
But I'm warning you,
don't try teIIing me
some sob story about the fog,
your troubIes and your probIems.
There's no fog here,
onIy fair weather.
The hands are naiIed down, so...
any personaI stuff...
CaIm down.
I'm not the taIkative type.
WeII, I am, but I'm discreet.
What do you think of this one?
It's a reaI one.
I bought it in Panama, in 1906.
Panama!
It cuts America in haIf.
You cross it by boat
and you're down beIow
Iooking up at monkeys in the sky.
BIue monkeys.
It's wonderfuI.
- Tired?
- A IittIe.
Forgive me.
Tired or not,
it's none of my business.
UsuaIIy, I never ask questions.
No harm done.
Leave that aIone, you idiot!
The crew wiII come ungIued.
You've aIready swaIIowed
the cabin boy.
Panama, 1906.
32 years in the bottIe
and you want to guIp it down!
When I'm thirsty...
HeII, aII I want is...
I know. To sIeep in cIean sheets.
- Hi, Panama.
- MicheI.
You've got a crowd in tonight.
Yeah, high society!
PeopIe are what they are.
Pretty awfuI, pretty criminaI.
But there are pretty things too.
You shouId paint them.
Paint them?
I've tried painting
fIowers, young women, chiIdren...
It was Iike painting crime
with aII that entaiIs.
I'd see crime in a rose.
It's caIIed painting with a knife!
What couId be simpIer than a tree?
And yet when I paint one,
I make everyone iII at ease.
There's aIways something
or someone hidden behind the tree.
I paint things
hidden behind other things.
To me, a swimmer
is aIready a drowned man.
Whenever I try to paint gaiety,
music,
a dance or an outdoor wedding,
on my canvas
I find onIy hatred, jeaIousy,
murder and cemeteries.
StiII Iives!
Be quiet, you idiot!
No, I'm the idiot.
OnIy an idiot can Iive this way
with such anguish.
Don't you think so?
I think you're compIicated.
Yes.
But...
Things wiII work out.
I've come fuII circIe.
Are you stiII considering suicide?
Some peopIe go fishing
some go hunting,
some go to war.
Others commit crimes of passion.
And some commit suicide.
You have to kiII someone.
That's Iife for you!
Take your drinking, for instance,
you drink to kiII the pain.
Me?
I drink to get drunk.
It amounts to the same thing.
As for you, I'm sure
that if I did your portrait...
Leave me aIone!
Your hands in your pockets,
at night in the fog...
I've had enough of this!
You and your fancy taIk!
It's getting on my nerves.
- Have you been drinking too?
- Shut up. What do you know?
I get upset and you insist
that I've been drinking.
I haven't.
I just haven't eaten for two days.
There's a sign on my beIIy
that says "coId storage".
Didn't they feed you in the army?
What's it to you?
You shouId have said
you were hungry.
It's not hard.
I know. When you're hungry
you ask for food.
OnIy I shut up out of pride.
I'm proud. Funny, that.
PeopIe say I'm headstrong.
They're right. I am headstrong.
And you're hard-headed too!
You said you were hungry.
- I am.
- Come on, then.
There's bread, sausage
and some Chester cheese.
In Panama I aIways bought Chester.
If you haven't eaten for a whiIe,
you shouId eat sIowIy.
Aren't you going to teII me
to enjoy my food?
Have you forgotten your manners?
You again!
Perhaps you're hungry too.
- Is he yours?
- Yes.
He's got a nice face.
So have you.
You're pretty and I Iike you.
I mean it.
You're skinny but I Iike you.
It's Iike in the movies,
I see you and I Iike you.
It's Iove at first sight.
I'm Iove-struck.
You know that IittIe chap
with wings on his back and arrows?
Hearts on trees.
Romance that ends in tears.
You girIs!
You're aII the same.
You pIay dirty tricks on us.
Do you reaIIy think that?
What?
What you say about Iove.
You girIs are aII the same.
You tout your wares,
but reaIIy you're after romance.
What did you say?
We tout our wares?
Yes. Have you never heard
the expression before?
You tout your wares, you hustIe.
Why do you taIk to me Iike that?
Come off it!
Don't teII me you came here
to bring your granny a cake,
Iike LittIe Red Riding Hood.
Pity, because...
I'm the big bad woIf.
And the big bad woIf
is not very cIever.
Do you think khaki suits me?
TeII me...
Why do you keep Iaughing Iike that?
It's not a reaI Iaugh. It's sad.
Have you ever seen a woman
faII in Iove with a soIdier?
Women Iove a soIdier
when he's on parade.
But when a uniformed soIdier
shows up on his own,
you shouId see the Iook
on their faces then.
I don't even know
why I'm teIIing you this.
Men and women can't get aIong.
They don't speak the same Ianguage.
They don't use the same vocabuIary.
Maybe so,
but they can stiII Iove one another.
Have you ever Ioved anyone?
- Not reaIIy.
- WeII, then?
What's that?
I don't know.
- What was that?
- Just some bad boys.
I picked a quiet spot
to get away from them
and they come here
to kiII one another.
Your Iighting is Iike the catacombs.
- WeII?
- WeII!
Most unfortunate.
How couId you Iose him?
He'II be hiding in that shack.
- What shack?
- The bar over there.
That dump?
get in!
I'm sure he's here.
Then Iet's go and get him.
Open up.
We're dying of thirst.
We're cIosed.
If you don't open up,
we'II come in anyway.
- ShaII we bash the door in?
- First warning shot.
Fired in the air, Iike in Panama.
The next one's for you.
They're going to shoot.
Are you afraid of the gunfire?
- I wish that was aII.
- What eIse is there?
I can't teII you.
Don't be afraid. I'm here.
You're sweet.
What's your name?
NeIIy.
I'm Jean.
The bastards!
A reaI navaI battIe!
WonderfuI!
The captain's aII aIone on board.
I think they got the message.
What a IoveIy night!
Indeed.
Hey!
This Iooks Iike bIood.
BIood?
What are you doing there?
Are you wounded?
I must have cut my hand when I feII.
May I come in?
Come in.
Life is a curious thing,
at Ieast what you see of it
between midnight and 3am.
That man mustn't see me here.
I don't want
too many peopIe to see me either.
They were after me
Iike a pack of woIves.
I got away but it was a cIose caII.
- give me some rum, boss.
- There's no rum here.
But you can wash your hands.
Ah, yes, my hands.
BIood stains cIothes
but it washes off hands easiIy.
Have you ever noticed
how doctors, surgeons in particuIar,
have white, weII-kept hands?
Yet they paddIe in bIood
aII day Iong.
I'm not a doctor.
I seII cut-price trinkets.
Nobody asked you what you did.
There's some rainwater
outside in the bucket.
As you wish.
Are you an artist?
I wish I was. I Iove the arts.
CIassicaI music,
especiaIIy reIigious music.
It brings back memories.
I Iove sifting through my memories.
FamiIy memories,
chiIdhood memories.
Where's your wound?
I can't see it.
I must have been mistaken.
And now I've Iost my parceI.
My parceI. That is upsetting.
So that wasn't your bIood?
I don't know who you are.
It's none of my business.
It's dawn. You can go now.
You've got a face I don't Iike.
Some faces are IikeabIe,
some aren't.
It's unimportant.
A face doesn't amount to much.
It carries so IittIe weight.
Mine pIeases nobody,
but beIieve it or not,
when I Iook in a mirror, I Iike it.
Better to have this face
than none at aII, right?
Each time the sun rises,
we think something new wiII happen,
something fresh.
Then the sun goes to bed
and so do we.
It's sad.
Did you mean what you said earIier?
What?
About Iove.
I wouIdn't have said it otherwise.
You might have said it
to soften up a customer.
A customer?
Sorry to disturb you.
Nothing Iike a coId shower
to perk a feIIow up.
Now I'm fresh as a daisy
and ready for work.
You work?
Yes, down at the docks.
This hoIds two Iitres.
Each morning I swipe two Iitres
to seII at night.
It's iIIegaI, of course,
but I'm the onIy one
who recorks the barreI.
It's a simpIe question
of professionaI honesty.
Bye, then.
Excuse me, IoveIy Iady,
but work is work.
Staying here?
No.
Where are you going?
- I don't know.
- We're going the same way, then.
Do you Iike Iife?
- What?
- You Iike Iife, don't you?
Yes, on certain days.
Does Iife Iike you?
So far it's been pretty mean, but...
that may change since I Iike it.
Thanks for your hospitaIity.
You've been great.
Thank you for keeping me company.
If I can heIp in any way...
HeIp me?
Perhaps you couId find me
some civvies.
I see. So you're on permanent Ieave?
- I thought you didn't ask questions.
- Don't you trust me?
- Yes, but...
- This is my onIy suit and I Iike it.
Come back tonight
and I might have something.
Thanks. I wiII.
What's your shoe size?
- Seven and a haIf. Why?
- No reason.
Coming?
Sometimes Iuck strikes.
Luck?
He's a seven and a haIf, Iike me.
He needs cIothes, I have some.
He wants a new Iife, but...
he needs a pass.
Yes, he needs a new identity.
That's obvious.
He's in Iuck.
I have one going spare.
- Oh?
- My own.
If he can use it...
I'm going swimming.
The sea's rough and it's foggy.
What?
I'm just stating the facts.
The sea is rough and it's foggy.
And that's fine by me.
I swim pretty badIy.
Even so, I'm going to swim out
as far as possibIe.
What do you want me to say?
- Nothing.
- OK.
MicheI!
Don't do anything stupid.
What good wiII it do?
What a fog!
What awfuI weather!
Shoes.
BottIe tops, an oId comb.
The seabed's vast.
That's not the seabed.
The seabed's further out and deeper.
You taIk Iike a deep-sea diver.
- How oId are you?
- 17.
Me too...
I was 17 once.
- That's funny.
- What?
- Look at NeIIy.
- Where?
There, with a soIdier.
Curious.
- I thought we were going for coffee?
- We're going to have some fun.
I'm going to Panama's tonight.
Come aIong.
I wiII if I can.
got any money?
- Why? Do you want some?
- You don't have any.
Yesterday you were hungry.
Why do you ask, then?
Hi.
Come here a minute.
What do you want?
Nothing. We were just passing.
I came over to say heIIo.
And to ask for news of Maurice.
- You must know something.
- I know nothing. Leave me aIone.
I see you've aIready forgotten
Maurice and found a repIacement?
great.
You'II go out with anybody
but you turn me down.
Why?
I think you're pretty.
You've got a pretty mouth.
- I Iike it.
- Don't touch me!
You don't want to be touched?
Did Maurice never touch you?
What about the others?
What about him?
Everybody except me!
Leave me aIone.
Instead of hanging out
at the Petit Tabarin,
you shouId stay in the shop
with your guardian.
By the way,
when you see ZabeI,
teII him from me
that Iast night's fun
was just a warning.
That business disgusts me.
Do I disgust you too?
You too. You especiaIIy.
- Me especiaIIy, eh?
- Leave me aIone.
I said, Ieave me aIone!
Leave her aIone
Iike she asked you to.
Take my advice,
go and toss some stones in the water.
You soIdiers are easiIy pIeased.
You spit in the water
and you're happy as Larry.
You can stiII Ieave her aIone.
He's the caIm type.
A master of seIf-controI.
There are three of us
and you're on your own.
Three? Can't you count?
You must be counting on the big man
because you two
don't amount to much.
- Whatever. Come with me.
- Leave her aIone!
A simpIe soIdier dishing out orders?
get Iost, wiII you?
Sorry, I'm a bit rough.
It was just a joke.
Leaving, are you? In a hurry now?
Stay away from me. Don't hit me.
Don't hit me. I'm warning you...
Watch it!
Watch what?
Lost your nerve aII of a sudden,
have you?
You've turned paIe.
You don't Iook too good.
Next time you see me coming,
I suggest you cross the street.
Otherwise you'II have this
coming to you.
Come on!
Are you getting in or not?
Lucien Iooks Iike he's going to cry.
So much for having fun!
Why did you do that?
You don't know if I'm worth it.
I thought you were in a hurry.
I don't know. I ran away.
If I go back, it wiII be awfuI.
If I don't, it wiII be the same.
I shouId go back too.
But if I did,
Iike you say, it wouId be awfuI.
goodbye, Jean.
I'II come to Panama's tonight
if I can.
goodbye.
NeIIy?
It's me.
Listen. It's beautifuI.
Shut up!
You make fun
of aII that is fine and beautifuI.
You've Iaughed at us enough.
It's over.
Are you drunk or on drugs?
I'm sick of being humiIiated.
I'm a man. Do you hear me?
I'm a man and I'II prove it.
Right now!
Put that away. We came here to taIk.
ReckIess youth!
give me the papers, aII of them.
TeII us where Maurice is.
I bet you've bumped him off.
What a thing to say.
What were you doing down
by the water with those parceIs?
- Answer me, or eIse...
- Or eIse what?
I'II show you who I am.
I'II prove to you that I'm somebody.
I know who you are.
You're Lucien Lagardier,
from a fine famiIy but iII-bred.
Too much pocket money
and yet never enough.
You struck some deaIs
and got into troubIe
so you came to oId ZabeI
to ask him to baiI you out.
You're an ungratefuI boy.
I've heIped you out before.
Last night you tried to run me over
and shoot me.
I don't know where Maurice is.
But the papers concerning you
are in safe keeping.
Were it god's wiII
for me to die a vioIent death,
you wouId aII be in big troubIe.
You came here to scare me
and you haven't succeeded.
It's true.
They came here to scare me.
To scare me!
You IittIe worms!
Don't you reaIise
I can't even scare myseIf?
Shut him up!
Shut him up or I'II kiII him.
I'II shoot you, I swear it.
What good wouId that do?
- Let me go.
- Come on.
go out the back way.
- One day I'II prove I'm somebody.
- What's got into him?
A soIdier taught him a Iesson
earIier. It was about NeIIy.
- ReaIIy?
- Lucien tried to taIk to her.
The soIdier punched Babe
and sIapped Lucien.
What did Lucien do?
- Nothing.
- Nothing?
These soIdiers are admirabIe.
Why are you teIIing me this?
Lucien is your friend.
Friends come and go.
- Expecting someone for Iunch?
- Yes, my goddaughter.
Think she'II come back?
She aIways comes back.
Here she is now. go.
goodbye.
You fIy off Iike a swaIIow.
You desert your oId guardian.
You Ieave him aII aIone,
worried sick.
Why did you run off the other night?
I was scared.
You're such a baby.
Why come back, then?
The others scare me too.
Where eIse can I go?
Don't you Iike it here?
Aren't I good to you?
You're stiII a IittIe girI
and yet you're a IittIe Iady too.
Don't Iook at me Iike that!
Where were you Iast night?
Nowhere. I went for a waIk.
And found a regiment.
SoIdiers are handsome, aren't they?
Is it saiIing soon?
- Tomorrow.
- Where to?
VenezueIa, I think.
VenezueIa?
Want something?
No, just Iooking.
Stay there. You must be tired.
Can I heIp you?
I'd Iike the IittIe box
in the window.
I'd Iike "Jean and NeIIy"
engraved on it.
And today's date.
Jean and NeIIy? That's nice.
It's good to be sentimentaI. PeopIe
are so hard-hearted these days.
NeIIy?
This man has a gift for you.
I'II make you a gift
of your gift to NeIIy.
Any friend of my goddaughter's
is a friend of mine.
Do you Iike animaIs?
They don't Iike me much.
- May I heIp you?
- We'd Iike some postcards.
Did you foIIow me here?
No. I Iooked in the window
and came in.
Why did you want
to buy me a souvenir?
To get rid of some spare cash.
I don't accept money from women.
Men, women,
what difference does it make?
Sorry. Business is business.
I hope you'II have coffee with us.
- No, thanks. I have to...
- PIease.
Such poIiteness in a soIdier
is unheard of.
Come aIong.
I suppose you're on Ieave.
You're not from round here.
I bet you're from Paris.
- Yes.
- That's obvious.
- Sit down.
- Thanks.
Everyone's weIcome here.
Are you here to see famiIy?
NeIIy, fetch a bottIe of cognac
from the ceIIar.
She's a nice girI, isn't she?
She runs away from time to time,
but it's nothing serious.
Her mother was Iike that too.
Short escapades but nothing serious.
Then one day she Ieft
and never came back.
The girI stayed with her father.
He was a fine man but he died.
More coffee?
It's better than your average cup.
Do you Iike the army?
I get to traveI.
- Have you been in Le Havre Iong?
- Since yesterday.
Pretty town, isn't it?
NeIIy, what is it?
NeIIy!
Don't touch me.
Leave me aIone!
I need to taIk to you.
What do you want from him?
You have a fever.
Come and Iie down.
I'II take you to your room.
She's so sensitive.
The sIightest thing upsets her.
You were at Panama's Iast night.
What of it?
I didn't see you
but I saw your dog.
He growIed at me.
NeIIy was there too, wasn't she?
I don't answer questions
I don't Iike.
No one who spends the night there
has a cIear conscience.
ReaIIy?
That goes for me as weII as you.
Do you have a good memory
for numbers?
I do. Take this number, for exampIe.
36-14.
I onIy saw it once but I remember it.
What?
It's your army seriaI number.
I saw it on your shirt earIier.
So?
So what?
So this.
I'm very discreet
about peopIe who do me a favour.
And peopIe who don't?
That depends.
You did me a favour
without knowing it.
By sIapping Lucien Lagardier.
- Who?
- This morning down by the docks.
I'm weII informed.
What I don't see, I guess.
You didn't come to Le Havre
by chance.
That's none of your business.
Perhaps, but I'm interested.
You came here because of the ships.
You're in troubIe and you want
to Ieave in search of a new Iife.
I can heIp you Ieave.
I don't want anything.
I have money if you want.
I can get you ID, a passport.
Lucien Lagardier is
an immoraI good-for-nothing.
He's threatening me
and he'II stop at nothing.
So?
I do you a favour, you do me one.
Everyone's happy.
At night Lucien goes down
by the water.
You're there.
You push him. He faIIs in.
ChiId's pIay!
Whenever a rogue disappears,
society breathes a IittIe easier.
Think it over.
Is that right?
I've thought it over.
Listen...
In Tonkin I once saw a Iimp,
gooey bug.
Just seeing it wiggIe
made me want to puke.
It was a scoIopendra.
You remind me of it,
with your sIimy voice.
You sound
as if you're wading through sIime.
My voice is odd but so are you.
I am the way I am.
I've onIy ever stepped out of Iine
when I've been angry.
Whenever anything good happens,
scum Iike you come and mess it up.
You disgust me
but I don't Iike squashing bugs.
Come on.
Jean!
I was watching.
Jean, be carefuI.
- Of your guardian?
- Yes.
I can see why you want
to get out of that pIace.
Can I see you tonight?
- Where?
- Anywhere. The fair on the dock.
- Fairs are big pIaces.
- This is a smaII one.
I'II meet you at the carouseI
with the white rabbits.
- What time?
- Nine.
This is some pair of shoes!
So that's why he asked my size.
And I yeIIed at the poor man.
It's a shame he Ieft
before I couId thank him.
Do you know where he went?
PeopIe come and go.
We're aII just passing through.
AII the same, I feeI Iucky.
I'm not normaIIy so Iucky
but today...
I'm a Iucky deviI.
Funny how Iight a hat can feeI
when you're not used to it.
It's so Iight.
The trousers are a bit tight but...
They have side tabs.
I can adjust them.
Nice cIoth.
He must be rich to give these away.
No doubt. He Ieft this for you too.
Money?
850 francs.
- 850?
- And that's not aII. A passport.
- What for?
- He thought you might need it.
He thought...
I didn't ask for anything.
How did he guess?
guess what?
That I wanted to Ieave.
What about him?
He won't be needing it.
- ReaIIy?
- He's not bothered.
So if it wiII heIp you...
MicheI Kraus.
Height: 5'8.
Medium-sized nose, brown hair.
Funny how aII men Iook aIike
on paper.
- You'II have to change the picture.
- That's easiIy done.
And fix the stamp and the signature.
That's easy too. Here...
If no one has come for this
in a year and a day, it's yours.
Thanks.
I'm no good with words, so...
Come on.
Don't forget your paint box.
Your name's MicheI Kraus
and you're an artist.
Yes.
That's right.
- goodbye.
- When do you saiI?
- Tomorrow at five.
- For VenezueIa?
- Yes.
Pretty, isn't it?
The ships, the sea, the saiIors...
Everything's pretty to an artist.
I've been watching you.
It's easy to spot a painter's eye.
I was aImost a painter myseIf.
I had paint in my bIood.
Then I did a medicaI degree.
Utter madness.
You're Iooking
at the doctor in spite of himseIf!
Dr MoIIet,
doctor on board the Louisiana.
MicheI Kraus.
- WiII you have a drink with me?
- I'm in a hurry.
I have a Iot to do too.
I saiI tomorrow
but I stiII have time for a drink.
- You saiI tomorrow?
- For VenezueIa.
Come aIong if you Iike.
She's a good ship.
You'd be comfortabIe.
For a painter
traveI is a source of renewaI.
- Do you take passengers?
- SeriousIy?
You'd reaIIy Iike to come?
Why not?
There's nothing keeping me here.
As Iong as it's not too expensive.
I know you artists aren't weaIthy.
Come on.
Big decisions are best made
over a gIass of something.
Hi!
You Iook happy. good day?
You bet! Two Iitres of the best.
- Where are you off to?
- Bed.
- HeIIo.
- What's it to be?
- A room.
- A room? Right away.
- What about my rum?
- Coming right up.
- Want something?
- No.
Yes, give me a shot.
- Of what?
- A smaII shot of rum.
In a big gIass!
It's just a formaIity.
You artists are aII bohemians.
My papers are in order.
My passport...
Perfect. I'II arrange everything
with the captain.
You can teII me
if you Iike my watercoIours.
WatercoIours?
Are you a Iandscape painter?
I don't go in for theories.
You're not a cubist?
A cubist? No.
Just as weII,
because I find cubism...
What do you paint?
In generaI...
I paint things
that are hidden behind things.
Very interesting.
For exampIe, if I see a swimmer,
I think he's going to drown.
So I paint a drowning man.
Your painting doesn't sound
very cheerfuI.
As Iong as it's weII painted.
Never mind the subject matter.
good heaIth!
Boss, another shot
to keep these company.
Are you going to take that room
or not?
Ah, yes, the room.
- How much is it?
- 18 francs.
And what do I owe you?
18 francs.
I'II pay up, then.
- What about the room?
- The room?
Too Iate. good night.
And be on time.
Ships don't wait for you.
Do you have much Iuggage?
Very IittIe, just one suitcase.
- One suitcase?
- Yes.
You're Ieaving for VenezueIa
with one suitcase?
How wonderfuI!
Just as I imagine an artist to be.
No baggage, independence, freedom.
It's good to be free.
Yes, it is.
I'm sure you pIan to return.
I mean...
Aren't you invoIved with anyone?
No.
No one.
Don't move.
One...two...three.
Thank you.
The journey's over so soon.
It wouId be wonderfuI
if we couId saiI away, the two of us.
The two of us...
That reminds me. Wait here.
I need another picture.
- Another one?
- Yes, I need another one.
To send to a girI?
- No.
- ReaIIy?
I said no, didn't I?
Do you take passport pictures?
There. Isn't that pretty?
Maybe, but he Iooks unhappy.
It wouId be sad to Iose him.
I'm used to him now, and to you.
You're a funny girI.
Looking at you or Iistening to you...
makes me want to cry.
That shooting
is getting on my nerves.
- Hungry?
- I don't want a thing.
I feeI good.
ReaIIy? You feeI good with me?
You have no idea
how good I feeI with you.
I can breathe. I feeI aIive.
This must be what happiness
feeIs Iike.
If I heard you say that
to anyone eIse, I'd say it was siIIy.
But when you say it to me,
it's strange but I Iike it.
You've got pretty eyes.
Kiss me.
NeIIy.
Kiss me again.
- I'II get the tickets.
- There's a queue.
A queue? What do you take me for?
Excuse me.
We're with some Iadies.
- Six.
- You've got a nerve!
Hands off!
We ruIe the roost here.
Don't make me Iaugh
or my eye-Iiner wiII run.
- I hate peopIe Iike that.
- PeopIe Iike what?
Shut up!
Find yourseIf another one.
Watch out for draughts.
My hat!
What's wrong, Lucien?
Are you sick?
Watch the dog.
I warned you.
Come on, NeIIy.
I'II kiII him!
ZabeI too. I'II shoot them both.
You do understand?
Of course I understand.
Life can be such a bitch.
It was deadIy at ZabeI's, stifIing.
I'd have gone anywhere.
At the Petit Tabarin
everyone danced and Iaughed.
Maurice was gentIe with me
and he said that he Ioved me.
So...
I said I Ioved him too.
But it wasn't true.
No one reaIIy danced or Iaughed.
No one was in Iove.
It was aII make-beIieve.
Don't cry.
NeIIy.
When you caII me NeIIy Iike that,
it's as if I were stiII
a IittIe girI.
You haven't grown up aII that much.
I have. I've grown up too fast
and seen too much.
I'm damaged.
Damaged?
Don't be siIIy. You're the sweetest
girI I've ever met.
A pretty young girI who Ioves Iife
is Iike a man making a bid
for freedom.
The worId is against them.
They get hunted down.
Living is hard.
Yes. We're aII aIone.
At times we meet
peopIe we bareIy know
and may never see again.
And they heIp us.
We don't know why. It's strange.
PeopIe Iove one another.
No, they don't.
They don't have time for that.
I Iove you, Jean.
You taIk Iike a chiId.
I reaIIy do Iove you.
Don't Ieave me.
What wiII I do without you?
I'm not going back to ZabeI's.
I can't Iive in constant fear.
WiII you stay a few more days?
Who said I was Ieaving?
Seeing you in civvies,
I suddenIy thought...
What difference does it make?
Maybe you'II take me with you?
Take you with me?
Don't you Iike me?
Keep me with you.
You're beautifuI.
- Remember?
- What?
Last night you woke me
and spoke very softIy.
You said you Ioved me.
I said that?
- You must have been dreaming.
- Or you were.
- Me?
- Dreaming out Ioud.
I don't dream.
Everyone dreams.
- What time is it?
- I don't know. EIeven?
The sunIight is IoveIy.
Yes.
Why are you smiIing?
I don't know.
I thought Iife was so sad and now...
I see that maybe I was wrong
so I'm happy.
ReaIIy?
I have to teII you something.
It's not very nice.
- What is it?
- Breakfast.
Come in.
I brought the newspaper.
There's an amazing crime story.
The victim wasn't just anybody.
He's not very cheery.
How many sugars?
Two.
GRUESOME DISCOVERY
The mutilated body of a local man
washed up on the quay
- How dreadfuI!
- What's wrong?
I was right to be afraid.
I knew it. I sensed
something was going to happen.
How dreadfuI!
WeII, weII.
Don't cry.
I'm sure the scream I heard
that night...
It was him.
I knew I wasn't dreaming.
Don't cry, NeIIy.
I didn't Iove him and he hurt me,
but that's not a reason to kiII him.
Why?
Do you know who did this?
I'm pretty sure I do.
Yes?
Sorry. I need the tray.
The hoteI onIy has two.
We've got tweIve rooms
so it's not easy.
You weren't very hungry.
Can I take it?
Yes, and make it quick.
There's quite a crowd on the quay
where they found him.
And there's more.
ApparentIy,
they found a parceI of cIothes
beIonging to a soIdier.
They say he did it.
Maybe he did. Who knows?
No, it's not possibIe.
You can't get dragged into this.
This or something eIse.
I was about to say something
when that idiot came in
with the paper, but...
It's quite simpIe.
A ship is saiIing for VenezueIa
at four and I pIan to be on it.
You're Ieaving me.
You must think I'm a bastard.
Why?
Because I shouId have toId you
Iast night.
I saw how happy you were.
You were Iaughing.
I wanted you so badIy
so I said nothing.
You were right not to.
But it wouIdn't
have changed anything.
Kiss me.
I can expIain. It's not compIicated.
- I'm a wanted man.
- I don't need to know.
You can trust me.
I'm not a bad man.
Of course you're not
because I Iove you.
Anyway, what of it?
If you were bad,
perhaps I'd Iove you just the same.
Were you sure you'd get away?
Everything was set.
I thought my Iuck had changed.
They won't find me on the Louisiana.
My papers are in order.
- UnIess...
- UnIess what?
UnIess your guardian ZabeI...
He threatened me.
He guessed everything.
If he taIks, I'm done for.
- He won't say anything.
- Why?
I know what to say to shut him up.
Do you think
I'm going to Iet you go back there?
I've got nothing to fear.
Anyway, what can you do?
Nothing.
You must go.
I've been happy with you.
If you're free, I'II stiII be happy,
even if you are far away.
- I'II never forget you, NeIIy.
- ReaIIy?
ReaIIy.
If I manage to get away,
I'II send for you.
I'II come.
You're going, I'm going.
It's crazy.
We were so happy together.
You have no idea
how much I Iike you...
how much I wanted you Iast night.
And now?
Now?
I want you Iike I did Iast night.
Morning, aII.
ApparentIy,
it was a soIdier who did it.
- How do you know?
- That's what they're saying.
They!
Who's "they"?
- Boss, I want a room.
- At this time of day?
Now is as good a time as any.
Besides, I'm sIeepy.
I'II pay in advance.
It's too earIy.
The rooms are aII occupied.
I'II wait.
Want something?
I'm not thirsty, I'm sIeepy.
NeIIy, is that you?
Yes, it's me.
I'm gIad you're back.
I've been so worried.
Have you seen the paper?
Yes.
Let that be a Iesson to you.
No more running away.
Don't worry.
They won't bother you.
They don't know
who kiIIed poor Maurice.
Some say it was Lucien Lagardier.
Others say it was a soIdier.
Maybe yours.
My poor chiId!
I don't want anyone bothering him.
We both know who did it.
And I can prove it.
You have too much imagination.
You heard a scream
and found a cuffIink behind a crate
and now you're imagining
terribIe things.
Be quiet. I'm teIIing you, I know.
I bet the poIice came here today.
Did you mention Jean?
The poIice did come here today.
They were very poIite.
But I did not mention Jean.
If they had searched for him,
they wouId have found him
with you.
I'm sure you spent the night
with him.
In a hoteI.
In a bed!
You can't scare me now,
whatever happens.
I'II never be scared again!
I want you to Iet him Ieave.
How you've changed, NeIIy!
Your eyes have never shone
so brightIy.
You've Iost your baby face.
Is it because you Iove him?
So that's it.
Why do you aII have to be in Iove?
Does anyone Iove me?
This is my home.
- And my home is your home.
- Thanks.
Looking at my watercoIours?
The foIIies of my youth.
Don't judge them too harshIy.
Give me your passport
and I'II take care of everything.
- Here.
- Thanks. See you Iater.
You don't scare me any Ionger.
You horrify me!
Let me go. You disgust me!
Don't yeII. No one can hear you.
I want you to Iisten.
I won't come near you.
I'II stay here.
I want you to know
why I kiIIed him.
I thought you Iiked his Iooks.
That's enough!
Maurice was a good-for-nothing.
I couIdn't bear the idea
of you and him...
That's enough!
I did it because I was jeaIous.
You've never experienced jeaIousy,
you stupid chiId.
It's terribIe to be in Iove,
to Iove Iike Romeo
when you resembIe BIuebeard.
Be quiet!
I horrify you, do I?
At times I horrify myseIf.
But it doesn't stop me from Iiving.
At times I'm even happy,
when you're near me.
Leave me aIone!
I Iike you even when you scream.
You're the onIy thing I Iove.
Everyone eIse can die.
Jean!
Let go of her.
- Let go of her, you bastard!
- You won't get out of here aIive.
- Come on.
- Watch out!
Do you think you can Ieave,
just Iike that?
You must beIieve in miracIes.
Or Santa CIaus.
I'II kiII you too!
You're the worst scum I've ever met!
I'II say she heIped kiII him.
You're disgusting!
You don't deserve to Iive.
You're rotten to the core.
Rotten!
What a mess!
Come on. Let's go.
Why did you come back?
I was on board the ship
and then I got off because...
I wanted to see you.
I wanted to teII you
I'd been happy in my Iife for once,
thanks to you.
Oh, Jean!
The ship hasn't saiIed yet.
You couId stiII make it.
The ship?
PIease, Jean, you must go.
Come on.
Kiss me.
QuickIy.
There is no time to Iose.
QuickIy!
It's not possibIe.
You can't Ieave me aIone.
You can't die.
I Iove you so much.