♪ ♪
I want to open a gift.
Which one should I open first?
This one? Oh, it's a pretty green, so...
Yeah... oh, this one's from me.
Go ahead, open it. Yep.
Whew. Pressure's on. Okay!
Oh, I know I'm going to love it.
Oh!
This is so cute!
Thanks, Emma.
Oh, there's another engraving on the back.
Oh!
"Congratulations, Melanie and D... Darren."
Oh, my gosh...
I'm so sorry.
I must have got confused from last time.
-That's okay.-Let's do a toast.
To Melanie and Robert.
May you have a life of love, laughter
and happily ever after.
Thanks, Mom.
Cheers to that.
[laughing]
- Yes!
- Yay!
Okay, ladies, now...
to the games!
To the games! Let's do it!
[cheering]
Okay, Mom, you can do it.
- What's it gonna be?
- Yes! Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Oh! What do we have?
A wedding tip!
I'm sure Mom will have fun with this one.
Come on, Mrs. B, tell us your secret!
Okay, I have a few.
Um, let's think...
Well, as you know,
Gord and I are celebrating
our 30-year anniversary.
[cheering]
[applause]
So I'm just saying,
I do have a tip or two.
Melanie,
sweetheart,
don't overthink things
like we women do.
Sometimes you just have to go for it.
Take the plunge.
Head first.
Feet first. I don't care.
Just do it.
Not very subtle, is she?
Do you blame her?
Hey, you got this.
Three times the charm, right?
Right, let's just hope I get his name right
when he's at the altar.
You can totally get that
engraving burned out.
Okay.
Whose turn?
Is it... okay!
What? Me?
Spin that wheel, baby.
[chatter, talking over each other]
Whoo!
[cheering, chattering]
What's it going to be?
[Mel]: I love him...
I love him not.
I love him...
Hey, your sister will be out in a minute.
Then we're ready to go.
-Mom...-You look gorgeous.
How did you know you truly loved Dad?
I mean,
that "I want to spend the rest of
my life with this person,"
kind of love.
By marrying him.
Trust me, they grow on you.
So you grew to love Dad?
Yes, yes, of course.
Love grows and blossoms,
like... like these flowers in your bouquet.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
My hair would not stay put.
Okay, let's go! We've got to go.
We're doing it!
Yay!
[laughing and cheering]
[talking indistinctly]
Third time's the charm.
Hey, Dad.
Mom.
Gorgeous.
Thank you.
You got this, Roo?
["Wedding March" playing]
Yeah.
No!
I'm sorry.
No! No! Sweetheart! Wait.
You know, I was thinking,
maybe we should expand our
business into products.
You know, like,
offering home-made granola bars
after our yoga classes,
or fresh smoothies,
or maybe even a delivery service
for healthy meals, you know?
Personally, I love these fruit bars.
[tearful] There's so filling and delicious.
Mel...
are you okay?
I don't know. Am I?
I mean, all I do is mess everything up,
so if that's considered
okay, then I guess I am,
but I'm kind of starting to
think that maybe I'm not.
Mel...
No...
Please, no, no, no. Don't
feel sorry for me.
It's Rob who you should feel sorry for.
He's a really, really great guy.
It's just...
What?
I like him. I do. I like him a lot.
It's just...
I don't love him.
Not in that happily-ever-after way.
Oh...
What is wrong with me?
I've broken off three engagements.
Well, it's better than three divorces.
Sorry.
How is he?
Well, after you left,
he got all red in the face,
like he'd just bench-pressed300 pounds.
Oh, this is all my fault.
I should have never said
yes in the first place...
although he did ask me to marry him
in front of a packed spin class,
and he wouldn't stop
spinning until I said yes,
so I don't know,
he could have had a heart attack
had I said no.
So it was better to break his heart?
You're right. I'm awful.
That's not what I'm saying.
You know what? I'm done with it all.
I am done with hurting anyone.
I'm done with dating, engaging,
almost marrying...
I am... I'm done!
Obviously, Rob, Justin, Darren...
they all just weren't The One.
The One.
Have you ever met The One?
No.
I'm done.
Yeah, that's it!
[cheering]
Come on, man!
That ball had no speed.
Pay up, Damon.
C-note. Thank you.
Where are you going?
I promised Gineen
I'd help her with some wallpaper.
[coughing]Whipped!
[Man]: What did you say?
He said you're whipped.
That doesn't surprise me.
You've got to put down the married dudes
to make yourself feel better.
Okay, first of all, technically,
you're not married.
You're separated,
and yet, you're still
doing Gineen's bidding.
So I would just feel better for you
if you kept playing.
Is this funny to you?
It's kind of funny.
Fine, I'll play one more game.
Right.
But that's not what I was talking about.
Okay, what were you talking about?
Well, it's obvious you've
got a chip on your shoulder
because you know
you're never going to get married.
Uh, and that would be a
bad thing because...?
You don't get a warm body to
lay next to every night,
someone to have kids with.
Yeah.
Fred, your kids sleep with
you and Susan every night.
You are sleep-deprived and going crazy.
A wife is someone to grow old with,
someone to witness
the miracles of life with.
-Right?-Mm-hmm.
Vince, there are three things in life
that require a witness...
crimes, accidents,
and marriages.
Need I say more?
[friends chortle]
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Yeah!
Hey, pal,
we married guys are actually
living the dream.
Yeah.
The only thing your wives dream about
is you guys actually doing the dishes.
[chuckling]
Besides...
if I want to marry, I can get married.
Oh!
Look, Damon,
I'm not denying you date a lot of women.
You're just not a guy girls want to marry.
You serious?
Very. Gineen feels the same way.
Okay, well, Gineen has never liked me.
Fred? What about Susan?
What does she say about me?
I don't know. That you're fun?
See?
But she wouldn't set you
up with any of her friends.
Oh!
See?
Face it, Damon. You're that cool bachelor.
Women can sense when a guy can't commit,
which is why you will never get a girl
to say "I do."
Oh, I could, if I wanted to.
Want to bet?
[laughs]
Tell you what...
you find a girl, any girl,
and get her to say yes to your proposal
by the end of the month,
I will give you
the Juicy Cola account...
all the perks, all the parties.
If you lose...
you get Bran Buddies.
Juicy's my account.
And I'm the boss. What do you say, Damon?
No. No.It's crazy.
Well, you've already lost one bet tonight,
although I've never seen
you walk away from one.
Come on, man,
the end of the month, that's 30 days away.
What? You can't make it happen?
I mean, that's what we're
talking about here.
Right, guys?
Yeah, but Juicy's my account.
Come on, buddy.
Do it.
One month.
Fine. It's a bet.
Let's bowl!
Let's do this!
Hey, Rob.
Hey.
Do you need help?
No. No, I'm good.
What brings you here, Mel?
Rob, I am so, so sorry.
I should have talked to
you when I was feeling unsure.
It's just that I thought that...
maybe things would change, you know?
Grow, like a weed...
I mean, a flower,
'cause you are definitely not a weed.
You're a...
a big, strong flower.
A rose with thorns...
not hurtful thorns.
Manly.
Resilient, like a perennial.
Exactly,
which is why I know that
you're going to be okay.
You know what's great about perennials?
They never give up.
They keep pushing through, every spring,
and I'm not giving up either.
Rob, I don't think it's going to happen.
You don't know that.
I mean, you said so yourself.
You're unsure.
I was unsure,
but now I'm pretty sure.
Look...
I know you have your fears,
but just hang onto the ring.
Just trust me.
You'll figure out we're
meant to be together.
'Kay.
[Damon]: You want to
change the way people think
about dental work
and we want your brand to reflect that.
So when people see this sign...
they don't cringe...
they smile.
I don't know how you made root canals cool,
but you did.
Heck, I want one.
I'm just glad I stayed awake.
They gave me nothing! No feedback!
That was a total snooze-fest.
[applause, Fred laughing]
Yes!
Life is bolder with Juicy Soda...
which is my account.
We nailed it! Mm.
So, Casanova,
did you find the girl?
Not yet.
What about Fiona?
Come on, man,
I'm 10 years older than her last boyfriend.
Maybe you'll get lucky
tonight at the J-oomph launch.
Oh, yes...
a room full of granolas and juice heads.
Should be lots to pick from.
You kept the ring?
I tried giving it back,
but he was all, like...
"I'm a perennial, and I'm not giving up."
I don't even want
to try to understand what that means,
but what I do know
is you need to stop saying
"yes" to these guys
because you want to save yourself
public embarrassment.
Jules, you don't understand.
When someone asks you to marry them,
and you have all of these eyes on you...
eyes that want you to say yes
because if you don't,
then wow, that would
be really uncomfortable...
it's hard to say "no".
Mel, you need to be more assertive,
like when you're instructing boot camps.
You never have
trouble demanding 10 more reps.
You need to see these propositions
like a boot camp.
You're right. I can be a sergeant.
There you go.
So are you going to give him back the ring?
Maybe next week.
What?
So, what's our strategy?
I was thinking about what you were saying
about tying in product
with our workout and nutrition programs.
Jules, that was a botched wedding rant.
We need to do something bigger.
This city is full of personal trainers
and nutritionists.
We need to find a way to
set ourselves apart,
and seeing as this is a launch party,
they're obviously trying to find
ways to get their brand out there.
So, let's get familiar with the products
and meet some people.
'Kay.
Hi.
May I try one of your
Green Goddesses, please?
Thank you.
Great smoothies.
Sorry, um... Will Peters.
I'm in advertising.
Melanie.
Melanie. It's a pleasure to
meet you, Melanie.
So, you herewith company peeps,
or are you here alone?
Actually, I came herewith my sister.
We are the company.
Hey, sis! My bad. I got stuck over there.
Don't worry, I was just keeping your
sister company, actually.
We were just getting acquainted.
You don't understand.
She's fragile right now,
getting over a broken engagement.
She is done...
dating, marriage, the whole thing.
[laughs]
Listen, it's...
been a pleasure, you ladies.
Enjoy.
See what I did there? I just shot him down.
Bam!
Bam. Got it.
'Kay, good,
'cause I have got some interest going.
Oh, yeah?
Not that kind of interest.
Some product placement.
So if I leave you, you'll be good, right?
I'll be so good.
Scout's honor.
Maybe you should put that ring back on.
Hey.
[techno music playing]
Hey, could I just get a soda?
Diet... no?
Okay, I'll just not drink this.
I just found your future bride-to-be.
Yeah?
So why aren't you hitting on her?
Fine, I struck out.
[laughs]
Then I like her already.
I think you'll like her a lot.
One in the red.
Oh yeah, you're right.
She's cute.
So do we have a contender?
Sure. Why not?
She's the one.
I know, right?
This stuff would work better as fertilizer.
I won't tell anyone.
So if you're not a fan
of all this good stuff,
what's keeping you here?
My sister.
She thought maybe we could tie some product
to our brand.
Brand, really? That's what I do.
Branding, advertising...
Wow, that's...
pretty popular tonight.
So, uh...
what do you and your sister do?
We are
personal-trainers slash-nutritionists.
Really?
'Cause I'm looking for a personal trainer.
You mean you don't have
a gym where you work?
You know, I'm not really a
fan of going to the gym.
I work out. I play basketball,
but I'm just not into people watching me,
you know?
I'm sure a lot of your clients feel that.
I guess.
You know, I'd love to know
more about what you do,
the classes you offer,
the whole nutrition... thing.
Maybe you could tell me about that
over some real food?
There's a great Italian
place just down the street.
No.
No, you're gluten-free? We
could go somewhere else.
Nope. Not gluten-free.
Well, maybe I could just
get your card, or...
your number.
We could help each other, you know,
you with getting me in shape,
me with your branding.
Sorry. No.
Actually... yes.
Um... remember, no?
Mel would be thrilled to
give you a consultation.
That's what we do, you know,
go over people's personal goals.
That's great.
How about Saturday?10:00 A.M.?
Saturday it is.
Here you go.
Great.
I will shoot you an email with my address,
and I'll see you then.
Okay.
Bye.
What?
[Mel]: Take a deep breath in...
[inhales]
and release.
[exhales]
Thank you for sharing
your practice with us today.
Namaste.
Great class, everyone.
See you next week, and
remember, stay active.
Thank you! Bye!
Bye.
So you've got to get cleaned up.
You've got your 10 A.M.
Okay, you said shut it down,
and there I was, shutting it down,
and you just... started it back up.
He's in marketing, Mel.
That's exactly what we need.
Oh, come on, Jules. He's a salesman.
It was probably, like, a line or something.
Actually...
he's legit.
Okay, well then,
why don't you give him his consultation,
and maybe the two of you can
talk about all this stuff?
I can't.
I've got to do some errands.
So you'd better hurry. You
don't want to be late.
Fine...
but I'm wearing the ring.
This is strictly business.
[buzzer sounds]
Come in.
Looks like a rich
man's bachelor pad in here.
Wow.
Yeah, I guess it could
use a little redecorating.
A woman's touch, maybe?
Can I get you anything? Coffee? Danish?
No, I'm good.
Did you already eat?
Yeah, sorry, I was starving.
What did you have for breakfast?
Uh... a macchiato from the coffee shop,
and some cereal.
This cereal?
It's a... childhood habit.
Is this what you eat every
day for breakfast?
No, not every day...
Okay, yes, every day,
but sometimes, I also
get something at work.
This will obviously have to change.
So...
do you ever have breakfast with Will Peters?
Will?
Yeah, he's my boss, but he's also a buddy.
You know, we play poker, shoot hoops.
So, what, your buddy struck out,
and you figured you'd give
it a good old college try?
I'm sorry, I have no I...
You both hit on meat the party.
Well, obviously.
I mean, look at you. You're
beautiful and... oh...
Married?
Engaged.
Right.
[grunts]
What was that?
Nothing.
Sorry, I'm just surprised
because you weren't wearing your
ring the other night.
It's a bit loose,
so I get nervous wearing it out.
So, what are your exercise and
nutrition goals?
Actually, I think I'm already pretty fit.
Oh, yuck...
Do you know what?
Would you look at the time?
I actually have a...
Sorry, I do a lot of take out. Here.
I can see that.
Thank you.
[water running]
[gasps]
Oh, no, no, no, no!
What?
Um, my ring just slipped off.
This is... this is bad. This is really bad.
It's okay, it's okay.
It's probably just stuck in the pipe.
[Mel]: Is it in there?
You know what,
you're going to have to
give me just one second.
Please, I can't lose it.
Yeah, I get that, but I'm
sure worst-case scenario,
your fiancé would understand.
That's the thing.I'm...
I'm not really engaged.
I'm giving the ring back.
What?
Why is that?
It didn't work out.
So you just wear the
ring to deter guys like me?
Okay, well, I've just been through a lot,
and yeah,
I do want to deter dating,
marriage, all of that stuff.
I'm done with it all.
[bang, grunts]
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Oh, my gosh, thank you so much.
All right.
Well, I guess the next steps are
I will write you up a grocery list
of healthy food staples,
and we'll arrange a physical assessment,
and take it from there.
Sound good?
Sure, whatever you think.
Okay.
Oh, no, no, it's okay. I'll
just let myself out...
and thank you again for the...
Don't mention it.
'Kay.
You should have seen the look on his face
when I told him I was done with dating.
It was like a balloon deflating.
Well, did you at least talk to
him about our branding?
No, of course not.
What? I didn't want him thinking
I wanted to spend more time with him.
Besides, I'm pretty sure
he's trying to get out of
this whole training thing
anyway.
All right, here's the
rest of the guest list,
complete with addresses.
Why don't you start handing some to me,
and I will sign.
Sign what?
The invitations to your wedding anniversary.
Whoa. Is that the guest list?
Anna, I thought we agreed to keep it small.
You only expect60% of those you invite
to actually show up.
Well, if we're going to
haveth at many people over,
it was a good thing Rob was just here,
cutting back the shrubs.
He was?
I asked him to do some landscaping out back.
It's a garden party, right?
He mentioned, um... you've kept the ring.
I'm going to give the ring back.
Oh, Mel, why?
Rob's a great catch.
He has his own landscaping company.
He comes from a really nice family.
In fact, I just saw his mother...
[Gord]: Anna...
I think Roo made her decision.
Okay, fine.
If neither of you girls are getting married,
then I am.
What?
Your father and I have decided,
at our wedding anniversary party,
we are going to renew our vows.
Aw...
And we want the two of you
to stand up for us.
Mom, Dad, that's amazing!
That's really beautiful.
Yeah, I thought so,
and maybe you girls will see
how special getting married can be.
Hey!
Hey.
I'm calling a do-over.
Starting from scratch.
No way.
The girl has sworn off everything, for good.
I mean, I should have known
something was up the other night
when she turned you down... but me?
Oh!
Nice.
Wait a second. You hit on her first...
which means you knew... you
knew she was damaged goods.
It's not my fault you didn't ask.
Nice, Will, real nice.
Ah...
Look, why don't you just admit defeat, okay?
I'm sure you can find the
hook in Bran Buddies,
be the Bran Buddy poster boy.
Is that what this is about?
[Fred]: Whoo-hoo-hoo! Check these out.
I just scored a pair of court-side seats
from the Juicy reps.
No, you didn't.You've got Little League.
Wow...
some accounts have all the perks.
I wonder how many perks Bran Buddies has?
Fine.
You know what? I'll make it happen.
My man!
Vince, want to go to the game?
-Yeah!-Yeah!
I can get out of Little League.
[Jules]: Take a deep breath. Hands up...
[inhaling]
and Swan down...
No, I'm going to take a class right now.
[whispering]It's already started.
Bye. Bye-bye-bye.
[Jules]: Up in the chest...
[whispering]Can I squeeze in between you?
And when you're ready,
step back into Plank pose,
and down into Cobra.
Open the chest...
[inhales]
[Jules]: Downward-facing dog.
[back cracks, groans in pain]
Take a few steps with your feet,
stretch out the calves...
Take a breath up.
Back down... and arms up.
[Jules]: Prayer to the heart.
Breathe.
Into Eagle pose.
Wrap your foot around your left leg.
Hands together. Bend into it.
Put your left under your right.
Settle in deep.Breathe.
- [groans]
- Breathe...
Feel your body.
And when you’re ready,
uncross your arms and then your legs,
and take them out of the pose...
and hands to heart,
Prayer pose.
Thank you so much for coming today.
Namaste.
-Thank you!-Thank you!
-Thank you so much.-Namaste. Namaste!
Namaste![high fives]
[Jules]: 'Kay, thank you so much, everyone!
Have a great week! We'll see you soon. Bye!
Wow.
This is a really great set-up you guys have.
You think?
Actually, we're looking for a bigger space.
Really?
I love this whole home vibe thing.
I think it really works with
your sister act.
-You think?-Yeah, for sure.
You know, if you were
thinking of branding,
that's the whole approach I would take.
If you wanted,
I could do up, like, a social media pitch,
press kit...
That's a great idea! Right, Mel?
Uh, did you get my grocery list?
I did. There's just one problem.
I get it.
It's probably too complicated,
what with your lifestyle,
so if you don't want
to go through with this whole thing,
I completely understand.
No, that's not it. I just...
I wouldn't have the first
clue where to find, uh...
chia seeds,
or... broccolini?
I don't even know what that looks like.
Is that, like, a little mini broccoli?
It's actually a cross
between asparagus and broccoli.
See? No clue.
I was thinking,
maybe we could go grocery shopping together.
Together?
No, no, we don't have to do that.
Actually, I can order the food
and have it delivered right to you.
Sure,
but I probably should learn how
to do it myself, right?
I mean, the only aisle I'm familiar with
is the freezer aisle.
Well, he's got a point.
Jules, why don't you go ahead and
take Damon grocery shopping,
seeing as how we've got this
whole sister act thing
going on.
Hey, Mel.
Rob! Hi.
What are you doing here?
Thought I'd come by
and see if you wanted to go for a jog.
Remember our Sunday 10Ks?
Yeah, I do, but, um...
actually, I was just about to go take Damon,
our new client, grocery shopping.
Right? Are you good to go?
Yeah, sure, I can... I'll shower later.
Okay, great.
Yeah.
10K? That's impressive.
You want an energy bar for your run?
Hi.
This is broccolini.
Oh!
What do you do with it?
You can steam it, sauté it...
Maybe you could show me some time.
Don't worry, I'll make sure you
get a step-by-step recipe.
Are you sure?
'Cause I'm really not a good cook.
My... my mom, she never taught me,
not that she was much of a cook anyway.
Actually, I usually ate alone,
but me and the pizza guy,
we got pretty chummy.
Why were you alone so much?
My mom, she worked a lot,
and Dad wasn't really around.
Well, I love pizza.
Really?
Like, whole wheat with soy
cheese or something?
That kind of thing?
No.
Extra cheese, double the
meat, mushrooms, and olives.
I love olives on my pizza.
It brings out the flavor in
the salami or something.
Exactly.
So Rob, he's your...?
Ex-fiancé.
I guess he didn't get the memo.
Which is odd, because I feel like
leaving him at the altar
was sending a pretty big message.
Suppose he's not The One?
Nope... whatever that means.
You're telling me you don't
believe in soulmates
and all that?
Why? Do you?
Yeah, yeah, of course.
Have you ever met The One?
Not yet, but...
still looking.
Off to the grain section.
Now, you're going to want to look for
whole grains, not refined.
Have you always been into all this?
Are you kidding me?
I was the awkward, unhealthy kid.
I loved candy bars.
Thank you.
Great, let's check out some fruit.
All right, the good stuff.
Apples, yeah...
Oh, sorry! Sorry! Uh...
Mel?
Justin! Hi! How are you?
Great.
I was going to call you about
your running group.
Kelly says we need to start doing something,
'cause you know what they say,
the couple that runs together
stays together.
Is that what we should have done?
I'm kidding.
Right.
So we'll just go online and sign up.
Absolutely. I'll see you on the track.
Hey, bud,
there's some spilt juice by the smoothies.
Who was that guy?
Oh, that was Justin...
my, uh... my first fiancé.
You were engaged before Rob?
Twice, actually.
Three times. You've been
engaged three times?
Mm-hmm.
Well, it looks like we’re done here,
so I'm just going to get going.
Yes, do you want me to drive you or...?
Oh, no, it's okay. I'll walk.
I didn't go for that run, so...
I will see you for your assessment.
Yes.
Okay.
[Damon]: Three dudes have proposed to her,
and she said yes every time.
Isn't that good?
I mean, she's said "yes" three times,
so a fourth should be no big deal, right?
No, it's not good
because she didn't marry any of them,
and I'm guessing that's
why she’s thrown in the towel.
Sounds like you should start working
on the Bran Buddies account.
Three pulled pork tacos,
please, extra hot sauce.
Have you asked her
why it didn't work outwith the first three?
Are you kidding?
I mean, I could tell she was embarrassed.
Plus... what if it's her?
You know, what if
there’s something wrong with her?
She looked fine to me.
You should dig a little deeper.
I mean, women love it
when you seem interested in them.
Susan thinks I'm right into her Reiki,
when really, I don’t understand it at all.
Who does?
Well, she likes olives.
Wow, good for you.
You're really getting to
know her, aren't you.
Thank you!
[laughing]
What a guy.
[Mel]: Keep breathing. Legs up.
Okay, toss the ball. Right?
All right.
Catch.
Nice. Toss it back.
Okay.
Keep breathing, breathing...
I'm giving you a weight now.
Easy.
You've obviously got a strong core.
Let's go down to the
ground and do the Pigeon.
Okay, follow me.
Right leg forward, left leg back,
go down onto your elbows.
Breathe. You feel that stretch?
Oh, I feel that.
All right, Bendy, can you do this?
Oh, impressive, hot shot...
but my dad can do that.
Can your dad do...
this?
Nope, but my Scouts can.
Oh.
All right, can you do this?
Right leg forward, left leg back.
Okay.
Knee, uh... an inch above the ground.
Right there, yeah.
We're going to test your stability.
I'm going to push you, okay? Ready?
Yeah, how's that for stable?
'Kay.
Don't hurt your fingers.
Ready?
Yep.
That's Choco Puff power.
Yeah?
How's this for vegetable power?
Well, let's check your stability,
-Vegetable power.-Oof!
[hisses in pain]
Uh... ooh...
-Your knee?-Yeah.
You all right?
- I'm fine.
- You sure?
Mm...
It's okay. It should be fine now.
I don't know about that.
You really should rest
it the first few hours.
I think I know what I'm doing.
[whimpers in pain]
Okay, that's it. You're staying...
at least until the swelling goes down.
Fine.
[Mel]: Pizza's not
usually on the health menu.
[Damon]: It is tonight.
Doesn't hurt to cheat every now and then.
This is so good.
What? Do I have something on my face?
No, it's just me. I, uh...
I just like when people surprise me.
So tell me something about yourself.
Is it just you and your sister,
or... you have family here?
My parents are here.
They're actually celebrating
their 30-year wedding anniversary
in a month.
Really? Wow, that's amazing.
What about your parents?
They're celebrating20
years of being divorced.
Is that why your dad wasn’t around?
Yeah, that would be why...
but my mom did the best she could.
You know, she worked a lot of night shifts,
but she always made a point to
have breakfast with me.
A bowl of Choco Pops, every morning.
You mentioned Scouts earlier.
You a leader, or just a really tall Scout?
I volunteer at the community center
on Tuesdays.
Were you a Scout?
Straight through to Explorer.
This was right after I
got my survival badge.
Oh!
-That's a tough one to get.-Yeah.
These guys were like the
brothers I never had.
I promise to always do my best,
to keep myself strong in mind and body,
to always help those in need,
and to help myself through positivity
and good values.
I'm impressed.
Thanks.
Hey...
I know it wasn’t on the grocery list,
but I happen to have some ice cream
in the freezer.
Now, I know you said to get
rid of all that stuff,
but come on, it's ice cream.
Well, it does have calcium.
Especially if you put whipped cream on top.
Oh, I have got whipped cream.
I'll make us a couple sundaes?
I love it.
Good.
You know, you are turning out
to be the best
personal-trainer slash-nutritionist ever.
So you hurt your knee,
and then you stayed over and had dinner
together with Damon.
No... I mean, yeah,
but it wasn’t like that.
You know,
the first few hours after an
injury are crucial,
so I was doing the right thing.
Uh-huh.
Don't "uh-huh" me, Jules. He's a client...
one that you insisted we take on.
Besides, even if I was interested,
which I am not,
I doubt it would go anywhere,
because his parents
divorced when he was younger,
and I can tell by the way he talks about it,
he still has some serious issues from it.
Actually, I wouldn't be surprised
if he was scared of marriage.
Then you don't have anything
to worry about...
you know, with you two hanging out
and eating pizza.
Exactly.
Actually, I kind of just feel bad for him.
I mean, it'd be sad
if he was putting off getting married.
Who's putting off getting married?
Me.
Damon.
Sweetheart, don't say that.
I mean, wait... look what I had fixed.
If this can be fixed, so
can your relationship.
Mom, why did you do that?
Now, now, now, don't bug Mom
because she changed your ex's name
on the cheese board.
Speaking of cheese board,
let's put some cheese on there, huh?
Who's this Damon your sister mentioned?
Hmm?
Oh, he's just a client.
Single client?
I don't know. Is he?
I don't know.
You know what?
Let's go help Jules with that cheese
because I am suddenly so hungry.
She is in unreal shape. It's insane.
She was doing these abs
things like they're nothing.
I'm going to be hurting for a week!
So she's doing all these moves, right,
trying to impress me with
these exercise moves,
and she, like, blows out her knee,
so we just end up eating pizza...
uh, with olives, obviously,
and they were black, not green.
You should have seen her.
It was awesome.
She had, like, five slices.
Oh, and then,
I find out that she used to
be a Scout, like me,
only she still does it, like...
a volunteer, you know?
How nice is that?
Are you going to bowl or what?
Right.
[Fred]: Well, I'm glad you
took my advice to heart.
I mean, when you start
falling for someone...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Okay, no one is falling for anybody,
all right?
It's like you said.
I don't even know what she's into, you know,
if we're going to have anything in common.
It's just... hit or miss.
Just sometimes... I hit it.
Like this...
Oh! Yes!
I am on a winning streak.
Unbelievable.
Okay, we are going to start working
on our friendship badges.
No better way to do that
than to start with working and
making friendship bracelets.
This is everything you’re going to need.
This is for your table.
You can take that back.
All right, have fun!
Avery...
why not join the other girls
and make a friendship bracelet, too?
Oh, no thanks. I'd rather not.
Besides, I won't have a
friend to give it to anyway.
Avery... just try.
Please make a bracelet.
You will arena nifty badge,
and it will come in handy one day...
and I promise,
you will have a friend to give it to.
Okay.
What do you think? Blue? It's so pretty.
Okay...
Today, we're going to be Good Samaritans,
as we should be every day,
and we are going to now
work on our environment badges
by going outside
and cleaning up the park next
to our community center.
So everybody grab a pair of gloves!
Okay, does everyone have a pair of gloves?
Yeah!
[Damon]: You know, actually...
I don't.
Could I borrow a pair?
Oh, thank you!
Just a second, girls.
What are you doing here?
I'm volunteering.
Uh, well,
technically, I'm training to
become a volunteer.
Right now, I'm on probation,
but I'm sure with you as
my coach, I'll pass.
Right?
Is this something new, or...
You inspired me.
So here I am.
All right,
but don't think I'll go easy on you.
Hey, you've already put me through
the gears as my trainer,
so I wouldn't expect anything less.
Good.
Okay, girls, this is your new
Scout leader-in-training,
Mr. Damon.
[they giggle]
Hi, Mr. Damon.
Pleasure to meet you. May I say,
you all look very smashing in your uniforms.
Okay, everyone, find a partner.
Pair up and let's go.
Okay, Eva, you want to be my partner?
That's Avery. She always
has such a hard time.
Give me a minute.
Yeah.
Avery, please join the other girls in line.
They don't like me.
It's okay. I'll be right there with you.
[Damon grunts]
[strains and grunts]
Avery, did you give
me tiny gloves on purpose?
Hey, listen.
It's my first day, and
I'm a little nervous.
Would you mind showing me the ropes?
-Yeah, okay.-Okay?
Avery, you can walk with me
and help me keep an eye on Mr. Damon.
Yeah, okay.
Okay, girls!
Uh, Mia, Lisa, lead the way out.
Let's go! Let's go!
Avery, maybe outside,
you can join Mia and Lisa and be a trio.
So what's the story there?
[Mel]: Avery?
She's just really shy.
She gets bullied at school,
that kind of thing.
Her parents figured
this would be a positive
environment for her.
Well, it worked for me.
So how many badges did
you end up collecting?
21.
Impressive.
Mm-hmm. What about you?
Just shy of 18.
Oh, not bad, not bad.
I wanted to get more,
especially the leadership badge.
I was working towards that
one when my parents split, so...
had to give it up.
You know, no one to take me...
I figured my mom could use the
help around the house.
Put the Scout training to work, you know?
Helped with the garbage, the lawn...
Well, I'm sure your
mom appreciated all that you did.
Maybe we can start working on
your culinary badge.
You did get my recipes, right?
Yes, I did.
Going to try out the first one tonight.
[blows whistle]
Okay!
How about we play a game of "it" tag?
Guess who's it?
I am!
[screaming]
[Damon]: Oh, no!
I'm going to get you, I'm going to get you!
[laughing]
You're it! She's it!
[Mel screams and laughs]
Mel!
I'll be right back, okay?
All right, come here.
Rob...
what are you doing here?
I just landed
the community center landscaping project.
It's big.
They're landscaping their entire property.
Wow, that's great.
What's your client doing here?
Damon?
Oh, he's training to become a Scout leader.
For girls?
Men can be Scout leaders, too.
In fact, Chloe's
dad volunteered all last year.
Oh, Damon has a kid?
No.
He's not even married.
Oh, really?
Time out, time out!
Well, look,
I wanted to talk to you about
setting another date.
Date?
Nothing too soon from now or anything.
Rob, I...
I don't know. We talked about this.
Girls, I've got an idea
as to who might really like to be it,
but you're going to have to
help me convince her, okay?
I know, and I told you,
I'm not giving up on us.
Just think how happy it
will make your mother.
Plus, we make a really good team.
Rob...
I don't want to just make a good team.
I want...
What?
Hey, what are you guys doing?
You're "it".
Oh, I am, am I?
[laughs]
Mel...
I'm sorry, Rob, this is their time,
but we'll chat later, okay?
I'm going to get you!
She's it, she's it!
Girls, your moms are here,
so make sure you have everything.
Great job today.
Bye, girls! Bye!
You did all right today.
Well, thank you,
and hey, I'm sorry about earlier,
but it kind of looked
like you needed an out.
Right.
So, uh...
when did you realize that
Rob and the other...
is it two?
Yes, there are just three, thankfully.
Right.
When did you realize you
should have said no?
I'm pretty sure I knew even
before they proposed.
It was just so overwhelming when they did.
I mean, Justin,
he did it over the loudspeaker
of the store that he managed.
Darren did it while
reporting on the weather,
and Rob was in front of a packed spin class.
Ouch.
I know, right?
And then my mom, she tried to convince me
that I would grow to
love them in "that way,"
but I didn't.
And what way is that?
You know, the way you should feel
when they propose...
that giddy feeling knowing
you'll get to spend the rest of
your life with this person
that makes you believe in
happily ever after.
That way.
Wow, you look all fancy for taco night.
Actually, I am not going to
Mom and Dad's tonight.
I have a date.
Really? Is it someone I know?
Ian, from running group.
Oh, Jules, that's so great. He
seems like such a sweet guy.
Yeah.
It's been such a long time, I
hope I remember how it's done.
Mm, just be yourself,
and it will be amazing.
Thanks.
Hey, um, keep your phone on you
in case I need to send you a "help me" text.
I got you.
Have fun.
Okay, season lean chicken breast...
and then pop in the oven for 10 minutes.
Okay.
Now... you.
Oil pan...
and...
trim ends of the broccolini.
Okay!
Done!
Hashtag, master chef.
Yes!
Yes, yes!
[laughs]
[sizzling]
[smoke alarm beeps]
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Oh, no, no, no, no! No, no, no!
[alarm continues beeping]
Come on, come on...
[stops beeping]
[phone rings]
Hey, Damon.
I just set my kitchen on fire.
Oh, no!
Yeah.
I was trying one of the recipes you gave me,
and then there was smoke and fire
and my alarm going off.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Maybe you were right,
and I should have helped
you out the first time.
No, it's not you. It's, uh...
just...
now I'm forced to order take-out again,
so I was...
wondering if you... if
you wanted to join me?
Actually, I can't.
It's taco night at my parents' house.
Tacos, huh?
I love tacos.
Me and my buddies, we hit the truck
at least twice a week.
Well...
would you maybe want to join us?
I mean, what kind of nutritionist
would I be anyway
if I sent you off to some
greasy take-out joint?
You have a point.
Great. I will come by and pick you up.
Okay, see you soon.
Bye.
Who shoots hoops?
Oh, that's me and my dad.
After dinner, we usually come outside
and play a little one-on-one.
Yeah, you any good?
Well, let's just say my dad calls me "Roo"
because I got bounce.
Really?
'Cause I play with some buddies,
and I'm a bit of a ringer myself.
Oh, yeah? We'll see about that.
Hello!
Oh, Mel, honey! Hi, sweetie!
Oh, and...?
Hi. Damon Hadley.
Hi, Damon. Nice to meet you.
Anna.
Mel didn't tell me she was bringing a date.
Oh, Damon's not my date. He's a client.
Oh.
I almost burned down my kitchen
trying one of your daughter’s recipes, so...
Gord, this is Damon, Mel's...
Client, Dad.
I figured the least I could
do is invite him over to dinner
after one of my recipes failed.
Nice to meet you.
Pleasure to meet you, sir,
and your daughter's recipes, they're great.
I'm the problem.
I never really learned how to cook.
[Mel]: You know,
I usually help my mom make the tacos,
but if you wanted to...
I wouldn't want to impose.
No, no, not at all.
Come on in. We'll get you set up.
All right, now, a pinch of cumin.
Oh, okay.
Taste it. Always taste.
What do you think?
Oh... I always like a lot of spice.
Perfect, me too.Here.
This one's for you.
All right!
And then the key
is to julienne the carrots like this.
You throw those in with the cabbage,
toss it...
and then you make your taco...
Uh-huh.
Like that...
Perfect.
All right! There we go.
Yes! Okay. If you can grab the tacos...
Yes.
I will get the hot sauce.
Dinner's served!
[crunches]
Damon, these are so delicious.
Thank you.
He's a quick learner, too, which is good.
Who doesn't love a man
who knows his way around a kitchen?
Or a gal who knows her way around
the basketball court.
Isn't that right, Roo?
Oh, yeah, Roo.
Mel told me about that.
She got that from her mad
skills on the court?
Uh, you know what?
I'm just going to clear away some dishes.
Well, actually,
she got it
from her bounce at the altar.
I mean, just like a kangaroo,
this one would bounce out of there
before anyone had a chance to say, "I do".
Gordon!
Um, well, I'm sure once Mel
meets the right person,
she won't bounce anymore.
You're absolutely right, Damon.
What about you?
Anyone special in your life?
No, still... still searching.
[Anna]: Really?
Uh, hey, Mom, what's all this stuff?
Oh, I'm putting together a video collage
for our anniversary party.
30 years.
I heard. That's incredible.
I'm a lucky man.
Why are you putting these in there?
To show our joy over the last 30 years,
which, of course, includes
you and your sister.
By the way,
I hope her date's going well.
Oh, yeah, I forgot to check my phone!
And here’s our little go-getter.
Melanie. Cute Girl Scout, huh?
Yeah.
Oh, so cute.
Aw...
[Anna]: Yeah.
Isn't she beautiful?
Yeah, she is.
Uh, well, no "help me" text from Jules,
so I guess her date’s going pretty well.
Think both of our daughters
are having a successful night.
Hey, Dad, how about some pick up?
You bet. Damon?
I'm in.
Yeah, let's go.B-Ball.
Yeah!
Oh, nice!
Oh, oh, oh!
Cold drinks and cookies when you're ready.
Oh... hi.
Mom, why did you invite Rob over
when you know it’s taco night?
Well, he's always liked
coming over in the past before,
so I just thought...
You thought what?
That maybe we’d get back together?
[Rob]: Damon, nice to see you again.
[Anna]: You're hardly broken up.
I mean, you still have his ring.
I was really surprised
when you brought a date tonight.
Mom, Damon is not my date,
and I am giving the ring back to Rob, okay?
So whatever it is you’re doing,
you need to stop.
Because of Damon? He is lovely.
He's still searching...
Please, just stop, okay? Stop.
Hey, how about a game of 21?
[Mel]: Uh, you know what?
Dad, I don't think
Rob came over to play basketball.
-Right, Rob?-I'll team up with you, Mel...
unless Damon thinks that would
make the teams uneven.
We got this. Right, Gord?
You bet.
We'll take it on.
Gotcha, Dad.
♪ ♪
In your face.
Whoa.
Nice shot.
Okay, that's a tie.
[Damon]: All right, good game.
Oh, it's not over.
First person to make a basket from
the end of the driveway
wins.
I don't think we need to...
Hey, if you can't do it, just say so.
-Oh, I can do it.-Want to bet on it?
Fine.20 or 50?
1987 Lakers Championship ring.
Bought at auction.
Rob, what are you doing?
You in or not?
Right.
Limited Edition GMT Chronograph.
Awarded to me for landing six
clients in a month.
[sighs]This is not good.
Thanks for the game, Mr. Banning.
Oh, and Mrs. Banning?
I'll be by at, let's say, mm...
noon to finish off that landscaping.
[chuckles]
Good one, Mom.
Sorry.
Let's go inside, honey.
I'm sorry about all that.
No, you have nothing to be sorry for.
It's me.
I never have been able to
walk away from a bet...
even when I should.
Yeah, well...
my mom, she pushes sometimes,
and I don't... I don't want any
more pressure, you know?
I just want it to feel right, for me,
and not just because
I don't want to hurt anyone's feelings.
Wait, are you saying
you haven't completely
given upon everything?
Good night, Damon.
Good night, Melanie.
Mm, look what just came in.
Bran Buddy samples.
The bet's off.
What, the olive angle didn’t work?
No, it's just...
she's already been engaged three times,
and now I come along and start messing
with any chance she might ever have
of doing this again.
I'm confused.
I thought she wasn't
ever going to do this again.
Yeah, well, I don't
think she’s totally given up.
Because of you?
I don't know...
but I can't say I don't hope so.
Whoa, are you telling me
you actually want to marry this girl?
I'm telling you the bet's off.
Really?
Well, if it is,
you're going to be chewing on these
instead of hanging outwith the Juicy crew,
who, by the way,
are live streaming their private jet party
for their online promo.
I'm good.
Really, I don't mind losing.
I'm not going to ask her to marry me
over a bet I never should have placed.
Works for me.
Damon!
For your morning coffee.
Okay, ladies!
Today, we are going to
learn some dance moves
in preparation for your dance badges.
Okay, everybody, spread
out, arms-length apart.
All right, let's start with the twist!
Yeah!
♪ ♪
It's okay. I'll handle it.
Okay.
Good job! Good job.
Hey, Avery?
Do you think you might want
to dance with me?
I'm not very good,
but maybe you could show me a few moves?
-Okay.-Okay?
Come on.
♪ ♪
I like this.
Good job!
Roll it down.
And up. Down low.
You have got some seriously good moves.
Ready to show these girls what you got?
-Yes!-Yes.
All right, ladies? Ladies!
If I could just have your
attention for one minute.
Okay, girls. Come on.
Hit it!
♪ ♪
Take it away, Avery!
Keep going, Avery!
[Scouts applauding]
[Mel]: Aw...
That girl doesn't know how amazing she is.
The other girls could
learn a thing or two...
I'm so sorry. I...
Mel?
Darren, hi!
Thought that was you.
How've you been?
Uh, I... I've been great. How about you?
I'm going to ask my girlfriend,
Diana, to marry me.
Hopefully, she'll say yes and
not run out of the church.
I'm sure she won't.
Uh, not... she won't run out of the church.
Right.
Yeah.
It was nice to see you, Mel.
You too.
Wish me luck.
Good luck!
[buzzes in]
I just got off the phone
with the coordinator for
the KLP morning show.
Remember I sent them
the press kit Damon put together?
They want us to be on their show.
Isn't that great?
I told you hiring Damon was a good idea.
Oh, it was a good idea, all right.
Well, I'm glad you finally agree.
So I was thinking we should do something
to show our appreciation,
like a free class, or...
A kiss?
Excuse me?
I kissed him, Jules.
What?
When?
At Scouts.
Okay, first of all, I would
have never guessed that,
and secondly, why?
Because I love him.
Damon's the one.
As in, "The One" you
wouldn't leave at the altar?
Yup. That's The One.
That is great.
No, it's not.
It's not?
No. I mean,
I finally find a guy I could
do happily ever after with,
and he's not the marrying kind.
Are you sure?
Jules, I know his type.
He says he's searching,
but he's damaged goods,
and he would bounce faster than I would.
Did he kiss you back?
Yeah, I think so.
See?
Then you won't know unless you ask him.
You want me to ask him to marry me?
[laughs]
You're the one who's
always been put on the spot.
Maybe it's time to put the
shoe on the other foot?
So she kissed you,
and now she won't return your calls?
Sounds to me like you were right,
and she's the one with the problem.
I don't know.
She's amazing in every other way...
and that kiss was...
Was what?
You know, that kind of kiss
where the music just stops and...
You watching Rom-coms in your PJs,
eating ice cream?
Of course not.
Who's that?
[Damon]: Fiancé number three.
[Will]: That's why you should bail,
before you become casualty number four.
Come on, I’ll buy you a taco.
[Mel]: Great job, Heather.
Mia, that is some seriously
beautiful bead work.
You definitely deserve this.
Avery,
you have light in your
feet and in your heart.
Don't ever forget that.
Mm? Oh, I have it right here.
Me?
For you.
What is this?
The Leadership badge you wanted.
Thank you.
Okay, it's time to say goodbye,
so let's close our eyes and make a wish.
Okay!
Have a great night, everyone,
and again, good job today!
[Damon]: Bye, guys!
[cheering, chatter]
-Bye!-Bye!
Bye!
Bye, Avery!
That was really nice of you.
Well, you've been a really
great volunteer, so...
Mel, I was...
uh...
I was wondering about the other day.
Right, of course.
Again, I am so sorry about that.
Oh, no, it's...
it's okay.
You've got a lot going on,
and...
you don't have to worry
because I don't want to
add to that confusion.
I promise, I'll leave you alone.
Marry me!
Excuse me?
[laughs]I know that sounds crazy,
especially after everything I said,
but...
this is different.
I know it is,
and I wanted to be sure next time,
so...
will you marry me?
Uh...
Oh, my gosh, I've seen that face before.
It's mine.
It's my face.
So I get it,
and please, don't feel
pressured into saying yes,
because there's no one around,
so we can just walk away and
pretend this never happened.
Mel, wait. Uh, wait.
I'm just speechless
because I can't believe you
knew what my wish was.
You.
I wished for you.
Does that mean...?
Yes.
Yes?
Yes, I will marry you.
[laughs]
I mean, are you sure?
Because if you need more time, I will...
Yes.
[laughs]
You proposed?
I did.
Isn't it great?
Hey, let's give cred for where it's due.
It was my idea.
Of course it was.
Are you sure about this, Melanie?
I mean, it just seems all really impulsive.
That's the thing.
I don't have to wait for him to grow on me
because I know that I love him,
and I promise you,
I would not put you through this again
if I wasn't sure.
Well, congratulations, Roo.
So what do you think, Mom?
Will you help me plan the wedding?
Because I want everything to
be absolutely perfect.
Really?
In the past, you haven't
wanted to make a big deal.
I know, but this is different.
He's the one. He really is The One.
You hear this, Gord?
We're planning a wedding!
[chuckles]
Does that mean we can stop planning
the anniversary party?
Dad!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
[cheering]
Good game, man.
Whoo!
I don't believe it.
Well, believe it, 'cause it's happening.
Wow. Talk about a slam dunk.
You sure about this wedding, buddy?
I mean, because you bailed on the bet,
you don't have to go through with it.
I'm sure,
and this has nothing to do with the bet.
I wanted to say yes.
Yeah, but you've still got to say "I do."
Trust me, it's pretty scary up there.
I sweated right through my blazer.
Yeah, well, it doesn't phase me.
You know why?
Because I love her...
in... you know, in that way.
What way?
In that, uh...
"I feel so lucky to have met her,
and I can't wait to
see what tomorrow brings,"
kind of way.
[sniffling]
I'm sorry. It's just...
I mean, who would have
thought by you making a bet
to get her to say yes,
you'd end up being the one proposed to...
but it doesn't change the
fact that you bailed,
right?
Don't worry,
I'll make magic with that
Bran Buddies account.
My man.
[Fred]: Juicy Soda’s my account.
[Jules]: Wow.
How long have you been
hiding your Choco Pops addiction?
They're for Damon.
He and his mom
used to eat them
for breakfast every morning,
so I thought it’d be nice
to add them to his grocery list.
What are you going to do with your dresses?
You're not going to wear
one of those, are you?
No, of course not.
I'm going to find the
perfect dress this time,
and these, I'm going to give to charity,
except, I don't know...
maybe I'll keep this.
Have you told Rob?
I'm going to stop over and see him
on my way to Damon.
[doorbell rings]
Rob!
Mel.
I was just on my way to see you.
Is that the one you plan on wearing
when you marry Damon?
What? No, of course not...
I'm sorry, how did you...?
I heard, Mel.
Rob, I'm so sorry.
I was just about to go tell you.
It was a bet, Mel.
What?
He bet on you,
but instead of this watch,
the wager was some account at work.
You say "yes" to his proposal, and he wins.
Rob, if this is your way of
trying to get me back
and break it off with Damon,
then you're not doing a...
I know you asked him, Mel,
because at the basketball court,
they were all talking
about what a slam dunk your proposal was.
Okay, it's time for you to go now, Rob.
He rolled the dice on you, Mel,
and he won.
Mel.
Mel!
Hey!
Does the dress shop know you
left with that on?
Ooh, were you thinking a
big wedding or small?
'Cause my mom's already calling relatives.
That depends. What did you bet on?
Or did the wedding not even matter,
and it was just about getting me to say yes?
I don't know what you're talking about.
I know about the bet, Damon.
Mel, it wasn't like that.
Oh, I know...
because I'm the one that proposed to you.
So what?
Did that just raise the stakes or something?
No, I called it off.
I called the bet off before you asked.
Mel, I was falling in love with you.
I didn't want it to be about a bet.
What's the first law in the Scouts, Damon?
A Scout is trustworthy.
Wow...
This is going to be quite a party.
Yes, it is.
You know, I joke,
but I'd have a party for a hundred people
if it'd make your mother happy,
because when I saw her working that grill
at the street fair,
I knew she had to be my wife.
The only problem was, so did my buddy.
Frank Hendersen...
yeah, he was something.
Handsome, a doctor...
So I asked him. I said,
"Frank, give me a chance."
He said, "Sure, go for it...
"but if you lose,
it's anyone's game."
So, needless to say,
I spent the next month trying to outdo Frank
for your mother's attention.
Did mom know?
You know, I'm not sure...
but the point is,
the circumstances in which you meet someone,
or fall in love...
it really doesn't change how
you feel about them,
because when you know it’s right,
it's right,
and when it's not...
we move on.
Thanks, Dad.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Are you sure about this?
Because there’s no going back.
Yeah, I'm sure.
Okay. Bye.
Bye.
Hey, Rob.
Hey.
You all right?
Yeah, I will be.
Look, Mel, I didn't
enjoy having to tell you.
I just figured you should know...
whether it meant you came back to me or not.
Have you?
No, Rob, I haven't.
You deserve somebody
who’s going to love you back
just as much as you love them.
Hey, Mel?
Despite the bet...
it's really not that unbelievable
to think Damon fell in love with you.
What do we think about when
we think about home?
Warmth.
Family.
Comfort.
That's what Bran Buddies are.
They are homegrown goodness.
That's your brand... a homegrown company
made with homegrown love.
Out of everyone on my team,
I knew it would be you
to brand those tasteless pieces
of cardboard,
and to show my appreciation,
I am putting you on the Juicy team...
but before you say thank you,
I hear they’re having a sponsored luau,
and you know what that means.
Hula girls, Damon.
Great. Thanks.
Don't mention it.
How about you and I go grab a taco,
shoot some hoop?
You know, I think I'm
just going to head home.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Here, let me help you with that.
Damon! Thank you.
That's a lot of cookies.
Yeah, shopping for the anniversary party.
Right.
30 years.
Mm-hmm.
How's Melanie?
Miserable.
I'm so sorry, Mrs. Banning.
I should never have placed that bet.
Once I got to know Mel,
I was...
I was embarrassed.
It was selfish.
Maybe.
Let me ask you this.
Without placing it, would
you have met Melanie?
No, probably not.
Then it was meant to be.
That night you came over...
I know Melanie insisted it was not a date,
but I know my daughter.
Mel loves you...
so bet or no bet,
I can see that you love her.
I do.
I do love her.
There's no way
I could convince her of that now.
Of course there is.
Do the one thing she doubts the most.
Marry her.
[Jules]: Guests are arriving!
I am getting excited.
Me too.
Wow, everything looks perfect.
I think we're ready.
Oh, I've got to go. My date is here.
Oh, he must really like you
to come to a family event like this.
You think so?
Jules, all weddings freak men out,
even wedding anniversaries,
so yeah, he likes you.
[squeals] Yes!
Mom, you look amazing!
Thank you! So do you.
Thank you.
Let's get this show started.
Let's do it.
[Minister]: Do you, Gordon Banning,
give to Anna a new promise
to continue loving her
with the same heart that has
loved her for 30 years,
from now to eternity?
I do.
[Minister]: Do you, Anna Banning,
give to Gordon a new promise
to continue loving him
from the heart that has
loved him for 30 years,
from now to eternity?
I do.
[Minister]: Well then, one more time,
let's seal it with a kiss.
[applause]
Yay!
-So beautiful!-Thanks, sweetie.
Congratulations.
Here, Mom.
You get to throw it again.
Actually, sweetheart,
you might want to hold onto that.
You invited him?
I did.
Mel...
Mel, just give me a chance.
A chance to what?
Explain how you used me?
No, not here.
Not at my parents' wedding anniversary.
Well, then how about at our wedding?
What?
I know making that bet was
a lousy thing to do,
but if I hadn't...
I never would have met you,
so...
if you asked me if I'd do it again?
Yeah.
Yeah, I would...
because before I met you,
I never could have seen
myself walking down that aisle.
You made me believe in happily ever after.
I love you, Mel.
I just...
I hope you still feel the same way.
Melanie Banning...
Will you marry me?
Oh, my gosh.
Hi!
You invited my Scouts?
I figured what's a
wedding without flower girls?
Um...
Hey, honestly,
it's not my intention to
make you feel any pressure,
so if the answer is no...
I understand.
I just wanted to show you
how committed I am to you,
and that I would be honored
to marry you right here...
right now.
I...
I get it. You're not feeling it.
Yes.
I'm sorry, did you say...?
Yes!
Yes?
I said yes.
[cheering, clapping]
Thank you.
[Mel laughs]
You got this, Mel?
Yeah.
["Wedding March" playing]
[Mel laughs]
Thanks, Avery.
In the spirit of Gordon and
Anna's anniversary...
do you, Damon Hadley,
give to Melanie
a promise to love her with all your heart
from now to eternity?
I do.
[Minister]: And do you, Melanie Banning,
give to Damon
a promise to love him with all your heart
from now to eternity?
I do.
[Minister]: I pronounce
you husband and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
[guests cheering and clapping]
Yay!
We did it!
Congratulations.
Who wants cake? Who wants cake?
So, we took the plunge.
Head first.
Are you sure?
I am.
Scout's honor.
I love you, Melanie.
I love you, Damon.
Hit it!
[Avery's dance music playing]
What?
May I have this dance?
What did you do?
[Mel]: You didn't!
[laughs]
Oh, my goodness!
♪ ♪