(indistinct radio chatter)
(Indi) My father always said
that you could never trust a person
that needed something from you.
(Grunts)
But he also said he'd never met anyone
who didn't need something from someone.
Perhaps that's why he
never showed his hurt.
Maybe why he ran away
from all of his problems.
All I know is that somewhere along the path
he lost his purpose.
Which is why I traveled
to the ends of the universe.
To find him again.
(Thunder rumbling)
(Wind howling)
Dad's accident happened
on an earlier combat mission
he led in the Trinity system.
- (Jet whooshing)
- (Explosion)
His mistake was simple,
but resulted in the death
of nearly all of his crew.
On his return to Earth, Dad was accused
of negligence through substance abuse,
but the findings were inconclusive.
Due to his decorated
career as a fighter pilot
- he was pardoned of the case.
- (Engine humming)
But it didn't matter.
He was never the same.
Our family was never the same.
(Kane) You know, you decided
to come out here, remember'?
You wanted to come here.
I didn't come to come here,
I wanted to see you.
Well...
I'm seeing you now, right?
Do you miss home?
This is home.
No, I mean real home.
Earth.
No.
No, I love it out here.
Mom says you're just running away.
Yeah, well, I haven't spoken
to your mother for a long time.
She doesn't know what's going on out here.
True.
(Kane) It's not every day you get to be
part of something new.
I'm making history out here.
We're building an entirely new world
from the ground up.
Pretty crappy world so far.
(Kane) All right, you know what?
Let's take a detour.
Got something I think you'll like.
(Kane) I say we call that one a hit.
No way, Dad. One more, I can do it.
We don't have time.
We've gotta get moving. We're late.
Come on. One more, please.
- Last one?
- Last one.
(Flies buzzing)
OK, hand it over.
Then we've got to go inspect this bunker.
Does this bunker have visor games,
or a hot tub or maybe a bowling alley?
It's a bunker. It's got supplies and food.
That would be boring.
God, I hate these flies.
Know what we call 'em out here?
Spies. You know why?
Enlighten me.
Cos they're space flies.
(Chuckles)
Get it? Exor brought 'em out
on a cargo ship and they're in space...
Why do we even need safety bunkers
when everything's already safe?
Oh, it's just Exor protocol.
You know, sometimes, there's an accident
or something unexpected
and we need a safe place
to get the General and the dignitaries.
Why are they so important?
Because in times of crisis,
we need leadership.
(Flies continue buzzing)
Otherwise, it just becomes anarchy.
- Anarchy?
- Yeah. You know, chaos.
Disorder.
People going crazy.
- Oh, like zombies.
- Yeah, kind of like zombies.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
- Keep that shoulder relaxed.
- Yep.
- Focus on your breathing.
- Mmm-hmm.
- Which way did you miss last time?
- Right.
So, which way you gonna aim this time?
(Indi) A little left.
- What's the wind doing?
- I... I got it.
You got it?
You sure?
- Squeeze it...
- (Fires)
(Kane) Whoa!
Ha-ha! That's my girl!
- Whoo!
- Whoo! Good shot.
Best... shot... ever.
Best teacher ever.
OK, next stop, bunker.
And then I have to drop you back in the
city. Got Rominja coming to stay with you.
Dad, I don't need a nanny.
Why can't I stay up in
the Flotilla with you?
(Kane) Because the Flotilla
is a military base.
And trust me, it's even
less fun than a bunker.
But I'll be back in a week.
And you know you can call me
any time, right?
I'm just gonna be up there in the clouds,
right above you.
(Men shouting indistinctly)
(Indi) Do all those
prisoners get paid to work?
(Kane scoffs) Paid? No.
No, they don't get paid.
It's called reform.
They work to pay back
their debt to society.
(Indi) How do you know
when they've done enough?
(Kane) Those types of people,
they could never do enough.
(Thunder cracking)
(Man on radio)
Anybody! Can anybody hear me?
It's coming toward us
and the prison is breached!
It's out of control!
Whatever these things are,
they killed everything in their path!
(Creature roaring)
(Growls)
(Roaring)
Travek, what's the time?
- (Travek) Time to get up.
- (Groans)
(Jets whooshing)
Good morning, Lieutenant.
(Snaps fingers)
(Groans)
(Coffeemaker beeps)
(Coffee pouring)
(Lights powering up)
Oh no, no. Down.
(Travek) Rise and shine.
Down.
(Powers down)
I am reading higher than normal
alcohol levels in your bloodstream, sir.
- You have seven infrastructure reports...
- (Sighs)
to go through.
And you have three new messages.
Play messages.
Location, Flotilla.
(Secretary Millan) Sommerville.
I heard you snuck down
to the outpost last night.
I'm just wondering why you
never think to invite me?
Cos you're an asshole.
Anyway man, I got that stuff you wanted
but it's gonna cost double.
- Delete message.
- So, give me a call.
(Travek) Location, Earth.
(April) Kane, the deal with Indi
going out there
was that you actually spend
quality time with her.
And taking her shooting while you're
at work is not what I'm talking about.
Next message.
(Travek) Location, Osiris.
(Indi) Hey, Dad.
I called in late because I thought
you might be in, but obviously not.
(Rominja) Evening, Mr Sommerville.
Oh, we picked some of these ourselves
from the greenhouse.
- (Rominja) Oh, they're good, right?
- Yeah, delish.
We have an excursion that I've been
trying to get your indent on
and if I don't by tomorrow
I'm going to miss out.
Which kinda sucks, unless you want me
to keep having no friends at all.
(Rominja) It's just to
the Sentient Ranges, uh,
just for the day, and I
have all the details
but I know you want to sign off on
everything, so, we waited for you.
(Indi) She waited for you.
(Rominja) Oh, and I think your new
neighbours are moving in.
I heard somebody in there yesterday.
They have a young boy.
So, that should be quite fun for Indi.
- (Indi) Boys are so annoying.
- That's my girl.
Oh, and Dad, Mom also called.
She wanted to talk to you about some
Europe trip her and her new boyfriend,
Todd, are thinking of.
(Feed scrambles and terminates)
Who the hell is Todd?
(Travek) I can't answer that, sir.
Travek, restore the feed. Now.
I cannot.
All communications to the surface
- have been temporarily disrupted.
- (Sighs)
That is helpful.
We have an ETA
on when they're coming back up?
Not at this time, Lieutenant.
But I assure you
we are doing our very best
to rectify the problem.
Yeah, I bet you are.
Travek, send an Ingram to my daughter
as soon as you can.
Tell her, of course, she has my permission
to go on the excursion
and you will forward my indent today.
Travek, do we have any more information
on the disturbance at the prison?
Not at this time, sir.
Travek?
Yes, Lieutenant.
Find out everything you can
on this Todd guy.
Yes, Lieutenant.
(Indi) In the race to colonize
new planets,
Exor was the undisputed leader.
Trusted by the hundreds of millions
who lived and worked under its rule.
Which is why the General
could never let them know
of the project she'd
been assigned to oversee
in the prison far below.
- (Automated voice) Secure line playback.
- (Recording plays)
(Man) It's coming toward us
and the prison is breached.
It's out of control!
Whatever these things are,
they've killed everything in their path.
I don't know what the
hell is happening here,
but the goddamned prisoners are out.
They are out. These things are everywhere!
(Man screams)
(Automated voice) End transmission.
(Indi) In the only time I ever met her,
she told me my name reminded her
of the state she grew up in.
Indiana.
I should have known then that she was more
concerned with her own place in the universe
than the people who actually lived in it.
(Colonel Michaels)
General, the outer cities are gone.
These creatures are going to
kill everything on the surface
and this is our responsibility now.
We created them.
This is coming to the point
where we won't be able to turn back.
If you were in my position, Colonel,
how would you resolve this?
Ethically?
We save as many people as we can
and then tell the truth.
If our involvement in
this were known it would
cripple the company.
The fallout would destroy
generations of sacrifice and legacy.
How long can we honestly maintain
this Comms blackout?
Command won't get wind of it
for a couple of days.
By then, we should
have the situation resolved.
Resolved?
This isn't a maintenance issue here.
It's a population in the hundreds
of thousands.
Our people have families down there.
Millions of lives are at stake
if public outrage shuts down this company.
If we're found out,
what's the worst they can hit us with?
Genocide.
And, while that would be
only one of the charges,
(Inhales) it would be the one
that sticks forever.
The one that our grandchildren
remember us by.
We must not fail.
Of course.
(Exhales)
Call the meeting.
(Wind howling)
(General Lynex) I regret to report
that we are now considering
that the prison has been breached.
The prisoners are in possession
of a lethal Etholanide virus.
We've been informed that any attempt
by us to intervene in any way
or extract any person
or persons from the surface
will be met with the release of the
pathogen into the Capital, Osiris.
(Kane) Sommerville, Kane.
- (Travek) You sound distressed.
- Listen to me.
I need to get a message to Indi
by whatever means possible. Can I do it?
Not at this time, sir.
I want a tag on every single person
at this table for the next 23 hours.
Any unusual movement, isolate them.
Colonel.
This could work.
(Kane) Here's what I need. I need a marked
timeline on all incident reports
from the Capital and the prison every day
for the last seven days. Can I do that?
(Travek) That information
is now classified.
Classified under what jurisdiction?
(Door alarm beeping)
(indistinct announcement over PA)
For the sake of our friendship,
I'm going to tell you the truth.
After that, it's on you.
Most of what you just heard was a lie.
There is no virus.
The prisoners are in possession
of a lethal Etholanide virus.
(Secretary Millan) That's preposterous.
Etholanide is comparable
to a grade-six bioweapon.
It can't even be certified to transport
here, let alone be housed inside a prison.
The prison facility
has a classified research arm
to help fight and prevent disease
on emerging planets.
- So, we grew it here?
- Yes, we grew it.
Five years ago, we did build a facility inside
the prison, but it wasn't for research.
We were breeding a beast called a Ragged.
The idea was to contain these beasts
until there were enough of them
and ship them out of there and use them
in the creation of new colonies
to kill or assimilate indigenous species.
Our prisoners have commandeered
three local supply freighters
and are demanding safe passage
out of the system.
That virus has the potential
to kill all colonies in this galaxy.
By duty of order,
a stage-six threat must invoke
Protocol 84.
Protocol 84 requires
an entire decimation of colony.
However, when the prisoners become aware
of our obligation to invoke the protocol,
I believe we will have
a strong position to negotiate
a more favourable outcome.
There is no hostage situation.
Eight hours ago,
the Raggeds broke free from the enclosure,
and there's carnage in the city.
They're moving toward the Capital.
Kane, it's out of control.
Have they supplied us with a deadline?
We have 23 hours, 11 minutes.
- (Colonel Michaels) It's a cover up.
- (Watch beeping)
In 23 hours, we're gonna blow the reactors.
To them it's just collateral damage.
A mining strip, couple
of cities and a prison.
Every single person on that surface
is there because we put them there.
Because of this organization.
- The General is well aware of the situation...
- (General Lynex) Lieutenant.
I'm aware you have a little girl
alone in the Capital.
You moved me out here
and you knew all along
that this was going on?
The chances of this happening are
so minute, I'm not even going to...
- (Shouts) You let me move my family here!
- I'm not going to argue, OK?
Trust me when I tell you
that we're looking at every angle here.
And I believe that we are gonna
come out of this just fine,
as will your families
and all the other folks down there
on the surface.
They're going to lock down the hangar bay
in the next 20 minutes
at which point no one
can get on or off the station.
(Genera Lynex) But we have to stay calm.
Have a little faith.
We will endure.
(Colonel Michaels)
You're her only hope, Kane.
I just hope you're still
the pilot I remember.
- (Missile explodes)
- (Jet whooshing)
(Missile whooshing)
(Beeping rapidly)
(Switch clicks)
Come on, come on.
Jeez! (Grunts)
(Guns firing)
(Grunts)
(Firing continues)
(Alarm beeping)
(Breathing heavily)
(Yells)
(Guns firing)
(Grunts)
Arm missiles!
Fire!
- (Kane huffing)
- (Pilot groaning)
(Automated voice)
Warning. Exceeding maximum G-force.
Warning.
(Pilot yells)
Warning. Exceeding maximum G-force.
(Engine losing power)
(Alarm beeping rapidly)
Warning.
Emergency override.
Warning. Overload.
Ejection seat engaging.
(Gasping)
(Yells)
- (Seatbelt clicking)
- (Grunting)
(Yelling)
(Screaming)
(Gasping)
(Kane grunts)
(Man grunts)
(Kane groans)
(Gun cocks)
Who are you?
Doesn't matter who I am.
You got a gun pointed at you.
So, why don't you tell
me what you're doing,
cos I just saw you fall from the sky.
(Groans softly)
I was escaping.
Prison's down here.
Not up there.
I'm not a prisoner, but I am a dead man.
If you keep sitting here
like this, so are you.
Now, am I supposed to
take that as a threat?
No, it's not a threat. It's a fact.
We've got just under 22 hours
before this place becomes a dead zone.
You talking about the creatures?
What creatures?
You tell me your problems,
I'll consider telling you mine.
There's a hostage situation at the prison.
The inmates have control
of the nuclear reactors.
They're threatening to blow 'em.
If they do, it's going
to happen in 22 hours.
Is that what they told you up there?
Cos I was there when that riot happened.
Sector 2 Ward Nurse.
Now, I know for a fact
that there's no one left in that prison.
So, either they're lying to you,
or you are lying to me.
I am no threat to you.
So, how about we forget
this ever happened...
Sit down!
You can't make it on your own.
Not with those things out there.
Well then help me!
Because sitting here
getting to know each other isn't working.
You want my help?
What can you do for me?
Why don't you tell me
what exactly is out there?
Why don't you offer me something?
We have 22 hours left
before they blow up this entire planet.
You said that. Good luck.
You're gonna need it.
I have to save my daughter!
She's 11 years old,
and she's alone in the Capital.
Help me!
If I don't get there, she will die.
And I guarantee that no one
up there gives a shit
about anybody down here.
And?
I have access to a military grade
safety bunker.
You help me get to the Capital,
you help me find my daughter,
I will give you refuge.
How's that for an offer?
You're gonna have to trust me on that.
It's tough down here.
Trust has to be earned.
I don't have time for that.
(Sy) Hey.
Hey!
You want the Capital, right?
Osiris is that way.
You need to go east.
OK.
Nice jacket.
(Warden Mourdain over PA)
Your life ended the day you were sentenced-
You are no longer a person.
You are no longer valued by the human race.
(indistinct shouting)
The only thing you can give back
is your unrelenting commitment to work,
and serve
the every need of this prison
and the people of this colony.
(indistinct announcement over PA)
Every day, I find one of these hairs
in my meal.
And I know where it comes from.
I know the Warden
he goes into the kitchen
and he takes one of his hairs
and he puts it in my food.
You see that? You see that, Vim?
Always.
(Vim) All clear.
All right.
Carmel's serving solitary. He has the key.
You guys remember his drawing
from last week, right?
Yeah.
The only part missing
is getting the hexon filament,
divert it from the emergency release.
You actually understood all of that?
Didn't he say we needed a conduit
of some kind?
Yeah. That part's simple.
Our socks. The cotton fibres.
- That's it?
- Any one of us could do it.
Carmel also lost his mind
on that last stint in solitary.
Gentlemen, we need to question
the validity of this information.
He might have been jacking off
onto that lamp post for all we know.
Quiet.
Besides, we can't even
get inside the spectral tubing.
It's pressure sealed.
We can't even get to the filament.
We can't get to it. So, why are
we even talking about this, huh?
Carmel's already gotten into one.
Undetected.
- Bullshit.
- No.
That's why we need to move. Now.
Before they discover that.
Which Cell?
He doesn't know.
(Laughing)
He doesn't know. They all look alike.
- He doesn't know?
- (Charles) Of course he doesn't know.
He's insane.
(Plate clatters)
Insanity is a very common affliction
around these parts.
(Sy) This is our only shot.
We just need every solitary cell full.
It's the only way to ensure
that one of us is in the right one.
Then we get free.
Get access to the system via the guard post
and trigger the emergency release
to all the cells.
Is Bostok's group still in?
(Sniffs)
They remain decidedly undecided.
(Kreat laughing) Of course, of course!
Cos any way you think on
it, it's a suicide run.
You hear that? Suicide.
They just want more time.
(Kreat muttering)
More time, more time. More time for what?
(Warden Mourdain)
Well, well, well, Mr Carmel.
What is it about solitary
that you love so much, hmm?
Is this yours?
Looks like you're already
ahead of the game.
I find, in here many turn to God
in a desperate realization that their life
has no meaning any more.
So, they pray to a fictitious idol
and tell themselves they're forgiven
as a way to deal with the guilt
of what they've done.
But that's all up here.
Because in reality
if there's a heaven, there
must be a hell, too.
And while I don't believe in any of that
it's still my job to make
good on the idea of it.
So, have faith.
Have faith that this place will become
your own personal hell.
(Laughing)
Maybe you think this is my first stint
in a place like this.
My first time dealing
with a limp-dick loudmouth like you.
I do.
(Chuckles derisively)
Because there's nothing like this place
anywhere else.
We don't even exist under UNSI law...
Am I supposed to care
about any of this?
(Exhales)
Yes, you are.
But you don't.
And that's why you're here.
There'll be no more solitary
for you, Mr Carmel.
Do you understand?
(Groaning)
You think I didn't have a hard life?
You think I didn't have
the same choices you did?
- (Groans)
- Get him up!
The next time you see me,
you show me some goddamn respect!
- (Grunting)
- (Groaning)
Get this maggot out of here!
Straight to the lower cages.
(Chuckles)
You know how many guys go into solitary
and they don't come back?
How many boys we lost, huh?
How many boys don't come back?
But, Kreat, let me ask you something.
How long is your sentence?
Fifty-seven years left.
In this place.
Look, brother,
you're never getting out of here.
Vim and I,
we're never getting out of here.
Unless we do something about it.
(Vim) It's now or never.
It's dark and day.
It's the same
shit stinking soul.
Kreat?
Please.
Bostok's in.
Are you in, Vim?
Let's burn this place to the ground.
(Laughs)
(Sy) I need you two to rally the troops.
Don't leave me hanging.
- (Thuds)
- (Grunting)
(Inmates clamouring)
(Genera Lynex on speaker)
Good day to you, Warden Mourdain.
And you, General Lynex.
I was just hoping to get
your thoughts on the latest report.
This progress seems quite astounding.
Well, we are dealing
with some exceptional source material.
And my staff are extremely passionate
about making this work.
Photosynthetic skin shrouds.
Regenerative limbs.
At this rate, we'll be looking at our first
deployment in a matter of months.
There are certain qualities that seem
evident in the top spectrum of the report.
(Clamouring continues)
Confident you can maintain
this level of success?
(Alarm blaring)
Is there a problem, Warden?
Nothing I can't handle.
We'll chat soon. Bye-bye.
- (Yelling)
- (Groaning)
Let him go!
- (Clamouring stops)
- (Inmate) Yeah!
(Nimal) I'm gonna kill
this cockroach on my own.
(Guard on speaker)
Sir, there's a problem in the mess hall.
Yes, I know.
Tell the guards to stand down.
- (Spits)
- (Tooth clatters)
I didn't think you and I had a problem, Sy.
(Smacks lips)
I was just hoping for a date.
(Kreat laughing)
(Makes kissing sound)
(Nimal yelling)
(Inmates clamouring)
(Inmates shouting)
Open it, please.
- (Guard) Sir.
- Open it!
(Door beeping, buzzing)
(Clamouring continues)
- Stand back.
- (Nimal gasping)
(Guard 1) End it!
(Guard 2) Step back.
(Warden Mourdain)
Don't let me stop you, Mr Lombrok.
You wanna prove your place in here?
Let's see what you got.
- Guards!
- (Panting)
As long as the crowd behave,
let them enjoy the show.
(Yelling)
(Roars)
(Snarling)
- (Nimal grunting)
- (Choking)
(Roaring)
- (Stabbing)
- (Inmates shouting)
(Nimal groaning)
(Yelling)
(Inmates shouting)
(Screaming)
(Man screaming and laughing)
(Buzzing)
(Breathing heavily)
(Man laughing)
(Whispering) Mourdain...
Mourdain...
(Inmate whooping)
(Muffled screams)
(Loud screaming)
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Yeah!
- I'll do everything you say!
- (Banging)
Stop!
Stop it!
(Lights buzzing)
(Shushing)
(Groaning)
(Warden Mourdain) Gentlemen!
I just wanted to come down here
and wish you all a safe journey
on the road ahead.
(Over speakers)
You should consider yourselves pioneers.
Great explorers of a new age.
(Over speakers)
Remember that society
is no longer a place you can belong.
(Electricity crackling)
What do you want?
This one.
(Vim) No! No! Don't do me!
(Vim screaming)
No! God gracious!
(Warden Mourdain over speakers) It is now
that you will find your true purpose.
(Vim) No! No!
I am the conqueror of my own soul!
(Over speakers) You will understand
the mythology of the mighty phoenix,
rising up from the ashes of your past.
This one also.
Mr Lombrok.
We're going to have to sedate you.
I have a feeling you could really
hurt yourself down here.
(Kane) Tell me something.
What's a ward nurse doing
with a military issue assault rifle?
I hope you know we aren't going
to make it to the Capital on time.
Not on foot, we won't.
Am I missing something?
(Kane) Just beyond those mountains
is a contraband outpost.
(Sy) What's your plan once we get there?
(Kane) Figure that out when we get there.
What do you know
about these creatures, huh?
Down, now! Down!
(Whooshing)
They looking for you?
Yeah.
This is gonna be fun.
(♪ Rock music)
(Indi) My English teacher once read us
a strange poem about love.
I can't remember what it was,
other than I know
it would have fit these two perfectly.
(Inhales deeply)
(Laughs loudly)
- (Man whistling)
- You need to stay on them toes!
(Kane) I was hoping for
a greater selection of vehicles.
Haven't seen one of those
clunkers for a while.
(Sy) You guys know about these places
and you don't shut 'em down?
(Kane) Shut 'em down?
Where the hell would we get a beer?
- (♪ Upbeat music)
- (People cheering)
(Woman) Hey, baby, you wanna go out?
(Woman laughing)
(Woman) Hey, cutie. Hey, come in.
(Man whistling)
(Woman laughing)
Hey.
- How are ya?
- Great. How are you?
You know whose bus that
is parked out front?
Why?
Cos we need a ride.
Those guys.
- (Knife thuds)
- Yeah!
(Cheering)
Oh, no, I wouldn't go over there.
You're gonna wanna wait till they're done,
otherwise you ain't leaving here at all.
(Bill) Oh, let's go suck on it, baby.
That's it. You know what to do.
(Man laughing)
Sit down.
They're whacked out of their minds.
Have a drink.
(Woman giggling)
I guess we need two.
(Gyp moans)
- How hard do you wanna go?
- Gonna go straight to the top.
(Pouring drink)
- Take a water for me.
- We don't do water.
Of course.
So, why don't you tell me
why you became a nurse, Sy?
(Woman) Hey, can I get a round of...
I like helping people.
You know, most of the people
I've helped in my time
turned out to be assholes.
(Bill) And that is your opener!
- (Kane) You find that?
- (Grunts)
Not in the moments that count.
Well, you're a better man than me.
Maybe.
(Man whistling)
(Bill) What you doin'?
Let's have another game.
Ah, come on.
Does he not listen?
- Best of five.
- Hey!
- (Sniffs) Mmm.
That your bus parked out front?
(Stammering) We're in the middle
of something here, huh?
I need a ride to Osiris.
I need to leave now.
(Laughs) You're funny, man!
(Gyp) Real fuckin' funny.
(Kane grunts)
(Grunting continues)
- See?
- I ask her to do that to me every night.
What you all lookin' at?
I said, what you all lookin' at?
Play your little domino weirdo game.
(Whistles) Buddy, back to your game.
- Play the music.
- (Glass shatters)
Music! Play!
(♪ Rock music)
You might wanna go help him.
Think we're a little taxi service?
Is that what you think we are?
What's your name, abdominal?
My name is Kane.
Kane?
Nah, you're not from around here, huh?
I may need you to top that off.
No, right now, I'm a very,
very long way from home.
Which is why I need a ride.
Me and my buddy at the bar.
(Bill) Goddamn, look at you, man!
I'm on my knees for you, man.
You're a perfect guy!
(Gyp grunts)
(Exclaims)
You make the perfect couple.
You belong on a magazine cover, don't you?
But you don't belong out here, huh?
Don't be shy now.
- Come on over.
- Come play.
(Gyp) Bill, I wanna take him home.
(Bill) Oh, no, no, no.
You take the bar lady home.
You don't take him home.
I'm sorry about my friend here.
Mmm-hmm. Thank you very much.
It's that time of the month.
Take a seat.
Good cop over here knows how to do it.
That's all you had to do. Bring me a drink.
By the looks of it,
you're military, right?
(Kane panting)
I'll pay you 10 grand one way...
That ain't worth spit.
You got a knife to your throat
and you're still trying to talk turkey?
Mmm-mmm, mmm-mmm.
He's a defector of Exor.
He's just trying to get back to his family
before they come after him.
(Gyp) Mmm-hmm.
Is that true?
Yes, it is.
- Cut his throat.
- No!
You wanna pay me 10 grand for that?
- Ten fuckin' grand?
- No, no, no, no, no!
He's lyin' like a tombstone.
I thought I heard him say 20.
He did say 20.
(Softly) Twenty.
Twenty grand?
- I'll give you 20 grand.
- Whoo-hoo!
- (Gyp) Ah-
- Yeah! Let him go.
- That's a whole big load of straw.
- (Gyp cheering)
- Hey, that bus outside looks modified.
- (Bill) Mmm-hmm.
Is that armour up to spec?
Why you askin'? We gonna get shot at?
We like to travel safe.
I mean, we're talkin' about
no old prison bus here.
We're talkin' about Gracie, aka...
(Grunts) "My Momma." (Laughs)
Yeah.
You can come inside my Momma,
and she will take care of ya.
Twenty grand. One way. Got a deal?
Mmm...
(Kane) Let's go.
Not yet.
You wanna ride with me?
Wanna ride in my Momma?
You gotta take a kiss on this.
(Bill) Take a knee.
OK.
Lasts 20 seconds.
You get the knife on the board,
then we got ourselves a deal.
(Inhales deeply)
That'll make you dizzy.
(Grunts)
(Man whistles)
(Woman) Oh, yeah!
(Woman cheering)
(Gyp) Well, look at you, Sparky.
Got a bit of snap in that garter, huh?
You got talent.
Got yourself a deal! Whoo!
We're gonna need some guns.
- (Bill) Guns?
- So, we are gonna get shot at?
Just like I said, we like to travel safe.
- So, we can stop by Hopper and Mandel.
- (Chuckles)
- But it'll cost ya.
- Cost ya.
How far is this place?
How far to the Hopper and Mandel place?
Oh, no, no, it's not that far.
It's like about 30 minutes there and back.
Close enough.
(GYP) Yeah.
You wanna keep swapping spit
or should we hit the road?
(Gagging)
(coughing)
(Metal clangs)
(Door whirring)
(Snarling and growling)
(Metal clanging)
(Snarling)
(Footsteps approaching)
(Growling)
(Gasping)
(Sniffing)
- (Roaring)
- (Screaming)
(Distant screaming)
(Breathing heavily)
(Grunting)
(Ragged roaring)
(Warden Mourdain) Do you know
what terraforming is, Mr Lombrok?
It's the act of making
a hostile environment
habitable for humans.
(Ragged roars)
Unfortunately, many planets have indigenous
species that refuse to cooperate.
We needed a more cost-effective way
of exterminating them.
I'm telling you this
because I need you to understand,
very clearly,
what you have a chance to be a part of.
(Roaring continues)
Our friend next door
just met one of our all-star team.
(Vim screaming)
- (Continues screaming)
- (Ragged growling)
Many of them your former prison inmates.
And hopefully,
his constitution withstanding,
he'll soon be able to join them
and become something he was unable to do
as an inferior human.
- (Roaring)
- (Screaming)
(Screaming continues)
A being capable of evolution...
(Ragged growling)
Adaptation,
even in the hardest of environments.
(Grunting)
(Growling)
I've seen what it takes
to survive the change.
Don't fight it.
Don't fear it.
Allow yourself to be the manifestation
of the monster that I know
lives inside your soul.
(Footsteps approaching)
Surviving this next period
will push your mind further
than it's ever gone before.
And that's when you need
to remember that this
is a second chance.
Take solace in that.
(Gasping)
Guards!
- Bostok?
- (Sighs)
- You did it!
- We gotta move.
- (Sy) ls this everything?
- (Bostok) Yeah.
- Where are the IDs?
- Here.
- Got you a special one.
- Nurse?
You don't want to know
what I did to get that.
(Kreat) I opened the cells!
(Cackling)
- There were these other doors and... And...
- What?
(Stuttering)
(Gasping)
- What?
I let the devil loose.
- (Growling)
- (Screaming)
Guards! Report back.
- (Growling)
- Go, go, go!
(Men screaming)
Go!
(Growling)
- (Growling)
- (Men screaming)
(Bostok) You're telling me Vim's gonna
turn into one of them?
(Kreat) All I know
is what I saw on the monitors.
(Bostok) We've got to
get to Osiris before dark.
Come on, let's go.
I can't go with you guys.
What?
What are you talking about, man?
We gotta stay together.
(Growling)
Easy. Easy, easy.
Easy, boy.
What you gonna do, huh?
Where you gonna go, Sy?
- I'm going to the opera.
- (Laughs)
The what?
No, baby Sy, you don't wanna go to
the opera. They sing at the opera.
Don't you turn your back to me, Sy.
(Sy) Good luck.
Let him go. You and me.
You're gonna die out there.
(Growls)
(Warden Mourdain) I made you.
I made you.
(Growling)
- (Screams)
- (Growls)
(Distant roaring)
Bye, Vim.
(Distant clamouring)
(Helicopter blades whirring)
(Lamar) Normally you'd get 20 years
in a local secure max.
Maybe out in 15.
But I highly doubt that.
Despite
all our best efforts
they're going to paint
you as being a monster.
They're gonna emphasize the breach of code,
betrayal of trust that the public grants
to someone in your position.
They're going to make
an example out of this.
Eye for an eye, and all that.
I wish I had better news.
It doesn't matter.
Nothing does any more.
(Metal clinking)
(Kane) Hey.
These guys reliable?
Nope.
(Beeping)
Who's paying?
Me.
(Hopper) Not too happy
about that Exor jacket.
We don't much like your kind.
How much?
Mandel says no deal.
Fuck.
Well, how about you ask Mandel
exactly what number's
gonna make him happy?
Thirty Gs.
(Gun cocks)
Thirty's fair.
Thirty. Deal.
Deal.
(Chuckles)
(Beeps)
(Chimes)
May I ask where you're all headed
with this kind of hardware?
Yeah, you can ask.
I was just being polite!
(Both laugh)
(Kane) You got nice friends.
- (Laughs)
- That was a really good transaction, man.
- Oh
We made some serious money!
(Both laughing)
Hey! Ow! Ow! Ow!
- (♪ Rock music)
- (Whooping)
♪ I got myself some
♪ Sweet juice
(Laughing)
♪ Got my sweet juice ♪
Thirty Gs.
(Chuckling)
Hmm...
(Whirring)
(Distant roaring)
(Hopper) Mandel!
(Grunts)
Get the hell over here!
(Laughing)
Come on.
♪ Sweet juice ♪
(Laughing)
What is that?
What's that?
(Hopper) I swear I just saw something.
(Door creaking)
(Flies buzzing)
(Metal creaking)
(Growling)
(Roaring)
(All roaring)
(Grunts)
(Hopper) Check the back!
(All roaring)
(Breathing shakily)
(Growling)
They're everywhere!
(Sniffing)
(Hopper) Where are the shock rockets?
You mean we sold them?
(Growling)
(Roaring)
- (Screaming)
- (Machine guns firing)
(Hopper) They're not going down!
Reloading!
(Screaming)
Got one!
Yeah!
(Screaming)
(Distant screaming)
- (Gunfire)
- (Screaming)
(Screaming)
(Growls)
- (Screaming)
- (Explodes)
(Gyp) So, what you're saying is
in less than 12 hours,
this whole place could be wiped.
Every living thing.
We'll all be dead.
Yeah, that's right.
(Bill) Throw in those damn monsters
you're describing,
this place don't look anything
like it did in the brochure.
(Sy) You ever wonder
how you end up where you do?
You have all these plans...
Make so many plans and yet...
Here we are.
No, not really. I know
exactly how I got here.
Talking about fate, Sy?
Talking about astrology and shit?
I don't believe in fate.
Just consequence.
(Bill) Oh, that's right, square jaw.
Live with no regrets. Can't ever go back.
Hindsight's only to help you move forward.
Well, I regret coming to
this shithole planet.
(Chuckles)
What's so funny about that?
I love it here.
That makes two of us,
my cherry pie with cream on top.
Got wide open spaces, clean air.
- Food that don't come from a laboratory now.
- Mmm.
That's paradise.
Momma used to say people don't change.
Only their version of the past does.
I say "Give a man a match,
he'll be warm for a minute.
"Light him on fire,
he'll be warm for the rest of his life."
Right.
That's right.
What about you, Abdominal?
(Beeping)
You dig this place? You dig the frontier?
I liked it a lot better 24 hours ago.
(Bill chuckling)
But it's a fresh start and
that's what I needed.
That, and I couldn't get
any further away from Earth.
Bet they pay you well up there.
In that... In that Sky fleet.
Yeah, it pays okay.
Mind you, for that career I...
I got a failed marriage
I got a shoulder that is never gonna heal,
and I got daughter that I hardly know.
But yeah, the money's great.
Well, our folks kicked us out.
So, we had no choice
but to do something a little drastic.
Your folks?
You guys
are related?
That's right.
She's my little stepsister.
Mmm-hmm.
That's why we don't look the same.
(Gyp) That's why we don't kiss the same.
Ooh, Sparky, that's turning you on.
My little sugar Kane.
What's your area up there?
What do you mean?
What do you do up there?
I was in charge of infrastructure.
Overseeing the growth
of the cities and surrounds.
Everything. You know, like, uh,
Capital,
the mines, prison.
You mean slave labour camps.
Prison colonies changed
deep space exploration forever.
The only way these frontiers grew so fast
is through mandatory labour.
We wouldn't be here otherwise.
That might be
a good talking point at one of your
weekly meetings up there...
But those prisoners,
beyond what I personally thought of them,
they came to me wrecked.
Worked way beyond any humane point.
We used to drive for the prison
when we first got here.
What we saw was pretty bad.
Least they're doing something useful.
Prison's supposed to be hard.
It's punishment, right?
It's a big choice to turn your back
on everything you once stood for.
You got a family, Sy?
You got a family? You got kids?
(Exhales)
Then you wouldn't understand.
(Bill) I gotta say it.
Phew! What if your
daughter ain't there, huh?
Huh?
She'll be there.
And then you take us to the bunker
and we'll be safe there?
One hundred percent?
Yeah, you have my word.
Just as soon as my daughter is safe.
Even if she ain't.
Yeah, even if she ain't.
Well, we gonna be one big happy family.
I'm gonna be an uncle.
It's gonna be fun. (Chuckles)
(Sy) Hey, Bill, how long till Osiris?
(Bill) Ah, it's probably gonna be
a couple more hours, square jaw.
But don't worry, we got plenty of time
to shoot us some critters.
No one messes with old Billy boy.
Gonna be fun!
(Explosions)
- (Growls)
- (Gasps)
Holy shit! There's a huge
snapping turtle attacking Momma.
(Growling)
(Gunfire)
(Crackling and hissing)
My apartment's right above us. Third floor.
Damn, stop hitting my goddamn bus!
Bill and Gyp, you protect Momma.
Sy, you come with me.
(Bill) You gotta go!
(Bill) All right boys! It's now or never.
Let's get going!
Whoo-hoo!
Hey, you know there's a chance
she's not up there or worse.
If that happens, we're straight back here.
You got it?
Yeah, I got it.
Kane, I hope you find her.
Go get your daughter, Abdominal.
All right, we'll cover you.
Let's go, Gyp. Move!
(Growling)
- (Bill) Let's go, Gyp!
- Go, go, go!
Get your asses out here, boys! Come on!
(Gunfire)
(Growling)
Let's go!
Get the door! Go!
- (Grunts)
- Power's out. Use the stairs.
(indistinct)
- (Gunshot)
- (Screams)
- (Man) You stay out of our stairwell.
- (Alarm blaring)
Ozmin, is that you?
(Ozmin) What?
Ozmin, it's Kane from upstairs.
How do I know that?
Oh, it's Kane from 38!
You seen Indi, or Rominja?
Well, uh, I checked.
There was no answer.
They haven't come through this way.
Whole damned world's near gone mad.
I have someone with me.
We're gonna come up, okay?
Well, it's not my stairwell.
You pay rent, too.
(Kane) That's very kind.
(Sy) Keep safe.
And aim lower.
Come on!
- (Growls)
- Aha! Got you, little turtle!
(Shrieks)
(Laughs)
Damn!
Shit! (Grunts)
(Kane) Indi!
Stand back!
(Gunshots)
(Grunting)
(Distant gunfire)
Kane.
(Indi) Dad?
Dad, I'm here!
- Dad, I'm here!
- Honey!
(Gasping) I love you.
- (Indi sobbing)
- You OK?
Rominja told me to hide in there
and not come out until you came.
Oh, honey.
Where's Rominja?
Uh...
She's gone home.
- She's not here.
- OK.
(Indi sobs)
Kane, we gotta go.
- Yeah.
- Who's that?
(Kane) That's our friend, Sy.
He's a good man. He's gonna help us.
But you have to come with us.
You need to stay right next to me, OK?
And we're gonna be fine
but we have to run now.
(Sobbing)
- (Growling)
- Kane!
We gotta go. Go, go, go! Come on!
(Ozmin shouting)
(Indi) What is that?
(Growling)
(Gunfire)
Move, move!
(Gyp sobbing)
(Door opens)
(Gyp) Bill, where do we keep the meds?
(Sobbing)
No! No, no, no!
(Grunting)
(crying)
Go, go, go!
(Indi) Dad, Dad, where are we going?
There's nowhere to go!
- Now what?
- (Gunfire)
I don't know. Let me think. Indi!
Indi!
- (Growls)
- (Thuds on door)
'Dad!
'(Growling)
Dad, there's a bus down there!
We can make it.
Gotta jump.
Hey!
- Come here.
- No! No, it's too high! Sy!
- (Indi screams)
- Sy!
(Grunts)
(Yells)
- Give me your hand.
- (Yells)
(Sy) Kane, come here.
(Grunting)
Indi, come here.
Come here, come here, come here.
- Stay down, stay down, stay down.
- Bill! Gyp!
- (Banging)
- Open the hatch!
Open it!
(whimpering)
"(Growling) 'Open it!
Open the door!
- (Indi shrieks)
- (Sy) Open it!
Open the hatch!
(Beeping)
(Kane) Come on. Come on.
- Get her.
- Got her.
(Kane) Grab her. Take her!
(Sy) Got her! (Grunts)
Got her. Stay here.
All right, I'm in! Let's go!
You okay? You okay?
- Let's go! Stay down.
- (Indi sobbing)
Drive!
Gyp!
Gyp, we've gotta move now!
(Engine starting)
(Kane) You understand
everything I've just told you
about the creatures,
about the people I worked for.
About everything that's
happening out there.
This is important to me.
I do, Dad. I understand.
I'm sorry for being the crappiest,
crappiest father.
And I'm sorry that things
didn't work out with your mother.
I loved her.
I loved her so much. I still love her.
And I'm sorry that
I wasn't there for you growing up.
And I'm sorry that I didn't get
to come to your games.
Your softball games,
and your soccer games
and your singing practice.
It's OK.
I'm so sorry I never came
to any of that, because I think
you are amazing.
(Sniffling)
I need to know you forgive me.
(Whimpering) Of course.
(Signs)
If we get through this,
it's gonna be different.
I promise you, it's gonna be different.
(Breathing heavily)
(Kane) Gyp, about a mile up the road,
we're gonna take a right.
The bunker's in an old
abandoned mine shaft.
And stay alert.
Those creatures could be anywhere.
There's a code on the door. It is 14286.
- Sy, you get that?
- 14286.
- Gyp?
- Got it.
- Say it.
- 14286!
14286. Got it.
14286.
(Computer on PA) Protocol 84. Commencing.
General, scanners indicate there is a bus
headed for Apex Ridge bunker.
(Beeping)
(Whooshing)
Dad.
Sy! Company, three o'clock.
- Stay down here, OK? Just stay there.
- What's happening?
- What's it doing?
- It's watching us to see where we're headed.
Gyp, keep going straight.
Don't take the turn.
- (Sy) We don't have time for that.
- (Kane) We don't have a choice.
But, Dad... Dad, what's happening?
Indi, stay down, please!
That thing needs at least four minutes
to get to a safe distance.
It's too small to withstand the blast.
When it leaves, we turn back.
How much time have we got?
Four fifteen.
Four fifteen'?
That's pushing it.
What if it doesn't leave?
Then we've got nothing
to worry about, right?
- Dad!
- Stay down, OK? Listen to me.
Wrap yourself up.
Be like a ball, okay? A very small ball.
Stay as low as you can, you understand?
How's your daughter?
She's scared.
(Kane) Sy, where is it? Can you see it?
It's going over us.
- It's leaving.
- Turn!
(Indi shrieks)
Indi, you OK?
Yeah.
Go. Turn.
You line it up with that mountain peak
and give her everything.
Are we gonna make it?
We're gonna try.
(Sy) Almost there!
I see the junkyard!
- (Kane) Remember the way to the bunker?
- Uh-huh.
(Kane) Stay down here
and when we get there, you run.
(Sy) Kane!
Kane!
(Tyres screeching)
(Guns clicking)
- Dive!
- (Groans)
(Indi shrieks)
(Kane) Indi! Stay down!
(Shrieking)
(Whooshing)
(Sonic boom)
(Groaning)
(Panting)
(Sniffling)
Indi.
(Indi) There was no goodbye.
No final words.
And I knew the moment I
stepped off that bus
I would never see his face again.
(Indi) My Dad!
Stay with me, Indi.
(Sobbing)
- I want my Dad!
- I know.
(Indi) I didn't want to leave him.
And yet, a convicted murderer
serving life would not allow it.
Whatever he lost along the way
was now pushing him forward
with each and every desperate step.
(Growling)
They're here!
Go, Indi!
Go!
(Indi) But no matter how far you run...
This way!
Or how well you hide...
- Which way?
- That way!
(Indi) You can't escape destiny.
(Groaning)
(Gasps)
(Roaring)
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Hurry, Indi!
14286, Indi.
I got it!
(Groans)
Six! Come on! Come on!
Go, Indi!
(Roars echoing)
(Grunting)
(Computer on PA) Plutonium core exposed.
Meltdown commencing.
(Powering up)
Ten...
Nine...
Eight...
Seven...
Six...
Five...
Four...
Three...
We're out of time! Come on!
One.
- (Rumbling)
- (Groaning, coughing)
Sy!
Sy, what's happening to you?
(Slurring) I'm becoming one of them, Indi.
What do I do?
You're not safe with me here.
Tell me, what do I do?
(Yells)
Tell me!
Find... Find me something sharp.
Hurry! Scissors...
Bring it to me.
Yes. Yes! Yes!
What are you going to do with these?
You're not safe with me here.
Bring 'em here! Come on.
(Gasping)
No!
I can't do this by myself.
I need you to help me.
I need you to help me. Come on.
No, I can't. No.
You're gonna protect me,
just like Dad said.
No!
I can't do this on my own!
Sy!
You're all I've got!
No!
(Screaming)
(Woman) Charlton Hospital.
Directing you now.
(Antonio) Nurse Lombrok.
What'd you do wrong
to get back on this shift?
How're you feeling?
Right now, there's people in that bar
enjoying a nice single malt.
I'm wondering why the hell
I'm not one of them.
- Incoming?
- Two vehicle collision.
- Three persons involved.
- ETA?
Right now.
How was the opera tonight?
- First time you've been, right?
- Mmm-hmm.
It's so over the top.
This is the mother of a young girl
who died at the scene.
Incoming is a 24-year-old male
who caused the accident.
He's highly intoxicated,
but in stable condition.
Going to theatre one!
(Sy) Kiara,
Kai, they loved it.
They really loved it.
It was nice.
That's what family time's all about.
Well, do it while you can.
(Distant sirens)
- Blood pressure being taken.
- (Nurse) Immediate casualties.
Suspected pelvic,
abdominal and pelvic trauma.
It's gonna be...
Kiara...
(Nurse 2) She's haemorrhaging.
Call the surgeon's team.
Kiara.
(Beeping)
(Nurse 3) We have a situation here.
(Dr Curruthers) Nurse Lombrok,
please leave the room.
Stay with me. Stay with me.
Baby, stay... Stay with us.
Stay with us.
It's my wife. Can you hear me?
(Dr Curruthers) We will do everything we
can to save her, but you can't be here.
- (Jandi) Sy...
- (Sy) Keep breathing. Keep breathing.
(Jandi) You have to come with me.
(Whimpering) I love you.
I love you so much.
I love you.
(Dr Curruthers)
We have some haemorrhaging here.
- Sy, you have to go.
- (Gasps)
If you can hear me, sweetheart,
squeeze my hand.
Squeeze his hand.
Please, honey.
- (Dr Curruthers) We're losing her.
- (EKG beeping rapidly)
Where's my daughter? Where...
ls she the one that...
ls she the fatality, too?
- I'm so sorry...
- Where's my daughter, Jandi?
Where's Kai?
Where's my baby girl? Where's Kai?
I'm so sorry.
Let me go get someone to talk to you.
(Beeping)
(Gasps) No.
(Dr Curruthers) Asystole! Commencing CPR!
On, baby.
They're gonna make an example out of this.
Eye for an eye,
and all that.
- (Thuds)
- (Grunting)
- (Taser Zapping)
- (Groans)
(Indi) My father always said
that you could never trust a person
that needed something from you.
But he also said he'd never met anyone
who didn't need something
from someone.
I say we are what we are
when we need to be.
(Man) Well, there's the beacon.
Do you recognize that?
(Woman) Looks like an old model.
(Man) Must have been manually activated.
There's gotta be someone here.
(Woman) That means we're gonna
have to do this the hard way.
(Man) Well, there's a bunker close by.
Let's start there.
- (Woman) I'm going to go and get the kit.
- (Man) Yeah, okay.
(Woman) Whitmore.
(Whitmore) Yeah?
It's a kid.
(Woman) Stay there. We'll come and get you.
- (Thuds)
- (Groaning)
(Growling)
(Roaring)
(Taps on helmet)
There was a large ship.
The Flotilla.
It used to orbit here.
Where has it gone?
It's en route to Earth.
It was recalled after the disaster.
Tell me what they said happened here.
(whimpering)
They... They just said that
the prisoners revolted
and they sabotaged the reactors.
There was a meltdown.
How many survivors were there?
None.
At least, that's what we thought.
Do you want to die out here?
I don't wanna... I don't wanna die.
Then you will take us to the Flotilla.
You will ensure that we
enter undetected, or...
It will cost you your life.
(Growls)
All right.
OK.
(Engine starting)
Sy.
We're going home.
Goodbye, Dad.