-[drum beat]
-[clapping]
-[rhythmic breathing]
-[drumroll]
ANNOUNCER: Fosse/Verdon.
All new, Tuesdays at 10:00
on FX.
ANNOUNCER: FX presents
What We Do in the Shadows.
[bats squeal]
[lively gusli strumming]
It's nightfall.
The job of a vampire's familiar
is not an easy one.
It's very dangerous.
I mean, they are vampires,
after all.
We can go in now.
Good evening, Master.
MAN [muffled]:
Guillermo?
Yes, sir?
-Is that you?
-Yes, Master.
-Okay.
-Okay, Master.
It's time to... rise.
MAN:
The... Okay.
[rattling]
MAN:
Guillermo, it is stuck.
I think it is the latch.
GUILLERMO:
Being a vampire's familiar
is like being a best friend.
Who-Who's also a slave.
-MAN: Guillermo, it's too loud.-What?
GUILLERMO:
Tomorrow night marks
the ten-year anniversary since
I started working
for my Master.
I think he's planning
something pretty special.
[whispers]: I think he's gonna
make me a vampire.
MAN:
This is very embarrassing.
[whispering]:
Okay, Master.
He awakens.
[lively strumming]
Very cool, Master.
Very scary.
Thank you.
["You're Dead"
by Norma Tanega playing]
♪ Don't sing if you want
to live long♪
♪ They have no use
for your song♪
♪ You're dead, you're dead,
you're dead♪
♪ You're dead
and out of this world♪
♪ Now your hope and compassion
is gone♪
♪ You sold out your dream
to the world♪
♪ Stay dead, stay dead,
stay dead♪
♪ You're dead
and out of this world.♪
NANDOR:
Everyone?
Nadja, Laszlo.
-Yeah?
-Yes?
-Can you come downstairs
for a second, please?
Thank you, Laszlo.
In your own time, Nadja.
[chuckles]
Yes, good, excellent.
So, listen.
We have received a letter
and I would like very much
to read it to you.
-But not here, we want to go
into the library.
-Why not here?
I'd like to read it in there.
It's just a formality.
It'll sound
exactly the same if you
read it here than if
you read it in there.
I'm not going to disagree with
you, but that's not the point.
NANDOR:  I was a very ferocious soldier
in the Ottoman Empire.
Which meant a lot of killing,
lot of pillaging.
People would say,
"Please, don't pillage me."
And I would say, "No.
I'm pillaging everyone,
you included."
I was relentless.
They would call me Nandor
the Relentless.
Because I just never relent.
So I'd like very much for us
to go into there, please.
Just a formality.
Come on, please,
it's just a formality.
-You could have read it by now.-Hmm.
Just a formality, okay?
Look, it's not even that far.
-Oh, fuck this, fine.
-Thank you, Laszlo.
It's just a formality,
please, Nadja.
-Just a formality, thank you.
-[Nadja groaning]
Guillermo, the door.
-That wasn't so bad, was it?
-[door creaks shut]
Now before we go into
the reading of the letter,
I wanted to talk about
general hygiene in the cell.
-[groans]
-Last night,
there were all these people
down there,
shouting and screaming,
half-drunk.
Where did they find the alcohol?
No, they were half-drunk.
They'd been half drunk.
-Oh.
-Please, finish a whole victim
before moving on
to a next one, okay?
It's very unhygienic.
I think I know who's leaving
them down there,
-but I don't want to say.-If you've got something to say,
-then damn well say it.
-It's not hygienic.
How dare you. [hisses]
[both hissing]
The problems with living
with other vampires
are the vampires
I have chosen to stay with.
[Nandor and Laszlo struggling]
Nandor is like
a big turkey
just walking around
trying to control everything
on the farm.
-Hyah!
-[Laszlo snarls]
NADJA:
And Laszlo is my big, crazy,
wild bear and we love to chase
each other around the house.
-I ought to fucking kill you!
-[panicked yelling]
We have a great time together.
LASZLO:
I was the most handsome man
in our village.
His village
was very badly affected
by leprosy and the plague.
That's true.
And I, myself,
did contract leprosy,
but I was quite lucky
'cause it couldn't be seen.
It was only one part
of my anatomy.
Well, I can see it.
Anyway, one night,
I was awoken by this...
horrible clawing at the window.
And I thought,
"Who the hell is that?
'Cause I live
on the third floor."
So I went to investigate it,
I threw back the curtain...
Well, I saw the most beautiful
woman I had ever seen.
But she was gripping the window
and she was clawing
at the glass.
I was hypnotized.
I used hypnosis on him.
Which I found out later.
Anyway,
obviously I invited her in.
We were about to make love
when she turned into this
hideous, leathery bat thing.
She drained me of my blood,
giving me the curse
of eternal life
and thus making me
a bloodthirsty
creature of the night.
[hissing]
[both hissing]
-[hisses]
-[thuds]
Why don't we just
write on them with marker pen?
Put our names and the date?
LASZLO:
Oh, that's a good suggestion.
-NADJA: Yeah.
-Good idea, Nadja.
Marker pens, Guillermo.
Make sure they're permanent.
-Sharpie.
-LASZLO: Genius.
-NADJA: With date, as well.
-Yes, great thinking, Nadja.
-And yes, this... yes.
-The name of the month,
day, year.
Okay.
And now we come...
to the reading... of the letter.
-[groans]
-At last.
Guillermo? Close the door.
-The door's closed, Master.
-Close it more.
More.
Good.
-Now that we are
gathered here...
-[snarling]
together as one, finally,
in accordance with
the protocols...
Which you made up.
Yes.
We have received this letter.
From Baron... Afanas.
Really?
Yes.
NANDOR:
How do you...
-GUILLERMO: Like that.
-Shh.
The Baron...
...is coming to visit us.
Holy shit.
Silence, Guillermo.
Vampire comments only.
The Baron never leaves
the old country.
Has he told us what the purposeof his visit is?
Uh...
No.
LASZLO:
The Baron is a firm believer
that vampires should rule
the world.
I think the main purpose
for the Baron's visit
is to find out whether
we as vampires
have populated America.
But as you can see,
the place is fucking massive.
When is he coming, exactly?
-Tomorrow.
-Shit.
NANDOR:
Why didn't you give this
to me earlier?
It arrived this morning, Master.
[hisses]
NADJA:
Baron Afanas is...
a very charming member
of the vampire royalty.
A few hundred years ago,
we enjoyed a very intense,
very long sexual affair.
It was pretty wild.
Lots of acrobatic stuff.
This could make it awkward,
to see him with Laszlo...
present.
LASZLO:
Just between you and I,
a while back, the Baron and I
enjoyed a very intense
sex affair.
Very animalistic.
Acrobatic stuff, you might say.
So I, personally,
am very much looking forward
to reconnecting.
We should get a chariot led by
12 black alligators.
-I like that.
-That's a lot of alligators,
a lot of paint.
What about a van?
A van? [groans]
That's not the same, is it?
Can you at least make sure
it's black?
Yeah. Black van for tomorrow?
Excellent. Uh, what about
the Baron's bloodlust?
-Virgins.
-Oh, yes, let's do that.
Guillermo, two virgins
by tomorrow evening.
-[Nadja chuckling]
-Yes, when the Baron arrives
we shall feast on virgin blood.
[both cackling]
[vampires laughing]
[Guillermo chuckling]
Vampire only laughing.
-Should we tell Colin Robinson?-Laszlo,
-that is a terrible idea.
-[Laszlo clears throat]
He'll ruin the evening.
Uh, what would ruin the evening?
I told you-- didn't close
the door properly.
Are we having a house meeting?
-No.
So, your gathering here...
is just a coincidence?
Yes.
COLIN:
My name is Colin Robinson.
And I am what's known as
a psychic vampire.
Or energy vampire.
This is my office.
Also known
as the hunting ground.
Hi, Deb.
Energy vampires drain
people's energy
merely by talking to them.
Actual v. Budget,
year-to-date, no thanks.
You're gonna be at that all day.
We either bore you
with a long conversation...
Feeling better now, I was
a little sick this weekend.
[inhales sharply]
Hey, Don.
Don?
I have to pee, too.
Or...
Hey.
...we enrage you.
[sharpener whining, whirring]
In fact, you probably know
an energy vampire.
We're the most common kind...
of vampire.
[sharpener screeching, whirring]
We are day-walkers,
not affected by the sun.
[sharpener screeching]
And we are
the only kind of vampire
that can drain
another vampire's energy.
It's very cool.
The power grows stronger
in him by the night.
[snoring]
GUILLERMO: There's different kinds of jobs that I have to do.
Keep the house tidy.
Make sure there's no sunlight.
["Danse Macabre"
by Saint-Saens playing]
[mimicking Nandor]:
Sunlight! Why, Guillermo,
why?!
Not on my watch.
Getting rid of carcasses,
I feel, is a big one.
So, we are under the stairs
and this is my bedroom.
[chuckles softly]
This is a picture of me
as Armand
from Interview with the Vampire.
Played by Antonio Banderas.
That was the first time
I've ever seen
an Hispanic vampire
in mainstream, like, movies.
And I said,
"If he can do it, I-I...
[scoffs] I can do it."
Guillermo... boarded
this whole window up,
it's a huge sunlight risk.
We wouldn't want the Baron
waking up to sunlight
and being turned into
barbecue meat.
Yeah, really cover it.
He's made a lot of comments
recently, like,
"I'm going to make you
a vampire."
This is a little coffin toy
that, uh...
I hope to be
in one of these one day.
What ho, good friends.
LARPERS:
What ho!
There's still a few places
to find virgins.
LARPing stands for
Live Action Role Playing.
In regular life,
I'm just Jonathan.
But here, I am
a very high-level paladin.
GUILLERMO:
I'm not a killer.
I find people who are easy...
to... kill.
Is that a 14th-century
battle-ax?
Oh, it's so exciting.
Uh, will we be able
to touch the swords?
Oh, you'll touch the swords.
NADJA:
We moved here from Europe
about 200 years ago
because there was
a lot of prejudice  against vampires at that time.
[people clamoring]
-[explosions, gunfire]
-[man groans]
They don't like
the color of our skin.
Or the fact that
we killed and ate people.
Probably more that.
LASZLO:
We're being very careful
not to stand out,
which is why
we're both dressed down.
-Uh, good evening.
-Go back to your own country.
What the fuck did you just say?
You heard me,
Ghost of Christmas Past bitch.
Oh, Mike, shut up.
Silence to you.
We've been here since 1861.
At least, our families have.
Begone.
We should just suck their blood,I'm absolutely starving.
-They're perfect.
-No, I'm furious.
He just insulted me,
I'm in fifth gear.
-We should kill them.
-Yes, that's what I'm saying.
-We should suck their blood.
-Yes.
[both moaning]
-LASZLO: Now?
-NADJA: Wait. Wait, darling.
-Now?
-Now!
What? [grunts]
-Mike?
-[slurping, Mike groaning]
Where the fuck are you?
[snarling, gulping]
What the fuck?
Yum, yum, yum. He was delicious.
Now, listen,
I don't know about you,
but I'm very much in the mood
for some sexual intercourse.
[both laughing]
Darling. Right next
to the public toilet?
Yes. But why don't I get home,
get cleaned up, then we can
carry on with our love-making.
Um, I'm going to walk home.
-[chuckles]-Why the hell would you do that?
Why would you walk home?
When you could turn into a bat?
Bat!
[bat squeaking]
NANDOR:  I would like some of that, uh,
colorful dust that sparkles.
-Glitter?
-Yes.
Get me some glitter.
Whatever for, Master?
Oh, I want to do
something special
for the Immortal One's arrival.
I'm going to sprinkle it
on my face and on my body.
Like Twilight.
So deliciously macabre.
-Creepy paper.
-It's crepe paper.
-It's crepe paper, Master.
Creepy... Oh, multipack.
Master, this is
pretty "macarbre."
[groans]
[gasps, screams]
NANDOR:
Guillermo is my familiar,
but sometimes he's a little toofamiliar, you know what I mean?
I mean, he's always
just there.
I think it's good, Master.
NANDOR:
I mean, he works really hard,
he's just not great at it.
Guillermo, my cape is stuck.
[Guillermo grunts]
I don't like saying
this kind of thing
in front of him, of course.
Sorry, Guillermo.
I don't like saying this kind
of thing in front of you.
That's okay, Master.
[scanner beeping]
Lot of glitter.
-Cash or card?
-Credit.
You cannot pay with that.
GUILLERMO:
I'm so sorry.
-Did you just throw a coin
at me?
-Yes.
Sir, you can't be throwing
ancient coins at me.
-Just... Credit card's fine.
-Guillermo, stab this man.
-He's joking.
-Stab him.
-Ahh...
-Thank you.
-I tried, and...
-Here you go, man.
-Thank you so much.
-You kind of disobeyed me
just now.
And I'm noting it.
NADJA:
Recently I have been
seeing another man.
[rasping growl]
He doesn't see me, though,
because I sneak behind him.
I watch him in the night,
in secret.
In the old country,
centuries ago,
I was in a very passionate
love affair
with a human man called Gregor.
He was a knight.
He got decapitated
in battle.
I don't think I ever really
got over Gregor.
Even when I met Laszlo.
June, I've lost my boot.
June?
Come on, June.
The man I saw last night,
I think it is him.
I think it is my reincarnated
ex-boyfriend Gregor,
with his head.
LASZLO:
Put it on, June.
-Shut up, Laszlo!
-Yes, there we are.
Boot on.
Okay, it's just
down here somewhere.
Why haven't I been to
this part of the house before?
It's so lovely.
-No one has for 80 years.
-[gasps] Gorgeous.
What are we doing down here?
There is a chamber, okay?
It's going to be perfect
for the bloodfeast.
If we have the ceremony
in here,
then you-know-who
won't even need to know.
I mean Colin.
-Colin, what are you doing
in here?
-Oh...
This is my bedroom.
I'm resting.
[door creaking]
-[hissing]
-You idiot.
I didn't know he was
gonna be in there.
-Why didn't you check?
-[stammering]
It's fine, we're gonna have
the ceremony in the attic.
We can't,
the StairMaster's in there.
Well, we're going to move
the StairMaster.
[ship's horn bellows]
LASZLO:
Is it definitely this boat?
NANDOR:
There he is.
NADJA:
I knew he'd have a big box.
June, you need to go
and fetch him.
[ship's horn bellows]
WHARFINGER:
Sir, I just need someone
to sign for it.
-Where's the pen?
-So, the tablet is the paper.
Your finger is the pen.
Okay, that's weird.
Okay, that's nothing.
Both of you, for some reason,
aren't registering here.
You got long nails maybe
or something?
Would you like a go, Laszlo?
-Do you have a quill?
-No, it's all digital.
Then I'm not signing that.
Guillermo, give me your hand.
-Ah.
-Okay!
GUILLERMO:
I think the baron
might be here
to see me become a vampire.
That would be really cool.
[inhales sharply]
I'm ready.
[exhales]
NADJA:
I should be preparing
for the bloodfeast,
but I can't seem to stay away
from new Gregor.
[whispers]:
Man. Human man. Man!
-S-Sorry, what did you say?
-Gregor,
it is you.
Oh, my name is Jeff.
-Jeff?
-J-Jeff Suckler.
My sweet Greg... Jeff S...
Really-- J-Jeff Suckler?
-Yeah.
-Ew.
[somber organ music plays]
I call that "Nadja's Theme."
[clock chiming]
[chiming stops]
Guillermo, are the virgins
arriving soon?
They should be
any minute now, Master.
-Fingers crossed.
-[hissing]
Sorry.
Don't do that.
[doorbell rings]
Ah. Dinner is served.
Yum, yum, yum, yum,
yum, yum, yum....
[door creaks open]
Hello. [chuckles]
So glad you could make it.
Please come in, quickly.
[quiet, indistinct chatter]
Everyone, this is Jenna
and Jonathan.
-Hi.
Are you virgins?
LASZLO:
Mm.
I don't see how that's relevant.
-Mm.
-I'm actually
in a relationship online,
but we've yet to meet IRL.
Well done, Guillermo.
Yeah.
JONATHAN:
All right, okay, let's do it.
[indistinct chatter]
Are they a vampire LARP group?
Yeah, well, why don't we
wait in here?
The party's gonna start
in a few minutes,
so we can just hang out,
and I'll come get you when...
[people moaning, muttering]
GUILLERMO:
No. No, no, no!
No, no, no, no.
No, no, no.
I said no!
[indistinct muttering,
groaning continues]
[Guillermo exhales]
We take our LARPing
very seriously.
And that was just an example.
I wanted you to see that.
I'm inspired.
So, are you a knight?
Yeah, I'm...
Well, no, uh, sorry.
I thought you were
gonna say "night watchman."
I'm a-I'm a night watchman
Mmm.
Protector of the people.
Oh, no, not-not really.
[laughing loudly]
Oh, my sweet Gregor-Jeff,
I forgot how much ofa fantastic raconteur you were.
-[laughing]
-Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Ooh, do you remember
that first time
that we made love,
and it was so passionate
that I accidentally
cut off your head?
-No. What?
-Mm!
But then I kept going, squeezing
until my needs were met. Hmm.
We should do that again.
But I mustn't.
But I want to.
But you can't.
But I have been married
for such a long time.
-[laughing]
-Oh.
[groaning violently]
-I must go.
-Okay.
-Let me just get your number
before you go...
-[bat squeaking]
...so we can... I can...
we can do that again.
Uh...
♪
-You're late.
-NANDOR: Throw it.
That's it.
Okay, Guillermo.
We three... not counting
Guillermo... or June...
or you...
are gathered here in accordancewith the ancient...
Get on with it.
-NADJA: Get on with it.
-Guys.
-In bearings with the ordinance-[hisses]
of the nine generations
that have surpassed us
before this historic
and memorable moment.
[groans]
Guillermo, open the casket
of Baron Afanas.
-[metal clicking]
-Oh...
Oh, it opens all by itself.
It's so cool.
♪ In nomine Patris♪
♪ Et Filii♪
♪ Et Spiritus Sancti...♪
-[crunches]
-[grunts]
LASZLO:
Whoa. Whoa, whoa, whoa...
I say, old chap,
that's our familiar.
[hyperventilating]
Good God.
Guillermo, did you see?
He ate the familiar.
[roars]
That's scary.
Ne la materia
che mai non dorme
re de le forme.
I have risen again.
Hello, Nadja.
Hello.
He's so hilarious.
-Laszlo.
-LASZLO: Yes.
I seem to remember him
having genitals.
NADJA:
No, never. That is why he was
such a good lover.
Guillermo, fetch the virgins.
As an advocate of the old ways,
-can I just apologize
for the crepe paper?
-NANDOR: Hey...
It should have been
human skin, obviously.
And I deeply apologize
for the StairMaster.
-It's all his fault.
-I go through all this effort,
I get the creepy paper.
-I get Guillermo to...
-LASZLO: It's not "creepy."
It's crepepaper, crepe.
Silence!
I come with a proclamation.
The old ways...
are over.
Which is what I just said.
The New World, as you call it,
is our lifeline
to an eternal future.
Si...
It's a documentary crew.
They're cameras.
It's like they're not even here.
-They are filming me?
-Yes.
NANDOR:
Just pretend
like they're not there.
It's kind of a natural piece.
You were saying, Baron?
Centuries have passed,
and you have not conquered
the New World.
You hide in the shadows.
Bah. You are weak.
JONATHAN:
Oh, God. Oh...
NANDOR:
Not now, Guillermo.
GUILLERMO:
Go, go, go. Go, go, go.
-Go.
-BARON: Oh, by now,
you should rule this,
this, uh...
-what is this place again?
-Staten Island.
This Staten Island.
[thunder crashes,
metal clatters]
Is this Staten Island
the seat of power
in the New World?
It is where the boat
dropped us off.
Down with the old ways.
Up with t-the New World.
I've been saying it for
centuries, and he would never
-listen...
-Shh.
Mm. I must slumber.
But when I awaken,
we will rule this...
Staten Island.
Y-Yes.
-Yes!
-Yes.
Nadja?
Baron.
[laughs]
-Laszlo.
-Baron.
It's Nandor.
[wind whooshing,
thunder crashes]
LASZLO:
Thank God.
NANDOR:
The Baron is furious with us.
It's so dumb
that I wore glitter.
Let's get rid of this shit.
If we don't conquer
the New World,
he's going to kill us.
Again.
-Basically, we're fucked.
-Fucked. [groans]
NANDOR:
Well, that was
a complete disaster.
At least we have the virgins.
-[keys jingle]
-Uh, yes.
[lock clicks]
[indistinct chatter]
...for an economy car.
-NANDOR: Oh, great.
-GUILLERMO: We're too late.
Colin Robinson has drained themof all their energy.
COLIN:
"How are you gonna
wash this car?"
NANDOR:
They have
no nutritional value now.
COLIN:
And I know you two said
you don't drive,
and don't have
driver's licenses,
but are you gonna do a...
a-a different type
of car wash,
maybe having detailing done?
Now, detailing,
they go into your car
and they get into the nooks
and crannies, so...
Anyway, you take care, okay?
You are glum, Guillermo.
-[quietly]: No.
-Yes.
You think that I've forgotten
that tonight
is a special occasion for you
as well, haven't you?
♪
Does not an anniversary
deserve a reward
recognizing your years
of service?
[song in foreign language
playing]
I'm ready, Master.
Good.
Prepare yourself.
[exhales]
Happy anniversary, Guillermo.
-Wow...
-It's a glitter portrait.
It's a portrait
made from glitter.
Look, it's you.
I made you a vampire.
And look who's next to you.
It's me.
-Wow.
-Enjoy it.
You can put it
in your depressing room.
And you deserve it.
Two years of service.
T-Ten.
Ten years of service.
[inhales sharply]
-Ten.
-Ten years of service?
[mouths]
Okay.
[Nandor sighs]
♪
NANDOR:
Night, Guillermo.
♪ Tonight in the moonlight♪
♪ When I'm alone with you♪
♪ With you.♪
["You're Dead" by Norma Tanega
playing]
♪ Don't sing
if you want to live long♪
♪ They have no use
for your song♪
♪ You're dead, you're dead,
you're dead♪
♪ You're dead
and out of this world.♪
♪
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
[eerie chanting]
[high-pitched screaming]
[chanting continues]
[singing in foreign language]
[woman warbling]
[hissing]
[flames roaring]
-Oh!
-Aaah!
ANNOUNCER:
What We Do in the Shadows.
All new
Wednesdays at 10:00 on FX.
-We're not having a wedding.
-We're eloping, suckas!
[gasps]It's like Inceptionfor pooping.
-[muffled screaming]
-[chiming]
[screaming]
ANNOUNCER: You're the Worst. The final season.
All new. Wednesdays at 10:00 only on FXX.
[grunts]
How did this happen? Uh!
Have you been under
a lot of stress lately?
There's mean-girl issues
with my youngest,
and birth control
with my oldest.
My boyfriend broke up with me.
-Which one?
-Um...
-And some mornings, I just...-Oh, my God.
Fun mom! Hey!
Can you please arrange
for a pleasant dream
while I'm under?
-It's my specialty, dear.
-Guess what my specialty is.
[wheezing laugh]
ANNOUNCER: Better Things.
All new
Thursdays at 10:00 on FX.
-[fanfare]
-[rhythmic breathing, drums]
[rhythmic stomping]
-[stops]
-Again.
ANNOUNCER: Fosse/Verdon.
All new, Tuesdays at 10:00
on FX.