t.me/@Abolix
[bell tolls]
[girls giggling]
Do you know how much
I love you?
No.
More than all the sand
on all the beaches
in all the world.
Describe her to me again.
What was she like?
She had long hair,
a beautiful smile.
She wore a pretty blue dress
that shined in the sun.
What about this?
She loved it
and wore it every day.
Just like you.
Was she pretty?
Very pretty.
The prettiest.
Did she love us?
Always.
I am not going
to tell you both again.
All right?
I put you in here,
and I want no talking.
And I don't want you
to think about leaving
this fucking closet.
Do I make myself
crystal clear?
Yes, Daddy.
And don't make me come back
one more time,
because if I do, I swear to God
I'll grab that necklace
from around your fucking neck
so fast.
Now cover your ears,
both of youse.
- [Dad humming]
- [woman laughs]
I wish Mommy was here.
Come on.
Now I lay me down to sleep.
[both]
Pray the Lord my soul to keep.
If I should die before I wake,
pray the Lord
my soul to take.
God bless Mommy,
God bless Daddy,
God bless the house.
[Jordan]
What are you doing, silly?
[Ashley] You have a better chance
of going to heaven than I do.
I wish you would
take me with you.
[Dad singing indistinctly]
[woman laughs]
[Dad grunts]
[Dad] I like it.
[voice, whispering]
Jordan.
[whispering]
Ashley.
[sighs]
[water trickling]
[footsteps]
[inhuman growling]
Unbelievable.
Kids?
You had kids in here?
You son of a bitch.
- What are you talking about?
- You're so disgusting.
[Dad]
Rosemary, wait. Don't. Don't go.
[breathing heavily]
What did I tell you two?
Eh?
- Good morning.
- Morning.
You slept on the couch again.
Is your bed not comfortable?
My bed was shaking.
Shaking?
Maybe we had
another tremor.
[juice pouring]
I have an idea.
Why don't you come to church
with me today.
Um...
I have so much
I need to get done
before school tomorrow.
Okay, well, I'm going to try
again next week.
I'll see you
when I get home.
Please eat something, okay?
[door opens and closes]
[rumbling]
[kettle whistling]
[glass breaks]
Hello?
[rumbling bang]
Aunt Tanya,
are you here?
Hello?
[Pastor John] The Lord says,
if your sins be a scarlet,
let them be made
white as snow.
And if they be red as crimson,
they shall be made
white as wool.
So it is important
to both forgive
and allow forgiveness
in order to receive
God's true blessings.
So remember that next time
someone swoops in
and steals your front-row
parking spot
- at the grocery store.
- [parishioners laugh]
Just like Mrs. Johnson
forgave me last night
when I accidentally swooped in
and stole her spot.
My bad, Mrs. Johnson.
And speaking of blessings,
I'm truly blessed to be welcomed
into this church community
with such loving
and open arms.
You've really made
this transition
this past two months
an easy one.
And I'm especially blessed
to receive the spiritual
guidance
and leadership
of Reverend Michael.
[applause]
Seems like we had
a good turnout today.
[Michael] Yes, we did.
I thought you did very well.
[Pastor John] I just need
to put together some readings
for the next youth meeting.
I see you found a title
for my personal collection.
Oh. Um...
yes, sorry.
It just caught my eye.
Well, that's okay.
Could you put it back, please?
Absolutely.
I didn't know that you were
into demonology and exorcism.
I was.
Well, I find it fascinating...
Some books are best left
on the shelf.
Of course.
All right, well, I'm off.
See you later.
[Michael] Good sermon.
[girls' voices whispering]
[girls laugh]
[crow caws]
[ghostly voice, whispering]
Ashley.
Ashley?
Hello?
Hey.
You don't remember me,
do you?
It's Hannah.
[laughs]
Hey.
It's amazing.
You look exactly the same,
except older and taller.
Do I look the same?
You're taller.
Where did you guys
end up going?
You kind of just disappeared.
It's messed up how we didn't
even get to say goodbye.
Yeah, we went up north.
That's a cute necklace.
Where did you get it?
- It's so vintage.
- Thanks. It was my mom's.
It's cool.
How's your sister?
Where's she at nowadays?
She's good, she got
a scholarship to Penn State.
[Hannah]
What brought you guys back?
Jesus, once I escape,
I am never coming back.
Do you remember the last time
you were here?
[Ashley] It was a long time ago.
[Hannah]
Nothing much has changed, so...
- [Ashley] Yeah.
- [Hannah] Won't be different.
[Ashley]
So, what do you do around here?
[Hannah] Gosh.
Um, we go to the lake.
We...
you know.
[Ashley] Yeah.
[Hannah]
Go to the movies. That's fun.
There's a couple cute boys
at school.
This is it.
Your room's a little crazy,
friend.
What is all this stuff?
Oh, this is my gear.
The Mormons might
be kind of weird,
but they're onto something.
Onto what?
Angels and demons
walking the earth.
I know, it sounds crazy,
but I've been reading
a lot about it,
and it all sounds so epic.
Just want to make sure I'm ready
in case anything ever happens.
- Serious? Angels and demons?
- Yes, seriously.
Demons are serious stuff.
Haven't you ever seen
"The Exorcist"?
Once Regan used that Ouija board
to invite Captain Howdy in,
she was fucked.
I've never seen it.
You never seen "The Exorcist"?
- [cell phone chimes]
- We have to watch it one night.
Do you remember Shane Stevens?
He was the nerdy kid
with the turtle.
He'd follow us around the gym.
Had a crush on you.
Kinda.
He's hot and single, and we're
hanging out tonight.
Do you want to come?
I don't know, Hannah.
You're invited.
You're coming.
- [thumping overhead]
- [wheezing breath]
- [objects clatter overhead]
- [door opens]
[keys jingle]
Oh, there you are.
I thought you were upstairs.
Hi, I'm Hannah.
You must be Aunt Tanya.
Yeah. Miss Winbourne,
or Aunt Tanya.
"Tanya" is good.
- [laughs]
- [Hannah] Cool.
What are you guys up to? I was just going to
make dinner. Do you wanna stay for dinner?
Oh, no. Hannah are I were going
to go to the dock
and hang out
with a bunch of friends.
Oh, you were going to go?
Do you mind if we go?
Just don't be late.
You have school tomorrow.
Yeah, we won't.
We won't be.
Okay. Do you know what happened
with that picture?
Yeah, I found a school picture
of Mom,
and I thought
I'd put it up there.
Is that all right?
Yeah, it's fine.
Whatever you need
to feel at home.
I'm gonna run upstairs
and get changed.
- Okay.
- It was nice to meet you,
Aunt Tanya, or Tanya,
or Miss Winbourne.
Ooh!
[laughs]
Ooh, you're so creepy.
[hip-hop music playing]
- [Hannah] Carrie!
- [Carrie] Hannah's here.
[Hannah] What is up?
- The life of the party is here.
- Finally. Took you long enough.
How are you?
Great. Good to see you.
I thought I'd spend
more time with my girl.
- Your girl?
- [laughs]
You know what I'm saying.
So, everyone, this is our
long-lost friend, Ashley,
You may know her as
the little girl from art class.
But as you can see, she's fully
grown to start some trouble.
- [Bryce] Whoo!
- So, friends, Ashley.
- Ashley, friends.
- Nice to meet you, Ashley.
Hey, I'm Bryce.
Call me Big Bryce. Big Bryce.
[laughs]
Hey.
[Hannah] How are you?
[indistinct chatter]
[Bryce]
Get you something to drink.
- It's good to see you again.
- It's good to see you too.
It's been a while.
Yeah.
Well, make yourself
at home and...
let's party.
[all chatter excitedly]
- You want a drink?
- No, thanks. I'm good.
Oh, yeah, I don't drink either.
It's cool.
- All right.
- Let's go.
Do you remember me?
Yeah.
You used to follow us
around gym.
Oh, man.
How's your pet turtle?
Myrtle?
She wasn't long for this world,
I guess.
She, uh...
she's in a better place.
[laughs]
It's good to have you back.
Thanks.
[crickets chirping]
Hey, I know something fun.
Do you guys have that new
EVP app?
What, the stupid
"Ghost Hunters" shit?
- You're such a dork.
- Yeah, a cute dork.
What's EVP?
Oh, my God. Check it out.
EVP is "electronic
voice phenomenon."
It's the app they use in all
those ghost-hunting shows.
- It totally works.
- I got it on my phone here.
- Of course you do.
- [all laugh]
- Dude, he's so whipped.
- [imitates whip cracking]
Everyone, listen, the phone's
going to pick up anything
from the spirit world: voices,
paranormal activity, anything.
Listen.
Are there any spirits out there
that want to talk to us?
I don't know, Hannah.
This is kind of weird.
Come on,
don't worry about it.
I'm sure this stuff
doesn't even work.
[Bryce] You guys hear that?
Oh, my God.
I think it's saying for the
girls to show us their boobs.
I'm sure that's what you heard,
perv.
No, but really, listen.
[ghostly voice, whispering]
Ashley.
[girls laughing]
- [shrieks]
- [screams]
What the hell
is wrong with this girl?
[Hannah]
Are you okay? What's wrong?
I don't know.
I think I saw my mom.
You're such a dick, Bryce.
- Ashley, wait up.
- Dude, what's your problem?
She's screaming, we're trying
to have a good, quiet evening.
I'm leaving.
Are you coming?
I drove you here,
so you better come.
[owls hooting]
[ghostly voice, whispering]
Ashley.
[breathing heavily]
[voices whisper indistinctly]
[music playing over earbuds]
[ghostly voice, whispering]
Aunt Tanya.
[turns music off]
[knock on door]
[Tanya] Ashley, you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine,
Aunt Tanya.
I'm taking a bath.
[Tanya] Okay.
[shrieks]
[breathing heavily]
[knock on door]
Come in.
Hey. How was your thing
with your friends?
It was okay.
You look so much
like your mom.
That's her necklace, isn't it?
Yeah.
I've worn it since
I was a little kid.
It's like a little
piece of her.
You know, I bought that for her
on her 16th birthday.
[laughs]
I hope you know how happy I am
to have you here, Ashley.
I do.
I just wish
Jordan was here.
I know.
It's going to be okay.
You know that, right?
How do you know?
Because I know.
And I know that God never gives
us more than we can handle.
I just feel like
he's given me a lot,
and I'm really trying
to handle it all.
I know you are.
But you are so strong.
You're going
to get through this.
And if there's anything I can do
to make you feel more at home,
please let me know.
Thank you.
Ready for your first
day of school tomorrow?
[laughs]
Ready or not,
here it comes.
[both laugh]
All right, you get some sleep,
sweetie, okay?
I'll see you in the morning.
- Good night.
[sighs]
[toilet seat bangs]
[urinating]
[toilet flushes]
[tap water runs]
[floorboards creak]
[faint snarling]
[wood creaking]
[rumbling]
[gasps]
[camera whirs and clicks]
You boys don't be late to school,
now, or we'll all be in trouble.
Okay?
Thanks, Sam.
Good morning.
Hi, good morning.
[indistinct chattering]
Pastor John,
what's the word?
Oh, hey, Sam. Same as always.
God's word.
Ashley?
Yeah?
Hi. I'm...
I'm John.
I'm the new pastor
at Celebration.
I work a lot
with the youth ministry,
and your Aunt Tanya
told me a lot about you.
Okay.
Well, how are you doing?
I mean, are you happy
to be back?
Yeah. It's all right.
Well, what's left of it.
Yeah.
I know the feeling.
Well, I like this part of town.
I feel like it's got
a lot of personality.
I kind of feel like
it's the last link to the past.
You know, we got a lot of really
great events planned at church.
It'd be really nice
to see you there sometime.
Yeah, it'd be cool.
Is that the 7D?
Yeah, it sure is.
That's right, Tanya told me
that you're into photography.
Yeah, I love it.
I have the Mark V,
but I heard the VII
takes better pictures.
Yeah, the picture quality
is great.
It just... sometimes
the exposure's off.
Maybe you could
take a look at it?
Yeah.
You know, I'm always looking
for talented photographers
to take pictures
at church events.
I'd love to. Can I get back
to you about that?
- Okay, great.
- Pastor John. Hey.
- Hey. I'll see you Sunday.
All right.
Hannah, haven't seen you
at church in a while.
I see you smiling.
What, you think he's hot?
No, but he's pretty cool.
Yeah, okay, you know
for a pastor.
Whatever.
Hey, are you okay?
Freaked out yesterday.
Yeah, it was nothing.
It was something.
Did you see something?
What were you saying
about your mom?
I don't know.
My mind's playing tricks on me.
Are you sure?
Because it just seemed...
Hannah, it was nothing.
Whatever you say, Ash.
But it was definitely something.
[horn blares]
You girls playing
the next EVP session?
- I want in.
- Come on, man, knock it off.
You guys want a ride to school?
Really? This is our workout
for the day.
And besides, the school's
right up the street, dumbasses.
All right, fine,
but you're missing out
on the pleasure of our company.
See you later, ladies.
[Dylan]
See you at school, sweetie!
[sighs]
[cell phone chimes]
Wait, hold on.
Hannah, what is this?
It's Shane.
I gave him your number.
Wait, Hannah...
What are you doing?
I don't know.
What do you think?
- [cell phone vibrates]
- You take a look.
One second, excuse me.
Hello?
Speaking.
[indistinct chattering]
- Hey.
- Hey, have you seen Ashley?
I've been texting her all day
and she's not responding.
I was actually about to ask you.
I was going to see
if she needed a ride.
Did you hear what happened?
Yeah, is she okay?
There she is.
Hey, Ashley,
what happened to you?
- Nothing.
- It wasn't nothing.
You almost gave Mr. Diggler
a heart attack.
I just want to go home.
All right, just stay here.
I'll go get my truck
and I can take you home, okay?
Did you see
your mom again?
Um... I don't know.
Holy shit, you did.
Hannah, please stop, okay?
No, Ashley, there's something
going on with you.
I'm coming over tonight.
I just... I need sleep,
that's it.
I'll see you tonight.
[laughs]
Not the best
first day of school, huh?
I just want to say that
I'm sorry about this morning.
We were just messing
with you guys.
[cell phone vibrating]
[phone line ringing]
[Ashley's voice]
This is Ashley. Leave a message.
Hey, Ash, I'm just calling
to check on you.
I just got off the phone
with your principal.
So call me when you can, okay?
- Thanks for the ride.
- Yeah, no problem.
So I guess I'll see you
tomorrow?
Yeah.
Could I give you
another ride tomorrow?
Sure.
[cell phone chimes]
[cell phone vibrates]
Hey.
No, no. I'm just glad
you're okay.
Okay, we'll talk
when I get home, okay?
All right,
I'll be home soon.
Okay.
[sighs]
[loud banging]
Hello?
[doorknob rattles]
[children giggling]
[girl laughing]
[doorknob jiggles]
Hello?
This isn't funny.
[girl chuckling]
- [loud bang]
- [girl laughs]
[wood creaks]
[door creaks]
[deep snarling
and wheezing]
- Hey!
- [gasps]
Hannah, you can't...
shit, scare me like that.
- Sorry. I'll knock next time.
- Oh, my gosh.
You were just, like,
knocking all over the house.
What are you talking about?
[scoffs]
Very funny.
It wasn't me, but okay.
[sniffs]
What's that smell?
I don't know.
Something must have died
in the vent or something.
Hey, is that a Bible?
We're going to need it.
[match strikes]
[blows]
So, what are we doing?
[Hannah] This is my first time
trying this.
Do you remember that EVP thing
that I showed you last night?
Well, this is way better
for communicating
with one specific
dead person.
- It's totally old-school.
- I don't know, Hannah.
Trust me. We have to figure
out if this is actually your mom
trying to reach out to you.
- What if it's...
- What if what?
What if it works?
What's your mom's first name?
It's super important.
Sarah.
Okay. If Sarah reveals
herself to you,
you have to acknowledge her
and ask her to come back to you.
That way, we can figure out
what's keeping her here.
Okay.
Okay. Let's begin.
Hello, Sarah.
I'm Hannah, and I'm here
with your daughter, Ashley.
She'd like to speak with you.
Will you communicate
with us?
Sarah, if you're here,
give us a sign.
Hannah, what's with
this mirror?
Should we close our eyes
or something?
No, I think the mirrors acts as
a conduit to the spirit world.
We have to look directly into it
in order to see your mom.
Sarah, please speak now.
Sarah, please come forward
and speak with your daughter.
- [wind rushing]
- [voice whispers]
What the hell?
Did you hear that?
- Yeah. What was that?
- I don't know.
Sarah, show us
that you're here.
[wind roars]
What the hell? I saw something.
What did you see?
I don't... I don't know.
Call her, Ashley.
She's here.
- Mom.
- Ask her again.
Mom, are you here?
Please, Mom, I'm begging you,
I want you in my life.
Will you please come back to me?
I love you. Please!
[demonic chuckle]
What did you do?
I did what you told me to do.
[Hannah]
This doesn't feel right.
[Ashley] What do you mean?
[inhuman growl]
Hey, it's freezing in here.
What are you guys doing?
What is that smell?
I should probably get going.
- Bye, Miss Winbourne.
- Hannah, wait.
Hannah, wait.
We're messed up.
That shadow was dark.
I'm not sure it was your mom.
- I just...
- What do you mean?
I don't know.
I'll see you.
[Tanya]
Well, she left in a hurry.
- What's going on?
- Nothing. It was nothing.
Next you'll tell me what
happened in school is nothing?
I don't want to talk about it.
- Okay, Ashley...
- I don't want to talk about it!
Listen, Ashley, you may not
want to talk to me
about every single thing
you're doing,
but you will not
disrespect me.
I'm sorry, Aunt Tanya.
I didn't mean
to be disrespectful.
Look, this isn't easy
for me either.
I'm sorry, okay?
Today was really hard.
Is there anything
I can do to help?
I don't think so.
How about we have
a movie night?
We can watch something light,
we can pig out on popcorn.
It was your mom and my favorite
thing to do.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
[indistinct chatter over TV]
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
So, tell me more about
you and mom's movie nights.
Oh, they were our favorite
things to do.
[laughs]
Mostly, it was just an excuse
to stay up late
and talk about boys
and school.
And boys.
[both laugh]
We talked about
everything.
Did she ever talk
about wanting to be a mom?
Or having kids?
[fire crackling]
[Michael] I've preparest
a table before me
in the presence
of mine enemies.
Thou anoints...
I... I have failed.
I have failed you.
I have failed thee.
I need to tell you something.
- Okay.
- [sighs]
I'm pregnant.
Tanya, listen.
There's something
going on with me.
I'm hearing these voices
in my head.
And it's... it's making me
do things.
Really bad things.
[sniffles]
And I can't control it.
I don't know what you mean,
that you can't control it.
- I need your help.
- I don't...
Tanya...
You need to see someone.
You need medical help.
- Sarah...
- I'm scared.
Please, Tanya,
just pray with me, okay?
Okay, okay, okay.
Dear heavenly Father,
please watch over Sarah.
Please cast out
her afflictions
and heal her mind
and her thoughts and action.
- Please watch over my sister.
- [chanting in foreign language]
- [sniffles]
- [flies buzzing]
[chanting in foreign language]
What is it?
What are you saying, Sarah.
- You don't believe me.
- I do.
I don't know what to do.
[in demonic voice]
You don't believe me.
- [gasps]
- Aunt Tanya?
Ashley.
Oh, God, I'm...
- Are you okay?
- I must have had a nightmare.
I'm sorry I fell
asleep on you.
No, it's okay.
Um...
You know, I'm going
to go to bed.
I don't think you'll like
the movie anyways.
It doesn't have
a happy ending.
No, you know what?
I'm...
I'm going to head to bed too.
It's way past my bedtime.
You sleep good, angel.
Thanks.
[flies buzzing]
[flies buzzing continuous]
[inhuman snarling]
[growling]
[roars]
[gasps]
[gasps and pants]
I see you got
your appetite back.
How'd you sleep?
[truck horn honks]
[slurps]
Ashley, what happened
to your shoulder?
Oh, I just bumped into some
branches in the woods.
It doesn't look like
you just bumped into branches.
- Let me see.
- I got to go, I'm late.
Bye.
Hey.
Hi.
Ready to go?
Yeah.
I was thinking after
what happened yesterday,
we could use a little
adventure.
What do you say?
I say, get in.
All right.
Wait, where are you going?
Hop in.
[truck engine starts]
They say that if you close
your eyes,
you can feel that my hands
are going to move a lot faster.
You want me
to close my eyes?
Yeah, close your eyes.
Trust me.
You ready?
Oh, come on.
- I'm going easy on you.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
- Close your eyes.
All right.
- Last one.
- Okay.
- Actually try this time.
- All right.
Ow.
Jeez.
So, what's it like
being back?
I don't know.
Do you like my outfit?
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
Then come closer.
Okay.
Do I scare you?
- Do you scare me?
- Yeah.
No, you don't scare me.
Then kiss me.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
come on.
Slow down a bit.
We don't have to go that fast.
Oh, come on,
isn't this what you want?
I guess.
Hold on. Ashley,
I just want to see something.
Stop for a second.
[coughs]
What the fu...
You bit my tongue.
Oh, come on, Shane.
[gasps]
What the heck
is wrong with you?
[vibrating]
Sorry, excuse me a second.
Hello?
I'm sorry, what?
No, she left this morning
for school.
Are you sure?
Okay, thank you.
[sighs]
[phone line rings]
[Ashley's voice]
This is Ashley. Leave a message.
Where are you?
Call me now.
- Is everything okay?
- No. I got to go.
[Ashley's voice]
This is Ashley. Leave a message.
Hey, Ash,
where were you today?
Call me.
Ashley?
[footsteps thumping]
- Ashley?
- [door slams]
Ashley?
[flies buzzing]
[gasps]
[Hannah]
"Inviting spirits into our world
"can lead to the unintended
and lethal consequence
of demonic possession."
[dials]
[phone line ringing]
[Ashley's voice]
This is Ashley. Leave a message.
- [answering machine beeps]
- Ashley, can you call me?
I have to tell you something.
[Tanya] Ashley?
Ashley, we need to talk.
Ashley, I am talking to you.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. What happened?
Okay, put your head back.
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
- [whimpers]
- It's all right.
What are you doing here
so late?
Oh.
I just wanted to come
and make sure
everything was good
for tomorrow's small group.
What about you?
What are you doing here
so late?
[sighs]
Pray.
Hmm.
Come on, Reverend.
I'll give you a ride home.
I can come in early tomorrow.
We can talk in the car.
Well, thank you
for your generosity,
but I don't need a therapist
or a chauffeur at the moment.
What do you need?
Uh...
forgiveness.
Don't we all?
[sniffles]
[chuckles]
Well, you came
to the right place.
What's on your heart?
You ever doubt, John?
Of course.
Doubt is part of humanity.
I doubt and I question,
but in the end my faith
is strengthened in... what?
Spare me the seminary
bullshit.
I mean, really doubt.
Not just in him,
but in yourself.
Your goodness.
Your ability to fight
for goodness in others.
Hmm.
I believe there's a name
for that.
- A wavering assurance.
- Oh, that's right.
We're always quick
with the names, aren't we?
To name is to destroy.
There was a time when I was
pretty good at that:
naming.
Goodness and God, love.
Wish I could name it now.
Hmm.
I'm afraid I don't follow.
Well, you won't, Reverend.
To destroy your
wavering assurance?
To find peace
in your own goodness?
What do I want?
What do I want more
than anything?
More than finding peace
in my own goodness?
I want to destroy
the darkness.
I want to make it right
for all those souls
that I have failed.
Then that is what
I will help you do.
And into the presence
of the Lord, there is no doubt.
Yes.
In the presence of the Lord,
there is no doubt.
[nurse] That was more blood
than I have seen come out of
anybody nose in my whole life.
Two pints.
Tanya.
- How is she?
- She's fine.
It's just a nosebleed.
Just a nosebleed?
There was blood everywhere.
Look, nosebleeds often look
much worse than they are.
It's the stress of the
environment could be the cause.
Change affects each of us
very differently.
No, I'm... I'm really
worried about her.
You don't need
to worry, Tanya.
No, you weren't there.
You didn't see her.
[man, on P.A.]
Paging Dr. Carraz.
I got to run.
But, you know,
I left her in the care
of an on-call psychiatrist,
Dr. Liles.
You can go see her.
She's in good hands.
It'll do her good
to talk to someone.
Okay?
[Liles]
Hi, Tanya, I'm Dr. Liles.
Thanks for coming in.
There are just a few things
I needed to go over
with both of you.
I'm going to prescribe
an anti-depressant
I want you to take
for a few weeks.
It'll help make the transitional
period a little easier.
I'm also going to prescribe
a sedative
to help you sleep.
Do you really think
she needs all that?
I do.
Her mind and body need sleep
in order to heal themselves.
And the medicine
will make her calm
and enable that to happen.
Okay?
But if you have any questions,
please feel free to call me.
I will. Thank you.
You're okay, kiddo.
But if you need anyone
to talk to,
call me anytime.
[growls]
- [car horn honks]
- screams]
[loud crash]
[snarling and phlegmy breathing]
[car horn depressed]
[ghostly voice, whispering]
Tanya.
Tanya...
[typing]
[birds tweeting]
♪ Our love
♪ Too mighty to overcome
♪ You are faithful
♪ Burning bright
As the morning sun ♪
♪ And all I know of you
♪ Fills me with desire
♪ That I may know you more
♪ To lift you higher
- Good morning.
- [all] Good morning.
Thank you for being here on
this beautiful Sunday morning.
Please be seated.
Now, this is the will of him
who sent me,
the Father,
that I should lose nothing
of what he has given me,
but that I should raise it up
on the last day,
for this is the will
of my father who sent me.
That whoever holds the son
and believes in him
shall have everlasting life.
And I will raise him up
on the last day.
[indistinct whispering]
They said therefore to him,
"Lord, give us always
this bread."
But Jesus said to them,
"I am the bread of life."
[growls softly]
"He who comes to me
shall not hunger."
[breathing heavily
and snarling]
"He who believes in me
shall never thirst.
"But I have told you
that I have seen thee,
and you do not believe."
[snarling and grunting]
[joins cracking]
[in demonic voice]
I thirst Apostles' Creed.
I'll feast on her soul.
[Carraz] Look, I got to run
to the hospital.
I'm going to come check on you
as soon as possible.
I beg you, leave her with me.
I can help her.
I am not leaving her side.
The only reason I brought her
was because I didn't know
what else to do.
Her soul is in jeopardy.
She needs to be on holy ground
for her own survival.
It's happening again,
what happened with Sarah.
Don't you dare
say her name.
What did you do to her?
I knew something
was wrong with her,
and I left anyway.
Well, that is not
happening again.
Tanya...
[car starts]
I'll figure it out on my own.
Come to my office, now.
So, what's going on
with Ashley?
I need to know exactly
what we're up against.
I've seen more evil
than any one man should.
And demonic possession
is real.
I've had too many people
that I have loved and led
consumed by evil,
and I have fought
tooth and nail,
and I have lost.
I have lost more than you can
begin to imagine.
It is shaken my faith and
my belief in myself to the core.
I don't know what to say.
I want to help any way I can.
[sniffles]
The greatest weapon we have
against the demon
lies within his name.
Well, the demon is commanded
to give his name
in the name of Jesus Christ,
shouldn't it?
Not always. I believe this one
has been invited in,
like Ashley's mother's case.
He won't give up his name
so easily.
Ashley's mother?
Yes.
Well, then we have
to figure out a way.
We have to help
any way that we can.
Yes. Grab as many books
as you can on possession
and name demonic entities.
I'm going to give you
a crash course
in performing an exorcism.
We have to go to Tanya's
and fight for Ashley.
We can't have evil win.
Not again.
Possession has three
demonic stages.
The first is infestation.
A demon will be active
in a place, or space.
Some of these signs
may be objects moving,
unrecognizable whispering
and putrid smells.
The second is oppression.
This is when the demon
is focused
on one specific person
or individual.
The demon will take the form
of a loved one to earn trust.
The final stage
is possession.
This is when the person
invites a demon in,
allowing the demon
to take complete control.
The only way to defeat
the demon
is to unlock
the secret of his name
and use it against him.
[knock on door]
How is she?
She's not good.
- Where is she?
- She's upstairs, resting.
There was an accident
involving Hannah.
Is she okay?
[sobs softly]
I'm going to go
see Ashley.
[knock on door]
[door closes]
Tanya.
This is more than you can handle
on your own.
It's beyond your control.
It's gotten worse,
hasn't it?
I don't know what to do.
Tell me what to do.
[inhuman snarling]
Oh, dear Lord.
Redo that restraint.
- [demonic snarling]
- Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done on Earth,
as it is in heaven.
[Ashley, in demonic voice]
And what of my will?
Lord, Jesus Christ,
is upon you.
[snarling]
Lord, protect Ashley.
- [roars]
- And keep her safe.
Ashley's not here.
[chuckles]
Is this your handiwork?
Ah, ah, ah, Michael.
- Who are you?
- [shrieks]
- [sizzling]
- Who are you?
[Ashley] Who the fuck are you?
[Michael] Dear Lord...
I'm John Douglas,
the pastor of Celebration.
"I'm John Douglas,
pastor of Celebration."
Cocksucker!
[Michael]
Dear Lord, cast away any evil
that harms this child, Ashley,
or Tanya.
Her soul is mine.
[gasps]
Oh, my God!
"Oh, my God!"
[speaking Spanish]
Why hast thou forsaken me?
[gasps]
You don't believe me.
[Ashley's voice] Help me, Tanya!
Get her out of here.
Get her out of here!
[sobbing]
[John] We need to be alone with the demon.
[demon grunting and yelling]
The only chance we have
of learning the demon's name
is to get her back to holy
ground after she's sedated.
[shrieks]
I need you to hold her
while I inject her.
[panting]
[demonic roar]
[gasps]
[strained moan]
[hyperventilating]
[bell tolls]
[Michael]
We will prevail with the power of the Lord.
[John]
And if we do not?
We will vanquish
wavering assurances
in the presence of the Lord,
there is no doubt.
[demon whispering in Latin]
[speaks Latin]
- [sizzling]
- [demon groans]
Demon, in the name
of Jesus Christ,
I rebuke you
and cast you away.
Fuck...
you.
- [sizzling]
- Ah!
Don't throw my piss on me.
[laughs]
[Michael]
God, the Father Almighty,
maker of heaven and earth,
and to Jesus Christ,
his only son, our Lord,
who was conceived
of the Holy Ghost,
born of the Virgin Mary,
suffered unto Pontius Pilate,
was crucified,
dead and buried.
He descended into hell.
The third day,
he arose from the dead
and ascended into heaven,
and siteth upon
the right hand of God!
The power almighty.
He shall come to judge
the quick and the dead.
[laughs]
Demon, you have
no place here.
I cast you!
- [sizzling]
- [roars]
[screams]
I submit to the will of God.
[sizzling]
[laughs]
I am God.
You are a demon
and a coward!
And you hide in a child.
You are a coward.
In the name
of Jesus Christ,
I command you tell me
your name.
You are mistaken.
She has invited me in.
[chuckles]
[shrieks and roars]
[Michael] No! No!
Get her away from him!
[roars]
John? John!
Get the book. Get the book.
[demon snarling]
In the name of Jesus Christ,
tell me your name.
[snarls]
Thy kingdom...
[Michael] I rebuke you, Satan,
and all your dark angels,
in the name of Jesus Christ.
Tell me your name!
[roars]
[shrieks]
[growls]
[screams]
[match strikes]
[demon snarling]
I am the Lord.
[hisses]
I will not fail to punish
your children and grandchildren
for the sins
of their parents.
[Michael] I rebuke you, Satan,
and all your dark angels,
in the name of Jesus Christ.
Tell me your name!
[groans]
[screams]
[owl hoots]
[Tanya] Ashley?
Ashley.
Ashley, where are you?
Ashley?
[in normal voice]
Tanya, please help me.
I just want to go home.
Okay. Come, come...
It's okay. It's okay.
[Ashley sobbing]
[demonic roar]
[screams]
Get her back
to the church.
[shrieks]
[cries]
[cackles]
[sniffles]
Jordan.
Jordan, you need
to come home.
[sniffles]
Tanya, you shouldn't be here.
I am not going anywhere.
Then I have something
to show you.
May God bring you peace, Kyle.
[demonic groaning]
May God bring you peace, Ashley.
May God bring you peace, Sarah.
[growling]
[screams]
[shrieks]
♪