Well I think I'm going crazy. Dennis. I really do. Are you happily married?
What?----I mean. why did you get married? Was it all trumpets and fireworks. and...
I got married because Betsy said we had to break up or get married. So we got married.
But when you first met her. did you believe that she was the only person for you. that in some mystical. cosmic way it was fated?
Annie. when you're attracted to someone it just means that your subconscious is attracted to their subconscious. subconsciously.
So what we think of as fate. is just two neuroses. knowing they're a perfect match.
I don't even know him. I am having all these fantasies about some man I have never even met who lives in Seattle.
It rains nine months of the year in Seattle.
I know, I know! I do not want to move to Seattle! But what I really don't want to do is end up.
always wondering what might have happened and knowing I could have done something. What do you think?
It's just cold feet, isn't it? Everybody panics before they get married, I mean, I didn't you? ------Yes, I did.
Yes, you did. Thank you very much, Dennis. I feel so much better just having blown this off. ------Anytime.