YAH!
YAH...HAH!
BRING ME...
SUN LO, WONG TI,
HAN SU LOK.
YOU ARE SWORN
IN SECRECY AND BLOOD
TO SERVE OUR ORDER--
THE ORDER OF
THE AVENGING DRAGON.
YOU ARE SWORN TO WIPE OUT
THE STAIN UPON OUR HONOR
AS GUARDIANS
OF THE ROYAL HOUSEHOLD,
FOR OUR FAILURE TO PROTECT
THE LIFE OF THE IMPERIAL NEPHEW,
SUN LO
WONG TI
HAN SU LOK
WE, YOUR BROTHERS
CALL UPON YOU
TO FULFILL YOUR OATH.
YOUR PROVEN EXCELLENCE
IN SEPARATE SKILLS HAVE EARNED
YOU THE SACRED PRIVILEGE
OF BEING THE FIRST
TO BE SENT FORTH.
THE ORDER COMPELS YOU TO LEAVE
AT ONCE FOR AMERICA.
SOMEWHERE WITHIN THAT
COUNTRY'S WESTERN LANDS,
THE MAN WHO HAS DISHONORED US
WANDERS AT WILL
SEPARATED FROM OUR VENGEANCE
BY A GREAT OCEAN.
YOU MUST CROSS THE WATERS
OF THAT OCEAN
SEARCH OUT THIS MAN
WHO HAS DISHONORED US,
AND DESTROY HIM AT THE COST
OF YOUR LIVES
THIS RENEGADE SHAOLIN PRIEST...
KWAI CHANG CAINE.
Master Kan: YOUR TREAD
MUST BE LIGHT AND SHORT
AS THOUGH YOUR PATH
WERE UPON RICE PAPER.
IT IS SAID A SHAOLIN PRIEST
CAN WALK THROUGH WALLS...
LOOKED FOR, HE CANNOT BE SEEN...
LISTENED FOR,
HE CANNOT BE HEARD...
TOUCHED, HE CANNOT BE FELT.
THIS RICE PAPER IS THE TEST--
FRAGILE AS THE WINGS
OF THE DRAGONFLY,
CLINGING AS A COCOON
OF THE SILKWORM.
WHEN YOU CAN WALK ITS LENGTH
AND LEAVE NO TRACE
YOU WILL HAVE LEARNED.
WHERE'D YOU
COME FROM?
A MAN HAS DIED HERE
LAST NIGHT.
THAT'S NEWS TO ME.
UH, SHERIFF...
MATTER OF FACT,
A MAN DID DIE.
HE IS HERE
IN THIS BUILDING.
NOW, LISTEN,
I DON'T--
MATTER OF FACT,
HE IS.
VINNIE WAS FIGURING
ON PUTTING HIM AWAY
TOMORROW.
I WOULD LIKE
TO SEE THE BODY.
WHY?
I BELIEVE IT IS
SOMEONE I HAVE KNOWN.
WELL, THAT'S MORE THAN
THE REST OF US CAN SAY.
THE WAY IT IS,
I'VE BEEN AWAY
MOST OF THE DAY.
WE FOUND HIM IN A SHACK
OUTSIDE OF TOWN.
LOOKS LIKE HE SET FIRE
TO THE PLACE AND...
BURNED HIMSELF TO DEATH.
VINNIE HERE'S
THE CORONER--
UNDERTAKER.
BODY WAS BURNT
PRETTY BAD.
EVEN IF YOU KNEW HIM
LIKELY YOU WOULDN'T
RECOGNIZE HIM.
I WILL KNOW HIM.
FOLLOW ME.
THIS IS WHERE
WE KEEP THE BODY...
WAITING FOR SOMEBODY
TO CLAIM HIM.
THERE HE IS.
WELL?
HIS NAME IS
HENRY RAPHAEL CAINE...
MY GRANDFATHER.
STAND UP. PLEASE.
YOU HAVE
YOUR FATHER IN YOU.
I HAVE NOTHING
TO GIVE YOU.
FOR YOU...
I HAVE A FATHER,
A GRANDFATHER,
A GREAT-GRANDFATHER
STRETCHING BACK
TO THE ROOTS OF TIME.
THIS WAS MY FATHER'S.
THIS WAS YOUR FATHER'S.
IT'S ALL I HAVE.
MR. CAINE?
I'M DR. BAXTER.
THE SHERIFF TOLD ME
THAT YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO IDENTIFIED THIS MAN.
YES.
ARE YOU RELATED TO HIM?
HE WAS
MY GRANDFATHER...
HENRY RAPHAEL CAINE.
THE STONECUTTER.
OH, I KNEW HIM
MANY YEARS AGO.
MR. CAINE...
IT MAY COMFORT YOU
TO KNOW
THAT SMOKE
OVERCOMES A PERSON
QUICKLY AND MERCIFULLY.
I'M SURE THAT YOUR
GRANDFATHER'S DEATH
WAS LESS CRUEL
THAN IT MIGHT SEEM.
MY GRANDFATHER DID NOT
DIE OF SMOKE OR FIRE.
WHAT?
WHEN I WASHED HIS BODY,
I FOUND A BULLET HERE.
MURDERED?
WHY?
HENRY HASN'T LIVED IN THESE
PARTS FOR MANY YEARS.
THAT SHACK
WHERE THEY FOUND HIM--
NO ONE EVER GOES THERE.
OR A DRIFTER.
YES, THAT COULD BE.
HENRY PASSING THROUGH,
STOPPED TO REST
DRIFTER CAME UPON HIM,
WANTED HIS MONEY.
HE WAS NOT ROBBED.
HIS MONEY IS HERE.
SADDLEBAG.
BUT YOU SAY
HE WAS SHOT.
THERE MUST BE
SOME REASON.
I WILL DISCOVER IT WHEN
I FIND HIS MURDERER.
YOU SEEM VERY SURE.
I AM.
WHAT ARE YOU AFTER--
VENGEANCE? JUSTICE?
PEACE...
FOR HIS TROUBLED SPIRIT.
WHEN YOU HAVE CROSSED THE SEA
YOU WILL ABIDE FOR A TIME IN
THE CITY CALLED SAN FRANCISCO.
IN ALL THIS TIME, YOU MUST CLING
TO YOUR BLOOD OATH
AND THE STRENGTH OF YOUR WILL
TO VENGEANCE
WILL REACH OUT AND TOUCH
THE SOULS OF OUR SHAME.
Lok: THE LOATHSOME PRESENCE
OF THE HATED SHAOLIN
IS STRONGLY FELT.
HE IS NEAR.
EVEN NOW OUR POWER GOES FORTH
TO SEEK HIM OUT.
LET US PREPARE TO MEET HIM.
WITHIN THIS CUP
IN THE MANNER OF THE FIRST TRIAD
OF THE SUBLIME SERVANTS
WE MINGLE THE BLOOD OF OUR VEINS
WITH THE BLOOD
OF THE AVENGING DRAGON
AND PLEDGE DESTRUCTION
OF KWAI CHANG CAINE.
SOON OUR CHALLENGE
WILL BE PRESENTED.
WE WILL FACE OUR ENEMY.
THE ANCIENT FORMS OF
THE CODE OF TAI SING LULEE
WILL BE HONORED.
HE WILL RESPOND AS HE MUST
AND WE WILL BE FREE
TO ACCOMPLISH OUR DESTINY.
DEATH TO THE PRIEST
KWAI CHANG CAINE.
HOW'D IT END, SIS?
VERY QUICK.
I TOLD YOU HE WAS
TOP ANIMAL, MISS McLEAN
AND HE'LL SIRE YOU A LOT
MORE JUST LIKE HIM.
HE LOOKS TO HAVE SOME BARB
IN HIM, MR. PERKINS.
WHY, HE'S A PUREBRED
FROM THE DARLEY ARABIAN.
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
SIS?
HE'S PURE ENOUGH
ARAB FOR ME.
LOOK.
A TRUE ARAB HAS A MORE
FINELY TAPERED HEAD...
HIS TAIL ISN'T SET LOW. THERE
MAY BE NO MORE THAN THE FACE
AND I DON'T DOUBT
THAT YOU COULD ARGUE.
IT'S NOT GOOD ENOUGH
FOR MY LITTLE SISTER.
NO SALE.
PULL HIM OUT.
SARAH.
AH. COME IN, GEORGE.
COME IN.
IT'S BEEN
QUITE SOME TIME.
UH, CAN I GET YOU,
UH...SOMETHING?
OH, YOU HAVE SOMETHING
ON YOUR MIND.
YES, UH...
YES, SARAH,
I'M SORRY.
IT'S ABOUT HENRY.
HE'S DEAD.
HE WAS MURDERED.
THEY FOUND HIM
IN A CABIN.
THERE WAS A FIRE,
BUT FIRST HE WAS SHOT.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THIS?
YOU'VE BEEN
TO LORDSVILLE?
NO. THAT HAPPENED HERE.
HE CAME BACK
TO CALIFORNIA?
WHY?
I DON'T KNOW.
FROM THE LOOKS OF THINGS,
HE WAS STOPPING OVER.
I THOUGHT HE MIGHT
TRY TO CONTACT YOU.
I CLOSED THE DOOR ON HENRY CAINE
OVER 20 YEARS AGO.
THERE'S NEVER BEEN A WORD
EXCHANGED BETWEEN US SINCE...
NOR REASON FOR ONE.
NOT MANY
BETWEEN US EITHER.
I SAW JOHNNY
AND MARGIT.
THEY COULD HAVE BEEN
OUR GRANDCHILDREN.
NO, GEORGE, NEVER.
THAT'S A DREAM
YOU HAD...ALONE.
I KNOW.
I KNOW BETTER NOW,
BELIEVE ME.
BUT, SARAH, I CAME HERE TO TALK
ABOUT HENRY'S DEATH.
YOU MUST REALIZE THE SHERIFF
WILL HAVE TO MAKE
AN INVESTIGATION.
THAT DOESN'T CONCERN ME.
IT MIGHT.
THERE'S A MAN
IN TOWN...
HENRY'S GRANDSON.
GOOD. MAYBE HE CAN GIVE
THE SHERIFF A HAND.
UH-UH. HE WON'T WAIT
FOR THE SHERIFF.
HE'LL LOOK FOR
HIS OWN ANSWERS.
I THOUGHT YOU
SHOULD KNOW.
THANK YOU, GEORGE.
THANK YOU
FOR COMING BY.
DR. BAXTER,
HOW'VE YOU BEEN?
-FINE, MARGIT. YOU?
-FINE.
ANYTHING WRONG
WITH SARAH?
OH, NO, NO, NO.
I JUST RODE OUT TO SPEAK
TO HER ABOUT A...
AN OLD FRIEND.
ANYBODY I KNOW?
HIS NAME WAS
HENRY RAPHAEL CAINE.
WAS?
HE'S DEAD.
MURDERED.
SARAH NEVER
MENTIONED HIM TO YOU?
NO.
I NEVER HEARD OF HIM.
HMM.
WELL, TAKE CARE.
GOOD DAY.
JOHNNY?
WHAT'S WRONG?
TELL ME.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
HEY, I'M YOUR SISTER,
REMEMBER?
I CAN TELL WHEN
SOMETHING'S BOTHERING YOU.
WELL, YOU KNOW MORE
THAN I DO, THEN.
I DON'T THINK YOU WERE
TELLING THE TRUTH
TO DR. BAXTER
ABOUT THAT MAN.
SIS!
NO. YOU SAID YOU NEVER HEARD
OF HIM. I THINK YOU DID.
WHAT CAN I DO
TO CONVINCE YOU?
LISTEN, SIS, TELL YOU
WHAT I'M GOING TO DO.
SOON AS I FIGURE OUT WHAT IT IS
THAT'S BOTHERING ME
UH, I PROMISE I'LL
COME RUNNING TO YOU
AND YOU'RE THE FIRST
PERSON I'LL TELL, OK?
Man: KEEP, THEN, HIS HATED IMAGE
BEFORE YOU.
KNOW THAT HE MAY LOOK
FOR CONCEALMENT
IN THE VASTNESS OF SPACES
FOR WITHIN THIS VASTNESS,
THERE IS A CLOSENESS
AND WITHIN THIS CLOSENESS
THERE IS ONE
WHO WILL BETRAY HIM.
GOOD AFTERNOON,
MISS McLEAN.
HI.
-DR. BAXTER?
-OH, MARGIT.
I ALWAYS SEEM TO COME
TO YOU, DON'T I?
WELL, I WOULDN'T WANT
THAT TO CHANGE.
WHY DID YOU COME OUT
TO THE RANCH TODAY?
UH, WELL, I HAVEN'T SEEN YOUR
GRANDMOTHER IN A LONG TIME.
BUT WHY TODAY?
IT HAD SOMETHING TO DO WITH THAT
MAN THAT WAS KILLED, DIDN'T IT?
WHAT WAS HIS NAME?
HENRY RAPHAEL CAINE?
WHO IS HE?
UM, HE WAS AN OLD FRIEND
OF YOUR GRANDMOTHER'S.
YOU BOTH KNEW HIM?
YES.
TELL ME ABOUT HIM.
WHAT WAS HE
TO GRANDMOTHER?
MARGIT, UH...
SHE'S THE ONLY ONE
WHO CAN ANSWER THAT.
YEAH, BUT SHE WON'T.
YOU WON'T EITHER,
WILL YOU?
LOOK, MARGIT--
LISTEN, DR. BAXTER,
I'M SCARED.
I'M SCARED FOR JOHNNY.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
YES?
I DID NOT KNOW
YOU WERE BUSY. I AM SORRY.
MISS McLEAN
IS JUST LEAVING.
MARGIT McLEAN
KWAI CHANG CAINE.
CAINE?
I'LL SEE YOU OUT.
ANYTHING ELSE YOU WANT
ME TO DO, DOC?
WHAT? OH, NO, NO.
JUST GO ON SWEEPING.
YOU'RE DOING
A GOOD JOB.
Man: YOU ARE THE NEW
STUDENT. COME CLOSER.
YOU CANNOT SEE.
YOU THINK
I CANNOT SEE?
OF ALL THINGS
TO LIVE IN DARKNESS
MUST BE THE WORST.
FEAR IS
THE ONLY DARKNESS.
TAKE YOUR BROOM AND
STRIKE ME WITH IT.
DO AS I TELL YOU.
STRIKE.
AGAIN.
HERE. CATCH.
HA HA HA!
NEVER ASSUME THAT
BECAUSE A MAN HAS NO EYES
HE CANNOT SEE.
CLOSE YOUR EYES.
WHAT DO YOU HEAR?
I HEAR THE WATER
I HEAR THE BIRDS.
DO YOU HEAR
YOUR OWN HEARTBEAT?
NO.
DO YOU HEAR
THE GRASSHOPPER
WHICH IS AT YOUR FEET?
OLD MAN, HOW IS IT THAT
YOU HEAR THESE THINGS?
YOUNG MAN, HOW IS IT
THAT YOU DO NOT?
I'M SORRY TO KEEP
YOU WAITING.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
I FOUND THIS
IN THE FIRE--
A BOOK OF THE BIBLE.
INSIDE,
AN INSCRIPTION...
IN A WOMAN'S HAND...
IN MEMORIAM.
IS IT NOT STRANGE
THAT THIS WOULD BE SENT
IN MEMORY OF MY GRANDFATHER
BEFORE HIS DEATH?
HOW DO YOU KNOW
IT WAS SENT TO HIM?
SUPPOSE HE PICKED IT UP
SOMEWHERE?
THERE IS A PASSAGE
MARKED.
"AND WHEN HE HAD OPENED
THE FOURTH SEAL
"I HEARD THE VOICE OF THE FOURTH
BEAST SAY COME AND SEE
"AND I LOOKED, AND BEHOLD
A PALE HORSE...
AND HIS NAME THAT SAT
ON HIM WAS DEATH."
A THREAT.
A WARNING.
A PREDICTION.
OR PERHAPS, AS IT SAYS,
A REVELATION FROM THE LORD.
YOU DON'T KNOW THAT
IT WAS MEANT FOR HIM.
BUT I BELIEVE
THAT IT WAS.
MR. CAINE, YOU'VE BURIED
YOUR GRANDFATHER.
LET HIM REST IN PEACE.
A MURDERED MAN CANNOT REST
IN PEACE, NOR CAN I.
IT IS MY DUTY TO REMAIN
UNTIL THE TRUTH IS KNOWN
ABOUT MY GRANDFATHER'S
DEATH.
AND WHERE DO YOU EXPECT
TO FIND THE TRUTH?
WHO WAS THAT WOMAN
WHO WAS HERE?
MARGIT McLEAN.
WHY?
DO YOU KNOW WHY MY GRANDFATHER
CAME TO THIS TOWN?
NO.
NO, I DON'T.
THANK YOU.
WHAT WAS SO FUNNY?
WELL, ASK YOUR BROTHER.
I THOUGHT IT WAS A PERFECTLY
INNOCENT REMARK.
INNOCENT? SARAH!
NOW, I'M REALLY GOING TO
HAVE TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT YOUR MANNERS, JOHNNY.
WAS THERE SOMETHING
YOU WANTED, DEAR?
WHO WAS
HENRY RAPHAEL CAINE?
WHY DO YOU ASK?
DO I ALWAYS GET EVASIONS
INSTEAD OF ANSWERS?
WELL, SUPPOSE I TOLD YOU
I NEVER HEARD THE NAME?
WELL, YOU BOTH OBVIOUSLY
KNOW WHO HE WAS.
HE WAS...
A NOBODY.
COME ON, MARGIT.
WHAT'S ALL THE FUSS ABOUT?
SHE'S BEEN TALKING
TO GEORGE BAXTER.
YES, I HAVE.
YOU KNOW, GEORGE SHOULD
HAVE BEEN BORN A WOMAN.
HE ENJOYS GOSSIP SO MUCH.
WHAT'S ALL THIS INTEREST
IN HENRY CAINE?
WHEN I WAS LEAVING
DR. BAXTER'S OFFICE
-I MET HIS GRANDSON.
-OH.
YES. HE WAS CARRYING A BOOK
WITH A RED BINDING
SORT OF LIKE THE ONES
IN YOUR SET, SARAH.
HOW DID HE GET IT?
I SHOULD THINK
YOU'D HAVE ASKED HIM.
JOHNNY, WHAT DO YOU HAVE
TO DO WITH ALL OF THIS?
WITH WHAT?
WITH WHAT! JOHNNY!
WHAT ARE YOU GETTING
SO UPSET ABOUT, MARGIT?
THERE IS SOMETHING
GOING ON HERE
THAT I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
BUT I DON'T LIKE IT...
AND I AM SCARED FOR YOU.
COME ON, SIS.
THE ONLY THING THAT'S GOING ON
AROUND IS IN YOUR IMAGINATION.
MY IMAGINATION.
LOOK, WE'LL TALK ABOUT IT LATER,
BUT RIGHT NOW
I HAVE A FEW THINGS THAT I GOTTA
GO OVER WITH SARAH, OK?
COME ON.
MARGIT?
THIS CAINE,
THE GRANDSON
WHAT DOES HE LOOK LIKE?
HE'S CHINESE.
CHINESE?
HALF CHINESE.
I MIGHT HAVE
EXPECTED IT.
SHE'S NOT GOING
TO LET IT GO.
AND WHAT IF SHE DOESN'T?
YOU GOING TO LET
A CHINABOY WORRY US?
IT WOULDN'T HURT
TO HAVE A LOOK AT HIM.
IF YOU SAY SO.
JOHNNY?
DID I EVER TELL YOU
HOW PROUD I AM OF YOU?
I WAS JUST IN THE POST OFFICE
GETTING YOUR--
RICHIE, IF YOU WANT
TO BECOME A DOCTOR
YOU'VE GOT TO START WORKING
ON YOUR BEDSIDE MANNER.
-SORRY. HERE.
-THANK YOU.
YOU KNOW THAT MAN WHO
WAS IN HERE YESTERDAY?
CAINE?
I THOUGHT
HE LOOKED FAMILIAR.
YOU KNOW HOW I LIKE TO LOOK
THROUGH THE WANTED POSTERS?
THAT'S HIM.
WHAT ARE
WE GOING TO DO?
I'M A DOCTOR,
NOT A LAWMAN.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO?
I SAW YOU WORKING IN FRONT
OF THE DOCTOR'S OFFICE.
IS IT NOT GOOD
TO SWEEP
KEEP THINGS CLEAN?
I ONLY DO THAT
BECAUSE I HAVE TO.
MY REAL AMBITION IS
TO BE A DOCTOR SOMEDAY.
YOU HAVE LEARNED DISCIPLINE
AND ACQUIRED MANY
NEW ABILITIES.
HOWEVER, NEVER FORGET THAT
A PRIEST'S LIFE IS A SIMPLE ONE
AND MUST REMAIN
FREE OF AMBITION.
HAVE YOU NO AMBITION,
MASTER PO?
ONLY ONE.
5 YEARS HENCE,
IT IS MY WISH
TO MAKE A PILGRIMAGE
TO THE FORBIDDEN CITY.
IT IS A PLACE WHERE EVEN PRIESTS
RECEIVE NO SPECIAL STATUS.
THERE, IN THE TEMPLE
OF HEAVEN
WILL BE A FESTIVAL
THE FULL MOON OF MAY.
IT WLL BE THE 13th DAY
OF THE FIFTH MONTH
OF THE YEAR OF THE DOG.
THAT IS NOT SUCH
A GREAT AMBITION.
BUT IT IS AMBITION
NONETHELESS.
WHO AMONG US
IS WITHOUT FLAW?
CAINE?
I'D LIKE TO TALK TO YOU.
UM, DR. BAXTER TOLD ME
ABOUT YOUR GRANDFATHER...
THAT HE WAS DEAD.
I'M SORRY.
MISS McLEAN?
DID YOU KNOW
MY GRANDFATHER?
NO.
BUT YOU KNOW
SOMETHING ABOUT HIM.
NO.
WHY DID YOU COME
TO SEE ME?
WELL, YESTERDAY
YOU HAD A BOOK
THE SCRIPTURE, I THINK
WITH A RED BINDING.
YES.
I'D LIKE TO BUY IT
FROM YOU.
WHY?
NO SPECIAL REASON.
I'D JUST LIKE
TO HAVE IT.
I DO NOT WISH
TO SELL IT.
ALRIGHT.
THE BOOK WAS SENT TO MY
GRANDFATHER BEFORE HE DIED.
THERE WAS A PASSAGE
UNDERLINED.
INSIDE THE FRONT PAGE,
THERE WERE WORDS.
WHOEVER WROTE THEM KNEW MY
GRANDFATHER WOULD BE KILLED.
Johnny:
CHINABOY.
Margit: JOHNNY.
YOU THINK IT'S YOUR PLACE
TO TALK TO MY SISTER?
I DO NOT WISH
TO OFFEND.
WELL, THEN, COOL OUT MY HORSE
AND CURRY HIM FOR ME...
NOW.
I AM SORRY.
I CANNOT.
YOU'RE A STABLE BOY,
AREN'T YOU?
I HAVE BEEN GIVEN
OTHER WORK.
I'M TELLING YOU
WHAT I WANT YOU TO DO.
JOHNNY,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M NOT DOING
ANYTHING, SIS.
I JUST WANT THIS STABLE BOY
TO TAKE CARE OF MY HORSE.
HE'S NOT A STABLE BOY.
-THIS IS CAINE, THE MAN--
-I DON'T CARE!
HE'LL DO WHAT I TELL HIM TO DO
AND HE WILL, AREN'T YOU, BOY?
DO I HAVE TO USE
A LITTLE PERSUASION?
I HAVE NO WISH
TO FIGHT WITH YOU.
WELL, IT DOESN'T LOOK LIKE
YOU HAVE ANY CHOICE.
Caine: AH! AAH!
UNH!
Margit: JOHNNY!
OH. LET ME SEE.
LEAVE ME ALONE.
THIS DON'T END IT, BOY.
I AM SORRY.
BETTER GET YOU
TO THE DOCTOR.
YOU GONNA
SEE ME AGAIN.
THIS AIN'T THE LAST
AND YOU CAN COUNT ON THAT!
DOC, UH,
I'VE GOT A SCRATCH.
UH-HUH.
WELL, LET ME
HAVE A LOOK.
OH.
UH-HUH. GET ME
SOME SCISSORS
WILL YOU PLEASE,
THERE, MARGIT?
HERE. SIT DOWN.
FIX YOU UP
IN A MINUTE.
HOW'D THIS HAPPEN?
SOME CHINABOY DOWN AT
THE STABLE GOT ORNERY.
UH-HUH. AND THEN YOU GOT ORNERY
RIGHT ALONG WITH HIM, HUH?
YOU WOULDN'T WANT ME TO BACK OFF
FROM A CHINABOY, WOULD YOU?
HIS NAME IS CAINE.
WHAT WAS
THE FIGHT ABOUT?
IT WAS NOTHING. IT WAS JUST KIDS
PLAYING IN THE BARN.
MM-MMM.
YOU THINK HE'S
REALLY PLAYING?
GRANDFATHER'S
BEEN MURDERED.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
THIS MEANS TO YOU
BUT HE'S NOT GOING
TO FORGET IT.
YOU SAW
WHAT HE'S LIKE.
HE'S GOING TO STAY WITH THIS
TILL HE FINDS
THE MAN WHO DID IT.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
Man: YOU ALRIGHT,
JOHNNY?
I'D LIKE TO SEND A WIRE.
AND THE MESSAGE,
MISS McLEAN?
UH, THE CHINESE LIGATION
IN SAN FRANCISCO.
THE MAN YOU WANT FOR MURDER
IS HERE IN GURNEYVILLE.
HOW DO YOU WANT
TO SIGN IT?
NO SIGNATURE.
THE LAW REQUIRES IT,
MISS McLEAN.
ANY NAME WILL DO.
JUDAS.
Man: HEAR US, PRIEST.
THE MOMENT OF MEETING
WRITTEN IN BLOOD
FROM THE BEGINNINGS OF TIME
IS HERE
ACCORDING TO THE ANCIENT CODES
OF SACRED HONOR.
WE BID YOU HERE
AND WE BID YOU COME.
Master Kan: YOU MUST PREPARE
YOURSELF FOR WHAT LIES AHEAD
IN YOUR CHOSEN ROLE
AS PRIEST.
THE NATURE OF WIND
AND FIRE AND ICE
THE FRAILTY OF THE HUMAN
CONDITION IN HUNGER AND THIRST
AND FATIGUE
THE PREDATORY INSTINCTS
OF LIVING THINGS
THE GREED AND FINALITY BURIED
IN THE HEARTS OF MEN.
YOU MUST BE PREPARED TO SURVIVE
THROUGH ALL OF THIS.
THESE GRACEFUL MOVEMENTS
YOU NOW PERFORM
BELONG WITH THE RIGORS
OF ALL THOSE DISCIPLINES
WHICH YOUR MASTERS
IMPOSE UPON YOU
WILL HELP YOU TO DEVELOP
THE INNER STRENGTH--
THAT WHICH WE CALL CHI--
AND WHEN YOU COME TO MEET
YOUR GREATEST TEST
YOUR HIGHEST CHALLENGES
WHEN YOU CALL UPON YOUR CHI,
IT WILL NOT DESERT YOU.
COME ON.
HE'S WAITING ON YOU.
YOU WISH TO SEE ME?
MR. CAINE, UH, SOMETHING'S BEEN
TAKEN FROM THIS OFFICE HERE
THAT CONCERNS YOU...
A POSTER.
YOU KNOW THE ONE
I'M SPEAKING OF?
YES.
IT WAS REMOVED WITHOUT MY
KNOWLEDGE OR MY PERMISSION
BY MARGIT McLEAN.
I DIDN'T REALIZE IT
UNTIL SHE'D GONE.
YOU DON'T SEEM
VERY ALARMED.
THERE IS NOTHING
TO BE DONE.
MARGIT MAY NOTIFY
THE AUTHORITIES.
I BELIEVE SHE HAS
ALREADY DONE SO.
THEY'LL COME HERE
LOOKING FOR YOU.
YES.
YOU'RE JUST GOING
TO LET THEM COME?
I...STAND.
OH!
YOU'RE AS STUBBORN
AS HE WAS!
MY GRANDFATHER?
YEAH.
WE WERE FRIENDS
40 YEARS AGO...
TILL WE FELL IN LOVE
WITH THE SAME GIRL...
SARAH KINGSLEY.
IS SHE STILL ALIVE?
YES.
I TALKED WITH HER
THIS MORNING.
THE INSCRIPTION
ON THE BIBLE
WAS IN THE HAND
OF A WOMAN.
YOU STILL LOVE THIS
WOMAN, DO YOU NOT?
I'LL ASK YOU
NOTHING ELSE.
UH, NO.
MR. CAINE?
YOU'VE ALREADY MET
MARGIT'S BROTHER...
IN THE LIVERY STABLE.
JOHNNY?
WHATEVER HE MIGHT
HAVE DONE
IT WAS SARAH
THAT MADE IT HAPPEN.
ONE MORE THING I THINK
YOU SHOULD KNOW.
YOUR GRANDFATHER
HENRY CAINE
AND SARAH...
THEY HAD A DAUGHTER.
JOHNNY AND MARGIT
ARE HER CHILDREN.
YOU, JOHNNY,
AND MARGIT...
ARE THE SAME BLOOD.
WHAT DO YOU LOOK FOR BEYOND
THE SEA, GRASSHOPPER?
THAT PART OF ME WHICH
I KNOW LITTLE OF--
THE PAST OUT OF WHICH
I WAS BORN.
THEN SOMEDAY
YOU MUST SEEK IT.
BUT IS IT GOOD TO SEEK
THE PAST, MASTER PO?
DOES IT NOT ROB
THE PRESENT?
IF A MAN DWELLS
ON THE PAST
THEN HE ROBS THE PRESENT.
BUT IF A MAN
IGNORES THE PAST
HE MAY ROB THE FUTURE.
THE SEEDS OF OUR DESTINY
ARE NURTURED
BY THE ROOTS OF OUR PAST.
IT WILL DULL THE PAIN.
IT'S ALREADY FORGOTTEN.
OF COURSE.
I'D EXPECT THAT.
THERE'S ANOTHER WOUND...
DEEPER.
WELL, YOU TOLD ME
TO HAVE A LOOK AT HIM.
YES. EXACTLY.
HAD YOU DONE WHAT I ASKED,
YOU WOULDN'T NEED THAT.
YOU LOWERED YOURSELF,
JOHNNY...
GOT DOWN ON HIS LEVEL
TRUSSLED LIKE
A COMMON RUFFIAN.
HE DOESN'T FIGHT
LIKE A MAN.
DID YOU THINK HE WOULD?
PEOPLE LIKE THAT
HAVE NO SENSE OF FORM.
THEY MAKE THEIR OWN
RULES LIKE ANIMALS.
SARAH...
WHY CAN'T WE
BE DONE WITH IT?
I MEAN...
-I THOUGHT IT WAS FINISHED.
-IT WILL BE.
HE'S STUBBORN.
DOCTOR SAYS HE THINKS HE'S GOING
TO KEEP POKING HIS NOSE IN.
WE MAY HAVE TO DEAL
WITH HIM, THEN.
SARAH...
DON'T PUSH ME TO THAT.
I'M NOT.
I'M ONLY WORRIED
FOR YOU.
YOU'VE GOT A LOT OF
YEARS TO LIVE, JOHNNY.
YOU WANT TO BE FREE TO
LIVE THEM GRACEFULLY...
LIKE A KINGSLEY.
HE'S NOT A KINGSLEY.
HE'S A McLEAN, SARAH.
MARGIT...
SUPPOSE YOU LEAVE THIS
TO JOHNNY AND ME?
DON'T YOU THINK
I BELONG IN THIS?
HE'S MY BROTHER.
OH, MARGIT.
LISTEN, IT'S AS IF I NEVER
WAS A PART OF THIS FAMILY
AS IF YOU 2--
IF YOU FEEL THAT WAY,
WHATEVER IS HOLDING YOU HERE?
SARAH, YOU DIDN'T
HAVE TO DO THAT.
WE CAN'T WORRY ABOUT
HER NOW, JOHNNY.
I'M CONCERNED
ABOUT YOU.
THIS CHINAMAN
NOSING AROUND
IT'S NOT GOOD.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING
SOMETHING?
YES. IN THE FUTURE
REMEMBER WHO YOU ARE.
DO THE RIGHT THING.
SARAH...
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
THE RIGHT THING IS.
HEH.
THERE IS A RIGHT
AND THERE IS A WRONG.
WE'VE ALWAYS KNOWN IT
AND WE'VE ALWAYS ACTED
ON THAT PRINCIPLE.
YOU WILL DO IT
BECAUSE YOU CAN'T
HELP YOURSELF.
I'M SURE OF IT, JOHNNY.
I HAVE SOMETHING
TO TELL YOU...
SOMETHING I DID.
I KNOW. THE POSTER.
YOU SENT A TELEGRAM.
YOU KNOW AND
YOU'RE STILL HERE?
YOU MUST HATE ME.
I DO NOT HATE YOU.
BUT I BETRAYED YOU.
NOT FROM ILL WILL
TO ME...
BUT LOVE FOR
YOUR BROTHER.
YOU FEARED THAT
I WOULD HURT HIM.
I DON'T FEAR THAT ANYMORE.
I DON'T FEEL THAT YOU'D
HURT ANYONE DELIBERATELY.
AND I DON'T--I DON'T BELIEVE
WHAT THE POSTER SAID.
WHY DID THEY OFFER MORE
FOR YOU ALIVE THAN DEAD?
THE CODE OF
TAI SING LULEE.
IF I AM ALIVE, THEN
THEY MAY KILL ME
IN THEIR OWN
SPECIAL WAY.
BUT YOU--YOU CAN RUN NOW.
AS THEY ARE
HONOR BOUND TO COME
I AM HONOR BOUND
TO STAY.
HONOR WILL BE SERVED, PRIEST.
THE TIME OF OUR MEETING
IS AT HAND.
WE AWAIT.
KWAI CHANG CAINE...
WE HAVE COME FOR YOU.
THE IMPERIAL GUARDS
OF THE DRAGON THRONE..
AT THE CENTER OF THE WORLD...
WHO FAILED IN THEIR DUTY
TO PROTECT THE PERSON
OF THE EMPEROR'S
FAVORED NEPHEW.
WHEN YOU KILLED HIM,
THE STENCH OF DISHONOR
DESCENDED ON OUR ORDER