(jet engine roars overhead)
(groans)
(gasps)
Hey, what the hell?
You could've killed me!
What are you doing?!
Campbell! You want
to explain to me
why you didn't secure
that equipment?
Make it stop. Please.
Make it stop.
All-all right. All right.
Calm down, sailor.
What's wrong?
Get it out.
Hey.
Get it out of my head!
RICE: Hey, somebody
get him some water.
Water, please.
(groaning)
Hey. It's okay.
No. No.
Hey, you're gonna be all
right. You're gonna be-- Hey!
(yelling)
♪ Boom, boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ Bang, bang, bang, bang ♪
♪ How, how, how, how ♪
♪ Hey, hey ♪
♪ You gotta come on. ♪
(ship horn blows in distance)
SEBASTIAN:
I'm telling you, Pride,
if I'm right about this,
then I'm wrong.
Well, not that-that
I was wrong, per se,
but just that the initial
calculations were incorrect.
But since those
came from the FBI
and not me...
Rambling.
Right, sorry.
It's an ongoing challenge.
We've come out here many times
in the last several weeks,
and have yet to find anything
to help us figure out
who killed Javier Garcia.
Okay, right.
Well, that-that brings us
back to the calculations.
So, we've been operating
under the belief
that the upward thrust
of the car bomb's detonator
sent the shrapnel out
in a concentric arc, right?
Yeah?
But what if the FBI
never accounted
for a-a lateral dispersion?
Well, then the blast zone
would've been more asymmetrical?
Exactly.
Which would've sent
the shrapnel out
in a whole different
trajectory.
Now, if my calculations
are right,
we might be able
to find something...
(beeping)
...right around...
(rapid beeping)
...there.
Or not.
(sighs)
How about...
something like this?
Oh, yeah.
Melted metal,
outward protuberance,
yeah, yeah.
This-this could be
from the detonator.
Pride, this might be the smoking
gun we've been looking for.
Pretty charred though;
been out here a long time.
Still think you can get
trace evidence?
Oh, yeah, believe me,
if I can find anything
to link Mayor Hamilton
to Garcia's murder, I will.
I know how much
this means to you.
(phone beeping)
Thanks.
(sighs)
Well, we're gonna
have to backburner it for now.
We got to work.
Dead petty officer
in Belle Chasse.
Let's go.
(jet engine roaring)
PRIDE:
What do we know, Christopher?
Petty Officer Robert Campbell,
a member of a construction
detachment out of Gulfport,
took a dive from five stories up
for reasons unknown.
As in, he
killed himself?
That's what we're here
to find out.
That was Campbell's
officer in charge.
He said
before Campbell jumped,
he talked about
a pain in his head,
that he couldn't take it.
Okay. Any history of drug abuse,
psychological issues?
Well, psych eval's normal,
drug tests clean.
Nothing I can see here
that would raise any red flags.
I questioned
nearly every man in his unit;
they all said
Campbell was full of life,
the last guy
they'd expect that from.
PRIDE: A man doesn't
just jump for no reason.
Something drove him
over the edge.
Need to know what.
Loretta.
Well, judging from
the massive head trauma
and the hemorrhaging
from the ears, nose and mouth...
(camera clicking)
...there's no doubt
Campbell died
from the impact of the fall.
He complained of head pain
just before he jumped.
Any indication
of what caused it?
I'd have to get him
into autopsy,
but there was
one thing peculiar.
His eyes are jaundiced.
That didn't happen
from the fall.
But some pre-existing condition
could've made that happen.
Yeah, gallstones,
bile obstructions.
Something tells me constipation
isn't what pushed him
over the ledge.
LOPEZ:
Agent Pride?
Lieutenant Commander Lopez.
I'm sorry I wasn't here
to greet you.
I had to update
the base C.O.
Commander.
P.O. Campbell's
one of yours?
I've been overseeing
the Seabees' work here,
40 of the finest men in uniform.
I'm sorry for your loss.
Any idea why Campbell
might've done this?
No, none.
He's been on time and on task,
and working his tail off
with the rest of my men
to complete the install.
What is it
that you're installing here?
High-speed fiber
optic cable.
Wiring the entire building.
Travel these men down from
Gulfport just to lay some cable?
The base's newest I.T. building.
Getting it online
is paramount
for a variety of reasons.
Do you mind if I go check up
on the rest of my men?
They're pretty shaken.
Course.
Something wrong?
No, just...
seems strange to bring down
a detachment unit
just to install
fiber optic cable.
Well, it is a pretty
specialized install.
LASALLE:
Hey, check this out.
I just did a quick rundown
on Campbell's unit.
Looks like he
wasn't the only one
not feeling well.
All right,
Petty Officer Bryan Howard
apparently checked
himself into
the base clinic
last night,
and he is now sick in quarters.
You'd think the commander
would've mentioned that.
Sebastian, go with Wade
back to the morgue,
when she's ready.
Let me know as soon
as you find out
what Campbell might've been
suffering from.
Meanwhile, we'll go pay
Petty Officer Howard a visit.
I woke up in the middle
of the night,
felt this pressure,
like my head was gonna burst.
Thoughts weren't
making any sense.
It was scary as hell, man.
So you checked yourself
into the clinic?
Doc said I had
dehydration sickness.
Gave me some fluids,
sedatives, sent me on my way.
Well, you were up on that
scaffolding with Campbell
all week, exposed to the sun,
working your butt off, right?
That's right.
So, dehydration, heat stroke--
maybe that's what this is.
(coughing)
If that's all this is, he should
be getting better, not worse.
You mind?
His eyes are jaundiced,
just like Campbell's.
HOWARD: Whoa, whoa, whoa,
are you saying
whatever I've got's
what made Robert jump?
No, we're not saying
anything, sailor.
We're just trying
to figure out what happened.
So, you woke up
in the middle of the night,
sick.
Any idea what caused it?
I don't know.
GREGORIO: When did Campbell
start showing symptoms?
Around the same time?
Yeah, about.
But he just went back to bed.
Look, Campbell
was a beast, okay?
He probably could've taken
a bullet and gone back to work.
Anybody else get sick?
I mean,
something's going around.
You share any food or drink?
No. Although...
Although what?
We had a king cake
delivered to us.
We all had some.
Delivered by who?
The note just said,
"Welcome to Belle Chasse."
We didn't eat
all of it.
I think Robert stashed the
rest in his foot locker.
Angelo Brocato's cakes.
Whoa.
King,
take a look at this.
Blood in the eyes,
foam in the mouth.
No way that's just from
food poisoning, right?
No way.
Any idea what kind of poison
we might be dealing with here?
I've tested all the
usual suspects--
cyanide, arsenic, strychnine--
they all came back negative.
SEBASTIAN:
Yeah, and I checked for ricin,
sarin and poison arrow frog.
No match.
Still, some type
of poison
mutated Petty Officer
Campbell's cells,
caused severe brain swelling.
That explains
what drove him off the ledge.
You know, tetrodotoxin
could've caused cell mutation,
but it... it's faster acting
than what killed Campbell.
Have you checked for polonium?
Hey.
Why aren't the two of you
working side by side?
Sebastian's a bit
of a hypochondriac.
Or, you know, some people
might just say extra careful.
You know. I-I have
a thing about poisons.
It's like how some people are
afraid of snakes or spiders or..
circus clowns, you know.
Four more Seabees from
Campbell's unit were just
admitted into a clinic,
and Petty Officer Howard
is getting sicker.
The base C.O. is isolating them
until they know
what's causing it.
WADE: It's odd
that it's affecting people
at vastly different rates.
Poisons don't usually
work that way.
Then we need
to find out what does
before we lose anyone else.
Sebastian, work with Loretta,
side by side, and learn things.
Okay, but the...
Need to know who ordered
that cake, Patton.
And I wish I can tell you,
but I can't
get anybody from the bakery
on the phone.
This time of day,
that's strange.
Yeah, but I did check
with the base, and according to
their gate log, Angelo Brocato
did, in fact, deliver a cake
at 21:00 hours.
Addressed to who?
No name in particular,
just Barracks 53.
Campbell's unit.
Sounds like they were targeted.
Why? Bunch of Seabees
installing cables.
Yeah, maybe not.
Christopher, Gregorio,
go to Angelo Brocato's.
I want to know
who sent that cake.
Patton, search
surveillance cameras
around the bakery,
I.D. everyone who came in
and out of there yesterday.
Copy that.
Who you calling?
Belle Chasse.
Commander Lopez, please.
I want to know what those
Seabees were really doing.
Tell her
it's Agent Pride, NCIS.
(vehicle door closes)
Excuse me.
Federal agents.
You work here?
Um, yeah.
Why? Is there
something wrong?
The bakery usually closed
at this hour?
No.
Should've been open hours ago.
I mean, I just got here
for my afternoon shift.
I don't know why
my boss didn't call me.
Honestly, I'm a
little worried.
(door creaks)
Door's open.
Oh, no. Jaundiced eyes
and foaming at the mouth.
Same symptoms
as the Seabees.
From sampling the same cake?
I don't think so.
He's got defensive wounds
on his arms and hands.
Looks like he put up a fight.
And lost.
What in the world
is going on here?
(sighs)
Richard Logan's been working
at Angelo Brocato's
for as long as
I can remember.
Yeah, best pastry chef
they've got, too.
Folks order
his king cakes by name.
Only way he would've poisoned
the Seabees' cake...
Is if he was forced
into doing it.
Doc says the killer
knocked out Logan
and must have injected him
with the same poison
that killed our Seabee.
She got time of death?
Yes. Between 9:00
and 10:00 last night,
which, according to
Patton, is the same time
the cake was delivered
to the base.
So killer waits for
customers to leave,
forces the baker
to poison the cake,
and then waits... until
it's delivered to kill him? Why?
Killer probably
didn't want
Logan to I.D. him--
tried to cover his tracks.
Yeah, but by leaving
Logan's body for us to find,
it does anything but.
Sloppy.
It doesn't make sense.
Yeah.
Still, you think
our Seabees were targeted?
No reason not to.
Especially since I can't get
in contact with Commander Lopez.
Even checked with her C.O.
at Gulfport.
Think she went U.A.?
The base C.O.
at Belle Chasse checked
the exit logs;
says that she left
right after we did this morning.
So, wait, are we thinking
she's a suspect now?
Well, only way to know
is to find her.
PATTON: Ah. One step
ahead of y'all.
Check it out.
I was combing through
surveillance footage
around the bakery.
Not a suspicious
customer in sight,
until... I decided
to expand my search window.
Voila.
Commander Lopez.
Lopez? What is
she doing there?
When was this taken?
About a hour and a half ago.
That's right before
Tammy and I got there.
Think we chased her away?
Well, still, what was she doing
there in the first place?
Especially considering the baker
had been dead for hours.
Yeah, too many things don't add
up, and no one's talking to us.
I'll call Director Vance.
See if he can cut
through this bureaucracy.
Guys, we got big problems.
WADE: Yeah, I'm afraid
it's not good, Dwayne.
No, it's worse than not good.
It turns out that the cake
wasn't spiked with a poison,
it was injected with a virus.
When I couldn't identify
the poison, I rechecked
the molecular structure
of the affected cells...
And discovered that
it was actually infested
with microscopic,
single-strand RNAs.
Which means virus?
SEBASTIAN:
Yeah, but not just any virus.
A supervirus--
we're talking
Congolese hemorrhagic fever,
dengue, Ebola
all rolled into one.
Is it contagious?
Very. But fortunately
not airborne.
SEBASTIAN: Right.
The only way to contract it is
either through ingestion,
like with the king cake,
or by touch,
so any skin-to-skin contact
with the infected
can risk exposure.
Means anyone
who's been around our Seabees
or the cake could get it.
The whole base
could be in danger.
So could we.
Except none of us
have shown any symptoms yet.
Still no reason
to take chances.
We stay put in the office
till we all get tested.
Is there a cure?
Not that I know of.
LASALLE:
King.
This could be more than
just an attack on our Seabees.
Could be bioterrorism.
Get the base C.O.
on the phone.
We're gonna lock down
Belle Chasse.
We cannot let this get out.
Dwayne.
(panting)
I'm afraid it already has.
MAN:
Dr. Wade?
Oh, please,
we're wasting valuable time.
Let me just work.
Yes, ma'am.
Loretta!
Loretta.
Talk to me, Loretta.
How did this happen?
(sighs)
It must have happened
at the crime scene.
Without my scrub suit on,
my skin was exposed.
And you handled Campbell's body?
Yeah. Blood particulates,
saliva, sweat.
Doesn't take much.
I assume you and your
team are all right.
Yeah, we-we all tested negative.
Ah, thank God
for that.
Sebastian cleared, too.
(laughs)
Next time, remind me
not to tease him
about being a hypochondriac--
it may have saved his life.
(coughing loudly)
Should you rest, Loretta?
There's no time to rest,
not with others
being infected, too,
and more to come
if we can't stop this
virus from spreading.
The situation at
Belle Chasse?
Base is locked down,
the sick quarantined.
Marine Chemical and Biological
Incident Response Force
is on its way.
How many infected so far?
Seven total--
four of Campbell's Seabees,
three machinists who shared
the barracks with them.
Burn their clothing,
all their belongings.
It's not airborne,
but obviously it's
highly contagious.
Deadly, if we can't
find the cure.
How much time do we have?
You mean how much
time do I have?
Well...
the virus affects
everybody differently.
But I am monitoring my
viral load while I work,
see how quickly it mutates
my white blood cells.
I would say maybe...
ten, 11 hours before...
I can't believe
that this is happening.
How's she doing?
Scared, like the rest of us.
She's counting on us, Sebastian.
Stay focused,
for everybody's sake.
Yeah, easier said than done.
(computer beeps)
Got a match
from the viral database.
QR6.
What is that?
It's a-a supervirus developed
by the Chinese military,
but supposedly, it
never left their lab.
Pride, if this is right, then
this has to be bioterrorism.
I mean, there's no
two ways about it.
But why now? Why Belle Chasse?
I don't know.
I mean, the only good news
is that there's no way
they would have developed
this lethal a bug
without also developing
an antidote.
So even if Loretta
can't come up with a cure...
Yeah, then we can,
as long as we can
find whoever infected
that king cake.
'Cause they'll
probably have the antidote,
since they don't want
to get infected, too.
Only problem is we don't
have that much time.
All right, stay here,
help Loretta.
Wait, hold on, you got
to get me on that base.
What?
Victims are being infected
at different rates, right?
Which means some are
more resistant to the
virus than others.
If I can test their blood, then
maybe I can create my own cure.
I'm-I'm not willing to risk
you getting sick, too...
That's not your choice!
Please, Pride.
I-I know that you want
to do everything you
can to save Loretta,
but so do I, all right?
I-I can't lose her.
(sighs)
We're not gonna lose her,
Sebastian.
I'll get you on with
the Marine Bio Response Force.
You work with them,
but listen to me--
hazmat suit,
wrist tape, the works.
I can't lose you, either.
Oh, wait. Pride.
Pride.
I almost forgot. Uh...
I was able to get a
partial fingerprint
off of that, uh,
Garcia shrapnel.
It's not enough
for an I.D.,
and obviously it's no
way to tie the bombing
to Mayor Hamilton,
but it's a start.
Okay, wh-why are you
showing me this now?
Just, you know, in case
something happens to me.
We'll work on this later,
Sebastian, together.
(phone ringing)
Focus.
Agent Pride.
♪ ♪
Just got off the phone with the
Office of Naval Intelligence.
Finally admitted that
Commander Lopez and her team
were doing
more than just
installing cable
at Belle Chasse.
More, meaning what?
Don't know yet.
ONI needs clearance
to get us read in.
Apparently, it's top secret,
compartmentalized.
They want to keep it that way
until they can get
more specifics
about what the Chinese
are really after.
Targeting Seabees
on a top secret project
not specific
enough for them?
The less people know
exactly what the project is,
the better,
far as they're concerned.
ONI just wants us focusing on
catching whoever's responsible.
What about Commander Lopez?
Did they hear from her?
No. And they're worried.
Turns out they're the ones
who sent her to the bakery
to quietly investigate.
Well, maybe she heard about
the king cake from her men.
At least that explains
why she was there.
Yeah, but not why
she disappeared.
You find anything
on the watch list?
Yeah, a list of Chinese
nationals linked to MSS,
but it'll take us all week
to narrow it down.
Loretta doesn't have all week
and neither do
the other victims.
We need another way to find out
who did this, fast.
Might have
something in here.
Been I.D.-ing
every person and car
in or around Angelo Brocato's
around the time
of the baker's murder.
Nothing came up until...
We matched the license plate
to a silver Toyota 4Runner
reported stolen two days ago
driving by.
Time stamp: 9:33 p.m.
Could be a coincidence, or...
Could be our operatives.
Good work.
I'll put a BOLO out,
notify LSP and FBI, too.
Should we trigger EAS,
go wide?
I mean, it's just...
No, no, no, no, no.
The media gets ahold of this
and puts it out there,
could cause a panic
that the virus
is gonna spread
beyond the base.
Make it all that more difficult
to find our operatives.
Well, the health department
already knows.
They quarantined Wade's morgue.
It's just a matter of time
before the media finds out.
Yep, and stokes
public fear.
We have to keep this contained.
Only one way to do that.
Let me know
when you find that car.
Where's he going?
I bet it's the last place
he wants to go.
(trolley bell clanging)
(Hamilton chuckles)
You got stones, Dwayne,
I'll give you that much.
Last thing we both need is for
the media to get ahold of this.
They've already contacted
my office, more than once.
Media hysteria is not gonna help
me find out who's responsible.
In fact, it'll hurt the cause.
I got a lead, just need
a day or two, maybe less.
Still, I couldn't very
well lie to the people.
I wouldn't be a very good mayor
if I did, now would I?
Apparently the Office of Public
Health is getting calls, too.
They're asking for an
official statement.
And by the way,
how's Loretta doing?
Real shame, isn't it?
So, what?
You're gonna make this personal,
is that it?
This is about trying
to stop an outbreak,
saving innocent people;
this isn't about us, Hamilton.
The hell it's not about us.
Everything's about us
since Garcia.
You may not see this,
Dwayne, but the truth is
we both want the same thing:
what's good for this city.
The only problem
is that you think
that bringing me down
is the best way to do that,
and I can't allow
that to happen.
So what do you want?
I want whatever you got on me.
Whatever you think you got.
Vis-à-vis Garcia.
Sounds like an admission to me.
Not admitting anything.
I just want you off my
back once and for all.
So you're threatening
to impede my investigation,
risk causing widespread fear
just to cover your own ass?
You're the one
doing the threatening,
and I'm not gonna stand for it,
not anymore,
even if it means getting you
and your whole damn team
kicked out of New Orleans.
NCIS is federal.
You don't have the power
or the jurisdiction...
Oh, man, jurisdiction
doesn't mean anything
if you got connections.
And me and SECDEF go way back,
believe me.
Apparently, there's
something called
a mobility agreement.
Says that if
Navy brass thinks
NCIS and the city
aren't getting along,
well, they can re-assign
you to God knows where.
Gloves are off, Dwayne.
You want my help, hmm?
Cooperation?
That only happens
you get me everything you got
on Garcia by this time tomorrow.
Understand?
GREGORIO:
We didn't get a BOLO hit,
but Patton's been tracking
satellite radio signals
from every 4Runner in the area,
when one suddenly vanished.
I think we just found it.
Gregorio.
LASALLE: Look at this.
What is it?
LASALLE:
I'm pretty sure it's Lopez.
Lopez is inside, Pride.
She's dead.
Must've caught her
investigating.
Two more in the backseat.
Wait. Two more?
Who are they?
I just got DNA I.D.s
on both victims,
but I'm afraid you're
not gonna like this.
(clears throat)
They're marines.
I'm sending the files
to you now.
(coughing)
Loretta, you have
to lie down.
We've been through this, Dwayne.
We both know I'm not the only
one running out of time.
LASALLE: Wait a second,
those aren't just any marines.
All right? They're part of
a Biological Response Force
that was headed
for Belle Chasse.
GREGORIO: Wait,
operatives killed Lopez
because she was investigating
them-- that much I get.
But why intercept and kill
the other two?
Try to keep them
from stopping the outbreak?
LASALLE: Hold on.
According to the Belle Chasse
entry log,
Corporals Davis and Lin
just checked in at the main gate
along with their unit.
GREGORIO: So operatives
must have snuck in,
killed them while
they were traveling
with the marine convoy.
But they did all that
just to steal their I.D.s?
LASALLE: Well, that doesn't
make any sense.
I mean, if they're with the
people that infected the base,
that'd be the last place
they'd want to go.
Dwayne.
I know, I know.
Sebastian's at Belle Chasse
waiting for the Response Force.
Which means he has no idea
who those people really are.
(clears throat)
SEBASTIAN: You guys from
the Response Force?
Yeah. Lance Corporal Lin, Davis.
Rest of the team's on its way.
Who are you?
NCIS, Forensic Agent Lund.
I'm here to figure out
how this all happened,
but more importantly,
how we can stop it.
Come on,
let's get geared up.
Straight to voice mail.
We got to get to the base.
(coughing)
Christopher, keep calling
Sebastian on his cell.
I'll call ONI.
Gregorio,
get the base police
to secure Belle Chasse,
put the gates on high alert.
Loretta, I'll call you as soon
as we know anything, promise.
(coughing, wheezing)
Hey! Dr. Wade!
(monitor beeping)
DOCTOR: Last antibiotic
isn't working, either.
Get me carbapenem, stat.
Let's intubate her.
Come on, come on.
Hurry up, people.
If we want to save her,
we've got to stabilize her.
PRIDE:
Is she conscious, talking?
All right, you tell her
to take care
and that we're out here doing
everything we can on our end.
Thank you.
How's Wade?
Thinking about putting her
in a medically induced coma
to slow her metabolism,
buy time.
How much time
she have?
Not much.
Agent Pride.
I'm Captain Rogers,
Base Commanding Officer here.
Any luck finding my agent?
Not yet, but it's a large base;
we're still searching.
But we're under full lockdown,
every access point guarded.
Operatives won't
be able to escape
without going through us.
Okay, well, the problem is
we got to take them alive.
They may be the only ones
with an antidote.
Still can't
reach Sebastian, King.
Why would he
turn off his phone?
He wouldn't.
Is there a secure area on base
where cell phones are jammed?
DOWNEY:
Yes, there is.
Commander Downey,
Naval Intelligence.
We spoke earlier. Follow me.
Yes, sir.
LASALLE: Looks like
we finally got clearance.
Hopefully. Better
late than never.
I'll download you on the way.
I got a vehicle.
SEBASTIAN: I still
don't know why we're here
or why we're wearing
protective gear.
P.O. Campbell's blood
particulates could be anywhere.
SEBASTIAN: Yeah, but the area's
already been cleared.
What we need to be doing
is testing the infected
for resistant antibodies.
This is our jurisdiction,
Agent Lund,
not yours.
There a problem?
No. Everything's good.
LIN: All right. Check for
residual contamination
out here, we'll check inside.
Let's go.
(panting)
Crap.
We think the biological attack
was really just a diversion
to get the operatives on base.
By killing
the Marine Response Force.
Because they knew they'd be
the first ones called in,
Navy 911.
DOWNEY:
Exactly.
But to do what?
Why go through all this?
Smokescreen?
Probably.
Best way to breach
a highly-secure area:
create widespread panic.
Commander Lopez's team
was installing secure cables
to what D.O.D. had hoped
would become the first
ship activation center
east of San Diego.
Ship activation?
You have to understand
how Navy ships work.
They're basically just
floating hunks of metal
until they're programmed
into warships.
It's a highly classified
procedure,
and the hope was this base
could expand our reach.
The more ships activated,
the more the Chinese
have to contend with.
They don't want that to happen.
At all costs, apparently.
So what do they want?
How do they expect to stop
the programming?
Steal the ship activation CPU
and all the stored intel.
Make D.O.D. lose faith
in Belle Chasse.
(indistinct radio chatter)
♪ ♪
(computer beeps)
(alarm wailing)
(Lin shouts in Mandarin)
(shouts in Mandarin)
(alarm continues wailing)
(tires screech)
Sebastian.
Get down, get down!
All right, check on Sebastian.
Alert the gate.
We need them taken alive.
Let's go!
Suspects headed to main gate.
Capture, do not kill.
Repeat, capture, do not kill.
Now.
Deploy the spike strip!
Go, go, go!
(tires screech)
Hold your fire!
Cease fire!
Stop shooting! There's nowhere
to go; you're surrounded!
Hands out the window, now.
Do it now!
Outside the window,
slow!
(gagging)
No, no, no.
Understood. Please, though,
just do everything you can.
I should have known the moment
I saw that those operatives
didn't tape up their wrists--
I don't know how I missed it.
Sebastian, you did your best.
You-you followed them,
you engaged them.
You-you were outgunned.
That's not what I mean.
I mean, I knew that they were
bad guys, it just didn't
occur to me that the only reason
they weren't afraid
of being infected was
'cause they had been inoculated.
The antidote was already
in their system.
I should've
figured that out sooner.
Wouldn't have
made any difference.
They weren't gonna
be taken alive.
They're trained
to protect state secrets.
All right?
No matter the cost.
Sebastian, hey,
can you duplicate it?
I'm-I'm trying to separate
the antibodies right now,
but Wade doesn't
have that much time.
Hey, King, Patton may have
found something
off the activation CPU...
I don't care about the case
right now, Christopher.
It's not about the case,
it's about Wade.
We found the CPU hooked up
to the docking station
in the operative's van.
They were uploading it
to someone while we were
chasing them.
Yeah, someone off-site.
They must've knew they weren't
getting out of there alive.
But they still wanted
to transfer the intel
to whoever
they were working for,
probably the handler.
Can you trace the signal?
That's why we're calling.
Tracking down
the receiver's I.P. address,
vectoring the location.
Stand by.
Pride, if we can
find the handler...
There's a good chance
he might have
the antidote on him
as a precaution.
Got it, sending it now.
Alferd Supply
in Chalmette.
We'll meet you there.
(siren wailing)
NCIS! Get your hands up!
Federal agents! Don't move!
Hey!
(panting)
Cyanide.
Clear.
Okay.
Start searching everywhere.
That antidote's
got to be here somewhere.
So we're not
wasting time here.
You are under arrest for murder,
terrorism, espionage.
But I don't care
about any of that.
All I want is to get
the antidote to the virus.
Virus? What virus?
You do not want
to mess with me right now,
do you understand that?
My friend is dying
because of you,
and if you don't
help me save her...
I'm not afraid to die.
SEBASTIAN:
No?
Not quickly, maybe, but...
how about slowly?
Painfully,
like all your victims.
You know, uh,
injecting the baker
directly with
the virus...
...that must've made his death
that much more excruciating.
His brain probably
swelled up immediately,
lungs filled with blood,
drowning him,
convulsions.
You can't do this.
(grunts)
He can't, but I can.
And there's nobody's
here to stop me.
(grunts)
No, wait! The table!
The antidote's
under the card table!
Got it.
All right, get it to the
base and Loretta. Hurry!
Sebastian.
Were you really
gonna inject him?
For her, yeah.
Get going.
What now?
Now we're gonna book you.
We got a treasure trove
of incriminating evidence
against you.
Probably the only way
to get out of the death penalty
is if you admit
to who you're working for.
You're not getting that
out of me.
Well, I don't think it's us
you got to worry about.
Oh, no, that's NSA
and DHS territory,
but if my memory serves me,
Guantanamo...
(gunshot)
What the hell?
Someone just shot him
through a friggin' brick wall!
(whispers):
Okay.
Bullet casing.
Still warm.
Is that .50 caliber?
Not just any .50 caliber.
Penetrates through a brick wall
without line of sight
and still hits its target?
It's got to be DARPA,
thermal scope, heat seeking.
Must have been another operative
who wanted to make sure
that this one didn't talk.
Except I don't think
the operative was Chinese.
This is U.S. technology, Pride.
It's brand-new, too.
Which means whoever did this
had to be homegrown American.
(heart monitor beeping steadily)
Knock, knock.
Hey!
Hey.
(chuckles)
How you feeling?
That's sort of
a stupid question, I know.
I'm sorry. It's--
I-I don't know how to act
in situations like this.
I mean, obviously,
after everything
you've been through,
you're not feeling great,
but at the same time,
I don't know what I'm...
Sebastian.
Just ask me again.
How you feeling?
I feel like crap.
But I'm alive and I'll take it,
thanks to you.
Thanks to me? No, I can't...
Oh, don't even go there.
Pride already told me
what you did.
Said you saved my life.
I mean...
I didn't, you know.
Not really.
Not by myself.
It was sort of,
like, a group...
Come here.
Want to give you a hug.
Mm.
Thank you.
Anytime.
I'm proud of you,
Sebastian.
You faced your fears.
You risked your life
to save others.
I heard you even
threatened to go a little rogue.
That's what I heard.
Yeah, well, you know.
Guess that means I'm finally
becoming a real agent.
No.
Means you're finally
becoming yourself.
Hey.
Am I interrupting?
No.
No. What's up?
Just thought
you'd like to know
I checked with the medic
at Belle Chasse.
Everyone's recovering.
Good. Good.
Kind of a major whirlwind
last couple of days, huh?
I still can't believe
everything that happened.
And everything
that almost happened.
Right? So strange, though.
All that goes down
all the time,
public never even
knows about it.
Not easy keeping it
that way sometimes.
Something else?
Yeah.
I, uh, got a
partial fingerprint
on the .50 caliber cartridge
that killed our handler.
You get an I.D.?
No.
But I think you'll
find this interesting.
Turns out the print
matches the partial
Sebastian lifted off of Garcia's
detonator you guys found.
Yep.
Same person
killed both people.
But wait.
If that's true,
then that would mean...
That would mean
the killer's working
for Mayor Hamilton,
which also means
Hamilton could be
behind both killings.
And, if so,
whatever the good mayor
is up to
is a lot bigger than we thought.
No wonder he's trying
to threaten us.
You're late, Dwayne.
Thought you weren't
gonna show.
Wouldn't want to
disappoint you, Mr. Mayor.
Good, I'm glad.
That for me?
Yeah.
Whoa, wait, wait.
Wh-What is this?
I told you I wanted everything
you had on Garcia's murder.
I remember.
Gloves are off.
Your words.
Captioning sponsored by
CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org
Uh-oh.