Previously on Prison Break:
It will work out. You have my word.
Be careful.
Jane's gonna look after you. Hey.
I have a sister I haven't talked to
in 15 years.
-You think she's better off for it?
-Bruce?
We said not to use this number,
but I needed to know you were okay.
It was you.
What are you talking about, Sara?
I got three words for you.
We gotta run.
I wanna turn myself in.
But I got one condition.
Your wife was released an hour ago.
She'll be here soon.
Just hold up your end of the deal.
I'll get you Scofield.
An NSA analyst
sympathetic to our cause...
...got his hands on a phone conversation
the president had with Terrence Steadman...
...two weeks
after you supposedly killed him.
Twenty-four hours later, Tancredi is dead,
the analyst is missing...
...and the White House echelon tapes
have been deleted from the mainframe.
There's a tape.
It gives us everything we need.
Linc will be set free if we find it.
You have something here.
There'll be a lot
who wish you didn't, but you do.
You think it's a conversation?
One they don't want us to hear.
-You ready?
-Let's do it.
Oh, my God.
Yeah.
Patoshik, dead.
Franklin, incarcerated and assisting
with the capture of Scofield and Burrows.
-What exactly is the protocol with that?
-I'll handle that.
We're at the halfway mark, people.
Burrows, Scofield, Bagwell, Sucre.
They're still out there.
-Now, I heard a report came in from....
-Mexico.
Fernando Sucre was almost apprehended
at the airport in lxtapa.
Excuse me.
My office, please.
-What the hell are you doing here?
-I came for my damn money.
-Your what?
-The Patoshik reward money.
See, how a reward works is,
someone gets rewarded the money.
And since I'm the one
who bloodhounded Haywire...
...the money gets rewarded to me.
You come to my office--?
If you'd returned any of my calls,
I wouldn't have had to.
-We had a deal.
-The deal was you stay under the radar.
Is this under the radar, Brad?
No, this is an office full of federal agents
who now have all seen your face.
Hey, I don't care what they see.
Hell, if you don't pay up,
I'll go out there and drop trou.
Patoshik died, you stupid son of a bitch.
There's paperwork involved.
Of course, you're gonna get the money.
But you'll have to be patient.
And if you ever
come in my office again...
...you will not only never see the cash...
...you'll never see another sunrise.
Now, we gonna keep crying about money
you've already got coming to you...
...or do you wanna make some more?
I'm listening.
Ever been to Mexico?
We give this to the press,
the government will discredit it.
Just like they did with the tape we made.
Okay.
So, what do we do with it?
There are people in the administration
Dad was working with.
If we give it to them, they'll finally have
the smoking gun they need...
...to bring Caroline Reynolds down.
But they'll release the tape, not us.
And how can she discredit
her own appointees? Sure.
We're gonna give the only thing
that can exonerate me...
...to someone who works
for the government?
The same government that set me up?!
We'll have to find someone we can trust.
Someone honest.
Jane Phillips.
She'll know someone that can help us.
She worked with Dad.
She's watching L.J.
I trust her, Michael.
She'll do it. She'll find someone.
Well, I hope you're right.
Because this is our last shot.
This'll do you right.
It's good from a thousand yards out.
She a clean shot?
Like a good woman, she does not stray.
Bariment stainless steel fluted barrel,
.308 caliber...
...175 grain, hollow point.
-I'll take the case too.
-She's a throw-in.
The serial numbers have been cleaned.
The chamber's been scraped
to throw off ballistics...
...just in case you're not,
you know, shooting at tin cans.
No, I'm hunting bigger game than that.
Hey! Hey, hey!
Radio silence.
I just don't know how often
he checks this thing, all right?
Well, it seems not that often,
considering you've posted three messages.
I'm starting to wonder
why I need you at all.
To get Scofield. What?
What are we doing here?
Well, I can type, and Scofield can't see
who's sending him the messages.
Well, he's gonna see whatever little
rent-a-fed cops that you guys have set up...
...whatever place you'll set up
to meet him.
You and I both know
how smart this kid is, right?
Smarter than you,
considering you're wearing orange.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah.
Fish is not gonna peek his little white ass
out from any rock that he's hiding...
...unless he sees a--
A familiar-- And that's your face?
Yeah, you're damned straight it is.
Don't pretend like you don't need me.
You said you overheard him telling Sucre
about a website....
-Don't pretend you don't need me!
-You overheard--
-He's a Boy Scout.
-I don't see how that helps!
If you have a bit of patience,
he will hit me back!
I'm the only one now
helping your family.
-I help my family, okay?
-So do I.
I got Kacee released.
I get Dede medical care.
I'm the one that allows you to visit them,
and I'm the one that can take it away.
It looks like we both need each other,
doesn't it?
-Do we?
-So I'll hold up my end of the bargain.
And guess what? You hold up yours.
Now, get off my back.
You can get what you want.
Just give me what I want.
Give me Scofield.
-Hello?
-Hey, buddy.
Dad?
Yeah, it's me. How you holding up?
Okay. How about you?
Good. Good.
I miss you.
Yeah, me too.
I didn't know you had Jane's number.
Yeah. Well, we exchanged numbers
when you guys split.
-You never called.
-No. Yeah.
I'm sorry. It's been,
it's been dangerous, you know.
-Real dangerous.
-It's okay.
L.J., listen. I know I've said this before...
...we've found something
that'll finally put this stuff behind us.
When it's good, when it's safe,
I'm gonna come and get you.
-You, me, your uncle, we can--
-Dad.
-Yeah?
-I want you to end this more than anything.
But I'm in school again.
Under a fake name,
but it's still school, you know?
I mean, it's not the same...
...but it's the closest thing to a home
I've had in a long time.
I guess-- I guess I'm just saying...
...that for now, for a while...
...I just wanna stay in one place.
Have something normal.
Yeah, yeah. I get it.
I....
-I need to speak with Jane.
-Okay.
I love you, Dad.
I love you too, son.
Mr. Webster, sorry to keep you waiting.
Oh, it's no problem, doc.
I just wanted to tell you
how much I appreciate you...
...seeing me on such short notice.
That's what I'm here for.
Good.
Because I got a few things
I need to get off my chest.
See you, Jane.
Cooper Green?
Former deputy attorney general.
Splits his time between D.C.,
Chicago and New York.
Jane says he's been an ally
of Dad's forever.
We find him, we got a shot.
How's L.J.?
He's all right.
Cooper Green's office.
-Sorry, Mr. Green isn't available at this time.
-Please, this is very important.
Just tell him I have some information
regarding the sons of Aldo Burrows.
-Aldo Burrows?
-Yes.
He and Mr. Green used to work together.
Please hold. I'll try to reach him.
She's tracking him down.
-Hello.
-Mr. Green, this is Michael Scofield.
Do you know who I am?
Of course. I knew your father,
and I know what happened to him.
I'm sorry. He was a good man
trying to do good things.
Well, so are we.
We have something.
-The tape?
-You've heard of it?
Well, I know a lot of people
have been looking for it.
What's on the tape?
If you want to find out,
there is a bronze statue of a mammoth...
...at the southwest corner of Ebert Park.
I need you there in an hour.
-Do you have a blue suit?
-Yes.
Wear it, and a red tie.
That way, we'll know who you are.
Ready?
Yeah.
Good luck.
-This'll work.
-You think?
Hello, Sara.
I figured you'd show up eventually.
You look good, Bruce.
You've done well for yourself
at my father's expense.
I had nothing to do with your father.
He was murdered.
By you, and then you tried
to have me killed. Don't--
How can you say that?
My line was tapped, they heard you tell me
that you were at that payphone.
-Sara, I've known your family my entire life.
-Which makes your betrayal disgusting.
For what it's worth,
I've been tortured already. Didn't work.
I shouldn't have to defend myself to you.
If you can't trust me,
then all I can do is just wish you luck.
Go.
Look, before you get started,
I'm gonna save you some time here, jefe.
I played rat for you once,
and that was it.
I got protection now.
I let the top bangers in here cherry-pick
the laundry, clean sheets, new shorts.
And for that, I'm untouchable.
So threaten all you want, homes.
Yo, man, what are you gonna do?
You don't look like
you play too much tennis, Manche.
This is probably more your speed.
Entertainment center.
Wide-screen plasma.
Pinball. Pool table.
-What the hell is this?
-Your future.
At Kankakee Minimum Security
Correctional Center...
...where the only thing softer
than the pillows are the guards.
I didn't come here to threaten.
I mean, why whip the mule...
...when he'll work even harder
for a sugar cube?
The same connections got this fox
out of the river so quick.
Well, I can use them for you too.
All I need to know is where down in Mejico
your cousin Sucre is headed.
Look, mami, look.
I told you. Llamas.
I think those are alpacas.
That's what I said. A pack of Ilamas.
Fernando! Fernando!
What I'm trying to tell you, doc...
...is I just feel like I've been a penny
on the train tracks my entire life.
And that old Union Pacific
just keeps on coming every day.
Back and forth, just running me down,
running me over, but I will not flatten.
I will not flatten.
You know the nice things about pennies,
Mr. Webster?
They have dates on them.
And you can pick the date.
Your own date.
Today's date.
You can get a fresh start.
You can be a brand-new shiny penny.
You know, I gotta be honest with you, doc.
I had no intention of, whatsoever...
...talking to you
once I got inside your office today.
But I have to admit, I find therapy....
Well, it's therapeutic.
I don't follow.
If you didn't plan on talking today,
why did you come in?
Well, I saw that ad
on the back of the bus stop today...
...and though it wasn't exactly
like looking in the mirror...
...you can't deny that there's a certain
commonality in our visages.
I guess we do look a little bit alike.
But I don't understand.
What--? What the hell you think
you're doing?
-Hello.
-Mr. Green?
-Yes.
-This is Lincoln Burrows.
Do exactly what I say.
Your suit jacket.
Toss it in the trash behind you.
-Excuse me?
-Do it.
All right, I just threw
my $2000 Zegna suit jacket in the garbage.
Good.
There's a fountain on the other side
of the park. Be there in four minutes.
Four--?
Make it quick.
The cell is running out of juice.
You were right.
-He's being tailed?
-Yeah.
On it.
-Yeah?
-I'm looking for a guy in a suit.
Lot of guys with suits--
It's me.
See the fountain?
-How could I not?
-Get in.
They wanna drown the mics,
in case we bugged him.
Hey, mister. This is for you.
-I'm not interested.
-I'm not selling it.
Some dude gave me 20 bucks
to give it to the first wet guy I see. Here.
See the building across from you?
-Yeah.
-Go inside.
This is getting ridiculous.
I've done everything you asked.
-lf you wanna meet me--
-Been burned way too many times.
We need to make sure
this thing goes down right.
Go inside,
and keep the phone to your ear.
-Yeah?
-Where are we?
They've gone inside the Beck Museum.
But we got men out back.
He's not going anywhere.
-Yeah?
-Get to Ebert Park.
I have men on Scofield and Burrows.
Ebert Park?
Scofield set a meet with a target
we're surveilling.
What the hell's Scofield doing
in Chicago?
You're asking why the deer walked
into your cross hairs?
Just take the shot, Mahone.
I'm on it, I'm on it.
And, Alex.
Franklin.
-I'm using Franklin to help me find Scofield.
-Yeah.
We don't need him for that anymore.
What I do need is a death
with no questions.
Hey, look, it's nothing yet, man,
but I'm sure he'll hit me real soon, okay?
You know, if I were in your situation...
...everything you've done,
every decision you've made...
...I'd have done the same thing.
You're a good man, a good father.
There's been a change of plans.
And it looks like I'm not
gonna need your help after all.
So you found Scofield.
My colleagues
are getting pretty close, yeah.
-So--
-So I guess you can set me free, then.
Of course not.
-You and me, we had a deal, right?
-Right.
I get your wife released,
take care of your daughter's health...
...and you get me Scofield.
But you're getting him yourself.
You just said that.
I know, I know.
I just want you to know...
...that I'm gonna keep my promise to you,
and I'm gonna help your family.
But I'm gonna need your help too.
And this is something
you're not gonna wanna do.
I don't want you to do this,
but I need you to.
If you don't,
I'll have Kacee arrested again...
...and I'll have
Dede's medical care stopped...
...and I will hate myself,
and it'll make me sick...
...but I swear to God....
I will ruin their lives. Don't make me.
What the hell are you saying to me?
Later, you'll get a package in your cell.
It's gonna be from me.
I need you to use it, okay?
Well, what's in it?
Yo. Yo, what the hell is in it, man?
Just use it or you'll wish you had.
What's in the package?
What the hell is in the package, man?
Yo, what the hell is in the package, man?
Okay, I'm in the lobby.
Take the stairs to your left.
When you get to the top,
cross the catwalk.
Okay, I'm across.
Go down the hall,
down the stairs to the basement.
Go through the white door.
The one on the left.
Sara, I wish you'd come to me first.
Cooper Green and I go way back.
If anyone can help Michael
and Lincoln, it's him.
-Can I help you?
-Yeah, is Mr. Green in?
Is he expecting you?
Bruce.
Oh, good, you're back.
I'm here to help you.
-Help me? With what?
-Scofield and Burrows. Where are they now?
-This is absurd.
-Mr. Green, this tunnel goes underground.
You're already under another building.
See the second door on your right?
Congratulations.
You made it.
I'm sorry, Sara Tancredi.
I trust you've met with Scofield
and Burrows today?
Well, I'm sure I'd remember if I did.
Sara?
If you're Cooper Green,
who's with Michael right now?
Mr. Green?
I'm Michael Scofield.
Well, it's nice to finally meet you.
Do you have the tape?
It's right here.
-Yeah?
-Lincoln, it's Sara. Listen to me.
The man Michael's with
is not Cooper Green. You hear me?
The man that Michael's with right now
is not Cooper Green.
We should hurry. We're in Chicago.
Won't be long before the Company knows
you're in town.
Where are we going?
Well, we're gonna make sure
that that tape goes into the right hands.
Whose?
A friend.
What kind of friend?
He's a federal judge.
Is that good enough for you?
Well, this tape is my brother's life
and mine.
And consequently, I need a name.
Judge Scott Warren.
A lifetime appointee...
...who was put on the bench
by President Mills.
He has no job to lose,
no loyalty to Reynolds.
Wants to see her gone, just like us.
Well, let's go.
I left my car over by the statue.
You were tailed, Mr. Green.
The judge comes to us.
I'll set up the meeting.
Do you see my clothes?
Your brother made certain that anybody
who was tailing me is long gone.
And on top of that, I'm an asthmatic.
My inhaler is in my jacket pocket,
which Lincoln made me throw away.
I'm okay now, but in about 10 minutes,
I'm gonna have a hard time breathing.
I've got a spare in my glove box,
so could we please just get back to my car?
My car is just a few blocks away.
-Albuterol, Cortizaide or prednizone?
-What?
My mother was an asthmatic.
-What do you use in your inhaler?
-What the hell difference does it make?
Just answer the question, please.
You're a real piece of work,
you know that?
How many times
I gotta prove myself to you?
Just one.
Fine. Cortizaide.
I'm sorry, it's just....
If you knew what--
If you knew what we'd been through.
I understand.
-Can we now just please go to my car?
-Yeah.
A one-way ticket to Bangkok,
s'il vous plait.
Oh, I'm sorry.
We don't have anything until tomorrow.
Unless you don't mind...
...taking a few connections
through Chicago?
And there's one more international stop.
Whatever leaves first.
Okay. ID, please.
Okay, Mr. Stammel?
Oh, it's Dr. Stammel.
-And thank you.
-All right. It'll be just a few minutes.
-I'll check this bag for you.
-Oh, no. It's coming with me.
Sir, I know that bag is way over
the weight limit for carryon.
What difference does a few pounds make
on a 3-ton aircraft whether it's up above--?
It's an FAA violation.
Sir, your bag will be safe.
Today will be a tough day for travelers
in the Windy City...
...as all streets in a six-block radius
of the Grand Carlisle Hotel...
...have been closed to traffic
in anticipation...
...of President Reynolds' speech there
this evening.
This will be one of several
Midwestern stops for the president...
...as she ramps up her election campaign.
Hey, Theo, I know you're new, but we use
both sides of legal pads in this office, okay?
Before we recycle, we reduce.
The Comanche used the entire buffalo.
So can we.
Actually, majority of tribes
would farm land...
...till it was stripped of its fertility,
then they'd just move on.
The Indian as conservationist is a myth
created by white liberal guilt.
-Paul.
-Hi, Kristine.
I'd hoped maybe I'd see you
at Dad's funeral.
That man died
long before his heart stopped.
That funeral was a formality.
-That's really not fair.
-It's true.
So you wanna know how Mom is?
Someone spitting you out of their crotch
doesn't make them your mother.
That woman is insane.
Do you remember?
Have you suppressed it all?
I know, Paul.
I was there every day, unlike you.
-I was there for 18 years.
-And then you just left.
I was 10, Paul.
You were all I had in the world,
and you just left me there.
I'm sorry.
If I could've taken you with me, I would've,
and I've thought about you every day.
I'm not the brother you remember.
I've changed...
...in a really bad way.
To the point where I don't know
what good or bad is anymore.
And I am gonna do something,
I have to do something...
...that a lot of people
are gonna think is horrible.
-Paul.
-And you just remember...
...the brother you grew up with.
Just remember him.
You're my sister, Kristine. I love you.
I was out cold.
I don't know where they went.
And it was their idea for you to meet them
here in the middle of Chicago?
Yeah.
Oh, man.
-Mahone?
-You brought me in too late. They're gone.
-Then find them.
-Let me get this straight.
They come back to a city 15 miles
from the prison they escaped from.
Why would they do that?
Maybe because the president's in Chicago
to make a speech, they're up to something.
Which is why we need to find them.
And of all people...
...they wanna meet somebody
from the attorney general's office.
Your point?
Burrows is innocent.
You're good, Alex, as advertised.
No one's truly innocent.
You, of all people, should know that.
It must've been the receptionist.
She's the only one I spoke to.
Michael Scofield, Cooper Green.
We gotta get as much of that in as possible
before the baby gets here.
Why?
Because.
Once the baby's growing in there,
doesn't it just get kind of wrong?
Oh, yeah.
-What?
-I just felt the baby move.
-No, Fernando, that's impossible.
-I know what I just felt.
Well, the doctor did say
that he can become active...
...after certain activities.
-Did you feel that?
-Yeah, like a flutter?
Flutter, my ass. He's strong.
He's gonna be the captain
of the national soccer team.
You hear that, junior?
Soon as you're born,
I'm putting a soccer ball in your hands.
No, he's gonna have books.
Fine.
Books about soccer.
Hey, baby.
I told you
everything was gonna work out.
We're out in the middle of nowhere.
The baby's doing great.
Everything's gonna be perfect.
Your attention, please.
It looks like we've got nothing
but smooth skies ahead...
...so we should be arriving in Mejico....
Excuse me, when is the meal coming?
I'm starved.
As a way to keep ticket prices low...
...we removed in-flight meals
from our service package.
Well, what's left on the service package?
Pretzels and bags of Krispity Krunch.
Pretzels.
Just a few minutes.
Freshen me up
when you get a chance, darling.
Right away, Dr. Stammel.
Dede's doing real good.
Responding to the meds, eating.
She's gonna be okay.
Because of you.
-She's gonna be okay because of you.
-Yeah.
I need to know...
...you know, that you forgive me.
I know that. Of course I forgive you.
You know, when Dede was like 4,
she wanted to watch this video.
And I kept telling her,
you know, after the game.
After the game, okay?
She kept asking and kept asking.
I lost my patience and I snapped at her.
I snapped at her real bad.
Well, she went over into the corner...
...and I didn't even go over
and say anything.
Why are you getting yourself upset...
...over something that happened years ago,
baby, years ago? Dede loves you.
I want you to do something for me.
I want you to tell her that I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry. And that my baby girl
means everything to me.
I want you to tell her
that she means everything to me, okay?
You tell her that every day.
-Time.
-No matter what.
-Ma'am.
-Tell her.
Tell her, okay?
No matter what, he loves her, okay?
-Ma'am.
-Please. Please, you gotta tell her.
-You have to tell her....
-Okay, okay, okay.
-Ma'am, you really have to go.
-Tell her that her daddy loves her.
Attention, attention.
All spectators must remain
behind the barricade at all times.
We got a Boom Charlie half a block south.
Team leader wants you there.
-What's the M.O.?
-He's got an I.E.D. strapped to--
He asked you to come
to this fountain specifically?
Yeah.
Let me take a look at that park map.
Why not the fountain
on the east side of the park?
Because this was closer
to the payphone they called me at.
No, because this one's closer to them.
They tell you to meet them at the statue,
then the fountain...
...then they send you
to the building across the park.
Why?
Because they wanna keep you
in their sights.
Because they're watching you.
But from where?
The statue, fountain, building.
There. The hotel.
You know what you have?
-I think we have a pretty good idea.
-What you doing?
Getting unique data from the memory key
so we can identify this key from any other...
...label it, start a proper record
of the chain of custody...
...to present to the judges I trust.
Cool.
-No.
-What's wrong?
No, it's the date stamp
on the memory key.
It's the copy date.
-I'm sorry, what's that?
-It's the date the damn thing was copied.
Not the date that the conversation
was originally recorded.
So what? I mean,
you heard what was on the tape.
Without a time stamp of exactly
when this conversation took place...
...we can't prove
that this is Terrence Steadman talking...
...after you supposedly killed him.
This could've happened
a year before his funeral.
No, it can't be authenticated...
...so it can't be admitted
to any court as evidence.
People died because of this.
My family died.
I'm sorry.
Legally speaking, this tape is useless.
-Hi.
-Alexander Mahone, FBI.
Have either of these men checked in?
-Not that I've seen.
-How about this woman?
Yeah.
Room 1006.
Ten-o-six. Ten-o-six. Thank you.
It's not over. We're this close.
You've already said it's done.
Actually, I said it couldn't help
exonerate you in a court of law.
Maybe it can help you outside the law.
How?
Well, we all heard the conversation.
There's more to this tape
than potential proof of Lincoln's innocence.
There is proof of Caroline Reynolds' guilt.
Guilt about something she does not want
anyone to know anything about.
So we blackmail her.
I'm an officer of the court.
I didn't say that.
Blackmail in exchange for what?
A presidential pardon.
So the woman that set me up
is gonna set me free.
I think she'll sign it with her own hand.
Ace Team, Beta Team, this is Leader One.
All spectators must remain
behind the barricade.
The president will be arriving shortly.
The president will reach Home Base
in T-minus 2 minutes.
I love you.