Hear, mister!
Today you leave me in peace, please.
Me not it to tell.
You I will not leave.
- I go.
- It Come, enters.
Oharu?
Did not you obtain
No man?
The 50 years do not result
Easy to disguise.
You are not the unique one that is old woman.
An elder called me
So that went to a cheap inn.
AND what?
I cheered myself to be able to work.
I went myself with him.
But then...
The face illuminated me
With the lamp.
The lamp?
And then it said to all
the men that were there:
"Mirad!
It wants to hide its age!"
"Who wants
to this old one urraca exhausted?"
That is what passed.
A small incident
In my loss life.
I feel it for you.
You look at! Has lit
A blaze!
Calent?onos
Before going us home.
Elderly,
Permit us to heat us.
Some time you thought
That you would finish in this manner?
I have understood that
You worked in the Cut.
What carried you to finish thus?
Me do not ask
On my past.
Eh... eh!
Again doing fire!
Is well. But you have
A great deal of care.
If worries too much,
it will lose the...
Not. Not hair remains it
That to lose.
Where do you go?
To do an ofrenda
in the temple
By my mister.
What good occasion.
You take you your time
And enjoys the views.
They would scold me if did it.
You would be able to pretend that...
You return soon home, Kikukoji.
Nishinotoin awaits your answer.
All counts it you, truth?
I suppose that sent you
Some shameless poetry.
What was?
It do not I know.
You excuse me.
They expect!
Please, they expect!
I am Katsunosuke.
I feel bothering it
But Kijukoji desires seeing it.
Ll?ele home of its friend
In Teramachi.
I feel it, but I should go
al temple to...
We know it.
But of road home...
Will be only a moment.
Please.
He would be thanked him.
Miss Oharu...
Read the letter
That I delivered it the other day?
Of course that not.
Who would read the letter
Of a simple servant?
I burned it without reading it.
I lack talent
To write ingenious poetry.
Not even I know to count
Well the jokes.
But I am loyal and sincere.
It can despise
My under rank.
But it cannot pass for high
My devotion.
If it believes that the devotion
is a sport of courteous...
And qualifies as it pompous...
Good, I not...
Never you will understand
The meaning of the regal?.
You cannot understand
The flavor of the nobility.
Then,
who wants it truly
From among the noble courteous?
Who would marry you.
Doing it happy?
You see house!
I tell itself it
Because I want seeing it happy.
Do not worry about me!
If really it displeasure
as person,
I will leave it in peace.
Not, do not you please me.
But if is for my low position
Never I will yield myself.
You see you!
Oharu, listen me.
A human being...
A woman can be happy
If he marries by love.
The social prestige
Does not equal to the happiness.
You leave me! I have not come here
To listen you!
I will expect alone
To Lord Kikukoji.
I have said that you go!
He is not going to come.
Expect!
I feel it.
Is that...
It had seeing it.
Since began
to come to the Cut,
I have desired it crazily.
Please, accept my love.
I read your letter.
But I cannot marry me
Of any way.
Why not?
Is obvious.
Neither the Cut neither my father
It would permit it us.
Then,
Fugu?onos together.
We will build
Our own home.
We can do it.
I know that can do you happy.
Have arrived.
Welcome.
The police.
I have understood that
The prostitutes utilize this house.
That is ridiculous!
Who has said that?
I will verify it.
Who is you?
A traveler.
You are a servant?
Yes. Of the "All" of lga.
I call myself Inosuke,
Of Yasui.
Prostitute, you have the postage
Of a lady.
From where you are?
Rough!
I am not a prostitute!
I am daughter of Okui,
A samurai of Chion in.
They see with me.
They see!
"Oharu Okui,
despite be
al service of the Cut,
you had an improper conduct
With a humble servant.
Due to this serious lack,
you cannot reside
In the city of Kyoto.
This court
It condemns you al I exile.
Likewise they should be exiled
the parents of Oharu,
as punishment to its deficient one
Paternal supervision.
This sentence enters vigor
to day of today,
7 of November of 1686.
Judge Itakura, Administration
of Religious Matters."
Silence!
You stop!
The relatives cannot pass
From here being said good-bye.
By your fault,
We should live ashamed!
You have destroyed completely
Our honor.
What shame!
What do there is of evil in which a man
And a woman be lovers?
Why itself to cross out of immoral?
How?
You went yourself to the bed with a man
Without our consent!
What would be able to be worse?
But if really we love ourselves,
What has of evil?
Silences!
You have something that to say?
Yes.
Give him a message
To Oharu.
Is well. Of what treats?
"Please, search
to a good man
and it carries a worthy life
To its side.
But...
you assure you that marries
only if treats
of true love."
That is all?
Swims more?
I expect that arrive
the day
In which there be not social hierarchies.
And the men can love!
My beloved one Oharu!
A man of the administration.
It has brought the last wills
Of Katsunosuke.
But you keep it in secret
Set against your father.
Quiet! What do you do?
You free me!
Wait, Oharu!
You leave me to die!
Wait.
I will go with Katsunosuke!
High!
You leave me!
You should not kill you!
The death is not the road!
Is urgent!
- Who is?
- Of part of Lord Matsudaira.
Matsudaira?
That is important.
Of what treats?
Is a messenger of Edo.
You accompany him to the parlor
Right now.
I am going to prepare me.
Welcome.
You help him!
You leave us alone.
I feel very honest, mister.
What mission...?
I seek a lover
For Lord Matsudaira.
A lover?
Yes.
You have come here running
In search of a lover?
Does not be a matter of any joke.
Lady Matsudaira
Cannot have children.
If a gentleman does not leave heirs,
His clan will be ruined.
Is a very serious matter.
Some girls of the feud
They were offered.
But al mister
Not it did none please.
That.
So we decide to seek
A girl in another place.
Kyoto is famous
By its women.
So me they sent here
in search of a woman
Very beautiful.
Of that treats?
I thought that you had come for
Something very costly.
Your mission seems
Very simple.
I fear myself that it is not so simple.
It puts many conditions.
Go, this!
Wants a girl
As this.
It said it my mister.
Already I see.
Of age understood
Among the 15 and the 18 years.
With the round face.
Whose eyes be not
Too much small.
With good eyebrows
And the eyes well separated.
Pretty nose, small mouth
And white and even teeth.
That it not sobresalgan
too much the ears
Neither they be very large.
The long neck
covered with locks
Of unkempt hair.
Long fingers of artist
And the precious nails.
A difficult assignment seems.
Still there is more.
In serious?
With delicate and smooth
piececitos, that they do not smell...
Should have a figure
Round and seductive.
And pretty hips
Acampanadas.
That be guap?ima and without a single
Lunar in all the body.
Fingers of artist.
Has the large mouth.
- What age you have?
- 25 years.
Is a little old woman.
Has the small ears.
The round face.
Go, this!
You leave me to see.
The face too much long.
Has the round face.
Oh, is well...
But with a mole.
Has eyes of zorro.
It has the nose twisted.
Flat nose!
A mole!
Hairy!
What so great standing you have?
24 centimeters.
Is a true grief.
Has the barbilla
Too much sharp.
Has the wide front.
Fat lips.
To see, to see...
Go, the barbilla.
Hatred vanagloriarme,
but more would nobody be able to meet
such quantity of girls
So beautiful.
Are the better
That there is in all the city.
You cannot choose a?
None?
To obtain a heir,
will be worth any girl
Provided that being healthy.
Pretty eyebrows
And the eyes well separated.
Small mouth and
White and even teeth.
You know it yourselves by memory.
I will die before finding
That ideal woman.
I feel it for vos.
I do not come I to understand why
They entrusted you this task.
Not?
Young one more man
It would be able to do him something.
But I, what would be able to do him I
In the road of return?
What is that?
A blind one of Edo.
Standard to sing
To the girls.
Are very popular girls
Among the samurai.
They serve them in its festivals.
Please, a moment.
Look at there.
You have moles in the body?
Lunar?
Not, do not I have.
Absolutely none?
None.
Kahei! The search finished!
I will buy it!
Truth!
The messenger awaits
Your answer.
I will return to tell him
That you are arranged.
I cheer myself a great deal by you.
If a heir gives him
also it will bring you
The happiness to you.
And of course, to me,
Its new one padrino.
Many thanks.
I cheer myself a great deal
That can help us.
We are you
Very you thanked.
Has been a blow of luck
Totally unexpected.
This it will compensate completely
Your passed error.
I will not continue cursing you.
Never we think
that the dance was able
To bring so good luck.
Is certain, it do not we think.
You will receive 100 ryos al counted.
And you will obtain
A good assignment.
Which is the problem?
Do not you be happy, Oharu?
I am going to be a concubine,
Truth?
AND what?
Is a great one mister.
Already you worked in the Cut lmperial
so you know
that al to obtain the favors
Of a gentleman you will rise from rank.
What they expect of you is that
Them of a heir male.
You will obtain a good one
Economic position.
Thus is.
It will be better than ask to the Cut
that it they maintain in secret
before Lord Matsudaira
It harms to investigate.
And of the temple also.
Of course.
We think what to buy
And to carry us to Edo.
We go, Oharu.
I do not want to go.
What?
Irme with a strange one
to give him a son...
Will not be a normal boy.
He will be the heir of a feud.
Katsunosuke it will not permit.
What stupidity!
Still you continue speaking of him!
To say what to say,
I will accept the offering.
Its body has developed well.
It is capable to bring
A boy al world.
In that case, Kazui,
You teach him courteous manners.
And you carrying it before Lady Matsudaira.
In agreement.
The messenger has brought
A future concubine.
In serious? What quick!
Therefore yes.
It is expecting to see you.
You will receive it?
Please, I know tolerant
After the clan.
It is called Oharu.
Oharu, raises the face.
It greets the lady.
Already you can withdraw you.
You leave that it is felt here.
The music pleases you?
Did not you expect to listen
This music here, truth?
The food pleases you by here?
If there is something
That you does not please, d?elo.
Has born a male.
Is a male.
Lnformad to the house.
Of course.
I have stupendous news!
Has born a male!
A male! Is stupendous!
We should report
Al mister immediately.
Is a precious baby.
Is igualito that you.
In serious?
Is happy
The mister because of it?
Of course.
Seems very happy.
When they brought me here
for the first time,
I felt myself alone.
But now I have given birth
to a boy...
You would should to say: "they have done Me
to give birth a boy."
Since they have done me
to give birth a boy,
for the first time I feel
That this is my home.
The mister should be...
Is it more convenient
For the clan.
I cheer myself a great deal.
Where do you carry it yourselves?
I refer al heir.
I am going to give him of mamar.
Not, not! I
I can give him of mamar!
Thanks.
I will remove good benefits
Of this silk.
But do not worry
By the payments.
Lord Matsudaira
It will support me economically.
But my mister
Is very strict.
You refer to Kahei?
My daughter has just to give birth
To a male.
Has given birth
Al heir of the clan Matsudaira.
The heir of the clan?
I have just to inform me
Of the news.
The money is not problem,
you simply
Tr?me what I ask you.
Sight.
Congratulations.
Cheers me o?lo.
I bring also merchandise
Of Hishiya?
Good...
Of course.
You can bring me what please.
Some day I will open a store in Kyoto
To do you the competence.
There is some problem
With the concubine?
Since had the boy,
the love of the mister toward her
Has grown.
There is not no problem.
Unless...
It seems to to be exhausting
The energy.
The doctor says that
she is shortening her
The life.
Since already it was born the heir,
She no longer is of utility here.
Do not you agree?
By good of the clan,
You sending it of return home.
It understood?
They have sent it again
Here for well?
You are sure?
I do not know what to say.
I was so happy.
I filled myself of pride
When had the baby.
I feel it a great deal.
So you have returned.
After giving him
a heir al mister,
you should not show you
So desirous to satisfy him.
Good, now already all it finished.
How Much they gave you?
300 ryos would be
A quantity jousts.
How? Only 5 ryos?
I bought many things.
Had counted
With which you were rich.
And now I am to the neck
Of debts.
You help me and convert you
In courteous of Shimabara.
As soon as gain the sufficient thing,
I will bring you of return.
You would be capable to sell
Really to your own daughter?
I feel it, but does not remain
Another remedy.
Has just to return
Of a great deception.
And now this.
Welcome.
Always I desired to go
To any Shimabara time.
I have worked hard
since the dawn
Until falling the night.
During more than 20 years
I have saved money.
And I believe that already I have
It saved the sufficient thing.
I have come to here
From Echigo.
I feel it a great deal, but not
Remain free rooms.
What beautiful!
Exit of a picture seems!
Besides, our house
Is very expensive.
Is not good my money?
You look at!
Is more than good!
How much money!
Welcome, mister.
I am the owner.
Is that certain?
You prepare the large room.
You serve him the best food
And you give him the best girl.
Welcome.
Thanks, many thanks.
I want that my men
Also they entertain.
The riders? Already I see.
I have my own wine.
We use the best wine
That there is. Thanks.
Thanks.
It gives equal. Centr?onos
In the business.
Why them do not you catch?
It takes.
You have been very gross with him!
I have not been gross! He yes!
I am not a beggar!
Wait!
You know how to entertain
To the men.
You believe yourself too much
Good for it?
Do not you be here
For your own enjoyment.
And do not be so proud
Of your ancestors.
For which I know, you would be able to be
The daughter of a trapero.
What? You call me
Daughter of trapero?
They have bought you
And they have paid by you.
You are not better
That a fish.
We can arrange of you
As us plazca.
Money gave you.
Very well. Your work here
It has finished!
What will say to this your mister?
Nobody more than the region
it will want to hire you
As courteous.
Has been my every fault.
Please, forgive me.
I will change of attitude.
But itself do not tell it.
I do not endure more.
Mister! The young man
Flame to the courteous one.
I will give it another courteous better one.
Not. It Says that this
Pleases it a great deal.
A girl
That it rejects the money!
It wants buying it.
Buying it?
Already the ear.
Please, it reconsiders and you serve him.
We go up.
I know pleasant with him.
You are sure
that you want to forgive me
And to carry me with vos?
Yes. I will be in charge of you.
In reality, I came to Kyoto
In search of a wife.
So you MYSELF will carry with me
As my wife.
If truly me yourselves love,
I will be you faithful.
Why do you laugh yourselves?
Money!
With the money I control the things
And to the persons to my craving.
Everyone succumbs
Before the money.
Incluso a woman
As presumptuous as you.
You do not create that I am covetous.
I want to be with vos because...
I can buy you with money.
The fortune has begun
To smile you.
The money is it all.
Not to have swum larger.
Impostor! Me not strange
That yourself spend so much!
Is a known one falsificador!
Your money is false!
And the forgery
It signifies death.
You remain arrested!
Please, sonr?.
Lntenta to maintain the spirit.
You are again our daughter.
I have been awaiting
This happy reunion.
Never we will return
To carry us badly with you.
Please, you forgive us
And sonr?.
Where did you learn
That song?
Is very pretty.
You have to be someone special.
I feel very ashamed.
I was a courteous acquaintance
when a happy neighborhood existed
In Rokujo.
You take care of.
Thanks.