A SHINTOHO-KOI
COPRODUCTION
THE LIFE OF OHARU
Produced by
HIDEO KOI
Screenplay by KENJI MIZOGUCHI
and YOSHIKATA YODA
Based on a Novel by SAIKAKU IHARA
Story Editor ISAMU YOSHII
Cinematography by
YOSHIMI HIRANO
Lighting by KO FUJIBAYASHI
Sound by MASAKAZU KAMIYA
Musical Director ICHIRO SAITO
Production Design HIROSHI MIZUTANI
First Assistant Director
RYOHEl ARAI
Assistant Director
SEIICHIRO UCHIKAWA
Starring
KINUYO TANAKA
HISAKO YAMANE
TOSHIRO MIFUNE
JUKICHI UNO, ICHIRO SUGAI
EITARO SHINDO, AKIRA OOIZUMI
MASAO SHIMIZU, DAISUKE KATO
TORANOSUKE OGAWA, EIJIRO YANAGI
YURIKO HAMADA
HARUYO ICHIKAWA, KOMAKO HARA
KIKUE MOURI
SADAKO SAWAMURA
TOSHIAKI KONOE
KINNOSUKE TAKAMATSU
BENKEl SHIGANO YA
UNPEl YOKO YAMA
TSUKIE MATSUURA
Directed by
KENJI MIZOGUCHI
This way, mister.
Let me go home.
You know what it means
to come to this side of the gate.
- I'm going home.
- Come inside, quick.
Oharu?
You couldn't find
a customer either?
A woman of 50
can't make herself look 20.
If you feel that way,
imagine how the rest of us feel.
An old man took me
to an inn for pilgrims.
I was glad
to get some business,
so I went along.
Some pilgrims were gathered.
He held a candle up to my face.
A candle?
Then he said
to the young men there...
"Look how she tries
to hide her age!
Would you sleep
with a woman like this?"
I think he was giving them
a lesson in karmic retribution.
You're off
to a bad start tonight.
Look, the old man's
making a fire again.
Let's warm up
before heading home.
Old man, let us get warm.
You used to serve
in the imperial court.
Did you ever think
you'd end up like this?
How did you fall so far?
Please don't ask about my past.
Hey!
Making fires again!
I guess it's all right,
but be very careful.
We will.
Don't worry so much
or you'll go...
Oh, I guess
it's too late to go bald.
Where are you going
in such finery?
To make an offering at the temple
on behalf of my master.
That's good of you.
You should see the sights too,
since you so rarely get out.
I'd be scolded if I did that.
Not at all. Just pretend
you didn't know any better.
You're going home early,
Lord Kikunokoji.
I almost forgot...
Nishinotoin is anxious
for your reply to his poem.
He can't keep anything
a secret, can he?
It seems his poem
was rather forward.
What did it say?
I don't know.
Please excuse me.
Wait! Please wait!
Please wait!
My name is Katsunosuke.
Lord Kikunokoji begs your indulgence
to discuss a certain matter.
Might I ask you to call at the house
of his friend in Teramachi?
I'm sorry, but I've been sent
to the temple on an errand.
Then perhaps
on your way home.
We would be deeply grateful
for just a moment of your time.
Lady Oharu.
Did you read the letter
I sent the other day?
Of course not.
Who would read a letter
from a lowly retainer?
I burned it
without reading a word.
I have no talent
for composing verse.
I lack the wit
even to tell jokes well.
But my heart is true.
You can look down
upon my low rank,
but not upon my sincerity.
The nobility makes sport of sincerity,
turning it into mere wordplay.
If that's how they define
elegance, then I...
You'll never know
the meaning of elegance.
You can't understand
the tastes of the nobility.
Well, then...
does any nobleman love you
as truly as I do?
Has any asked to marry you
and give you a happy home?
Please leave.
I say this because
I want to see you happy.
I don't need your concern.
If you truly dislike me
as a person,
I'll leave you alone.
Yes, I do!
But if it's my low rank
you disdain,
then I'll never give up.
Go away.
Lady Oharu, a human being...
no, a woman
can only be happy
if she marries for love.
Rank and money
don't mean happiness.
I asked you to leave.
I didn't come here to listen to you.
I'll wait alone
for Lord Kikunokoji.
I said leave.
My lord isn't coming.
Please wait!
I'm sorry.
I simply had to see you.
Ever since
you came to the court,
every glimpse of you
has torn at my heart.
Please at least consider
what I've said.
I did read your letter.
But no matter what you say,
we can never be together.
Why not?
Neither the court nor my father
would ever allow it.
Then we'll run away.
We'll make a home of our own.
I'll do my utmost.
I'd gladly do anything
to protect you.
Lady Oharu!
Madam, we have guests.
Welcome.
The imperial magistrate
sent us.
We understand that
prostitutes use this house.
That's absurd!
Who said such a thing?
I'll see for myself.
Who are you?
I'm just passing through.
Aren't you a retainer?
Yes.
I belong to the Todo clan
of Iga province.
My name is Inosuke.
I serve Lord Senuemon Yasui.
You dress
like a noblewoman.
Where are you from, whore?
How dare you!
I'm not a prostitute.
I'm the daughter
of Shinzaemon Okui,
a samurai
serving Chion-in Temple.
Take her.
I'm taking you
to the magistrate.
Go!
Oharu Okui, while serving
in the imperial court,
you violated protocol
by associating
with a personage of low birth.
As punishment for this illicit liaison,
you are sentenced as follows:
You are hereby banished
from the city of Kyoto,
never to return.
Your parents, for failing
to provide proper guidance,
are hereby also
sentenced to exile.
This judgment
is effective today,
the 7th of November, 1686.
Katsufusa Itakura,
Magistrate of Temples and Shrines.
Stop!
Relatives may go no further.
Bid them farewell here.
It's your fault we must live out here
in the middle of nowhere.
You've single-handedly destroyed
this noble family's honor.
You're a horrible child.
Why is it wrong for a man
and woman to fall in love?
Why is it immoral?
What?
You slept with a man
without our consent.
If that isn't immoral, what is?
Stop talking nonsense!
So what if we differ in rank?
How can it be wrong
if we truly love one another?
Silence!
Do you have
any last words?
Yes.
Please give Lady Oharu
the following message.
Very well.
Proceed.
"Please find a good man
and make a happy home.
But be sure to marry
only for true love."
Is that all?
Anything else?
I hope the day will come
when people can love freely,
regardless of rank or class.
Oharu!
It was a messenger
from the magistrate.
He brought
Katsunosuke's will.
But you mustn't tell Father.
Oharu, stop!
What are you doing?
Let me go!
Stop!
Wait, Oharu!
Leave me alone!
I'm going
to join Katsunosuke!
Stop!
You mustn't!
Let me go!
This isn't
the end of the world!
If you kill yourself,
that's the end!
- An express messenger has come.
- From where?
- Lord Matsudaira in Edo.
- Matsudaira? Oh, goodness!
What is it?
A messenger
from Lord Matsudaira.
Show him
into the drawing room at once.
I'll change
into something else.
Are you all right?
Oh, my!
Give him a hand.
Now leave us alone.
Thank you for your trouble.
It must be a matter
of grave importance.
To tell you the truth,
I seek a concubine
for Lord Matsudaira.
- A concubine?
- That's right.
You rushed here from Edo
to find a concubine?
This is no laughing matter!
Lady Matsudaira's illness
has left her barren.
The clan will be ruined
if the lord has no heir.
There can be
no greater calamity.
The retainers,
sick with worry,
quickly found
some suitable young women,
but they were all
country girls
and not
to the lord's liking.
Give me that.
The retainers were at a loss
and decided that since Kyoto
is famous for its women,
there must be one here
that he would like.
They ordered me
to rush here and find her.
Is that so?
I was worried His Lordship
was seeking a large loan.
Your mission seems
a rather simple one.
I'm afraid
it isn't so simple.
He has some
very specific requirements.
Look at that!
To put it simply,
he wants a girl like that.
I see.
First of all,
"She should be
between 15 and 18.
Her face should be
fashionably round.
Her eyes
must be round too.
Thick eyebrows,
with enough space
between the eyes.
A small mouth, with a full set
of even white teeth.
Long ears
with narrow rims
and detached,
translucent lobes.
A natural, unaltered hairline.
A long neck without wisps of hair.
Long, slender fingers
with diaphanous nails."
That's a tall order.
- There's more.
- More?
"Feet smaller than eight inches,
with nice arches.
She must have
a long, willowy torso,
a firm waist, but not too muscular,
a plump bottom,
a pleasant demeanor,
a fine figure
in whatever she wears,
noble in birth,
meek in personality,
and without
a single mole on her body."
Slender fingers...
Let me see your face.
Her mouth is too big.
How old are you?
- Twenty-five.
Oh, you're the leftovers.
I'm her father, sir.
No, her ears are too small.
Her face isn't round enough.
- What about her?
She just might be it!
Let me see the picture.
Let's check.
Her face is too long.
Her face is round.
Kahei, she may be the one.
No, she has a mole.
Her eyes are too slanted.
Her nose is crooked.
Her nose is flat.
She has a mole.
Her hairline is uneven.
- What about this one?
She looks promising!
She might be the one.
Turn her that way.
Your foot size?
- Ten inches.
What a pity!
Let's see here.
No, her chin is too pointed.
No, her forehead
is too broad.
- Please look at my girl.
- She looks sickly.
This one's ears are wrong.
What about her?
Her chin isn't right.
Even in Kyoto,
nobody could assemble
as many beauties
as I have here today.
There's nothing more
I can do.
Won't you choose
one of them?
Are none of them suitable?
If the point is
to produce an heir,
any girl should do,
as long as she's healthy.
"Thick eyebrows,
enough space
between the eyes,
a small mouth, with a full set
of even white teeth..."
You have it memorized.
I'll drop dead
before I find such a woman.
I sympathize...
but why send a man your age
on such a mission?
I'll tell you why:
A younger man
might try something.
But me? I couldn't do
anything even if I tried.
I see.
What's that?
A blind man from Edo
teaches singing and dancing
to the daughters
of good families.
Really?
The girls are popular
among the samurai
and serve at their parties.
Is that right?
The town
Is laid out in a grid
Just like a Go board
Facing
Each other
Your hand
Clasped in mine
All is well
Let us lie
in each other's arms
Her!
Come here a minute.
Let's have
a good look at her.
Face the other way.
Turn her again.
Do you have
any moles on your body?
- Moles?
- Do you?
No.
- None at all?
- I don't think so.
Kahei, the search is over!
I'll buy her!
Yes, indeed.
The messenger from Edo
is awaiting your reply.
I'll rush back
and tell him you consent.
What a relief.
If she bears him an heir,
it will bring
even greater happiness
to you than to her.
And to me as well,
as her new godfather.
Thank you very much.
If you please.
Thank you for everything.
We must be thankful.
Things are looking up.
I never expected
anything like this to happen.
Oharu,
you've redeemed yourself.
All is forgiven.
Who would imagine mere
dancing lessons could lead to this?
We certainly had no idea!
You'll get 100 ryo
for clothing,
and an allowance too.
What's wrong?
Aren't you happy?
I'm to be a concubine,
am I not?
What of it?
He's a daimyo
with a stipend of 30,000 koku.
You were at the imperial court,
so surely you understand.
If a lord favors you,
you'll be given high rank.
Indeed!
You've been chosen
to bear the heir to the line.
You'll be a high-ranking
lady-in-waiting.
That's right.
I must ask the court
not to reveal her secret
before Lord Matsudaira
begins his inquiries.
- And the temple too.
- Yes. I'll go now.
Then we'll decide what to buy
and what to take to Edo.
Come, Oharu.
- I don't want to go.
- What?
Going to a complete stranger
just to bear his child!
It won't be just any child.
He'll be heir
to a 30,000-koku domain!
Katsunosuke would
never approve.
You idiot!
Still going on about him!
I've accepted the offer!
You can't back out!
She's in excellent
physical condition.
She is capable
of bearing a child.
Lady Kasai...
instruct her
in our etiquette
and take her
to Lady Matsudaira.
Yes, my lord.
The messenger
has returned from Kyoto
with the girl chosen
to be the concubine.
Already?
She's waiting outside.
Will you receive her?
Please endure this
for the sake of the clan.
Her name is Oharu Okui.
Show your face.
Won't you pay homage
to Her Ladyship?
You may go now.
Princess Morning Glory
answered the nobleman
She plucked the flowers
and offered them
Come sit here.
For a long time
She stares pensively
at the flower in her hand
Does it remind you of Kyoto?
You didn't expect to see Bunraku
plays here in Edo, did you?
No, I didn't.
Can this be real
It is her fate
To wither
In the shade
Day and night
She stares
at the deutzia blossoms
They fill her heart
Can you eat
the food here in Edo?
If you don't like anything,
just say so.
By good fortune
She is given
To the imperial palace
What a lucky flower
How enviable
How fortunate you are
Reluctantly
She offers
The flower in her hand
But this flower
is only the go-between
In fact,
your face is the flower
That captured my heart
She has given birth
to an heir.
Inform the head maid.
Auspicious news:
An heir has been born!
A boy!
Auspicious indeed!
We must inform
His Lordship at once.
A lovely baby.
He looks just like you.
Is that so?
Is His Lordship pleased?
He's delighted.
I was so unhappy
when I was
first brought here.
But now
that I've given birth...
No, you must say you were
"allowed to give birth."
Now that I've been
allowed to give birth,
I feel for the first time
that this is my home.
His Lordship must be...
Oh, pardon me.
Nothing could be
more auspicious for the clan.
You have done well.
Where are you taking my...
I mean, the infant heir?
I'm going to nurse him.
Nurse him?
But I can nurse him myself.
Thank you.
I'll make a tidy profit
with this satin.
You're worried
about payment, aren't you?
Relax.
I have Lord Matsudaira's
30,000 koku backing me up.
My master's very strict
about these things.
You mean Kahei?
Listen, my daughter
just gave birth
to the heir to the clan.
You look surprised.
He'll inherit those 30,000 koku.
Heir to the clan?
Word arrived
the day before yesterday.
Money is no object.
Bring me the finest you have,
and lots of it.
Congratulations.
Look.
It seems
your worries are over.
Shall I bring out
the habutae silk?
- Don't be hasty.
- Bring out everything.
I'm opening a shop
on Muromachi Avenue.
I want it to rival Sasaya's store,
so show me everything.
What's happened
to the concubine?
His Lordship's love for her
has grown since she gave birth.
What's wrong with that?
It's just that
he seems to grow weaker
by the day.
The doctor says
if she continues
to share his bed,
it may shorten his life.
We can't let that happen.
The heir has been born.
She's of no further use.
Isn't that right, Isobe?
For the sake of the clan,
send her home.
- But...
- Do it.
She was dismissed?
Are you sure?
I don't know what to say.
When she gave birth,
I was filled
with happiness and pride.
I'm very sorry.
So now you're back.
After you bore the lord an heir,
you should have
withheld your affections a bit.
Anyway, too late now.
How much
did they give you?
Three hundred ryo
would be a great help.
Just five ryo?
I thought you'd be rich.
I bought
a huge amount of fabric.
Now I'm deep in debt.
For our sake,
work in Shimabara
as a courtesan.
I'll buy your freedom
when I sell the fabric.
You mean you'd actually
sell your own daughter?
There's no other choice.
After everything
she's been through...
and now this!
Welcome.
I've always wanted
to live it up in Shimabara
at least once before I die.
I've risen
every day at dawn
and worked hard until the stars
came out in the sky.
It must be 20 years
that I've been saving
my money.
I think I've finally
saved enough,
so I've come
all the way from Echigo.
Unfortunately
we're full at the moment.
- Are you turning me away?
You're all
as pretty as a picture!
Pardon me, sir,
but this is a particularly
expensive establishment.
Do you have
a letter of introduction?
All righty.
If it's money you want...
here's what I got.
Enough to fill a five-quart container.
Is that enough?
More than enough!
Welcome, sir.
I'm the owner here.
Is that so?
So you'll let me stay?
Prepare our largest room
and lay out our finest food.
Call for Shizuhata.
Hurry!
Thank you for honoring us
with your presence.
See that my men
have a good time too.
They've come a long way.
Your packhorse drivers?
As you wish, sir.
Hey, welcome them inside!
I have some sake
on my horse.
Sir, we serve
the very best sake.
Thank you.
Shizuhata...
our finest courtesan.
All right,
let's liven things up a bit!
Hey, why aren't you
picking them up?
Here.
Hey!
Where are your manners?
It's he who has
no manners.
I'm not a beggar.
Wait!
Stop!
Come back here!
Just a minute.
What do you think
your job is?
Think you're too good
to be here?
You're not here
for your own enjoyment.
Constantly carrying on
about your pedigree!
For all I know, you could be
a ragpicker's daughter.
How dare you suggest
such a thing!
You're bought and paid for.
You're no different
from a fish on a chopping board.
We can serve you up
any way we like.
He offered you money.
What's wrong with that?
Fine, then.
Never come back here again.
What will your master
say to that?
If I dismiss you,
no one in these parts
will hire you as a courtesan.
Now get out.
It was all my fault.
I'm sorry.
Please forgive me.
I'll try to do better
from now on.
But please
don't tell my master.
It's too late now.
Get out.
Master, the big spender
is calling for her.
I'll give him
someone better.
No, he says
he likes this one.
He's never known a girl
who refused money.
He wants to buy her
and take her home.
Buy her?
You heard her.
He wants to buy you
and take you to Echigo.
Please put on a happy face
and serve him.
Let's go.
He's buying your freedom.
Be nice to him, please.
Will you really
buy my freedom
and take me to Echigo?
Yes, I'll take care of you.
Actually, I came
to Kyoto to find a wife.
I won't go back without one.
Will you join me?
If your feelings are genuine,
I'll serve you faithfully.
Why are you laughing?
Money.
Money!
As long as I have money,
I can have
anything in the world.
People see money
and their eyes gleam.
They crawl on all fours.
Even a haughty woman like you
smiles and sidles up to me.
You think I'm greedy,
but I'm not.
I want to be
with you because...
Because everyone has a price,
and this is yours.
Thanks to this money,
your fortune has turned.
Lord Money!
Almighty Money!
You fraud!
No wonder
you spend so freely!
He's a counterfeiter!
Your money is bogus!
You'll be beheaded!
Come quietly!
Don't resist!
Fool!
You're under arrest!
Please...
try to smile.
I'm begging you.
You're our daughter again.
You don't know
how I've waited
for the day you'd return to us
from Shimabara.
We won't cause you
any more suffering.
Please forgive us and smile.
Welcome.
My sad fate
Is pitiful indeed
Where did you learn
that song?
It's so beautiful.
You must be
an accomplished singer.
I'm so ashamed.
Back when there were
pleasure quarters in Rokujo,
I was a courtesan
named Katsuragi.
Take care of yourself.
Thank you.
Here you are.
My pillow is soaked
With tears
I'm glad you came.
You were once
Lord Matsudaira's concubine.
I'm hesitant
to ask for your help.
Please don't feel that way.
Try to think of me
as your sister.
We'll treat you well
while you're here
and find you
a good husband.
I'm very grateful.
My wife has few relatives,
so please be
a good friend to her.
May I have
a word with her?
I must ask you
something right away.
Will you hear me out?
What is it?
Please write a solemn oath
never to reveal
my secret to anyone.
Why would I ever
reveal your secret?
Please, just do it.
Thank you very much.
Now, how may I serve you?
There's only one thing
I'll ever ask you to do:
Will you please
dress and style my hair?
I expected you
to ask much more.
Then you'll do it?
I'm so glad.
The woman I had doing it
suddenly
became indisposed.
I'm not very good at it,
but I can try.
The thing is,
my hair's so...
Your hair is beautiful.
No, it's not.
Come with me.
I was seriously ill last year.
This is what
it did to my hair.
I made this wig
while recuperating
at my parents' home.
I've tried
to keep it a secret.
I'm terrified that
my husband will find out.
He'd be revolted.
Please don't tell him.
I promise I won't.
Having your hair dressed?
Very nicely done.
Oharu's quite good.
She did it for you?
Dear...
what would you say
to adopting Oharu
and finding her
a nice husband?
Certainly.
Perhaps a man
from your store?
No, there's nobody
good enough here.
Pardon me.
What is it?
Shall I send the bill
to the customer?
Ask Jihei. He knows.
What are you looking at?
I'll do that.
Now what?
What about the turmeric
salesman's bill?
Don't ask me.
Ask Jihei.
You're getting on my nerves.
Fine. I'll go
to the shop myself.
What are you staring at?
Bunkichi,
stop staring and hurry up!
- Welcome.
- Good day.
Oh, you're here.
What a rare treat.
Please come in.
- Sorry I haven't been in touch.
- Not at all.
Bring some tea.
- Please don't bother.
Looks like business is booming.
- I wouldn't go that far.
Oharu, please make
some tea for our guest.
Shall I take it in for you?
No, thank you.
May I observe you?
You're making me nervous.
You do it so well.
Stop that.
Get away from me.
I just can't make
any money these days.
- I hear you do.
- Nonsense.
People like to talk.
Thank you.
It's you!
I didn't know you were here.
Won't you wait a moment?
Wait!
You know her?
What's she doing here?
I'm taking care of her.
You make it sound so noble.
What on earth do you mean?
Don't play innocent.
You bought her, right?
Bought her?
She's a Shimabara courtesan.
Shimabara?
Shimabara,
as in the pleasure quarter?
Where else?
So when Hishiya told you,
that was the first you'd heard of it?
Yes.
You knew before,
didn't you?
That's why you took her in.
Don't be absurd.
You sent her
to Lord Matsudaira.
You must have known.
I didn't know.
I was shocked.
You saw her at Shimabara,
didn't you?
What are you talking about?
I've never even been
to Shimabara.
You think I'd waste
good money in a place like that?
I'm so tight I step carefully
so I don't damage my sandals!
You're lying!
Stop this!
Excuse me.
What is it?
- A letter from the money exchange.
- I see.
Be careful!
Watch what you're doing!
Cut your hair.
Your hair... cut it!
Why?
You plan to use
your beautiful hair...
to steal my husband away!
I heard all about it.
I know all about your past.
You lied to me.
I apologize.
But I swear I never...
Cut it. Cut it!
Cut it! Go on!
That's not enough.
Cut off more!
Please don't, madam!
Cut it!
If you don't cut it, I will!
I'll cut it off.
Just watch me.
Good morning.
Oharu,
where did my wife go?
To the cemetery.
I see.
Oharu...
you're a naughty girl.
I heard all about your past.
I'm sorry.
I'm not scolding you.
I'll bet you had
some fun times, eh?
One would never guess
just looking at your face.
But you really liked doing
those dirty things, didn't you?
That's how you twisted
Lord Matsudaira
around your little finger.
I did no such thing.
It's all right.
I understand completely.
You can relax
and be yourself around me.
I can enjoy
a top courtesan...
and not even
have to pay for it.
Calm down!
Remember this smell.
All right?
What's wrong?
My hair!
Where are you going?
Oharu!
It was you!
You did this to my hair!
It's nothing.
Go back to bed.
She's just mumbling
in her sleep.
Here you are.
- More?
- No, thank you.
Don't worry.
It's too soon to despair.
If one god forsakes you,
another will save you.
Yakichi here works in the fan shop.
He's singled you out.
His boss is going
to help him
set up his own shop.
He's asking
for your hand in marriage.
I think
I'll excuse myself now.
What about your proposal?
Perhaps you could
discuss that with Oharu.
Look how naive he is.
I hear he's devoted
to his work.
He's never once been
to the pleasure quarters.
You couldn't hope
for a happier life
than as his wife.
I'm hardly worthy
of such a man.
After all, my past...
He knows all about you.
We told him everything.
Didn't hide a single detail.
He said,
"I don't mind.
I want to make that poor,
unlucky girl happy."
He's in love with you.
- Going out so early?
- Yes. I won't be long.
You were up late last night
working on the books.
Yes, it was nearly dawn
when I finished.
I'm quite sleepy.
Why don't you rest
for a while?
I have to deliver these today.
Really?
I'll buy a sash for you
on the way home.
How nice!
Thank you!
Wait a minute.
Face this way.
Perfect.
Hurry back.
Excuse me.
Welcome.
I'd like a dancing fan
for my daughter.
Certainly.
It's very hot today.
These are some of our best.
I see.
You have a lovely shop.
Thank you.
You should marry soon
and run a shop like this.
Running an honest business
is a good life, isn't it?
Your husband
has accomplished much
at such a young age.
He's just an honest,
hardworking man.
I envy you.
You're so pretty.
You two make
an ideal couple.
Any children?
Not yet.
Is that so?
- Madam!
- What is it?
Awful news!
It's your husband!
What's happened?
He was probably killed
by a robber.
He died clutching this sash.
Yakichi!
A handsome youth at morn
is by dusk a heap of bones.
All is truly impermanent
in this world.
What do you plan
to do now?
My late husband's uncle
sold the shop.
Where does that leave you?
I'm going back
to my parents.
Did he leave you anything
to remember him by?
No, nothing.
Nothing?
I don't need anything.
I want to become a nun
and serve Buddha.
A nun?
Please show me the way!
Bunkichi?
Hey, where's Bunkichi?
Here I am.
Look at this.
Who's this charge account for?
An acquaintance of mine.
I've told you repeatedly:
We don't extend credit.
This is unacceptable.
Go collect the money tomorrow.
Can't it wait a month?
No.
If it's too awkward for you,
I'll go myself.
Where is he?
You refuse to tell me?
You won't tell me?
Excuse me.
Jihei!
It's been such a long time.
You're incorrigible,
luring poor Bunkichi
to a place like this.
What do you mean?
He heard I was here
and kindly brought me
some fabric.
Fine. I'm here to collect
for what he gave you on credit.
If you don't have the money,
return the fabric.
I already made it
into a kimono.
Already?
In that case,
I'll take the kimono.
Jihei, you and I
aren't strangers.
How can you be so cold?
Here you go.
Cold?
I'm not Bunkichi.
I can't be seduced
by a whore like you,
so pay up.
What did you call me?
Fine, I'll return it.
Is that the kimono
you made?
And the sash too.
No need to undress.
Here's the kimono.
Now hurry up and leave.
This is going to take
longer than I thought.
Take this money...
and get yourself
some tea and cake.
Drink as much tea
as you can, okay?
Understand?
Oharu,
you must be very tired.
Please leave!
I don't want to see your face.
Leave at once!
I'm not the kind of woman
you think.
He was trying to rape me.
Please believe me, sister.
I beg of you!
I really believed
you wanted to become a nun.
You were just making
a fool of me.
Did you really think
you could get away with it?
What kind of person are you?
Get out!
Oharu.
What's the matter?
I've been driven
out of the temple.
What? You too?
I was dismissed too.
You were?
Oharu, come with me.
I know I can make you happy.
What?
Don't worry about money.
When I left,
I stole 50 ryo in gold.
What? Bunkichi!
They all think I ran off
with you anyway.
No! I won't go
with a thief like you.
I can't! No!
Would you like some?
It's very good.
Wait a moment.
How about an egg?
I'm at a loss.
May I have one of these?
Oharu, these are good!
- Bunkichi!
- Jihei!
He's the thief!
Catch him!
Stop! Come back!
Jihei!
Stop!
Please let him go!
Out of the way!
- Oharu!
- You wench!
Go off somewhere and die,
you rotten whore!
Oharu!
This fleeting world
Is full of pain
And I, oh I
Am a thing of pity
This life
So full of regrets
Will vanish
Like the morning dew
What's the matter?
What's wrong?
Come along with us
and take a rest.
Yes, let's go.
Come along.
I'll carry it for you.
I'll get that too.
She hasn't eaten
in three days,
and she's chilled
to the bone.
Help yourself to the food.
Your hair's turned
really gray.
Yes, it has.
Here we are,
covered with wrinkles...
yet we try to coo
like young maidens:
"Hey there, handsome!"
What nerve we have!
You wanna earn
some money too?
It'll take your mind off things.
I'm too old for that,
unlike you.
Listen to her,
acting all innocent!
It's a pitiful life we lead,
but nobody's
going to help us out.
Ain't that the truth!
It would be easier just to die,
but we can't even do that.
Drink the sake while we have it.
It'll lift your spirits.
We've fallen this far.
Might as well do
what we want.
I can get you some clothes.
What do you say?
Come on.
Whatever we do,
the world's not about to change.
That's right!
Old man,
we've got a newcomer.
Bring her something to wear.
Are you the newcomer?
You could probably
make good money.
I'll rent you a kimono
and undergarments
for three bu a night.
A sash and socks
will be one bu.
Footwear will be five mon.
This is so gaudy.
What's wrong with it?
You can't make money
if they don't notice you.
I expect payment soon,
so hurry up and get to work.
If you're done here,
go away.
Nasty old man.
Come on.
I'll help you get dressed.
Hey, mister, wait a minute.
Why don't we have some fun?
Old hag! Are you crazy?
Hey, handsome!
Come on,
let's have some fun.
Go away!
- I'll give you your money's worth!
- I said no!
Madam, would you come
with me for a moment?
Certainly.
Come in.
Sit down over there.
Cold, isn't it?
Shall I sing you a song?
Is there something wrong?
Your silence
makes me uneasy.
Don't worry about it.
You can just sit there.
Please drop the fake voice.
I'd really prefer it
if you spoke
in your natural voice.
Come this way.
Everybody
take a good long look.
You see that?
You still want to sleep
with women now?
You all want happiness
in the next world.
That's why you're on
the Thirty-three Temple Pilgrimage.
However...
if you'd rather steep yourself
in the impermanence of earthly life,
then follow the example
of this goblin cat
in human form.
Thank you for coming.
That will be all.
Now please go.
When you return
to your homes,
you can tell everyone
how you met a real goblin cat.
Thanks a lot.
What are you doing?
Looking at a statue
of an arhat.
It looks like him.
Like who?
Think of men you know
and try to find their faces
among the statues.
You'll find quite a few.
She's right!
They all have
such funny faces!
Oharu, what's wrong?
Look, it's your mother.
I think she's waking up.
I'm so glad to see you.
Why have you come?
Someone told her
they saw you around here.
She's been looking for you.
I'm glad
to know you're safe.
How is Father?
He passed away.
He worried about you
to the very end.
But don't cry.
You'll find happiness again.
Me? Happiness?
It's true.
You won't have
to suffer anymore.
You'll live in a big manor.
A messenger came
from the Matsudaira palace.
He said Lord Matsudaira
passed away.
The young lord
has succeeded him.
My son?
He's Lord Matsudaira now.
The messenger said
the young lord wants his mother
to live with him in the palace.
You mean
I'll get to see my son?
I can live with him?
Thank goodness.
He's grown
into a good young man.
I'd like Shinozaki and Tashiro
to deliver a stern rebuke.
Have you forgotten
your debt of gratitude
to our late lord?
Who do you take us for?
The family line runs
from Tsunemoto Genji,
grandson of Emperor Seiwa,
through the Nitta clan.
The lords of our clan
are direct descendants
of the great
leyasu Tokugawa.
The late lord
was fourth in line.
His son Yoshitaka is fifth.
You were
the late lord's concubine,
but you reduced yourself
to a courtesan
and finally a prostitute.
Do you have any excuse?
Are you not ashamed?
If word of your vulgar behavior
were to get out,
it would besmirch
the clan's name,
and the shogunate's punishment
would be severe.
We cannot allow you
to come and go as you please.
You are sentenced
to lifetime confinement.
You must spend day and night
repenting for your sins
and beseeching the spirit
of our late lord for forgiveness.
Now...
in an exceptional
display of mercy,
His Lordship will grant you
a brief viewing...
so that you may
bid him farewell.
Keep your distance!
This is a serious affront!
Please allow me
to approach him.
He's my child.
I gave birth to him.
Remember our orders!
I'm going after her!
You there!
Isn't she ready yet?
- Any minute, sir.
- What's taking so long?
What is it?
We've lost her.
How can that be?
Spread out and find her.
Inform the others!
Spread out
and look for her!
The woman has disappeared!
Disappeared?
Find her at once!
Sentient beings
are innumerable
I vow to save them
Delusions are inexhaustible
I vow to extinguish them
The teachings of the dharma
are immeasurable
I vow to master them
Buddhahood is incomparable
I vow to attain it
THE END