- I - want you to join us.
Is that the
mission you were going on about?
You still feel it. Mary's song.
You know what a
better world could be like.
First time Mary sang,
only the Touched that were
in the room could hear it.
We'll make Mary's
voice loud enough
that it could be heard by
Touched across the city.
We need
to get those fliers taken down.
They could be all over London.
What did they do to the girls?
Experiments.
We need to know
everything they've been doing.
Oh! Who are you?
The Order is to eliminate Maladie.
Maladie has done us a favor.
She turned sentiment
against the Touched.
We're being attacked,
locked up, and thrown in the street.
We have enemies you
don't know about yet.
The Touched,
they'll all come to us.
They'll be safe.
♪ Now the
laborer's task is o'er ♪
♪ Now the battle day is past ♪
♪ Now upon the farther shore ♪
♪ Lands the voyager at last ♪
♪ Father,
in thy gracious keeping ♪
♪ Leave we now ♪
♪ Thy servant sleeping ♪
♪ There the tears
of Earth are dried... ♪
Down!
♪ There it's hidden
things are clear ♪
♪ There the work
of life is tried ♪
♪ By a juster judge than here ♪
♪ There the
penitents that turn ♪
♪ To the cross
their dying eyes ♪
♪ All the love of Jesus learn ♪
♪ At his feet in paradise ♪
♪ Father,
in thy gracious keeping ♪
♪ Leave we now thy
servant sleeping... ♪
- Witches! - Freaks!
- Why don't we drown you all? Ha, ha!
- Good riddance!
Drown her! Let's
see if she floats!
- Vile creatures!
- Go on, piss off!
Please, Inspector. Not now.
Not here.
- You're under arrest.
- Come on, you two.
There we go...
I know your loss is
greater than any of us
- can even...
- Where the fuck is she?
Where's the lady who
can see the future?
A kiss for a pint.
That was the deal.
I am a woman of my word.
Kiss for a pint.
Oh, no, you fucking don't...
I'm gonna need you in a minute.
Who speaks for these men?
Him, m'lord.
Jacobs.
The men learnt there are
explosives among the cargo here.
They feel they're due higher
wages for handling them.
Who here knows what this is?
Well, that's a shell, sir.
Loaded with cordite.
Ready for the war.
Top marks.
It's good for blowing
up the enemy,
and for saving our lads.
That's who you're holding
hostage here. Your brothers.
That doesn't change the facts...
Jesus!
If they were unstable,
we would simply roll
them over the line,
wouldn't we?
You men are seeking a grievance.
The docks are full of men
who care about our troops,
and foreigners who
care about nothing.
I can fill your jobs in an hour!
Get back to work,
and I will forget this happened.
No repercussions.
You won't be docked
for this stoppage.
It's very generous.
Go on. Go on. Back to work.
Go on. Go on.
Next time,
come and talk to me as individuals.
To band together when
you could stand alone?
I expect more courage
from Englishmen.
They're taking the carrot,
my lord.
They're mouthing the carrot.
They spit it back out,
we'll use the stick.
I thought Aneel was with you.
He had to get back to school.
I mean, he gets to.
If you're up to it,
I need a favor.
- - The new folk,
there's rumors one or two
have outstanding warrants.
Petty charges, likely cooked up.
Oh. It should mostly just be fines,
I imagine.
Some of them might
not technically be citizens.
They don't all speak English,
so it's hard to tell.
I don't know if that matters,
but I'll find out.
- You're a daisy.
- I'd rather be a barrister.
Then I could
prosecute the men...
I don't see how, though.
I can't even apply
to Aneel's school.
How are we ever
gonna see justice
if we're not a part of justice?
All I can see my way
through is a grape.
You know you're gonna have
to clean up those shards, right?
Yeah.
So, is this what we can expect?
A leader who doesn't lead?
Are you looking
to fill that position?
She does have the nicest room.
You know True
should have been there.
I've shown more respect for Mary,
and I'm her kidnapper.
Amalia misses the point of things,
as often as not.
But if that chair is
warm when she sits in it,
she'll know why.
You don't think I can best her?
I don't think you want her job.
It's very draining.
Did you see anyone out
of place at the funeral?
Not Maladie. None of the gang.
Beggar King sent a wreath.
- The great big one?
- She lost a friend.
She didn't win the Derby.
Big one wasn't signed.
Couple of Purists making a fuss.
You probably saw.
The pink rags.
- Purists all have them.
- So they have a name now?
- Christ preserve us.
- Thought that was my job.
- We don't want more violence.
- This is London, Doctor.
There's always more.
I still don't see how you can
go from working for Maladie...
to being here with Amalia.
You really think
they're that different?
True still not back?
I swear to Jesus, I would...
Have you not finished
discussing my faults?
Come on, Penance. Jesus awaits.
He already knows
what I was gonna say,
and I'll add a few Hail
Marys for that later.
Frank Mundi'll owe a few himself,
poor man.
Maladie didn't
show at the funeral.
Can you believe the
rudeness of that woman?
It'd be madness to show,
and not her kind.
The papers that bothered to report
on the shootin' are all blamin' her,
and we don't know
that we shouldn't be.
I still thought she might go.
So why didn't you?
The man who tried to
drown me is Nicholas Perbal.
Ach. That brute?
The blasphemy
of walking on water
for the purpose of murder...
He's called Odium.
Not by his dear Granny Perbal,
who owns a snug little attic
somewhere in the narrows.
Beggar King's man says he's convalescing,
likely at Gran's.
Do violins cost a lot?
The two attacks could be unrelated,
you and Mary.
- Lot of people don't like you, I'm told.
- I know.
...a casualty of war...
I need a bath.
Tell Lucy we're
meeting in an hour.
Start listing suspects.
But she's broken up
worst of all the girls.
We'll take her mind off it.
It's all hands on deck,
and she has the best hands in the group.
In the meantime...
Make yourself comfortable.
Ah, True,
sure and you should've been at the service.
You're a bitter poor
example to the girls.
But I'm so tough
and mean, and I hate sentiment.
And also people. And myself.
Ah, Lord,
Mary Brighton trusted you,
- and you failed her.
- Is that what you think?
I think the
longer we wait to find the killer,
the greater the
chance we never do.
Mary doesn't need me
crying over her corpse.
True, I can't imagine how many
funerals you've been to, but...
None. We don't do
that when I'm from.
We don't have enough time
and we don't have enough ground.
You know better than
anyone what pain does
when you don't make time for it.
All time does is run out.
I was left here,
completely alone,
with nothing but a mission
I was never actually given.
No orders, no objectives...
They left me here and
they fucked right off.
Maybe they died.
Who cares? I'm here...
where a woman can be
killed just for having a voice,
which will be the
world's fucking epitaph
if I can't do something
other than make it worse.
I know your burdens,
True. But is vengeance
going to make the world better?
If we... if we find out
who took away our Mary,
I have a worry as to
your next course of action,
because the rest of us,
we had a chance to say goodbye...
To remember the
goodness of her heart,
and not just the unfairness
of her being taken.
You keep saying taken instead
of murdered. Mary was murdered.
- I was there, True.
- So was the man with the gun.
He was set up
before we got there.
So stop worrying about
who wasn't at the funeral,
and start asking who
wasn't at that park.
You don't mean one of us.
Well, I know it wasn't me.
Myrtle?
Do you want to talk?
May I see?
Oh, Myrtle.
This is so...
You... heard her?
You wish you could hear her.
You want to learn to read?
Mary sang to you.
To... I'm trying.
To this person.
About this person?
When Mary sang, you heard...
Words.
Language.
Mary was telling us something,
and you understood it.
Was it something nice?
So now you're after
our jobs as well?
What angle are you pursuing?
Hemlines of the deceased?
I have every right to be here.
No, you fuckin' don't.
Lovely. Now I've had gin for breakfast,
too.
Inky fingers don't make you a reporter,
Boyle.
Inspector Mundi.
Why are those
Purists being detained?
Is there a connection between
them and Miss Brighton's death?
Or was it your detail's
failure to catch Maladie?
Is Mary another of her messages?
That story's been told.
I don't believe it has.
I think there is something much
larger at work than one maniac.
Have you got information I can use,
Miss...?
Boyle. Effie Boyle
from "The Sentinel,"
and, well, nothing yet.
But I do know the Touched
are being vilified in the press,
often for no reason.
It was a Touched that
killed Mary Brighton.
You learn more than that,
come calling.
So you just happened
by Mary Brighton's funeral.
Nobody told you
about the service.
We were out walking.
You live in the south end,
work at Marster's Mill.
That's four miles
out of your way.
We's peripatetic.
- Look, I told you... - Tell me.
- We were walking.
- And you stopped to yell obscenities
at a grieving family.
You're already going to jail.
You can't put us
in for expressing ourselves.
No. No, I'm putting you in
for assaulting a police officer.
- - Well, I like that plan.
Enter the Ape...
The Ape? Wait. The boxer?
The East End Ape?
Is that... Is that Frank Mundi?
- Inspector Mundi.
- Whew. No. You're all right.
Look,
a couple of guys in suits approached us
at a Purist meeting, all right?
I don't know the guy who said go,
but...
he gave us this.
Said they were burying a
Touched with decent folk,
and we should call 'em out.
Great, that's 6:00 in
the main dormitory downstairs.
Thank you.
That's another two, so we can...
Hi. Sorry,
are you new to The Orphanage?
- Okay, do you speak any languages or dialects?
- Mm-hmm.
Yeah? What are they?
Cops, the church, the Purists...
and our masked freaks.
There's no shortage
of people who hate us.
But only a few are
powerful or inventive enough
to have gotten Kroos
out of prison undetected.
Maladie?
Kroos was her man.
And she's still got a network.
They found Horatio
easily enough.
Gilbert Massen?
What, Lord Massen?
The Great White Hunter.
Oh, he's a piece of work.
I got chums in his factory
talkin' about a strike,
cause he pays a pittance!
And it's dangerous.
It's bombs and the
like they're handlin'.
But it's a fine fuck-thee-well
if you're injured.
He'd stick your head
on his wall for a trophy
'fore he'd give you
thruppence to feed your kids.
Oh...
I've gone all political. Sorry.
No, it was quite rousing.
Horatio, Lucy, and Penance: No.
- - Right. So...
- The Beggar King.
- A bit public for him.
But he runs Odium,
and since we have a
hard-won lead on his address...
I'll take it. I know the area.
If Mrs. True isn't
looking for a rematch.
No. I'm going to talk
to Massen. Alone.
You sure that's the way to go?
- He's hardly gonna fall into...
- No, I mean, I'm going to.
Sometime today.
I've already seen it.
Wasn't sure where I was at first,
but... or will be.
Wait,
does... does that mean Massen killed Mary?
Did the ripplings tell you that?
They tell me I don't
get to plan my own day.
They're not treasure maps.
I'll learn something,
I'm sure, but...
And once you have?
I mean, if you get something
in the way of, uh, "he did it."
Then I will bring that
information back here.
I'm not planning to
attack a Peer of the Realm
inside his well-guarded house.
Hmm, sure,
but what you mean to happen
and what actually
happens in the thick of it...
It's not just you, True.
Everyone has to
keep their heads.
Mary's death needs to be answered,
and not with another death.
And it's not just
about what's right.
We're hated right now.
Our first response
cannot be hate.
We'll be lined
up in the streets.
And they may have killed
Mary exactly for that purpose.
Make us do something
they can rain hell on us for.
See? Annie agrees,
and she's terrible.
- And so do I. - Good.
- Level heads.
- All right. Augustus Bidlow?
Yeah, we should murder him.
I'm with Penance.
That party they thrown,
seeing how he treated her,
I nearly pulled off me gloves.
Lavinia Bidlow, as well.
Or are you just writing
down people you know?
Amalia told her we
were going to the park.
- And she knew where I'd be coming from.
- Still,
she might be a bit over-puckered,
but she's the reason we've got all this.
Mm-hmm. The family that
sponsored my medical training...
That brought me from
Jamaica to England...
A week in their house,
and I almost swam back.
I've been left for dead by
men with less contempt.
Now, Miss Bidlow,
she means well,
and I know she does
good work for the Touched,
but it doesn't
make her a friend.
So she goes on the list with her terrible,
bird-watching brother.
He's the ringleader.
You know he...
Likes... birds.
Birds are stupid.
And it's high time
you told him that.
What? Go and talk... No!
- I should do Annie's.
- Track an assassin?
Come on, Pen,
you can give Bidlow the old parasol.
- -Lucy,
Penance, and Horatio: No!
- Oh. - Sorry.
Doctor Cousens,
we got a few peaky ones down there.
- How are you holding up?
- Oh, well,
my Nigel doesn't really
understand what's going on.
But I'm keeping my chins up.
Sometimes pretending you
feel good makes you feel better.
- Trust me.
- All right.
Let's see to those patients.
- Don't do anything rash.
- I won't.
I was talking to Penance.
Shouldn't
you take Désirée with you
- to Massen's?
- I should.
But I don't.
That's a pungent gambit, Tommy.
- - Frank.
Frank!
You've been mixing
with the Purists.
Stirring them up.
Did you want to
scare the Touched,
so you could tell 'em they
was only safe with you?
Uh, first of all, who...
- - Who are the fucking Purists?
That's not mine.
You really think I'd be handing
out personalized evidence?
Master Swann.
Any assistance required?
Uh, no, thank you. Uh...
Just a bit of sport.
We'll keep quiet.
This is a members
only establishment.
And you need to
fuck off. Please.
Uh, yes, uh,
do fuck off. There's a lad.
Look. Think about this.
If they'd said it was
Lord Such-and-What,
you'd be gathering
evidence. Having him followed.
Behaving like a detective.
Someone pointed you
and pulled your trigger.
It's no secret that
you loathe me.
That don't mean you're innocent.
When... When
have I ever claimed...
Wait. Are you talking
about the shooting?
I'm not a murderer.
- I had nothing against Mary.
- She was a rival.
I think you know she wasn't.
Look, I... I will provide
you with my whereabouts.
I wanted to learn
about Amalia True,
and what I've
learned is stay away.
- I am not a part of this.
- 'Course you are.
And if it ain't you,
it's one of them toffs you play chess with.
Oh, uh,
actually we call it cheese because we...
It's rich men grinding
up them who's helpless
for extra penny on the pound,
or, or the rights to a
patch of sand. Or a fuck.
- Are we done?
- Oh, we're done, Swann.
Across the board.
And our little arrangement,
my debt, is done.
Cause I got something
over you now.
I don't fucking care.
- Translators.
- Bring Klaus?
Yes, bring Klaus. Anyone
who speaks another language,
or who studied a dead
language really well.
I've only got law Latin.
- - Oh, it's trouble.
Well, you can sneak out for a kiss anytime,
but not when I need your help?
- Aneel, you know I wouldn't ask...
- No, of course, I'll do it.
Thank you. I love
you. Yeah. Six o'clock.
- Mr. Bidlow. - Oh.
Miss Adair.
Uh, what are you...
Uh, so,
does Lavinia know you're here?
I know very well that
I'm not welcome here.
No, you are. You are. It's,
it's...
It's wonderful to...
Did, did anybody see you?
You seem a bit nervous.
Well, I mean, I usually am,
but, but you're well? No,
Lord, no.
No,
of course. I'm so sorry. Um...
May I offer my most sincere
condolences about Miss Brighton?
She wouldn't have been
entertaining to your friends,
so you needn't grieve overly.
Lavinia made me do it.
She, she,
she said it would be bad for you.
- Bad for me?
- Yes, that's why I did it.
She said if I didn't,
that there would be cons...
Wait.
Wait, it wa... It was bad.
- So, how is it bad?
- Are you making a joke of this?
You can't,
you can't p... Possibly have had any deep,
emotional conn...
connection to...
Oh, no, I'm saying,
I'm saying this all wrong.
I'm saying it wrong.
I thought it was the
gentlemanly thing to do.
Murder?
- I'm sorry, what?
- Oh, you are a monster.
And you're gonna go to prison.
- I don't care how rich you are.
- What's happening?
What's happening? I don't
know what's happening.
You just confessed to the
murder of Mary Brighton,
and I made a
wax recording of it.
Ugh.
- Fuckin' prototype.
- Miss Adair.
- You are a terrible person!
- Yes, I know. I know!
But I... I didn't
kill Miss... Can I...
Uh, I'm fine.
I was referring to the party.
It's my... awful...
I was just abominably rude.
And I've barely slept since.
When I heard what happened,
I wanted to reach out to you in your grief,
and it just... it seemed... It
seemed opportunistic, or...
You, you didn't kill Mary?
Is... is that bad? Um, it's...
Of course you didn't.
You're as gentle as a blush.
But you're still terrible.
Yeah.
Tell me just anything that
I can do to make amends.
I cried,
which seems petty now to think about,
but...
I don't... I don't have a
lot of experience with men.
Certainly not of your class,
which from what I've seen...
No, nobody is quite as
barbaric as the well-to-do.
Your Lucy had me figured out.
Miss Adair,
I would give anything
if you would erase
that day from your mind.
That's not how it works.
No.
Nor should it be.
Remember my transgressions,
so that I may re-earn your trust honestly,
over time.
If we are...
If we are to be acquainted,
I shall endeavor...
No, no, no,
no! Damn acquaintance.
Acquaintance is
exhausting. I just...
I want to be your friend,
Miss Adair.
I want... I want to
become your friend.
You sent the flowers for Mary.
- Was the wreath too much? It was, it was garish.
- No.
Do you think your sister
did the murder then?
What?
I was only askin'.
Maybe it's your tone of voice.
- How'd you get there?
- I'm Nimble.
No, I'm Nimble,
as in,
"How do you do? Nimble Jack.
- But my friends all call me..."
- You didn't answer my question.
Well, I'm wondering what a sweet
thing like you is doing 'round here.
I'm from around here.
- They don't seem to remember you.
- No, they did.
- What do you want?
- A drink, maybe.
Light supper? Three
Vicars does a nice eel pie.
Private room.
Too fast?
- You work for the Beggar King.
- With.
On occasion.
One of his gang
plays the fiddle.
Gave up an address
to a belligerent widow.
Fiddler said he tried to fight,
but...
she got him pinned,
and squeezed it out of him.
Poor Declan. He really
can't find decent help.
- Which is why he'd prefer you don't kill Odium.
- Yeah.
This wasn't the
King's work. Come on.
Maladie's man
shoots the Brighton girl.
Beggar King's chief
enforcer goes after the widow.
Someone's puttin' on a show.
I need more than "someone."
Odium knows fuck all.
He's dim, bless him,
and he's in for another thrashing.
But he's necessary
to keep the peace.
Keep appearances.
Leave Odium be,
and the opium you
torched is bygones.
Friends.
Or... common enemy.
- Where is she?
- This lot, he doesn't care about.
- Seems like they all remember you.
- Just keep your head down.
Never have, never will.
Thank you for seeing me.
The Bidlows are old friends.
Lavinia and I may not see
eye-to-eye on everything,
but she doesn't waste
her time with trifling people.
I think she regards
you quite highly.
I owe her a great deal.
Everyone at The Orphanage does.
Forgive me. I did read about your girl,
Miss Brighton.
I suspect you've had all the
condolences you have room for,
so may I offer you a sherry?
Bit early, but...
And may I also offer
a conjecture?
You think that I had something
to do with your friend's death.
Did you? It would save
me such a lot of time.
I'm going to have to disappoint you,
I'm afraid.
No one at the club is
vying for credit either,
though I will keep an ear out.
Appreciated.
But, what I could really
use is your perspective,
as a military man and a powerful
member of the established order.
Whoever did have Mary Brighton
killed was making a public statement.
Like stepping on stage
and murdering six people.
- A different message.
- The same messenger.
That gunman, Kroos.
- Well, he's taken care of.
- Shame.
He might have talked.
You killed her. Let's say.
If you'll indulge me,
I've found this a
useful exercise.
Let's assume it wasn't
Maladie or an erstwhile lover,
but someone with a broader view.
You'll take the part of the
mastermind behind Mary's death.
And you'll be the
irate inspector?
I'll be Mary.
Why would you want me dead?
I doubt that I do.
I'm not entirely clear
what your "turn" is.
A beacon of some sort?
Anyway benign,
and you're an inoffensive woman.
No history of radicalism,
I assume.
So why me?
Why not kill that widow,
Mrs. True?
She's a willful creature,
and the leader of
this motley coven.
Which means she
must have enemies.
Her death might be tragic,
but perhaps not unexpected.
You, on the other hand,
are a pure
and blameless woman.
And all in white, no less.
A statuesque beauty
with a mass of auburn hair
and great shining eyes...
Christ, I'm not just a beacon.
I genuinely resemble
a lighthouse.
It isn't just a warning.
It's about hope.
It's about pulling the
heart out of the orphans.
I would think so.
In fact, I would say,
Miss Brighton,
that you are a casualty of war.
So we're at war.
A few years back,
a pestilence ran
through this city.
Some anarchic cabal
found or developed a
power that mocks God.
That molests and
disfigures His natural law.
It was an attack on the stability,
the harmony,
if you will, of the empire.
And we must show the
victims of this deliberate plague
that they are not special.
They are not a community.
Victims is all they
have license to be.
If I am your killer revealed,
behold the lion,
Great Britain.
An empire unparalleled
and unmerciful in
its self-preservation.
My enemy is England.
- Well, that narrows it down. Thank God I came.
- I said your killer.
Your enemy, Miss Brighton,
is the scum who
caused this plague,
the fools who call it power,
and the woman who
should have known
what would happen
to you in that park.
Unless, of course,
she did.
So,
he confessed without confessing.
It was honestly impressive.
I should have worn
your recording frame.
But he didn't
give up his source.
He never flat-out said.
Even if we had proof,
Massen knows we couldn't touch him.
- I could touch him.
- Oh, please tell me we're not havin' this talk again.
No. Even if he gave the order,
he's part of something
much bigger.
Pull out one piece,
it would be replaced in a day.
And damn it, it's wrong.
He's a human being who's alive,
damn it.
We still need a response.
If we let murder slide,
it will only slide down.
Whatever's next will be worse.
Even I know that's true.
Well,
some of the lads say he has a warehouse
full of munitions
we could torch.
- Hmm.
- I don't think there's anyone in there at night.
He deserves much worse,
but it would be a start.
All in favor?
You fuckin' idiot.
You might as well have
marched in the House of Lords
and had a slash!
Superintendent's had an earful.
I was pursuing a lead.
Unless Maladie was
havin' tea in that club,
Superintendent
don't want to hear it.
Mundi! Get in here!
It'll be fine.
- Can I have your desk?
- You can cop a mouse.
Shh... shh...
- Let him go.
- But he lies about me.
He'll stop.
And, and he'll resign,
and, and he'll never
- bother you again...
- Oh, now you're lying! I heard you wouldn't.
And, whoa, the papers!
They say I killed Mary.
They call me crazy.
I never did it.
I only kill angels. Mostly.
I liked Mary so much.
She was gonna be my pet,
and sleep on my belly.
- You were gonna hang her.
- Well, we had a lot of plans.
She talked about the detective
who was smart, and honest.
And she didn't marry
him because he was sad.
For Mary's sake, will you...
- Will you let him live?
- Oh, she doesn't have a sake, love.
She's dead. She's
all cold in that box.
Everyone crying as
they lowered it in the hole,
singin' about the workday,
and what.
Y... You were there?
Of course.
I was in the box.
I had a little cuddle.
But she smelled different.
And I will not believe
that was her favorite dress.
What do you want?
I want everyone to stop lying.
Can you see to that?
I will try.
I have to think about
my reputation.
Things never come
back when they go away.
Ha! - Frank: In here! Now!
Oh, Christ.
Oh, no!
That's a form of lying!
No!
Mundi.
Fuck, it's her! It's Maladie!
He fucking got her!
Right. Not so scary now...
All right.
- - Hey.
Justice.
She gets justice from us.
I'll have badge and balls
off any man who tries that.
She gets justice from us.
Okay, everybody.
Ready?
Okay.
Right. Myrtle?
Nice and loud.
Myrtle.
A little slower.
Uh...
Again?
Um, uh...
I know it!
The darkness.
Dark. Um, uh, before the dark?
Uh, come before the dark.
Sí, sí.
Was that near the end?
- - Again.
My mate said the
warehouse... Yeah.
It's that one.
And the entrance
is on the far side.
And that lot?
I promised Penance.
- Because it's your turn again!
- No, it ain't my turn to get the cup.
- I always got to get the cup.
- Just do what you're told, all right?
If the foreman finds out we've left...
Do you hear that?
Bloody hell. What
the blazes is that?
Do you ever think
maybe Penance is frightening?
And what were you gonna
do? Hand 'em a daisy?
- Stay outside.
- I'm the one with the fire.
And we need to make
sure no one goes up in it.
Your funeral.
- No one. - Looks good.
Due to ship out at dawn.
I'd like to see his face.
Let's open a couple. Make
sure we have the right shipment.
You sure the guards
are still sleepin'?
We have time.
Yeah. No,
I just have that... that feeling.
Lucy.
Open the crate.
Well,
now we know why the war isn't going better.
They swore they were weapons,
True.
They must be workin' for...
- How'd you cop it?
- It was the rippling.
Your talk of Massen's
hunting. His trophies.
You'd have to have been
in his study to call that up.
I might have missed it
if I hadn't seen it twice.
- My clapper of a mouth.
- And then this perfectly convenient plan.
Warehouse of munitions
no one's really guarding?
Christ,
it was all already there.
The questions, the absences,
the money you swore you didn't
steal so we'd assume you did.
- I figured that'd get a bit tired.
- You clean my study,
but you can't make your
own bed. I am such an idiot.
I didn't know what they
was plannin' for Mary.
- I swear.
- What else would they have ever done,
after you told them
Mary was a beacon?
- What do you want, True?
- I want it to be someone else!
I want it to be Harriet, or Jo.
Or the one who does,
she... Helen.
- Maud.
- The one who does the cartwheels. Fuck!
You were the first woman,
the first woman
to walk through those doors!
The one I could lean
on instead of protecting,
that understood the world
- the way that I do.
- You don't know fuck about the world.
All your war stories.
You don't know which war. Oh,
oh, it's awful.
'Cause you've left
bodies on the field,
and you're all damaged.
I broke my son to pieces.
I held my baby,
and it killed him.
And it wasn't
sudden like I said.
The breaks, they were sudden.
But he... he held on.
And he screamed.
He screamed longer
than I did pushin' him out...
'fore his heart gave.
So you tell me, are we sisters?
It's been three years since
I've touched another person.
And Massen,
he says he'll find a cure.
Of course he tells you that.
And what are you telling us?
A better world?
How many of your precious
orphans would be lining up
to be free of your better world
if they had half a chance?
It wasn't supposed
to be like this.
I don't know what happened.
How do you know how
it's supposed to be?
Did you do this?
Did you make this nightmare?
I just got left behind.
'Course you got left
behind. What good are you?
You, a leader?
You're out whoring
when your girls need...
Your boss told me
today that we're at war.
I didn't start it.
I didn't even
volunteer. But he's right.
I hope he told you what
happens to spies during wartime.
Is that what this is?
There's rules of engagement.
And not just you needing to
take your failure out on someone.
You think Penance
will forgive you for this?
You think Mary would?
And that's where you lose me.
You're finished in
London. Forever.
Annie and I will put you on
a boat and you'll stay on it
until you're well
and fucking gone.
And you'll tell me
everything you know.
Everything. Yes?
Where are the real munitions?
A fire? Oh, no!
- It's everywhere.
- How?
My men were just
doing the rounds.
Everything exploded,
and it was, it was chaos!
Was anyone at
the factory harmed?
No, it was the factory, the...
Luckily no one was hurt.
The Paul Street
storage building.
I see.
This wasn't the plan.
Well, it was your plan,
wasn't it?
I'm just your instrument.
I've always been
your instrument.
Why won't you play me?
Why?
I still can't make sense of it.
- Lucy.
- We should have seen it a long time ago.
I just hope she's the only one.
Losing her the same
day we buried M...
Anyway,
I'm grateful you spared her life.
I didn't.
You did.
That idiotic pin.
She could have gotten away,
but she wouldn't leave without it.
That was always my plan,
of course.
She said I had no idea what
anyone is going through here.
I hate that she's right.
But I can't... get
close to them.
Lucy's proof of that.
She shows her face in
London again though,
it'll take more than a
piece of jewelry to save her.
So, um,
a bigger piece of jewelry?
A belt, maybe, or a hat?
True,
I can't make her a whole outfit.
You are the strangest
person I've ever met.
It's why you're the one I trust.
Augie Bidlow's Touched.
Birds. He sort of controls them.
I'll be damned.
Do you think that's why
Lavinia took up the cause?
He's certain she doesn't know.
I think he's afraid to tell her.
But he's not afraid to tell you.
- - You're here!
- They're here! - We are here.
- You won't believe it.
- Myrtle, what's wrong?
No, it's not wrong at all.
Harriet, tell them. It was
mostly Harriet that worked it out.
I helped with the French,
though.
Harriet, please.
I'm sorry,
it... I don't want to say it wrong.
And it,
it wasn't me. It was Myrtle.
Myrtle understood
Mary's song. Mostly.
Even Mary didn't know
what her songs meant...
She always said.
Some of it was more
about emotion than...
Or emotion plus semantics,
but she remembered a lot. She
just didn't know how to tell us.
Myrtle.
- What did she say?
- Uh, she said, "You're not alone."
- Well, I think we could all feel that...
- You, Mrs. True.
She said it to you.
She said, "Amalia,
my lonely soldier."
Um,
something about wearing stripes.
But that part...
But she said,
"I didn't leave you.
"I went into,
in-inside the city.
I was damaged..." uh,
"incomplete?
"I had to heal.
- Soon we will all be ready..."
- Oh, that part was me.
"But it's dark.
There's a darkness."
She said to-to everyone,
all of us,
to gather,
and protect each other.
Because of the dark.
And was there more?
Uh, "Find me.
"Let them help, those who will,
but come below and find me."
Um...
"Come before the dark,
and we can save..."
It ended there. That's when...
Those aren't Mary's words,
are they?
That was someone
else talking through her.
That's right.
Then who?
Who do we need to find?
Maladie is the worst
killer in London's history.
This is a case where
justice must be seen.
There is a concern about
enflaming the Touched.
We keep the Touched accountable,
visible.
If London is going to be safe from chaos,
it needs
to see chaos.
What I want from
you is just... enough.
We all have a soul,
no matter what viciousness
people are spewing.
Let the world see,
the Touched are not here
to be slaughtered for show.
Amalia,
before this Massen scene,
has had a ripple that tells her
that she will be at his estate.
Mary's
death needs to be answered,
and not with another death.
I'm going to talk to Massen,
alone.
The confrontation scene
between Amalia and Massen
is really interesting.
You think that I had something
to do with your friend's death?
Did you? It would save
me such a lot of time.
We flipped roles,
and he uncharacteristically,
as you would think,
simply goes along with it.
You'll take the part
of the mastermind
behind Mary's death.
And you'll be the
irate inspector?
I'll be Mary.
You wouldn't
have thought that would happen
in a conventional 1899 drama
with conventional
gender stereotypes.
These people are roleplaying
in a way that's
really very modern,
as a way of trying to find
the truth of the situation.
But an amazing scene to shoot
because it's just so ambivalent
and ambiguous the whole time,
and wonderful to get, you know,
toe to toe with
Laura in that scene.
That was my favorite day,
I think, really, so far.
It was great having that scene with him,
and also seeing that
it's kind of two adversaries,
but nobody saying anything
in clear and plain language.
If I am your killer revealed,
behold the liar
of Great Britain,
an empire unparalleled and...
unmerciful in its
self-preservation.
Filming
at Knebworth is incredible,
because it's this huge
Gothic Tudor building
with so much history.
And it seems fitting
that something
that solid and powerful
has a man who would
be that solid and powerful.
So,
it very much embodies Massen's spirit.
Knebworth has these
extraordinary gates
with vast great dragons on them.
So, the exterior is fantastic,
but the inside's lovely as well.
When you look
at old Victorian photographs,
to any of the interiors of
Victorian prominent gentlemen,
you would find a lot of them
would have hunting trophies,
and things on the wall.
To do the interior
of Massen's estate,
you're looking at maybe
not antiques and furniture
from that Victorian period,
because they would often
have them maybe 50
or 100 years earlier.
So,
you're looking at really fine antiques.
Amalia notices
all his hunting trophies,
and his armor...
It speaks to his power, I think.
I suppose
you can say Massen is a villain.
In modern day,
he looks like a villain
in his black and
his high collar.
Actually,
that was just what men wore then.
I love the way the men
have to hold their head
with these incredibly
high collars sometimes.
What I really enjoy is,
as a costume develops,
you see the character emerge.
Particularly Amalia,
with the corset.
It was incredibly important
that she would really want
to be controlled and precise.
Some anarchic cabal
found or developed a power
that mocks God.
It was an attack on the empire.
So we're at war.
Massen doesn't
believe that the Touched
represent progress
of any good kind.
He is the living,
breathing embodiment
of the patriarchy,
and power as it
exists in that society.
Massen embodies that empire
and the values of that empire,
and if that means
people being sacrificed,
then that's the
way it's gonna go.
Massen, I suppose,
is fundamentally a bad guy,
in that he's about
destroying the Touched.
We always ask
ourselves about villains,
"How do they get
to be like this?"
With Massen,
he lost his wife young,
and now he's lost a child.
So,
that makes him rather compelling.
If you have a personal tragedy,
all that does is fortify
your allegiance
to the larger force.
So,
the larger British Empire for Massen.
There's a regular power play
between Massen and Amalia.
He's the old power,
she represents the new power,
and neither one of them
is gonna give that up easily.
So, I think she comes out
of there feeling frustrated...
and angry.
So he confessed
without confessing?
It was honestly impressive.
Amalia is
looking for how she is supposed
to be moving forward,
but she really is quite lost.
I was left here completely alone
with nothing but a mission
I was never actually given.
She is learning where to find
the information that she needs,
and the thing that...
really sets that in motion,
first of all, of course, is...
Is hearing Mary's song.
Myrtle's turn is she can
speak every language,
she can understand
every language.
So she does understand
everything Mary's saying.
And she also knows she
cannot say what it means.
She can't communicate
that with anyone.
And she knows that
this is life-changing
for everyone around her.
When Mary sang,
you heard words, language.
Primrose and Harriet kind
of seize this opportunity.
She's trying to
communicate with us
what she heard Mary sing.
We tried really hard to
include as many as we could.
You know, Asian languages,
Afro languages,
European languages.
It was a little
bit dictated by...
what contacts we had.
Viola is a remarkable person,
because she's so good
at picking up the sounds
and the rhythms of a language,
and the tune of a language.
She kind of absorbs that very,
very quickly.
Myrtle...
A little slower.
But I think we both felt
we want to do justice here,
if we're going to
use a bit of Afrikaans,
use a bit of Dutch,
or Turkish, or whatever it is,
we want to try
and do that justice.
So,
I put out an email to the whole crew.
The response was phenomenal!
Loads of people got involved,
and translated
pieces of script for us.
We had something like 30,
40 languages.
I just thought it was fantastic.
It was really joyous,
this coming together.
It's
sadly quite unusual in the world
for so many different
cultures to come together
and help each other.
We had some very,
very interesting debates,
you know. I'd say,
"Oh, um, can you say,
'Because of the darkness,
'" and people would say,
"When you say 'darkness',
what do you mean?
Do you mean total black?
Do you mean night-time?"
- I know it. "Darkness."
- "Dark..."
And, um, "before the dark?"
Uh, "Come before the dark."
Si!
That's so incredible,
that we're going
into this detail.
And you suddenly realize that
English has some words
that cover some things,
but other languages
have amazing words.
It's just really exciting,
'cause it's the coming together
of a lot of different people
who speak a lot of
different languages,
and can't necessarily
communicate
with one another clearly,
but still have the ability to do it,
regardless.
They were able to
find out what Mary's song meant,
so that's finally a message.
What did she say?
She said, "You're not alone."
She said it to you, Mrs. True.
And "There's a darkness."
She said to everyone, all of us.
So, it's really just a kind of
blind scrape through the dark
to get where she needs to get,
in the hope that there is
some light at the end of that.
- Was there more? - "Find me."
Who do we need to find?
>>>>oakislandtk
www.opensubtitles.org