NARRATOR:
In the criminal justice system
the people are represented by two
separate yet equally important groups,
the police
who investigate crime
and the district attorneys
who prosecute the offenders.
These are their stories.
(SIREN WAILING)
(BARKING)
It came from down there, Officer.
You call it in?
Yes, sir. On my cellular.
I'm Russell Lehrman.
How many shots?
Just one.
Scared the hell out of my dog.
You see anybody run out?
No. Nobody.
(DOG BARKING)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(WOMAN CHATTERING
OVER POLICE RADIO)
Over here.
2-0, Peter to Central,
signal 10-54.
We got a male down. Possible DOA.
80th and Riverside.
Oh, man, Wally.
Look at this.
OFFICER: The victim is Detective
First Grade Bill Morino.
Worked sex crimes
out of the third precinct.
We found his car parked half
a block down on Riverside.
We'll want to look at it.
Any witnesses?
Mr. Lehrman and his dog.
That's all.
Get a team to canvas the
buildings across the street.
Maybe somebody else was taking
their dogs out for a squirt.
One hit. In the front, out the back.
Powder burns on the face.
It's like he walked
right into it.
CSU's looking for a shell
casing and a weapon.
What about his?
Holster's empty.
They left his wallet.
11 bucks?
That's about right for a cop.
Anybody know
what he was doing here?
Put a call in to his partner.
He was home in bed.
Good place to be
at 2:00 in the morning.
Mike? What's the matter?
Better call his wife.
What, you know this guy?
Yeah. Billy Boy Morino.
I grew up with him.
Three stoops down.
WOMAN ON PA:
Doctor Richards...
Yeah. Okay, that'll work.
Thanks a lot.
Extension 25.
His partner will meet us
at the third precinct.
Judy...
I'm sorry.
Can you talk to us a minute?
Yeah.
How you holding up?
Okay.
They said there were
some forms I had to fill out.
A PBA person will come over,
they'll walk you through it.
My partner, Lennie Briscoe.
Mrs. Morino.
We're trying to put together what
Billy was doing in Riverside Park.
He was working.
His partner will know.
We thought maybe your husband
might've said something.
I was out with the kids.
I came home, there was a message
on the machine from Billy
saying he was gonna work late.
Did he say what time
he'd be home?
No. He just said not to wait up.
I was used to that.
Look, I gotta get home
before the kids wake up.
Thanks.
If he was working a case last
night, he didn't check in with me.
Nothing in the command log,
either.
Riverside Park's got to be a
natural for your line of work.
Yeah. Rapes, muggings.
In season, it gets busy.
But come wintertime, the perps
look for warmer quarters.
Well, Morino was there. We'd
like to know how he got there.
We're open to suggestion. I mean, a meet
with a snitch, a bad habit to feed...
What? I said
something wrong?
Only bad habit
he had was his work.
We cleared 82% of our cases.
Our conviction rate's 91%.
That holds up
to anybody's record.
Anybody's.
His service piece
hasn't turned up.
Zip for a shell casing. They're
still looking for the slug.
In that park? Good luck.
What about his car?
Nothing. Just his prints
and his wife's.
We emptied his desk and his locker.
We checked his notebooks.
Whatever he was up to, he
didn't tell anybody about it.
A secret hobby
he wasn't proud of?
Not according to his partner.
Not according to anybody Lennie. I
knew the guy since kindergarten.
He made the tough calls.
He was solid.
Mike.
What?
You want to know about his hobbies? Work
and family, family and work. Period.
Right. Right.
Mr. 82% case clearance.
It's a nice average. Makes for
a lot of angry defendants.
See if any of that 82%
came back to visit.
(PHONE RINGING)
VAN BUREN:
Yeah. Mike. I'll tell him.
Anti-corruption task force wants to talk.
Cragen's office.
Yeah. I saw
Morino take a bribe.
The counterman at Skouros'
comped him a piece of pie.
You gonna dig him up
and arrest him?
Just answer the question, Mike.
He worked sex crimes. That's
not exactly a gold mine, okay?
And before that he worked
narcotics at the 1-5.
A lot of guys at the 1-5
drive home in Corvettes.
Morino drove
a five-year-old Dodge.
When was the last time
you talked to him?
Couple of weeks ago.
He called me.
Just like that,
out of the blue?
Yeah, just like that. He found
the cure for the common cold.
Look, I was busy. We talked maybe a
couple of minutes. It was a nothing call.
What's going on here? Was Morino
under investigation or what?
We're talking to anybody who
ever hung a coat at the 1-5.
Well, does that
include their friends?
Okay. What do you say you guys go sharpen
a few pencils here, huh? Let's go.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Internal Affairs, Mike. They
never heard of Dale Carnegie.
Look, I've been to Morino's house
a couple of times a year. Okay?
I never saw anything
that made me think twice.
Well, that's good. That confirms
everything I saw in his file.
Then what am I doing here?
Because it's about to
hit the fan at the 1-5.
Maybe somebody thought
Morino'd be a liability.
Are you saying
another cop whacked him?
My 14-year-old plays
spin the bottle on a computer.
I'm telling you,
anything's possible.
So we just step aside and let
Internal Affairs get into it, huh?
Well, they would like that. But
I can tell them to take a hike.
Now, listen, here's a list of the
people we're looking at, at the 1-5.
Any of those names come up in connection
with Morino, you let me know.
And Mikey, this could
get hot and heavy.
So you keep that famous temper
of yours in your pocket, huh?
See you.
This is a waste of time.
If Morino was having lunch with
the old gang from the 1-5,
he wouldn't be stupid enough
to put it in his date book.
He would've been stupid not to.
If I was being squeezed
by those slime balls
I would have made
a note of it in big letters.
Unless he had as much
to hide as they do.
Hey, Lennie, for the last
time, Morino was clean.
Got it.
I don't get this.
Morino's precinct command log
for the last month.
Three times, he called in
off duty to Riverside Park.
So he was either
crazy about the neighborhood,
or he had something
going on the side.
What on the side? Come on,
just spit it out. Hey, Mike.
You want to write
Morino's eulogy,
or you want to catch
the guy who killed him?
Let's talk to the wife.
Billy never talked about
what went on at the 1-5.
I know he wasn't happy there.
Maybe some familiar names
came up over dinner?
No. He never
mentioned anybody.
Judy, we noticed he was around
Riverside Park a few times last month,
but his partner said
it wasn't work-related.
On the West Side? We don't
have any friends over there.
(CLEARS THROAT) Maybe your
husband had a friend.
Now, look...
We're gonna have to ask you this.
How was it going between you two?
Fine. Considering
we were married 15 years.
You know, Billy had his moods.
What kind of mood lately?
Most nights he was up pacing.
He was having nightmares.
I thought it was because of his work, you
know, the kind of cases he was getting.
Really sick stuff.
The department has shrinks on the payroll.
Could he have been talking to any of them?
I don't know.
I think he was talking to
somebody else, though.
I took a message for him
about three weeks ago
from a Father Joe.
You know Billy went back to the
church after the kids started school.
He wanted me to convert, too.
Are you talking
about a Father Joe Krolinsky?
Yeah. You know him?
Yeah.
He was our parish priest
when Billy and I were kids.
Did he leave a number?
No. He said he'd
try Billy at work.
I was just glad
he was getting help.
K-R-Jo.-I-I-N-S-K-Y.
Krolinsky.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Joseph.
No, we already checked Queens.
Okay. Thank you.
Archdiocese doesn't have him.
Yes?
All right.
Thank you very much, Sister.
He's not pounding the pulpit
in New Jersey, either.
What do you want to do,
call the Pope?
Gonna start with the DMV.
What? Priests don't drive?
Yes, this is
Detective Briscoe of the 2-7.
The color of the day
is aquamarine.
Right, I need an address on
a Joseph Krolinsky, with a
No, no date of birth.
Start with the locals.
Uh-huh.
Say that one again.
Thank you very much.
We have a winner.
Joseph Krolinsky,
406 West 78th.
That'd be two blocks
from where Morino was shot.
It's good to
see you again, Mike.
Can I offer you some coffee?
We're okay, Father.
The only people who call me
that are my kids.
I haven't been a priest
in nearly 15 years.
Do you have a family?
No.
Well, don't wait too long.
I nearly did.
And I take it you're not
here for a social call.
You phoned Billy Morino
a couple of weeks ago.
That's right.
Why the sudden inspiration?
JOE: He called me.
My company transferred me here last year.
I ran into Bill's mother on the subway.
I used to counsel her
when I was a priest.
Anyway, she told me
how well Bill was doing.
Thought I'd like to
hear from him.
Did you?
Of course.
But I haven't talked to him.
We traded phone calls.
Why, what happened?
Detective Morino was killed Tuesday night,
a couple of blocks from here in the park.
Oh, my God.
Did he ever come by the house,
maybe when you were out?
No. My wife
would've told me.
KATE: Joe.
The kids want to
say good night.
I'll be right there.
You'll excuse me.
BRISCOE: Yeah.
Sure, go ahead.
One more thing, Father.
Where were you Tuesday night?
I was right here with my family.
Why? Am I a suspect?
It was just a question.
Father Joe was in charge
of the altar boys.
He...
He had a reputation...
And?
Look, I...
I haven't even told
Lennie about this.
Father Joe put
the moves on me once.
Billy had some involvement,
some of the other kids, too.
What? Nobody reported him?
No, we were just kids. I mean, he was a big deal.
Our parents loved him.
What are kids gonna do
against a parish priest?
CRAGEN:
What're we saying here?
Morino heard Krolinsky's back in town.
He knows he likes kids.
Then what?
Fill in the blanks, Mike.
I can't.
Look, Mike, I'm here for you,
and you know that.
But you are gonna have to bring
in Lennie and Van Buren, okay?
Now, what does this
Krolinsky do for a living?
Senior Accounts Supervisor
at Dominion Life.
He's got the package deal. Nice
job, nice home, nice family.
So it'd be a shame if somebody were to
come along and upset that apple cart?
Especially if that somebody
had their hand out.
We checked Krolinsky's IUDs.
Two calls from his office, one call
to Morino, one call to his precinct.
And no calls to Krolinsky
on Morino's IUDs.
It bears out what
Krolinsky told you.
Well, don't put him up for sainthood yet.
Because I called up his yellows.
One arrest in '68, third-degree sexual abuse.
No disposition.
Sex abuse three. Catch-all for
everything, including a pat on the ass.
Anything more recent?
Well, no.
We got...
The archdiocese sent us stats.
1969, he was assigned to
a parish in Ohio.
Then five more parishes
over the next 12 years.
Last parish was in Buffalo.
Two years later, he hangs up his
collar and moves to Jersey.
According to the computer,
he kept his nose clean.
So this reputation
could've been all talk.
Hey, I was there. I didn't imagine
it and neither did Morino.
He was in Krolinsky's
neighborhood for a reason.
Because of Krolinsky.
Yeah, but he's
not around to tell us.
Maybe he told some of the
others from the old parish.
He called me before he died.
Maybe he called them.
Even after he said his name, it took
me a while to make the connection.
Billy Boy Morino.
First kid on the block
to grow a mustache.
I don't hear squat from him in 20 years,
and all of a sudden he wants a sit-down.
Right off the bat,
he gets into it. Father Joe.
One name I had
no problem remembering.
Why is that?
Come on, Mike. You know
what I'm talking about.
Pretend I don't.
Father Joe molested me
when I was 11.
A lot of other kids, too.
Billy was pretty worked up.
Said we should do something
about what he did to us.
Take him to court, sue him.
That might not be a bad idea.
It happened
a long time ago, Mike.
I had some problems in my
marriage, but I got help.
I settled up with Father Joe in my head.
I told Billy that's all I needed to do.
I can't get over it. I just talked
to him a couple of weeks ago.
Yeah. Well, getting back to that
conversation, Mr. Scully...
It was about that
sick bastard, Father Joe,
whatever he calls himself
these days.
Morino said he'd been
keeping tabs on him.
Meaning what?
Meaning Morino's in the
business of busting perverts.
Father Joe certainly qualifies.
Billy said he wanted
to take him to court.
He told me he had
a talk with Father Joe.
Son of a bitch offered him
money to go away.
Billy asked me
what I thought about it.
Well, what did you think?
Told him I'd get back to him.
I already know what
I want to do to Father Joe,
taking his money
isn't part of it.
Now that we got the death penalty
back, I know who's got my vote
for the grand opening.
Hey, you want to
get even with Krolinsky,
put him in the shower room
at Ossining for five minutes.
Yeah, it's Logan.
You beeped me.
Anyway, it sounds like Morino was
looking for a more rewarding payback.
Krolinsky offered him the money. I
didn't hear that Billy took it.
Well, maybe he never
got the chance.
Maybe Krolinsky figured he's gonna
be on the hook to this guy forever.
And he solves his problems
with one bullet.
Yeah, where? Okay.
Speaking of, they got the slug.
CSU found it on the ground
with a metal detector.
70 yards from where
Morino was shot.
We're lucky it didn't
catch the uptown bus.
A .38 semi-wad cutter.
Are you ready for this?
I matched it to Morino's service revolver.
We had his lands and grooves on file.
That can't be right.
There's the microscope.
Help yourself.
Did anybody check Morino's
gloves for powder residue?
Let me look.
The answer's no. The
gloves were in his pocket.
Well, just for the hell of it,
check them anyway.
You read our report. It's all
there in black and white.
Well, my reading skills aren't
what they used to be. Why
don't you walk us through it?
We came down the hill,
found him lying there.
His gloves,
were they on or off?
He wasn't wearing any.
They were in his pocket.
We can't figure out how powder
residue got on his right glove.
It's all here in the report,
fellows, in black and white.
(SIGHING)
Those lab guys are amazing.
They found a slug and matched
it up to Morino's piece.
Now either they're wrong, or your report
isn't what I would call comprehensive.
Maybe you'd like to
pencil in a few adjustments?
Look, we were just trying to
do right by the guy's family.
Just try doing right
by regulations.
We found him with his service
piece in his right hand.
He was a suicide, no question. We
ditched the gun, took his gloves off.
What in hell crossed your mind
to do something like that?
He goes on the books as a
suicide, the widow gets what,
a lousy 50 grand payout?
If he gets written up as
"killed in the line of duty,"
it rates a couple of
hundred grand, minimum.
Yeah, I mean, come on,
guys, he was a cop.
We gotta take care of
each other, am I right?
I talked to McCoy. We won't be
pressing charges against the officers.
The department'll handle it. At most,
they'll draw a 30-day suspension.
Great. They can use the time to raise
money for the widows and orphans' fund.
I don't get it.
Billy just wasn't the type.
Yeah, well, we'll save the
post-game wrap-up for the shrinks.
Wait a minute.
We talked to four people who
were molested by Krolinsky.
And those are just
the ones we know about.
Thirty-year-old crimes, Mike.
That's 25 years
past the expiration date.
He left the state.
Doesn't that stop the clock
on the statute of limitations?
Only for five years.
Krolinsky's in the clear.
And Morino might be dead
because of what he did to him.
You're gonna let him walk?
We don't have a choice.
His record's clean.
Except for a sex abuse
arrest in '68.
Which was never prosecuted.
Claire, the guy
belongs in a box.
You know what, Mike? Talk to the sex-abuse victim.
Find out what really happened.
I was 10 years old.
My dad sold plumbing supplies
so he was on the road a lot.
Father Joe picked up
the slack, you know.
And he got me into the choir.
He helped me with my
homework, stuff like that.
My mother thought
he walked on water.
She didn't catch on, right?
Nah. Neither did I.
It wasn't like he was sending
a dozen roses every day.
Well, after the big build-up,
what happened?
(CLEARS THROAT)
He asked me to stay after
choir practice one Saturday.
It was this little room
at the school.
He started asking me
a lot of questions like,
you know, did I have a girlfriend.
And they got more and more personal,
and then it was, "Show me yours
and I'll show you mine."
It's okay, Mr. Waller.
You're doing just fine.
(CLEARS THROAT)
He put his hand in my pants.
Gray flannel pants
I got for Christmas.
And when it was over, he...
He made a mess on my new pants.
(EXHALES)
He started crying and he said that
we'd sinned and if I told anybody,
God would punish both of us.
But you did tell somebody?
Because of the pants.
I hid them in the basement,
and my dad found them.
At that time, did you tell the
police what you just told us?
No.
My mother was very pious.
She burned the pants.
My father wanted to kill him.
And they had a big argument.
And I was told that
all I was allowed to say was,
Father Joe touched me
through my clothes.
And what happened
after he got arrested?
(SCOFFS)
You know, I'm really not sure.
Man, I was young.
Father Joe left the parish, and my
parents never brought it up again.
I was a happy kid.
And I loved my parents.
That scum took
all that away from me.
So the man's a criminal.
How does that get us past
the statute of limitations?
We can re-file the charge as a felony
and still be within the limits.
He was charged with
a misdemeanor.
Only because the police were never
told what actually happened.
You know it's a stretch.
Jack, Mr. Waller never
had his day in court.
Pick up Krolinsky.
Mike, what's going on?
You mind stepping outside,
Mr. Krolinsky?
Joseph Krolinsky, you're under
arrest for aggravated sexual abuse.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will be
used against you in a court of law.
Joe?
You understand that?
Get back inside, Kate.
You have the right to an attorney. If
you cannot afford one, one will be...
Thirty-year-old misdemeanor, and you
puff it up into a felony arrest.
He's lucky the statutes keep
me from bringing more charges.
Based on what? Stewart
Waller's book of fairy-tales?
They believed him 30 years ago.
And they didn't prosecute because
they saw it for what it was,
the imaginings of
a vindictive child.
I told Stewart he couldn't be
in the choir anymore.
He wasn't good enough.
He ran home and told his
parents this crazy story.
A lot of other people tell similar stories.
Are they all being vindictive?
Neighborhood gossip.
That's your case?
Let me spare you the egg facial.
Motion to dismiss.
Pleasant reading.
Even if you attach credence
to Mr. Waller's accusations,
the boat sailed
25 years ago, Your Honor.
The People are doing an end run
around the statute of limitations.
Mr. McCoy, this offense was filed as a
misdemeanor when I was in high school.
Why bring it back
as a felony now?
We believe it's only
the tip of the iceberg.
That's nonsense. This case sat in
someone's drawer for 30 years.
It was dismissed once.
To let Mr. McCoy proceed now
not only violates the spirit
of the statute of limitations,
it violates my client's
right to a speedy trial.
He violated Stewart Waller in the
most heinous manner imaginable.
The People had their bite at the
apple 30 years ago, Mr. McCoy.
I don't see how stretching the statute
serves the interest of justice.
The charges are dismissed.
Well, it was a noble effort.
I called Stewart Waller to tell him.
It wasn't easy. He had his hopes up.
He's suffered plenty.
The statute of limitations
doesn't help him.
Long as Mr. Krolinsky's been
behaving himself all these years.
He just hasn't been caught.
I've prosecuted pedophiles before, Adam.
They defy rehabilitation.
Even golfers retire. Is there any
evidence that he's still active?
No. But he moved from parish
to parish the last 30 years.
Makes you wonder why.
Let's ask the people
who moved him.
I pulled together Mr. Krolinsky's
personnel file, works and all.
It doesn't say very much for our
success in dealing with his problem.
The church knew
what he was doing?
Yes. We had reports from other priests,
from parents, starting in the late '60s.
Well, what were you
waiting for? Polaroids?
Of course not. Mr. Krolinsky
was relieved of his duties.
He was ordered to seek
medical care.
Once the doctors pronounced him
cured, he was sent to a new parish.
How often was he
pronounced cured?
The church tried everything, Mr. McCoy.
We sent him to our treatment centers.
We thought faith and prayer would
be enough to rehabilitate him.
We were wrong.
The church had him
for 20 years.
I'm amazed you allowed him to slip
through the cracks for so long.
We dealt with him
as best we could,
based on what we knew then
about his sickness.
Now we put people like
Mr. Krolinsky in your hands.
It's incredible. There must be 100
reports of molestation in here.
And only one of them
ends up on a police blotter.
When Krolinsky was sent to a
parish in Buffalo in 1980,
nobody even bothered to warn them. They
made him supervisor of the altar boys.
Krolinsky's last documented victims were in '81.
Still puts him out of our range.
Hand me the police interviews
with Detective Morino's friends.
One of them mentions a conversation
between Krolinsky and Morino.
Here.
Krolinsky offered him money
to leave him alone.
And Morino was
a police officer.
Do you want to arrest Krolinsky
for attempted bribery?
Say money did change hands. Bribery
is an element of a conspiracy.
A conspiracy to do what?
To molest children.
It extends from the time he
molested the kids in the '60s,
right up to the present
where he bribed Morino.
We can get him for everything.
It takes two to commit conspiracy.
Who did he conspire with?
The Roman Catholic Church.
What've you been inhaling?
You want to name the Catholic
Church as a co-conspirator?
An unindicted co-conspirator.
I see.
We don't charge them with conspiring
to molest kids, we just say they did.
That's gonna be a great
relief to the Archbishop.
We don't even
have to go that far.
Under People v. Villetto,
we can convict Krolinsky
even though the church never
intended to conspire with him,
nor commit
the underlying crime.
That's very slick.
But you still need an overt
act by the co-conspirator.
The church played a shell game
with Krolinsky.
They foisted him on one
unsuspecting parish after another.
Adam, this isn't
an indictment of the church.
It wasn't a priest who did
this, it was a pedophile.
If we want to get him,
this is the only way.
All right. I'll talk to the Archbishop.
I'll let him know what's coming.
And we still have to prove
Krolinsky bribed Morino.
Start with
the financial records.
Unindicted co-conspirators.
My aunt who says the rosary every
morning's gonna have a conniption.
The church should've dropped a
dime on this guy 30 years ago.
Oh, yeah. Right.
Because they're the only people in the
world who scratch each other's backs.
Unlike politicians and cops,
just to name two.
If it's any comfort to your aunt,
we have the Archbishop's blessing.
Hey, unless Krolinsky's supporting his
local bookie, I think I have something.
$50,000 cash withdrawal.
The week before Morino died.
If it turns up on
Morino's account...
The corruption task force already
went through Morino's books.
We're not gonna find
anything they didn't.
Has anyone bothered to look
into his wife's finances?
It's bad enough
what Billy did to himself.
Now you want to say
that he was taking a bribe?
You bought T-bills a couple
of weeks ago, Mrs. Morino.
$50,000 worth
in your children's names.
Judy, we have to know
where that money came from.
If it came from Krolinsky, we got him.
That's what Billy wanted.
I found the money in an envelope
a week after Billy died.
Was there anything else
in the envelope?
Yes. A note.
Billy said I was supposed to use the
money to take care of the kids.
I didn't give him a dime. I told
you, I never talked to him.
Then what did you do
with the money?
Take some Boy Scouts
on a field trip?
Mr. McCoy, unless you have actual
questions for him, we're done here.
He can start by answering
for 30 years of sexual abuse.
We have all the names
and dates and locations.
Where did you get this?
The archdiocese. They want him
behind bars as much as we do.
LOGAN: Where do you
want to start, Father?
At the top of the pile
or the bottom?
That won't be necessary.
ZINNS: Joe...
No, I want to do this.
I was a very sick man. That's
why I left the priesthood.
You're blaming the church? They
didn't molest kids. You did.
I'm a different man now, Mike.
You should be happy how I've turned out.
I have a wonderful family...
No. No. I can't
listen to this crap.
I don't think a jury will be
very much interested, either.
You'll never prove where
Morino's money came from.
I'll let 12 mothers and
fathers make the connection.
Give us a minute, Mr. McCoy.
That son of a bitch is lucky
I didn't smack him.
So are we.
There's people like him
in every neighborhood.
Could be the little league coach,
your kid's favorite teacher.
It's too bad they don't
glow in the dark.
It's a matter of law that a
payment between accomplices
isn't an element
of a conspiracy.
Meaning such payment does not
extend the life of the conspiracy.
Meaning you have no case.
What accomplice
are you talking about?
Back when I had my illness,
Billy Morino used to
invite boys to visit with me.
ZINNS: To put it bluntly,
Morino was his pimp.
My client gave him the $50,000
as a belated gratuity.
He's unbelievable.
He molested these kids.
And now he's trying to blame
one of his own victims.
Unfortunately, it may work.
If they prove Morino was getting
boys for Krolinsky 25 years ago,
the jury can infer that the payment
was for services rendered.
Therefore your case ended
back in the '70s somewhere.
Krolinsky can put whatever
spin on the facts he wants.
A jury won't take the word
of an admitted child molester.
Unless his victims
confirm Morino's involvement.
I spoke to them. They say that
Morino was not part of the equation.
And of course, they wouldn't
lie just to convict Krolinsky.
But you remind them that we still
put people in jail for perjury.
McCoy says Morino took a bribe. The
other side says he was a pimp.
Well, that's a hell of a choice. So
what is it, column A or column B?
It's just two friends
talking, Mikey.
When I was 12, Billy tried to recruit
me for a matinee with Father Joe.
What, do you think
less of him because of it?
Come on, Mike. You know how
guys like Krolinsky operate.
They manipulate these kids.
They know what buttons to push.
Kid's got no father,
the mother works two jobs,
the kid's small for his age.
Yeah, I know. I know.
So, you gonna let
McCoy in on this secret?
He's not calling me in
as a witness. I begged off.
What, was I supposed to get up in court and
put another bullet through Billy's head?
Oh, good. So you're off the hook. So
long as nobody asks you the question.
Maybe I won't remember.
Krolinsky goes to prison, I
wouldn't exactly cry about it, Don.
So you might as well toss that
badge of yours in the garbage.
Thanks for the help.
I'm not gonna run to teacher, Mike.
You do what you gotta do.
I'm just telling you, you
don't owe Morino a thing.
Oh, the hell I don't.
When he tried to recruit me
that day, you know what I did?
I decked him. Instead of
running to the nearest cop.
The other week when he called me, I had
a feeling what it was about, you know?
(SIGHS)
I did the same thing I've been doing for 25 years.
I avoided the subject.
I couldn't handle it.
My take? Neither could he. Seeing
Krolinsky brought it all back.
Imagine the guilt about all
the kids he fed that pervert.
The only problem is,
he shot the wrong guy.
Come on, Mike, he never even
realized he was the victim.
Billy mentioned this money Krolinsky
offered him to leave him alone.
Billy didn't know what to do
about it. Neither did I.
And that was the last time
I talked to him.
No more questions.
You were friends with Detective Morino
when you were kids, isn't that right?
SCULLY: Yes.
ZINNS: You went to
ball games together?
Sure, sometimes.
Did you ever sit behind
the dugout at Shea?
A couple of times.
At 7 bucks a seat, that's a lot
of money for a working-class kid.
Where'd you get those tickets?
I can't remember.
Didn't Billy Morino arrange for you
to get them from Mr. Krolinsky?
I don't know.
In fact,
didn't Billy Morino tell you, you could get
those tickets if you visited Mr. Krolinsky?
No. Billy Morino had nothing to do with it.
That bastard abused me...
Move to strike, Your Honor.
Yes. The jury will disregard
the witness's last comment.
No more questions.
So I'll call impound and see
if the convertible turned up.
Detective Michael Logan?
Yes.
Have a nice day.
A subpoena. What'd you do,
run over somebody's toes?
It's from Krolinsky's lawyer.
I'm gonna have to call McCoy.
Damn!
Billy was a year older than me.
I guess we were good friends.
He lived on the same block, and
we went to the same school.
Same church.
And did he make a proposition
to you involving Mr. Krolinsky?
I don't understand
the question.
ZINNS: Do you want me to speak
more slowly, Detective?
Do you want me to answer that?
Your Honor, permission
to treat as hostile?
Go ahead.
Detective Logan,
did Billy Morino suggest
you have sex
with Mr. Krolinsky
in return for baseball tickets?
You're under oath, Detective.
Yes, he did.
Billy was just a kid.
No more questions.
Mr. Krolinsky
manipulated him...
NOVAK: Mr. McCoy.
No questions at this time. The
People reserve the right to recall.
NOVAK:
You're excused, Detective.
I remind you you're still under oath, not
to discuss your testimony with anybody.
My client has been vindicated.
JACK: All that was missing was
the platter from Tiffany's.
Get off my back.
This is between me and Morino.
And the District Attorney's
Office.
You had an obligation
to tell us before the trial.
Wait a minute. Are you telling me
that what one scared young kid did
can compare to what that
freak did to 100 kids?
My friend's name just got dragged
through the mud up there, and for what?
That's a hell of a system
you got, Counselor.
Well, I think that was
both barrels.
His friend's character's
not the issue. Krolinsky's is.
Starting tomorrow, we get
to hear from his coworkers
what a fine human being
he's become.
Except we won't be hearing from his wife.
She hasn't been added to the witness list.
I haven't seen her in the court
for the last few days, either.
Find out why.
Logan was in an impossible position. I
won't push for disciplinary action.
In the meantime, he jammed
a stick in your spokes.
Technically, Morino was
Krolinsky's accomplice.
The money was not a bribe.
There is no act to extend
the life of the conspiracy.
The jury will acquit.
Not if we can convince them that Morino
couldn't consent to be an accomplice.
How do you intend to do that?
Every study on pedophilia
bears it out.
The adult is always in control.
The child can never consent.
Morino was 13. Sounds old enough
to me to know right from wrong.
We're talking about a neglected child.
Easy pickings for a pedophile.
They know how to play
on those weaknesses.
They become the authority
figure in the child's life.
Right and wrong doesn't mean anything. All
the kid wants is to please the adult.
He doesn't know he's being
used as a Judas goat.
So you present our
expert here in rebuttal,
and you're sure that the jury
draws the right conclusion?
Time to pull your pecans out of the fire
and give Krolinsky's lawyer a call.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
Yes.
We may be on to something.
Mrs. Krolinsky moved back to New Jersey
with her kids three days into the trial.
(SCOFFS)
There you go.
I wanted to get my boys away
from all the publicity.
I had to take them out of school. I mean,
the things people say, you can't imagine.
You've already heard them
said in court, under oath.
It's all lies.
Mrs. Krolinsky, if we could
just come in. Go away.
Mrs. Krolinsky...
Please, I'm just
trying to protect my boys.
What does she think
she's protecting them from?
Now, her neighbors
read the same papers we do.
It must've been pretty upsetting hearing
those things said about her husband.
She's been married to him 12 years.
That's the man she knows.
Maybe that's why she moved out.
But we checked the New Jersey
records, no complaints, no charges.
If you had a family matter
you wanted handled discreetly,
would you run
to the local precinct?
No. But I might
go to Family Services.
Mrs. Krolinsky came to my office
three years ago. She was in tears.
What did she tell you?
The night before,
she walked in on her husband
and their nine-year-old son.
Doing something God didn't
intend. Her words, not mine.
I started a file, scheduled
an interview with the boy.
Did he confirm the story?
Never got a chance to find out.
The next day, Mrs. Krolinsky was back,
apologizing to everyone in sight.
You believed her?
Without her cooperation,
an investigation would've
been a waste of time.
I kept her file,
in case she changed her mind.
I'm gonna need a copy of that.
Sure.
I was wondering when you
people'd get back to me on this.
Excuse me?
A couple of months ago, I got a phone call
from one of your sex crimes investigators.
A Detective Morino.
He said he was doing a work-up
on Mr. Krolinsky.
I sent him a copy of the file.
Never heard back.
This is wrong. Kate was mistaken.
She told them that.
Right or wrong, I don't care.
And neither will the jury.
They'll never see it.
It's irrelevant.
Not as a motive for bribery.
Detective Morino had this report. That's
what he was holding over your head.
That's why you paid him off.
You set aside
the conspiracy and bribery.
We're open to a plea of sex abuse
one on all the remaining counts,
to serve concurrently.
Two-and-a-half to seven years?
Your client is facing conviction on 19
counts of aggravated sex abuse one.
Tack them together, they'll be planting
tomatoes on Mars by the time he gets out.
For God's sake, Mr. McCoy,
I have a family.
I feel sorry for them.
No, listen. I want to get help. I'm
a sick man, I want to get help...
You're an adult.
Your victims are children.
There's nothing you could say that
would make me feel sorry for you.
Let's split the difference,
Mr. McCoy.
Knock it down to a C felony
with concurrent sentences.
He serves the maximum,
15 years.
Consider it a gift.
Before I impose sentence,
does the defendant wish
to make a statement?
Yes, Your Honor.
I just wanna say
from deep in my heart,
how sorry I am to all those
people I've offended.
I'm very sorry.
The defendant has met the
conditions of the plea agreement.
In accordance, the court sentences
Joseph Krolinsky to a term of 15 years.
The facility to be determined by
the Department of Correction.
Court is adjourned.
(GAVEL BANGS)
We called you Father.
How could you do that to us?
You even did it
to your own kid.
How could you do that?
They're ready to take him.