My dear children...
it is now better
than several years...
since I moved to New York...
and I haven't seen you
as much as I would like to.
I hope you will come
to this ceremony of papal honors...
given for my charitable work.
The only wealth
in this world is children.
More than all the money,
power on earth...
you are my treasure.
Anthony and Mary...
although I entrusted
your education to your mother...
for your own best interests...
you know how I look forward
to seeing you...
and to a new period
of harmony in our lives.
Perhaps you might
prevail upon your mother...
to come to this celebration...
and that from time to time...
we can all see each other
at family functions.
Anyway, I remain,
your loving father.
Hail Mary, full of grace...
blessed art Thou amongst women...
and blessed is the fruit
of Thy womb,Jesus.
Holy Mary, mother of God...
pray for us sinners--
Almighty God,
bless the insignia...
of Saint Sebastian the Martyr...
that it may contribute
to the sacredness of him...
to whom it is given.
Do you, Michael...
promise to be faithful
to the noble purposes...
of this order...
to have a special care
for the poor, the needy...
and those who are ill?
l do so promise.
May the blessing
of Almighty God--
Father, Son, and Holy Spirit--
descend upon you
and remain with you...
forever.
Amen.
Vincent, our name's
not on the list.
Write it in.
Mancini. M-A-N-C-l-N-l.
- ls there a problem?
- My name's not on the list.
Then you have to
leave immediately.
- No two ways about it.
- You want to dance?
Joe, it's Vinnie.
lt's okay. These are our guests.
l'm sorry, Dave.
lt's all right.
Vinnie, welcome to the party.
Good to see you.
lt's good to see you again.
This is my husband.
This is my son, Anthony.
The order of Saint Sebastian
is one of the highest honors...
the Catholic Church
can bestow upon a layman.
The award was first granted
by Pope Gregory--
What about Mr. Corleone's connections
with Las Vegas gambling?
Press kits have pictures--
How about his involvement
with the underworld?
Cut the crap, huh?
The pope,
the Holy Father himself...
has this very day
blessed Michael Corleone.
You think you know
better than the pope?
- Do it, do it.
- Vincent!
- Yes?
- She loves you.
- What'd he say?
- l love you too.
Hi, Vincent.
l remember you.
You remember me?
From where?
When we were at
a party together.
Did you come to the club?
- No, it was a wedding.
- A wedding?
l was eight, and you were 1 5.
l had a lot of girlfriends
when l was 1 5.
- Eight-year-olds?
- Especially eight-year-olds.
Where's Mary?
Would somebody please hail Mary?
Excuse me, Your Excellency.
You know, you haven't
kissed me hello yet.
- Relatives always kiss.
- Oh, now we're related?
l'm your little cousin.
Who's your father?
l'll give you a hint.
- He's ltalian.
- Mary.
Mary, we've been
waiting for you.
Remember...
keep your voice low.
Smile. Don't forget to smile.
Carissimi Amici...
the honorary chairman...
of the Vito Corleone
Foundation...
my daughter, Mary Corleone.
Thanks.
l think l inherited my father's love
for speechmaking...
but here it goes.
The Vito Corleone Foundation...
helps the impoverished
of every country...
gives grants to artists...
funds medical research...
and is particularly dedicated
to the resurrection of Sicily.
Archbishop Gilday...
here is $ 1 00 million
for the poor of Sicily...
in the name of Vito Corleone.
Don't spend it all in one place.
l'm so proud of you.
You've done a wonderful thing
for Sicily.
Let's just hope the money
gets to the people who need it.
- Amen.
- But the most important part--
Johnny Fontane!
Thank you very much.
l'm happy to be here with you,
and l'd like you to join me...
in honoring
commendatore Michael Corleone.
l have something special
for our host and godfather.
l just happen to know
his favorite song.
Michael, where are you going?
lt's your favorite song.
l'm off here to the kitchen
to hear some Tony Bennett records.
It's your favorite song.
It's salsiccia's own.
We're getting
a salsiccia sandwich.
l'll be back.
A rose must remain
With the sun and the rain
Or its lovely promise
won't come true
To each his own
And my own is you
Hello, Kay.
Congratulations, Michael.
That's really quite an honor.
lt's a little expensive,
wouldn't you say?
Cake?
No, thank you.
- Been a long time, hasn't it?
- Yeah.
Eight years.
You look wonderful.
Your son has something
he wants to talk to you about.
l came here for him.
Nice to see you.
Thank you.
If a flame is to grow
There must be a glow
To open each door
There's a key
I need you, I know
I can't let you go
- What's wrong with being a lawyer?
- Nothing, except he doesn't want it.
He wants his life
to be in music.
Music is great.
l love music...
but he should finish
what he started.
- l'm going my own way.
- Your own way?
- Professional singer?
- That's right.
And what happens if you fail?
l won't fail.
- Men always believe that.
- l know.
lf you have a law degree...
you're taking out
insurance.
After that, you can do anything--
work for me--
l will never work for you.
l have bad memories.
Every family has bad memories.
l will always be your son...
but l will never have anything
to do with your business.
Anthony, finish the law degree.
That he got from you,
that ''no.''
You could have helped me
to convince him, Kay.
Oh, yeah.
Convince him of what?
Of what?
He throws his life away.
He throws greatness away.
This is greatness?
Now that you're
so respectable...
l think you're more dangerous
than you ever were.
ln fact, l preferred you
when you were just...
a common Mafia hood.
- Now can we talk common sense here?
- All right.
Tony knows that you killed Fredo.
- What did you come here for?
- To protect my son.
l didn't come to see you disguised
by your church.
l think that was
a shameful ceremony.
l spent my life
protecting my son.
protecting my family!
Let's be reasonable.
That's your big thing,
isn't it, Michael?
Reason backed up by murder.
Oh, God.
God, you hate me. You hate me.
l don't hate you.
l dread you.
l did what l could, Kay, to protect...
all of you from the horrors
of this world.
But you became my horror.
Our children still love you, though.
Especially Mary.
That's something.
We can build on that,
for their sake.
Let's try.
Only if you let Tony go free
to have his own life...
away from you.
l'll let Tony go.
Thank you.
You could hurt somebody
with those.
Let me show you around.
Can you get me an interview
with Michael Corleone?
No. l'm a relative,
but l can't do that.
What else could l do for you?
- Handsome but useless.
- Oh, yeah?
- That's okay. l'll gamble.
- You like to gamble?
Let's go to Atlantic City. lt's my town.
l'll show you how to gamble.
How will l know
what numbers to bet?
Do l look like a loser?
Well--
That's a spooky-looking
guy there.
What's a guy like that doing
at Michael Corleone's house?
- That's Joey Zasa's bulldog.
- You know that guy?
Yeah, l know that guy.
That guy's name
is Anthony Squigiliaro.
They call him ''the Ant.''
He dips his bullets in cyanide.
Don Altobello.
l come to pay my respects.
You honor my father's friendship.
Where is my goddaughter?
lt was not so long ago
l held you in these old hands.
No, no.
l stand. l stand.
Michael, l lost
all the venom...
all the juice of youth.
l lost the lust
for women...
and now my mind is clear.
My duty to God is clear.
l have a special favor to ask.
Can l attach my name...
to the Vito Corleone Foundation...
so that you and l can be joined...
in name and spirit?
One million dollars.
- Godfather.
- Don Altobello...
you have such a heart.
Come, let's go
and sample some of it.
The Vatican knows nothing
about these shareholders.
Good.
l have a tendency to worry.
We've increased our position
substantially...
and naturally, l worry.
Come along now.
Stop worrying.
We have an agreement.
Good. How do you think
l got this gray hair?
Mr. Corleone.
- Two seconds.
- Frank, how are you?
Thanks for your swimming pool
contribution...
and we need your help on
Sam Wallace's candidacy for a judgeship.
- We always can use a good judge.
- Thank you.
Andrew.
Excellency, my godson,
Andrew Hagen...
my brother Tom Hagen's
eldest boy...
and he's been assistant
to Bishop Breelan three years now.
He's hoping for
a Vatican assignment.
There's always a place in Rome
for a fine priest.
His mother, Theresa Hagen.
Bishop Gilday.
Thank you.
lt's an honor to meet you.
Mr. Corleone, hi.
Grace Hamilton.
Vincent Mancini promised
he'd tell you about me...
that maybe you'd see me.
Vincent Mancini call about her?
No.
Grace, you promised me
you'd stay up there.
- l know.
- Twice.
Joey Zasa showed up.
We got him waiting in the lobby.
Says he wants to personally
congratulate you and show his respect.
Do l have to see him?
He says you're his padrone
and he only wants a minute.
Hey, Vinnie.
- Who's your favorite aunt?
- You are.
Today l'm going to talk to Michael
about your problem.
l wish you would have warned me, Con.
l could have worn a better suit.
The Meucci Association
has elected you...
their ltalian-American
man of the year.
Hey, Meucci.
Who's Meucci?
He's the ltalian-American
who invented the telephone.
He did it one year before
Alexander Graham Bell.
Really? Huh.
And this is the reason
you've come to my home?
l got a stone in my shoe,
Mr. Corleone.
A two-bit punk
who works for me...
the one who...
thinks he's related to you.
A bastard.
He's here.
Vincent Mancini.
He's at the party.
Bring him in.
l think it's good we talk.
l have a problem...
and l want to find out
if it is my problem...
or your problem.
Your business is your business.
l have no interest
in percentages.
l'm out.
Good.
Then it's my problem.
Michael, you know
Vincent Mancini, Sonny's boy.
How you doing, Mr. Corleone?
- How you doing?
- Good. How you doing?
- Good.
- Good party.
- Oh, you like it.
- Yeah. l had to sneak in.
You're dressed for it.
So...
what's the trouble
between you and Mr.Joe Zasa?
Just trouble.
l'll take care of it.
- That's foolish of you.
- Foolish of me?
lt's foolish of this guy,
don't you think?
Right?
Temper like his father.
Vincent...
Mr.Joe Zasa now owns
what used to be...
the Corleone family
business in New York.
Out of the kindness of his heart,
he gave you a job in his family.
Contrary to my advice,
you took the job.
l offered you something better
in the legitimate world.
You turned me down.
Now you both come to me
with this bad blood.
What do you expect me to do?
Am l a gangster?
- No. You're not a gangster.
- That was Papa's neighborhood.
Now it's a sewer.
Zasa runs it like a disgrace.
That's the past.
l earned that territory
with my talent.
The commission gave it to me,
and you approved it.
- Yes.
- l came to the party.
l'm not here for help.
l could kill this bastard.
- He needs the help.
- So kill him.
What does all this
have to do with me?
He's going around behind your back
saying, ''Fuck Michael Corleone.''
That's one thing
that has to do with you. Right?
Say it to his face one time.
Just one time.
Mr. Corleone,
all bastards are liars.
- Shakespeare wrote poems about it.
- What am l gonna do with this guy?
lf there is some guy
running around this city...
saying, ''Fuck Michael Corleone''...
what do we do with a piece of shit
like that?
He's a fucking dog.
Yes, it's true.
lf anyone would say such a thing...
they would not be a friend,
they would be a dog.
My interests don't conflict
with Mr.Joe Zasa's.
You don't know how much your interests
conflict with Zasa's, Uncle Michael.
Wait.
He needs your support.
Don't let me work
for this guy no more.
- Let me work for you.
- For me?
As what? Tough guy?
l don't need tough guys.
l need more lawyers.
Since we have no
conflicts, no debts...
l accept your tribute.
l wish you well.
Vincent, make your peace
with Mr.Joe Zasa.
Come on.
Okay. Go on.
Bastardo.
For Christ's sakes, stop!
What's the matter with you?
Get him out of here.
Oh,Jesus.
Uncle Michael, l told Connie
it wasn't the right time for this.
- Close it.
- l know you're into banks and stocks.
Everyone knows you're the final word,
like the Supreme Court.
l want to protect you from these guys.
Your lawyers can't do that.
- And you can?
- Yeah, l can do that.
Why should l be
afraid of Joe Zasa?
He knows you're stopping him
from rising up in the commission.
l say we make him dead.
Give me the order, l'll take care of it.
- You'll take care of it?
- Yeah.
Maybe you should come with me...
for a few weeks,
see what happens.
See if you learn.
Then we'll talk
about your future.
l won't let you down.
We're just about ready.
- So what happened?
- What happened?
They put me in a room with Zasa,
what's gonna happen? l bit his ear off.
Here we go.
Watch the card.
- There.
- Hold it.
l'll just change
the plate here.
Vincent.
Take the picture with us.
Come on.
- Nice jacket.
- Little girl--
Closer to the center,
if you would, sir.
And here we go.
Ready. Smile.
Excellent.
l'll have it for you on Monday.
Butter cake.
Beautiful.
Godfather, this is the cake
for you and your family...
from Enzo the baker.
Want to do it?
All right.
You lead.
Kathryn, you lead.
- Vincent?
- What do you want, sweetheart?
Do you love me?
- Come on. Go to bed.
- Come on. Say it.
- Go to bed.
- No. Say it.
l love you.
l love you too.
You got a cat?
Go get us some water,
would you? l'm thirsty.
Come on.
Well, l just guess
l know my place.
l can't believe l'm actually
getting up to do this.
''Get me water. Bake me a cake.''
Whatever happened to ''please''?
Come on.
Good boy, Sockface.
Let's go for a walk.
Let her go.
Fuck it.
Cut her throat, man.
- What'd you say?
- l said, cut her fucking throat.
Let her go.
Drop your gun,
or he'll cut her throat.
l hardly know this broad.
Go ahead and cut her.
What the fuck do l care?
You got no choice, man.
This chick's gonna be dead.
Hurt her,
l'll kill you both.
- Give up that knife, l'll let you go.
- You cut her throat right now.
l'll do something to convince you.
Don't get frightened.
Don't do any sudden movements.
Just watch me, all right?
- Hear me?
- Yeah.
Oh, shit!
Drop the knife.
Go ahead. Drop it!
Good boy.
Sit down.
l want to talk to you.
lt's a wise choice. Sit down.
Lose the mask.
Relax. Have a smoke.
You smoke?
Whose idea was this?
Who sent you?
Come on. Tell me.
- No one.
- Take a good look at this guy?
- Yeah.
- So who sent you?
lt was Joey.
Joey Zasa.
You okay?
- You were going to let them kill me!
- l wasn't gonna let that happen.
You pig!
You sick fuck!
Come on, sweetheart, that's gambling.
You wanted gambling? That's gambling.
Call the police.
- You killed the other guy too?
- He went for my gun.
lt's self-defense, justifiable homicide.
Go ahead. Call the police.
- Where are you going? Oh, no.
- l'm going to take pictures first.
No pictures.
You had a gun.
They only had a knife.
You could have talked them into
surrendering, handed them to the police.
Zasa sent these guys.
l just sent him a message, that's all.
- Now he has to send you a message back.
- He's gotta send me a message back?
- Zasa's going to send a message?
- He did the right thing.
- He got Zasa's name.
- What does he got to do with it?
Joey Zasa's a pazzo.
Joey Zasa.
All right.
You are what you are.
lt's your nature.
Stay close to me.
You don't do anything.
Keep your mouth shut
and your eyes open.
- Do what l tell you. Understand?
- l understand.
l got problems
with the commission.
- l know.
- Yes. You don't make them easier.
l understand that.
lt wasn't my idea that this happened.
All right. Go on.
Get out of here.
Now they'll fear you.
Maybe they
should fear you.
BJ, excuse me.
What's up?
The archbishop just called back.
We've arranged
some amazing things for you.
The publicity is phenomenal.
You're the new Rockefeller,
a philanthropist.
- Sign right here, please.
- Times do change, don't they?
My father hated foundations.
He loved doing it
by himself, man to man.
But we're different, huh?
lt's no different than
any large corporation.
You control a lot of money
with very little...
minimize taxes...
with no government control.
Godfather?
Andrew.
- Godfather--
- Off to Rome.
l wanted to thank you
for all you've done for me.
- Want to have some breakfast with us?
- No, thanks. l can't.
How's your ltalian?
- His father was a great lawyer.
- l know.
Didn't live to see him ordained.
l did.
Did you ever see one of those?
Beautiful. l was so proud.
Let me walk you out.
Andrew, if you hear any rumors flying
around the Vatican, let me know.
No.
Andrew has the true faith.
Don Corleone...
l need your help.
And not just to light
a little candle.
My gift was to be able
to persuade people...
to give to the Holy Church.
Then Rome decides...
to put me in charge
of the Vatican Bank.
But l was never a true banker.
l trusted my friends.
Friendship and money...
oil and water.
lndeed.
But these friends used...
the good name of the Church...
to feed their greed.
lf money was lost...
then l am to blame.
Oh, if only prayer
could pay off...
our $ 700 million deficit.
769 million.
The Church owns 25%%
of a large corporation-- lmmobiliare.
You know the one l mean.
Largest landlord on earth, real estate
all over the world worth $6 billion.
That's true.
And the Vatican vote
is necessary for control.
No. No, no.
You're mistaken.
This isn't a question
of one person deciding--
one deciding vote.
This is like any other
company in the world.
We have directors. We have rules.
We have very old rules.
The pope himself would
have to approve you.
We've sold the casinos...
all businesses having to do
with gambling.
We have no interests
or investments...
in anything illegitimate.
The Corleones are prepared to deposit
$500 million in the Vatican Bank...
at such time as Mr. Corleone receives
majority control of lmmobiliare.
lmmobiliare
could be something new--
a European conglomerate.
Few families have control
of such a company.
lt seems in today's world...
the power to absolve debt
is greater...
than the power of forgiveness.
$600 million.
Don't overestimate
the power of forgiveness.
Don Corleone,
this deal with lmmobiliare...
can make you one of
the richest men in the world.
Your whole past history
and the history of your family...
will be washed away.
600 million.
[Keinszig]
The motion under discussion...
relates to Corleone Group's proposal...
to acquire 1 00 million...
newly issued class ''A '' voting shares.
Once issued, the shares will permit...
[B.J. Harrison]
Corleone's capital invested directly...
into International Immobiliare...
an old and respected
European company.
But Michael Corleone
has an ambitious program...
to expand this real estate
holding company...
into an international conglomerate
that can meet the challenge...
not by political ideologies...
but by Eastern
techniques of efficiency...
and focus...
- Mr. Corleone!
- and unlimited--
Mr. Corleone!
Excuse me.
lsn't it true that you deposited
$200 million in the Vatican Bank...
which is affiliated with
lnternational lmmobiliare?
- This is true. Why not?
- Wasn't there any questioning...
about the timing
on this particular deposit...
or wasn't there
some talk about...
- Mr. Chairman, if l may?
- the fact that--
The Vito Andolino Corleone Foundation...
of which Mr. Corleone's
daughter Mary is chairman...
has established an endowment
in the amount of $ 1 00 million.
The money comes from his own family...
and will be administered
by the Vatican.
Answer your question?
l have always believed...
helping your fellow man
is profitable in every sense--
personally and bottom-line.
My fellow shareholders,
if Europe and America...
can learn to cooperate...
if we can learn to pool our wealth,
share our markets...
we can defeat any competition...
anywhere in the world.
Thank you for the time
you've given me today...
and l hope that you
will look favorably on my proposal.
Thank you.
Listen, let me at
this microphone here!
How can we let that criminal
run our company?
He's got the map
of Sicily on his face.
- Order! Order!
- He's either Catholic or mafioso.
l say--
The Hamilton lnvestors Group
cannot support...
this proposal.
Your Excellency?
Mr. Chairman...
the Vatican Bank feels...
that lnternational lmmobiliare...
will be safe
in Mr. Corleone's hands.
Subject to audit
and final ratification...
which must
take place in Rome...
please join me in welcoming
Mr. Michael Corleone.
Dad?
Tony says that l'm a front
for the foundation...
that you're using me just to
pull the strings...
- to get the money where you want it.
- Come on. Please.
To shine up
your public image.
Mary, this is real,
this foundation.
lt's real.
l wanted Anthony
to be a part of it.
l thought you two
would be together on this.
l won't interfere.
l'll help only if you ask.
But what is this really for?
Why are you doing this?
Why am l doing this?
l'm doing this for my children.
You're doing it
for your children too.
This foundation is supposed
to help all people.
Of course.
That's the purpose.
This is legitimate, Mary.
l swear this is legitimate.
Dad, l want this to bring me
closer to you.
l would burn in hell...
to keep you safe.
No, no. You go in the other car.
l'll ride with Michael.
Go, go, go.
As your family's oldest friend...
l'm always chosen
to bring you messages.
Tell me, Don Altobello.
Your old partners are grateful
for the money you made them.
They worship you.
But their hearts are broken...
because they think
you abandoned them.
They want to share your deal
on lmmobiliare...
to be a family again.
lt can purify their money.
This l cannot do.
lmmobiliare must be legitimate.
l know.
But they're unhappy.
And you?
l ask nothing for myself.
Only peace in my old age.
But l must please
the world around me.
Michael, your father was
a reasonable man.
Learn from him.
l learned many things
from my father.
Call a meeting, my friend...
so there are no debts or grudges.
We will make the peace...
you and l.
They just had
a press conference.
They said the pope's
condition is grave--
gravissimo,
they said.
Please...
our group represents...
a consortium
of Catholic businessmen...
against the Corleone control.
The Vatican has cast its vote.
The Corleone Group
already controls the board.
According to the Lateran Treaty,
the Vatican's vote must be ratified...
here in Rome by the pope.
The pope is gravely ill.
Until he recovers...
l am powerless.
What if he dies?
Then...
as you Americans say,
all bets are off.
Gentlemen, please.
This is a brief delay...
nothing more.
Your Excellency, gentlemen...
l advise you join us
in our prayers...
for the Holy Father's recovery.
We had an agreement!
This meeting was to be merely
a formality. That's all it was.
-Please sit down.
-l'd rather stand. Could someone answer?
- We have put ourselves on the line--
- The lmmobiliare has its roots...
in the European tradition.
Please try to understand.
l understand.
Your tactics are despicable.
Well, that's quite an indictment,
coming from a Corleone.
Gentlemen!
Remember you're in the Vatican.
Please.
What is it that you want?
Yes.
You will take control.
We'll gladly put you at the helm
of our little fleet...
but our ships must all sail
in the same direction.
Otherwise...
who can say how long
your stay with us will last?
lt's not personal.
lt's only business.
You should know, Godfather.
Very well.
You want to do
business with me...
l will do business with you.
Vipers, all of them.
- We're back with the Borgias.
- Uncle Michael.
Andrew.
l heard you were here.
lt's so nice to see you.
- Vincent.
- How are you?
What is this with the Borgias?
Those days are over, Michael.
- Recognize it?
- Yeah.
Genco Olive Oil.
That's where our grandfather
got his start...
as a delivery boy making
three bucks a week.
Three years later,
he owned the company.
- Only in America.
- That's it.
Vincenzo, where have you been hiding?
You deserted us
when we need your help.
What can l do?
Get rid of Joe Zasa.
He sells drugs to children.
When l was a girl, it was different.
l'm an older woman...
afraid to walk the streets
at night.
Where are they supposed to be at?
- Lou, what's going on?
- He's going pazzo.
- We're late.
- Don't tell me that garbage.
- Have l ever let you down?
- l trust you.
- Don't worry about it.
- Thank you very much.
Enjoy yourself.
What was that?
Neighborhood's in trouble.
- You're keeping your eye out for them?
- That's right.
- And for me?
- From now on.
l missed you all this time.
l missed you, too, cousin.
l missed growing up
with all my cousins.
l didn't know you,
and l missed you.
Do you remember stories
about our fathers, the old days?
Yeah. What do you
want to know?
What was Sonny like?
He was the prince of the city.
He died before l was born, but l heard
a million stories. He was a legend.
What about my father?
A great man, your father.
He's a hero.
He saved the family.
- Vincent.
- What?
Did he kill
his own brother?
So those are all lies?
Just stories, sweetheart.
l believe you.
- l'm glad you're around.
- l'm glad you're here too.
l'd like to take Joey Zasa up
for a ride in this and drop him.
Joey Zasa is nothing.
He's a small-time enforcer.
He bluffs, threats, but nothing.
You'll be able to see him coming
a mile away.
We should kill him
before he kills--
Never hate your enemies.
lt affects your judgment.
Good evening.
Nice to see you again, Mr. Corleone.
Okay, girls, let's go.
Come on, girls.
We trusted you to manage
our money in the casinos.
lt's not even 20 years...
you sold the casinos
and you made fortunes for all of us.
Bravo, Don Corleone!
Thank you.
Friends, l have come here...
because our business
together is done.
We have prospered,
and now it is time for us...
to dissolve the business
relationship between us.
That's it.
But l do have
a little surprise. Al?
Your shares in the casino.
l thought l'd cut through
all the red tape...
so you can get
your money right away.
- $50 million!
- Not everybody gets the same.
- lt depends on how much...
- Nothing for you.
you invested and how long for.
Michael,
this is really generous!
Oh, wonderful.
- Hey, Parisi, how much did you invest?
- l don't remember.
Michael, you're blessed.
My family has done
much of the hard work...
taken many risks...
all to make money
for the rest of the families.
You all know Joey Zasa.
He is, l admit, an important man.
His picture is on the cover
of the New York Times Magazine.
He gets the Esquire magazine award...
for the best-dressed gangster.
The newspapers praise him...
because he hires blacks
into his family...
which shows he has a good heart.
He is famous.
Who knows?
Maybe one day...
he will make all of you popular.
lt's true.
l make more of a bella figura.
That is my nature.
But l also want to make a move
into legitimate enterprises.
l'd like to get a little pin
from the pope.
Sure, l take the blacks and the Spanish
into my family...
because that's America.
And you guarantee that they don't
deal drugs in those neighborhoods.
l don't guarantee that.
l guarantee l'll kill anybody who does.
Let me talk to him.
Who can refuse Don Altobello?
l say to all of you,
l have been treated this day...
with no respect.
l've earned you all money.
l've made you rich...
and l asked for little.
Good. You will not give?
l'll take.
As for Don Corleone...
well, he makes it
very clear to me today...
that he is my enemy.
You must choose between us.
We can reason together.
Please, let's agree, huh?
He doesn't know what he's--
The news is everywhere.
Everyone is saying
that you control lmmobiliare.
lmmobiliare already is laundering money
in Peru and Nassau.
We know that.
Listen to me. We've been
friends for 40 years.
We should wet
our beaks a little, huh?
- We want to do business with you.
- That's right.
- We've been together too much.
- We can wash our money clean...
in the holy water of--
What the hell is that?
- lt's a hit. Let's go. Follow me.
- Let's get outta here!
- My coat! lt's my lucky coat!
- Forget your coat.
lt's my lucky coat!
Stay right behind me!
- Fuck!
- Mikey, this way!
You son of a bitch.
Come on, we're outta here.
You did good.
The old Dons were pretty much
wiped out.
The ones that survived
made deals with Joey Zasa.
He survived. He's with his daughters
now in Staten lsland.
Says he's gonna retire to Sicily.
Joey Zasa would never pull something
like this without the backing.
He's just muscle.
He's an enforcer. He's nothing.
He doesn't have the wit
for that helicopter attack.
He doesn't even have the ambition
to wipe out the whole commission.
- Certainly not the balls.
- l say we hit back and take Zasa out!
Never let anyone know
what you're thinking.
Well, let's get a message
to Joey Zasa.
l respect what he's done.
The new overthrows the old.
lt's natural.
How can you do business
with this guy?
l'm a businessman, first and foremost.
l want no further conflict with him.
You tell him from me
that he can live or he can die.
Vincent, will you shut up!
That's it.
He can't be doing this alone.
Just when l thought l was out,
they pull me back in.
Our true enemy...
has not yet shown his face.
- Has he had his medicine?
- l don't know what he took.
- l got my wind back.
- Call a doctor.
Run, run!
Run at thunderbolt.
Thunder can't hurt.
Harmless noise.
- Get an ambulance.
- Bullshit!
You deceitful old fuck.
Altobello, you fuck!
Vitals are all steady.
Lift.
Oh, God.
- Okay, okay.
- Dad.
Excuse me. Clear, please.
l'll call Kay.
- Good evening, sir.
- Can we wait here? l'll be right back.
Certainly, sir.
Mr. Harrison,
you said it was urgent.
Have you come to confess your sins?
Michael Corleone suffered
a diabetic stroke.
l thought you should know that
before you read it in the papers.
He's in a coma
on the critical list.
l'm here to insist
the deal goes through in any event.
The pope has not much time left.
So, as you,
l am in a difficult position.
We have to ratify this deal
as soon as possible.
We have an understanding.
Good. l'm going to the hospital.
- l'll pray for Mr. Corleone.
- Thank you.
Our thoughts are with Mr. Corleone.
Thank you, Father.
Everything will be out in the open
if Corleone dies.
Pray for time, Keinszig.
A habit born of...
a long contemplation of eternity.
-Just forget about it, Vinnie.
-Why forget about it? lt's a simple hit.
Look, l'd love to smack Joey Zasa
then whack the fag, okay?
But it's impossible.
He's always mingling with people...
in front of TV cameras
in his own neighborhood.
- lt's impossible.
- lt's not. lt'll work for us.
How?
You think he's gonna let Uncle Michael
survive this thing? Would you?
He may not survive anyway.
How would you do it?
l'd do it.
l'd do it myself.
Do it!
- What would you need?
- See if you can get me a couple guys.
lt's Kay.
l never expected you to come.
No, l know, l know.
But l'm here.
- l'm glad.
- You know...
this is the first time
l've seen you look so helpless.
lt's not so bad, really.
l feel...
l'm getting wiser now.
- Yeah?
- Oh, yeah.
The sicker you get,
the wiser you get, huh?
When l'm dead,
l'm gonna be really smart.
- Yeah?
- l want to thank you for Tony.
He's doing really well.
He's gotten some very good notices...
and he's going to be making
his operatic debut in Sicily...
in Palermo, this Easter.
So, thank you.
That's a real honor.
ln Sicily.
l will be there.
l won't miss that.
Go see Dad.
- Oh, sweetheart.
- Everything's gonna be all right.
- How you doing, Papa?
- Come here.
Your mother told me.
She told me what happened.
About Palermo?
l really want you to be there, Dad.
Of course. Come here, kiss me.
- Cousin Vinnie?
- No, he isn't here.
Why don't you call his apartment,
leave a message on his machine?
- lt's your cousin, Mary.
- Let her in.
- Thanks. Hi, cous.
- Hi.
l just thought l'd drop by.
ls that okay?
l'm gonna get the guys.
No, it's not okay.
You shouldn't have come.
A couple minutes only, okay?
- You look beautiful, cous.
- Thanks.
So this is your club,
your hideout?
- Yeah.
- l came here to check it out.
lt's so strange, just me
and Aunt Connie in the house.
l feel better when l'm with you.
What's wrong, sweetheart?
- l'm really scared about my father.
- Don't be scared.
When l saw them take him out of
that ambulance, l thought he was dead.
l know.
Everybody says he's gonna be better.
Don't worry, okay?
l remember them shooting at our house
when l was little.
And Al Neri came one time
with other bodyguards...
and just took me and Tony away.
ls it all happening again?
Not like that, sweetie.
Then why are you hiding here?
ls something going to happen to you?
Nothing's gonna happen to me.
l'll take care of you.
- Can l stay here and hide out with you?
- You have to make gnocchi for the boys.
You know l don't know how to cook,
but l'll help.
Okay.
What do l do?
- l love you, cous.
- l love you, too, cous.
Okay, let's cook.
Hold me.
You know, the people like you,
the press, the police...
you use words like ''Mafia,''
''Cosa Nostra.''
This is a fantasy.
The ltalian-Americans are great people.
We laid the bricks that built
this city. We have the artists.
We have Meucci.
He invented the telephone.
We have Don Ameche who played the guy
who invented the telephone. Huh?
So, listen, buy yourself
a nice raffle ticket.
Maybe win yourself a Cadillac.
The salciccia is wonderful.
Here, have a sandwich.
Let's go.
Nice to see you, Mr. Zasa.
Have a nice time.
Don't forget to buy
your raffle tickets, huh?
What are you doin'?
- He's sorry. Come here, son.
- Okay, let's go.
What's what?
How are you?
How are you, buddy boy, huh?
Up your ass!
- Who is that, huh? You know him?
- lgnore him.
Hey,Joey, who's gonna win the car?
The Ant?
This is the thing that gives
the ltalian-Americans a bad name, huh?
A cappone like this, huh?
Hey,Joey, up your ass!
Get off of that fuckin' car.
You got a raffle ticket?
Take a good look
at my raffle ticket here.
Here's what l think of you
and your raffle ticket.
l told you,
get the fuck outta here, punk.
l'll break your fuckin' arm.
l want you to get the fuck outta here.
Get outta here.
Run,Joey, you piece of shit!
- Open the door! Open the door!
- Hi,Joe.
Don't ever again give
that kind of order.
Not while l'm alive.
Understand?
You were too sick to make a decision.
l got a go-ahead from Neri.
l got a go-ahead from Connie.
lt was the right decision,
Uncle Michael.
lt was the wrong decision.
l command this family.
Right or wrong...
it was not what l wanted!
Do you understand?
Yes.
Come on, Michael.
Yes!
Good.
Help me to my bed. l wanna
talk to you alone for a minute.
You know, l always felt
responsible for you.
You know that.
Your father-- my brother--
we were opposites.
We would fight and argue...
but l never doubted his love.
He would do anything for me.
But his temper...
it was too much.
Clouded his reason.
l don't want you to make
that mistake.
Also...
he, too, had a way with women.
- So l hear.
- What are you doing with my daughter?
What are you doing with her?
lt's too dangerous.
You hear me?
When they come...
they'll come at what you love.
Michael, you must lead
another life.
You have everything a man could desire.
lt's time for you to retire.
l have too much responsibility.
Too difficult now.
You should really get out.
What do you know
about those pezzonovante in ltaly?
l'm too old to know anything
about those new people.
l must accept my age
and grow my olives and tomatoes.
- We're not that old.
- But you're very ill.
Let me see what can be done.
Let me work to make your path
a little easier.
Your friendship does that always.
That makes me happy.
You were wrong about him.
l trust too much.
That's always been my fault.
Treachery is everywhere.
You still have your fingers
on the strings, even now.
Let's see more of each other.
- In Sicily?
- In Sicily.
How are you?
Don Bendino, my old friend.
l wanted to bring you here...
so that my old friend and protector,
Don Tommasino...
could advise us.
The bloodbath in Atlantic City
left New York a mess.
Now,Joey Zasa at least was running
a fairly tight ship.
But now that he's out of the picture,
we're obligated to step in.
Step back in?
lf we don't,
the Chinese and Colombians will.
Our ships must all sail
in the same direction.
ltalian politics have had
these kind of men for centuries.
They are the true Mafia.
The archbishop and the Vatican Bank,
that's the big problem.
They're the same problem.
BJ, they're connected.
The archbishop has
very powerful friends.
They totally protect him.
l will go see
this Cardinal Lamberto...
and see if we can work things out
in a civilized way.
You honor your agreements...
but these people
you're dealing with are crooks.
They have no honor.
My word is final.
l've invited you all here...
to celebrate my son's
first appearance in an opera house.
- We're playing Philadelphia.
- He'll be appearing...
- What's Philadelphia?
- in about three weeks...
Seven cards, two down,
four up, one down...
- at the Theatre Massimo...
- deuces and one-eyed jacks are wild.
in the opera ''Cavallaria''Rusticana.
lt's Cavalleria Rusticana.
l think l got tickets
to the wrong opera.
l've been in New York too long.
Anyway...
you will all receive tickets,
so come on time.
Dad, l've got a present for you.
lt comes from the town of Corleone...
and it's authentic Sicilian.
And l learned it for you.
She was wonderful, beautiful,
and I loved her.
Then she died.
My trusted bodyguard...
planted a bomb in my car.
She drove it before l did.
Why is such a beautiful country
so violent?
History.
Mom was telling me about the old days.
- Your biggest worry was passing exams.
- Yes, it was then.
l worry about you now.
Mary, you're such a warmhearted girl.
You always were.
- l love my family.
- Even your cousin Vincent?
l really love him.
- He's your first cousin.
- Then l love him first.
Mary, you can't see him.
Just don't see him anymore.
He's right.
lt's too dangerous.
Listen to me.
You can't see him anymore.
- Not in that fashion.
- No.
Please, promise me.
- Obey me on this.
- No, Dad!
Mary's smart, Dad.
She'll understand eventually.
- You wanted to see me?
- Yeah.
- l want you to do something for me.
- Okay.
lt's dangerous.
Good, l'm in.
What do you need?
l want you to sell your soul
to Don Altobello...
to betray me.
He'd never believe me.
Here.
- That depends.
- Sit down.
l have an idea.
See if you can learn
how high Altobello is connected.
Arrange a meeting.
You say how devoted you are to me.
Tell him your problems.
- You ask for his help.
- What problems?
That you want to run away
with my daughter.
Only you know that if you do,
l will become your enemy.
You know l would never do that,
Uncle Mike.
l know.
You ask Altobello to speak to me...
to further the marriage.
But you're cousins, after all.
Michael was always
a little old-fashioned.
Explain to him how...
you could never be a part
of my legitimate world...
that you want your own family.
l could straighten out
what Zasa left behind.
l could use your friendship
to persuade him.
l would be indebted to you forever.
Corleones know the value
of such a friend.
So then you would work for me?
Remember...
if he hints that he wants you
to betray me, get insulted...
because that's his trap.
You're not telling me
the whole truth.
lsn't it true, with Michael gone...
the girl controls everything?
You leave the girl out of this.
Of course, you love her,
and she loves you.
l guessed it, huh?
You're a wise man, Don Altobello.
l'm gonna be learning a lot
from you.
The richest man is the one
with the most powerful friends.
lt's my duty to make
the introductions.
Don Lucchesi.
Don Altobello tells me
you have a good character...
strong,
a man of respect.
This is the hero
who put Joey Zasa in his grave.
lf we'd have known of his existence,
we would never have backed Joey.
No one wants another Joe.
Let me be your friend.
Even the strongest man needs friends.
l'm flattered.
You're a man of finance and politics,
Don Lucchesi.
These are things l don't understand.
You understand guns.
Finance is a gun.
Politics is knowing
when to pull the trigger.
How can l help?
Blessed is the peacemaker...
for he can be called
the child of God.
l trusted this business arrangement
with the archbishop.
l trusted him. l was sure
his honesty was beyond a doubt.
But, as you see,
l'm now the victim of a swindle.
He's stalling me.
Vast money have gone to the pezzonovante
in high political places...
and the Vatican Bank
is the guarantor.
lf what you say is true,
there will be a great scandal.
Look at this stone. lt has been lying
in the water for a very long time...
but the water has not penetrated it.
Look, perfectly dry.
The same thing has happened
to men in Europe.
For centuries, they have been
surrounded by Christianity...
but Christ has not penetrated.
Christ doesn't live within them.
- What's happening?
- ls it possible...
that you could get me something sweet.
Orange juice, anything, a candy.
l have a little trouble with diabetes.
Blood sugar goes low.
l understand.
When l'm under stress,
sometimes this happens.
l understand.
To come to you
on such a delicate matter...
accusations against your archbishop.
lt was difficult for me.
The mind suffers...
and the body cries out.
That's true.
Would you like to make
your confession?
Your Eminence, l'm--
lt's been so long.
l wouldn't know where to--
lt's been 30 years.
l'd use up too much of your time,
l think.
l always have time to save souls.
Well, l'm beyond redemption.
l hear the confessions
of my own priests here.
Sometimes the desire to confess
is overwhelming...
and we must seize the moment.
What is the point of confessing
if l don't repent?
l hear you are a practical man.
What have you got to lose, huh?
Go on.
l...
betrayed my wife.
Go on, my son.
l betrayed myself.
l killed men.
And l ordered men to be killed.
Go on, my son, go on.
lt's useless.
Go on, my son.
l killed--
l ordered the death of my brother.
He injured me.
l killed my mother's son.
l killed my father's son.
Your sins are terrible...
and it is just
that you suffer.
Your life could be redeemed...
but l know
that you don't believe that.
You will not change.
All my life
l kept trying to go up in society...
where everything higher up
was legal, straight.
But the higher l go,
the more crooked it becomes.
Where the hell does it end?
Killing each other
for centuries here.
For money, for pride, for family.
To keep from becoming the slaves
of the rich pezzonovante.
l made confession, Connie.
l confessed my sins.
Why, Michael?
That's not like you.
You don't have to confess your sins
to a stranger.
lt was the man.
A good man...
a true priest.
He can change things.
You know...
sometimes l think of poor Fredo--
drowned.
lt was God's will.
lt was a terrible accident.
But it's finished.
Michael, l love you.
l'll always help you.
lt's okay.
- Welcome.
- How are you?
- Mary, l missed you.
- l missed you too.
- Hello, Michael.
- Hello.
- Mom, look at this.
- What?
Oh, my--
You know, it's too bad
that Douglas couldn't be with us.
No, l know. He wanted to come very much,
but he had a very important trial.
- l know he wanted to come.
- l know.
- The car is--
- Okay.
Well, your son's an artist, huh?
Oh, yes, thanks to you.
Oh, what for?
For making me let him go.
Oh, well.
After all these years, here l am
in Sicily for the first time.
- l want a picture of you together.
- Okay.
Hey, Dad, smile.
l see you still have Al Neri.
Why?
Well, l need him. He helps me
get in and out of the car.
He carries my briefcase.
You're still a liar, Michael.
Let me show you Sicily--
the real Sicily.
Maybe you'll understand
the family history a little better.
l think l understand it well enough.
Anthony, l have something
you made for me...
a very long time ago.
- To bring you luck.
- Thanks.
You saved it, huh?
- Remember?
- l remember.
Thank you.
Proud of you.
- Are they as good as they look?
- They're better.
They're the best.
As long as they're around,
Uncle Michael is safe.
Good-bye.
Tell your father
l'll be back for dinner.
- Have fun.
- Tell Tony to be sure and wait for me.
Okay, l will.
Bye, Mom!
At your service.
lf l see Dad,
l'll tell him you left.
You're the only one left in this family
with my father's strength.
lf anything happens to Michael,
l want you to strike back.
l'll have everything ready.
You swear?
l swear to you.
Here it is.
The house where my father was born.
This is where they came to take him
when he was a boy...
to kill him.
Wait, listen to that.
You know, Mary's in love.
Yes, l know.
With a handsome young ltalian man
with dark eyes.
l won't allow it.
lt's wrong.
lt's wrong, and it's dangerous.
Honor, huh?
You know, l remember the time
you came to my parents' house...
and you took me into that room
and told me about the family business...
and how you were never going to have
anything to do with it.
You sounded like Tony.
l was a lot like Tony.
- l can barely see. Kay.
- What?
- You mind driving?
- No. What's wrong?
My eyes-- sometimes
they're all right, and then--
- Sure.
- Listen, l have to see Don Tommasino.
Oh, my God!
Well--
- There's no bodyguards today.
- l really snuck away.
- How are you?
- Hi.
- Kay, this is Calo, my old friend.
- How do you do?
One of my bodyguards
in the old days.
- We can wait here.
- You want drink?
- Yes. Shall we go in?
- Sure.
l spent a lot of time in this room...
thinking of you.
And then you got married.
l still thought of you.
What's in that room?
l know this is dangerous for you.
This is Sicily.
- l love this country.
- Why?
Well, all through history...
terrible things
have happened to these people.
Terrible injustices.
But they still expect good
rather than bad will happen to them.
Sort of like me and you, huh?
- How so?
- l'm still here, right?
We do have a bad history.
- l'm still here.
- Yes, you are, but with dread.
Give me the order. Come on.
What is that supposed to do? ls that
supposed to make me not dread you?
We're in Sicily. lt's opera.
Okay.
What do we do now?
Be reasonable.
Let's try not to hurt each other.
l want you to forgive me.
For what?
Everything.
Like God, huh?
l need something a little closer.
You couldn't understand
back in those days...
l loved my father.
l swore l would never be
a man like him...
but l loved him,
and he was in danger.
What could l do?
And then later
you were in danger.
Our children were in danger.
What could l do?
You were all that l... loved...
valued most in the world.
And now l'm losing you.
l lost you anyway.
You're gone...
and it was all for nothing.
So--
You have to understand...
l had a whole different
destiny planned.
All right, l'll stop.
l really don't know what you want
from me, Michael. l really don't know.
- l mean--
- l'm not the man that you think l am?
- l don't know.
- l love you, Kay.
Don't dread me anymore.
You know...
every night here in Sicily...
l dream...
about my wife
and my children...
and how l lost them.
l guess, if it's any consolation...
l want you to know that...
that...
l always loved you, Michael.
And, you know...
l always will.
lt never ends.
Frederick Keinszig...
known for a decade as ''God's banker''...
has been reported missing.
He was last seen three days ago...
leaving the Rome offices...
of a Vatican-owned corporation,
International Immobiliare.
Also missing was a large sum of money...
and several documents.
Come on, Keinszig, you fool.
Mr. Keinszig's absence casts
further suspicion...
on the dealings
of the Vatican Bank.
For several years, the bank
and its subsidiary companies...
have been the object of allegations
of disreputable business practices.
Will you please try and understand?
l have phoned him.
l have waited here by the phone.
You would do well to remember,
Mr. Lucchesi...
that this pope
has very different ideas...
from the last one.
Good-bye, my old friend.
You could've lived
a little longer.
l could be closer to my dream.
You were so loved, Don Tommasino.
Why was l so feared,
and you were so loved?
What was it?
l was no less honorable.
l wanted to do good.
What betrayed me?
My mind? My heart?
Why do l condemn myself so?
l swear on the lives of my children...
give me a chance
to redeem myself...
and l will sin no more.
You look pale.
Bad news? Tell me right away.
lt's not just a bad banking deal.
These guys are butchers.
What guys?
Lucchesi--
he controls all of them.
Altobello, the archbishop...
other people higher up,
P2, maybe.
Secret, unknown.
They're running things.
- l'm in their way.
- Yeah.
He's hired a professional assassin
to kill you.
He's Sicilian.
l don't know his name,
but they say he never fails.
Then no one is safe.
Even the new pope
is in danger.
We still have time.
We can prevent this.
l tried.
l tried to keep everything
from coming to this.
But it's not possible,
not in this world.
Give me the order.
You won't be able to go back.
- You'll be like me.
- Good.
All my life l wanted out.
l wanted the family out.
Well, l don't want out.
l want the power
to preserve the family.
l'm asking for the order.
lt's done.
Because l can't do it anymore.
Well, it doesn't matter.
Vincent knows what to do.
Come on outside.
Take a rest
and don't think about it.
- All l do is think about it.
- l'm your son.
Command me in all things.
Give up my daughter.
That's the price you pay...
for the life you choose.
Nephew...
from this moment on...
call yourself Vincent Corleone.
Sit.
l know how you feel about Michael...
but you can't save him.
He's lost.
Think of yourself.
What's your answer?
Enjoy the opera.
lt's all taken care of.
Check the bar.
l'll check the top floor.
''Here's hoping Tony sings better
at the Theatro Massimo...
than he does in the shower--
Love, Douglas.''
My darling, Costanza.
- This is a great occasion.
- Come, sit down.
Happy birthday.
You're 80 years old,
you don't look more than 60.
You're the only one
who remembered.
Michael, we just got the word.
The pope's ratifying
the lmmobiliare deal. We've won.
Congratulations.
How strange, the way things work.
The pope's doing exactly what you said
he'd do. He's cleaning house.
He should be careful.
lt's dangerous to be an honest man.
l wanna put more muscle backstage
with Tony.
On your birthday,
you used to shower me with treats.
Tootsie Rolls.
The nuns who made these cannolis
took a vow of silence.
They're the very finest.
Hey, cous.
Where's your leather?
Stop it.
You're so thin.
You eat it.
lt's over. There are things l have to do
that you can't be a part of.
Don't look at your father. lt's not
your father's decision. lt's mine.
Don't hate your father.
There are things l wanna be a part of,
you can't be around.
After tonight,
you won't see me anymore.
You gotta understand.
l'll always love you.
Love somebody else.
- To Tony.
- They won't try.anything.
- Yeah, everything is fine. lt's clear.
l've already sent Al Neri
to the Vatican.
Check out the side.
Good. You got him.
Tonight the Corleone family
settles its accounts.
Keinszig...
that little Swiss banker fuck.
He's been swindling everyone
from the beginning. Fuck him.
Don Lucchesi, my friend...
Calo will pay him a visit
at his home.
Neri, take a train to Rome.
Light a candle
for the archbishop.
Michael, it's serious.
Our man inside the Vatican says...
there's a plot
against the pope.
You mean, he's gonna have
a heart attack?
This pope has powerful enemies.
We may not be in time to save him.
Let's go back to the opera.
Sleep.
Sleep, Godfather.
- l like this outfit.
- Yeah, l figured you would.
- Bravo. Say hello.
- Thank you.
- Did you like it?
- Great.
Let's get out of here.
- Can l please talk to you now?
- Not now, it's not a good time.
- You're just like my father.
- Come on, stay with the family. Go on.
- Talk to me.
- The twins are dead.
ln about one minute, there's gonna be
carabinieri crawling all over the place.
Okay. Let's get everybody
to the cars, nice and quiet.
- Got it.
- Quiet.
When they hear the name Corleone,
they're gonna think of a voice.
Dad.
This is my mom.
Dad, why are you doing this to me?
- Go on, move back. Go on, move back.
- Hey, move!
- You don't have to do this to me.
- Doing what?
What do you mean?
Mary, will you please--
Dad--
- Maybe she's not dead.
- Oh, God!
God, no, please!
Mom, come on.
Let her go.
Let go.