## [Woman Singing "A ve Maria'"In Latin]
[Whirring]
## [Continues]
[Rhythmic Chanting]
## [Ends]
[Thunder Rumbling]
- Fuck!  - It's not there.
- [Gun Cocks]  - It's in the kitchen where you left it.
How'd you get in?
You have a nice family.
They're fiine. Alive.
Asleep.
- Are you gonna kill me?  - If I was gonna kill you...
I'd have done it when you walked  to the car this morning-
been gone by the time  your body hit the sidewalk.
- Then why are you here?  - To talk.
But, Mike, if you make me kill you,  you will not go alone.
Sit.
Are you a good man, Inspector?
- I think.  - And yet you've killed men.
- Yes.  - I'm gonna ask you a question.
How you answer it  will determine how this night ends.
How does a good man  decide when to kill?
The man you've been chasing  is a killer, a ghost.
Rumor has it that he works for a group  known only as "the organization. '"
So secret, no one knows it exists.
It takes no sides,  yet it has ties to every government.
Its sole purpose is  the training and conditioning...
of professional killers.
These men are selected at birth-
- rejects, orphans-  - [Beeping]
All of them unwanted and disposable.
They are made experts  in every aspect of combat...
and programmed for one purpose: ;
to kill.
The man you have been chasing  for the last three years, Inspector...
is the very best of them.
- [Man Shrieks]  - Put him there.
[Panting, Groaning]
You shouldn't have  stolen from me, Brother.
Now you must pay.
- [Mocking Whine]  - [Groaning, Panting]
[Shouts]
[Screams]
Why you do that kind of thing?
[Groaning]
Still waiting.
[Gravelly]  I'm sorry.
What happened to his voice?
He made me swallow.
What did you do to his voice?
Nothing, Ovie.  Exactly as he was delivered.
Delivered?
- [Grunts]  - You didn't fiind him?
No. A contractor.  An American.
Swallow what?
- [Over Earphone] Swallow what?  - A bomb.
A bomb. A bomb.
Run!
[Rooster Crowing]
We have all heard your theories, Inspector.
This isn't a theory.
This is our guy-  no motive, no forensic evidence, no witnesses.
He's a- He's a ghost.
And how long have you been  chasing this "ghost"?
Three years.
Well, thank goodness you have Interpol  to fiinance your persistence, huh?
You see, Inspector,  despite being the anus of the third world...
we attempt to have  competent police work here.
And it is our belief that Bwana Ovie  was killed by his own brother.
Oh, so he choked down  a pound of C-4...
and knocked on Ovie's door?
Probably.
General, this man truly is  the best at what he does.
He is likely responsible  for over 100 deaths.
Let me show you what I mean.
This is Ovie.
And these arejust  the ones we know about.
Are you beginning  to get the picture?
They might kill you for that.
For what you're doing to that whiskey-  brutalizing it with ice.
But never more than two cubes.  It waters down the scotch.
- Oh.  - L-I'm sorry.
Aftermath of my pretentious  ex-husband, I'm afraid.
No.
I'm June. And you are?
This is where you tell me your name.
Excuse me.
[Woman Laughing]
[Electronic Beeping]
[Water Running]
[Beeping]
[Electronic Female Voice]  Africa job complete.
The money has been wired  to your account.
Nice work. Regrettably,  the next target date...
has been moved up  at the client's request.
And the client wishes it  to be public.
I've planned  something more... subtle.
I've made preparations.
Incumbent Russian president  Mikhail Belicoff s...
recent political shift  is in direct conflict...
with our client's interests and threatens  their control of the Russian government.
The client needs it to be public.
Do you accept the new parameters?
- Yes.  - We appreciate you breaking your normal protocol.
The specifiics are being uploaded.
[Applause]
I, for one, will not let  their cowardice deter me.
[Applause Continues]
[Crowd Chanting]  Belicoff! Belicoff! Belicoff!
[Chanting Continues]
[Cheering]
Mr. Belicoff? I'm sorry.  In light of your political positions...
do you think the hard-liners  will continue to support your reelection?
One only needs to look at-
[Screaming, Clamoring]
[Screaming, Clamoring Continue]
[Cell Phone Ringing]
[Electronic Female Voice] We have a problem.  There was a witness in Saint Petersburg.
How reliable are your sources?
Impeccable, as always.
Interpol has arranged a pickup.
- Will you intercept?  - Yes.
Uploading data.
[Man Speaking Russian]
[Chuckles]
[Woman Screams]
[Gunshots]
[Screaming, Clamoring]
I can't be sure.
He never works again so quickly.
But the Russians say that Belicoff  was grazed by a single bullet...
from over four kilometers away.
- [Man On Phone, Indistinct]  - But it defiinitely sounds like him.
Yes, sir.
Well, what bothers me  is that he missed.
Yes, sir.  I know what this investigation has cost.
L- I understand.
- I just need a little more time.  - Sir, you need to see this.
Sorry, sir.  I'm gonna have to call you back.
[Cell Phone Beeps]
Okay.
- He shoots the bodyguard  to get a clean shot at Belicoff.  - [Gunshot Rings Out]
Yeah. He splits these two civilians  by a couple of inches. Keep watching.
Keep an eye on the bodyguard.  See that?
Back it up.  Back it up again.
That's an awful lot  of arterial spray for a miss.
Sir, you have call.
- This is Whittier.  - [Man] Sir, they found Belicoff s shooter.
- They found him?  - Yes. Tip from a hotel concierge.
- Concierge where?  - Grand Hotel.
- They recognized him from a picture.  - A picture?
- Where the hell did they get a picture?  - I don't know, sir.
All right.  I'm on my way.
They found him.
Contact the Russian Secret Police  in Saint Petersburg...
and tell them Interpol has jurisdiction.
They're to keep him under surveillance only.  No one moves until we get there. No one!
[Electronic Female Voice]  Was the target not at the location?
[Man] The girl was there, but she was no witness.  She'd never seen me before.
[Electronic Female Voice]  We will be unable to transmit payment...
for the Belicoff assignment  as the task was not completed.
No. He took a direct hit through the nasal cavity.  I watched it myself.
[Electronic Female Voice]  Please wait.
Uploading live news feed.
The West, so afraid of my message...
that cowardly violence  is their only response.
- [Applauding]  - And that was the scene  outside of Saint Petersburg.
Who was the client?
Answer me!
Who ordered the hit on Belicoff?
If you set me up, I will fiind you...
and I will burn that building  to the ground around you.
Mike Whittier, Interpol.
What's the status of my suspect?
I was told you were coming, Inspector.
I am Captain Gudnayev,  Saint Petersburg Militsiya.
Please, make yourself comfortable.
- My men are almost in position.  - In position for what?
We have been informed that  the suspect intends to flee.
- My orders are to seek-  - Whoa, whoa, whoa. Orders? Orders from who?
- Interpol has jurisdiction here.  - Militsiya's only responsible for the extraction.
Captain Gudnayev is not directing this operation,  I'm afraid, Inspector. I am.
I'm Chief Agent Yuri Marklov  of the F.S.B.
The F.S.B. Why the hell...
is the Russian Secret Police  involved in this?
- [Speaking Russian]  - [Woman Speaking Russian]
- They're going in.  - I advise you to get your men out of there.
You have no idea  who you're dealing with.
I assure you, these men are capable  ofhandling this situation.
[Speaking Russian]  Shoot on sight.
- [Speaking Russian]  - Do not give that order!
[Speaking Russian]
[Phone Ringing]
[Woman]  47, it's Diana.
I could be retired  for contacting you directly.
The client was Belicoff.
Your location has been compromised.
[Beads Shatter]
[Electronic Beeping]
[Electronic Hum]
Come on.
[Hammers Cock]
[Speaking Russian]
[Woman Speaks Russian]
[Walkie-talkie: ; Man Speaks Russian]
[Alarm Ringing]
Stay here. Cover the elevator.  Call me on my cell and tell me where it stops.
[Elevator Dings]
[Speaking Russian]
[All Screaming]
[Alarm Continues]
[Elevator Dings]
[Dings]
- [Cell Phone Rings]  - [Alarm Blaring]
- Yeah.  - I've got fiive dead bodies in the lift, sir.
- None of them our boy.  - [Dinging]
He's on the third floor, sir! He must have  opened the doors from inside the shaft!
Freeze!
[Alarm Continues]
Get down!
[Speaking Russian]
- Get down!  - [Speaking Russian]
[Gasps]
- [Grunts]  - [Shooting]
Fuck!
Sir?
We had him.
[Speaking Russian]
- How many men did you lose?  - Sixteen dead.
No! No, no.  Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait! Don't touch that!
[Sighs]  Where'd you get your fucking license?
I need the room, Captain.
[Speaking Russian]
[Siren Wailing]
Where does he get all this stuff?
Can you make it work?
Probably. Why?
I've been looking  for you, Inspector.
I think we started off  on the wrong foot.
Who informed you  of the whereabouts of my guy?
I believe it's time  we had a chat, you and I.
Jenkins.
Yes, sir.
[Speaking Russian]
This, uh, assassin-
my associates tell me  you believe him to be freelance.
Your associates tell you that?
You do not believe he is connected  with Central Intelligence Agency?
Why do you ask?
No reason. It just seems a bit naive.  [Chuckles]
Well, it's a theory.
Yes, a theory.  But a theory shared by Moscow.
In accordance with Article 1764.3  of the E.U. Charter...
any state matters which deal  directly with intelligence...
shall be the sole jurisdiction  of the host country.
Ah, and the lightbulb comes on.
Took me a minute.  Must be the jet lag.
You're telling me to fuck off?
[Chuckling] No, no. Of course not.  You are a good man, Michael.
One of Interpol's best.
But leave this intelligence work  to the F.S.B.
And Belicoff?
I'm sorry?
You know, there's two things  wrong with this photograph.
One, the footage  has been tampered with.
Someone inserted that civilian  to cover up what actually happened.
Hmm.
- And the second thing?  - My boy doesn't miss.
[Buzzes]
[Speaking Russian]
- Delivery.  - You're supposed to leave those at the desk.
Mr. Belicoff sent them.
[Gasping]
Make a sound, I'll end your life.  You understand?
Who else is inside?
I know you-  from the street earlier today.
- You're coming with me.  - I can't!
Okay, okay!  I'll get my coat.
[Speaking Russian]
- Where are you taking me?  - Somewhere safe.
- Get in.  - Fuck you! I'm not getting in there!
Aaah! There's a dead man in there!
[Shouting In Russian]
Get me out of this car!
Are you going to kill me?
I'm gonna ask you some questions.
Before today on the street,  have you ever seen me?
- Why were you there?  - My boyfriend.
- He told me to meet his driver on that corner.  - Belicoff?
How, after I put  a bullet through his head...
was he able to give  that speech this afternoon?
Then you're of no use to me.
[Gasps]  Wait! Wait! There is something.
D-Doubles. Doubles-
Mikhail has doubles,  just like Saddam Hussein.
The man I shot was not an impostor.  Belicoff is dead.
Why'd you tattoo your face?
Because it's the only place  I knew Belicoff wouldn't hit.
[Releases Hammer]
Tell me about Udre Belicoff.
Mikhail's brother?
He runs slave girls, drugs, weapons.
Both the C.I.A. And F.S.B.  Want him dead.
- Mikhail's been protecting him.  - Get up.
- Get up. You're coming with me.  - I can't.
He'll kill me if he fiinds out  I left the apartment.
Belicoff hired me to kill him.  Used you to set me up.
The dead man in the trunk  was your driver.
He was gonna use it on you.
You're as good as dead without me.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna fiinish the job  I was hired to do...
and fiind out who's behind this.
- I need to talk to you.  - I need coffee.
Follow me.
We have three roadblocks.
Here, here, here.
We completely shut down  international airport.
All border security has been tripled.  He cannot get out of city.
- What about the train stations?  - Temporarily closed.
- And Saint Petersburg Station?  - There are no trains leaving Russia  from this station.
Only commuter trains  headed towards interior.
What make you think  he go further into Russia?
Because I know him  better than anyone.
Thanks for the coffee.
Go to the last platform and wait.
- Why?  - Now.
- Jenkins, anything?  - Nothing.
[Mike On Radio]  Stay sharp.
[Jenkins On Radio] I don't know, sir.  It seems odd for him to come here.
[Mike On Radio]  Trust me. This is where he'll be.
Jenkins- bench, shaved head.
[On Radio]  Got him, boss.
Fuck!
Jenkins?
I'm still on him, boss. Platform...
- number nine.  - [Static On Radio]
Boss?
[Grunting]
Gotten slow.
[Gunshot]
- [Grunts]  - [Gunshot]
Tell me why.
[Gunshot]
Why is there a hit on me?
- Stay here.  - [Gunshot]
[Shell Clatters]
How about dying  with a little dignity?
[Grunts]
[Shouts]
[Grunts, Shouts]
- [Bones Crack]  - [Shouts]
[Grunting]
[Staples]
[Breathing Heavily]
You think it's done?  It's just beginning.
[Gunshot]
[Sighs]
I told you to wait.
I know. I'm sorry.
- L- I know-  - [Clattering]
Shh.
- [Gunshot]  - Aaah!
- Freeze!  - [Shouts]
- [Groans]  - You're the one who's been tracking me.
The Russian Militsiya have got  the terminal locked down.
If you need a hostage...
take me.
Come on.
He hasn't seen your face.  He doesn't have to die.
Take me instead.
[Gunshot]
[Groans]
Please.
Stop.
She saved your life.
[Chattering]
[Speaking Russian]
- [Grunts]  - [Speaking Russian]
He said your ribs are broken.
Unlucky.
- You seem awfully calm, considering.  - Your assassin is dead.
[Chuckling]
Why are you covering this up?
You know that's not our killer.
I told you before, Inspector,  this is no longer your affair.
Now there are two ways  in which we may proceed.
One, my men will  accompany you to the hospital...
and, when you and your associate  are able to travel...
they will escort you to the airport.
Then I will write a report  extolling Interpol for its help.
Medals will probably be involved.
Or I can report your incompetence...
and disregard for my nation's laws  to your superiors.
This will undoubtedly fiind its way  to the state prosecutor in Moscow.
So, how do you think  we should proceed, huh?
How about...
go fuck yourself.
[Speaking Russian]  I was running out of oxygen in there!
- Don't be dramatic.  - Dramatic?
- I got rid of the body.  - I've been there for hours!
I brought you breakfast.
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Chuckling]
[Thunderclap]
I'd thank you  if I wasn't so mad at you.
Look at me.
Back at the station, you interfered.
I'm sorry.
I can't allow that.
- I swear I'll never-  - Stop talking.
If you're looking  for a reason not to kill me...
I don't really have one.
I'm not a whore by choice.
Belicoff owns me.  I'm his property.
Would you like to know  how much he paid for me? 300, American.
I've tried to escape.  The last time-
[Sobbing]
[Speaking Russian]
It is a strange thing to wish to die.
So, are you...
going to kill me?
No.
You don't want to fuck me  and you don't want to kill me.
I've never felt so much indifference  in my entire life.
- If you ever again interfere with me like that-  - I won't.
- Are we clear?  - Yeah.
Eat your sandwich.  I need to get some sleep.
- You know-  - Nika-
- Yes?  - Stop talking or I'll put you back in the trunk.
[Speaking Russian]
Shit.
[Russian]
[Phone Ringing]
Da.
[Man Speaking Russian]
I gotta give it to you, sir. Pretty slick.
Go fuck yourself.
It was a pretty stupid idea actually.
If we get caught, we'll be making  snow cones in Siberia for the next 20 years.
Yet here we sit.
Shh!
Belicoff.
- [Siren Wailing]  - Shit! Hide that thing.
We came to see Chief Agent Yuri.
- What's the problem?  - Chief Agent is very busy man.
He asked you to go directly to the airport.  We'll escort you there immediately.
Okay.
[Chattering]
[Cell Phone Ringing]
It's for you.
After all these years,  I'd think you'd trust me a little more than this.
Tell me what you know.
[Man]  Offiicially, nothing.
[Over Earphone] Unoffiicially, it appears  your employer has thrown you to the wolves.
- Why?  - Apparently...
Belicoff s softening political stance  and his refusal...
to cooperate with the hard-liners  upset a lot of people.
They ordered the hit  and replaced him with one of their own.
Seems you and your friend here are the only ones  who know Belicoff is actually a double.
What's the C.I.A.'s position?
The company usually likes to be  on the side of whoever wins.
Take the envelope from the girl.
Ah.
Udre Belicoff,  Mikhail's younger brother.
Rumor is you'd like him to disappear.
- That is the rumor.  - I'd like to help.
How's killing Udre Belicoff  gonna help you?
- Let me worry about that.  - Well, that might be worth something.
- What do you want for your trouble?  - Small favor.
This is a small favor?  I don't think I can do this.
- Not in your time frame.  - Keep reading.
Jesus Christ.
Tell me this isn't  what I think it is.
Okay. It's not what you think it is.
But I'd expect the last thing you'd want  is for me to be arrested with that fiile.
[Sighs]  Okay. I'll try.
- Thank you.  - Yeah, you're welcome.
We know Udre's been planning something  with a German arms dealer named Price.
The two have never met.  That's your way in.
Intercept Price,  and you get a shot at Udre.
I'll get you his fiile.
They're meeting  in Istanbul in two days.
Good morning.  Have you slept at all?
Some.
You know, you could sleep in the bed.  I won't bite you.
Unless you pay me.
It's not polite to stare.
So, when are you  gonna tell me your name?
- Get dressed.  - What for?
We're going to dinner.  We need to buy you a new dress.
You know, you're really quite charming  when you aren't killing people.
- This place looks nice.  - Yeah.
- Don't you think?  - Mm-hmm.
Wait here.
Hey! What'd you do, eat without me?
- How did you know I wouldn't just take off?  - I didn't. Come on.
We have dinner reservations at 8:00.
Jenks, how do you feel?
[Groans]  My pride hurts worse than my arms.
- Any word?  - The sketch is out to every  Interpol substation in Europe.
Train stations, airports,  border crossings and-
- What's that?  - This is what I wanted to show you.
It's every appearance  Belicoff has made within the last 12 months.
This is from the speech he made  in London on May the 7 th.
And this is from some shitty political luncheon  he had in northern Georgia.
Someone took a photo  from a mobile phone.
- Look at the date.  - May 7.
- How's that possible?  - I can't be sure...
but unless he's fiigured out  how to be in two places at once-
- Ha. He has a double.  - He's certainly paranoid enough.
That explains the arterial spray.
I hope he had health benefiits.
## [Man Singing  In Foreign Language]
[Nika]  When I was a little girl, I had this little squirrel-
you know,  with black stripes on the back?
- A chipmunk.  - Oh, yeah, that's right. A chipmunk.
His name was Tishka.
I'm sorry, sir,  but this is for another gentleman.
- Table 26?  - That's right.
My mistake.
You know what table that is?
I saw the layout when we came in.
- Do you remember everything you see?  - No, not everything.
What's the soup of the day?
Red lentil and mint with sauteed onions  and diced tomatoes.
The woman sitting two tables behind you-  what's she wearing?
- With the red hair and the silk dress, facing you?  - Yeah.
That's not a woman.
What color underwear am I wearing?
You're not wearing any underwear.
- [Glass Clattering]  - [Man Grunts]
[Groaning]
Come with us, sir.  Here we go. It's gonna be all right.
Nika, ask for the check.
- But I'm not done!  - Then hurry.
You scratch what I said  about you being charming.
Sorry, sir.
[Man Retching]
[Retching Continues]
[Moaning]
[Groaning]
[Man]  Shei(beta)e.
Mr. Price...
thank you for the introduction  to Udre Belicoff.
Little help, please.
- What the fuck?  - Let's go.
- What?  - Now.
Well, that was lovely.
Right up to the time  you dragged me out by my hair.
Undress me.
[Chuckles]  So very good at fiirearms.
Not so good with  ladies' undergarments.
Careful. I'm not wearing any panties.
- Nika, you're drunk.  - [Scoffs]
And?
- And this is a very bad idea.  - Oh.
- You mean this?  - Yes, that.
How about this?
Defiinitely that.
Then...
this must be really bad.
[Shrieks, Mutters In Russian]
[Car Engine Roaring]
[Engine Shuts Off]
## [Pop]
Give me case.
Mr. Price!
So, you took it upon yourself...
to change our appointment.
- How forward of you.  - As I told your men downstairs...
I was attacked earlier tonight  by some lunatic.
- Common sense dictated-  - Common sense should have dictated...
you not abuse my good nature.
Sit.
## [Continues]
I was just going over  a few of my lines...
with some of your competitors.
[Chuckling]  Lines.
A few of my lines.
Do you get it?
Where was I?
He's not Price.
Da.
This is the, uh- the Kedr.
Nine-millimeter, compact.
It's, uh, less than two kilograms.
Select fiire single,  or fully automatic.
- Empty-  - [Clicks]
And safe.
Or if you are looking for an assault rifle...
I have the M203 with  under-barrel grenade launcher.
A lot of third-world dictators...
got a lot of 7.62s stockpiled.
Saves them from having to buy ammo.
Everything here is  available in bulk, of course.
Prices not negotiable.
Any questions, Mr. Price?
Yeah. What about the little one there?
[Chuckles]  Here. I show you.
- This is a Makarov.22.  - [Gasps]
- A favorite of the K.G.B.  - [Woman] No. No.
Particularly effective  in the right hands.
But for a real target...
you need to fiind a soft spot.
- [Crying]  - Whoa. Hold up. Hey.
Wait. This is not a Kedr.
It's a Chinese copy.
In fact, I don't know if it's the drugs,  or if you're usually this inept...
but you've been wrong  about most of these weapons.
If the gun you're holding  is as cheap as this one...
even if you could manage to shoot her  in the eye-and I'm not saying you could-
you wouldn't kill her.
- [Woman Whimpering]  - [Shouts]
[Woman Screams]
[Woman]  Oh!
[Screams]
[Shouting]
[Groans]
- Why are you doing this to me?  - I need you to help me with your brother.
Mikhail? Fine. Fuck him.
I do whatever you want.
What the fuck do you want me to do?
Just this.
You know, it says here that when  the male penguin meets the female penguin...
he knows in the fiirst 10 seconds  whether he's gonna like her or not.
Are you listening?
I'm listening.  I read that.
These articles are full of shit.
- Why do you buy these magazines?  - For the advertisements.
What do you need  luggage like this for?
Because that perfectly holds  my Blaser sniper rifle and.245.
And a gag for irritating,  talkative little girls like yourself.
You want me to stop and get it out?
I don't know.  You think we have time for foreplay?
You know, when I was a little girl,  my father raised grapes.
And I told him that one day  I'd own my own vineyard.
It looks nice.
[47]  We need to get off the road.
[Chattering]
[Sighs]
- [Sighs]  - Jenks.
Is that his suitcase?  How did we get that?
As a consolation prize  Captain Gudnayev sent me.
Our boy's stuff from the hotel in St. Pete  in case it might help.
- Anything?  - Not much.
There is this.
What do you make of this?
[Jenkins]  "Trust unto God...
and he shall direct your path."
- It's-  - That's Psalms.
I never fiigured our boy as the religious type.  [Chuckles]
That's strange.
[Laughing]
Nika.
I have to go.
So much for happy endings.
I don't want you to do this.
Belicoff needs to die.
I don't care about that.  Not anymore.
As long as he's alive,  they will never stop looking for you.
[Train Horn Honks]
Take this.
At the next station,  get off the train as soon as it stops.
Move with the crowd.
But I don't even know your name.
The place I was raised, they didn't give us names.  They gave us numbers.
Mine was 47.
Well, that explains a lot.
- How will I fiind you?  - Don't worry.
I'll fiind you.
What are you going to do?
What I do.
[Buzzer Buzzes]
[Speaking Russian]
You're drunk.
You don't want to drink  with your new president, tovarich?
We are celebrating. Yes?
All the evidence is erased.
Mikhail Belicoff.
And his pathetic brother Udre.
Now I'm the one and only.
And the one man I have  asked you to kill...
the only one who can expose us...
is the one man not in this room!
So...
tell me, tovarich.
What exactly  have you done to fiind him?
It seems if we wait long enough...
he will fiind you.
Us, Tovarich Yuri.
- He will fiind us.  - The organization has sent in their best operatives.
I know.  Don't let your incompetence hinder them.
We will not have  this conversation again.
[Door Opens]
[Horn Honking]
Three hours ago, Belicoff! S brother Udre  was found dead in Istanbul.
They're waiting for the body  to arrive in Moscow for the funeral.
[Clears Throat]  Heads up.
Michael. How's things going?
Belicoff s brother has just been found murdered.  It's him, sir. It's our guy.
He's setting Belicoff up.
We're getting pressure from the ministry  and the E.U. To drop this investigation.
- But, sir, the Russians will-  - The Russians are the ones leading the E.U. On this.
They blatantly deny  your ghost exists...
and have fiiled papers  with the minister's offiice...
claiming you've  overstepped your authority.
Who? Who brought those allegations?
The F.S.B.  Specifiically, Chief Agent Yuri Marklov.
I need you to stop.
No. You don't understand.  The F.S.B. Is covering this up.
He killed Belicoff s brother.  Now why?
- Why would he do that, unless-  - [Man On TV] Mikhail Belicoff...
announced that he would attend funeral  services tomorrow morning for the burial-
- The funeral.  ...ofhis brother, Udre...
who died two days ago-
He's gonna take Belicoff  at Udre's funeral.
...some speculation  that Belicoff! S opponent-
[Door Slams]
[Coin Clinks]
[Groans]
This generator produces  over 3,000 amps-
much more than is necessary, but...
I wanted you to understand  the gravity of this situation.
At 2:;30, that radio taped to  your hand will activate.
You'll have 30 seconds to order  the shooting of your friend Belicoff.
If you don't,  the generator will start.
Your skin will melt.  Your blood will vaporize.
There won't be enough  left of you to identify.
You have gone to  a great deal of trouble.
I am just a bureaucrat.
There is nothing I can do  for you, I'm afraid.
I disagree.
This is not a request.
This situation is fiixed,  and you know both possible outcomes.
- [Breathing Heavily]  - Live... or die. Your choice.
Here's something to keep  things in perspective.
I picked it up last night  when I was in your house.
You bastard!
If I were you,  I'd keep that radio dry.
[Russian]
Yell all you like.
The Lord himself won't hear you.
[Russian]
[Groans]
[Crowd Chattering]
There are over 100 highly trained...
alpha Special Forces  soldiers in this cathedral.
It would be foolish  to attempt any type of violence.
A man as highly trained  as your assassin would realize this.
What if he does?  Look around you.
How much civilian blood  do you think will be shed?
We are prepared for that as well.
Gas canisters are being deployed.
If anything should occur,  the civilians will be rendered unconscious.
Now, if you will excuse me.
## [Chorus Vocalizing]
[Camera Shutter Clicks]
[Speaking Russian]
[Electronic Female Voice]  One minute, 50 seconds.
[Russian]
[Speaks Russian, Groans]
[Speaking Russian]
My brother- he was a troubled man...
but he was not always like that.
One minute, 25 seconds.
One minute, 20 seconds.
[Mikhail] Should we choose to be kind  and let her die much like my brother?
Or should we do what is necessary...
what is hard, to save what we love?
One minute.
[Whimpering, Grunts]
- [Groans]  - I, for one, will not fail again.
Not with this country.  Not with our children's future.
Not with you, my countrymen.
[Applause]
Thirty-fiive seconds.
- [Russian]  - [Beeps]
- Hurry! Come in!  - Da.
Change target.  Shoot Belicoff.
[Russian]
[Yuri]  It's an impostor! Do it!
- Just fucking do it now!  - [Beeps]
[All Gasp]
[Crowd Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
Do not let the assassin escape.
Release the gas.
Lock down the doors.  I suggest you and your men follow me.
Let's go!
[All Shouting]
[Man Speaks Russian]
[Russian]
Your man has made a mistake.  There is no exit.
He's trapped.
Doesn't make sense.
Why would he-
"Trust unto God...
and he shall direct your path. '"
Shit. He set this up  from the very beginning.
[Grunts]
[Screams]
- [Bone Cracks]  - [Screams]
Where does this key fiit?
The archbishop's personal chambers.
The third tower.  Over the Muscova.
He's going into the river,  like in St. Pete.
Jenks, get our men.  Let's go.
He is in the southwest tower.  Call in the gunships.
Do not let him escape.
Seems I underestimated you.
Consistently.
A miscalculation on my part.
- [Groans]  - Who are you?
- Answer me.  - Let me help you.
- How would you do that? By having me killed?  - Ah. No.
For that I'm sorry.  It was a mistake.
And Nika-was that a mistake?
- Or did you destroy her life  for your own amusement?  - What?
You think you can take  what has cost millions...
years of planning,  for the good of this country...
and destroy that?
Then what? Walk away?
You don't really think they will let you do that.  If you kill me, they will never let you go.
They will hunt you  for the rest of your life.
You did your job.
And you did it very well.
And for that, my boy,  you should be proud.
That's it?
Yes. I'm offering you  your life back.
That is why you are here, yes?  That is what you want.
Uh-uh.
No?
No.
[Helicopter Whirring]
[Machine Gun Fire]
[Walkie-talkie: ; Man Speaks Russian]
Interpol! Drop your weapons!
[Mike]  We have an arrest warrant for that man.
Don't move! Hands on your head!  On your head!
- On your knees!  - Don't do anything stupid.
Just one thing.
Knowing how this ends,  was it worth it...
killing Belicoff?
Knowing how this ends?
Defiinitely.
- What do you make of that?  - [Tires Squeal]
What the hell?
[Tires Screeching]
[Guns Cocking]
- Who the hell are you?  - I'm Agent Smith...
of the U.S. Central Intelligence Agency.
- I need all you men to the rear of that vehicle.  - You don't have jurisdiction.
We aren't here.  Which means when we open up on you...
and shred your bodies with automatic fiire,  then this will never have happened.
- Stand down.  - We have reason to believe...
you're involved  in terrorist activities.
We're Interpol.  And in accordance with section 3-
- We're transporting an international criminal.  - What criminal?
Oh, Jesus Christ!
You know what?  I'm sorry, man.
My mistake.
- I thought you were someone else.  - You prick.
On behalf of the United States government...
I'd like to extend to you  our sincerest apologies.
Load up, boys.
[Tires Squealing]
[Cell Phone Beeping]
- So now what?  - Now you have to answer my question.
Are you a good man, Inspector?
I think.
And yet you've killed men.
So, Inspector...
how does a good man  decide when to kill?
If I think that a man means  to do me or my family harm...
then I will do  whatever I can to stop him...
but beyond that...
it's a crapshoot.
The key.
[Chuckles]  You knew I had jurisdiction...
and would walk you  right out through the front door.
I wanna be left alone.
- Just like that?  - Yeah. Just like that.
This is the man  you've been looking for.
Ballistics will confiirm  he was shot by your weapon.
The magazine is in the nightstand  next to your bed.
Don't forget it when  you call your superiors.
Did you kill him here?
It's 5:00. If you wait a few hours,  until the girls go to school...
you won't have to  expose them to this.
Explains why you waited so long  before you called it in.
- I can't go along with this.  - I hope you can.
For both our sakes.
Good-bye, Michael.
[Thunder Rumbles]
I hope I never see you again.
[Exhales Deeply]
I told you to leave her alone.  You should have listened.
Subtitled By Littleliang  END