.
Dr Knowles, Dr Knowles, you've got to help me.
I've been invited to the annual beekeepers' ball tonight.
Ooh! That's exciting, Colin.
I know it is, but I can't go looking like this.
Hmm... Well, your look is a little... vintage.
- BANG
- Hey, lads, look what I got.
A total makeover kit, 100% satisfaction guaranteed.
Who wants to be on my guinea pig? Huh?
Oh, I think I know where this is headed.
This is Brain Freeze.
With Dr Knowles...
Professor McCourt...
And Colin, the floor manager.
Stand-by!
Hello again and welcome to Brain Freeze.
It's time for...
Today's question is...
Well, first things first, all mammals have hair,
and the primary function of hair is to keep us warm.
Even before we are born, we have a layer of fine, downy hair
which prevents body heat from escaping.
Yeah, that'd explain all the hairy babies in our family.
Now, there are two other types of hair.
The very fine colourless hair found on most of our bodies
and the thicker, longer, darker hair that grows on our heads.
So we're pretty much covered all over in some kind of hair?
That's right. In fact, there are only a few places where hair doesn't grow.
These include your lips, the palms of your hands
and the soles of your feet.
That's proof enough for me. Basically we're monkeys.
- Ooh-ooh!
- Well, speak for yourself, Professor!
- Ooh-ooh-ah!
We'll be right back after this break.
And we are clear!
OK, Colin, take a deep breath and prepare to be transformed.
Oh, crumpets! I don't like this.
Meet Colin, he's a floor manager from the Midlands
with the fashion sense of a sausage.
We need to freshen up his dated look and make him feel like 1 million.
Work it, Colin. Own it!
Yeah, baby. That's the look.
Oh, stop it! This is all wrong.
- BELL
- Positions!
Welcome back. Lynn got in touch to ask
"So what is hair exactly and how does it work?"
Our skin contains over 5 million tiny openings called hair follicles.
Inside these follicles, hair cells work together
to produce the hard protein, keratin,
which forms the hair shaft that grows out from the root.
Oh, don't talk to me about roots!
The root is the living part of the hair
and it's connected to blood vessels,
nerve endings and other glands
that help it function.
Well, we all need a little help from time to time.
But by the time the hair has reached the skin surface,
it's made up entirely of dead cells.
Which leads us conveniently to...
So, Dr Knowles, why doesn't a haircut hurt?
What the...? Well, the answer is quite simple.
There are no nerve endings in the dead part of our hair,
so we don't feel anything when it's cut.
But it does hurt if we pull hair
because we're pulling out all the little nerves inside the roots.
- See you next time on Brain Freeze!
- Toodle-oo.
- Hey! Where's Colin?
- I'm in here, Dr Knowles!
I'm just putting the finishing touches to my new look.
- Ooh, let's see, let's see!
- Very well. Prepare to be amazed!
But... Em... What happened to... ?
I decided, Dr Knowles, that I'm happy just the way I am.
You know what, Colin, you're right.
Well, perhaps just a hint of styling cream.
Beekeepers' ball, here I come!
Oh, honestly, Dr Knowles.
Some people just don't know style when they see it.
Argh!
# Brain Freeze! #