.
BELL RINGS
According to this, we've mapped more of the surface of Mars than
the bottom of the Earth's oceans. Isn't that amazing?
That is fascinating, Dr Knowles.
Er, what's going on, Colin? You seem VERY relaxed.
It's part of my new healthy regime.
No more stress for me, no matter what stunt McCork pulls.
Sorry I'm late, Colin.
My car broke down and my dog got sick and I fell in a hole...
Not to worry, McCork. Take your place when you're ready.
We're going live shortly.
What's up with your man?
This is Brain Freeze...
with Dr Knowles...
Professor McCork...
and Colin the floor manager.
Stand by!
Hi and welcome to Brain Freeze.
It's time to reveal...
Today we ask...
How deep is the ocean? That's a Justin Bieber song, isn't it?
The deep sea is the lowest layer of the ocean
and includes anything below 200 metres
right down to over ten kilometres.
And the deep sea is one of the largest habitats
for living creatures on the planet. That's a fact.
Now, since the 1960s, scientists have discovered some incredible creatures
that have adapted to the darkness and high pressure of the deep sea.
Creatures.
What kind of creatures?
There's the flashlight fish and the angler fish,
who have evolved their own system of lighting...
FISH ROARS, HE SCREAMS
The fangtooth fish, which has been found at depths near 5,000 metres
and has the largest teeth of any fish relative to its size.
Amazing. I wonder if he'd be tasty with a bag of chips.
HE SCREAMS
And these sea cucumbers, also known as sea pigs.
Well, they're just really well-adapted
to living under pressure.
Speaking of pigs under pressure, I'm off to see what Colin's doing.
But, Professor, we're live!
So unprofessional!
SHE CLEARS HER THROAT Back after this break.
Colin? Hey, Colin, Colin?
Ah, where's he gone?
Channel all negative thoughts outward
and embrace your inner butterfly.
Sorry, Colin. Just to let you know we're taking a break now, OK?
Ignoring all other distractions that may be present...
Oh, and, Colin, Dr Knowles was wondering
if you wanted anything down the shop.
..we are now in an unbreakable state of calm.
One last thing, Colin - did I show you my new pogo stick?
Oh, McCork, you've ruined it!
How am I supposed to relax when you keep interrupting me?!
Yeah, yeah, yeah. It's like it's got a life of its own!
Oh, crumpets! Get back to work, McCork.
We're going live.
Welcome back.
Megan just got in touch to say, "Will you please hurry up
"and tell us where the deepest part of the ocean is?"
That means it's time for...
At almost 11 kilometres deep,
the Mariana Trench in the Pacific Ocean is the deepest known part.
- To be specific.
- No, no, Pacific.
- Yeah, I was being specific.
To give you an idea of how deep that is, this huge trench is
a full 2,000 metres deeper than Mount Everest is tall.
Tell me, Doctor,
how does the pressure change being down that deep?
Pressure in the ocean increases at about one atmosphere for every
ten metres of depth.
So the pressure at the bottom would be like trying to
carry around 50 jumbo jets.
Whoa! Now that's real pressure.
That's all for today, folks. See you next time on Brain Freeze.
Clear, and that's a wrap.
Yes, of course, boss. No dangerous equipment on set.
Yeah, including pogo sticks.
Ah, isn't it great to see him back to his old self again, Dr Knowles?
Yeah. I don't know what he'd do without you, Professor(!)
Hup! Anyway, I'm off home. See you later.