- Any sign of the Professor, Colin?
- No, Dr Knowles. Late again.
- As usual.
- You seem a bit under the weather.
It's like there's a cloud hanging over me.
THUNDER
Hey, lads, there's a sale on at the joke shop. I got tons of stuff.
Look at this.
WHOOPEE CUSHION DEFLATES LOUDLY
- Yeah! Oh! Ho.
- Let's get this over with.
This is Brain Freeze!
With Dr Knowles....
Professor McCork...
And Colin, the floor manager.
STAND BY!
TELEVISION NEWS THEME MUSIC
# Brain Freeze! #
- Hi, folks. Welcome to Brain Freeze!
- It's time to reveal...
- Today we're asking where do clouds come from?
- Clowns?
- I'm sure everyone knows they come from the circus!
- Not clowns, clouds!
Oh, whoo!
As we all know, water occurs as a liquid and a solid,
- but it also occurs as a gas called water vapour.
- That's news to me.
You see, water floats around us
all the time, in the form of tiny gas particles.
As the sun heats water on the earth,
these particles rise up in a process known as evaporation.
Up, up and away!
As they rise up, they bump into other small particles called aerosols.
Aerosols are tiny little bits of dust and salt
and other stuff floating around in the air.
As the air gets cooler, water vapour sticks to the aerosols,
forming droplets,
and these droplets eventually come together to form clouds.
- This is called condensation.
- Heh!
And there was me thinking they were made of candyfloss!
We'll be right back after this break.
TELEVISION NEWS THEME MUSIC
# Brain Freeze! #
OK, everybody. Take five.
Hey, Colin, do you know what the best cure for the blues is?
Laughter. Hit it, lads.
FUNKY JAZZ MUSIC
What do you call a sheep with no legs? A cloud!
SNARE DRUM STING
SHE COUGHS
What do clouds wear under their trousers? Thunder pants!
SHE GROANS
Do you get it?
Ahhhh!
BELL RINGS
Back in five, four, three, two...
Welcome back, Brain Freezers. So, Dr Knowles, condensation.
Where were we?
Well, as the air continues to rise and cool,
clouds begin to merge and grow,
and as the droplets within the clouds start to stick together,
they become too heavy to resist the pull of gravity,
and fall to Earth as precipitation.
- Precipi-what now?
- Precipitation.
- Snow, sleet or rain!
- We know all about rain, don't we, Colin?
SAD PIANO TUNE, THUNDER
This water then collects in oceans, rivers and lakes,
ready to start the process all over again. We call this the water cycle.
So, hang on.
You're saying it's the same water going around and around and around?
Exactly!
In fact, the water in your glass could be the same water that
a dinosaur drank millions of years ago!
Blech! I knew it tasted a bit funny! Keh!
Anyway, folks, there you have it.
So now you know how clouds are formed.
And they are not, I repeat, not made of candyfloss! See you next time!
TELEVISION NEWS THEME MUSIC
# Brain Freeze! #
Cameras! Cut!
Hey, Colin, I have an idea that might make you feel better.
- Please, Doctor, it's just no use.
- Hmmm!
What?!
- Ahh!
- Any good?
- Oh, you know what? I think I really needed that.
- Sometimes a simple hug can do the world of good.
- Oh, thank you, Doctor!
Hey, can I have a hug? Where's my hug? Is someone giving out hugs?
Someone give me a hug!
TELEVISION NEWS THEME MUSIC