[steady acoustic guitar music]
d d
- d lt was in your
basement apartment d
d with all of its earth
and sea d
d making love on the carpet d
d under the light of the TV d
d Outside the sour moon
minstrels d
d shook their dark tambourines d
d the morning came in sinister d
d well window light menacing d
d with clouds up above d
d and clouds down below d
d killing time
but it won't stand still d
d lt won't stand still d
- Mike!
Mike, need you
to sweep the pool.
- Why?
- Because people want to swim.
d We try so hard d
d We try so hard to love d
- How you feel today, Ma?
- Feeling great today, Mike.
- Good.
Where's Dad?
- Crossword.
- Checking out of 202.
- And how was your stay,
Mr. Edmund?
- Fine, thanks.
- Thank you so much.
- d l threw my heart
into the street d
d With stars up above d
d And stars down below d
d Killing time
but it won't stand still d
d lt won't stand still d
d We try so hard d
d We try so hard to love d
- So, two nights.
- Uh-huh.
- Preferably a room upstairs.
- Oh, sure.
Let's see...
- Smoking or-
- Nonsmoking.
- l think l'll put you
in 203.
- Okay.
- Nice room.
This is our snack bar.
List of prices
are on the wall.
- Sorry.
- There you go.
Thank you.
And if-
Uh-huh, thank you.
Anything else you need,
just give me a call.
- Thank you very much.
- You need help
with your bags?
- Nope, l'm fine.
[truck horn blows]
- 1 1 0's called twice
to complain
that 1 1 1's
making too much noise.
- Yeah, what kind of noise?
- Not that kind of noise,
Michael.
Get your mind
out of the gutter.
Apparently 1 1 1's got some sort
of grinder in there.
- l thought you said to get
my mind out of the gutter.
- Don't be gross, Mike.
- l'm not.
- Get some sleep.
You look tired.
- l'm not tired.
- You look tired.
- You're the one
who's sick, Ma.
- Well, that's a nice thing
to say.
- Sorry.
- Love you.
- Love you too.
- Good night, Dad.
- All right.
[knocks on door]
- Who is it?
- Management.
- What?
- Management, welcome gift.
- Hi.
- l have your complimentary
bottle-welcome gift.
Wine, it's on the house.
l'm, oh, Mike,
and l am with management.
- Nice to meet you, Mike.
- Oh, it's my pleasure.
So where would you like it?
- You know what?
l can just-l can just take it.
- Oh, okay.
Do you-
l'm sorry; would you like me
to open it for you?
l mean, yeah, 'cause sometimes
guests don't have the screws,
corkscrews.
- Um...
Yeah, okay, sure.
Sure.
l'll just put this here.
All right, thanks.
See anything
interesting tonight?
- l haven't really been
paying attention.
- Yeah, l know the feeling.
You know, there should be cups
in the bathroom.
Completely sanitary.
- That's good.
- Wine is delicious.
Oh, man.
God.
Shall l?
- Okay, sure.
- This is a good year.
Sometimes guests invite me
to join them in a taste.
- ls that right?
- l mean, not always,
but often.
Should be another cup
in the-
- l actually have to get
to work, Mike, so...
- What do you do?
- l sell paintings.
- Really?
l love paintings.
What kind?
- That kind.
- Oh.
Oh, nice.
So that's what you're doing
in town.
- l have presentations tomorrow,
and then l fly out
the next morning.
- What's the name of the company
that you work for?
- lt's called Corporate Bliss.
- And where are you guys HQ'd?
- Maryland.
- Nice.
Wait, "Maryland is for lovers,"
bumper sticker.
- That's Virginia, actually.
Virginia's for lovers.
Maryland's for crabs.
- Yeah, you're right.
- Okay, Mike.
- Okay, l got to get back
to work.
Oh, Solitaire's a great game.
Okay, l'm gonna down
in the lobby till 1 1 :00
and then in my apartment
after that,
but always reachable
by front-door buzzer,
just from then on.
Just in case you need
another Solitaire partner.
- Okay, have a great night.
- Bye-bye.
- Then l went
to the laundry room,
and then l came down here
into the lobby,
and that's when l realized
that your establishment doesn't
have any options for recycling.
- You're absolutely right.
We don't,
which l apologize for.
lt's something
we're working on.
But as you may know,
the Kingman area
has been a little slow
to fully embrace
the recycling issue.
lt's been voted on
two or three-
- So what should l do
with this bottle?
- Well...
- l'm sorry, l don't mean
to be rude.
But this is something
that l'm just-
l'm very passionate about.
- Recycling?
- Yes, recycling.
- l can take it.
l'll do it.
l've just-l'll-
l was gonna make
a recycling run anyway, so...
- Well, that's nice of you.
This is my son Michael.
He's the official
night manager.
- Thank you.
That's very nice of you.
- You bet.
l'll just put it back here
with all my other ones.
l got a pretty good-
big pile going.
[knocks on door]
- Who is it?
- lt's Mike.
- Oh, my God.
- Champagne.
- Why?
- We give it to all our guests
who stay for two nights.
- Wow, that's
a pretty good deal.
Did you and your mom come up
with that on your own?
- So shall l?
- Why not?
- Observe well.
You know the drill.
The same place,
the cups.
[cork pops]
Ooh!
- Jeez.
Thank you.
- You gonna make a toast, Mike?
- Yeah, sure.
Your Sue, right?
- Yeah.
- Here's to people being happy.
Mm.
- Ooh.
- How were
your presentations today?
- Average.
- You have a great butt.
l noticed the moment
you checked in.
- Thank you.
- l hope that isn't too,
you know.
- No, l mean, yeah, but-
- Thank you for that.
- Do you do this a lot, Mike?
- No.
- Sometimes?
- Very rarely.
- Does it ever work?
- Never.
- What would constitute
having it work?
- l don't-
- Us having sex?
- No, l don't-
- You getting to touch my butt?
- That would-
Yeah, l'd consider that...
for the con-constitution.
- Hmm.
Okay.
You can touch my butt...
but then you got to go.
Okay.
- Are you serious?
- Yeah, touch it and go, Mike,
just touch and go.
- So you're from Maryland?
- Yeah.
- Where about?
- Columbia, what about you?
- Here, Kingman.
lt's very warm.
- Okay, Mike.
- Okay.
- l got a early plane
to catch tomorrow.
- Yeah, me too.
- Okay.
- Bye-bye now.
- Yep, bye.
- Mom?
Hi, it's me.
l'm just checking in.
l'm in Kingman, Arizona.
Okay, well, that's it.
l-l love you, and-
and l miss you.
Okay.
- Hi, Sue.
- Hi.
- l was wondering if l could
snag your cell phone number
or your email
before you left.
- l don't think so, Mike.
- Why not?
- Not my style.
- But we-
you know,
l touched your butt.
- l know, and it was nice.
l just think
that's all she wrote.
That was-
- Mike, are those high-tops?
- Yeah.
- You're never gonna
get those off.
- Oh!
Keep it-
don't-under me.
- Hi.
- You all checked out?
- Yeah, l did it
with your wife earlier.
- Shoot.
- Hey, Dad.
Oh, come back
and see us sometime.
- Mm-hmm, yeah, well, you know,
it all depends on work.
- What was that all about?
- She sells motel paintings.
- Mike, heat's out in 1 1 9.
- d Well, l've never
been to Spain d
d But l kind of like the music d
d They say the ladies
are insane thered
d And they sure
know how to use it d
d They don't abuse it d
d Don't go and lose it d
- Thank you for calling
last minute-
- l'd like to book a-
- Your call is important to us.
- Fuck!
- d Well, l've never been
to England d
- Please continue to hold.
Your call will be answered
in the order
in which it was received.
- Come on, Mike,
now or never.
l'm gonna do it!
- Hello, Last Minute Flights.
How may l assist you?
- Hi, yeah, l'd like to book
a one-way cash ticket
for as fast as possible from
Phoenix to Baltimore, got it?
- d Well, l've never been
to heaven d
d But l've been to Oklahoma d
d Well, they tell me
l was born there d
d But l really don't remember d
d ln Oklahoma,
not Arizona d
d What does it matter? d
- Hi.
- l'm here to see Sue Claussen.
- Mm-hmm,
is she expecting you?
- Yeah, l left a couple
messages.
- Messages regarding?
- Regarding Sue,
telling her l was in town.
l'm an old friend.
- l see.
Okay.
- Sue, hi.
- What are you doing here?
- l-l was wondering
if we could talk.
- Why are you here?
- l called twice.
Did you get the messages?
- You know what, you guys?
l'm sorry.
Why don't you-
you go on ahead.
- Are you sure, Sue?
- Yeah, no, good, go.
Good.
- Hi.
- Can l talk to you
for a second?
- Yeah.
- This is completely
inappropriate.
This is like a violation.
- l wasn't trying to violate-
- Well, you did.
You are.
You are violating
my personal space.
my personal life.
l can't do this.
l have to be somewhere.
l'm late.
- lt's-it's 5:00.
What could you be
late for?
- l have an event.
- You have an event?
What kind of an event?
- l'm not gonna tell you.
- Can l come?
Here.
Come on, you need it.
You do this every week?
- Yeah.
- You're really good.
- You can't stay, Mike.
- Why not?
- 'Cause it's insane.
l let you touch my butt,
and then you fly all the way
across the country.
- Well, it was much more
than a butt touch.
- Still, you can't stay.
l got a lot l got to do.
- Well, how much stuff
can you do in one night?
- A lot.
- Like what?
Do you go out with friends?
- Do you see that girl
over there?
She works
for Burger King.
She gives me vouchers
every week.
And l pass them out.
That's what l do.
- Hey.
l just want
to let you know,
if you want me
to leave tomorrow, l will.
l promise.
- Hey, guys.
- Sue's here.
- Okay.
Whopper.
- Yeah, sure, yeah.
- Whopper.
Whopper.
Whopper, Whopper.
Okay, chicken tenders.
Chicken tender.
Be careful,
easy, easy, easy, easy.
There you go, chicken tender.
Okay, BB-BK veggie burger.
- Fuck that, Sue.
- Come on, it's supposed
to be delicious.
- l don't think so.
- Come on, guys,
it's got soy in it.
lt's really-
it's really good.
- Fine, l'll take one.
- All right.
Hey, who wants a Powerade?
- l do
- l do.
- All right.
Got one there, buddy?
Oh, this is nice.
- Thanks, l've been here
two years.
Compact fluorescents.
- Oh, bummer.
- No, that's-
So l think l'm gonna
go to sleep.
- Do you want me
to touch your butt first?
- No, l only do that
when l'm traveling.
- Right.
So do you-are you alone
here in Maryland,
or do you have relatives around?
- My mom is over in Laurel.
That-
Her name's Mary.
- Oh, what does she do?
- She sells insurance
to deaf people.
- Oh, nice sweat suit.
- [chuckles]
l don't-you know, l don't want
you to take this the wrong way,
but l think we probably
shouldn't sleep in the same bed.
- That's a good call.
- So is your return ticket
all set?
- l actually don't have one.
- You don't have
a return ticket?
- No, l bought a one-way.
- Why?
- Um...
- That's completely
unacceptable, Mike.
- l know.
- You need to buy one.
l'm sorry.
l-l didn't have
enough money.
- What?
- l only had enough
for a one-way,
and l thought-l thought,
"l'm just gonna go for it."
- With me?
- Yes.
lt was
a far-flung notion.
- lt was a fucking
stupid notion.
- l guess.
- l'll lend you the money.
- No, you don't have to do that.
- Well, l'm going to.
- Okay, hey,
would you first consider
taking the morning off
from work?
- No.
- We could hang out,
and then l'll leave.
lf l don't, you can mace me.
- You're insane.
- We could go to the zoo.
That'd be fun.
- Mike, zoos suck.
- Okay, then we'll
do something else.
Come on, Sue,
take the day off from work.
You look like you could use it.
- l do?
- No, hey!
[voices overlapping]
- Bump something!
Bump those people.
Wait, wait, wait.
Give it to me.
- Not too hard, okay?
All right.
Oh, man.
- You shouldn't smoke.
- l'm done forever.
l'm serious.
- No, you don't-
hey, you don't have to-
You didn't have to do that.
- l know, but l am.
l'm done.
lt's time.
- Let me see
if l understand something.
Do you think that you, like,
like me, Mike?
- Yes.
- Why?
- 'Cause you have style.
- No, l don't.
- Yeah, you do.
- No, no, l don't.
- Yeah.
You-you give away 30%
of your income.
- You would too
if you made more.
- No, l wouldn't.
You're also
incredibly sweet.
Well, beneath, you know.
- Beneath what?
- Beneath the part of you
that's not.
- You better catch your bus.
- l'll pay you back
for the ticket.
- Don't worry about it.
- So will l ever
see you again?
- l wouldn't be
good for you, Mike.
l'm not good with people.
- No, that's not true.
- Yeah, no, it is.
- No, it's not.
What about
those homeless guys?
They love you.
What about the soccer gals?
What about me?
- Okay, buddy,
all aboard.
- l think, Mike,
you'd better get on the bus.
- Hey, Sue,
it's Mike calling again.
l'm trying not to call too much,
but l just want to make sure
that you got the poem
that l sent last week,
you know, the sort of elongated
haiku thing.
Anyway, you know my home number
and of course the front desk.
But seriously, you should call,
because l'm-
l'm definitely around.
Anyway, talk to you later,
l hope.
Bye.
- d More than begin d
d but less than forget d
d But spirits born d
d from the not happened yet d
d gathering there d
d to pay off a debt d
d brought back from the wars d
d We thought we lost you d
d Welcome back d
- l thought you were gonna
quit smoking.
- l just did.
What are you doing here?
- Work.
- Hey, did-did you get
my haiku?
- The elongated one?
- Yeah.
lt was nice.
- So you're just
passing through?
- Yeah.
l fly out
from Phoenix tomorrow.
- Oh, okay.
- l'll take that.
- Oh, thank you.
- So this must be a really,
you know,
good region
for corporate art sales.
- Yes, it is.
- Good.
Hey, l'm supposed to go to this
yoga class thing later.
Would you like
to come with me?
Do you have
a boyfriend, Sue?
- No.
- Did you recently?
- Yes.
- What was his name?
- Jango.
He's an ex-punk.
- Ex-like, an ex-punk?
- Ex-rock punk.
We broke up
when he moved away.
- Why'd he leave?
- To open
the Pacific Northwest branch
of his organic
yogurt company.
He's the president.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
So how's yourjob
these days?
- lt's okay.
- But it's not
your fantasyjob.
- l don't really
do fantasy, Mike.
- lf you could close your eyes
and pick anything,
what would it be?
- Uh...
- But you got to close
your eyes.
Otherwise,
it's not gonna work.
- Oh, okay.
Okay.
To run a full-service,
state-of-the-art soup kitchen.
- Wow.
- Multiple housing
units upstairs,
recreational facilities
in the basement,
job outreach,
midnight basketball.
- Really good soup?
- Always.
Excellent soup,
first and foremost.
- What about kids?
You want to have kids?
- You know what
was really great
about that yoga class?
lt was the breathing stuff.
l don't do that.
- Breathe?
- There are days where
l have to instruct my heart
to request additional air.
And l have to tell myself,
"Breathe, Sue.
Just keep breathing."
Yes, l want kids.
- Were you not sure
when l asked?
- l just don't think
l've ever really been asked...
that way...
before.
- Can l ask
one more question?
And then l'm done,
l swear.
- What?
- Will you come visit my mom
with me on the way home?
She's sick, and l-
l promised l'd stop by.
- Here, these are for you.
There's a flower
show downtown.
- That's nice of you.
- Um, hey, Ma, Sue flew in from
Baltimore just this morning.
- What do you do, Sue?
- l sell corporate
decorative art.
- l've met you before.
- Yeah, you know,
she stayed at the motel, Ma.
That's how we met.
- And where are you
from originally?
- l'm from Columbia, Maryland.
- Do you come
from a good family?
- Uh...
No, not really.
- ls there something
specifically wrong
with your family?
- Well, my father lives
on an ashram
in Northern California.
Pretty much sums up
everything about him.
He once forgot to pick me up
from gymnastics
for an entire night.
- That's quite a lot
of somersaults.
- [laughs]
- l didn't care.
lt reallyjust explains
more about him
than it does me.
- [coughs]
Could you hand me
those pills, Mike?
- Which ones?
- The ones on the left there.
Can l talk to my son in private
for a moment?
- Yeah, l-
Did l say something wrong?
- Not at all.
- l'll just be a moment.
- Okay.
- l like her.
- Really?
- She's a bit
of a long shot.
But she's logical
in an emotionally annihilated
kind of way.
But that's okay.
Underneath,
there's a heart of-
- Gold?
- No, l wouldn't say gold.
Maybe made of...
leather.
But if it works out,
she'll be good for you
when l'm gone.
Needless to say,
what would make me happy
is for you to find something
for yourself
before my checkout time,
just so l know it's not
you and your father alone here,
walking around like robots.
- Ma, Dad's not a robot.
- He is.
But l was mostly talking
about you...
unless you find
a way out.
- Of what?
- Of whatever it is
you're stuck in.
You get it from your father.
He came back
from the war stuck.
Been talking about
joining a gym ever since.
Never has.
But that doesn't
have to be you.
- You okay?
- Yeah, are you?
- Yeah.
- She liked you.
- No, she didn't.
- Yeah, she did.
She told me.
- What took you so long?
- Dad, do you remember Sue?
- Hi.
There's a toilet overflowing
in 1 1 0.
- Okay.
- Got to get home to your mom.
- You really leaving?
- l have to.
- You can't do one more night?
- l have meetings
this afternoon in Seattle.
- Blow 'em off
and just stay for a while.
- lt's myjob.
- l know.
But, you know, you could get
a job around here.
- Where, Szechuan House?
- No.
l'm just saying that,
you know-
- Mike.
l don't know
how to say this.
This isn't gonna work.
l mean, l'll-l'll stop by
when l pass through.
- Come on,
what do you mean?
- l can't move from Baltimore
to live in
a corner double room
of your parents' motel.
l mean...
be serious.
l'm sorry.
l'll stay in better touch
this time.
- Yeah, whatever you say.
So this is where she wanted?
- Well, this used to be
all scrub.
She'd be cringing right now
if she knew
they were building here.
But l promised her
l'd do it.
- Yeah, it's still nice.
- l meant to give this
to you earlier.
lt's your mom's favorite
piece ofjewelry.
As you know,
she was a necklace woman.
She thought
you should have it.
Don't know why.
Wouldn't want you
to start wearing it,
but maybe you can find
some use for it, something.
- Thanks, Dad.
- Also had some guy call me,
wanted to buy the motel.
- You gonna do it?
- l doubt it.
May as well keep
running it.
But you can do
what you want, Mike,
you know, if you-
you want to leave.
- This ain't a half bad
hunk ofjunk.
- Yeah, it was my mother's.
- Oh, God, let's not go down
the sentimental road.
- Oh, l'm not.
l'm just saying.
- Yeah, l know
what you're saying,
and l know
you're gonna start crying.
- What?
No, l'm not.
- How long you been
in the pawn business?
- The porn business?
- No, the pawn business,
God damn it.
How long you been
in the pawn business?
- Oh, no, l'm never-
l'm not in that.
- No, no, exactly.
So when somebody says
they ain't gonna start crying,
that's sure as shit sign
that they's just about
to start blubbering like a calf.
Oh, see what l mean?
- Just, how much
for the necklace?
- l'll give you $300.
- Okay.
- Oh.
- Hi.
- l'm here to see Sue, please.
- Sue no longer works here.
- l'm sorry?
- She moved to Washington.
- D.C.?
- State.
Her old boyfriend convinced her
to move out to Aberdeen,
showed up here with flowers,
first class plane tickets.
lt was very
Officer and a Gentleman.
- [screams]
Fuck!
- [speaking foreign language]
- Number eight?
- Eight?
- [speaking foreign language]
Dude, l'm just messing with you.
You're new in town, right?
- Oh, yeah.
- You looking for a job?
- Yeah.
- You, uh...
you want to work here?
- Seriously?
- Why the fuck
wouldn't l be serious?
- Al.
- l'm Mike.
- Mike, it is nice
to meet you, Mike.
- Yeah, you too.
- Dude, you stink.
- l do?
- Big time.
You can't work here
if you stink.
lt's my parents' place,
and they're old school.
They really hate stinky people.
- Okay.
- Yeah, so, like, go home,
take a shower, please,
come back,
and l will get you the job.
- l don't have a home.
- Really?
- He also needs
a place to live.
So l was thinking
that maybe we could, you know,
let him stay in the basement
and deduct some rent
from his pay.
- [speaking foreign language]
- Great.
- Hey, thanks a lot
for helping me out.
lt really means a lot.
- Dude, no problem, man.
You know, l've been trying
to get my folks
to hire someone American anyway,
'cause we catch less
bigot bullshit that way.
Plus, l freakin' hate
working the mornings.
- Why?
- 'Cause l smoke a lot of pot,
and l like sleeping in.
- That's cool.
- So why'd you come
to Aberdeen, Mike?
- This girl
that l'm in love with,
she moved here
to be with her ex-boyfriend.
- Oh, that sucks, man.
- Yeah, especially considering
the guy's a punk.
- Like, a punk punk?
- Ex-punk.
l think he's older now.
- Does he train dogs?
- l don't know.
- ls his name, like, Jango?
- Jang-yeah, l think it is.
- l have totally
heard of this dude, Mike.
- ls he a punk?
- No, he's an ex-punk.
- So the thing
with this guy is, right?
He's also, like,
a yogurt magnate.
Okay, totally huge
in the yogurt business.
This guy's, like,
a yogurt fucking mogul.
You see those kennels
over there?
That's where he
keeps the dogs.
- Damn it.
- What?
- This guy-
this guy is, like,
a total stud.
- What do you mean?
- l'm not a sexual superman.
This guy?
l mean...
- No, dude,
you're probably fine.
- You're just saying that.
- Yeah, that's true,
but what do you want me to say,
that you're right?
- No, but-
- Okay, look, look,
chicks these days,
they don't want sexual supermen.
Okay, they want hard workers,
you know, guys who hustle.
And l mean, you look like
a hustler, Mike.
l mean, you came all the way out
to Aberdeen, dude,
and that's got to count
for something, right?
Yeah.
- Yeah.
- This guy's got shrubbery
shaped like pit bulls.
[dogs barking]
Dude, l think l got an idea
for how you can
get your girl back.
- Really?
- See that dude
sitting over there?
He runs a flight school
in Olympia.
You should
talk to him, Mike.
- Okay, Mike.
What l need now is for you
to free your mind
so as to have
a spiritually fulfilling,
religious fucking moment.
- l'm pretty sure
l can do it, Stan.
- That's the Michael
l've come to know
over the last
eight hours.
That's the Mike.
Come on, now.
Three, two, one.
- Wait, one sec!
[screams]
- Yeah.
(Stan)
Okay, now, Mike.
You're on your own!
- [screaming]
Whoo!
[screaming]
[Mike screaming]
- Jesus!
Oh, my God!
Jango!
Oh, my God.
Who is-who is that?
- Sue, it's me, Mike.
- Mike?
- Sue!
- What are you doing?
Mike, come here.
[silenced gunshots]
Jango, stop with the BBs!
l know him.
- What the fuck's going on?
- Come here.
Mike, come here.
Jango, stop shooting people.
Stop it.
Come here to me.
Follow my hands.
Follow the noise.
[gunshots]
Stop it!
Come on.
There you go.
Here l am.
l got you.
Why?
Oh, my God,
are you okay?
- Back away.
Sue.
- Jango, give me the gun.
Give me the damn gun.
- l think l'm dying.
- lt's just BBs.
- No, l mean,
l really think l'm dying.
- Move back, Sue.
Clear.
- Ow!
- Jango!
What are you doing?
- CPR!
- Oh, my God,
l'm calling an ambulance.
Okay.
Well, thatjust looks like
you're kissing him, Jango.
- Hi.
- Where am l?
- The Aberdeen Medical Center.
[slurping]
- Did-did-
- Yeah, Jango shot you,
which caused you
to go into shock.
Mike, why?
Why did you come out here?
- Because l love you.
Do l have BB holes
in my neck?
- Yeah.
- They hurt.
- l can imagine.
- l thought it was over
with that guy.
- He's good to me, Mike.
He put me in charge of his
company's nonprofit yogurt fund,
which allows me to do a lot of
good things for a lot of people.
He also feels horrible
about shooting you,
and he would like
to have you over for dinner.
- Oh, that's nice.
- So who's this guy?
- That is...
me and Joe Strummer
in the summer of '79
at the 1 00 club in London.
- Who's Joe Strummer?
- Joe Strummer most likely
made love to your mother, Al,
and then wrote
a song about it.
Here's the two of us
throwing up together
at the CBGB's.
- Hey, who is that?
- Oh.
That's me and Ed McMahon,
Ed Mc-wild-man.
Now, he's a true punk.
Basically, for me,
dog work is a thrill,
an adrenaline rush,
if you will,
that's otherwise
hard for me
to replicate
in the world of yogurt.
- Especially now
that you're not a punk.
- Well, l'll always be a punk
in here, Al, make no mistake.
But there's less need for me
to call myself a punk
in a world when the very notion
of punkdom
has been commodified
for the mass market.
- Okay.
- How do you like your marsala?
- lt's really good.
- Yeah?
- Oh, you're not gonna eat any?
- No, l-l liquefied it.
Listen, l would just like
to formally
and quite sincerely apologize
to you
for the BB gun incident.
l lost my cool.
l was scared for Sue,
scared for the dogs,
scared for the general
well-being of the pool.
So l just want to say
that l'm-
l'm sorry, M-
- Mike.
- My friend. l blundered.
- Yeah, that's all right.
- Yeah, so now that's
behind us.
And Sue tells me
that-that you're a painter.
[Sue clears throat]
- Yeah, very...
very talented painter.
- When did you have
the opportunity
to become acquainted
with his work, Sue?
- That was-it was my
last business trip
for Corporate Bliss.
- Hmm.
And you saw her
and thought,
"Great opportunity
to promote my art,"
or you thought,
"Beautiful woman"?
- The first part-one-
the art one.
- Now, and so you're the guy
who paints foxes and hounds
for corporate art?
- Yeah.
- Okay, 'cause l've got
something to say about that.
You take a Rottweiler-
well, no, let's say
a Malinois chasing a fox,
you got a seriously
new dynamic on your hands,
because a Malinois
on a fox's ass,
that'd be a trip,
because a Malinois is gonna
turn that little fox
into fox meat
inside of 23 seconds.
You know what l'm saying?
So l'd just like to lobby
for that a little bit.
- Okay.
- That was really
great chicken, Jango.
- l love that fucking chicken,
Jango.
- Oh, hey, you had
better chicken than that,
you'd have to be
a rooster.
[laughter]
Oh, hey, speaking of,
who's up for some dessert?
- Wow.
- Got a new flavor l want
to try out on you guys,
Henry Rollins
Chicken Wing Crunch.
- Hey, Sue.
Mike and l are gonna go
to the cowboy club after this,
and if you want to join us,
you know,
they got
really great dancing.
- l'll think about it.
- What l'm trying to say
is that China is not only gonna
kick America's economic butt,
but is gonna invade
your whole country.
l am talking
about you guys getting,
like, a whole new flag
and whatnot.
- l'm not-
- You need
to reorient the way
you think about
the Asians, Mike,
because we will
blow your mind
with our uniqueness
and inner beauty.
You think she's hot?
Yeah, sort of.
- Hi, guys.
- Yes.
- Sue, hi.
- Hi, Mike.
- You didn't bring Jango,
did you?
- No, no, he-
he got kind of drunk,
so l just told him
that l had an errand.
- Hey, you want to dance
with us, Sue?
- No.
- Come on, l know
you got a move.
- l don't have a move.
- Everybody's
got a move, Sue.
- Mike, show her your move.
- l don't have a move.
- Sue, don't you think
Mike's got moves?
- l bet you have a move.
- Come on, let's bust a move.
- Come on.
- [laughs]
- d l put on lipstick, paint,
and powder d
d When l do, it's all you see d
d Giving someone
what they wanted d
d wasn't all
l thought it'd be d
d Don't make it better d
d Make it worse d
d Make it new or make it done d
d l guess l'll be all right
without you d
d Girl, it's better
when you're gone d
- Hey, did you hear?
Aberdeen is building
the biggest biodiesel fuel plant
in the country.
- Whatever you say, Mike.
- No, we should find a way
to get in on that.
- Yeah.
- Hey, Jango.
- You know why l'll always be
a punk, Matt?
- Mike.
'Cause l take
very little shit.
- Whoa, hey!
[dog barking]
- l'm watching you, Matt.
You stay away from her.
- [groans]
- Christ, Mike.
Mike, Mike,
you all right, dude?
- l'll get him back.
- All right.
Yeah, man, yeah.
He's a scumbag.
- He's gonna regret that.
- So you sure
you want to do this?
- Look, don't come
if you don't want.
- Dude, l'm with you.
- Okay, let's do it.
- Let's go.
[soft melody]
d d
- d Baby d
d when l think about you d
d l think about love d
d Darling d
d don't live without you d
d and your love d
d lf l had d
d those golden dreams d
d of my yesterday d
d l would wrap you d
d in the heavens d
d till l'm dyin' on the way d
d Feel like makin' d
d d
d l feel like makin' love d
d Feel like makin' love to you d
Dude, that was awesome.
[metallic clank]
- Just...
- Dude, let's go.
- Wait, wait.
Go, go, go.
- Shit.
- l love you, Sue.
Eat that, dog man!
- You suck!
- Mike, you have a visitor.
- Okay.
- We need to talk, Mike.
- l know.
l've been leaving you messages.
l mean, did-
did you tell him
about us?
- Yes.
- Why?
- Because l'm marrying him.
- What?
- Which l-l need you to accept.
- Why?
- Because l'm at a point
in my life
where there are certain things
that l need.
- Like what?
- Like a certain kind of love.
- Well, what-what kind?
- The kind that is not
like an unguided missile.
You can'tjust stalk people
around the country.
You can't parachute
into people's pools,
knock on people's motel rooms
just because
you're feeling lonely.
Life isn't like that.
For you to-to be with someone,
it's-it's not all about
what you need.
lt's got to be more selfless
than that, Mike.
lt's got to be
more selfless than that.
- Oh, like-like,
save everyone else in the world
except yourself?
- l don't-
that's not what l do.
- Yes, it is.
- No, it's not.
You're so busy
being selfless
that you end up
treating yourself like shit.
- ls that really
what you think of me?
- l'm just-l'm just saying,
l know what you need.
- Which is what?
- To take care
of yourself a little...
so that the people
who love you
don't feel like
they're annoying you.
Sue, Sue,
just marry me, okay?
Just let the world
go screw itself
for a half second
and just see what happens,
and maybe it'll be okay.
- l'm getting married
on Saturday.
- Why?
- Because l'm pregnant.
And l'm gonna have it, and...
it's what l want.
- You're having a child?
Could-could it be mine?
- No.
Which is why
l'm getting married.
Mike, l can't afford
to be selfish on this one.
l just have to be with somebody
who knows what they're doing
with their life.
Sorry.
Sweetjust doesn't cut it.
- Can you leave now, please?
Just leave, okay?
Get out of my basement, Sue.
Susan, get-
l'm serious.
Get the fuck out of my basement
right now!
- l wish l had that dickwad's
BB gun right now.
They going on a honeymoon?
- l don't know.
- Yeah, they're probably waiting
till yogurt season's over.
You're gonna be all right.
- Yeah, yeah.
l just want to say, Al...
You're the best friend
l ever had.
- Ditto.
What a douchebag, huh?
[cheers and applause]
You know, it's enough to make
you want to be a Buddhist monk.
My people are really good
at that stuff.
- Yeah?
- No, dude,
don't get carried away.
- d Well, l don't know
what l'm looking for d
- Oh, sure.
- And you can see
by our next slide-
- d For some people,
it's an easy choice d
d But for me, there's a devil
and an angel's voice d
d Well, l don't know
what l am looking for d
d But l know that l just
want to look some more d
d Well, l don't know
what l'm looking for d
d But l know that l just
want to look some more d
d And you hear it
from the strangers d
d and you hear it from friends d
d that love never dies d
- lt's one point.
Don't worry about it.
Now, serve the ball.
You got it.
Come on!
- d Well, l don't know
what l am living for d
d But l know that l just
want to live some more d
- Michael, the progress you've
made in your four months here
has been remarkable.
- Thank you, Father.
- Needless to say,
your immersion
in the duty of carrot chopper
and broom chief
has been full and complete.
- Thank you.
- But some worries
have arisen.
- Such as what, Father?
- Well, first of all,
you're not supposed
to call me Father.
- Oh.
- But l must say, l admit,
l've grown fond of it.
Michael...
an aspiring bodhisattva
such as yourself
should seek to produce a heart
that does not dwell.
- Of course, father.
- And your heart, Michael,
may l say, it does dwell.
- No, it doesn't.
- lt does, Michael.
You have not transcended
your earthly passions.
To put it bluntly,
you are stuck.
You also spend too much time
playing volleyball.
- Yeah, but l thought
that was permitted, Father.
- Yes, but not
for seven hours a day.
- Also, you encouraged it
for stress release.
- Yes, l did, yes.
But, Michael,
Buddhist monks
aren't supposed to have
seven hours a day
worth of stress.
We are Buddhist monks,
Buddhist monks.
- So what should l do?
- My parents died
when l was ten.
Two months later,
my uncle and l moved to America.
l was forced to let go
of everything l knew
in order to move on.
Sometimes in life,
you must do that.
- Where are you from, Father?
- Vietnam,
Hau Nghia Province.
My parents were killed
in the war.
- By the Americans?
- Yes.
And yet l moved here.
Life is odd.
- l'm sorry.
- No, no, no.
lt is not your fault.
Let go, Mike.
Let go and move on.
- l recog-noodle you.
- Yeah, l'm the guy who
sold you my mom's necklace.
- Oh, yeah, that's right.
What can l do you for?
- l want it back.
Dad.
Do you want me
to make you some dinner?
- No, l'm all right.
- Okay.
Dad, when you were over
in Vietnam,
did you ever do any fighting
in the Hau Nghia Province?
- Yeah.
Why?
- l just met this guy
up at the monastery
who's from that area.
He seemed to really
have his shit together.
- Good to hear.
- Dad, l've been thinking.
Maybe you should
sell this place.
You don't even
like it here.
This was Mom's thing.
- Why do you say that?
- 'Cause it's true.
Come on, Mom loved people,
loved running things.
lt's not like you.
You're not like
a people person, Dad.
You should let it go.
Move on.
Otherwise,
you're just gonna rot.
- Sell it and do what?
- Anything.
You still have time.
You'd have money.
- What do you need, Mike,
a loan?
- No.
l just wanted to say that this
doesn't have to be it...
And that l love you.
- "Dear Mike,
" l know you probably don't want
to hear from me,
"and l can't say l blame you.
"But l wanted to write anyway
to let you know what l think,
"which is that l think
you had a point that day
"about people who hide
behind their causes
"in order to avoid their lives.
"You had a point down there
in that basement,
"with the soy sauce
and the mice.
"And so l wanted to say thanks.
"Because of you, Mike,
l'm not the same person l was.
"Good-bye, Mike.
Love, Sue."
- So l thought about
what you said the other day.
l think you had a point.
That being said,
this is yours.
- What is it?
- Deed to the motel,
signed over to you.
- Dad, that's not-
that's not why-
- lt's fine.
l don't need it.
Your mom was good
about that.
You-you can'tjust give me
the motel.
- lt's your birthright.
- What would you do?
- l want to get in shape,
maybe join one of those
basketball leagues.
How about you?
- l don't know.
l'll think of something.
- You done
with the monk stuff?
- Yeah, l'll still
occasionally do it,
l mean,
not professionally, but-
- What about that girl?
- Oh, that didn't work out.
Yeah, we weren't, you know,
like, meant for each other.
- l don't know, Mike.
Things change in life.
- What do you mean?
- You're not
the same guy you were.
Good soup.
- Good soup.
You can do this, Mike.
- So l'm gonna hit
the gym.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah, they have
a senior citizen hoop run
from 3:00 to 5:00.
Got a new ball.
- Yeah, l see.
- All right, Mike.
- See you.
- Hello?
- Hi, Jango,
it's Mike, Sue's friend.
- Hi, Mike.
- Hi, look, l know
that l'm probably not the guy
you want to hear from right now,
but l need to tell Sue
about what l'm doing down here.
And l think that when she hears
what l'm up to,
she'll at least understand
that if nothing else-
- Mike?
- Yeah.
- We split up.
Sue and l split up.
She left me...
went back to Maryland
to be with her mom.
- d From the rainwater well d
d deep as a secret
nobody knows d
- d l know you want to d
d run far away from one more d
d and that it's coming
at a bad time d
d Some cold place d
d heartless ways d
d for all we know d
[doorbell rings]
- Hi.
Are you Mary Claussen?
- Yes.
- Hi.
- l'm a friend of Sue's.
ls she home?
- Who are you?
- Mike from management.
- Oh.
Sue.
Mike is here.
- d We thought we lost you d
d We thought we lost you d
- Hi.
- How's the baby?
- So far, so good.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
l'm really sorry, Mike.
- Why?
- 'Cause l really
messed up with you.
- But you were right.
l was like a kid.
This is the deed
to the motel.
l want to turn it
into a homeless shelter
with midnight basketball.
l already bought
the soup noodles.
l was actually hoping
that you might want to help.
l really love you, Sue.
And l want
to take care of you
and whoever it is
that's inside of you.
All l want is
to be with you.
That's it.
Breathe, Sue.
Just keep breathing.
- l wrote you a haiku.
Want to hear it?
- Sure.
- Mike, oh, Mike, my man,
keeps showing up like UPS.
Sue, you're such a bitch.
- l like it.
- You do?
- Yes.
- d What am l gonna do? d
d lsn't thatjustjelly? d
d All the things l've heard d
d of all the things you find d
d l wonder if you know d
d l wonder if you're bitter d
d And all that
you've considered d
d Like marmalade, your mine d
d And the tow will bring you
down real hard d
d 'Cause your house
is only made of cards d
d So sweetly is the dream d
d in the cookie jar d
d where everybody is d
d everywhere you are d
d Remember what you did d
d Remember what you said d
d A lonely macaroon d
d inside your biscuit head d
d And the tow will bring you
down real hard d
d 'Cause your house
is only made of cards d
d What about the jam we're in d
d What about
when we were friends d
d l kept my cookie jar d
d too high up on the shelf d
d Here's what l wish for you d
d Here's what you must do d
d Preserve yourself d
d Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah d
d yeah, yeah, yeah, d
d Preserve yourself d
d Oh, oh, oh d