Excuse me?
We are close
to Universal Studios?
It's about ten miles away.
Oh.
♪ ♪
(BELL DINGS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
I heard you the first time.
Reservations?
For us, uh,
your hotel is not right.
You will please give
us back our deposit?
No refunds.
But we need the money for a new hotel.
Welcome to America.
Look, you've already
paid for one night.
Trust me.
This place will grow on you.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
(BELL DINGS)
(FAINT MOANING)
Um, I-I forgot to ask you
the password for Wi-Fi.
We don't have that.
In fact, this whole building
is a dead zone for cell service.
There is a telephone in each
room for your convenience.
Local calls are free.
$50 fee for losing your keys.
Anything else
I can help you with?
Ice?
Ice machine is down
the second hallway to the left.
Knock yourself out.
Terrible accident in room 51;
just ghastly!
(SHOVELING ICE)
♪ ♪
(LINE RINGING)
Front desk.
We must change rooms.
There's a terrible smell
in here.
It's a musty hotel.
Try running
the air conditioner on high.
No, you must
give us another room!
We're sold out.
Nothing available.
(PHONE CLICKS, DIAL TONE DRONES)
(BOTH GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS)
Improved By: Fidel33
Who was that?!
What was that?
I have no idea.
Honey, I'm just as upset as you are.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
And I want you to know
you will not be charged
for that room.
I cannot stay in this place
one more second!
The police will be coming soon.
You can either
give them a statement here
or you can talk to
them later in jail
when they arrest
you for evasion.
I'll get your bags ready.
Until then,
you can stay here.
I thought you said it was no other room.
This one we never rent out.
- (DISCONNECT TONE PLAYS)
- OPERATOR: (ON RECORDING) We're sorry.
Your call cannot
be completed as dialed.
Please check the number
and dial again.
(JAZZ MUSIC STARTS PLAYING)
(STATIC HISSES, MUSIC FADES IN AND OUT)
Aggie?
(MUSIC, STATIC CONTINUES)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
(INDISTINCT RADIO TRANSMISSION)
So, we think our guy lifted the
master key from housekeeping.
Nobody heard anything?
Looks like both victims
were chloroformed
the second they walked
through the door.
Lovely.
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
Let's get some light in here.
(MUFFLED MOANING)
Male victim's eyeballs
are in the ashtray.
And his tongue?
MAN: He's in a world of hurt.
(MUFFLED MOANING)
(MUFFLED) Get me...
DETECTIVE: John, this area's
been documented already.
Not by me.
(MUFFLED MOANING)
They were married,
but not to each other.
They were cheating.
Very pissed-off
spouse, maybe.
No, this isn't jealousy.
This is something else.
The killer's saying the families
are blind to what's
been going on.
MAN: (MUMBLES) Get me out...
(MUFFLED MUMBLING)
Sir?
We're gonna get you out of here.
We promise.
That's not what he's saying.
He's saying,
"Get me out of her."
He's still inside of her.
You're gonna find
male potency drugs in his
system; probably a lot.
You won't be able
to detach them here,
so you're gonna have to
take him with the corpse.
(MAN WHIMPERS)
Cut him loose.
(MOANING)
You have that report for me?
WOMAN: Forensics is still on the scene.
No, not from the homicide
this morning.
From the Martin Gamboa case,
last month.
MAN: The victim's name--
Martin Gamboa,
age 47.
Profession listed
as Oscar blogger.
187 occurred in victim's home
in Silver Lake.
Victim died from blunt
force trauma to the head.
There's evidence of wounds on arms
and thorax; some defensive.
Whoever did this
wanted him to suffer first.
Fractures to the radius
and the ulna of the right arm;
compound fractures
of the humerus of the left arm
with bone protrusions
through the skin.
There are traces of what appear
to be gold paint chips
in the rectal cavity as well as
in what is left of the cranium,
so it may be assumed that
whatever the murder weapon was,
was also used
in the sexual assault...
(PHONE BUZZING)
Hi, Dad!
How was school?
Good. Lizzy Cooper threw up
in the middle of spelling.
It was gross and awesome
at the same time.
The boys are calling her
Lizzy Puker now.
How's Mom?
Does she want to talk to me?
Hey, Mom, do you want
to say hi to Dad?
MOM: No, honey.
GIRL: Did you eat?
Yes.
Liar.
All right, you ready to read?
It's almost bedtime.
WOMAN: Lowe?
You got a call on line three.
Take a message.
Uh, he was pretty adamant.
So am I.
Daddy, you can go.
Nope.
We read at bedtime.
Who's gonna start?
You.
All right.
"Boys are trying enough to
human patience, goodness knows,
"but girls are
infinitely more so..."
Can you cross-reference
the Gamboa forensics
with the hotel case--
prints, everything?
You got it.
(PHONE BUZZING)
Hello?
MAN: Hello, John.
Why didn't you take my call?
Who is this?
How'd you get this number?
I nailed them to the headboard.
I'm at the Hotel Cortez,
room 64.
I'm going to do it again.
(PHONE CLICKS)
(BELL DINGS)
I need a room, one night.
150.
- It says here 30.
- It's out of date.
Prices went up
after the remodel.
Okay, well, that's bullshit.
You know what?
It's your lucky day.
Mama's feeling magnanimous.
Room 64.
Oh, elevator's
out of service today.
(SIGHS)
I got dibs on this one, Iris.
I haven't seen one
that sweet in a while.
(INDISTINCT POUNDING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(BABIES CRYING)
♪ ♪
When people die,
they soil the sheets--
blood, shit, urine.
I can take care
of every stain there is.
(LAUGHS)
(YELLS, SCREAMS)
Woof.
You're a sight for sore eyes,
Mr. Police Officer.
It's that obvious, huh?
Mm-hmm.
You must have a lot
of run-ins with police.
My fair share.
What can you tell me
about the occupant in room 64?
That room's vacant.
You mind if I take a quick look?
Oh, be my guest.
Liz Taylor.
Show this nice policeman
to room 64.
64?
Yes.
Room 64.
Right away.
(GABRIEL SCREAMS)
Help me!
♪ ♪
(SCREAMING)
The more you scream, the more he likes it.
What can you tell me about the people
that come in and
out of this place?
They mostly residents
or transients?
Oh, we got a bit of everything.
Some pay by the month,
some pay by the hour.
Some of the old-timers have been
here since the dawn of time.
And you?
Who are you looking for?
Not at liberty to say.
Oh, I don't mean that.
I can see the pain in your eyes.
It's very familiar.
Oh, you've lost something.
And now you're frozen in time.
Can't move forward.
Can't go back.
(GABRIEL SCREAMS)
Tell me you love me.
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
Say it!
Say, "I love you, Sally,"
and it will all go away.
Say it.
I love you, Sally.
Say it again.
Say it... again.
I love you, Sally.
(MUSIC FADES)
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Alright, I'll take it from here.
I don't have any cash.
Money isn't everything.
♪ ♪
(GASPS)
(RADIO PLAYING JAZZ)
(STATIC HISSES, MUSIC FADING)
(CHILD LAUGHS)
(MUSIC, STATIC CONTINUES)
Holden?
(PANTING)
(CHILD LAUGHS)
(MUSIC CONTINUES DISTANTLY)
(PANTING)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYS)
♪ ♪
♪ Got a big plan, his mind's
set, maybe it's right ♪
♪ At the right place
and right time, maybe tonight ♪
♪ In a whisper or handshake,
sending the sign ♪
♪ Want to make out and
kiss hard; wait, never mind ♪
♪ Late night in passing
mention it ♪
♪ Flip to her best friend, it's
no thing, maybe it slipped ♪
♪ But the slip turns to terror
and a crush to like ♪
♪ And she walked, he froze up,
leave it to fright ♪
♪ It's cute in a way
till you cannot speak ♪
♪ And you leave to have
a cigarette, knees get weak ♪
♪ It's only just a crush,
it'll go away ♪
♪ It's just like
all the others, it'll go away ♪
♪ Or maybe this is danger,
and you just don't know ♪
♪ You pray it all away,
but it continues to grow ♪
♪ Ah... ♪
♪ I want to hold you close ♪
♪ Skin pressed
against me tight ♪
♪ Lie still,
close your eyes, girl ♪
♪ So lovely, it feels so right ♪
♪ I want to hold you close ♪
♪ Soft breath, beating heart ♪
♪ As I whisper in your ear ♪
♪ "I want to tear you apart" ♪
♪ Then he walked up
and told her ♪
♪ Thinking maybe it'd pass ♪
♪ And they talked and looked
away a lot, doing the dance ♪
♪ Her hand brushed up against
his, she left it there ♪
♪ Told him how she felt, and
then they locked in a stare ♪
♪ They took a step back, thought
about it, what should they do? ♪
♪ 'Cause there's
always repercussions ♪
♪ When you're dating in school ♪
♪ But their lips met, and
reservations started to pass ♪
♪ Whether this was
just an evening ♪
♪ Or a thing that would last ♪
♪ Either way he wanted her,
and this was bad ♪
♪ Wanted to do things to her,
it was making him crazy ♪
♪ Now a little crush
turned into a like ♪
♪ And now he wants to grab her
by the hair and tell her ♪
♪ Ah... ♪
♪ I want to hold you close ♪
♪ Skin pressed
against me tight ♪
♪ Lie still,
close your eyes, girl ♪
♪ So lovely, it feels so right ♪
♪ I want to hold you close ♪
♪ Soft breath, beating heart ♪
♪ As I whisper in your ear ♪
♪ "I want to tear you apart" ♪
♪ ♪
♪ I want to hold you close ♪
♪ Skin pressed
against me tight ♪
♪ Lie still,
close your eyes, girl ♪
♪ So lovely, it feels so right ♪
♪ I want to hold you close ♪
♪ Soft breath, beating heart ♪
♪ As I whisper in your ear ♪
♪ "I want to tear you apart" ♪
♪ I want to hold you close ♪
♪ Skin pressed
against me tight ♪
♪ Lie still,
close your eyes, girl ♪
♪ So lovely, it feels so right ♪
♪ I want to hold you close ♪
♪ Soft breath, beating heart ♪
♪ As I whisper in your ear ♪
♪ "I want to tear you apart" ♪
♪ I want to hold you close ♪
♪ Soft breath, beating heart ♪
♪ As I whisper in your ear ♪
♪ "I want to tear you apart." ♪
And you didn't feel
like going out tonight.
It's not the getting ready,
it's the clean up.
Call housekeeping.
GIRL: Daddy!
Hey.
(GROWLS PLAYFULLY)
(BARKS) That's what
I've been looking for.
How you doing?
Good, how are you?
Hey, sorry I'm late.
Did you get my text?
Yes, and it's clearly
more considerate than you,
'cause it showed up at 6:00
like you were supposed to.
Sorry.
Have a kid with a sprained ankle
in Beverly Hills
and twins with possible
whooping cough
in the Palisades right after.
Whooping cough.
Can you believe it?
Let me help your mother.
What's wrong with people?
I don't care
how much they pay me,
I refuse to see parents
who won't "vax" their kids.
Doctor.
I made that quinoa
casserole you two like.
Oh, good.
You okay?
Yeah, yeah.
I'm just hungry, I think.
Well, next time you should eat
the protein bar I
stuffed in your pocket.
Love you.
Bye, Mom.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Sushi?
Read my mind.
Yeah.
(TRAY RATTLING)
VENDELA: Please, let us go.
Eh, stop your whining.
You brought this on yourselves.
(WHIMPERS)
I went through your shit.
Looks like the two of you were
planning quite the party.
Xanax. Klonopin.
Whatever the hell
those pink pills were.
Those are for sleeping.
Your mothers know you're
a couple of shameless junkies?
You're polluting your bodies
with all that shit.
You dumb Swedish meatballs.
We're gonna fix that right up.
Yeah, we're gonna
You flush your system,
bring you back to the
epitome of health.
Just look at the spread
we got for you today.
Oysters.
Full of zinc and B12.
Boost your immunity,
help your wounds heal faster.
And we got you some
chicken livers...
...kidneys, packed with iron.
Get those red blood cells
pumping.
And to top it off,
a Châteauneuf-du-Pape
Grenache blanc.
Yeah.
Please. Please, don't.
Mmm.
Shut up.
This is just the thing
to get your bodies
to absorb all these nutrients.
Stop. Stop. Stop.
Don't.
Please don't...
We can do this the easy way
or the hard way.
But I'm not leaving
until you get all
your vitamins and minerals.
Please, please.
All right. Come on.
No! No! No!
Breakfast of champions.
Open your mouth.
SALLY: Do you really need
to be so aggressive?
Can't you have some compassion?
You get the hell out of here.
You don't give a shit about these girls.
And you do?
I've seen what your
caring looks like.
We've all seen it.
At least I care about something.
Think I want to be here,
surrounded by junkies and decay?
Well, then why don't
you leave? Go.
You've been whining about
the same thing for 20 years.
You talk a good talk,
but you stick around because
the truth is you like it.
No.
I'm stuck in this
godforsaken cesspool
of pain and shit 'cause of you.
Eh.
You're the beginning and the end
of all my suffering.
Good.
Well, I'm done.
Done with your bullshit.
Done with it all.
You think you can
do this better?
Then you do it yourself.
But you better do a good job.
Otherwise you can explain to her
why they still taste like shit.
(SIGHS)
I got to go feed
that thing in room 33.
VENDELA: Please.
Please.
Do you know what
this room used to be?
This old dude used to put on
a puppet show right there.
Marionettes, strings,
for entertainment.
And now you...
...are going to entertain me.
Move me with your tears.
Run.
Run!
Oh, crap.
♪ ♪
I don't know what happened.
She got loose somehow.
This can never happen again.
Shouldn't we ask if any
of this fish is from Japan?
Why?
Radiation.
(CHUCKLES)
You're starting to
sound like your mother.
She always said she had
a good reason to worry.
I had a dream about him
again last night.
I can't see his face anymore.
I can't remember it
except in my dreams,
then I can really see it.
When I wake up...
I can't remember.
Do you remember what he looks
like when you're awake?
Yeah.
Maybe we should put
the pictures up again.
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
No electronics
at the dinner table.
It's your mom.
(PHONE LINE RINGS)
ALEX: (ON RECORDING)
You've reached Alex, please leave a message.
- (TYRES SCREECHING)
- (HOME ALARM WAILING)
GIRL: Dad, what's happening?!
Been inside yet?
OFFICER: No, I just got here.
What's going on, Detective?
JOHN: I don't know yet.
Watch my daughter.
(HOME ALARM CONTINUES WAILING)
(ALARM CONTINUES WAILING)
(INDISTINCT RADIO TRANSMISSION)
(LEAVES RUSTLES)
(ALARM CONTINUES WAILING)
(CELL PHONE BUZZES)
Alex, are you okay?
KILLER: John Lowe.
Who is this?
Where's my wife?!
I told you I'd do it again.
(ALARM CONTINUES WAILING)
Show me your hands!
(CONTINUES WAILING)
JOHN: Stop...
Stop!
(SCREAMING)
Scarlett!
(ALARM CONTINUES TO WAIL)
JOHN: All right,
honey, you got it?
Oh, so close.
I'm gonna take Holden
to the carousel.
All right, babe.
Come on, buddy.
(GASPS) Slow it down,
slow it down.
Remember, hold it like a pencil.
Throw it like a baseball.
Concentrate on where
you want it to go.
Ready? Go.
Oh! Good job!
You hungry, buddy?
Yeah, I want some cotton candy.
(CHUCKLES)
You got to eat
some real food first.
I'm not hungry for that.
No? All right,
we'll get something after.
Here you go.
You got one with yellow feet.
He's a special one.
***
Holden?
Hey, you seen my boy?
He was on that horse
with the yellow feet.
Holden!
Holden?!
Holden! Holden!
ALEX: I mean, maybe we should
just go stay with Mary.
JOHN: In New Hampshire? I don't
want to do that to Scarlett.
It's already gonna be
hard enough as it is.
She should be able
to sleep in her own bed.
I'm gonna have two uniformed
men with you at all times.
One's gonna go to school
with Scarlett, one's gonna go
to work with you, and these guys
are very good at what they do.
You're not even gonna know they
are there unless you need them.
Do you even know
what this guy looks like?
I don't understand
how he texted you from my phone.
I mean, do you think that
he knows where we live?
Jesus, John.
What are we gonna do, huh?
Maybe I should get a gun.
No. No, you-you don't need
to get a gun, all right?
There are ways to clone
somebody's phone, all right?
Don't worry.
I'm gonna keep you guys safe.
What, by moving out?
I have a feeling he's
gonna come after me again,
and if that happens, I don't
want either of you near me.
Look, I'm not upset
because you're leaving.
I'm upset because I...
I secretly want you to go.
I-I understand. You...
I shouldn't have brought
Scarlett to that house.
I thought you were in trouble,
I-I told that idiot
cop to watch her.
I'm not mad about that.
I know you would never
put her in danger.
And I don't blame you
for Holden.
No matter what you think.
I love you so much.
He looks just so much like you.
I see him in your face
every day and I just want to die.
It's not fair-- they took
my little boy from me,
and I can't even look
at the one person in the world
who understands how I feel.
I just need a break from it all.
Do you ever hope?
(SWALLOWS)
I can't stop hoping.
That's the worst part.
♪ ♪
Welcome.
The rain may have stopped,
but it's still a gloomy day.
I had to put my dog down.
He came to me through very
unfortunate circumstances.
But you don't need
to hear about that.
Right this way.
So many buildings around here
are time capsules,
locked away by
an impersonal business trust.
I prefer dealing with a trust.
Anonymous.
Unsentimental.
So you'll live here,
or just work here?
I know that you were
interested in the top floor.
We're moving our life out here.
Work, home-- I've never
kept them separate.
It's very clear to me: the art
world has looked to L.A.,
and fashion is soon to follow.
The top floor is where I'll live
and just below will be an
atelier, mostly ready-to-wear.
Lachlan!
Lachlan?
Oh.
So much energy.
IRIS: How can I help you?
Uh, I'm the realtor
representing the sale.
We're here for the walk-through.
We'll let you know
if we need anything.
Sale?
What sale?
MARCY: Well, I know it was
a whisper listing, but surely,
the owner should have told you.
Nobody tells me shit.
I've never even met the owner.
MARCY: Well, you
have now, dearie.
This is the new owner,
Mr. Will Drake.
We'll start with the penthouse?
We'll let you know
if we need anything.
(KEYS JINGLING)
We're gonna be turned
out onto the streets.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
(HISSES)
The clouds have cleared.
Sightlines all the way
to the Pacific.
DONOVAN: Close it!
The light!
Who the hell are you people?
And what are you doing
in my room?
We've been invaded.
Shanghaied!
Some goddamn New Yorker
is sizing up my suite.
A little early
for you, isn't it?
MARCY: I know you'll
prefer the view
from the space we just saw,
but here's the other half
of the floor plan.
The lighting is,
of course, a challenge
and I don't know if all
this neon is the answer.
Will Drake.
I am so pleased to meet you.
I was completely impressed
with the gown you made
for Mrs. Obama.
It was the state dinner for...
The Spaniards, yes.
Kind of you to mention.
I'm on a cleanse.
Not anymore.
(SNAPS FINGER)
Lachlan! Honestly.
Fingerprints are
really hard to get off.
Messes are always forgiven.
The first time.
Is...
Yes.
It's an Arik Levy
and it doesn't come
with the building.
Of course, I'm hopeful
you're as interested
in the character
of The Cortez as we are.
There's energy here.
I walk through New York streets and
I don't hear the music anymore.
No more echos of who I was there.
Blocks are toppled, history erased,
weirdoes banished.
This place is far enough away
that it speaks to me--
it sings, even.
Well, I cannot wait
to see what you make of it.
That's really beautiful.
So where are weirdoes like us
supposed to live, huh?
Any songs telling you
anything about that?
Perhaps you could
show our neighbor
the James Turrell
light sculpture?
Dad, can I stay
and look at the records?
Of course you can.
People aren't supposed
to live in hotels.
Well, maybe this place
is special.
I want to show you
something you'll enjoy.
We'll only be gone a moment.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
I lived in New York,
many years ago.
I loved roaming the streets,
devouring the pulse of the city.
Electrifying.
I miss it very much.
Did your father
give you a choice
when it came time to leave?
My dad says I'm not supposed
to talk to strangers.
We're not strangers, Lachlan.
We're going to be great friends.
Here we are.
What's so special
about a hallway?
(KNOCKS)
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
Holden, we have a guest.
Where are your manners, angel?
Hello. Want to play?
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
IRIS: Did you hear?
They sold the hotel.
We'll be cast to the wind.
Consider it a blessing, Mother.
You should have left
this place years ago.
I'm here because
I need to see you
every day.
Time for you to let go.
(OVER RADIO)
♪ When you're alone ♪
♪ And life is making you
lonely ♪
♪ You can always go ♪
♪ Downtown ♪
♪ When you've got worries ♪
♪ All the noise and the hurry ♪
♪ Seems to help, I know ♪
♪ Downtown ♪
♪ Just listen to the music ♪
♪ Of the traffic
in the city... ♪
♪ ♪
IRIS: Can you tell me
what room they're in?
The couple that just came in?
I'm sorry, lady.
This is a no-tell motel.
That boy is my son
and that junkie's
about to give him dope.
(SIGHS)
Here.
Oh, come on.
Where's the nearest ATM?
At the corner drugstore,
right next to the maxi pads.
(SIGHS)
Oh, brother.
Goddamn it.
There we go.
(SNIFFS)
Ah...
(LAUGHS)
You're gonna give me
a fresh needle, right?
I'm the cleanest person
you know.
- (GIGGLES)
- (POUNDING AT DOOR)
(KISSING SOUND)
(POUNDING CONTINUES)
Yeah?
What'd you give him?
Donovan?
He's out cold.
Who invited you in, lady?
What did you give him?!
China White.
Which means he is just
where he wants to be.
Call 911!
No one's calling anyone.
Come on...
I told him not to try and keep up with me.
We took the same shit
and I am more than fine.
At least until you barged in.
You can't leave!
Oh, please.
You know how much
I paid for this dope?
(CRYING) Oh, God.
Oh, God...
(DOOR SLAMS SHUT)
(HUMMING QUIETLY)
♪ ♪
(APPROACHING FOOTSTEPS)
(SCREAMING)
(COUGHS)
("HOTEL CALIFORNIA" PLAYS)
Who are you?
Your boy has a jawline for days.
♪ ♪
♪ On a dark desert highway ♪
♪ Cool wind in my hair ♪
♪ Warm smell of colitas ♪
♪ Rising up through the air ♪
♪ Up ahead in the distance ♪
♪ I saw a shimmering light ♪
♪ My head grew heavy
and my sight grew dim ♪
♪ I had to stop for the night ♪
♪ There she stood
in the doorway ♪
♪ I heard the mission bell ♪
♪ And I was thinking to myself ♪
♪ This could be heaven ♪
♪ Or this could be hell ♪
♪ Then she lit up her candle ♪
♪ And she showed me the way ♪
♪ There were voices
down the corridor ♪
♪ Thought I heard them say ♪
♪ Such a lovely place ♪
♪ Such a lovely face ♪
♪ They livin' it up
at the Hotel California ♪
♪ What a nice surprise ♪
♪ Bring your alibis ♪
♪ Mirrors on the ceiling ♪
♪ The pink champagne on ice ♪
♪ And she said, we are all
just prisoners here ♪
♪ Of our own device ♪
♪ And in the master's chambers ♪
♪ They gathered for the feast ♪
♪ They stab it
with their steely knives ♪
♪ But they just can't
kill the beast ♪
♪ Last thing I remember ♪
♪ I was running for the door ♪
♪ I had to find
the passage back ♪
♪ To the place I was before ♪
♪ Relax, said the night man ♪
♪ We are programmed to receive ♪
♪ You can check out
any time you like ♪
♪ But you can never leave... ♪