Previously on SEAL Team...
What is it?
Nothing.
Kind of "nothing" you need me
to torch if you don't come back?
Ray, just bring my burn box, will you?
I'm asking the court
to give Ben a second chance
at having a good life.
Because I know Clay...
he'd think he deserved it.
This team needs Bravo 1.
Yeah, well, I hope not.
Because you're gonna
have to manage without me.
Is Mikey that bad?
Gonna need reconstructive surgery,
- so I got to be there for him.
- The rumors
of Bravo's demise
are greatly exaggerated.
Ain't that right, Magic Mike?
You are my priority, 100%, full attention.
Mikey.
What the fuck?
Michael's blood test
showed tranq in his system.
Tranq?
Fentanyl mixed with Xylazine,
an animal tranquilizer.
When I got hurt wrestling,
a-a teammate gave me some pain pills.
And I never used any,
but they were still in my bag.
Mikey didn't know when you'd be home.
So he took one.
Why am I in the hospital?
You had to work a problem that I created.
One of the reasons
why I came back home
was to show that I could
finally have a balanced life
being Bravo 1
and a dad.
Well, that just blew up in my face.
Because I almost got
my son killed and my teammates.
I'm just starting to believe
that war does have the last word.
So, how many more days you got
till you hang it up forever, Ray?
Fourteen. Not that
my whole family is obsessively
counting or anything.
And, yet here you are, still training.
Yeah. I get it.
It's hard to pass on the chance
to peg paintballs
into Sonny's throat.
Not gonna clock out early after 20 years.
All right, good. 'Cause I will take
every ounce of that
old man wisdom I can get.
Come on, you can't wait
to invade his cage.
Thirstier than a Mormon in a saloon.
Hey!
The bigger surprise is casting
Drew as the third Stooge.
He's still at Shemp level,
but under my tutelage,
he, may... may... unlock Curly.
I'm fucking Moe, you knucklehead.
Yeah, well,
kicking ass in Asia
cemented us as a go-to team,
and you are Bravo for the long haul now.
Bravo doesn't rebuild, we reload.
Well, all this team rah-rah,
maybe it's time Drew
claims a cage in here.
I'm good where I'm at.
Squirreling your gear in the,
abandoned, likely haunted,
basement of DEVGRU?
I don't mind the ghosts.
Understood.
Look who it is.
Big guy.
Long time no see, boss.
Well, just here for the muster.
How's Mikey? Torn ACL... that's rough.
With that Hayes grit, he's
probably kicking doors already.
Yeah.
Yeah, his knee's, you know,
it's coming along.
So, I heard you guys had
one hell of a last op?
Young guns made it through
the fire all on their own.
Look, I'm sorry
I left you guys all exposed.
- You kidding me, man?
- It was good for the underlings
to get their hands dirty, you know?
Besides, you were taking care
of more important things.
Weren't you? Like your son. Okay?
All right?
This way, Dad.
Right behind you, baby girl.
You put these here all wrong.
I was just distracted by all
the progress you and Mom made.
Seems like you wanted
to do it as fast as possible.
You know what, I'm gonna
go grab the other boxes
and try to limit my collateral damage.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Your daughter's working me hard.
She is so excited to have you here.
To keep having you here.
It's gonna be quite a change.
Can you believe it?
Two weeks and our "tomorrow"
finally begins.
Everything we've been waiting for.
How's it going, hon?
Good. Just finishing this one.
Sorry, I lost you for a second there.
Can you just say that one more time?
Hi.
Right, okay.
Great, thanks, Doctor. I appreciate it.
Mikey's CT results?
We're good, we're clear. There's no,
there's no sign of,
brain or organ damage
that, you know, leads to...
What a relief.
Thank God.
Right, Mikey? That's a relief.
No, I heard.
Only one busted head in the family.
Brad will be so relieved.
Assuming I ever connect with him.
I guess they don't
carve out a lot
of personal time in BUD/S.
- Right? She's going...
- Right, right. Right. Right.
That's right. Probably
can't remember his name, right?
After making sugar cookies all day.
I'd rather freeze my ass off in the Pacific
than listen to all this wedding talk.
Listen.
Mission success is determined
during mission planning. Okay, Mikey?
Hey, you know,
one family member spouting
military clichés is plenty, Mandy.
I'm gonna leave Brad a voice mail.
Time for me to run back to my hotel.
I may return
bearing pizza.
Right, okay, I'll...
Look, I can go and get food. Why don't...
No, no, you need
alone time with the kids.
Almost as much as I need a shower.
Hey, bud?
We, still need to talk, you know?
There's, still somebody out there.
Are you still chasing this bogeyman?
Right, the bogeyman
that gave your friend
the fentanyl-laced pill
- that nearly killed you.
- I told you.
Doug warned the person
that gave him the pills
to flush the rest.
- Who gave Doug the pill?
- Why's it matter?
It matters because he needs
to be held accountable.
What are you gonna do...
kick down his door?
Leave it alone, Dad.
I'm alive, thanks to you.
Mission accomplished, right?
Good. I have to show you something.
Got a location update on the barrels
of Chinese fentanyl precursor
that Bravo Team tagged at Heron Reef.
The barrels that landed
in Mexico three days ago?
Turns out the voyage continued
for some of the cargo.
One of the six tagged barrels
just landed in the port of La Ceiba.
Honduras.
SSE from the cartel members
that Bravo took out
indicated their bosses
in Tijuana were angry
about some shipments that
turned up lighter than usual.
Someone suicidal
skimming from a Mexican cartel?
Or the Chinese dipping
their toe into the market.
Attention on deck.
At ease, at ease.
Admiral Rivas. I wasn't aware
you were up from SOCOM, sir.
Had a sit-down with Captain Walch,
thought I'd see how
our DEVGRU liaison was doing.
Well, sir, having to surrender
our Chinese HVT
was a disappointing turn
for our first
integrated deterrence mission,
but we still have some
intel irons in the fire
that might redeem it.
From where I sit, that first
outing was already a win.
We gleaned hard evidence
of Beijing's involvement
in the fentanyl trade,
ammo we can use against them.
I'm thrilled to hear you say that, sir.
Between us, Lieutenant?
I'm heading to the Pentagon
this afternoon.
Some talk of me bumping up
to a new role.
That happens,
I'm gonna need a first-class
admiral's aide as my right hand.
Sir, that'll be a huge honor for someone.
I don't want someone.
I want the brilliant officer
that shepherded this program
from the start.
What would you think of that promotion?
Sir, it would be an absolute dream
to have that impact.
Great.
We'll talk later.
The first thing you
need to understand, Sonny,
is how little you understand.
Okay.
Bringing an invention to the gear market
it-it's a treacherous journey.
Sharks around every corner...
including within the Navy
will try to exploit you, steal your ideas,
undercut your profits.
All this shark talk, I'm gonna
have to change my underwear.
Lucky for you, we at
Huntley Tactical can guide you.
If we deem it worthy
of our time and energy.
Can I be frank?
Shoot.
Your blowout kit's a fun little notion,
but it's gonna take a heavy investment
from people who actually
know what they're doing.
I got to go to the bathroom.
Excuse me, sir.
God dang it.
Man, come on, Sonny, get it together.
They hate my med kit
more than they hate me.
Do you really think they'd endure
watching you deep-throat that steak
if they didn't see dollar signs?
Listen, man, I-I
I stashed you back here
for answers, okay?
- And not questions.
- Well, they're negging you.
Like, trying to beat you down
then save you with a low ball offer.
I-I'd much rather they
give me a kick in the nuts
than continue with this misery.
No, they're using
the same script my old man uses
every time he gets his eye
on a new sailboat or wife.
Okay, so, wh-what... w-what
do I... what do I do here?
Hey, know what scares the living
shit out of people with money?
- What?
- People that aren't driven by it.
Let 'em know you've got
other buyers interested.
They'll get more worked up
than Omar at a T-Swizzle show.
Okay. Play hard to get.
Play hard to get.
Slap me in the face right now, do it.
- Slap you in the face?
- Slap me in the face.
- There we go.
- Kick some ass.
All right. Here we go.
Sorry about that, gentlemen.
I
I got another offer.
In the men's room?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's a... it's a military town.
You know, we think there's been
enough talk from this side of the table.
Team guy to Team guy.
What do you want out of this invention?
Well.
I just want to make sure that my baby girl
she's taken care of,
no matter what happens to me.
There we go. Let's work from that.
Hey, Coach Turek. This is Jason Hayes,
calling you back again.
Listen, I need you to get back to me.
I'm trying to work a problem.
I need to, talk to you
about a few of your wrestlers,
Doug Mitchell being one of them.
I'm, trying to fix a problem here.
Can you just please give me
a call back when you can?
Thanks.
- Where are the kids?
- Mikey was going
stir crazy, so Emma took him for a ride.
Nice.
Sibling time for them
means we get to eat.
- You want a beer?
- Sure. Yeah. Beer's good.
Did I interrupt you
planning a mud wrestling match
to boost Mikey's spirits?
That was nothing.
Okay. Well
now I know it's not nothing.
I'm just trying to get in touch
with his wrestling coach, okay?
Mikey's friend's wrestling coach.
Tell me you're not going Columbo
on that laced Percocet?
I need to find out
who that pill came from.
- Why are you sharking?
- I'm sharking so I can nail
the fucker who's pushing that poison.
You going seek-and-destroy mode
isn't gonna help anything.
Well, it's gonna help me start
to work the problem, Mandy.
Taking care of Mikey,
that's the problem that you're working.
You know what?
I left deployment early
so I could come back here
and be an asset,
but I'm nothing but a fucking liability.
It was an accident.
Accident was me thinking
that I could have
some kind of a balanced life here.
Why would you say that?
Mikey OD'ing does not condemn you.
Mikey's just a drop in the bucket.
Heard you were looking for me?
Yes, I'm eager to run
something by you, sir.
The barrels of fentanyl
precursor that Bravo tagged,
one of them landed in Honduras.
Made me wonder what sway
that cargo was buying Beijing
in a volatile nation.
Well, it's no secret.
China's been setting a foothold
in the region.
Gifting public works projects
everywhere from Brazil to Cuba.
Right, but Honduras has been
more resistant to their advances.
So when the Taiwanese embassy
was firebombed last month,
the Agency dug into who was
behind such a pro-China move.
It was this man.
Ramon Nazario.
Former Honduran Special Forces colonel
who's been living off the grid
with a guerrilla force
and a populist following.
So why is he doing dirty work for China?
Pipeline of fentanyl precursor
is a hell of an incentive.
Intel suggests he's had his eye
on overthrowing Honduran leadership.
An injection of drug money
could fuel that.
Is this all a windup to a pitch
for the next
integrated deterrence mission?
Guess Rivas dangling
that promotion has you
gunning even harder on his behalf.
Yeah, he mentioned it.
Man has an impeccable eye for talent.
Thank you, sir, but, this isn't about me.
This is about China using drug money
to fund a coup in our backyard
and how we stop it.
Hey, what are you doing back here?
Blackburn called me.
Him and Walch want to talk to me.
Probably red ass about that
whole TBI power move we pulled.
I'm sure it's nothing to stress about.
- Asia put us back on the brass's good side.
- That's good.
Maybe we'll be heading
outside the wire, right?
Getting some old-school Bravo 1 energy.
Maybe, maybe throttle down
before you head in there?
What's-what's wrong?
Just dealing with some shit with Mikey.
Being cooped up in that,
garage apartment together.
Hayes men are bound
to bump protruding craniums
at some point.
You'll-you'll patch things up.
You know, I'm better at breaking
things than fixing them.
Not like you. You got that gift, right?
Helping people out with Spenser House.
1,000 miles from helping anyone, Jace.
You know, the modesty thing just
gives me a fucking headache,
Ray, all right? Just,
be grateful that your future's sorted out.
Come on in, Master Chief.
Seems Bravo has finally made it
through the choppy swell
to smoother waters.
And you've more than earned
your sweat equity with me.
So, want to talk about
something personal to you.
Sir?
Your push for action on TBI
while a tad dramatic...
has been answered.
DEVGRU's creating a new position
to work full-time on it.
Someone to guide war fighters
through treatment options
and track progress
in com batting the epidemic.
What do you think?
Navy should've been doing this all along.
He means what do you think
about taking on this job?
You're passionate about the issue.
The fact that you recently
offered up your Trident
tells me you're looking to what's next.
Well, I've been reminded that,
carrying a rifle is how I make my impact.
Your personal experience,
your fire for protecting your brothers.
I know you could excel in this role.
Think about it, Master Chief.
And it's still the early stages,
so keep it between us for now.
Yes, sir.
Mark my words, boys.
Tsunamis, nuclear meltdowns,
solar flares.
No match for the chaos
that will be unleashed
by Sonny Quinn with cash to blow.
That's right.
All right, boys. Well, look.
The deal ain't signed yet. Okay?
But I'll tell you what,
if it wasn't for
Trump Drewniversity over here
schooling me through, I don't know, man.
Like a wise man once said,
"Mo' money..."
No problems. That's right.
Tell you what, we got, cash in my pocket.
Bravo is back in swing. Come on now.
We're walking on Sonny-shine.
Look at this, he got jokes
like, Lenny Drewce.
You're early.
Caught the lone wolf
of the Franklin dynasty
yukking it up with what looks
like a tight pack of friends.
- Hey.
- Gonna introduce me?
Boozy soundbites are podcast gold.
They're just coworkers.
And holster that thing.
I said we'd talk about,
you know, maybe talking
about my family.
And we're not doing that here.
Come on.
Swing and a run.
Your great-grandfather built
a landmark mansion in Newport,
and you've created a home on wheels.
Come on in.
Unless you want to try a fourth bar
where we can't hear each other
over songs about trucks.
"She was a journalist,
naively looking for color for her story."
I'm not buying that scared act
from the fearless reporter.
Couple of your relatives
couldn't get me in this van,
I'll tell you that much.
So, you ever go back to Newport?
I hear that polo tournament
your family puts on
is pretty chichi.
I'll take bullets and bombs
over those uptight snobs.
Home can be tough.
When I go, my dad still guilts me
about not following him into
a career in cement sales, so...
No, my pops is too busy ghosting me
to do the, you know,
"follow my footsteps" thing.
And your mom?
I thought you knew all about that.
Not from you.
Yeah, she took off when I was 12.
Moved to France.
She left me and my sister behind.
I'm sure you've heard
what some people say.
Fuck what they say.
All people do is hurt and disappoint.
No, but, hey, you know,
without that damage,
you know, I might not be
you know, intriguing enough
to get you inside here.
You sure you don't want one?
I've got nowhere to be.
I
I shouldn't do this.
Yeah. I got it.
I need to go.
Fuck.
Boys.
I refiled the intake forms again
and updated your seminar schedule.
Great.
Feel like taking another stab
at fixing the printer?
Based on a recent run-in I had
with an air conditioner,
I probably should stay away, baby.
I can help.
Let's give a nod to
child labor laws on this one.
- Hey, Naima.
- Hey, Sonny.
- Hey, what's up, man?
- How are you?
What's up? What you doing here?
Hangover IV ain't on the menu.
No, actually, I brought somebody.
Ben, reached out to me this morning
when he got released.
And
well, I knew that you, you
guys hadn't met before.
No, we have not.
- Hello.
- Then, well
Ben, he's trying
to get his life together, and
he's looking for help.
And he needs you talking for him?
What...
What exactly are you
looking for here, Ben?
Was hoping to continue the progress
- that I was making before.
- And all the
the hurt that you caused
that's-that's progress?
Ray.
I'm sorry.
I know that Clay was
your friend, and I'm sorry...
No!
No, if you were sorry,
you wouldn't show your face here,
- so get out.
- But I was trying...
Get the fuck out!
Now!
Ben. Ben.
Really?
Ray, what was that?
I got to go to work.
Of course you do.
Ray, if we're getting spun up this close
to your end date,
you don't have to go, right?
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
The minute Drew gets here,
I got to get to this briefing, boys.
He's MIA.
Look, I've been texting Drew all morning.
Radio silence.
You think maybe he slept in
with that chick from the bar?
Somebody want to tell me
where the fuck Drew is?
Yeah, he was...
He was, he told me
he was going up to Norfolk
to get his gun serviced,
but you know how, like,
that place is like
a cell phone black hole, okay?
- Let's go.
- I tried calling him,
and all I heard was like...
Gentlemen, last time I addressed you,
I challenged you
to be the tip of the spear
rather than a pain in my ass.
Well, after your work
in the Golden Triangle,
consider yourselves back at the top
of the DEVGRU food chain.
Lieutenant Davis is here to brief you
on a joint SOCOM-CIA mission.
Where's Franklin?
Stuck on a gear run, sir, we'll fill him in.
Thanks to Bravo's efforts
in the Golden Triangle,
we have a working theory
that fentanyl precursors
trafficked by the Beijing-backed
Sai Lou syndicate
have been funneled to this man.
Ramon Nazario.
Former Honduran Army colonel who ran
their elite Spec Ops unit, Los Panteras,
currently believed to have designs
on a forceful overthrow
of his government.
A coup that we suspect will be financed
by turning the Chinese chemicals
into millions on the illicit drug market.
Honduras?
I thought it was the Mexican cartel
that was pushing this toxic poison on us.
They are.
But the more dire threat is
Nazario's potential rise
a narco-fueled Honduran head of state
who would be utterly beholden to Beijing.
Doped-up commie puppet show
right here in our backyard.
A Chinese proxy so close
to our borders would have
seismic implications
for American standing and security.
We cannot let that happen.
To that end, Bravo Team will be deploying
to La Ceiba, Honduras,
with the mission of proving
the Chinese-Nazario connection
and potentially neutralizing the HVT.
We still treading lightly
like we did in Asia?
Sneak, creep and, hold fire?
The number of violent factions
in the region's drug trade
offers more cover
for direct action without fear
of international escalation.
Plus, Agency assistance will help
conceal American presence.
The gloves are off, gentlemen.
- Happy hunting.
- Wheels up tomorrow.
0800.
All right, listen up, boys.
Long overdue for a little
seek and destroy here,
so let's dial it in. Got it?
Well, you sure you're even going, boss?
I mean, with Mikey
still at home healing up?
I'm going.
I know how to handle this problem.
Well, how about the fact that Drew
didn't even show for this briefing?
He misses troop movement,
he's out. Got it?
We're on it.
Ray. Hold up.
Look, I talked to Blackburn.
You're clear to stay home.
I didn't ask you to do that. What...
Did Sonny say something to you?
About what?
Nothing. Nothing.
Look, I'm going on this deployment.
That's still my job, okay?
Just saying, seems like things
may get a little kinetic down there.
You say that as if
you're looking forward to it.
Ray, you know what? You're so
close to spiking the football,
I don't want you to risk everything.
I'll see you on the tarmac.
What do you mean leaving tomorrow?
They can't do that to you. Not now.
I'm still on the clock, baby.
I mean, if you're really going,
then we need to talk.
What happened with Ben?
Surprised me at the wrong moment is all.
Is it your PTS?
What? No, no. Babe, no.
No, that's under control.
Because I haven't seen you
that angry since
I'm just supposed to welcome him
like he didn't get my brother killed?
I felt ambushed is all, babe.
Sonny should've known better
than to bring him in there.
It's exactly where Sonny
should've taken him.
Imagine how much pain Ben must be in,
how badly he needs our help,
to step foot in Spenser House again.
Yeah... needing help's been
on my mind, too.
I let Bravo roll without me
on our last op in Asia,
and,
and they nearly got wiped out.
Felt like I turned my back on them.
So, by retiring, you're
abandoning your brothers?
I don't know.
But who's gonna look after them
has been weighing on me.
Look, baby,
I should not have snapped
in front of you and Jameelah.
I'm sorry.
Can't you talk to Command?
Ask to stay home from this deployment?
I have to look after my guys.
Until the end.
That's all there is to it.
All this is all so sudden. I'm sorry.
It's fine, really.
I'm glad to get back
to my friends at school.
And Brad could use some support
back in Coronado.
We've learned to manage
without you, Dad, don't worry.
I'll drive Mikey up
this afternoon
and get him settled at school,
then fly home from there.
Maybe you and Mandy could
come visit when you're home.
Burritos really are better in California.
That sounds fun. I'll look at some dates.
I'm not sure Command's
gonna let me go this time.
You don't need
DEVGRU's permission to come see me?
Op tempo's picking back up.
I got to be all in all the time.
I'm sorry I took you
away from Bravo, Dad,
but I really loved
spending so much time with you,
you know, near-death experience and all.
Look, guys, I'm.
I'm really proud of both of you.
Everything you've had
to overcome on your own.
I love you.
Love you.
Hello, Drewnabomber.
Hello?
- We got movement.
- Yeah, I see him.
Put your clothes on.
Let's go, princess.
You guys ever hear of taking a hint?
Well, we don't just watch each
other's backs outside the wire.
Well, I hope this means you got
whatever's going on out of your system.
So, you overslept, missed
the war no, Cock-a-Doodle-Drew.
Omar and I covered for you.
I don't recall asking you to do that.
You miss the troop movement,
and Jace, he's not gonna be able
to revive you, you understand?
Well, feels like a no-go, boys.
Would you quit fucking around?
You're gonna be there, Drew.
No, I'll take that action.
How much we betting?
What are you doing, man?
This self-sabotage shit, it's got to stop.
Every squad you've been with
since Echo,
you shoot yourself in the foot, get tossed.
Right about now,
when you might be settling in.
Hey, it's All the President's Frogmen.
It's Woodward and Bern-sonny.
Take yourself off the team
so the team can't be taken from you.
Is that what you're trying to do here?
Psychoanalysis from the guy
whose deepest wish
is to call Jason "Mommy."
Yeah, easier to torch it all
and just run, yeah?
I've been there.
Cost me more than you can imagine.
I didn't, I didn't realize
we were measuring sob stories.
Man, I wish it were just a story.
Being a dope like you're being,
man, that cost me my son.
You do this,
you will regret it
every single day.
You be on that plane tomorrow.
Drew, look at me. Hey.
Look at me.
Be my worst enemy.
Not yours.
Well, thanks for stopping by.
Ace, hang on to these.
First kill is something
worth remembering.
Fuck.
You wanted to see me, sir?
I got everybody cranking
on those target packages for Bravo's trip.
It's not what I called you here for.
We need to talk, it's
regarding your future.
You mean my potential opportunity
with Admiral Rivas? I hope you know that
I would have discussed this with
you when the time was right.
- No, it's not that.
- As much as I'd miss serving here,
the chance to work
at that level in the Pentagon
is something I can't pass up.
And frankly, sir
it's a role that
would mean everything to me.
It's a career-maker, no doubt.
But listen.
You should close the door.
We're just gonna ignore
what's going on with you?
- Let's not do this right now.
- Okay.
Let's not do this, I...
Right, so you're already
back to: Your mission
and your men come first.
You know what, I cannot bring
all of this outside the wire with me.
Not now.
I thought you weren't that guy anymore.
So your fear that operating
again would destroy
all the progress you've made,
you're telling me
- that came true?
- Actually, all the work
that I have done has
actually helped me get over
what's happened to me, Mandy.
But not
not what you've inflicted on others.
Well, that's why the night
terrors are back haunting you?
Look, it's not haunting.
It is just reminding me
who I am, what I've become,
and what I have fucking done.
It's the same dream over and over.
You know, clearing a house
in Sangbor, Afghanistan.
It's the early days of the war.
Dime-a-dozen HVTs
hit our convoy the day before.
It was my first kill.
Took his prayer beads like
it was some kind of a trophy.
Little did I know how much shame
that would bring to me.
What shame?
The killings.
Just... all the killings.
In service of your country.
There's no shame in that.
There's a reason why
executioners wear masks.
I am contaminated.
How did Emma and Mikey turn out
so great, then,
if you're so toxic?
Because of their mother.
Friends, you know, schools they went to.
You know, the one time I tried
to come back and be a parent,
the one time
Mikey almost gets killed.
Everything that is good in them
does not come from me.
Only a few weeks ago,
you saw a life for yourself
after operating.
And now you're itching
to run back into the fire.
Why? What's that gonna help?
Yeah, fire is where I belong.
Nothing more to say.
I got to do what I got to do.
Damn it.
- This is Drew. Leave a message.
- Hey, anything for Drew?
- No.
- Man.
Should've frog-marched
his self-destructive ass here
when we had the chance.
Yeah. Hey, Davis?
What's got you slumming
with the unwashed masses?
Blackburn thought I should be present
to keep Bravo's eye
on strategic objectives.
So, SOCOM agreed.
Hitching with us below
a shooting star like yourself?
Just doing what I'm ordered.
Longer we wait
to tell Jason we lost Drew,
the bigger the blast radius is gonna be.
Well, you want to be 2IC, right?
So now's the time. Have at it.
No fucking way.
Look, he associates you
with disappointment already.
This is your rodeo.
You are going first
through every damn door
we hit when we get there,
you understand?
I know you tried to talk me out of it,
but I still got a job to do.
I don't need an explanation, Ray.
Hey, Jace, can I talk to you for a sec?
- What?
- Okay, so look.
Drew, h-he is a certifiable...
- Spit it out, Sonny.
- Asshole.
He's an asshole
- that... we are lucky to have.
- Yeah, he is, right?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- Yep, just wanted to let you know.
You want to be a businessman, Sonny,
learn to spot a bluff.
Wow.
That's so funny, Drew. Funny guy.
- This fucking guy.
- Unbelievable.
Squeezing in one last sun-soaked trip
on the government's dime?
Yeah, something like that.
Look, Sonny.
I'm sorry I got ugly with Ben.
I probably should've given you
a heads-up, you know?
But, hey, St. Ray is allowed
a stumble or two.
Way you've been able
to support Ben in spite of
everything.
I ain't the one wearing the halo.
Listen, man, you're gonna get
a thousand more chances
to help guys like Ben.
And you will.
'Cause that's the kind of guy
you are, Ray. Right?
Yeah, right.
Property was seized
in a cartel sting a decade back.
CIA bought it through a front,
so, goes without saying,
we need to keep a low profile
even in the safe house.
The late booger sugar era
with Scarface-ian touches.
It's tasteful.
El Rojo.
This must be the dethroned kingpin
whose gold toilets we'll be using.
A gangster fueled
by cocaine and hubris
instead of the Chinese state.
Simpler times.
I'll take throwback commando action
for O.G. Bravo's last ride.
What do you say, Jace?
Well, if you're banging this
whole "Bravo is dying" drum,
I just don't want to hear it, Sonny.
I'm not. I'm not.
Okay, look, I was wrong about that.
You know, even with Ray leaving
and-and... and you realizing
you can't do this forever,
I'm... I'm gonna be okay with that.
The next men up... they will hold the line.
I'm just glad that you got
something else to hold on to
other than your trident.
"Osman 'El Rojo' Garcia
was an especially feared figure
"in the Central American drug trade.
"A ruthless, bloodthirsty man
who torched his enemies,
"took no prisoners,
and mowed down anything
that got in his way."
Whatever gets the job done.
- Move, move, move.
- Fuck.
All clear in here.
- Nothing?
Target clear.
I got nothing.
Dry hole after dry hole.
What are we hitting next?
How about we catch our breath, Jason?
How about we find another target, okay?
Let's go.
Trackers on the fentanyl chemicals
you tagged in Asia are still offline.
Right. And we're 0-for-fucking-6
on supposed drug-trade targets.
Well, we can't start tying
the Chinese fentanyl
to our would-be insurrectionist
until we actually get a whiff
of the product.
Well, seems
the product might have come
with a lesson in trade craft.
Local traffickers
are a step ahead of our intel.
All right, look,
what are these places here?
Potential stash houses.
Shots in the dark as shaky
as the ones we've taken.
We may need to wait
for more robust intelligence.
From the same Agency oracles
that got us this far?
Fuck it. Keep swinging
till we get a hit, got it?
The old "even a blind pig
can find some fentanyl" tactic.
Look, every door we kick,
we risk exposing our presence.
Came all this way for a reason.
Let's keep getting after it.
That's a good idea.
Blue, blue, blue, blue.
Clear.
Son of a bitch.
Fuck! Anything?
Computers, a fucking phone?
I got cobwebs and cucarachas.
Fuck!
- Jace.
- What?
I don't want to hear it.
- No, Jason.
- Shit.
Place is a cash house.
Wait, that's at least a million right here.
It could be in all the walls.
Whoever's banking here isn't gonna
leave it unattended for long.
We need to set up surveillance
outside for when they show.
Finally get ourselves some leads
to chase.
Fuck chasing 'em.
We'll bring 'em running to us.
Look at that.
Let's go, boys. Move.
Time to light her up.
Is anyone gonna get judgy
if I duffel-bag my baby's girl's
college fund right here?
Let's go.
Let's fucking roll, come on, move.
We got two hidden cams
and a cell phone sniffer
all wired here to be left in place.
The feed'll route back to the safe house.
We can start clocking faces, vehicles,
cell phones of anyone who shows up.
Captioning sponsored by CBS.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org