(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
MAN: You did a wonderful job.
Wonderful.
(SHUSHING)
MAN: You did it. You did it!
(MAN LAUGHING)
To continue, you've listened
to a long and complex case,
murder in the first degree.
Premeditated murder
is the most serious charge
tried in our criminal courts.
You've listened
to the testimony,
.
you've had the law read
to you and interpreted
as it applies in this case
It's now your duty to sit down
and try and separate the facts
from the fancy.
One man is dead.
Another man's
life is at stake.
If there's a reasonable doubt
in your minds as to the guilt
of the accused,
a reasonable doubt,
then you must bring me
a verdict of not guilty.
If, however, there's no
reasonable doubt, then you
must, in good conscience,
find the accused guilty.
However you decide
, your verdict
must be unanimous.
In the event that you
find the accused guilty,
the bench will not entertain
a recommendation for mercy.
The death sentence
is mandatory in this case.
You are faced with
a grave responsibility
. Thank you, gentlemen.
The alternate jurors
are excused.
The jury will now retire.
(EXCLAIMS)
(EXHALES)
Want a piece of gum?
No, thanks.
JUROR #6:
This thing isn't moving.
I'll give you
a hand with that.
Oh, thank you.
That's it.
(SIGHS)
You know something?
I called the Weather Burea
u this morning.
This is going to be
the hottest day of the year.
You'd think they'd at least
air-condition these places.
What is your name, sir?
Oh, it's that one. Yeah.
Thank you very much.
Okay, gentlemen.
Everybody's here.
Now, if there's anything
you want I'll be right
outside the door. Just knock.
Okay.
(DOOR LOCKING)
Good morning.
I never knew they
locked the door.
Sure they lock the door.
What did you think?
I don't know.
It just never
occurred to me.
What's that for?
Oh, I thought
we might want
to vote by ballot.
Great idea.
Maybe we can get him
elected senator.
(LAUGHING)
(COUGHING)
How'd you like it?
Oh, I don't know.
It was pretty interesting.
Yeah?
I almost fell asleep.
I mean, I've never
been on a jury before.
No?
I've sat on many juries.
What gets me is the wa
y those lawyers talk
and talk and talk,
even when it's
an open-and-shut case
like this one.
?
I mean, did you ever hear
so much talk about nothing
Well, I guess
they're entitled.
They're entitled.
It's the system,
but, if you ask me,
I'd slap those tough kids
down before they start
any trouble.
?
It saves a lot
of time and money.
Let's get started, huh
JUROR #4: Good idea.
JUROR #7: Yeah.
Let's get going, huh?
JUROR #7: We've probably
all got things to do here.
I figured we'd start out
with a five-minute break.
There's one gentleman
in the bathroom.
All right. Are we going
to sit in order?
Gee, I don't know.
I guess so.
Buddy,
you're in my seat.
Oh, excuse me.
That's all right.
Hey, that's not
a bad view, huh?
What did you think
of the case?
I mean, it had a lot
of interest for me.
No real dead spots.
You know what I mean?
I tell you,
we were lucky to
get a murder case.
I figured us for
an assault or burglary.
Boy, they can be
the dullest!
Hey, is that
the Woolworth Building?
That's right.
Isn't that funny?
I've lived here all my life.
I've never been inside that.
JUROR #10: ...you had to sort
out all that junk,
like that thing
with the movies.
JUROR #7: Yeah, you can say
that again. What about that
business with the knife?
I mean,
asking grown-up people
to believe that kind of jazz.
You expect that.
You know what
we're dealing with.
Yeah, I guess so.
(BLOWING NOSE)
Well, your horn works.
Now try your lights.
What, you got a cold?
And how.
These hot-weather colds
can kill you.
I can hardly touch my nose.
You know what I mean?
Sure do.
I just got over one.
Oh, come on!
Mr. Foreman,
let's go here.
Well, the guy's still
in the bathroom.
What's new?
I didn't get a chance
to see a paper this morning.
I was only wondering
how the market closed.
You got a seat
on the exchange?
I'm a broker.
I run a messenger service.
The Beck and Call Company.
The name was my wife's idea.
Got 37 men working.
Started with nothing.
Okay, men. Let's take
our seats, huh?
Yeah, we can all
get out of here
pretty quick, huh?
I don't know
about the rest of you,
but I happen to have tickets
to that ball game tonight.
Yanks and Cleveland.
We've got this kid
Modjelewski in there.
He's a real bull, this kid.
You know...
(IMITATING BALL ZIPPING)
Real jug handle.
You know?
(IMITATING BALL ZIPPING)
You're a real
baseball fan,
aren't you?
Where do w
e sit here?
I thought we'd sit in order,
you know, by jury numbers.
One, two, three, four, five
and so on around the table,
if that's okay
with you gentlemen.
What's the difference?
I think it's reasonabl
e to sit in order.
Let it be.
Number twelve,
you sit down right here.
Yeah, we have 12.
We go around...
Start with you at one, right?
.
Two, three, four,
five, six.
Two, three, four..
What was your impression
of the prosecuting attorney?
I beg pardon?
I thought he was really sharp,
the way he handled all those
points, one by one, in logical
sequence.
I was very impressed.
I think he did
an expert job.
A lot of drive, too,
you know? Real drive.
Okay, fellows.
Can we hold it
down a minute?
Fellows? Say,
we'd like
to get started.
Gentleman at the window.
We'd like to get started.
Oh, I'm sorry.
JUROR #10: Pretty tough
to figure, isn't it?
The kid kills his father,
just like that.
Oh, listen, you analyze
the figures, you'll see it
happens all the time.
I'm telling you,
they let those kids
run wild up there.
Well, maybe it
serves him right.
You know what I mean?
Is everyone here?
The old man is inside.
Would you knock on
the door for him?
Yeah.
?
Are you a
Yankee fan
No, Baltimore.
Baltimore?
.
It's like being hi
t in the head with a
crowbar once a day
(CHUCKLES)
Who have they got?
I mean, who have they got
besides good groundskeepers?
JUROR #1: Say,
we'd like to get started.
Forgive me, gentlemen.
I didn't mean to
keep you waiting.
Baltimore?
Okay, gentlemen,
if I can have your attention.
You fellows can
handle this thing
any way that you want to.
I'm... You know,
I'm not going
to make any rules.
We can, well,
discuss it first,
and then vote on it.
That's, of course...
That's one way.
And, well, we can vote on it
right now, then.
I think it's customary
to take a preliminary vote.
Yeah, let's vote.
Who knows?
Maybe we can all
get out of here.
Uh-huh.
Okay. Then I think that,
of course, you know that
we have a first-degree
murder charge here,
and if we vote
the accused guilty,
we've got to send
him to the chair.
That's mandatory.
I think we
know that.
Yeah, let's se
e who's where.
JUROR #1: Okay.
Anyone doesn't want to vote?
JUROR #12:
It's fine with me.
Okay, then, just remember
that this has to be 12
to nothing, either way.
That's the law.
Okay, are we ready?
All those voting guilty,
please raise your hands.
One, two, three,
four, five, six, seven,
eight, nine, ten, eleven.
.
Okay, that's 11 guilty
Those voting not guilty?
One. Right.
.
11 guilty,
one not guilty
Well, now we know
where we are.
.
Boy, oh, boy!
There's always one
)
(CHUCKLING
So, what do we do now?
I guess we talk.
JUROR #10: Boy, oh, boy!
You really think
he's innocent?
I don't know.
You sat in court
with the rest of us.
You heard what we did.
The kid's a dangerous killer,
you could see it.
He's 18 years old.
Well, that's old enough.
.
He stabbed his own father
four inches into the chest
They proved it a dozen
different ways in court.
Would you like me
to list them for you?
No.
Then what
do you want?
I just want to talk.
What's there
to talk about?
11 men in here
think he's guilty.
No one had to think
about it twice,
except you.
I want to ask
you something.
Do you believe
his story?
I don't know whether
I believe it or not.
Maybe I don't.
So how come you
vote not guilty?
There were 11 vote
s for guilty.
It's not easy
to raise my hand
and send a boy off
to die without talking
about it first.
Well, now,
who says it's easy?
No one.
What? Just because
I voted fast?
I honestly think
the guy is guilty.
Couldn't change my mind
if you talked for 100 years.
I'm not trying
to change your mind.
It's just that...
We're talking about
somebody's life here.
We can't decide it
in five minutes.
Supposing we're wrong?
Supposing we're wrong.
Supposing this building
should fall down on my head?
You can suppose anything.
That's right.
What's the difference
how long it takes?
Supposing we do it
in five minutes?
So what?
Let's take an hour.
The ball game
doesn't start till 8:00.
Who's got
something to say?
I'm willing
to sit for an hour.
Great. I heard
a pretty good stor
y last night...
That's not why
we're sitting here.
All right,
then you tell me.
What are we
sitting here for?
I don't know.
Maybe no reason.
Look, this kid's
been kicked around
all of his life.
You know, born in a slum,
mother dead since he was nine.
He lived for a year and a half
in an orphanage
when his father was
serving a jail term
for forgery.
That's not a very
happy beginning.
He's a wild, angry kid,
that's all he's ever been.
And you know why?
Because he's been hit
on the head by somebody
once a day, every day.
He's had a pretty
miserable 18 years.
I just think we owe him
a few words, that's all.
I don't mind telling
you this, mister.
We don't owe him a thing.
He got a fair trial,
didn't he?
What do you think
that trial cost?
He's lucky he got it.
Know what I mean?
Look, we're all
grown-ups in here.
We heard the facts,
didn't we?
You're not going to tell m
e that we're supposed
to believe this kid,
knowing what he is.
.
Listen, I've lived
among them all my life
You can't believe
a word they say.
.
You know that.
I mean, they're born liars
Only an ignorant man
can believe that.
Now, listen...
Do you think you were born
with a monopoly on the truth?
I think certain things
should be pointed out
to this man.
JUROR #7: Come on,
this isn't Sunday.
We don't need a sermon.
JUROR #1: Come on, we have
a job to do, now let's do it.
Rice Pops. It's a product
I work on at the agency.
"The breakfast with
the built-in bounce."
I wrote that line.
Very catchy.
Say, do you mind?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I have this habit of doodling.
It keeps me thinking clearly
We have all this work
to do. There's no poin
t staying here forever.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
Now perhaps if
the gentleman down there
who's disagreeing with us,
well, perhaps you
could tell us why.
You know, let us know
what you're thinking
and we might be
able to show you
where you're mixed up.
Well, look,
maybe this is an idea.
Now, I haven't
given it much thought,
but it seems to me that
it's up to the group of us
to convince this gentleman
that he's wrong
and we're right.
Now, maybe if we each
took a couple of minutes
just to...
Well, it was just
a quick idea.
No, no, no.
That's a good one.
JUROR #1: Supposing we go
once around the table?
I guess you're first.
Well I...
It's hard to put into words.
I just think he's guilty.
I thought it was obvious
from the word go.
I mean,
nobody proved otherwise.
Nobody has to prove otherwise.
The burden of proof's on
the prosecution.
.
The defendant doesn't even
have to open his mouth.
That's in the Constitution
Oh, well, sure, I know that.
What I meant was, is...
.
Well, I just think
he's guilty. I mean,
somebody saw him do it
Okay. Here's what I think,
and I have no
personal feelings about this.
I just want to
talk about facts.
Number one.
The old man lived downstairs
under the room where
the killing took place.
At 12:10 on the night
of the killing,
he heard loud noises.
Said it sounded like a fight.
And he heard
the kid yell out,
"I'm going to kill you."
A second later,
he heard a body
hit the floor.
Ran to the door,
opened it up,
saw the kid running
down the stairs
and out of the house.
Called the police. They came
in and found the old man
with the knife in his chest.
The coroner fixed
the time of death
around midnight.
Now, these are facts.
You can't refute facts.
The kid is guilty.
I'm just as sentimental
as the next fellow.
I know he's only 18.
But he's still got to
pay for what he did.
JUROR #7: I'm with you.
JUROR #1: Okay.
Are you finished?
Yeah.
JUROR #1: Right. Next.
It is obvious to me, anyway,
that the boy's entire story
was flimsy.
He claimed he was
at the movies during
the time of the killing
and yet one hour later,
he couldn't remember
the names of the films he saw
or who played in them.
JUROR #3: That's right.
And no one saw him
going in or out
of the theater.
Listen, what about
the woman across
the street?
If her testimony
don't prove it,
nothing does.
That's right. She was the one
who actually saw the killing.
JUROR #1: Now, fellows,
please. Let's go in
order here, huh?
Just a minute.
Here's a woman...
(COUGHING)
Here's a woman
who's lying in bed.
She can't sleep.
She's dying with the heat.
You know what I mean?
Anyway she looks
out the window,
and right across the street
she sees the kid
stick the knife
into his father.
The time is
12:10 on the nose.
Everything fits.
Look, she's known
the kid all his life.
His window is
right opposite hers
across the El tracks,
and she swore
she saw him do it.
Through the windows
of a passing El train.
Right. This El train
had no passengers on it.
It was just being
moved downtown.
The lights were out,
remember?
And they proved
in court that at night
you can look through
the windows of an El train
when the lights are out
and see what's happening
on the other side.
They proved it.
I'd like to ask
you something.
You don't believe the boy'
s story. How come you believ
e the woman's?
She's one of them,
too, isn't she?
You're a pretty
smart fellow, aren't you?
JUROR #1: Okay, gentlemen.
Now, gentlemen.
Come on, sit down.
Sit down.
What's he so wise about?
I'm telling you...
JUROR #1: Okay, now come on.
Now we're not going to get
anywhere fighting.
Whose turn is it next?
Oh, his.
Number five.
Can I pass?
JUROR #1: Well,
that's your privilege.
How about the next gentleman?
Oh. Well, I don't know.
I started to be convinced,
you know,
very early in the case.
You see,
I was looking
for a motive.
That's very important
because if you
don't have a motive,
where's your case, right?
Anyway, that testimony
from those people
in the apartment
across the hall from
the kid's apartment,
.
that was very powerful
,
Didn't they say something
about a fight, an argument
between the old man
and his son around
about 7:00 that night?
I mean, I could be
wrong but...
It was 8:00, not 7:00.
It was 8:00, that's right.
They heard an argument.
They couldn't hear
what it was about.
Then they heard the father
hit the boy twice.
(COUGHING)
Finally they saw the boy run,
angry, out of the house.
What does that prove?
It don't exactly
prove anything.
.
It's just part
of the picture
You said it
provided a motive.
The prosecuting attorney
said the same thing.
I don't think
that was a very
strong motive.
This boy has been hit so many
times in his life that
violence is practically...
It's a normal state
of affairs with him.
I just can't see two slaps
in the face provoking him
into committing murder.
It may have been two
too many. Everyone has
a breaking point.
JUROR #1: Anything else?
(SIGHING) No.
JUROR #1: Okay. How about you?
I don't know.
It's all been said.
You can talk here forever.
It's still the same thing.
This kid is 5 for 0.
Well, look at his record.
When he was 10,
he was in children's court.
He threw a rock at a teacher.
When he was 15,
he was in reform school.
He stole a car.
He's been arrested
for mugging.
He was picked up
twice for knife fighting.
They say he's real
handy with a knife.
Oh, this is a very fine boy.
Ever since he was five years
old, his father beat him up
regularly.
He used his fists.
So would I.
A kid like that?
It's these kids,
the way they are nowadays.
When I was a kid,
I used to call
my father "Sir".
That's right, "Sir".
Do you ever hear a kid
call his father that anymore?
JUROR #8: Fathers don't
seem to think it's
important anymore.
You got any kids?
JUROR #8: Three.
I got one.
He's 22 years old.
When he was nine years old
, he ran away from a fight.
I saw it.
I was so embarrassed,
I almost threw up.
I said, "I'm going to make
a man out of you if I have
to break you in two trying."
Well, I made
a man out of him.
.
When he was 16
, we had a fight
Hit me in the jaw.
He was a big kid.
I haven't seen
him for two years.
(SCOFFS)
Kids.
You work your heart out...
Well, let's get going.
JUROR #4: I think we're
missing the point here.
This boy, let's say he's
the product of a broken home
and a filthy neighborhood.
We can't help that.
We're here to decide
whether he's
innocent or guilty.
Not to go into the reasons
why he grew up the way he did.
He was born in a slum.
Slums are breeding
grounds for criminals.
I know it and so do you.
It's no secret that children
from slum backgrounds are
potential menaces to society.
Now, I think...
Brother,
you can say that again.
The kids who crawl
out of these places
are real trash.
I don't want
any part of them,
I'm telling you.
Listen, I...
I've lived in
a slum all my life.
JUROR #10: Wait a minute.
Please. I...
I've played in backyards
that were filled with garbage.
Maybe you can
still smell it on me.
JUROR #10: Now,
listen, sonny...
JUROR #1: Come on, now.
There's nothing personal.
.
No, there was
something personal
Come on, fellow.
He didn't mean you.
Let's not be so sensitive.
This sensitivity
I can understand.
Okay, look.
Let's stop the arguing.
We're only wasting time.
Your turn down there.
Let's go.
I didn't expect a turn.
I thought you were all
going to try to convince me.
Wasn't that the idea?
JUROR #12: Check,
that was the idea.
I forgot about that.
He's right.
What difference does
it make? He's the one
who's keeping us in here.
Let's hear what
he's got to say.
Now, wait a minute.
We decided to do
this a certain way.
I think we ought
to stick to that way.
Oh, stop being a kid,
will you?
What do you mean,
"a kid"?
.
What do you think
I mean? K-I-D, kid
Listen, just because
I'm trying to keep
this thing organized?
Here, you take it.
You take on
the responsibility.
I'll just keep my
mouth shut, that's all.
What are you
getting so hot about?
Calm down, will you?
Don't tell me to calm down.
Here, you want to take
the chair?
Just take the chair,
that's all.
See if you can keep
it running.
Did you ever see such a thing?
Listen, you think
it's funny or something?
Hey, forget it, fellow.
The whole thing's
unimportant. Come on.
Unimportant? Well,
here, you try it.
No. Nobody wants to change.
You're doing a beautiful job.
Sit down.
JUROR #7: Yeah, you're doing
great. Just great, fellow.
You stay in there and pitch.
All right,
let's hear from somebody.
JUROR #8: Well, if you want me
to tell you how I feel about
it, it's all right with me.
Boy, I don't care
what you do.
All right. I don't
have anything brilliant.
I only know as
much as you do.
According to the testimony,
the boy looks guilty.
Maybe he is.
I sat there in court
for six days listening
while the evidence built up.
Everybody sounded
so positive.
I began to get a peculiar
feeling about this trial.
I mean,
nothing is that positive.
There are a lot of questions
I'd have liked to ask.
I don't know,
maybe they wouldn't have
meant anything but...
I began to get the feeling
that the defense counsel
wasn't conducting a thorough
enough cross-examination.
I'm not...
He let too many things go by.
Little things.
?
What little things
Listen, when these fellows
don't ask questions,
it's because they know
the answers already and
they figure they'll be hurt.
Maybe. It's also possible
for a lawyer to be just
plain stupid, isn't it?
I mean, it's possible.
You sound like you met
my brother-in-law once.
(CHUCKLES)
(COUGHING)
I kept putting myself
in the kid's place.
I'd have asked for
another lawyer, I think.
I mean, if I was on trial
for my life,
I'd want my lawyer to tear
the prosecution witnesses
to shreds, or at least try to.
Look, there was one
alleged eyewitness
to this killing.
Someone else claims he heard
the killing, saw the boy run
out afterwards,
.
and there was a lot
of circumstantial evidence
But actually those two
witnesses were the entire
case for the prosecution.
Supposing they're wrong?
What do you mean,
"Supposing they're wrong?"
What's the point
of having witnesses at all?
Could they be wrong?
What are you trying to say?
Those people sat on
the stand under oath.
They're only people.
People make mistakes.
Could they be wrong?
Well, no.
I don't think so.
?
Do you know so
Oh, come on,
nobody can know
a thing like that.
This isn't an
exact science.
That's right, it isn't.
Okay, let's get
to the point.
What about the switch knif
e they found in
the old man's chest?
Wait a minute,
there's some people
who haven't talked yet.
Shouldn't we
go in order?
They'll get a chance to talk.
Be quiet a second, will you?
Well, what about it?
The knife this fine,
upright boy admitted buyin
g the night of the killing?
Let's talk about it.
All right.
Let's get it in here
and look at it.
I'd like to see it again.
Mr. Foreman?
JUROR #3: We all saw what
it looks like. Why do we
have to see it again?
JUROR #4: The gentleman
has a right to see
exhibits and evidence.
Say, could you
bring us the knife
?
The knife?
Yeah. Thank you.
Sure.
The knife and the way it
was bought is pretty strong
evidence, don't you think?
I do.
Good.
Now suppose we take
these facts one at a time.
One, the boy admitted going
out of the house at 8:00
on the night of the murder
after being slapped
several times by his father.
No, no, no,
he didn't say "slapped."
He said "punched."
.
There's a difference
between a slap and a punch
After being hit
several times by his father.
Two, he went directly to
a neighborhood junk shop where
he bought one of those...
Switch knives.
Switchblade knives.
This wasn't what you'd
call an ordinary knife.
It had a very unusual
carved handle and blade.
The storekeeper
who sold it to him
said it was the only one
of its kind he had ever
had in stock.
Three, he met some friends
of his in front of a tavern
about 8:45.
Am I right so far?
Yes, you are.
You bet he is.
He talked with his friends
for about an hour,
leaving them at 9:45.
During this time,
they saw the switch knife.
Four, they identified
the death weapon in court
as that very same knife.
Five, he arrived
home at about 10:00.
Now, this is where
the stories offered
by the State and the boy
begin to diverge slightly.
He claims that he went
to a movie at about 11:30,
returning home at 3:10
to find his father dead
and himself arrested.
JUROR #8: He also claims
that the two detectives
who arrested him
threw him down
a half a flight of stairs.
Now, what happened
to the switch knife?
He claims that it fell
through a hole in his pocket
on the way to the movie,
sometime between
11:30 and 3:10,
and that he
never saw it again.
Now, there is a tale,
gentlemen.
I think it's quite clear
that the boy never went
to the movies that night.
No one in the house
saw him go out at 11:30.
No one at the theater
identified him.
He couldn't even remember
the names of the pictures
he saw.
(DOOR OPENING)
What actually
happened is this.
The boy stayed home,
had another fight
with his father,
stabbed him to death
and left the house at 12:10.
He even remembered
to wipe the knife
clean of fingerprints.
Now are you trying to tell me
that this knife
really fell through a hole
in the boy's pocket,
someone picked it
up off the street,
went to the boy's house
and stabbed his father with it
just to test its sharpness?
No, I'm just saying
it's possible
the boy lost his knife
and that somebody else
stabbed his father
with a similar knife.
.
It's just possible
Take a look at this knife.
It's a very unusual knife.
I've never seen one like it.
Neither had the storekeeper
who sold it to the boy.
Aren't you asking us
to accept a pretty
incredible coincidence?
I'm just saying
a coincidence is possible.
And I say
it's not possible.
Where did
that come from?
It's the same knife!
What do you
think you're doing?
Where did you get it?
I went out walking
for a couple of hours
last night.
I walked through
the boy's neighborhood.
I bought that at a little
pawn shop just two blocks
from the boy's house.
It cost $6.
It's against the law
to buy or sell
switchblade knives.
That's right.
I broke the law.
Listen, you pulled
a real bright trick.
Now supposing you
tell me what it proves.
Maybe there are 10
knives like that.
So what?
Maybe there are!
What does it mean?
You found another knife
like it. What's that?
The discovery of
the age or something?
You mean you're asking us
to believe that somebody else
did the stabbing
?
with exactly
the same kind of knife
The odds are a million-to-one.
It's possible!
But not very probable.
JUROR #1: Okay, fellows.
Let's take our seats.
There's no point
standing around
all over the place.
You know,
it's interesting
that he'd find a knife
exactly like the one
the boy bought.
What's interesting
about it? Interesting!
Well, I don't know,
I just thought it
was interesting.
.
There are still 11 of us
here who think he's guilty
JUROR #10: Right.
What do you think you're
going to accomplish?
You're not going
to change anybody's mind.
So if you want to be stubborn
and hang this jury, go ahead.
The kid will be tried
again and found guilty
, sure as he's born.
You're probably right.
So, what are you going to do?
We could be here all night.
JUROR #9: It's only one night.
A boy may die.
Well, why don't we
just set up house here?
Someone send for
Potsy the policeman
to get a pinochle deck
and we'll just sweat
the whole thing out
right here.
(LAUGHING)
I don't think he
ought to joke about it.
What do you want
me to do about it?
Listen, I don't see what all
this stuff about the knife
has got to do with anything.
Somebody saw the kid
stab his father.
What more do we need?
You guys can talk the ears
right off my head,
you know what I mean?
I got three garages of mine
going to pot
while you're talking.
So let's get done
and get out of here.
The knife was very important
to the district attorney.
He spent a whole day...
He's a 15th assistant
or something.
What does he know about it?
JUROR #1: Hey,
let's hold it down.
These side arguments
are only slowing us up.
JUROR #1: Well, what about it?
You're the only one.
I have a proposition
to make to all of you.
I'm going to call
for another vote.
I want you 11 men to vote
by secret written ballot.
I'll abstain. If there
are 11 votes for guilty,
I won't stand alone.
.
We'll take in
a guilty verdict
to the judge right now
But if anyone
votes not guilty,
we stay here
and talk it out.
That's it. If you want
to try it, I'm ready.
JUROR #7: All right.
Let's do it the hard way.
That sounds fair.
Everyone agreed?
Anyone doesn't agree?
Fine, let's go.
Pass these along.
"Guilty."
"Not guilty."
JUROR #1: "Guilty."
Boy, how do you like that?
And another chap
flips his wings!
All right. Who was it?
Come on, I want to know.
Excuse me.
This was a secret ballot.
We all agreed on that, no?
If the gentleman
wants it to remain secret...
Secret? What do you mean,
"secret"?
There are no secrets
in a jury room.
I know who it was.
Brother, you really
are something.
You sit here, vote guilty
like the rest of us,
then some golden-voiced
preacher starts tearing
your poor heart out
about some
underprivileged kid
just couldn't help
becoming a murderer
and you change your vote.
If that isn't
the most sickening...
Why don't you drop a quarter
in his collection box?
Oh, now just wait a...
Listen, you can't
talk to me like that.
Who do you
think you are?
Calm down, calm down.
JUROR #5: Who does
he think he is?
It doesn't matter.
He's very excitable.
Sit down.
"Excitable"?
You bet I'm excitable!
We're trying to put
a guilty man in the chair,
where he belongs.
Someone starts
telling us fairytales
and we're listening!
JUROR #1: Hey, come on.
What made you
change your vote?
He didn't change his vote.
I did.
JUROR #10: Oh, fine.
JUROR #7: I knew it.
Would you like me
to tell you why?
No, I wouldn't
like you to tell me why.
Well, I'd like to
make it clear anyway,
if you don't mind.
?
Do we have to
listen to this
The man
wants to talk.
Thank you.
This gentleman has been
standing alone against us.
Now he doesn't say
the boy is not guilty.
.
He just isn't sure
It's not easy to stand
alone against the ridicule
of others.
So he gambled for support,
and I gave it to him.
I respect his motives.
The boy on trial
is probably guilty,
but I want to hear more.
Right now,
the vote is 10-2.
!
I'm talking here!
You have no right
to leave this room
He can't hear you.
He never will.
Let's sit down.
Shall we
continue?
Well, I think we
ought to take a break.
You know, one man's inside
and I think we
ought to wait for him.
Looks like we're
really hung up here, huh?
I mean,
that thing with the old man,
that was pretty unexpected.
Wish I could figure out
some way we could break it up.
(CHUCKLES)
You know,
in advertising...
I told you I worke
d in an agency?
Mmm-hmm.
You know, there's
some pretty strange
people working there.
Well, they're not strange,
really.
I guess it's just
they have peculiar ways
of expressing themselves.
You know
what I mean.
Well, of course,
I suppose it's the same
in your business too, huh?
What do you do?
I'm a watchmaker.
Really? I imagine the finest
watchmakers in the world come
from Europe.
Well, anyway, as I was telling
you, in an agency, when we
reach a point like this...
I'm telling him about in an
ad agency when a point like
this is reached in a meeting,
there's always some character
ready with an idea, see.
And it kills me.
It's the weirdest
thing in the world
the way they sometimes
precede their idea
with a phrase, see, like,
some account exec
will get up and he'll say,
"Okay, here's an idea. Let's
"run it up the flagpole
and see if anyone salutes it."
I mean, it's idiotic,
but it's funny.
Hey, I got a little
excited back there.
I didn't mean
to get nasty.
Glad you're not one of those
who lets these emotional
appeals influence him.
I don't know what's
the matter with that fan.
Can't seem to get it started.
(SCATTING)
Are you a salesman?
I'm an architect.
You know what
the soft sell is?
Well, you've got it,
believe me.
I've got
a different technique.
Laughs, drinks, jokes,
tricks. You know?
Yeah.
"Hit them where they live,
" that's my motto.
I made 27 grand last year
selling marmalade.
That's not bad.
I mean, you know,
considering marmalade.
What are you getting
out of this? Kicks?
?
Or did somebody bump you
on the head one time and
you haven't gotten over it
Maybe.
You know, you do-gooders
are all alike.
You're always blowing
your stacks over some
guy that fanned.
But what are you
wasting our time for?
Why don't you donate $5
to the cause and maybe
it'll make you feel better.
This kid is guilty, pal.
It's as plain as
the nose on your face.
So why don't we stop
wasting our time here?
We're going to all get
sore throats if we keep it up.
What difference does it make
if you get it here
or at the ball game?
No difference, pal.
No difference at all.
(WHISTLING)
Nice bunch of guys
, huh?
They're about
the same as anyone else.
(SIGHING)
Boy,
what a murderous day.
Do you think
we'll be much longer?
I don't know.
He's guilty for sure.
Not a doubt in
the whole world.
We should've
been done already.
Oh, I don't mind,
you know.
(CHUCKLES)
Beats working.
Uh...
You think he's
not guilty, huh?
I don't know.
It's possible.
Well, I don't know you,
but I'm betting you've never
been wronger in your life.
You're wasting your time.
You ought to wrap it up.
Supposing you were the one
that was on trial?
Well, I'm not used
to supposing. I'm just
a working man.
My boss does
the supposing.
But I'll try one.
Supposing you talk
us all out of this
and the kid really did
knife his father, huh?
Are you ready?
Sorry, blue eyes.
Well, where else?
JUROR #1: Okay, fellows.
Let's take our seats.
Looks like we'll be
here for dinner, huh?
Okay, now let's
get down to business.
Now who wants
to start it off?
I will.
Okay, go.
You, down there.
The old man who
lived downstairs says
he heard the kid yell out,
"I'm going to kill you."
A second later,
he heard the body
hit the floor.
Now he ran to
the door and he saw
the kid running down
the stairs and out
of the house.
What does that mean to you?
I was wondering how
clearly the old man
could have heard
the boy's voice
through the ceiling.
He didn't hear it
The window was open.
So was the one upstairs.
It was a hot night, remember?
It was another apartment.
It's not that easy
to identify a voice,
particularly
a shouting voice.
JUROR #12:
He identified it in court.
JUROR #3: That's right,
and don't forget
the lady across the street,
she looked right
in the open window
and saw the boy stab
his father. Isn't that
enough for you?
No, it isn't.
Boy, how do you
like this guy?
It's like talking
into a dead phone.
JUROR #4: She said she
saw the killing through
the windows of
a moving elevated train.
There were six cars on
the train. She saw the killing
through the last two cars.
She remembered the most
insignificant details.
I don't see how you
can argue with that.
Has anybody here any idea
how long it would take
an el...
This isn't a game.
Did you see him?
The nerve!
JUROR #1: All right.
Listen to me.
The absolute nerve!
All right. Forget it.
It's not important.
"This isn't a game"?
Who does he think he is?
JUROR #1: Forget it now.
Has anybody any idea
how long it takes
an elevated train
going at medium speed
to pass a given point?
.
What has that to do
with anything?
How long? Take a guess
I wouldn't have
the slightest idea.
What do you think?
I don't know,
maybe 10, 12 seconds?
I think that's
a pretty good guess.
Anyone else?
JUROR #11:
That sounds right to me.
JUROR #10: Come on.
What's the guessing game for?
What do you say?
Ten seconds
is about right.
All right. Say 10 seconds.
What are you getting at?
This. It takes a six-car
El train 10 seconds to pas
s a given point.
Now, let's say
the given point
.
is the open window
of the room where
the killing took place
You can reach out of that
window and almost touch
the El tracks, right?
Now let me ask you this.
Has anyone here ever
lived near the El tracks?
.
Well, I just finished
painting an apartment
that overlooked an El line
.
I was there
for three days
What was it like? Noisy?
What do you mean?
Oh, brother!
No matter, though.
We were punchy.
I lived in a second floor
apartment near the El line
once.
When the window's open and
the train goes by, the noise
is almost unbearable.
You can hardly
hear yourself think.
JUROR #3: All right, you can't
Will you get to the point?
I will, now just a minute.
Let's take two pieces
of testimony and try
to put them together.
First, the old man
in the apartment downstairs.
He says he heard the boy say,
"I'm going to kill you,"
.
and a split-second later
heard a body hit the floor
One second later,
right?
JUROR #2: That's right.
Second, the woman
across the street
swore positively
she looked out of the window
and saw the killing
through the last two cars
of a passing
elevated train, right?
The last two cars.
JUROR #3: Well,
what are you giving us here?
Now, just a minute.
We've agreed that it takes
10 seconds for a train
to pass a given point.
Since the woman saw
the killing through
the last two cars,
we can assume that the bod
y hit the floor just as
the train went by.
Therefore, the train
had been roaring by
the old man's window
a full 10 seconds
before the body
hit the floor.
The old man,
according to
his own testimony,
"I'm going to kill you,"
body hitting the floor
a split-second later,
t
would have had to hear
the boy make this statemen
with the El roaring
past his nose!
It's not possible he
could have heard it.
That's idiotic,
of course he heard it.
You think he
could have heard it?
He said he yelled at
the top of his voice,
that's good enough for me...
Even if he heard something
, he still couldn't have
.
identified the voice
with the El roaring by
You're talking about
a matter of seconds!
Nobody can be that accurate.
Well, I think testimony
that could put a boy
into the electric chair
should be that accurate.
Can I tell you something?
I don't think he
could have heard it.
Maybe he didn't hear it.
I mean, with all that
El noise.
JUROR #3: What are you
people talking about?
JUROR #5: Well, it stands
to reason he couldn't
have heard it.
Why should he lie?
What's he got to gain?
Attention, maybe.
You keep coming in
with these bright sayings.
Why don't you send
them in to a paper?
They pay $3 apiece!
What are you talking
to him like that for?
A guy talks like that to a
n old man really ought to ge
t stepped on, you know.
You ought to have
more respect, mister.
You say stuff like tha
t to him again, I'm goin
g to lay you out.
Now you go ahead.
You say anything you like.
Why do you think
the old man might lie?
It was just that I looked
at him for a very long time.
The seam of his jacket
was split, under the shoulder.
Did you notice that?
I mean, to come to court
like that.
(JUROR #10 COUGHING)
He was a very old man
in a torn jacket,
and he walked very
slowly to the stand.
He was dragging his left leg
and trying to hide it
.
because he was ashamed
I think I know this man
better than anyone here.
This is a quiet, frightened,
insignificant old man
who has been
nothing all his life.
Who has never had recognition
or his name in the newspapers.
Nobody knows him.
Nobody quotes him.
Nobody seeks his advice
after 75 years.
Gentlemen,
that's a very sad thing,
to mean nothing.
A man like this
needs to be quoted,
to be listened to.
To be quoted just once,
very important to him.
It would be so hard for him
to recede into the background.
JUROR #7: Wait a minute.
What are you trying to do?
Tell us he'd lie
just so he could
be important once?
No. He wouldn't really lie.
But perhaps he made himself
believe he heard those words
and recognized
the boy's face.
That's the most fantastic
story I've ever heard.
How can you make up
a thing like that?
What do you know about it?
Does anybody
want a cough drop?
No, thanks.
JUROR #8: I'll take one.
JUROR #12: You can
say what you like,
but I still don't see
how anybody can
think he's not guilty.
There's something else
I'd like to talk about
for a minute.
Thanks.
I think we've proved that
the old man couldn't have
heard the boy say,
"I'm going to kill you."
But supposing...
?
You didn't prove it at all
! What are you talking about
Wait. Supposing he
really did hear it?
This phrase, how many time
s have all of us used it?
Probably thousands.
"I could kill you
for that, darling."
"Junior, you do that once more
and I'm going to kill you."
"Get in there, Rocky,
and kill him."
We say it everyday.
That doesn't mean
we're really gonna
kill anybody.
Wait a minute. What are you
trying to give us here?
The phrase was,
"I'm going to kill you."
The kid yelled it at
the top of his lungs.
Don't tell me he
didn't mean it.
Anybody says a thing
like that the way he said it,
they mean it!
Well, gee,
now I don't know.
o
I remember I was arguing
with the guy I work next t
at the bank a couple
of weeks ago.
He called me an idiot,
so I yelled at him.
Now listen, this guy is trying
to make you believe things
that aren't so!
The kid said he was going
to kill him and he did
kill him.
Let me ask you this,
do you really think
the boy would shout it
out a thing like that
so the whole neighborhood
could hear him?
I don't think so.
He's much too bright for that.
Bright? He's a common,
ignorant slob.
He don't even
speak good English.
.
He doesn't even
speak good English
Mr. Foreman, I'd like to
change my vote to not guilty.
You what?
You heard me.
JUROR #1: Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
The vote is 9-3
in favor of guilty.
Well, if this isn't
the living end!
What are you basing it on?
Stories this guy made up?
You ought to write for
one of those kooky
detective magazines,
you'd make a fortune.
For crying out loud,
the kid's own lawyer knew
he didn't stand a chance.
Right from the beginning,
his own lawyer knew,
and you could see it.
Boy, oh, boy,
I'm telling you. This guy
here is really something.
Look, the kid had a lawyer
, didn't he?
He presented
his case, not you.
How come you got
so much to say?
JUROR #5: Look, lawyers
aren't infallible, you know.
Baltimore, please.
He was court-appointed.
Now what's that
supposed to mean?
Well, it could
mean a lot of things.
It could mean he didn't
want the case or he
resented being appointed.
It's the kind of case
that brings you nothing,
no money, no glory,
not even much
chance of winning.
That's not a very promising
situation for a young lawyer.
He'd really have to believ
e in his client to put up
any kind of a good case
and as you pointed out
a minute ago,
obviously he didn't.
Of course he didn't.
Who the heck could?
Except maybe
some guy's mother
or somebody, I...
Oh, look.
Will you look at the time?
Come on, for crying...
Pardon me.
I have made
some notes here,
and I would like,
please, to say something.
I have been listening
very carefully and
it seems to me that this man
has some very good points
to make.
From what was
presented at the trial,
the boy looks guilty,
on the surface.
But maybe if we go deeper...
Come on, will you?
There is a question
I would like to ask.
Let us assume that the boy
really did commit the murder.
Now, this happened at 12:10.
Now, how was he
caught by the police?
He came back home
at 3:00 or so,
and he was captured
by two detectives
in the hallway of his house.
Now, my question is,
if he really had
killed his father,
why would he come back hom
e three hours later?
Wouldn't he be afraid
of being caught?
He came home
to get his knife.
It's not nice to go around
leaving knives sticking
in people's chests.
Yeah, especially relatives'.
(LAUGHING)
JUROR #4: I don't see
anything funny about it.
The boy knew the knife could
be identified as the one he
had just bought.
He had to get it
before the police did.
JUROR #11: But if he knew
the knife could be identified,
why did he leave it there
in the first place?
Well, I think we can assum
e the boy ran out
in a state of panic
after having just
killed his father.
When he finally calmed down,
he realized he'd
left his knife there.
"
This, then, depends on
your definition of "panic.
He would have had
to be calm enough
to see to it that
there were no fingerprints
left on the knife.
?
Now, where did this panic
start and where did it end
Look, you voted guilty
. What side are you on?
I don't believe I have
to be loyal to one side
or the other.
I'm simply asking questions.
Well, this is just
off the top of my head,
g
but if I were the boy
and I'd done
the stabbing and everythin
I'd take a chance and
go back for the knife.
I'll bet he figured
that nobody had seen
him running out
and that the body wouldn't be
discovered till the next day.
After all, it was
the middle of the night.
I'll bet he figured nobody
would find the body till
the next day.
Pardon.
This is my whole point.
The woman across
the street testified
that the moment after
she saw the killing,
that is, a moment
after the train went by,
she screamed,
and then went to
telephone the police.
Now, the boy certainly
must have heard the scream,
so he knew that
somebody saw something.
I just don't think
that he would have gone back.
Two things. One, in his state
of panic, he may not have
heard the scream.
Perhaps it wasn't
very loud.
Two, if he did hear it,
he may not have connected it
with his own acts.
Remember, he lived in a
neighborhood where screams
were fairly commonplace.
There's your answer.
Maybe. Maybe the boy
did kill his father.
Didn't hear the scream,
did run out in a panic,
did calm down
three hours later
and come back
to get the knife,
risking being
caught by the police.
Maybe all of those things
happened, but maybe
they didn't.
I think there's enough doubt
that we can wonder
whether he was there at all
during the time
the killing took place.
?
What do you mean, "doubt"?
What are you talking about
Didn't the old man see him
running out of the house?
He's twisting the facts.
I'm telling you.
Did or didn't the old man
see the kid running out
of the house at 12:10?
?
Well, did or didn't he
.
He says he did
Says he did?
Boy, how do you like that?
Look, witnesses
can make mistakes.
Sure, when you
want them to they do.
Or when he wants
them to they do!
You know what I mean?
Keep the yelling down.
Oh, you keep saying that.
Maybe what we need
is a little yelling in here.
These guys keep
going off every which way.
Did hear the scream,
didn't hear the scream,
what difference
does it make?
You people are talking
only about
the little details.
You're forgetting
the important stuff.
I mean, all of a sudden...
I'm gonna call
for another vote.
I'm talking here!
Another vote
called for.
Now let's take
our seats.
I never saw so much
time spent on nothing.
It only takes a second.
JUROR #1: Okay, I guess
the fastest way is to find
out who's voting not guilty.
All those voting not guilty,
please raise your hands.
Still the same.
One, two, three not guilty
. Nine guilty.
JUROR #7: So now where are we?
I'll tell you,
we can yakety-yak
here till next Tuesday.
Where's it all getting us?
Pardon. I vote not guilty.
(JURORS EXCLAIMING)
What are you talking about?
I mean, we're all going
crazy in here or something.
The kid is guilty.
Why don't you
listen to the facts?
Tell him, will you?
This is getting to be a joke.
JUROR #1: The vote is 8-4
in favor of guilty.
Hey, what is this? "Love Your
Underprivileged Brother"
week or something?
I want you to get up
and tell me why you
changed your vote.
Come on, now,
give me reasons.
I don't have to defend
my decision to you.
There is a reasonable
doubt in my mind.
What reasonable doubt?
That's nothing but words.
.
Here, look at this
The kid you just
decided isn't guilty
was seen ramming
this into his father!
Now what about this,
Mr. Reasonable Doubt?
That's not the knife,
don't you remember?
Oh, brilliant!
I'm telling you,
this is the craziest.
I mean, what are we
supposed to believe?
You're sitting here,
you're pulling stories
out of thin air, you know?
A guy like this,
if he's sitting ringside
at the Dempsey-Firpo fight,
he'd be trying to
tell you that...
Look. Now what
about the old man?
Are we supposed to believe
that he didn't get up
and run to his door
and see the kid
tearing down the steps
15 seconds after the killing?
He's just saying so
to be important, right?
What's the point
of the whole thing?
Hold on a second.
And the Baltimore rooter
is heard from again, now.
And pop-ups are
falling for base hits
wherever we look.
Hey, hold on a second.
Now, look.
Did the old man say
he ran to the door?
Ran, walked,
what's the difference?
He got there, didn't he?
No, well, wait a second...
He said he ran.
At least, I think he did.
Look, I don't
remember what he said,
but I don't see how he
could have run to the door.
He said he went from his
bedroom to the front door.
Now, isn't that enough?
Where was the bedroom?
It was down
the hall somewhere.
I thought you
remembered everything.
Don't you remember that?
.
No. Mr. Foreman,
I'd like to see
a diagram of the apartment
JUROR #7: Look, why don't we
have him run the trial all
over again, so...
Mr. Foreman!
How come you'r
e the only one
in this room who
wants to see exhibits
all the time?
I want to see
this one, too.
And I'd like to
stop wasting time.
If we're going
to start wading throug
h all that nonsense
.
about where
the body was found
.
We're not. Not unless
somebody else wants to
But I'd like to
find out if an old man
who drags one foot when he
walks because he had a stroke
last year
can get from his bedroom
to his front door
in 15 seconds.
.
He said 20 seconds.
He said 15
What are you
trying to distort?
JUROR #11: He said 15.
How does he know
how long 15 seconds is?
You can't judge
a thing like that.
JUROR #9: He said 15 seconds.
He was very positive about it.
He was an old man!
Half the time
he was confused!
How could he be
positive about anything?
I don't see what you'r
e going to prove here.
The man said he saw
the boy running out.
Well, let's see if
the details bear him out.
As soon as
the body hit the floor,
he said he heard footsteps
upstairs, running toward
the front door.
Heard the upstairs door open,
the footsteps
start down the stairs.
He said he got to his own
front door as fast as he could
and he swore it
couldn't have been
more than 15 seconds.
Now if the killer
began running immediately...
.
JUROR #12: Maybe he didn't
The old man said he did.
.
You ought to be at
Atlantic City at that
hair-splitters' convention
Hey, why don't you stop
making smart remarks
all the time, huh?
My friend, for your $3 a day,
you have to listen
to everything.
Now that you got
that thing in here,
what about it?
All right,
here's the apartment
where the killing took place.
The old man's apartmen
t was directly beneath
and exactly the same.
Here are the El tracks,
the bedroom, living room,
kitchen, bathroom,
here's the hall,
here are the stairs.
.
Now, the old man was
in this bedroom right here
He says he
crossed to the door,
walked down the hall,
opened the front
door just in time
to see the boy
running down the stairs.
Am I right so far?
JUROR #3: That's the story,
for the 19th time.
15 seconds after
the body hit the floor
.
JUROR #11: Correct.
Now, let's see. It was...
It's 12 feet from
the bed to the door.
The hall is 43 feet.
He would have had
to walk 12 feet,
open the bedroom door,
walk 43 feet down
and open the front door,
all in 15 seconds.
You think he
could have done it
?
JUROR #10:
Sure he could have done it.
JUROR #11: He can
walk only very slowly.
They had to help him
into the witness chair.
JUROR #3: You make it soun
d like a long walk.
For an old man
who had a stroke,
it is a long walk.
What are you doing?
I'm going to try it.
See how long it took.
?
What do you mean,
you want to try it
Why didn't his
lawyer bring it up
if it's so important?
Maybe he just
didn't think about it.
What do you mean he
didn't think of it?
Do you think the man's
an idiot or something?
It's an obvious thing.
Did you think of it?
Listen, smart guy.
It don't matter whethe
r I thought of it.
He didn't bring it up
because he knew
it'd hurt his case.
What do you
think of that?
Maybe he didn't bring
it up because it would
have meant bullying
and badgering
a helpless old man.
You know that doesn't
sit very well with a jury.
Most lawyers
avoid it if they can.
So what kind of
a bum is he then?
That's what I've
been asking, buddy.
Pass me that chair, will you?
Those two chairs
are the old man's bed.
I just paced off 12
feet across the room.
This will be
the bedroom door.
That's crazy.
You can't recreate
a thing like that.
The hall was 43 feet.
I'll pace from that
wall and back again.
This is absolutely insane.
What are you wasting
everybody's time in here for?
According to you, it'll only
take 15 seconds. Now we can
spare that, see.
(JUROR #7 WHISTLING)
Come on. Knock it off.
Okay. Okay,
okay, killer.
Yeah.
Will you stand right there
and mark the front door?
It was chain-locked
according to the testimony,
remember.
Has anybody got a watch
with a second hand?
I have.
When you want me to start,
stamp your foot.
That'll be the body falling.
You can time me from there.
JUROR #7: What are we going
to do, play Charades now?
JUROR #7: Come on!
Okay, I'm ready.
JUROR #10:
What are we waiting for?
.
I want to wait till
the second hand reaches 60
JUROR #7: Come on!
(STAMPS FOOT)
JUROR #10: Come on,
speed it up. He can walk
twice as fast as that.
If you want me to walk
faster than that, I will.
Lock. Door. Stop.
JUROR #2: Right.
What's the time?
Exactly... 41 seconds.
41!
Here is what I
think happened.
The old man heard the fight
between the boy
and his father
a few hours earlier.
Then when he's
lying in his bed,
he heard the body
hit the floor in
the boy's apartment,
heard the woman scream
from across the street,
got to his front door
as fast as he could,
.
heard somebody
racing down the stairs
and assumed it was the boy
I think that's possible.
"Assumed"?
(LAUGHING)
Brother, I've seen all kinds
of dishonesty in my day,
but this little display
takes the cake.
r
You all come in here
with your hearts
bleeding all over the floo
about slum kids
and injustice.
You listen to
some fairytales.
Suddenly,
you start getting through
to some of these old ladies.
Well, you're not
getting through to me.
I've had enough.
What's the matter
with you guys?
You all know he's guilty!
He's got to burn!
You're letting him
slip through our fingers.
"Slip through our fingers"
? Are you his executioner?
I'm one of them.
Perhaps you'd like
to pull the switch.
For this kid,
you bet I would.
I feel sorry for you.
What it must feel like
to wanna pull the switch.
Ever since you
walked into this room,
you've been acting like
a self-appointed
public avenger.
You want to see this boy die
because you personally
want it,
not because of the facts.
You're a sadist.
You...
Let me go!
I'll kill him! I'll kill him!
You don't really mean
you'll kill me, do you?
Anything wrong, gentlemen?
I heard some noise.
No, everything's all right.
We're just...
Friendly little argument.
Listen, we're through
with that diagram.
You can take it if you want.
Here you are.
Thank you.
What are you looking at?
JUROR #1: I suppose somebody
has to start off again.
I beg pardon...
"I beg pardon."
What are you
so polite about?
For the same
reason you're not.
It's the way I
was brought up.
This fighting...
That's not why we
are here, to fight.
We have a responsibility.
This, I have always thought,
is a remarkable thing
about democracy.
That we are...
What is the word?
Notified.
That we are notified by mail
to come down to this place
to decide on
the guilt or innocence
of a man we have
never heard of before.
We have nothing
to gain or lose
by our verdict.
This is one of the reasons
why we are strong.
We should not make
it a personal thing.
Thank you.
If nobody else has an idea
, I might have a cutie here.
I mean, I haven't
given it much thought,
.
but let's throw it dow
n on the stoop and see
if the cat licks it up
"The cat licks it up"?
Yeah. The board...
(ALL LAUGHING)
Look how dark it's
getting out there.
I bet we're gonna
have a storm now.
Boy, oh, boy.
It's really hot, huh?
Pardon me,
but don't you
ever sweat?
No, I don't.
Listen,
I was wondering if...
Maybe we should
take another vote.
Great. Maybe we can follow
this one up with a little
dancing and refreshments.
Mr. Foreman?
Well, that's okay with me.
Anyone doesn't wanna vote?
Hey, come on.
Sorry.
I think we ought to
have an open ballot.
Call out our votes, you know?
Let's see who stands where.
Well, that sounds fair to me.
Anyone object?
?
Okay, I'll call off
your jury numbers. One
Oh, that's me.
I vote guilty. Two?
Not guilty.
Number three?
Guilty.
Number four?
Number five?
Not guilty.
Number six?
Number seven?
Guilty.
Number eight?
Not guilty.
Number nine?
Number ten?
Guilty.
Number 11?
Not guilty.
Number 12?
Number 12!
Guilty.
The vote is now 6-6.
And we go into
extra innings here, huh?
(MUTTERING)
6-6! I'm telling you,
some of you people in here
must be out of your minds.
A kid like that!
.
I don't think
the kind of boy he is
has anything to do with it
The facts are supposed
to determine the case.
Don't give me that
! I'm sick and tired
of facts.
You can twist them
any way you like.
You know what I mean?
That's exactly the point
this gentleman
has been making.
You keep shouting
at the top of your lungs...
I'd like to be
a few years younger.
That man gets on my...
My, it's hot in here,
isn't it?
Want a drink of water?
.
No, no. Thanks. Thanks
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
It's gonna rain.
Well, how'd you
figure that out, killer?
How come you
changed your vote?
It just seemed to me
there was room for doubt.
You haven't got
a leg to stand on.
You know that, I hope.
I don't feel that way.
There were a lot
of details that
never came out.
Yeah, well, good luck.
Come on. You're like
everybody else.
You think too much,
you get mixed up.
You know what I mean?
Listen, I don't think
you have any right...
Loudmouth.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Look at that
come down, will you?
You know, this reminds me
of a storm we had last...
Oh...
Was it November?
I don't know. Something.
It was quite a storm we had.
It was right
in the middle of a game.
.
We were behind 7-6
But we'd just started
to move the ball,
made a real tackle.
It sort of cut right in,
slash through,
slashed right in,
cut right through.
And...
We had this kid,
Slattery.
He was an ox.
You know, a real ox.
I wish I had another one
just like him.
I forgot to tell you.
I'm the assistant head coach
at Andrew J. McCorkle
High School.
Really?
That's out in Queens.
And anyway,
we're starting to
move along real nice.
You know, their whole line
is just coming apart.
And it starts to come down
, cats and dogs,
just like this.
Just... You know,
right down.
Well, it was murder,
you know?
.
I swear,
I nearly bawled.
We couldn't go nowhere
Hey, what is it
with this fan here
? How come...
Hey!
(CHUCKLES)
Must have been on
the same switch
with the lights.
Well, things are
looking up here, huh?
Yeah.
Boy, that's better.
Hey! Two points.
Any of you guys
ever go to the Garden?
That's a damn
stupid thing to do.
Oh, I'm sorry. I...
You know?
Pardon me.
Well, how do you like it?
Even-steven.
Pretty surprising, isn't it?
Yes.
That business before,
when that tall guy,
what's-his-name,
was trying to bait me?
.
That doesn't
prove anything
I'm a pretty
excitable person.
Where does he come off
calling me a public avenger,
a sadist, and everything?
Anyone in his right mind
would blow his stack.
He was just
trying to bait me.
He did an excellent job.
I'll tell you what I think
, we're going nowhere here.
I'm ready to walk
into court right now
and declare a hung jury.
There's no point in
this thing going on anymore.
Yeah, I go for that, too.
Listen, let's take it
in to the judge
and let the kid take
his chances with 12
other guys.
I don't think
the judge will
accept a hung jury.
We haven't been
in here very long.
Well, let's find out.
JUROR #11: I am no
t in favor of that.
Listen, this kid wouldn't
stand a chance with
another jury, and you know it.
Come on, we're hung.
Nobody's gonna
change his vote.
Let's take it inside.
You still don't think
there's room for
reasonable doubt?
No, I don't.
Pardon. Maybe you
don't fully understand
the term "reasonable doubt".
What do you mean,
I don't understand?
How do you like this guy?
I'm telling you,
they're all alike.
They come over here,
running for their life,
and before they can
take a deep breath,
they're telling us
how to run the show.
Boy, the arrogance
of this guy!
JUROR #1: All right.
Let's stop the arguing
for about two minutes in here.
Now, who's got something
constructive to say?
I'd like to go
over something,
if you gentlemen don't mind.
An important point
for the prosecutio
n was the fact that
s
after the boy claimed
he'd been at the movie
during the hours
that the killing took place,
s
he couldn't remember
the names of the movie
or the stars who
appeared in them.
This gentleman here ha
s brought up that point
in here several times.
That's correct.
It was the only
alibi the boy offered,
and he himself
couldn't back it up
with any details at all.
,
Putting yourselves
in the boy's place
do you think you
could remember details
after an upsetting experience
?
such as being slapped
in the face by your father
I think so, if there were
any special details
to remember.
The boy couldn't
remember the names
of the movies he saw,
because he wasn't
there that night.
According to the polic
e testimony in court,
the boy was questioned by
the detectives in the kitchen
of his apartment,
while the body of his father
was lying on the floor
in the bedroom.
Do you think you
could remember details
under those circumstances?
I do.
Under great
emotional stress?
Under great emotional stress.
.
He remembered them
correctly in court
He named the pictures
and the stars
who played in them.
Yes. His lawyer took
great pains to bring that out.
He had three months
from the night of the murder
to the day of the trial
in which to memorize them.
It's not difficult
for a lawyer to find out
what played at a particular
theater on a particular night.
I'll take the testimony
of the policeman
who interrogated the boy
right after the murder,
when he couldn't remember
a thing about the movies,
great emotional stress or not.
I'd like to ask you
a personal question.
Go ahead.
Where were you
last night?
I was home.
How about the nigh
t before that?
JUROR #10: Come on
. What is this?
No, it's all right.
I left the office at 8:30
and went straight home
and to bed.
And the night before that?
That was Tuesday night.
The night of
the bridge tournament.
I played bridge.
Monday night?
JUROR #7: When you get down
to New Year's Eve 1954,
let me know.
Monday night?
Monday night,
my wife and I
went to the movies.
What did you see?
The Scarlet Circle.
It is a very clever whodunit.
What was the second feature?
The...
I'll tell you in a minute.
The Remarkable Mrs...
Something...
Mrs. Bainbridge.
The Remarkable
I saw that. It's called
The Amazing Mrs. Bainbridge.
Yes. The Amazing
Mrs. Bainbridge.
I think that's right.
Who was in The Amazing
Mrs. Bainbridge?
Barbara Long, I think it was.
A dark, very pretty girl.
Ling, or Long.
Something like that.
Who else?
I'd never heard
of them before.
It was a very inexpensive
second feature,
with unknown...
And you weren't under
an emotional stress,
were you?
No.
I wasn't.
I think the point is made.
Big point.
You can talk till your tongue
is dragging on the floor.
The boy is guilty. Period.
Know what I mean,
my friend?
You got those
cough drops?
They're all gone, my friend.
Oh, boy.
Look at that rain.
.
There goes
your ball game
It's only a shower.
Besides, they got
the infield covered.
Say, could I see that knife
a second, please?
?
Well, we're still
tied up 6-6.
Who's got a suggestion
It's 6:05.
Let's get some dinner.
Why don't we wait till 7:00?
Give it another hour.
Okay with me.
There's something
I'd like to say.
I mean, it's been
bothering me a little,
and as long as we're stuck...
There was this whole business
about the stab wound and how
it was made.
The downward
angle of it, you know?
Don't tell me
we're gonna start
with that again.
They've been
over it and over it.
I know they did,
but I don't go along with it.
Now, the boy was 5'7" tall
. His father was 6'2".
That's a difference
of seven inches.
It's a very awkward thing
to stab down into the chest
of someone who's
more than half a foot
taller than you are.
Give me that.
I'll give you a demonstration.
Somebody get up.
I want you to watch this
'cause I don't wanna
have to do it again.
I'll make myself about
six or seven inches shorter.
Okay?
That's about right.
Maybe a little more.
Okay, a little more.
(ALL YELLING)
.
Now, nobody's hurt
Right?
Right. Nobody hurt.
Now, this is the way
I'd stab a man who was
taller than I was.
Look at the angle.
Down and in.
And this is
the way it was done.
Now tell me I'm wrong.
Down and in.
I guess there'
s no argument.
Hold on a minute,
will you?
Will you give me that?
Boy, I hate these things.
Did you ever see
a knife fight?
No.
.
You?
No
Anybody here ever
see a knife fight?
Well, I have. You know,
on my back stoop, the lot
across the street, backyard.
Switchblades came
with the neighborhood
where I lived.
Funny I never
thought of it before.
I guess you try to
forget those things.
How do you
use a switchblade?
Well, you'd never
use it like this.
See, you'd lose too much
time switching hands.
Here's how. Underhanded.
e
Anyone who's ever
used a switch knif
wouldn't handle
it any other way.
Are you sure?
I'm sure.
.
It's why they're
made to open like that
You'd say the boy
was pretty handy
with a knife?
Mmm-hmm.
You think he could have
made the kind of wound
that killed his father?
No. Not with the experience
he got all his life handling
these things.
I feel he'd have gone
for him underhanded.
How do you know?
Were you in the room
when the father was killed?
No. Neither was anybody else.
Then what are you giving us
all this mumbo jumbo for?
I don't believe it.
I don't think
you can determine
what type of wound
the boy might or
might not have made
simply because he knew
how to handle a knife.
What do you think?
I don't know.
What do you mean,
you don't know?
I don't know.
How about you?
I don't know about
the rest of them,
but I'm getting a little
tired of this yakkety-yakking
back and forth.
It's getting us nowhere.
So I guess I'll
have to break it up.
I'm changing my vote
to not guilty.
You're what?
You heard me.
I've had enough.
What do you mean
you've had enough?
That's no answer.
Listen, you just
take care of yourself.
You know?
.
He's right
That's not an answer.
What kind of
a man are you?
You have sat here
and voted guilty
with everyone else
because there are some
baseball tickets burning
a hole in your pocket.
Now you have changed your vote
because you say you're sick
of all the talking here?
Now, listen, buddy...
Who tells you that you have
the right to play like this
with a man's life?
.
Don't you care...
Now, wait a minute
You can't talk
like that to me.
I can talk like that to you.
If you want to
vote not guilty,
then do it because
you are convinced
the man is not guilty,
not because
you've had enough.
And if you think he is guilty,
then vote that way.
Or don't you have the guts
to do what you think is right?
Now, listen...
Guilty or not guilty?
I told you. Not guilty.
Why?
Look, I don't have to...
You do have to. Say it. Why?
I don't think he's guilty.
I want another vote.
JUROR #1: Okay, that's
another vote called for.
I guess the quickest way
is a show of hands.
Anyone object?
Okay,
all those voting not guilty,
raise your hands.
One, two, three,
four, five, six, seven,
eight.
Um...
Nine.
All those voting guilty,
raise your hands.
One, two, three.
Well, the vote's 9-3
in favor of acquittal.
I don't understand you people!
All these picky little points
you keep bringing up,
they don't mean nothing!
You saw this kid
just like I did.
You're not gonna tell me you
believe that phony story about
losing the knife
and that business
about being at the movies!
Look, you know how
these people lie.
It's born in them.
What the heck?
I don't have to tell you.
They don't know
what the truth is!
And let me tell you,
they don't need
any real big reason
to kill someone, either.
.
No, sir.
They get drunk
They're real big drinkers,
all of them.
You know that.
And bang! Someone's
lying in the gutter.
Nobody's blaming them
for it. That's the way
they are, by nature.
You know what I mean?
Violent.
Where are you going?
Human life don't mean
as much to them
as it does to us.
Look, they're lushing it u
p and fighting all the time,
and if somebody gets killed,
so somebody gets killed!
They don't care!
Sure, there's some good things
about them, too.
Look, I'm the firs
t one to say that.
I've known a couple
who were okay,
but that's the exception.
You know what I mean?
Most of them, it's lik
e they have no feelings!
They can do anything!
What's going on here?
I'm trying
to tell you.
You're making a big mistake,
you people.
This kid is a liar.
I know it.
I know all about them.
Listen to me.
They're no good.
There's not one of the
m who's any good.
I mean, what's happening
in here?
I speak my piece,
and you...
Listen to me.
We're...
This kid on trial here
. His type.
Well, don't you
know about them?
There's a...
There's a danger here.
These people are dangerous
. They're wild.
Listen to me.
I have. Now, sit down
and don't open
your mouth again.
Some of the time...
I tell you.
It's always difficult
to keep personal prejudice
out of a thing like this.
Wherever you run into it,
prejudice always
obscures the truth.
I don't really know
what the truth is.
I don't suppose anybody
will ever really know.
Nine of us now seem
to feel that the defendant
is innocent.
But we're just
gambling on probabilities.
We may be wrong.
We may be trying to le
t a guilty man go free.
I don't know.
Nobody really can.
,
But we have
a reasonable doubt
.
and that's something
that's very
valuable in our system
No jury can
declare a man guilty
unless it's sure.
We nine can't understand
how you three
are still so sure.
Maybe you can tell us.
I'll try.
You've made some
excellent points,
but I still believe the bo
y is guilty of murder,
and I have two reasons.
One, the evidence given by
the woman across the street,
who actually saw
the murder committed.
As far as I'm concerned,
that's the most
important testimony.
And two, the fact that
she described the stabbing
d
by saying she saw the boy
raise his arm over his hea
.
and stab down into
the father's chest
She saw him do it,
the wrong way.
That's absolutely right.
Let's talk about
this woman for a moment.
She said she went to bed
about 11:00 that night.
Her bed was
next to the window,
and she could look
out while lying down
and see directly
into the boy's room
across the street.
She tossed and
turned for over an hour,
unable to sleep.
Finally, she turned toward
the window at about 12:10,
and as she looked out,
she saw the killing
through the windows
of a passing El train.
She said the lights went out
immediately after the killing,
but that she got a good
look at the boy in the act
of stabbing his father.
As far as I can see it,
this is unshakeable testimony.
Well, that's the whole case.
What do you think?
How about you?
I don't know.
So much evidence to sift.
This is a pretty
complicated business.
Frankly, I don't see
how you can
vote for acquittal.
It's not so easy to arrang
e all the evidence in order.
JUROR #3: You can throw out
all the other evidence!
The woman saw him do it!
What else do you want?
Well, maybe...
JUROR #8: Let's vote on it.
JUROR #1: Okay, there's
another vote called for.
Anyone object?
All right.
I'm changing my vote.
He's guilty.
Anybody else?
The vote is 8-4.
?
Why is this such
a personal triumph
for you, this one vote
Okay. I say we're
a hung jury. I say we
take it in to the judge.
.
How about it?
I wanna hear arguments
You, you're the leader
of the cause. What about it?
.
Let's go over it again
We've been over it again.
The boy in the gray flanne
l suit here
is bouncing
backwards and forwards
like a tennis ball.
There's no point
in getting nasty.
You keep trying to
turn this into a contest.
Okay.
.
Maybe we can talk
about setting some
kind of time limit
Yeah. Once around
for the deal, huh?
It's 6:15. Someone
before mentioned 7:00.
I think that's a point
at which we might begin
to discuss the question
of whether we're
a hung jury or not.
Don't you feel well?
I feel perfectly well,
thank you.
I was saying that 7:00
would be a reasonable time...
The reason I asked about that
was because you were
rubbing your nose like...
Oh, I'm sorry
for interrupting.
But you made a gesture
that reminded me
of something.
I'm trying to settle
something here. Do you mind?
Well, I think
this is important.
Thank you. Now, then,
I'm sure you'll
pardon me for this,
but I was wondering
why you rub your
nose like that?
Come on, will you?
At this point, I happen
to be talking to the gentleman
sitting next to you.
Now, why were you rubbing
your nose like that?
If it's any of your business,
I was rubbing it because it
bothers me a little.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Is it because of
your eyeglasses?
It is.
Now could we get
onto something else?
Your eyeglasses made those
two deep impressions on
the sides of your nose.
I hadn't noticed
that before.
That must be annoying.
It is very annoying.
I wouldn't know
about that.
I've never worn eyeglasses
. 20/20.
Listen, will you
come on already
with the optometrist bit?
The woman who testified
that she saw the killing
had those same marks
on the sides of her nose.
Holy smokes!
You know, he's right.
Please.
Just give me a minute,
and I'll be finished.
I don't know if anyone else
noticed that about her.
I didn't think of it then,
but I've been going over
her face in my mind.
She had those same marks.
She kept rubbing them
in court.
He's right.
She did do that a lot.
This woman was
about 45 years old.
She was making a
tremendous effort to look 35,
for her first
public appearance.
Heavy make-up. Dyed hair.
Brand-new clothes that
should have been worn
by a younger woman.
No glasses.
Well, women do that.
See if you can get
a mental picture of her.
What do you mean, no glasses?
How do you know
whether she wore glasses?
Just 'cause she
was rubbing her nose?
She had those marks.
I saw them.
So what?
What do you think
that means?
Listen, I'm getting so sic
k of your yelling in here...
Come on. Forget it.
.
Hey, listen. Listen,
he's right. I saw them too
I was the closest one to her.
She had these things
on the side of her nose.
What do you call those
, on the side?
What point are
you making here?
She had dyed hair,
marks on her nose.
What does that mean?
Could those marks be made
by anything other
than eyeglasses?
No. They couldn't.
I didn't see
any marks!
I did.
Strange, but I didn't
think about it before.
What about the lawyer?
Why didn't he say something?
There are 12 people in here
concentrating on this case.
11 of us didn't
think of it either.
What about
the district attorney?
You think he'd pull
a trick like that?
Have her testify
without her glasses?
Did you ever see a woman
who had to wear glasses
and didn't want to
because she thinks
they spoil her looks?
Okay, she had marks
on her nose. I'm giving
you that.
From glasses, right?
.
She didn't wanna wear them
out of the house so people
would think she's gorgeous
.
But when she saw this kid
killing his father,
she was in the house alone
That's all.
Do you wear glasses
when you go to bed?
No, I don't.
No one wears
eyeglasses to bed.
JUROR #8: It's logical
to assume that she wasn't
wearing them
when she was in bed,
tossing and turning,
trying to fall asleep.
How do you know?
I don't know.
I'm guessing.
I'm also guessing that
she probably didn't
put her glasses on
.
when she turned and looked
casually out of the window
And she herself testified
the killing took place
just as she looked out.
The lights went off
a split-second later.
She couldn't have had
time to put them on then.
Wait a second...
Here's another guess.
Maybe she honestly
thought she saw
the boy kill his father.
I say she only saw a blur.
How do you know what she saw?
How does he know all that?
!
How do you know what kind
of glasses she wore?
Maybe they were sunglasses
?
Maybe she was far-sighted!
What do you know about her
I only know
the woman's eyesight
is in question now.
She had to be able to identify
a person 60 feet away,
at night, without glasses.
You can't send
someone off to die
on evidence like that.
.
Don't give me that
Don't you think the woman
might have made a mistake?
No.
It's not possible?
No, it's not possible.
Is it possible?
Not guilty.
Do you think
he's guilty?
I think he's guilty.
Do you?
No.
I'm convinced. Not guilty.
?
What's the matter with you
I have a reasonable
doubt now.
.
It's 11 to one
What about all
the other evidence?
What about all that stuff?
?
The knife?
The whole business
Well, you said we could
throw out all
the other evidence.
JUROR #7: Well,
what do we do now?
You're alone.
I don't care whether
I'm alone or not.
It's my right.
It's your right.
Well, what do you want?
I say he's guilty.
We want to hear
your arguments.
I gave you my arguments.
We're not convinced.
.
We want to hear them again
We have as much
time as it takes.
Everything. Every single
thing that took place
in that courtroom,
but I mean everything,
says he's guilty.
What do you think?
I'm an idiot or something?
Why don't you take that stuff
about the old man.
The old man who lived there
and heard everything!
Or this business
about the knife.
What? 'Cause he found
another one exactly like it?
The old man saw him!
Right there, on the stairs.
What's the difference
how many seconds it was?
Every single thing.
The knife falling through
a hole in his pocket.
You can't prove he
didn't get to the door!
Sure, you can take all
the time, hobble around
the room,
but you can't prove it!
And what about this
business of the El?
And the movies?
There's a phony deal
if I ever heard one.
I'll bet you $5,000
I'd remember
the movies I saw.
I'm telling you,
everything that's gone on
has been twisted and turned!
This business with
the glasses? How do you know
she didn't have them on?
This woman testified
in open court!
And what about hearing
the kid yell? Huh?
I'm telling you,
I've got all the facts here.
Here...
Well, that's it.
That's the whole case.
Well?
Say something!
.
You lousy bunch
of bleeding hearts
You're not gonna
intimidate me.
I'm entitled to my opinion.
Rotten kids.
You work your life out!
(MUTTERING)
No...
Not guilty.
(SOBBING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(DOOR UNLOCKING)
JUROR #1: We're ready now.
Hey!
What's your name?
Davis.
.
My name's McCardle
Well, so long.
So long.