Alright! We're here.
It's raining so hard here.
Must be hard to drive around.
What? It still haven't moved?
Did you manage to move the truck?
It still can't be moved yet.
Why?
We need to wait until this car been moved.
The owner doesn't answer the
phone even after an hour
I even sent a text message
but still no reply.
Damn, when its raining this much!
Hello..
What's happening?
Wow, this guy is so rude!
Wow, are there really people like this?
Seriously.
Damn.
Bastard!
You!!
Mister!!
Me?
Yes you!
Why didn't you answer your phone
when we called this much?
The cargo truck can't be moved.
We had to wait for your car to
be moved for over an hour.
I set the phone to vibrate.
But earlier I heard your cell
phone ringing loudly?
I didn't hear it.
I was sleeping inside.
OK?
Ahh I really don't understand.
What do you mean?
Is it so hard to apologize to someone?
What do I need to apologize for?
You are the one who should apologize.
This is Sunday! It's not good
to disturb people's holidays.
My car was parked well, but still told
to move, what a waste of gas!
If you take all day to move house.
How much more annoying are you!
Am I wrong?
Can you speak well and politely?
I'm speaking polietly, arent I?
Then why did you poke my chest?
I think you need to exercise.
What?
I said you should exercise!
Dear!
Hello..
Oh, this is must be your family..
Welcome.
Dad, were you fighting?
Fighting?
Fighting? What fighting?
Fighting between adults?
No, we didn't fight.
It's going up..
Now its coming down.
It's raining so hard.
You must be new here.
Oh yes, hello.
You live here too?
Yes.
Oh, I live in 501
nice to meet you..
Oh the same.
Oh my.
I heard that moving on a rainy day
is said to make a lot of money.
Ah, thank you.
Have a good day.
Yes. be careful.
Hello.
Sung-Hoon.
If you are hungry.
Just use the microwave to heat the rice.
Yes.
And never open the door to strangers.
Mom come home early.
If it rains, close the windows!
- Alright.
- Good!
Its very relaxing.
Its because this is our home.
This house is very nice.
Because this is our home.
This house is really very comfortable.
That's because this is our house.
Dad.
When will the TV arrive?
Su-Chan.
Take a look at our house first
TV TV!!
Here! Su-Chan!
Honey Because you're going to
be working much harder now.
Exercise a bit more and.
Learn English again.
Do everything you want.
We still have a lot of debt.
We need more money
I will pay the tuition fee for you.
You seem thrilled to hear your
wife pay the money for you?
Stupid!
Yah! Haven't had breakfast
like this in years.
Busy company business makes
me unable to eat breakfast.
Su-Chan, let's have breakfast!
Ok.
Here we go
eat a lot, please.
Do you want me to show you something fun?
What? what's that?
Great catch!
Wow? What did the movers do yesterday?
This table should be placed stably.
No! they can also roll on the floor.
Hey, why are you even playing while eating?
Damn!!!
Why are you so afraid like that?
I'm just a human.
Who's scared?!
It's obvious you're scared?
Come on in!
Enter!
You are right, go here.
You have to stay fit.
You are right.
For you, I give it cheaper
Come on!
Are you the owner of this Gym place?
I'm not the boss.
But something similar
I'm the coach here.
Oh, look at that...
I'm afraid it's too late
I will consider coming back.
What's too late? Really weird.
Excuse me.
Yes Yes Good!
Ok so.
You made the right decision.
Not that...
Stop it! Let's register right away.
House.. House..
- House.
- What happened to the house?
Do you think our houses are a bit tilted?
How can our houses be tilted?
I think my living room
floor is a bit slanted.
It unbalances household items.
No! no! No!
My living room is very flat.
- If you have marbles in your house...
- WHAT!!
I'm a grown man now.
Do you think I still play with marbles?
No.
Forget it, let's register
I am late!
Strange people!!
What am I doing?
What is such a person called?
- Chief!
- Yes.
I heard you bought a house
in Seoul and have moved?
Yes.
Congratulations.
Why didn't you tell us?
Congratulations Chief Park.
Oh, it's not that big of a deal.
Congratulations.
Thanks, all of you.
To celebrate Mr. Park who
bought a house in Seoul city.
Let's all clap!
Clap Clap.
Our chief Park bought a house in Seoul.
His own house!
Don't clap, don't clap.
It's not something big.
In which neighborhood do you live?
Changshou-dong.
Ah that.
Isn't there an industrial complex
in Changshou-dong?
The industrial complex has
been gone for a long time.
When I was little, my dad's
car was dumped there.
The car waste plant has been
gone for a long time.
Now there is an eco-friendly community.
Isn't there a noisy subway
in Changshou-dong?
How can I hear the sound of the subway?
Then how can a new building be built now?
Also the wall is surrounded
by two or three layers.
Even if there is a war,
we can't hear anything.
Is this your house?
No, no!
Watch the ball roll.
The ball just rolls on the floor.
Is this the floor of a room
or a football field?
- This is a house?
- When are you guys coming?
When will you guys visit for house warming?
- Its nice if its sooner.
- Ok. The sooner the better, right?
I accept.
- Please work.
- Okay.
Why are you playing with that?
I heard if the house is tilted..
The window frame will change and
the sliding window will get stuck.
Is it okay now?
Excuse me.
Anyone here?
You made an appointment beforehand right?
I made an appointment online.
For half discount.
Great!
I want too.
How is it?
If our family could hang a family portrait,
it would be beautiful, wouldn't it?
Yes.
Looks real good.
Right?
The owner of this place.
Has it set up nicely.
It's supposed to be this cool.
Hello.
Hel..
OH..
Why do you always get scared
every time I see you?
Is the owner of this place away?
I am the owner.
Hello.
Gosh.. hello.
Hi hello too.
You are very handsome.
How about the gym upstairs?
The gym was opened by my sister
I just... help check it every few days.
This's my main task.
Okay? You are very well dressed today.
Set.
Okay, this is a good composition.
Lets shoot.
Oh madam.
Your posture is too elegant.
Hello sir.
Do you feel uncomfortable?
Let's take a quick photo now.
Okay, then.
Let's put on a nice expression
I wil take a portrait of
this harmonious family.
Pity.
Come one, smile.
Hey that's great.
Come on!
I'll take a picture!
One…
Two three!
Ahh so nice.
Wow, what a great result
Seoul looks more beautiful when it rains.
We came here from far away empty handed.
It took 11 years to own my own house.
You worked hard.
Its all thanks to you
I'm the one thankful to you.
Let's drink
I'm driving.
This is Seoul.
How expensive is it to find a driver?
I'll pay.
Okay then, let's have a drink.
Cheers!
I want too.
Cheers!!
Mister driver, where are you?
Ah! I'm here.
Ah I see you
I can see you.
I will do my best.
To take you home comfortably.
Hello.
Oh hello hello.
Why are you afraid again?
The speed limit ahead is 60 kilometers.
Stop.
Stop!
Photographed.. we were photographed!
Ahh we're being photographed
by speed cameras.
Not photographed.
I saw a speed camera flash.
Gosh, we're not being photographed.
Yellow... the yellow light mean to stop.
How can you go on?
Some people stop at a yellow light
and some continue to drive
I'm one of those people who keep driving.
According to traffic laws you must stop.
No.. We can go.
Wow.
Wow... I'll show you.
I found it, here look!
This!
See?
Look!
Here look!
We have arrived.
Isn't this telling the yellow
light means to stop?
Oh, Su-Chan did you have a good time.
- Right.
- Thank you Uncle.
Please go inside.
Hey.
Do you prefer anything?
It's easy for us if you like something.
- Maybe something you need in your new home.
- What's the budget?
200,000 or more
200,000?
Manager Kim!
Isn't that Eun-Joo?
Go help her.
Eun-Joo, just let it be,
I'll do it later.
No need
- I can do it.
- Okay.
Damn bastard!
Cooking utensil.
Electronic blankets.
Can't you just give me some money?
- It will be engraved with your name.
- Just give me the money
I have something I want and
am a little short on money.
What is this chair?
Company collegues bought
me this as a present.
Isn't it expensive?
How do I know
I'm the one whose tired,
why are you the one on the expensive chair?
It's common chair, common.
Dad
I also want to try
just go play.
No.
Just let him try it.
Isn't it common property which
whole familiy can use?
My wife want to sit on it too.
Then you just sleep in that rocking chair.
Sleep forever!
Let's go.
Why is this happening?
What is wrong? It's not like
getting hit by a rock.
Could it break by itself?
Mister.
I didn't do it.
Who else if not you?
Damn, it's really not me!
Fix it as soon as possible.
Or do you want me to call the Police?
- Ah!
- What do you mean police?
Why are you looking like that?
Alright, then work hard okay.
- First, I'll take care of it...
- I don't have to help you.
Yes yes.
It's a newly built 5 storey
residential building.
Of course the municipal council should
take care of unsafe development.
Is there any visible damage?
So the residents should
have a meeting first..
And must all residents agree?
This building where we live in.
Maintenance service is not good.
Frankly I want to tell you all is that
something is wrong now.
What's wrong with the house?
First of all the windows
start to get stuck.
And it's not good.
This proves that our house is tilted.
- Damn the tilted house again!
- Our house is tilted?
If it is reported that our house is like
this, it will cause house prices to fall.
- That's right.
- But my window is stuck too.
How about house 202? Is it alright?
Ah.. I'm at the store more often,
so I'm rarely at home.
How about number 502?
How is it?
I just always smell of smoke from below.
And the windows of our house have long
been closed I'm not so sure either.
Maybe from house number 401?
No one smokes in my house.
If its not you who else then?
Look at your dry face.
Isn't it like a bamboo pole?
Ahh damn, what a bastard is this woman?!
I've quit smoking for over 10 years.
What smell of smoke?
Okay.
Try to smell this.
There is a smell of smoke!
- What?
- He smells of cigarettes.
Don't fight, please don't fight!
You two are like husband and wife.
You are sinners.
Everyone, stop arguing, stop arguing.
No, they suspect me.
I hate being suspected!
Ahh, I want to die.
Dad, next month.
Will send you to Civil Servant school.
Do not worry.
But dad has no money.
Hey, dad has distributed flyers.
Worked in call center.
If you smoke.
Go up to the top floor and smoke.
The occupant of our upper house said
the smell of smoke, they said.
They can smell the smoke.
I don't smoke.
Right, you don't smoke, do you?
Look, I'm going to go to tell her...
I have to give a 502 tenant a lesson...
Hey Seung-tae.
Daddy won't say, eat, eat.
Let's eat.
Come out.
- Take the gifts -Okay.
The environment is quite clean, right?
Let's go!
Calm and it's suitable for kids.
It's very quiet here.
What is this?
The old woman who lives in 301
keeps threatening me to death.
It's the plastic used to
make winter Kimchi.
That's pretty good in my opinion.
It's definitely not glass.
Of course! I know that.
This is not real glass.
You are so stiff.
I haven't seen winter
kimchi in a long time.
They came here for house warming right?
Hello, we are all co-workers of Chief Park.
Ah, apparently you are a Chief
thank you
hey no. 501, wait a minute!
I found some flaws.
Look at this!
It's in that back parking lot
I think it has a crack.
This is the entrance to the parking lot.
You saw it right, the big crack.
You have to take a closer
look to find them!
Our house is really a mess.
There's more here.
Are you saying this is
the current situation?
Current situation!!
This is not only a current problem
but a future problem too.
This is amazing. Look over there!
There are more.
Alright now!!
Take a look at this.
It's everywhere here.
This is...
Come see.
This is dangerous, seriously!
How come people live here?
Why do you press that?
Come here! straight through here!
Enter!
That is true.
Come on in.
Enter!
Why, thank you.
- You bought a lot.
- Thank you.
- Yes.
Hello.
Su-Chan!
Welcome, come in!
The house is very spacious.
- It smells great.
- It's not that much though.
Hello.
How much does this house cost?
Um... 3 Billion.
Gosh... Amazing!
What's amazing?
That!
Isn't it very similar to Mount Everest?
The mountain you see
but you can't visit.
Even if you win the jackpot,
you won't be able to go there.
Who doesn't understand Apartments?
Don't you understand the market?
I wouldn't buy it if I couldn't afford it.
You have to find money by taking a loan.
Then you can buy an apartment.
Manager Jung bought an apartment
for 450 million earlier this year.
Hey don't say that.
House prices increased by
200 million in 6 months
200 million??
Yes!!
Wow up 200 million.
Up 200 million.
That much..
Eun-Joo?!
Its not polite to leave the table
until you're done drinking.
Come here sit down again.
I want to drink alone.
Suddenly?
Yes!
Eun-Joo, your glass is empty.
Manager Kim!
Please pour some for Eun-Joo.
Where are you going?
Toilet!
Oh, I should get some watermelon
from the fridge too.
Manager Jung, why aren't you drinking?
I have to drive home.
Just drinking coke is enough
I will help call a driver for you
I really just want to drink coke.
No need no need
I have the driver's phone number.
Really crazy.
Here he is.
This.
- Let's drink!
- No.
- No need.
It does not matter.
- It's okay.
- I'm serious.
Damn it!
What?
I will take you comfortably.
You came sir!
You came.
Oh you called the right person.
How can you drive if you drink like this?
This master will drive despite
the yellow light.
So you guys have to keep
an eye on it, okay?
Dear.
Have you eaten yet?
Are you asking for real?
Yes.
Oh brother?
Kimchi winter plastic installer is here.
Come on I'll pour you a glass.
No, no!
Cause I'll be driving.
Photographer Jeong Man, food is ready.
Is that right.
Ok.
Cheers.
Why didn't you have a drink
earlier Manager Jung?
Because the driver is here..
- Drink!
- When are we going home?
Why?
Wait a little longer.
What time is it.
Why are you whispering?
Why whisper??
Are you guys dating?
No!
No.
Chief.
Don't talk nonsense.
Am I talking nonsense?
Mr. Park really misunderstood.
Did I misunderstand?
Chief Park, are you drunk?
You're not wrong.
We really love each other.
You bastard!!
What are you doing?
They say they love each other
I'm sorry senior.
Don't call senior bastard!!
You're not my junior at all bastard!!
Hyo-Jeong!!
You can't call that name asshole!
Yes yes I'm ready to go!!
Manager Kim, don't follow your past!
Drink.
It must be hard but.
Now its time to go home.
It's not good to stay in someone
else's house for too long.
Where do you live?
Cheongun-dong.
Hmm Cheongun-dong.
Where does Miss Rocking Chair live?
Anyang.
Anyang?
The car keys!
I will go to Anyang first then Cheongun.
But I won't drive.
Why?
I don't have a car.
Then we'll use our car.
Go to Anyang first then Cheongun.
Starting from Changsin-Dong...
30,000 plus 50,000.
Originally 90,000.
Makes you 80,000 only!
Eighty thousand????
Why?
This is the discounted price.
Just sleep here.
There are 3 rooms in our house.
Wow.
I have to take you home soon.
Because your parents should
be worried about you.
Right?
I live alone.
Oh.
Living alone.
There are 3 rooms, 3 rooms.
My son is sleeping in his room
I sleep with my wife in that room.
In the other room, let Manager Kim
and Eunjoo sleep together.
And..
Su-Chan sleeps in Su-Chan's room.
In the other one you sleep
with Manager Jung.
In the last room, Su-Chan't mother sleeps
with the woman who lives alone.
I will go home and sleep alone!!
Wow you are so smart.
Right?
Where is Manager Jung?
Please be careful.
Ahh mom, be careful.
Oh Sister..
We were just about to leave.
Are you leaving?
I forgot I have an appointment today.
You know mom never misses to go
to the bath house on Saturdays.
Mom always waited for this all week,
how could you forget...
Just take mom to the bath house.
Okay, I understand. I will take care of it.
The number you have dialed
is temporarily unavailable.
Please try sending a voicemail.
Try once again.
Hello.
Oh my God, this kid is so polite.
Yes.
Oh!
Your house still don't have water right?
Yes.
We go on vacation when the water runs out.
By going to the sauna!
Vacation in sauna on today and tomorrow.
Ahh I'm so happy.
But.
This building of ours is
really of poor quality.
Why are you talking about that again.
Why?
Let's go!
Oh yes.
- Be careful
- Oh yes, the same.
See you later.
- Mom.
- Yes?
Daddy doesn't answer the phone.
How about I go back and get the trolley?
Can you do it alone?
Yes!
My son is all grown up.
Go Go!
Be careful.
Yes.
Damn it!
I'll be there after crossing the bridge.
Okay, Okay.
Yes.
- Please drive faster.
- Yes!
No.
This is peak time for traffic.
Ah today is Saturday?
Saturday?
Oh be careful!
I'm hanging up,
I will arrive soon.
Mister driver
I'm sorry but I missed my bag.
Can you stop and come around once more?
I'll go up and come down again soon.
Sorry
I'll be back.
Damn it!
Excuse me, is anyone home?
Is there water in your house?
No one is in the house.
Eun-Joo.
Eun-Joo, my bag..
Hello.
Oh good.
Su-Chan.
Yes.
If you see uncle 10 times a day,
would you still greet him?
Yes!
You are really a good boy and very polite.
I knocked on your door but
your father didn't open it.
My dad is sleeping.
Su-Chan, do you have water in your house?
No.
No water.
Oh damn, who's smoking on the
roof of this building? Damn it!
Wait a minute, I have to check
if the water pump is working.
Sorry
I've thought about it.
Make me crazy.
Not much time.
Hello Uncle
I just wanted to ask, if there's
water running in your building?
In our building there is no water.
Oh there's water.
- Ok ok.
- There's water!
Yes yes.
No problem.
Okay, why are you spraying me?
Watch out mom!
Damn it!
Help!
Uncle call 119119!
Mom.
Uncle quickly call 119
11... Call 119...
Yeong-Yi!!
Su-Chan?
Su-Chan!!
Where are you bastard?!
Bingseu, listen to me carefully now!
What? What?
I'm afraid I can't go to the wedding today.
- What did you say?
- I…
I'm sinking underground now.
Just drown forever, bitch!!
I'm really drowning asshole!!
119 call 119.
Oh my God, What is this?
What is this?!!
Help.
Please Taxi, let's go.
Let's go home. Let's go home.
Don't come any further.
I beg you.
What is this?
How come there's a taxi here?
Oh my chair!
Chief, please help me!
Mr. Kim?
What are you doing there?
I do not know.
Open the door, get me out!
Damn taxi, why are you driving again?!
Quick pull! pull firmly
I beg you!!
Pull!!
Pull hard.
Mr Kim?!
You bastard!!
- What do I do?
- You killed me!!
Mr. Kim, don't give up!
Keep trying inside!
I beg you!
Mr. Kim!
This is bad!!
Mr. Kim, come out.
Thank you for real.
Help me!
Dear??
Yeong-Yi.
Chief!!?
Dear??
Seriously! Come on quickly pick up!!
Eun-Joo??
- Are you okay?
- Yes!
Have you seen my family?
How long will it take for the SAR
Team to carry out the rescue?
It could take a long time.
Please evacuate the citizens immediately
and check the situation of the victims.
Yes I understand!
Damn it!!
It's done.. It worked.
Su-Chan?!!
We're here!
I saw it I saw it...
Su-Chan?
Who are you?
I saw it.
When I'm standing at the door at 502.
Su-Chan then left the house
I saw him take the elevator.
Then I went to the rooftop.
This incident happened in
just a few minutes.
Su-Chan must be fine.
He will be fine
thank you
my god.
Ah ah.
It hurts.
Do not do it!
Seung-Tae?
My child?
Seung-Tae
Seung-Tae!
Where did Seung-Tae go?
- Who is Seung-Tae?
- Seung-Tae!
Seung-Tae!!
Seung-Tae.
This way!
Seung-Tae
Seung-Tae.
- Where are you?
- Seung-Tae!!
Seung-Tae.
Shoes!
Shoes!!
Shoes?
Shoes? Whose shoes?
Look at the shoes!
Shoes.
Shoes aren't here!
Shoes! What shoes do you mean?
My Seung-Tae's shoes.
Not in the shoe closet right now.
That means he went to the internet cafe
Seung-Tae goes to the internet cafe??
Means he's fine.
It looks like one of that...
Sinkhole.
My estimate is we're
around 500 meters down.
Is it because of an earthquake or the war?
I'm certain..
It's a sinkhole.
Eun-Joo, where are you going?
Going to the top of the building,
maybe you can get a signal there.
Or maybe you'll face death.
Let's go together!
Ahh.. I won't go.
It's too dangerous.
Didn't you say the yellow
light means go on?
This is a red light.
Gotta stop.
The foundation is unstable,
you have to be careful.
Danger! Avalanche!
Everyone, quickly pull it quickly!!!
Quickly! you are in danger!
Climb!!
Be Careful, It's dangerous.
Don't... don't go through there.
It's..
Dangerous there.
Why did you come?
- I...
- Okay, you stay here!
Thank you.
Eun-Joo, you got a signal?
No!
- Keep looking!
- Yes.
There must be a place with a signal.
Have you ever seen anything like that?
I've seen something like that.
When?
At 9 years old..
I once fell into a well.
Well?
Yes!
I crawled out by myself.
Maybe with this too.
Help!
- There's people down here.
- Help!
Help!
- Hello!!
- Is there anyone?
There are people here.
Help!!
Please save us!!
Ouch... That's why I told you..
To go home.
Costs 80,000 but didn't want to go.
What do you mean?
Last night you know.
I want to use my car to take
you and that woman home.
Go to Anyang first then to Cheongun.
It would be 90,000 then 80,000,
Didn't I tell you?
Still says it's too expensive.
Didn't even wanted to go.
I did that?
No, It was your chief Mr. Park.
Me?
You don't remember?
You were so drunk.
Eighty thousand???
Isn't that what you said?
Did I say that Eun-Joo?
Yes.
Damn it!
Shut up, shut up!
- There are people here.
- His voice seems familiar.
Hello.
Help.
- Hey.
- Hey, isn't that Seung-Tae?
- Seung-Tae?
- Hello?
- Dad!!
I'm here.
Wait
Seung-Tae.
What is this? Was there an earthquake?
Sinkhole.
- Sinkhole?
- Yes.
Didn't you go to the internet cafe?
I've stopped going there.
Then what were you doing on the roof?
Getting some air.
Why didn't you go to the cafe?
Didn't dad tell me not to go?
What's the matter..
That you didn't go to the internet cafe.
Why not go...
Are you hurt? My son?
Are you hurt?
Oh damn.
Then let's think about what
we should plan next.
We are now in a disaster.
First of all, we have to collect
supplies to survive.
Drinking water, food.
Drugs.
And a clean bed.
And we have to let the outside
know that we're still alive.
We have to stand here and count one by one.
If we find movement above.
We send a signal with a flashlight.
How can you understand
a situation like this?
I learned from Brother Chris on YouTube.
Really weird.
What is it?
He shouldn't know any brother.
I don't think he goes to the
internet cafe all day.
He's at home and just surfing the internet.
Maybe a foreign friend.
He can't speak English,
where are foreign friends from?
We better find a way out.
It is currently very dangerous
near the scene.
It's hard for us to verify the
situation inside the sinkhole.
But later after evacuating the citizens.
We will try to enter the sinkhole.
Please everyone trust us.
Please be patient waiting.
Please take care of it sir.
Ok we will try our best.
Then let's check the list of family
members buried in the ground.
Please say one by one
Lee Seung-Hoon is 10 years old.
This is No. 202
Park Dong-Won is 37 years old...
I'm sorry Mr. Kim.
Eun-Joo too, I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have asked you to
come to the house warming.
I never thought I would die in
your house ever in my life.
What's wrong with you thinking about dying?
I have struggled for 11 years to buy this house
and it became like this in just 2 weeks.
Even I don't want to die,
So don't even think about dying
I really didn't want to think.
But there's these images of
death in my mind.
You should think about Hyo-Jeong.
You like that, don't you?
What's the point of liking her?
Isn't she currently dating Jung?
It's not like they're getting married.
Better to just confess
if you come out later.
Didn't you also hear that Mr. Jung
had bought an apartment?
While I live in one room.
Really incomparable.
Hey, can't you also buy an apartment?
Didn't everyone say it was
valued at 200 million?
I really don't want to repeat
I..
I'm really thinking of dying!!
I also live in one room.
So who lives in one room can't get married?
One room can be two rooms.
Two rooms can also be three rooms.
Of course, Eun-Joo is right.
Look at me, I used to live in one room.
Isn't it three rooms now?
Didn't you say you've been fighting
for 11 years? 11 years…!
In addition to the 3 rooms, you now...
Hey Seung-Tae
Seung-Tae.
What are you doing?
I'm looking for something.
Let's get out soon, something's falling.
Quickly!
Okay I'll come.
Damn it!
Damn, look at this.
What is this.
EVACUATION BUS FOR THE VICTIMS' FAMILY
Why didn't the Rescue Team people come?
Can't believe a day has passed.
Not even one has shown up yet.
They should know that we are still alive.
Of course they know.
Please calm down and be patient waiting.
Discard the expired.
Does it matter now about
the expiration date?
Mr. Kim, you are so sensitive.
I will have diarrhea if I eat expired food.
Around 10:50 this morning
in Changsin-dong, of Seoul.
The phenomenon of underlying caves
collapse, Namely a sinkhole occurred.
So far, the accident has caused a building
to collapse to the bottom of the sinkhole.
The cause of the incident was the
subsidence of the foundation.
Thus causing ground shear.
The newly completed building, collapsed.
We are currently investigating the disaster
32 people were slightly injured
7 seriously injured.
The injured are currently being taken to 11
hospitals including Yonsei University Hospital...
What I'm afraid of down there is
what if they can't eat anything.
What's this?
Roast turkey!
Let's eat.
Hey number 501, wait a minute.
Eat!
Eat.
Here you go number 501.
Let's eat.
Isn't that the new rocking
chair that you bought?
Yes.
I always thought I should buy good
furniture when I have my own house.
To not use the type of furniture that
is damaged by moving around.
I've always wanted a piece of furniture
that can be passed on to my children.
You can buy it again later.
But now I have no home.
The rain doesn't stop.
It keeps raining.
Hey, don't worry.
Wait a little longer
119 is coming.
Mr. Kim is not married yet, right?
Yes.
Don't do it.
I can't get married.
I don't have a house.
And have no future.
Mr. Park, I envied you when
you bought a house.
Did you buy it?
You bought this house?
Yes.
What is the price?
390 million.
It didn't take that long to go up.
How much did you buy yours for?
I only rent.
Deposit 30 million and rent
800,000 per month.
Oh it's so cold.
Where is firewood?
Ah there is a lot of
firewood here.
Hey you guys, let's pull the wood out.
There's a lot of firewood here.
Come on.
Use this broken chair, let me destroy it.
To be used as firewood.
Come on, quickly.
Oh so much.
Why is this so strong?
Why can't I destroy it?
What is wrong with it?
Maybe the signal is weak.
This is a big problem
Dad!
119 here.
Daddy 119
119 here
119?
Hey 119 is here 119.
Come out fast.
Team 119
119 is here 119
Where's 119?
Here!
Here.
Where?
Where? Where? Where?
Is this 119?
It says 119 on it
We are saved!
Saved!!
It fell from above.
The signal in this place must
be relatively weak.
Can't be perfect.
Ahh isn't there a big hole up there.
Why is there no signal?
When we are in tunnels and mountains,
sometimes there is no signal.
We are at 250 meters from the ground above.
Of course there will be no signal.
Can the camera still be used?
Everyone, help us.
We're stuck here.
My name is Kim Seung-Hyeon.
- Come help us
- Help me!
We're here…
Is that yours?
You don't need to know.
Why so much money?
Watch out!!
Go there.
Quick.
Come here quickly!
Go there.
Over here.
Mr. Kim!
Help me.
Where?
Mr. Kim!
Don't go, don't...
Eun-Ju, don't go...
Eun-Joo, don't dodge the rocks!
Catch!!
Mr. Park please help me pull the rope!!
Mister!
Help me.
Chief, please pull the rope.
Help! help.
Help me.
Mr. Kim!
I'm coming.
Wait a bit.
There's nothing to wait
for you bastards...!!
Pull strongly.
Keep pulling.
It must be pulled at the same time.
Pull.
Same time.
Keep going!
Help! help.
It hurts.
My feet...
Eun-Joo, hold tightly.
Dad!!
It's okay, dad is fine.
Dad!
Do not move!
Don't drown.
Dad.
It's okay, dad is fine.
Its okay.
- Dad!
- Do not!
Dad.
Dad
Seung-Tae, let go!!
Seung-Tae
Seung-Tae.
- Look at me!!
- Dad.
Brother!!
Keep standing.
Raise your head
Seung-Tae raise your head!
Oh my son
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Dad.
Dad, Dad.
Follow me!!
Brother!!
Seung-Tae!!
Are you alright?
Wake up!!
Get up!!
Seung-Tae, are you okay?
Wake up!!
Seung-Tae
Seung-Tae where is he?
Seung-Tae...
Seung-Tae wake up, Seung-Tae wake up!!
Seung-Tae wake up!
Are you all right?
Seung-Tae!!
Seung-Tae wake up!
Are you okay?
We are temporarily securing
the building with chains.
But the probability of collapsing
is still very high.
Isn't that our drone?
Let's get it!
He's an employee of my husband's company
Hong Eun-Joo, Kim Seong-Hoon.
Why is my Seong-hun not there?
That is it.
How about my Seong-Hoon?
I'm sorry.
This is all we have
Seung-Hoon...
No!!
Mr. Seo.
My husband and Su-Chan
don't seem to be together.
Please look for them.
You said Su-Chan was holding
your phone, right?
Yes.
What are people living for?
I'm just busy with the shop.
Can't even give my Seong-Hoon..
Hot food every day.
What's my life for?
If Seung-Hoon can be saved,
I will close the shop
and will always be by his side.
I have to do that.
We've tracked the phone's location.
Su-Chan's phone...
The last location was..
At the residency building.
How could this happen?
How could that be?
Good grief.
But…
This sinkhole disaster still
has its benefits.
What?
It's rare to see Seung-Tae sleeping
at my house like that.
Thank you 501.
I will repay for this in the future.
At least you should come out
alive to repay later
119 sending drones explains what?
They know what's going on.
They know we're stuck here without nothing.
By the way, are the people living
in this building all right?
Do not worry
I've been around in the morning.
Maybe due to lack of water.
There's was no one at any home.
Really?
That's really good.
I was worried about them.
Is that your mother?
Eun-Joo, did you have any
difficulties at the company?
Let me know if any.
Is that so?
Doesn't the company send gifts
home during the holidays?
I want to send it to my parents
I've never sent them to this day.
I will try...
Do you want to listen to
music or take a selfie?
Let's take a selfie.
This news just in.
It has been confirmed that there
are survivors in the sinkhole.
Meanwhile the local rescue operation
confirmed that there were more survivors.
Also doing their best to seek and save.
But there is danger of a
next possible collapse.
And it is expected that there
will be heavy rain tonight.
Will increase the difficulty
of search and rescue.
Now we know there are
survivors in the sinkhole.
But if another standing building
comes crashing down.
Then something big will happen.
How can you say that?
Who would agree to blow up a nice building?
Again, we won't blow it up.
The concrete collapse below.
It then moves the center of gravity in the
opposite direction from the sinkhole.
If we don't do this, your homes will
all sink into the sinkhole.
Do you want to save only them?
How about us?
We have to live too.
Is it right??
Of course.
If we continue like this.
We will never reach an agreement.
Right?
Of course I don't agree.
Do not agree…
There is no way to agree.
Let me say something.
I saw someone on the roof of that building.
He was looking at me all throguhout
when it happend.
When I looked at him
I was going crazy.
It took me 20 years to buy this house.
But... if now I don't agree.
I will definitely be cursed.
I agree sir.
Are the satellite phones
and rescue items ready?
We're still looking for a parachute
It takes time sir.
Hey, it's going to rain soon.
Be quick.
Yes sir!!
Lower.
Take it, son, isn't this yours?
Can't even go to school.
Although earn so much without buying books.
Take it.
Hey Seung-Tae.
Can I ask me something?
Yes.
What are you saving that money for?
My dream is to have a hundred million won.
Your dream? 100 million won?
Yes.
If you got it? What do you want to do next?
I do not know.
Ahh this kid.
So boring oh my god.
Hey Seung-Tae
look at that.
That dream... is like that star.
Very far away.
Dad, it seems to be getting closer.
What do you mean close?
Are you drunk right now?
What's this?
What's this? Is it a shooting star?
We are saved, we are saved.
It is now clear that 119 is coming soon
thank you Lord.
Ahh the water is so sweet.
What's this?
Isn't this a satellite phone?
There's a signal.
Can we call?
Mom!!
Mom.
Why wasn't that my mom?
How come.
Not your mother?
It was a man speaking.
Eun-Joo, try calling home.
It's alright.
They will worry even more if I call now.
Can make them sadder
I'll go up and meet them directly.
Seo-Jeon.
Um, It's me Manager Kim and
Eun-Joo, we're doing well.
Thank you for worrying about me.
Seo-Jeon, I want to tell you something.
We have that gift event for
Chuseok next month.
Add Eun-Joos' name for that too.
Can it be something like ribs?
Korean beef...
Don't forget to print the company name
thank you.
Here 501.
Call Su-Chan's mother quickly.
What is it?
- Quick answer, answer!
- What's this?
Hello.
This is from the search and rescue
center can you hear us?
Thank you.
Yes, my name is Park Dong-Won.
There's five of us who survived.
Is everyone safe?
Has anyone been hurt?
Yes... everyone is fine.
I have to go in.
I have to save my son.
Park Dong-Won's wife!
We will arrive in an hour.
No, in less than 30 minutes down there.
Su-Chan is down there!!
Yeong-Yi??
Didn't Su-Chan go to the
supermarket with you?
Su-Chan took my phone.
The last location was in that building.
Dear, Su-Chan is down there.
You said you saw my son Su-Chan get
on the elevator and get out, right?
Yes, right! Is there something wrong?
- My child is missing.
- What?
He didn't go to his mom.
What are you saying?
I... I saw it clearly.
Park Dong-Won! Park Dong-won!!
You have to find your son.
You have do it before the flood.
Mom.
Chief.
Be careful.
Slowly.
Hang tight.
Are you all right Mr. 501?
Yes.
There's a cover on top of it.
Open it.
Did you see it?
Yes!
Lower.
It's collapsing!
The building is collapsing!
Raise!
Seung-Tae, go inside quickly!
What about dad?
Dad has to hold this.
Go in, hurry up! tell Seung-Tae to come in
Seung-Tae come on!!
Su-Chan!?
Dad!
Seung-Hoon let's go together!
Seung-Hoon!
Seung-Hoon let's go together
Seung-Hoon
Seung-Hoon.
Where is the chief?
Under.
I failed to.. keep hold of the rope.
How could that be?
Su-Chan.
Su-Chan!!
Su-Chan dad here!!
Dad.
Su-Chan.
Su-Chan!?
Dad.
Dad will save you.
Su-Chan.
Dad.
Su-Chan, are you okay?
My son, are you okay?
Where's mom?
Mom?! mom is waiting for you at home.
Su-Chan, let's go home.
Let's go home.
Where's Seung-Hoon?
Seung Hoon?
Grandma?
Thank you, is grandma okay?
My son is not doing well.
What?
Grandma.
Grandma, you have to come with me.
You all go.
Come with us please.
Grandma.
How is the situation now?
Everywhere has collapsed and
the water has flooded in.
Chief.
Sorry Seng-Hoon.
Sorry.
Uncle can't take you to your mother's side.
You have to live
I'm sorry grandma
Seung-Hoon.
Su-Chan let's go to mom.
Su-Chan, hold tight to dad.
Yes.
Su-Chan, are you okay?
Dad.
Hold on to dad.
Yes.
What sound is that?
We're here!
Chief?
Manager Kim!!
Mr. Jung!!
Brother Jung!
Manager Kim!!
Its 501
Brother!! Manager Kim!!
Come with me.
Follow me!
Come on!
Brother Jung!
501??
Chief!?
Brother!
- Hold on!
- Are you alright?
Manager Kim.
Su-Chan!
- Come here.
- Su-Chan, are you okay?
Chief Park, come here.
Be careful of your head.
Su-Chan.
Oh Lord.
Quickly.
Su-Chan, are you okay?
Okay?
Hello
are you okay?
Help us.
Hold him.
Be careful.
Ahh you're still alive.
Chief! Chief!
- You are safe! you are alive!
- Good Work.
Good work.
Hurry up, it's starting to flood.
Ohh look above...
Why is there a building above?
Will it fall later?
I see it moving.
The water seems to be rising.
What should we do?
What should we do about this?
This!
Use this.
Bring everything that can float.
Come search!
The floating ones.
Here.
This
Seung-Tae
Seung-Tae, look again!!
Look what mister brought!
All of you, get up here.
Come on!
Mister, this is that!
Yellow Submarine.
The Beatles' Yellow Submarine.
Dad? where is the lid?
Lid?
Has anyone seen the lid?
That's it.
Is that it?
Try closing it.
It fits!!
Yes.
No. 501, let Su-Chan go first.
Ok.
Eun-Jjoo go up!
Su-Chan.
Manager Kim.
Yes.
Be careful.
Dad.
Go on, quickly.
Get in
Seung-Tae.
Hurry up.
Be careful
you 501, get in.
Come on chief.
Brother, come on in.
Dad, climb in
I'll come back quickly.
What?
Whose going to close it
after if we all went up?
Dad!!
Dad.
Brother!!
Mister.
Dad.
Mister
Seung-Tae, dad will catch up.
- Dad!!
- Mister.
Dad.
- Uncle
- Mister.
Brother.
Mister.
- Mister
- Brother.
Dad.
Brother!
Mister.
Dad…
Dad.
Dad!!
Open the lid!
Dad.
Su-Chan, are you okay?
Seung-Tae, are you okay?
It seems to be tangled in something.
It's okay Su-Chan.
We have to push!
Jump!
Jump.
It's going up.
Eun-Joo push!!
- Push Eunjoo hard!!
- What do we do??
Keep pushing!!
Take it out!!
What is this?
Water is coming inside.
Its leaking!!
Is there anyone there?
- Help!
- Help.
Help!
Anybody there?
Dad.
Help! help.
Is there anyone there?
Anybody there?
Hey! What's that!!
Captain, they're alive!!
They are safe, They are safe!
My dad is here!!
Is everyone fine?
My child.
Hello.
Yes.
Dad.
My son Seung-Tae..
We're safe!!
Where are we?
Try calling.
He said near here, beside the Han River.
We've been along the
Han river all this time.
How can there be a house here?
Exactly, how can he have a house here?
Chief Park!
Hey Manager Kim, I brought this.
Ah you bought toilet paper.
Aih.. is this your house?
Is this your house?
This is home.
Today's view is Han River and tomorrow's
view is Mount Namsan
I'm going to Haeundae on the weekend. This
is my new home where you can go anywhere.
Bed, refrigerator, stove,
everything is there.
There's everything here.
Reasonable.
However.
A house must be in one place.
It is called a house if it is occupied
for 10 or 20 years.
Hey.
Don't wait 10 years to be happy.
- Let us be happy today.
- Let us be in love forever.
Good.
This is just our thoughts.
We plan to use the house buying
money to travel to the North Pole.
But there's too little
food and drinks here.
You can order delivery of any kind,
Should I order anything?
Delivery?
Ground Roast Chicken!
Amazing!!
Take a look at this! Look!
You guys scared?!!
Come see this.
Ah damn, it scared me.
Scared?
Isn't our house amazing?
Ahh so nice.
Ahh I want to live here too.
Ahh really beautiful.
Good!!