Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Nothing we can do, Dad.
Official YIFY movies site:
YTS.MX
We'll have to wait until someone passes by.
Stop!
Patrick!
I did everything possible, Dr. Herschel.
He'll live,
but in a coma.
A coma he may never come out of.
PATRICK STILL LIVES
It's beautiful here.
I don't like this place.
I could do without all this.
You were invited as well,
don't you forget that.
There are some appointments
even you can't miss.
Hello, Miss Randolph, I'm Lydia Grant.
Hello, Mr. Suniak.
Welcome to the Herschel Wellness Resort.
Mr. and Mrs. Cough have arrived as well.
I hope you'll get along.
During this time of the year
we don't have a lot of guests,
so I hope you have a nice, relaxing stay.
Please follow me.
Right this way, please.
The rest of the luggage will be
brought to your room.
You'll have to excuse us,
this is the slow season
and we have few guests,
so we have a reduced staff.
But I'll make sure you have
everything you need.
I can't wait to take a shower.
What a long, exhausting trip.
Don't you agree, Mr. Cough?
Mr. Cough, here is the suite that has been
reserved for you and your wife.
I hope it meets your expectations.
Thank you, Miss Grant.
Dr. Herschel will be happy to
welcome you in person.
You're welcome.
This way, please.
What's up with that guy,
is he stuck up or what?
Who is he?
Lyndon Cough is a Member of Parliament.
Lyndon Cough.
Oh sure!
What's someone like him doing here?
Doesn't he want to run for Prime Minister?
I'm sorry, I was never interested
in politics.
Mr. Suniak, this is your room.
Bye.
Here is your room, Miss Randolph.
The rooms are connected.
The door is locked, as you requested.
- Thank you.
- I'll see you later.
- Yes?
- Pardon me, Dr. Herschel.
I wanted to inform you that the
four guests have arrived at the villa,
The Coughs, Ms. Randolph, and Mr. Suniak.
Weren't there supposed to be five of them?
Yes, Mr. Davis also made reservations
for today, but he hasn't arrived yet.
Excuse me for a moment.
He just arrived this minute, Doctor.
Now everyone is here.
Very good, take care of everything.
I don't want to be disturbed
under any circumstances.
Okay.
Good boy.
Sit, sit!
Go back to your food.
Have you just arrived, sir?
Yes, just this moment.
Ah, I understand.
The guest rooms are on the other side.
I'll take you there.
It's strange, they're so vicious.
That's not normal for German shepherds.
People believe that, but these are
the fiercest animals in the world.
You must know how to train them.
- Hello there!
- Good day.
Did you know that dogs are just like men?
They like some people and dislike others.
Makes sense.
Leave us alone. The boss doesn't want you
around here, Meg.
Go to hell.
She's nice.
She seems nice, but I think she's an idiot.
Goodbye, sir.
I'm sorry, you can't stay here.
You'll have to leave.
Okay. Okay.
Don't let it go over.
Continue just like that, Brad.
Maintain a constant pressure.
If there are any changes,
let me know immediately.
Yes, Doctor.
Everything is going according to plan.
Patrick, my dear son.
The girl is here.
- It's about time, honey.
- My name is Meg.
Okay, baby, whatever you want.
Thanks.
- Not bad, huh?
- Just try it.
Here's to us.
Stella, what do you think of those two?
Do you like them?
He's a mannequin, and she's a cow.
You don't say.
I say, my dear.
Those two hate us.
Calm down, Cheryl.
I'm telling you, I'm sure of it.
Relax.
He's also a champion swimmer.
What do you think?
I'll cook him, don't worry about that.
Lydia!
What are you doing here?
But, I...
I told you that no one was allowed
in this area, not even you.
I apologize.
I called you on the intercom
but you didn't answer, so...
That's not true.
What do you want?
I wanted to know if
you had any orders for me.
There are no orders.
You can leave.
Ms. Grant...
Don't make any more mistakes.
Don't worry, Doctor. It won't happen again.
I appreciate your diligence,
but don't go overboard.
The fact that you are new here
shouldn't make you nervous.
Do we understand each other?
Yes, Doctor.
Very good.
You may go now.
What are you doing?
Is your brain fried?
I was never the smartest kid in class.
But my talents helped you get into the
House of Lords, correct?
I didn't disgust you back then.
You promised you would forget.
It's water under the bridge.
Considering that now we
find ourselves here,
I'd say not much water
has passed, dear Lyndon.
The person who wrote that letter
we received knows many things
about your political career,
and he knows a lot about me.
I don't want to hear it.
I've forgotten.
You should do the same.
Unfortunately, someone has a good memory.
If you want to stay clean, we'll have to
pay whatever he or she wants.
What I want to know is how
they found out about us,
and why they invited us here.
They could have caused a huge scandal
if they'd gone to the media.
I really don't understand.
We'll find out soon, don't worry.
And if it's a man we're dealing with,
which I hope is the case,
we'll get out of this pretty easily.
Just let me handle it.
Cut it out, Cheryl.
We don't have a choice, old friend.
Stop it.
I told you to cut it out.
You really are a slut.
You make me sick, Lyndon.
You're nothing but a small, small man.
The least you could do is
get out of my way,
considering I'm trying to help you out.
Whore.
Yes, yes, yes, I love you.
You're so handsome.
No, calm down, be quiet.
You really know what you're
doing with those animals.
It isn't hard for me to love.
- In general?
- Yes, in general.
- Would you like one?
- No, thanks.
Listen, Mr. Davis,
you can't stay. Get out of here.
Get away from this place.
Thanks for your concern, but I can't leave.
I warned you.
If you know something,
come on, let's hear it.
No, I don't know anything.
Excuse me.
I'd just like to mention that the
clinic's facilities for check-ups
are available to anyone who'd like
to take advantage of them.
Most of our guests gladly
undergo a preventive exam.
Based on the results of the exam,
I can prescribe the appropriate
diet for you.
In case of any illness,
I can supply the treatment.
Mrs. Cough and her husband shall go first,
based on their reservations.
I'll see you tomorrow morning in my office.
Is 10:30 good for you?
Well, I don't know if...
My wife and I are in excellent health,
Dr. Herschel.
We're only here for some peace and quiet.
As you wish.
So...
Mr. Davis, what do you say?
No thanks, my health is perfect.
Oh, don't look at me. The last time
I undressed in front of a doctor,
well, let's not talk about that.
Okay then, the only one left is Mr. Suniak.
Who, me?
Well, I'll think about it.
For now, let's not do anything.
As you wish.
I wouldn't want to be misunderstood.
I only want to provide you
a pleasant vacation.
Above all, your honored presence here is,
to me, a medical obligation.
Whatever reasons
have led you here, you may
count on our total discretion.
I don't need to mention the
strict confidentiality policy
the medical profession
is obligated to observe.
Please understand that I am at the disposal
of whoever would like to consult me
at any point during your stay.
Miss Lydia Grant, my able secretary,
is at your service as well.
And now a toast to your health.
Cheers.
What was that?
Miss Grant,
in the future, please make sure to
check the crystalware personally.
Don't worry, dear.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Unfortunately, at this moment,
we have a reduced staff,
and it's inevitable that there will
be some small mishaps.
Please rest assured that we'll
do everything possible to ensure that
nothing disrupts your stay.
Well, ladies and gentlemen, that's all.
Pardon me, I must check on my patients.
Before I forget, room service is available
twenty-four hours a day.
You may call anytime.
Excuse me.
Lyndon, let's get out of here.
This place gives me the creeps.
- It's so gloomy.
- Calm down Cheryl, please.
Do I have to tell you again?
While we were eating, I noticed that...
Goodnight.
See you tomorrow.
What were you going to say?
That guy, Suniak or whatever his name is,
he's carrying a pistol under his jacket.
Do you think he's the one?
I don't know, but who would come
to a resort carrying a weapon?
That's a good point.
What are you going to do?
Maybe I'll confront him.
It's better to resolve this
situation once and for all.
Be careful.
That man could be dangerous.
Let me handle it.
No.
Besides, blackmailers don't kill,
I think.
Let's not worry about it right now.
Try to get some sleep.
And lock the door, understand?
Better to be careful.
Lyndon.
Forget about what I told you earlier.
I want us to stay together.
It's been forever since we
slept together, Lyndon.
Not tonight, excuse me.
Maybe tomorrow.
Right, always tomorrow.
Good evening, Doctor.
How are my patients doing?
The same, they look like mummies.
Very well, you may leave.
I'll stay here for awhile.
Better you than me. Goodnight.
Lyndon, Lyndon!
This is impossible!
Calm down, ma'am.
Yelling doesn't help anything.
Try to relax.
- What are you screaming about?
- They've killed him!
It's a terrible tragedy.
They'll kill us all!
You're upset.
Try to calm down.
Meg will accompany you to your room.
I've given you a sedative.
In a little while you'll be asleep.
Lyndon!
Miss Grant, please take care of the
paperwork for the funeral.
Later on, I'll write the death certificate.
Please take her to her room.
I'm sorry your stay began
with this awful incident.
It's clear that Mr. Cough's
death was accidental.
The actual manner in which he perished
remains unknown at the moment.
The autopsy will shed light on the cause.
Not so fast, dear Doctor.
Someone who dies in the
shower doesn't look like this.
Why don't you tell us what really happened?
Don't say such things!
You see, Mr. Cough suffered
from severe alcoholism.
This was told to me in confidence
by Mrs. Cough.
As you all surely know,
the abuse of alcohol has this effect.
It actually precipitates,
at the endocrine level,
a neoplastic process in the human body.
I admit that it's a rare symptom,
but it appears to be what happened
this morning to Mr. Cough.
However, I assure you,
ladies and gentlemen,
there is nothing to worry about.
However unpleasant and unusual,
this incident is now over.
Please go back to enjoying your vacation.
It's kind of scary.
- What?
- The pool.
Yeah, sure.
But that's not what I was thinking about.
It's strange though.
Nobody wants to take a swim, not even you.
Well, it's not that important to me.
Why are you here?
I could ask you the same thing,
but usually I prefer to wait
and see what others do.
I think we're here for
the same reason. Fear.
Right.
Like a bunch of idiots.
But you look like a good fellow.
What's bothering you?
Those aren't questions that...
Don't ask me that.
Don't be a child.
It'll do you good to talk about it.
Leave me alone.
You're still here.
Well, why not?
Let's talk about it.
Your curiosity is interesting.
All right.
A few years ago, there was an accident.
Three people died.
It was at night and I'd been drinking,
so I fled the scene of the crime.
That's it?
I can't risk it, my father is
an important public figure.
That's why I came here.
Now that I think about it...
Davis, Davis...
By any chance is your father
the Davis of British Insurance?
Yes, so now you understand.
Don't think about it.
Why don't we go for a walk in the park?
No, I want to be alone.
Come on, it's nothing personal.
That's the way I am.
All right, let's go.
I want to apologize.
I don't mean to disturb you.
I want to do something for you.
I don't want to!
Hello, people!
How's it going?
No, no.
Wait a second,
let me rephrase the question.
How's death treating you?
Quit it. You're drunk.
Is that all you have to say?
Maybe it'll be better like this.
Go back to your room.
Get your hands off me, pig.
Don't you dare touch me, you hear?
Ma'am, don't you think you could
act more appropriately?
Well, well.
The standard bearer for
morality has spoken.
Why don't you shut up, you ugly bitch.
You think we don't know why we're here?
A wonderful gathering of so-called "fine,
upstanding citizens."
All together on a phony vacation.
What on earth are you talking about?
I'm sorry sweetie, but you're a bad liar.
The letter your husband received
is identical to mine and his.
Everyone's letter is identical.
The only possible difference
is the dirty deeds that
each of us has committed.
He was a drug dealer.
I walked the streets at
night as a prostitute.
And what about you?
We all know that you
let yourself be slammed like a cow by a
bull to help your husband's career.
That's what you did.
You're no better than any of us.
Ugh, you whore.
That's enough!
Stop, stop!
Get away from me before
I catch syphilis from you.
No more!
Stop, stop already!
I'll kill her, I'll kill her.
Stop it!
- Let me go!
- No!
I told you to let me go.
Stop, stop!
Take your hands off me.
You handle this.
Screaming women make me nervous.
No you bastard, let me go!
Come with me.
Let go of me, come on...
Let go of me, I said.
Take it easy.
Move it.
Let me go.
Don't you dare touch me!
What the hell are you doing?
What are you doing?
Here it is, just what I was looking for.
Jesus, leave it alone!
Not that!
What are you doing, are you crazy?
Leave that bottle alone!
Quiet!
You're the crazy one.
Haven't you done enough?
I'm telling the truth, nothing more.
I'm tired of being the
black sheep of this group!
Why don't you think things through, Stella?
With a good night's sleep,
you'll feel better.
You could keep me company.
Thanks for the invite,
but I usually have sex with women,
not whiskey bottles.
You like that Cheryl, don't you?
Stop with the bullshit, please.
Bastard, I shouldn't have expected
anything different.
Asshole.
Don't you like me anymore?
Maybe.
The drugs turned you into a faggot.
You'll die alone, whore.
Death...
What's the matter Davis,
do you suffer from insomnia too?
I can't fall asleep in this damn place,
no matter what I do.
Where did you leave your
gorilla, at the zoo?
My gorilla, as you call him,
is precisely that. An animal.
A beast.
Seeing as how you hold a drink so well,
after you.
Thank you.
In all my life I have never heard
anyone say something rude
so stylishly.
Let's call it British.
Here's to us.
What a nice setup.
I think this bed is nicer than mine.
If I try, I could fall asleep right away.
Well, don't just stand there.
Put down your whiskey and sit by me.
You don't like me.
- Is that it?
- No.
Well, yes, you know what I mean.
You were a lot of fun tonight, I must say.
You left them all lying on the mat.
One thing I don't get is,
why did you spare me?
It's simple.
Because in the end,
you'll have to defend me.
Don't you think?
Don't be shy.
You know I like you.
Get off me!
No Stella, I don't like garbage.
Especially a gorilla's garbage.
Bastard.
You're a coward.
Damn you!
Listen to me, when I come back
I don't want to see you in here.
You're just a whore.
You little boy.
You wouldn't be able to
understand anything else.
If you're still here in ten minutes,
I'll kill you.
Sure, little boy.
I wouldn't expect you to understand
anything else.
Little boy.
Little boy...
I'm telling you again, you have
to get out of here.
You have to tell me the truth, Meg.
What do you know about Lyndon's death?
I don't know anything, I swear.
But strange things have been
happening around here lately.
Run while you can. Run away.
Goodbye.
Death.
No! No!
Help, help!
Why did it have to be him?
No!
Watch those sensors, Brad.
I've noticed some atypical oscillations.
It can't happen again.
Help! Help!
Who's there?
Who turned off the lights?
No!
No! No!
Go away!
Stay back!
Get back!
No!
Get away from me!
No! No!
Who's yelling?
The door won't open.
I can't explain it.
It's, it's absurd.
Absolutely irrational.
I could understand the tragedy
that happened to Mr. Cough,
but what happened to those poor
bastards falls outside of human logic.
The only explanation is that
they were murdered.
I don't know.
Who could have done such a thing?
Davis was no featherweight.
You'd need the strength of a bull
to hang him up that way.
And why on earth do those
things to Miss Randolph?
I know the reason why.
- What are you saying, Mrs. Cough?
- I said I know why.
She was afraid. Afraid.
You stay away from me. Don't touch me.
Meg, please take her back to
her room immediately.
Yes, Professor.
I'm staying here. I'm staying here.
I'm staying here.
Dr. Herschel, I've had enough.
We're better off calling the police.
It's already been done, Mr. Suniak.
Don't worry, I just called
Inspector Mark Gutherie.
He'll be here soon, okay?
Have some patience.
In the meantime, he told me not to
allow anyone to leave.
I'm sorry.
Here I am.
For the love of God, don't scream.
I'm not going to kill you.
Oh yeah? So what
are you doing here?
I'm about to leave this graveyard,
and I won't bother looking back.
Take me with you.
Not a chance.
Please, I'm begging you.
I'll only take a dress.
I'll be ready in a second.
I'll do anything you want.
Get me out of here. Don't leave me.
Fine, I'll wait for you in the garage.
I'm driving a Buick.
If you're not there in five minutes,
I won't wait. Are we clear?
Yes!
Mrs. Cough!
Cheryl?
Oh, go to hell.
Help, help!
Let me out of here!
Patrick, what's happening?
Why are you refusing?
It's not over, you have to kill again.
Come on, I need you to concentrate!
Patrick you can't have forgotten.
How could you forget?
Listen to me, Patrick.
Remember
that damn road.
You have to concentrate.
We waited for them to help us.
It took me three years to find that car.
There were only six people who could
have been there to throw the bottle.
From that point on, Patrick,
I searched like a madman
into their lives,
trying to dig up any dirt,
any crimes I could find.
And I made them come here,
to their date with destiny,
to their date with you.
So you could carry out justice.
I've lived only for this day.
And in a few moments, revenge will be ours.
Are you listening to me, Patrick?
Are you listening?
You must focus, my son.
That's it, Patrick.
That's the way. Keep going.
You can't stop anymore.
The only one left is Lydia,
and you can strike her this
second if you want.
The mental energy I helped develop in you
all these years you couldn't move.
Powered by those three guinea pigs.
What a powerful force,
what a marvelous force.
You can do as you will with it!
Come on, Patrick.
You have to strike.
Strike, strike!
Kill!
What are you doing?
Why did you stop?
Patrick.
Answer me, Patrick.
Why won't you answer?
Okay, Patrick.
If you don't want to do it, I will.
No, Patrick, you can't stop me.
What the hell is going on?
Brad, go to the circuit breaker
and shut everything off.
No! No!
Help, help!
No!
Help!
No, Patrick!
No!
You can't do this to me!
Help!
Open up! Someone help!
Somebody help me!
Help!