His name is Leopold Kessler
My God! Isn't he aware of
the situation in Germany?
No! I don't want any gratitude
If your nephew is ready,
we'll begin the check-up
Thank you, Herr Kessler. There's
no need for further examination
Your nephew is of sound health
Standard fee, please
Humility, Kessler,
never forget humility
Close it!
There's nothing to see!
- Good evening, Herr Kessler
- 'Evening, Fraulein Schulze
- Tonight you'll be on train 317
- Frankfurt-Berlin
- Tomorrow, train 212
- Berlin-Munich
Then on train 522
Timetable, list of sales, receipts,
electrical chart, green cheque-book...
...book of tickets, account book
and the green journal
Thank you, Fraulein Schulze
The inspector wants you
to go to turntable 3
Really?
I've promised not to say any more...
...but I think he has
a surprise for you
Wait
I see the young Herr Kessler
has not yet paid his guarantee
I thought I'd tell you right away
- Car 2306 is back in working order
- Is it, inspector?
It is indeed, Kessler
Your nephew is off to a great start;
you may turn the handle, please
Yes, inspector
Track 8, Kessler
You will have the honour of serving
on the first First Class sleeper...
...to run under the revived
Zentropa company
We have worked night and day to
get this train back on the track
I understand you specifically wish to
become a sleeping-car conductor
A fine choice
But there was also a
symbolic element...
...in the management's decision
of giving the job to a foreigner
We are dealing with the important
matter of human transportation...
...which no borders should impede
I also started out as a
sleeping-car conductor
Those were my happiest days
An engine-driver's work is exciting
The same goes for the
systematics in the tower
But only the conductor comes into
direct contact with the passengers
He can say "I can promise you
a most pleasant journey
"You can all enjoy a peaceful sleep"
- Right, Kessler?
- Certainly, inspector
I call this a mythological task
You will accompany your uncle
while you are training
After your exam in three months'
time, you can move on
But you can read all about that
in the service rule book
Here it comes
First class tickets only!
First class tickets!
Money... please...
Give us some money
It's the rule!
You can make the bed
Please forgive me, it's my first trip
Herr Kessler, you are a true idealist
Let me tell you,
it is most frightening
Young Kessler, you're a blockhead!
Wake up! Leo, you have to hurry
My nephew, Leopold Kessler,
has been invited to dine at seven
He is entirely to blame
for any delay
I leave him in your hands. I will
wait for him in the kitchen
They've already sat down to eat
"...at the right hour You feed them
"You open Your hand and bless
all who dwell there. Amen"
Our guest has arrived
So sorry I'm late
Never excuse yourself, young man
Life is too short
Kat tells me you have recently
joined our company
I'm very pleased
Father is pleased you're American
He'd like Zentropa
to be international
Germans are ill-regarded right now
Rubbish, Larry. Let's eat
My sister's got her eye on you
Calm down, both of you
It's very brave of you to come
to Germany at such a time
A great tragedy has befallen
this part of the world
What kind of question is that
to ask our guest?
I'm afraid I'm not very religious
Herr Kessler is a sensible man
He realises that if the scars
of this war are to heal...
...then we must turn to one another
My sister says you're a deserter
In my father's opinion, so am I
That's enough, Larry
My son was too ill to join up
Ill! The illness my father
has never understood
He thinks it stems from my mother
spoiling me till the day she died
Excuse me
I apologise for my son's behaviour
- I thought you didn't like excuses
- Damn it!
Excuse me, Father
In war, life is so simple
It's only afterwards that
complications arise
- Don't you agree, Father?
- Certainly
Religion is important in wartime...
...but even more so when the silence
of arms toys with our peace of mind
When we pray to God
in time of war...
...we can only rely on His support
if we have faith in our cause
Excuse me, Father...
...but what about the other side?
Why, of course, Herr Kessler.
God is on everyone's side
But when you fight for a cause
with all your heart...
...then God finds it
easier to forgive...
...if, in doing so, you disobey
His commands
Who does God not forgive?
Those who do not believe
Those who remain lukewarm,
who don't take sides
They are condemned to
eternal wandering
He shows them no mercy,
Herr Kessler
"So, because thou art lukewarm,
and neither cold nor hot...
"...I will spew thee out of my mouth"
They're about to blast them
The Allies are blowing up cranes in
Westhafen. They're dismantling...
Dismantling?
To prevent another German
military power from rising up
They're destroying everything that
could be used for military ends
I fail to see how the few cranes
we have left might pose a threat
The food supply situation
will become even worse
You're so naive, Kat. The cranes
are loading coal for IG-Farben
The Americans are clever, they
get hold of the chemical patents...
...and then they destroy the plants
to prevent production
All in the name of demilitarization
So that's that. You can
serve the coffee now
You must understand, Leopold...
Our family has always treasured
international contacts
Pay us a visit from time to time
How about dinner on Friday?
I'm sure you'll like Alex
We studied together in Berlin
and now he's back in Germany
Colonel Harris
Thank you for a pleasant evening
I must go and check on the church
before curfew
I'm afraid we won't have time for
chess tonight, Colonel Harris
Come and sit down
Your uncle wants to leave now.
He's waiting in the hall
Goodbye, Fraulein Hartmann
Herr Kessler
I'm a friend of the Hartmann family
They said I could ask a small favour
My nephews are going to Cologne
Would you please look after them?
They'll be picked up at the station
The tickets and papers are in order
You can stay in here
Sekt for Ravenstein
The Allied command in Frankfurt
has appointed my husband mayor
- Congratulations
- Thank you
Excuse me
- Are you the engine-driver?
- I'm the sleeping-car conductor
I don't wish to impose...
...but my family and myself lived
in London during the war...
...and now we're returning
to Wolstadt
But my wife is suddenly refusing
to get off the train
She's very upset about the state
Germany is in right now
Would you be so kind as to
help me set her mind at rest?
If you could perhaps reassure her...
...that Wolstadt has been
spared the havoc of war
We live at 43 Sachsenstrasse
I don't know Wolstadt, but what
I've seen from the train looks bad
But you must help me
I'll never get her off the train
Wolstadt is our home, we can
get a taxi from the station...
My dear, I have encouraging news
Please repeat what you told me
I don't really know Wolstadt...
But you did tell me Wolstadt
had been spared
I only know what I saw
from the train
Did you hear?
Next station is Wolstadt.
You'd better get ready
Palestine!
She wants us to live in the desert
We are Jewish, but we are German,
but we are Jewish
Savages!
It's outrageous!
We have problems with the heating,
but we can offer you blankets
Give the children some chocolate
- We'd like another bottle of sekt
- Of course, right away
Go on, have another piece
Chocolate?
Papers, please
I insist on a return game
today, Colonel Harris
I've never understood how anyone
could be proud to be German
If I had my way, I'd be on a plane
bound for America today
You find that hard to understand
I think the war was a waste of time
It's how you would feel if you were
to attend the good Father's Mass
The ceremony might be colourful,
even entertaining...
...but to an unbeliever it's simply
a sophisticated waste of time
Shoddy too, when the sacrament
is nothing but a dry cracker
She's flirting with you
A bit scheming, don't you think?
Why not dance with her?
Not today, I'm a little tired
It's time, Max. The Jew is here
Marie...
Bring me those silly papers
They're the rules
I must ask, do you know this man?
Max Hartmann is my friend. He gave
me food and hid me in his cellar
No more!
I won't do it again
Do what you like!
Is it my move?
What am I doing? No...
I think I'll retire now
No need to disturb
the Father and Alex
Good night to you both
Good night, father
Your uncle has always
been a good man
Don't forget that
whatever happens...
...you must always do
what you think is right
Never let anyone tell you otherwise
Katharina...
Put the lamp out
The lamp
I am a werewolf!
Yes, I'm afraid I have to admit
you have won
It's just a game
It's time to go home, Colonel
Do you have a moment?
We need your help
I beg you, Herr Leopold,
come with me
Be careful
Welcome, Herr Kessler
I can understand that this set-up
might puzzle you somewhat
But this sector is in a
state of emergency...
...and the authorities won't allow us
to give Max a proper burial
Gatherings are forbidden,
Herr Kessler
Therefore we must resort to this...
...most unworthy arrangement
We will proceed with our ceremony
in secret...
...like the Christians
in the catacombs
Everyone is gathering at the old
marshalling-yard at Darmstadt
Your job is to stop the train there...
...so that we can get the coffin
off the train
You've pulled the emergency brake!
Herr Leopold!
Over here
Kat is a lovely girl
I just wanted to thank you
My nephews' journey
went splendidly
What would they have done
without you?
Our superiors appreciate your help
in the Ravenstein assassination
We have a new job in mind for you
There's your girlfriend
Listen, Leo
I'm not asking you to
decide right now
We will offer Herr Kessler
a ride back to Frankfurt
Then we must fix the back door
It sticks
You have a visitor
- I hope I'm not intruding
- Not at all
Have you been promoted yet?
My exam is in a few weeks
What are you doing in Munich?
I'm at St Christopher's Church
I've come...
I've come to ask you not to
judge Kat too harshly
I know that she told you
about her mistake
Kat is confused, as so many
others are these days
But she is not a werewolf
She repents her sins and is trying
very hard to make amends
She had to flee from those people
in Frankfurt. They stop at nothing
Max Hartmann received
threatening letters
His collaboration with the
Americans was no secret
And after he died, the authorities
confiscated his entire estate
Do you have any contact with Kat?
I really must go now.
We will meet again
Herr Kessler, if I were you...
...l'd attend the Midnight Mass
at St Christopher's tonight
With this ring I thee wed
In the name of the Holy Trinity
I'm afraid the young Herr Hartmann
wasn't as co-operative as yourself
But then, what's one faggot less?
We've taken her to a
temporary hiding place
We thought you'd be more
co-operative if she was with us
I'm so glad you came, Leopold.
We can discuss your next job
We would like the Bremen line
to be shut down, tonight
You're a capable man
We're sure you can handle
a big job like this
All you have to do is place some
explosives underneath your sleeper
The bomb will be detonated
on the Neuwied Bridge
You'll have ample time to get out
I'm sorry to press you like this,
because I do like you
Remember, tonight you're
going on the Bremen Express
Allow me to present the examinee:
Leopold Kessler, my nephew
Herr Seifert and Inspector Stelemann
are in charge of the examination
There is a practical
and a theoretical part
First, we'll ask some questions
Then we will accompany you...
...to see how you manage with both
the passengers and the equipment
The conductor must be both
polite and firm at all times
Accompany us to compartment 9
and we can begin
Has this exam taken you
by surprise?
No, it's just that I was attending to
one of the passengers
If you don't mind, I'll just finish what
I was doing and be back at once
They want you to place a bomb.
Listen to me!
Tell him your life is at stake
I can't say any more
They're watching you, remember
Checkpoint Urmitz!
The external examiner is
getting a little impatient
I think we had better proceed
with the examination
So, we would like to know
what you would do...
...if the cleaner handed you
a green card...
...filled in like this
Have you gone completely mad?
Get out of here this instant!
My nephew's behaviour
cannot be excused
My first thought was to advise you
to cancel the exam at once
- Do you wish to proceed?
- That is up to the examiner
I shall repeat my question
What would you do if the cleaner...
...handed you a green card
filled in like this?
Can't you see it's filled in
incorrectly?
Completely incorrect
Would you like to tell the examinee
the correct answer to the question?
It's a trick question
The answer is:
Report the cleaner immediately!
The green card should never be
in the cleaner's possession
The cleaner never keeps any
papers for the conductor
On the contrary, the conductor
must give him a receipt...
...as soon as he takes over
And which form is used for this?
Yes, B, that is correct
And now a question after
Herr Seifert's own heart
What is stated in paragraph 4,
section 62 of the rule book?
I must inform you that an open collar
is against the regulations
Your uncle kindly got a card for you
We now want you to make bed 42
I have put the correct number
of bedding covers out for you
You may begin when I say so
We want you to make the bed twice
Then we will examine the bed
Are you ready with the clock?
You may now begin
The clock is ticking
The clock is ticking!
No time for that
The clock is ticking
Hurry, Herr Kessler,
the clock is ticking
The clock is ticking!
Thank you
Herr Kessler
Would you please come to
compartment 9 for a moment?
I was told I might find
the conductor here
I have a problem. Is it too much
to ask for a bit of service?
We must be quiet
The external examiner needs to rest
before we proceed with the exam
Let me give you a piece of advice
In my opinion, you have
only one chance
When Herr Seifert wakes up, ask him
to follow you through the train...
...as you give each of the passengers
an unconditional apology
Conductor!
These shoes need polishing
I wanted them polished
I am sure the shoes
have been polished
I don't think so,
there's no chalk mark
You'd better watch your step!
You pulled the emergency brake!
Refreshments?
Bedmaking?
Shoe-shine?