His name is Leopold Kessler.
My God! Isn't he aware of
the situation in Germany?
No! I don't want any gratitude.
If your nephew is ready,
we'll begin the checkup.
Thank you, Herr Kessler. There's
no need for further examination.
Your nephew is of sound health.
Standard fee, please.
Humility, Kessler.
Never forget humility.
Close it!
There's nothing to see!
- Good evening, Herr Kessler.
- Evening, Fraulein Schulze.
- Tonight you'll be on train 317.
- Frankfurt -- Berlin.
- Tomorrow, train 212.
- Berlin -- Munich.
Then on train 522.
Timetable, list of sales, receipts,
electrical chart, green checkbook,
book of tickets, account book
and the green journal.
Thank you, Fraulein Schulze.
The inspector wants you
to go to turntable three.
Really?
I've promised not to say any more,
but I think he has
a surprise for you.
Wait.
I see the young Herr Kessler
has not yet paid his guarantee.
I thought I 'd tell you right away.
Car 2306 is back in working order.
- Is it, lnspector?
It is indeed, Kessler.
Your nephew is off to a great start.
You may turn the handle, please.
Yes, lnspector.
Track 8, Kessler.
You will have the honor of serving
on the first first-class sleeper
to run under the revived
Zentropa company.
We have worked night and day to
get this train back on the track.
I understand you specifically wish to
become a sleeping-car conductor.
A fine choice.
But there was also
a symbolic element
in the management's decision
of giving the job to a foreigner.
We are dealing with the important
matter of human transportation,
which no borders should impede.
I also started out
as a sleeping-car conductor.
Those were my happiest days.
An engine driver's work is exciting.
The same goes for
the systematics in the tower.
But only the conductor comes into
direct contact with the passengers.
He can say "I can promise you
a most pleasant journey.
May you all enjoy a peaceful sleep."
Right, Kessler?
- Certainly, lnspector.
I call this a mythological task.
You will accompany your uncle
while you are training.
After your exam in three months' time,
you can move on.
But you can read all about that
in the service rule book.
Here it comes.
First-class tickets only!
First-class tickets!
Money... please...
Give us some money.
It's the rule!
You can make the bed.
Please forgive me. It's my first trip.
Herr Kessler, you are a true idealist.
Let me tell you,
it is most frightening.
Young Kessler, you're a blockhead!
Wake up! Leo, you have to hurry.
My nephew, Leopold Kessler,
has been invited to dine at 7 :00.
He is entirely to blame
for any delay.
I leave him in your hands.
I will wait for him in the kitchen.
They've already sat down to eat.
"... at the right hour you feed them.
You open your hand and bless
all who dwell there. Amen."
Our guest has arrived.
So sorry I'm late.
Never excuse yourself, young man.
Life is too short.
Kat tells me you have recently
joined our company.
I'm very pleased.
Father is pleased you're American.
He'd like Zentropa
to be international.
Germans are ill-regarded right now.
Rubbish, Larry. Let's eat.
My sister's got her eye on you.
Calm down, both of you.
It's very brave of you to come
to Germany at such a time.
A great tragedy has befallen
this part of the world.
What kind of question is that
to ask our guest?
I'm afraid I'm not very religious.
Herr Kessler is a sensible man.
He realizes that if the scars
of this war are to heal,
then we must turn to one another.
My sister says you're a deserter.
In my father's opinion, so am l.
That's enough, Larry.
My son was too ill to join up.
Ill! The illness my father
has never understood.
He thinks it stems from my mother
spoiling me till the day she died.
Excuse me.
I apologize for my son's behavior.
- I thought you didn't like excuses.
- Damn it!
Excuse me, Father.
In war, life is so simple.
It's only afterwards
that complications arise.
Don't you agree, Father?
- Certainly.
Religion is important in wartime,
but even more so when the silence
of arms toys with our peace of mind.
When we pray to God
in time of war,
we can only rely on his support
if we have faith in our cause.
Excuse me, Father,
but what about the other side?
Why, of course, Herr Kessler.
God is on everyone's side.
But when you fight for a cause
with all your heart,
then God finds it easier to forgive
if, in doing so,
you disobey his commands.
Who does God not forgive?
Those who do not believe.
Those who remain lukewarm,
who don't take sides.
They are condemned
to eternal wandering.
He shows them no mercy,
Herr Kessler.
"So, because thou art lukewarm,
and neither cold nor hot,
I will spew thee out of my mouth."
They're about to blast them.
The Allies are blowing up cranes in
Westhafen. They're dismantling.
Dismantling?
To prevent another German
military power from rising up.
They're destroying everything
that could be used for military ends.
I fail to see how the few cranes
we have left might pose a threat.
The food supply situation
will become even worse.
You're so naive, Kat. The cranes
are loading coal for lG Farben.
The Americans are clever.
They get hold of the chemical patents
and then they destroy the plants
to prevent production.
All in the name of demilitarization.
So that's that.
You can serve the coffee now.
You must understand, Leopold,
our family has always treasured
international contacts.
Pay us a visit from time to time.
How about dinner on Friday?
I'm sure you'll like Alex.
We studied together in Berlin
and now he's back in Germany.
Colonel Harris.
Thank you for a pleasant evening.
I must go and check on the church
before curfew.
I'm afraid we won't have time for
chess tonight, Colonel Harris.
Come and sit down.
Your uncle wants to leave now.
He's waiting in the hall.
Good-bye, Fraulein Hartmann.
Herr Kessler.
I'm a friend of the Hartmann family.
They said I could ask a small favor.
My nephews are going to Cologne.
Would you please look after them?
They'll be picked up at the station.
The tickets and papers are in order.
You can stay in here.
Sekt for Ravenstein.
The Allied command in Frankfurt
has appointed my husband mayor.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Excuse me.
Are you the engine driver?
- I'm the sleeping-car conductor.
I don't wish to impose,
but my family and myself lived
in London during the war
and now we're returning
to Wollstadt.
But my wife is suddenly refusing
to get off the train.
She's very upset about the state
Germany is in right now.
Would you be so kind as to
help me set her mind at rest?
If you could perhaps reassure her
that Wollstadt has been
spared the havoc of war.
We live at 43 Sachsenstrasse.
I don't know Wollstadt, but what
I've seen from the train looks bad.
But you must help me.
I'll never get her off the train.
Wollstadt is our home.
We can get a taxi from the station.
My dear, I have encouraging news.
Please repeat what you told me.
I don't really know Wollstadt.
But you did tell me Wollstadt
had been spared.
I only know what I saw
from the train.
Did you hear?
Next station is Wollstadt.
You'd better get ready.
Palestine!
She wants us to live in the desert.
We are Jewish, but we are German,
but we are Jewish.
Savages!
It's outrageous!
We have problems with the heating,
but we can offer you blankets.
Give the children some chocolate.
- We'd like another bottle of Sekt.
- Of course, right away.
Go on, have another piece.
Chocolate?
Papers, please.
I insist on a return game today,
Colonel Harris.
I've never understood how anyone
could be proud to be German.
If I had my way, I'd be on a plane
bound for America today.
You find that hard to understand.
I think the war was a waste of time.
It's how you would feel if you were
to attend the good Father's Mass.
The ceremony might be colorful,
even entertaining,
but to a disbeliever it's simply
a sophisticated waste of time.
Shoddy too, when the sacrament
is nothing but a dry cracker.
She's flirting with you.
A bit scheming, don't you think?
Why not dance with her?
Not today. I'm a little tired.
It's time, Max. The Jew is here.
Marie.
Bring me those silly papers.
They're the rules.
I must ask, do you know this man?
Max Hartmann is my friend.
He gave me food and hid me in his cellar.
No more!
I won't do it again.
Do what you like!
Is it my move?
What am I doing? No.
I think I'll retire now.
No need to disturb
the Father and Alex.
Good night to you both.
Good night, Father.
Your uncle has always
been a good man.
Don't forget that
whatever happens,
you must always do
what you think is right.
Never let anyone tell you otherwise.
Katharina.
Put the lamp out.
The lamp.
I am a werewolf.
Yes, I'm afraid I have to admit
you have won.
It's just a game.
It's time to go home, Colonel.
Do you have a moment?
We need your help.
I beg you, Herr Leopold,
come with me.
Be careful.
Welcome, Herr Kessler.
I can understand that this setup
might puzzle you somewhat.
But this sector is in
a state of emergency
and the authorities won't allow us
to give Max a proper burial.
Gatherings are forbidden,
Herr Kessler.
Therefore we must resort to this...
most unworthy arrangement.
We will proceed
with our ceremony in secret,
Iike the Christians
in the catacombs.
Everyone is gathering at the old
marshaling yard at Darmstadt.
Your job is to stop the train there
so that we can get the coffin
off the train.
You've pulled the emergency brake!
Herr Leopold!
Over here.
Kat is a lovely girl.
I just wanted to thank you.
My nephews' journey
went splendidly.
What would they have done
without you?
Our superiors appreciate your help
in the Ravenstein assassination.
We have a new job in mind for you.
There's your girlfriend.
Listen, Leo.
I'm not asking you to
decide right now.
We will offer Herr Kessler
a ride back to Frankfurt.
Then we must fix the back door.
It sticks.
You have a visitor.
- I hope I'm not intruding.
- Not at all.
Have you been promoted yet?
My exam is in a few weeks.
What are you doing in Munich?
I'm at St. Christopher's Church.
I've come --
I've come to ask you not to
judge Kat too harshly.
I know that she told you
about her mistake.
Kat is confused, as so many
others are these days.
But she is not a werewolf.
She repents her sins and is trying
very hard to make amends.
She had to flee from those people
in Frankfurt. They stop at nothing.
Max Hartmann received
threatening letters.
His collaboration with the
Americans was no secret.
And after he died, the authorities
confiscated his entire estate.
Do you have any contact with Kat?
I really must go now.
We will meet again.
Herr Kessler, if I were you,
I'd attend the midnight mass
at St. Christopher's tonight.
With this ring I thee wed.
In the name of the Holy Trinity.
I'm afraid the young Herr Hartmann
wasn 't as cooperative as yourself.
But then, what's one faggot less?
We've taken her to
a temporary hiding place.
We thought you'd be more
cooperative if she was with us.
I'm so glad you came, Leopold.
We can discuss your next job.
We would like the Bremen line
to be shut down, tonight.
You're a capable man.
We're sure you can handle
a big job like this.
All you have to do is place some
explosives underneath your sleeper.
The bomb will be detonated
on the Neuwied Bridge.
You'll have ample time to get out.
I'm sorry to press you like this,
because I do like you.
Remember, tonight you're
going on the Bremen Express.
Allow me to present the examinee:
Leopold Kessler, my nephew.
Herr Seifert and lnspector Steleman
are in charge of the examination.
There is a practical
and a theoretical part.
First, we'll ask some questions.
Then we will accompany you
to see how you manage with both
the passengers and the equipment.
The conductor must be both
polite and firm at all times.
Accompany us to compartment nine
and we can begin.
Has this exam taken you by surprise?
No, it's just that I was attending to
one of the passengers.
If you don't mind, I'll just finish what
I was doing and be back at once.
They want you to place a bomb.
Listen to me!
Tell him your life is at stake.
I can't say any more.
They're watching you, remember.
Checkpoint Urmitz!
The assessor
is getting a little impatient.
I think we had better proceed
with the examination.
So, we would like to know
what you would do
if the cleaner handed you
a green card
filled in like this.
Have you gone completely mad?
Get out of here this instant!
My nephew's behavior
cannot be excused.
My first thought was to advise you
to cancel the exam at once.
- Do you wish to proceed?
- That is up to the examiner.
I shall repeat my question.
What would you do if the cleaner
handed you a green card
filled in like this?
Can't you see
it's filled in incorrectly?
Completely incorrect.
Would you like to tell the examinee
the correct answer to the question?
It's a trick question.
The answer is:
Report the cleaner immediately!
The green card should never be
in the cleaner's possession.
The cleaner never keeps
any papers for the conductor.
On the contrary, the conductor
must give him a receipt
as soon as he takes over.
And which form is used for this?
Yes, B, that is correct.
And now a question after
Herr Seifert's own heart.
What is stated in paragraph four,
section 62 of the rule book?
I must inform you that an open collar
is against the regulations.
Your uncle kindly got a card for you.
We now want you to make bed 42.
I have put the correct number
of bedding covers out for you.
You may begin when I say so.
We want you to make the bed twice.
Then we will examine the bed.
Are you ready with the clock?
You may now begin.
The clock is ticking.
The clock is ticking!
No time for that.
The clock is ticking.
Hurry, Herr Kessler,
the clock is ticking.
The clock is ticking!
Thank you.
Herr Kessler.
Would you please come to
compartment nine for a moment?
I was told I might find
the conductor here.
I have a problem. Is it too much
to ask for a bit of service?
We must be quiet.
The assessor needs to rest
before we proceed with the exam.
Let me give you a piece of advice.
In my opinion,
you have only one chance.
When Herr Seifert wakes up, ask him
to follow you through the train
as you give each of the passengers
an unconditional apology.
Conductor!
These shoes need polishing.
I wanted them polished.
I am sure the shoes
have been polished.
I don't think so.
There's no chalk mark.
You'd better watch your step!
You pulled the emergency brake!
Refreshments?
Bed-making?
Shoeshine?