(Disher)
Out of the way!
This is Disher.
We're in pursuit on foot.
West on Jackson!
Suspect is armed
and dangerous.
Out of the way!
He's wearing a beige suit
and a purple shirt.
I think it's purplish.
It might be lavender
or mauve,
I'm not sure!
Randy, nobody cares!
Request backup!
Repeat, backup!
[sirens]
Freeze!
Let the girl go!
Drop the gun, Escobar!
Put the gun down!
Let the girl go, Escobar!
I swear to God,
I'll kill her!
Let the girl go.
You put the gun down now!
Okay.
Put it down.
Ugh!
That's him.
That's Miguel Escobar.
We just saw him on the news.
He's the number one
most wanted man.
Yeah, not any more.
Can you do me a favor,
Captain?
Shut up.
Call my fiancee.
And tell her that
the wedding's still on.
And don't cancel anything.
Tell her I'll be back home
in Bogota, Colombia
real soon.
[Randy Newman ragtime theme]
* It's a jungle out there
* Disorder and confusion
everywhere *
* No one seems to care
* Well, I do
* Hey, who's in charge here?
* It's a jungle out there
* Poison in the very air
we breathe *
* You know what's in
the water that you drink? *
* Well, I do,
and it's a-ma-zing *
* People think I'm crazy
'cause I worry all the time *
* If you paid attention,
you'd be worried too *
* You'd better pay attention
or this world we love so much *
* Might just kill you
* I could be wrong now
* But I don't think so
* 'Cause it's
a jungle out there *
* It's a jungle
out there *
Good morning.
Picked up your mail.
What is going on?
Oh, I'm having fun.
I love this stuff.
Yeah, so I see.
You know, I usually
don't like shaking hands,
but I ever met the man
who invented Tupperware,
I would shake his hand.
I think he might be dead.
Well, I would
still shake his hand,
because he's probably
perfectly preserved.
Look, it's virtually
airtight.
Look at this.
Uh-oh.
Uh-oh what?
Uh-on nothing.
I'll show you later.
What?
What...what is that?
Don't worry, you don't have to
report for weeks.
Report for what?
I've been drafted?
They've reinstated
the draft.
Ah, I'm gonna have to shower
with...naked people.
Naked.
Naked naked...men with...
Okay, Mr. Monk,
you're not being drafted.
You have jury duty!
Oh, my God.
I'm gonna get picked.
Mr. Monk, you're not
gonna get picked.
You're
an ex-police officer.
You have tons of friends
on the force.
I've been to plenty
of trials.
Ex-cops get picked
all the time.
I can't believe they're still
renovating this place.
They should put up a sign,
"Your tax dollars
not at work."
Mr. Monk,
you're not moving.
I'm not?
No, you're not.
Here we go.
Go on.
There you go.
You're walking.
Look at you.
I'm so proud of you.
I'm gonna get picked.
Mr. Monk, you're gonna have
to take off your belt.
Ah, I was going to anyway.
To hang myself.
Don't get me wrong,
it's a great system.
It really is the best
justice system in the world.
I agree.
I just don't wanna
be a part of it.
Mr. Monk, what if everybody
felt that way?
Everybody does.
Mr. Monk, I don't understand.
You dedicated your life
to fighting crimes, right?
Solving mysteries.
Sending guilty people
to jail?
Well, you can do that here.
That's what juries do.
It's the same thing.
But I work alone.
I'm a lone wolf.
You're a lone wolf?
Even when I was
on the force,
I didn't really like
having a partner.
I can't work with
other people.
Okay, well, I think
that's kind of sad.
I agree.
It's very sad.
You know, I hope you do
get picked.
I think it'd be
good for you.
Don't say that.
You know, you work with
different kinds of people.
You know, you listen
to their opinions.
Argue, compromise.
Thank you, Natalie.
I know you mean well.
I'd rather be sucked out
of an airplane window.
(female reporter)
Good afternoon, I am live
from in front of...
Look, it's the Captain.
...where Miguel Escobar
is scheduled to arrive
any moment--here he is!
Sergeant!
Sergeant, excuse me.
Can we get a word, please?
Sergeant!
Sergeant Stottlemeyer!
Actually, it's Captain.
Captain Leland Stottlemeyer,
with three Ts.
Four, if you count
the one in "Captain."
(reporter)
Escobar has already
escaped twice.
Do you think
he'll try again?
We're taking every precaution
to avoid that.
Isn't that what they said
last time?
I wasn't in charge
last time.
Well, what are you doing
to ensure--
(jury clerk)
Hello!
Did everybody sign in?
If I call your name,
you are required to come back
tomorrow morning at 9:00 a.m.
and report to room 302.
If you do not hear
your name...
you are excused.
Here it comes.
Adrian Monk!
There it is.
Yes!
Is this a bad time?
Yeah, it is now.
Randy, you remember
Special Agent Lapides.
Actually, I'm not alone.
I'm here with
the Attorney General.
The Attorney General
of the United States?
He's in here.
You wanna read it?
I don't need
to read it.
I'm not giving you Escobar.
No way.
No how.
Leland, this case is bigger
than San Francisco.
Escobar was supplying drugs
to seven states.
Yeah, but we caught him here.
You're damn right we did,
and we got him
on homicide.
Right here in the
city of San Francisco.
This case represents
three years of my life.
Well, you have the thanks
of a grateful nation.
But it's a done deal.
A Federal indictment's
already been filed.
We're gonna try him first.
Sons of bitches.
There's an extradition hearing
on Thursday.
Here's how
it's gonna work.
You baby-sit Escobar
until then.
You bring him
to the courthouse.
We meet you in the lobby.
You drop him off.
You go home.
What's that, sir?
Yeah.
I'll tell him.
The Attorney General says,
"Don't screw it up."
Mr. Daughtry,
it says here
that you've been excused
from jury duty
three times before?
I got a business to run.
Well, you're gonna have to
find someone else
to run it.
The defense accepts you,
so does the prosecution.
So do I.
Have a seat,
you're juror number 10.
Okay, next.
Stand up.
(court clerk)
State your name.
Uh, Natalie Teeger.
Spell it.
Oh, no, I wasn't called.
She's my assistant,
Your Honor.
And you are...
Adrian Monk.
Capital A.
Small D, small R.
Small I, small A,
small N. Space.
Thank you, Mr. Monk.
I think we have it.
Your Honor...
I will not be able
to serve today.
Unfortunately.
For a number of reasons.
First off...
[blows nose]
There's the
bathroom situation.
I can't share
a bathroom.
I just can't.
You can ask Natalie.
Natalie?
Yeah, he's persnickety.
He's very persnickety.
He's persnickety squared.
And I have special
dietary needs, Your Honor.
I can't eat food
unless I actually see it
being prepared.
That's true, Your Honor.
Anything else?
Yes, sir.
I have two plants at home
that are completely
dependent on me, Your Honor.
Plants.
I have a fern.
And a small azalea bush.
And you have an assistant.
Can't she water
the plants?
Good question,
here's the thing.
She has a tendency
to overwater.
Okay, that is not true.
That happened once.
It was two ounces.
Two ounces to
an azalea bush is like
a swimming pool,
Your Honor.
Mr. Monk, I have seen
hundreds of people
pretend to be disturbed
to avoid jury duty,
but you, sir, are in a class
by yourself.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Well, it's not
gonna work, sir.
You have a seat, Mr. Monk.
Objection.
You are juror number 11.
It's okay, Mr. Palmer.
Take your time.
Could you show us exactly
where you were stabbed?
Right here.
In the thigh.
Mr. Monk...
you have to look!
(Judge Rienzo)
Number 11.
Evidence is presented, sir,
for you.
(prosecutor Fox)
What did you do then?
I was bleeding pretty bad.
So I grabbed an old towel
out of my car.
There was one
on the floor.
And I pressed it
against the wound.
[cell phone ringing]
Whose phone was that?
It's hers, Your Honor.
Number 3.
And she fell asleep.
The old number 8.
Nobody likes a tattletale,
Mr. Monk.
I think number 9
is a tattletale.
That'll do, Mr. Monk.
Proceed...
Mr. Fox.
What happened
after you were stabbed?
He grabbed my deposit envelope
and took off.
Carl, is the person
that stabbed you
at that rest stop,
took your money
and ran away,
in this courtroom today?
Yes, sir.
He's right there.
[sneezes violently]
[sneezes]
What are you doing?
He needs a wipe,
Your Honor.
Sit down, Miss Teeger.
Sit down!
If you interfere
with the jury again,
I will have you arrested
for tampering
and contempt.
Understand?
Yes, Sir. Sorry.
[clears throat]
Let the record show
that the witness
has identified
the defendant
Robert Perry.
Oh, my God.
No cell phones
are allowed.
You'll get 'em back
when you're done.
I'll be down the hallway
if you need me.
Just ring the buzzer.
Thank you.
Okay.
What did you think?
I thought it was
pretty interesting.
Very interesting.
I filled up
three notebooks.
What are you doing?
I'm just
making them even.
So we can all concentrate.
And not be distracted.
By uneven Venetian blinds.
Okay, everyone,
let's get started.
I've done this before,
so, uh, I would be glad
to be our foreman
if there are no objections.
No.
All right, great, well,
let's all have a seat.
Actually, it'd be best
if we all sat in order.
If you don't mind,
I'm juror number 7
and...we'll go this way.
Number 8...
And so forth.
Okay, great.
You look happy.
This is very exciting
for me.
I feel like
a real American.
Excuse me?
Yeah?
Do you mind if we
traded seats?
Why?
I'd rather be number 10.
My favorite number.
It's kind of important.
Look, the guy is trying
to change seats.
You know what, pal?
Nobody's trading anything
with you.
Now sit down, okay?
I mean it.
Sit, okay?
So I've been on
a few juries.
And it's customary
to start off
with a preliminary vote
by secret ballot.
Just to see
where we all are.
Any objections?
None.
Great.
Anybody mind if I, uh, smoke?
[all minding]
All right, all right,
all right.
I'm not the one on trial.
Okay, folks, huh?
Just pass 'em down, please.
All right, well,
let's do this.
Guilty.
Wow, that was easy.
Guess I'll be home
for dinner.
Wait a minute,
that was only 11.
Who didn't vote?
Smudge.
You gotta be kidding.
Thank you.
It's no problem.
Not guilty.
[all griping and groaning]
That makes it 11 to 1.
You know, there's always one,
isn't there?
There's always one.
Do you really think
he's not guilty?
I don't know.
Of course he's guilty.
Look at the evidence.
They found the knife.
The knife he used.
In his knapsack.
Plus, the victim
identified him.
I mean, what more
do you want?
I don't know,
I have a feeling
there's more to it.
It's a feeling.
I would just like to
think about it for a while.
[all grumbling and arguing]
I'm gonna need you all
to be quiet.
[all grumbling]
To concentrate.
Shhh.
I'm gonna
walk around now.
And pace back and forth.
Then, when I'm ready,
I'll tell you the solution.
That's how it works.
No.
No way.
You're not alone here.
You have to
talk to us.
Tell us what
you're thinking.
That's not how I do it.
I have a system.
It's a gift and a curse.
Here's the thing,
I don't like working
with partners.
Well, like it or not,
you've got 11 partners now.
Pay attention, I'm only
gonna say this once.
Escobar's hearing
is tomorrow at 12:00 noon.
We lock this joint down
tonight at midnight.
Every exit,
every window.
1:00 a.m.,
we sweep for bombs.
Head to toe.
6:00 AM, I want snipers
on this roof
and on the roof next door.
We arrive at 11:30.
11:40, we meet Lapides
at the elevator
and hand him off.
After that,
he's the Bureau's headache.
Sir, could you
repeat that, please?
Yeah, what part?
Uh, everything after
"Pay attention,
I'm only gonna
say this once."
[knocking on door]
Exhibit 15B.
Thank you.
What's he doing now?
We're not sure.
Did you talk
to the judge?
(Bailiff)
He says it's too late.
He's already sent
the alternates home.
You're stuck with him.
[chuckles]
[sneezes]
Bless you.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Would you mind
trying these on?
What for?
You're about the same height
as the victim,
and I just wanna
try something.
It'll just
take a minute.
What do we got,
a fashion show?
You believe this guy?
We know that these
are the pants...
that the victim was wearing
when he was attacked.
Could you step up,
please?
Of course, you can see
where the knife
went through the fabric.
Well, something
doesn't add up.
I noticed Mr. Palmer likes
to wear his pants low.
In the courtroom, we could
almost see his...
bottom part.
Rear posterior.
Side...
His butt?
Thank you.
Look at the wound.
He was actually stabbed
in the upper thigh.
It doesn't match up.
He's right,
look at that.
At least,
not when he's standing.
Could you
have a seat, please?
Son of a bitch.
He was sitting down.
What does that prove?
Mr. Palmer said he was
standing up
when he was stabbed.
He was lying.
I think he pulled
into that rest stop,
saw Robert Perry,
who was sleeping.
Stabbed himself,
pocketed the money,
and then blamed everything
on Perry.
I'm switching my vote...
to Not Guilty.
[all expressing disbelief]
(Patel)
We should listen
to this man.
He was a very brave man
to stand up
against us all.
[dog barking]
(postal worker)
What about
the DNA evidence?
You can't just
ignore that.
They found the victim's blood
on Perry's knife.
How do we know it was
Robert Perry's knife?
He denied ever seeing it.
Of course he denied it.
What the hell
do you expect?
Well, his prints
weren't on it.
Well, then,
he wiped them off, huh?
Look, it was
in his knapsack!
What the hell kind
of a detective are you?
I'm the kind of detective
who wonders
why someone would
take the time
to wipe down the handle,
but not the blade.
[groans]
Also, the timeline
is all wrong.
Robert Perry was picked up
an hour after the assault.
Less than two miles
from there.
So what?
He wasn't running away.
If I had
just stabbed somebody--
Somebody moved that tarp.
Excuse me?
There's a dumpster down there
with a tarp in it.
Yesterday the tarp
was rolled up
and draped over the side.
What does this
have to do with us?
Or this case?
Or anything?
I'm sorry,
you're right.
You're right.
Okay, what's next?
The money.
Okay, the money.
What happened
to the money?
Maybe he buried it.
Lime.
Somebody poured lime
all over that tarp.
I think there's
a body down there.
Oh, we're never
getting out of here.
[buzzer]
Hello, I'm number 11.
Yeah, I remember.
I know
this sounds crazy,
but there's
a dumpster downstairs.
I saw a police dog
sniffing around.
I think there's a body
under that blue tarp.
(bailiff)
Judge Rienzo said
I should keep an eye on you.
He said to report you
if you cause any delay
or disruption.
Is that what
you're doing?
No.
No, no.
Natalie!
Mr. Monk,
I brought your dinner!
I'm gonna leave it
downstairs!
The dumpster!
What?
It's Natalie.
There's a body
in the dumpster!
You want a hot toddy
and Munster?
I brought a Cobb salad!
There's a body
in the dumpster!
I just got
the Cobb salad!
What are you
talking about?
There is a...
dead....
body in the dumpster.
Call Captain Stottlemeyer!
Okay, wait, a body?
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
We should not
listen to this man.
He is ruining America
for everybody.
Tell me again.
I've been called away
from the most important case
of my career because...
Because Mr. Monk
said he saw a body.
From up there.
From the third floor.
While he was deliberating
on another case.
(Disher)
Captain!
We got a body.
Rope everything off.
That side too.
Natalie,
don't touch anything.
Well, he was right
about the body.
People, whatever happened
down there
has nothing to do
with us.
We still have
a job to do.
Maybe we should
take another vote.
Good idea.
Let's just see
who stands where, all right?
Everybody back.
Now, just by
a show of hands,
who's still voting guilty?
Guilty.
Not guilty.
Six to six.
And we go into
extra innings.
(Natalie)
Mr. Monk,
it's a woman!
She's about
60 years old!
Who is she?
No ID.
No ID!
No idea?
NO ID!
No...I...
D!
No idea?
No...
Here here here.
I...
D!
No idea?
No ID!
Check her identification!
Are those
orthopedic shoes?
What?
Those shoes,
orthopedic shoes.
Yeah, I think so!
I remember I saw her
in the waiting room!
I think she's a juror!
What?
A juror!
What the hell is that?
Looks like of your jurors
leaning out of a window
talking to
a police officer.
I want that jury sequestered
as of now.
[breathing deeply]
What are youse doing?
You were smoking.
I'm allowed to smoke.
Read the sign.
It's keeping me awake.
You're gonna
start a fire.
So there's no problem.
You're awake, right?
[coughing]
If there's a fire,
you'll see it.
And you put it out, right?
Hey, right?
Right.
Don't be such an ass
in the jury room.
[breathing deeply]
Good night.
I'd like to confirm
a reservation
for tomorrow afternoon.
My reservation number
is X73294.
Yes, flight 32
to Buenos Aires.
The two of us,
me and my husband.
4:30.
Don't worry,
we won't be late.
Lieutenant,
my nose itches.
Forget it.
Ah, it doesn't matter.
I'll scratch it myself
soon enough.
Captain, he just said
he was gonna scratch his nose.
Okay.
The way he said it,
it was like a threat.
He threatened
to scratch his nose?
Lieutenant,
bring the van around.
Let's get this over with.
Not guilty?
It's still 8 to 4.
Is that clock right?
(Teacher Juror)
Number 11.
You've made some
really good points.
I admit that.
But everything you said
about the timeline,
the location of the wound,
is all circumstantial.
Exactly, what he's doing is
he's taking the facts
and he's twisting them around
like a pretzel.
Now, where's the proof, man?
(Patel)
We don't need any proof.
All we need is
a reasonable doubt.
You know what I say?
I say we're at
a deadlock.
And I say we go back
in there right now
and tell 'em
we got a hung jury.
What is he doing?
I'm afraid to ask.
Excuse me.
Carl Palmer testified
that after he was stabbed,
he grabbed this towel
off the floor
of his car.
And he pressed it
against his leg.
So?
Well, look at the stains.
They're symmetrical.
I don't think
he just grabbed the towel.
I think he folded it...
very carefully.
Before he used it.
[murmurs of recognition]
You know, so what?
The guy was a neatnik.
He was in pain.
He'd just been stabbed.
Nobody would stop
and fold a towel.
That's right.
He folded the towel
before he stabbed himself.
It was definitely
self-inflicted.
I'm convinced.
Me too.
Not guilty.
Thank you.
What about you?
Not guilty.
I'd like another vote.
Absolutely.
All of those
voting Not Guilty.
I'm switching my vote...
to guilty.
[all expressing disbelief]
What about the towel?
It means nothing to me.
The vote's 11 to 1.
Where are you going?
To the bathroom.
You got a problem
with that?
Can you believe that?
No.
I can't.
You're a science teacher,
right?
Mm-hmm.
Is this what I think it is?
It's lime.
That's what I thought.
I think number 12 murdered
that woman in the dumpster.
Why?
She needed to get
on a jury.
I remember her talking
to a woman
in the assembly room.
I think she was
looking for someone
who lived alone
with no family
who wouldn't be missed.
Killing somebody
to get on a jury?
That's a first.
She's been looking
at that clock all day.
That's right.
She's waiting for something.
She's stalling us.
She doesn't care
what the verdict is.
Look, whatever way we vote...
she will vote the opposite.
But in the first ballot,
she voted with us.
That's right.
(Monk)
But she was sitting
next to me.
She must have seen
how I was voting
and went the other way.
I don't believe it.
I can prove it,
I think.
But I'm gonna
need your help.
Wait a minute,
we can't just--
Yesterday, you said
we were partners.
I can't do this alone.
What'd I miss?
(Monk)
Well, we were
just talking and...
Well, we thought about it,
and we've decided
that you were right.
He's guilty.
Really?
Yeah, we're all
changing our vote.
In fact,
let's make it official.
Who's voting guilty?
I'm undecided.
Just give me
a few minutes.
What are you up to?
I have every right
to change my mind.
I think it's time
to call the bailiff.
Have a seat, number 11.
We're still deliberating.
Number 11,
I have to thank you.
I had to keep everybody
here in this room busy
arguing for
a day and a half.
I wasn't sure
how I was gonna do it,
but you made it easy.
(Monk)
Don't mention it.
Why are you doing this?
She's helping her boyfriend
escape.
She had to have a way
to get into this building.
How about
a little privacy, huh?
It's not even.
It's not even--
Shut up!
It's not even.
I've been waiting a long time
to do this.
This is not...
[grunting]
[bell rings]
Listen, did you
check upstairs?
There's a dropped ceiling--
Whatever it is, Captain,
we got it covered.
Right.
Okay.
What's that?
It's your receipt.
Why don't you keep it...
as a souvenir?
[muffled screams]
[knocking on door]
(Natalie)
Mr. Monk, is everything okay?
[muffled screaming]
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
Mr. Monk, what happened?
[trying to talk]
What?
Hold on.
Ah!
What?
I was saying
for the love of God,
please don't rip off
the tape!
Are you guys okay?
Is everyone all right?
[gunshots]
You did it,
Preciosa.
[exhales]
[cell phone ringing]
Disher.
Shots fired, third floor.
Oh, God!
Give me paramedics on three.
We're in the North Wing.
We have two agents down.
They're gonna be okay.
They were both
wearing vests.
They went up.
Why would they go upstairs?
Can I borrow that?
Well, he didn't
come through here.
Get somebody
in the basement.
Lock down
the parking garage.
Disher.
Captain!
It's Monk.
Monk?
Right here, this way.
Slowly.
Calm.
Outside.
Look out!
Hello, Miguel!
And you must be
the fiancee.
Aren't you supposed to be
upstairs?
Some people will do anything
to get out of jury duty.
Step down, please.
And this is number 6.
She didn't say much,
but she was
a very important
part of the team.
Stay cool.
I will.
I'll stay cool.
Yeah.
Part of the team, huh?
Good for you.
Yeah.
And this is number 2.
Natalie.
Hello.
You should listen
to this man.
He is good for America.
And this is number 7.
We were kinda co-captains,
really.
I mean, sort of.
And that's number 4.
He sorta hated my guts
in the beginning.
You can admit it now.
I'll see you
at the reunion, okay?
One year from today.
Benihana's.
You know,
that's not gonna happen.
I think I'll stay
and straighten up.
No.
Going.
Captioning by CaptionMax
www.captionmax.com