Let me go!
Edward!
Lord!
RECTANGULAR ark
Edgar Allan Poe
Edward!
Edward, come back!
Edward! No!
You did not leave a choice.
Radok!
Edward!
- Do not do that!
Control yourself!
xxx
Catch him!
Good evening, gentlemen.
- Good evening.
xxx
I do not know what you two are going
but you have to take it from here!
- You're being paid.
- And did it well.
Insufficient.
If the police Dane, what to say? Em?
You do not have nothing to be afraid.
You're the only owner of the accommodation
for drunken thieves and whores.
The disgusting smell! What's he there for?
? I would like to know that.
Enough!
None of your business and.
After all, soon eotii.
The sooner the better,
If you ask me.
- It is still not ready..
- But, it's gonna tonight?
Yes. Have you made money?
- Gold?
- Guinea.
You will not get
money until they complete the work.
When done, can? Participation this
bring to Africa with you,
the same ship which
You came here.
You'll be rich, N'Galo.
This is what? Ellis.
Do you think they will succeed?
Zaspae when he took this,
and would appear to be dead.
Even,
and if you bring
Sir Edward here...,
May will he help him?
I saw what Vradim? Stage Donga had done
Trust me, Norton.
You saw what my powers
seemed, right?
Yes.
We know things
you know nothing.
I was thinking, D? Ulijan.
I want to veins at sea
the open boat.
Yes.
The wonderful skarletnoj dress that would entertain
sailors and shook my father.
- What? Sorry, Elizabeth,
I was away for miles.
I noticed.
Again in Africa?
Why do you think?
I think that is obvious.
Since you're back
are quite different and unlikely people.
- It's nonsense.
- No.
Look at you.
Permanent sanjaris,
're depressed.
Often forget that you're with me
and that'll be...
Elizabeth, dear,
I really get? ao.
What happened there?
What are you constantly thinking about?
Please tell me!
No.
Not worth your worry.
When we veneali,
? Want to share? Life.
Let us poeinjati with secrets.
Let's start immediately to share.
Mo? To think, about some things,
but that does not mean that I have not changed.
Crew Cab? In.
I never thought of that.
I thought...
? Want to see that
laugh as before.
So!
Your usual good
Report, Tren..
- A thorough and clear..
- I am very glad to be back.
- Africa is full of savages.
- Yes.
Thanks.
If you will be directed to
needs of your
planta? will in Africa
? Iveete well
You and your brother.
Can not? We forget
Sir Edward, is not it?
Sir Edward did not want to
dinner, sir.
Thanks, Radok.
Pokusau to convince him later.
As Sir Edward?
What were you expecting, that is better?
I was hoping that was normal.
normal.
It seemed that the more normal
While he did not remove the chains.
Madness came over him again,
so he tried to escape.
Since then he's getting worse.
Every man,
? Wants to be free.
How may will to be free,
when as it seems?
Do you understand that he is losing and reason?
Sometimes the disease
so hard hit
to become dangerous
as an insane beast.
And that puts it in an institution?
No.
No. About this we will not even think.
I could not stand
thought of my brother screaming in Bedlamu
together with those nesrenicima.
The operation is not an option?
You think they'd poor doctors
able to draw up his face?
You think that it touched,
not? elei to
experiment?
No.
I would like to see him.
I do not allow anyone,
to Vig..
- It's too dangerous..
- I'm not afraid.
Last time it looked like
that it is pleasing to see me..
Yes, he was better
some time..
Well, perhaps? Participation up.
But please do not allow
to see that you're shocked
how his condition deteriorated.
I nepribli? Alas too..
If it comes upon madness,
your only protection of the chains
which is attached..
- Thanks. Zapamtiu.
- Radok.
Take Mr. Trenea
to see Sir Edward..
- I'll be at a distance, sir.
- OK, Radok.
Sir Edward!
Sir Edward, I'm Moment
I do not have much time.
I want you to know that I
returned from Africa.
- Have you done what I tra? About?
- Yes.
When will it be?
He'll be ready for two days.
You'll be nagragen if you succeed.
I have to get out of here.
Account at you.
So I was afraid.
You upset him.
I am afraid that to anyone
We must not allow to see him.
Good night!
View.
What happened?
- Thieves corpses,
Mr. D? Ulijan.
They ran away.
Doctors are required
Warm guinea pigs.
You are not shocked?
Better to their barbaric methods
already? conceived of the dead than the way we live.
- I suppose | that you'll pay them dearly.
- Of course.
For some of our people,
that price is the difference BETWEEN
full and empty stomach.
- You're shocked?
I understand how important this is? No
poor souls.
That and a good rating in the sky.
Should not God willing
rating, | and not you.
It is? Honorary D? Ulijan!
A man is known
and worse things, Elizabeth.
I'll forget it all.
You must be thinking only about us.
- I hope we will soon veneati.
- As soon as possible.
Your father will power? To succeed me
odvuee in Italy. - What?
- I thought I had his blessing.
- It was before.
Before?
Before you come back
from the black continent.
Before you're fired
most of the servants.
Before you were in town
begun to circle? s story.
I'm talking about me?
A house?
Can not you see that you have become
hermit? Of course that story!
Crazy stories about demons and
ghosts rattling chains.
You do not believe in this nonsense?
What do you think?
- What do you think?
- I think they are all lunatics, fools.
Well.
To master.
From mistress Elizabeth.
- Thanks, Radok.
Did you took dinner
Sir Edward?
I did not.
Immediately I was taken.
Favourite? And D? Ulijan, can not
more reluctant to oeevoj? desired
to send me to Italy.
Disturbed by the thy
peculiar behavior
and? want to be sure
I will not do mistake.
I want you to know that is not my
? Wish to leave you,
But his will is stronger than mine.
Mr. D? Ulijan!
xxx
Sir Edward!
What's the matter, Radok?
Better to Doggett.
Edward, why
take you?
Will your soul
forgive my?
Radok.
Bring me Trenea.
No one else is allowed to know.
Yes, sir.
Moment has arrived.
- He died my brother Edward.
- ? I'm sorry to hear that.
There is no reason for? Unfortunately.
For him, death
oslobogenje.
- When you gonna be buried?
- When pronages other body.
I do not understand.
The family already long
there was no funeral Tren.
xxx
You forgot to Markham go to the grave
with the feeling of responsibility.
Villagers have to pay their respects.
but not? We want the world to see
how Edward looks.
? Elish another corpse
that villagers watched?
Yes.
Edward is already in the ark.
When the city is nagledao
this second corpse, pokopaemo true.
I do not want to be involved in it.
You are connected with the family
greater part of his? life Tren.
Do you know that the corpse krag
ka? explains hanging?
- As well as forgery.
- What?
I said counterfeiting.
These papers are managed,
get away thousands
Guinea from plantations? e.
I'm an attorney,
I'm not a businessman.
You're a counterfeiter
and proneveritelj,
and now you'll be
and a thief corpse.
Not by his will, D? Ulijan.
Ka? In it becomes easier
the deeper sink.
- How long do you know about this?
- I doubted for a while but now I know.
but now I know.
What are you gonna do?
I'll give you another 1,000 guineas,
or I'll give
authorities.
All right, sir D? Ulijan.
Your brother will have
dignified burial.
Give me time
to pronagem body
that would not be ashamed
for your noble lineage.
Will you with me to drink brandy?
Thanks.
Brought you the money?
- So?
- Called me.
- It Happened?
- Yes.
When we enter the house
to save succeeding Sir Edward?
Now we will not.
Why not?
My dear Mark,
Sir Edward was already in the ark.
What?
I locked the door behind
of which I have no key.
I do not understand.
However, there is a possibility
to earn.
How?
D? Ulijan not? Want people to see
that his brother looks like.
People? Want to show? E.
a second body.
This is madness!
Insanity or not, it'll do.
We shall give him another body.
You do not have anything to do.
At least I do not have to.
Lord, snap! Forget that
Edward? Alive in the ark!
Control yourself, Mark.
I already told you anything
can not? emo me to do.
Yes, but.. D? Ulijan offers
a thousand guineas for the corpse.
We shall give him one.
Where do we?
Answer me.
N'Galo, we may will help.
- You know what to do?
- Yes, Doctor.
They buried him we excavated it.
So quickly.
What about those who are
I promised?
We had some problems,
but do not worry
This will be warmer.
Dogoh to pay you.
Inside.
Evo. Hajde, work? And up.
You'll see that everything is there.
xxx
I came near Hackett
Mr. Hackett?
- Sr. Hackett.
- I'm afraid it's busy.
for me it's not busy
love.
- Good evening gospogo.
- Yes.
I am afraid that Mr.
Hackett was not good.
- Well, what happened this time?
- I am afraid that he drank some more wine.
I did not iznenagena.
I assure you
that will soon rise.
Radok tell your gospodaruda Samuel
Member? Want to be seen with him.
It is very important? No.
This is Mark Norton.
- I told you to do it alone.
- I could have.
It'll be better to enter
your valuables.
Yes. Radok!
As you know by how
We returned from Africa,
my brother? lived in solitude
and was,
? Victim of a tropical disease.
Yet he has not forgotten,
village of his youth.
Left great contributions
for the church,
and the poor.
xxx
- A thousand guineas for this.
- Bloody money.
Hardly.
The man was already dead.
- So what really happened in Africa?
- What do you mean?
- Nothing. Only the unusual.
- A what?
No one has heard is that takes you
Edward deserves? And
so u? asnu penalty.
Revenge?
I think it is
concerned.
- Revenge.
- Bo? I revenge.
Earlier that are not interested
The Christian myths.
Sin and Punishment.
And in Africa we were sinful.
Pljaekali have their
land still
robbery of their resources, but
They are too innocent to understand.
To Edward's fate may will
to be punishment, retribution.
xxx
Now I am even more curious.
Why did not you say?
I understand.
I could not be sure.
I did not know how to tell you to? Em.
And I sent the letter...
Lots of me? Ao.
You are my last chance
for a little peace and luck.
Will you stay?
Will you marry me?
Of course I want to dear.
xxx
- Sir Edward Markham.
- Again we'll open the house,
It'll be like it once was.
Pustiemo the sun shines
our new? life.
Baron EDWARD MARKHAM 1827
- 1865
Murder! Murder!
- Murder! Murder!
- Dr? Keep it.
Mieite up!
Come on.
xxx
Give it here. Come on.
I thought it will never arrive.
For this will require time and money
Doctor, I think you understand.
Yes.
- What this time you have for me?
- A man just buried.
His name and the place where the
Chilling is my thing. You know that.
Incidentally, I have something for you.
- What?
- Bring him up and put on the table.
I am afraid there is little
damaged.
We were not able to take a
without the other. Get it?
- You killed it
- Act as it's called.
We call this:
"Lucky okolnosu.
Now you have two pieces
for your needles and night? eve.
I and the guys are happy
the uobieajan way.
Of course, it's gonna best
that on this never
talking about.
Valero!
Remember that you are
involved in this as I am.
xxx
All for the sake of science
do not?
Why honeymoon
not spend in Africa?
No.
Is not the time, and at first I thought,
to love the land before.
No more, Elizabeth.
I do not want to be right back there again.
- Why?
- No sviga me too...
lo que Africa
puede significar,
y lo que hemos llegado
a significar para Africa.
De hecho, yo...
Yes?
I think for restoring
there too late.
What do you mean?
Bueno, que significaria seguiriamos
Sir Julian y siendo Lady Elizabeth,
pero no habria nada mas
acompanara que al titulo.
Ya veo.
Durante anos, esta familia
sólo ha sido una Fachada vacio.
- ¿Y aún piensas abandonar Africa?
- Mo? Never.
There they will find
part of their peace.
You're a good host
Doctor.
I feel like
at home.
- Thanks.
- I am grateful to you, doctor.
Especially as,
will you give me? iti refuge.
Why would you hide
in my house?
xxx
Your resurrectionist
last night became a murderer.
Would you like
someone learns about it?
He's already a penalty for pljaekanje
graves of the rope, right?
Were you happy or not, my body
is enough? ivo to talk about the story.
Who are you?
- Do not know whose graves were robbed?
- I do not know.
Empty tomb at the end
tell you a story her.
You are wrong. Looks
not open to anything.
Then only you know
I'm about? lived.
I could at? Elet better.
Now you'll take care of me.
Indeed.
How long?
As necessary.
xxx
Maintain? KEEP me
healthy,
until you make
some urgent debts.
Duk!
Where are you, Duk?
Here, Duk!
Servants are back.
Now that you have to provide generally for
that your body...
What to say? Em about you?
Excuse them...
Excuse them about rogaku
which was badly damaged by fire and abroad,
and who? want to scare people
with her about? iljcima.
I think it's smart.
- You are a very lucky man.
- Why?
I am an exceptional case, even
and the man of your experience.
Man omagijan
some dark sides,
narcotic.
My mind is poremeen,
My face is destroyed.
I killed and then miraculously I
reinstated in? life.
I
It'll be very, Doctor.
And you worry about
What will the servants think.
- I have to watch what I do.
- Finish it!
I Izaga out!
If you? You want, zakljueajte me here
and not worry for slaves.
Just wander around at night.
Poor thing.
I wonder who it is.
Will come to know.
Mr. D? Ulijan Kemp
found the body.
- In fact, my dog.
- You have stumbled on the mystery, Sr.. Kemp.
Yes.
- Whoever he is, not drowned.
It appears that he died
natural death,
so it is dropped or
pushed into the water.
Thanks.
Thanks, Sally.
Beautiful girl.
What's that supposed to mean?
Just a comment.
Would you tell me how
You'll still stay here?
I told you, doctor.
Until we go? Them.
I hope you
do not bother to work.
In fact I intend to
your financial help.
Certainly in? Awful when you
face so burned
that you must not allow it.
others see them.
- Just it to me? Ao, looks great
d? entlmen. Do not let it take you away.
- Gospogo Hopkins!
- Do you too "GGO-Hopkins!
I know what you are interested in
Gentlemen, Sally Baxter.
You people are not interested,
is not it?
Good Mark all sregeno
how are you prompted? well.
The U.S. bank notes of the
gold in the account.
You're not going to thank me?
Thank you, Trench, for empty
promises and the blood on my hands.
You took money
I helped him get to you.
You did not mention the need
to kill a man!
You really frightened,
is not it?
Yes.
My dear Mark, if Heketovo
body is pronageno,
not be able to identify him.
- A Sir Edward? Iv buried.
It was an accident.
I am all forgotten.
And you as soon forget the better.
Going from England.
I wish that you never
I have not seen, Trench.
And I hope that more
ll never see.
I think it's time
for tea, Graves?
For Dover.
Koeijasu!
You do not need no?.
No, if you tell me? Participation
where it is getting back.
- Sir Edward.
- Where is he?
- I do not know.
- It's too late by that? Participation.
- I swear I do not know.
- So, you're useless to me.
Good evening, gospogo.
xxx
- Sir Julian.
- I'm glad you came.
xxx
Baraona, I'm glad to see you.
Sir D? Ulijan, never looked better.
O? Enyl you.
Yes, agree? Em up.
- Kemp.
- Julian.
How nice that you came.
I'm glad to see you.
I'd like to one day
do Elizabeth's portrait.
It'll be my pleasure.
Tonight looks fabulous.
What is it?
A man with purple kapuljaeom!
It must be a highwayman.
- Radok!
- Sir?
Invite other servants.
Here is an intruder.
- Go into the garden and search? Men's.
- Good.
Please do not go!
Believe me you do not have
cause for concern.
xxx
Servants will take care of everything.
For my toast? Women
Lady Markham
before us the luck
and comfort.
It will be more than
enough for two people.
Let's dance!
To help the
experiments.
Good night, Doctor.
- Are not you afraid?
- Why should I be afraid?
I am a stranger who
hidden under kapuljaee.
xxx
Little bitch!
You were with him last night, right?
- So what if I was?
- That man is dangerous.
That man is in agony!
You are not? About crippled?
- Did you see his face?
- No.
Burned, right?
Why should I be afraid of? Scars,
when you constantly look at dead bodies?
All are most common? Them!
If it upsets you
you have no reason to worry.
You're fired.
Mo? Common to go home.
With their properties
I'm sure you'll find a good
accommodation and appropriate position? tea.
I'm gonna need some money, doctor.
You should pay me
because we leave this
a good position? tea.
Otherwise, the village will hear
for your surgical research? making.
OK.
Just do not get carried away
you'd be able to me ucenjujes
or you'd be able to
zucnes about it.
What if I do this?
Mo? That I one day
buy your nice body.
xxx
- Where's Sally?
- She's gone.
Where?
She went away.
Why?
I would not hurt.
May you that talking about what you want
it will not return.
I am you need.
Without my help,
I would not survive a minute!
I've read your recommendations, Sally.
Mo? Participation immediately poenes
work.
- Thanks gospogo.
- Sally...
Why you left
Al. Njuharta?
Rogak came to him, and more
there was no place for me.
If we are satisfied with your
work, here you'll be fine.
- Thanks gospogo.
- Perish with me, Sally.
Beautiful girl.
I want that for you all
be perfect, Elizabeth.
Being.
The house is wonderful, D? Ulian.
- Only one scares me.
- And, what is?
She rooms up.
- Diligence for him.
- Thank you, sir.
Sir.
Doing something tonight?
Zasta will need that mask?
xxx
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Everything is fine.
- You were at the party.
- For a rich-man's ball?
No, ugite for a drink.
- Thanks, but I really do...
- Pogite with us.
- Let the MacGregora to drink.
- Thanks, next time..
I have to go.
Wait to see
what is happening.
See when I thought?
What will he the hood?
Must be very important? An
as soon as hiding the face.
Or very ru? An.
Or both.
How are you tonight, dear?
It must be one that is called...?
- You're too proud to
show the face? - Sally?
My name is Heidi.
But every day
it's different name.
If you? Elish to be Sally,
I'll be Sally.
Perish with me.
How do I? Elish?
I would not,
supposed to be here.
Of course it should.
What's the matter?
Are you afraid?
Nemoras to coming off the mask.
For it does not bother me.
Svigas me who you are.
xxx
I dress! I said I'd
pay more for a dress.
It is my? Woman, sir.
You'll have to pay out of here,
even if you're the Prince of Wales.
If you are really the prince of Wales,
you'll have to pay even more.
The d? Epics there is gold,
enough to oslepis.
Who are dogavola you?
Heidi, perhaps? In the hands of
we have the right resources.
Let's see
What is behind this mask.
No.
You will not go
from here until I see your face.
xxx
Get away from me!
Murder!
- What animal is this done?
- I told you... it was a man.
I know.
A man with purple kapuljaeom.
That's it?
Put away all!
Get out of you.
- Surely you know who he is.
- I do not know.
Was to be
customers?
No.
I think that for her? Woman
took the madmen of Bedlam?
Poznajui you, Harry,
I think it would.
But you shall soon know.
If someone learns something,
Bring him back.
All right, Mr. Hawthorne.
Ka? Common that the man
with kapuljaeom had no money.
Heidi told me so.
Are you wanted it to him
Note?
We did not.
You would not have done such a thing,
is not it?
Of course it would not.
- Do you think that the gentleman?
- No znam. Nisam talked to him.
- Excuse me, sir. Look at this.
At this otiraeu have blood.
- It's his coat!
- His!
- He had on a coat?
- Yes.
"J. N."
- I wonder...
- What?
Is it of something under.
"E. P. Higgs. "
Tailor.
"Langford. "
xxx
Dr. Njuhart?
- Yes.
I am an officer of the Crown in London.
I want to talk.
OK. Ugite.
These are your initials doctors,
This is your coat?
It told us tailor
which it is sewed.
Yes, my.
This is blood!
The blood of prostitutes in London
prerezanog throat.
- Prerezanog throat? - This is done
someone who is wearing the garment.
I do not understand.
I must ask you
some questions.
Where were you last night?
I was in the house of Mr.
D? Jenkins, a local judge.
Veeerao there.
He will show us.
May you explain it
how come your coat in London?
I can not. I've lost it.
I must have left it somewhere.
Where?
Yes I know sir
Harton would not be lost?
Make sure that last night I
was Lengfordu,
continue the investigation in London
and carry this with you.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, doctor. Dovigenja.
- Well, what did they say?
- Nothing.
You killed? Wife,
is not it?
Interest groups.
Thank you, D? Ulian.
Beautiful composition.
Yes. For it has a lot of work.
This portrait I've done
for Lord Wallace.
Propose? Say that the portrait lady
Elizabeth is the same size.
Of course different for the style,
to show its beauty.
Julian, here are things that
and may be of interest.
- Wonderful landscape?.
- I think this can be satisfied.
View sleep? Nu sti line? E
on the left..
A guy whose portrait is this?
Sketch I
drew on memories.
By remembering?
Yes. My dog?has found a corpse
an unknown man in a river.
This dream? The line goes
top... D? Ulijan..
- Yes.
- Do you know who it is.
It was a great shock.
We just fell about.
Yes, interesting person.
xxx
Would it have sold?
Sold?
Mo? Participation is taken for free.
- This gentleman I just disturbing.
- Thank you.
This image woods...
I have to go.
Later will may develop
details.
Very thank you, it was pleasant.
You have Norton and threw the corpse
into a river. Why?
- Nonsense! Who said that?
- I.
His body was now in
the judge hands.
Anyway is impossible
to identifijuje.
Just as the people from
my village saw as
my brother!
And not only that.
The man who found him a painter.
Drew a sketch. See.
Fortunately I was able
that I take.
Why not return the body
to where you have taken?
- It was too risky.
- Why?
So what's at stake.
Trench...
How he died that man?
- Why are you so curious about
tugeg work? from any grave is izvagen?
- What for all this
- You heard me. Answers.
What do you hide?
- I have enough of their problems!
- Do not hide nista. Nesto happens.
Sviga not sound to me more.
If you is important? But you know,
I was much more important? is not to
not to? em. I I will not.
One more thing. After this
will no longer do business with me.
You have become too
curious.
In my work
It is too dangerous.
- Weller...
- Dovigenja doctors.
Well, what happened after
Edward is released?
Nothing.
You do your own lock
and chained.
- Our plan has failed
- Continue.
Oslobaganje was not possible.
Lord, Trench,
Do you know what that means?
My brother? Iv buried!
No more.
I went to pick up more.
You did not come for me, and had
We agree, Trench?
xxx
Lord.
Sir Edward.
- I thought you...
- Buried?
Yes.
I woke up in that
u? asnom ark,
I had no air.
I was trapped. The country is
down on the lid.
With every swing of shovels buried
I am more deeply.
No, Sir Edward.
D? Ulian...
D? Ulijan guilty.
Let me explain.
I want that getting back.
After all, this was a deal.
Inn "Starbak.
In Shorehamu.
Shorehamu?
Trench!
Why Shorham?
He's waiting... ship.
Waiting.
Why is waiting for me?
You're the man for whom
I put a cure?
Yes.
It is well acted.
xxx
Have you seen the face of
such as mine?
Once.
Is it possible? Frequently to help me?
Yes, for the gold.
Sit.
Do you know what happened in Africa?
Why do I do this?
I need to know.
You rode through
planta? in
White King, among
black slaves,
who do not know that you are
their enemy.
No.
xxx
No. I do not understand.
I know it was not me.
You are the man
who called Markham?
My brother has the same
name.
Markham... Markham...
Markham...
Nothing has changed you!
I'm still the same!
You must help me, doctor.
Give me something to endure? Them
until morning.
Well, perish with me.
- What's funny?
- Begins're vigenja mode,
man with purple
kapuljaeom.
but really I have seen!
Now it all vigaju!
Rumor has it that a man
with purple kapuljaeom
killed? woman in London.
Killed her.
- What are you, Sally?
- I can not believe it!
- What?
- Yes he did something like that in? Awful!
Sally, and you saw
man with kapuljaeom?
He stayed in
Al. Njuharta.
I promised I will not
tell anyone.
- Dr. Njuhart, yes.
Yes, of course.
Elizabeth, forgive
izai'll briefly.
Watch out for Sally.
Radok!
If you do not lie down,
umrees till morning.
So we need time.
- For more deaths?
- The final death.
And blood?
First? Want reasons, Doctor.
Then be? Blood.
Ka? In the blood
raga blood.
Do not you understand?
You know what we have done.
Do not you? Wanted
truth and revenge?
How do I know how
do you feel?
This census.
And that is?
That you are prompted? Well. Maintain?
Ae and until morning.
Or will ever be placed in the grave!
Why not sit down, dear?
're Pale.
I think that we
enjoy your brandy.
No, I will bring it.
Hey!
Is anyone there?
Who did this?
Man...
A man with purple
kapuljaeom? - Yes.
Where did it come from?
He was warm,
izvagen from the grave.
Where did he go?
I have to Nagem!
Villa Markh...
Markham.
- No.
- Sally...
- You gotta help me!
- You are a murderer!
- I do not understand!
You do not understand!
- I have to pronagem D? Ulijan.
- Where is he? Not here!
La? Participation!
Elizabeth,
what happened?
It was Sally.
Shortly before she was here.
- Sally?
- View!
- It's Edward.
- Edward?
Yes. I can now
you explain.
I go out.
You stay here, Elizabeth.
- D? Uliana!
- Please stay here!
D? Ulian!
Edward.
Edward, stop!
Why, Julian?
Why?
Edward, stop!
Allow me to explain
Why, Julian?
Why?
Edward, it was an accident.
You!
- You must have been you!
- Yes, I know!
Apr? Or Markham
to take revenge.
They found Markham.
Doeepali were you and not me.
There was nothing I could have me to do.
It was too late.
It's not too late, Julian.
Let doeepaju both!
This you are prompted? Or.
- Edward Markham?
- Yes.
Get out now.
Markham.
Where is Sir Julian?
I think it has gone up
D? Uliana?
D? Uliana, what is it?
Nothing.
This is Edward's
room, right?
No, Elizabeth.
This is my room.