Ah! We made it.
I gotta go, I gotta go! I gotta go!
Last one out's a rotten cheese!
Just breathe that air! Very Alpsy.
Look! Look! Horses!
Let's go riding! Can we please?
Can we?
Chelsea, chill. We've got all month to ride the horses.
Whoa!
I know! It's the Matterhorn! Isn't it amazing?
No, I mean this LCD screen!
Thirty-three megapixel resolution with 24.7 million colors!
It's like we're there!
Skipper, we are there.
Oh, yeah. Nice mountains.
But on this baby I can zoom in!
Barbie!
Aunt Marlene!
Skipper!
Stacie!
Chelsea!
Welcome to the Alpine Riding Academy!
Hello, Barbie.
- Hello, Max. - Barbie!
Whoa!
Oh, Marie!
Hi, Marie! You're really here!
Please excuse my sister. She was raised by squirrels.
lam so glad you're all here!
Please, come inside.
Barbie, I love the hand-tooled detail on your luggage. It's awfully smart.
Thanks.
I got a suitcase just like it!
Except mine is covered with scorpions.
Get out of the way!
Ooh!
This is it.
The flowers were my little touch.
And I picked off most of the bugs.
Most of the bugs?
Oh, and I put sweets on all of your pillows, just like in a hotel!
Oh, 'course, that was three days ago
and some of them melted, and Popcorn ate the rest,
but you can still smell them when you sleep.
Thank you, children. Popcorn!
Now back to your chores.
I got dibs on the top bunk!
No, me!
One, two, three, shoot.
Yes! No!
The room's perfect, Aunt Marlene. And I can't wait to find my horse!
Your champion horse! Barbie's gonna win
the Pacific Steeplechase with it!
Well, I don't know about that.
Of course you'll win.
You're only the best rider on the West Coast.
Thanks, but that depends a lot on finding just the right horse.
The horse of your dreams, hmm?
Every rider has one.
Something like that.
Well, I believe we raise the finest jumping horses in all of Switzerland.
I'm certain you'll find one here that is to your liking.
Have you got one that looks like this?
My, that's quite a horse.
Isn't it?
I hope I brought enough glitter.
When can we get started?
How about now?
Yay! Woo-hoo!
Let's go!
Skipper? Don't you want to see the horses, too?
You guys go ahead. I need to update my blog.
You used to love horses. When you were younger we couldn't get you off them.
Well, I guess people change.
And right now, all my peeps are at Tech-Con, trying out the latest gear,
while I'm stuck here listening to cows yodel.
So, first time on a horse, is it?
Yeah, it's my first,
but it won't take me long to ace it, like I do every sport.
Still, you might want to go slowly at first.
Thanks, but not too slow.
Did I mention I'm kind of a natural jock?
Yes. We caught it the first time.
We'll match Chelsea and Stacie with their horses first.
Girls, meet your teachers.
Ooh, I want that one! Or that one! Can I have two?
Can we pick whichever horse we want?
No, no, cherie. The beginning riders never pick their horses.
Huh? The horses pick you.
Excuse me?
You'll see.
Step into the corral and...
Then stand really still.
Aw.
It's okay, Chels.
Looks like you've got a new bestie, Stace.
What's her name?
Stacie, meet Pepper.
Nice to meet you, Pepper.
Aw.
It looks like you, too, have been chosen, Chelsea.
Meet Dash.
Where's the rest of her?
I'm afraid that's all there is.
But Dash is a very sweet pony.
And she seems to really like you.
But she's so little.
Why can't I have a big horse like Stacie's?
Chelsea, give Dash a chance.
There'll be plenty of time for big horses
when you're a little bigger.
Hmm.
Catastrophe! Disaster! Calamity!
C'est choquant, quelle horreur!
Madame Marlene,
we are ruined!
What is it this time, Etienne?
Look at these fly bonnets!
Just look at them!
So? "So?" I ordered them in aubergine
to match the halters! But look! Look!
Would you call that aubergine? Hmm?
Um, no?
He has a point. That is so not aubergine.
You see? The child is clearly offended!
How are we supposed to win a tournament with clashing fly bonnets?
Even the flies will be laughing at us!
Tournament? I like the sound of that.
The annual tournament between our academy and all the other local riding schools.
And the prize money is substantial. This year we're hosting.
But not if our horses are too embarrassed to take the field!
I'd better take care of this.
Max, Marie, you get Stacie and Chelsea started.
Barbie, you of course may choose your own horse.
Look over the thoroughbreds in the stable.
Every one's a prize jumper.
Did you see the stitching? I specifically asked for a cross-hatch stitch.
This is not a cross or even a hatch...
Who was that?
That was Monsieur Etienne, our riding master.
Is he always like that? Like he just bit into a lemon.
Pretty much. He's a good teacher, though.
Go!
Come on, girl! Good girl.
She's all yours.
Hmph.
Okay! So how do I get on this thing?
Ah, yes! Well, before we begin, I thought it might be instructive to review
the history of the English, or eventing, saddle.
Is that necessar...
Here you'll see the gullet, the cantle, the girth buckle, the...
What my brother's trying to say is,
stick your foot in here and throw your leg over the horse.
That's the big thing right there.
Got it. Thanks.
Right. Of course. Who needs four hundred years of tradition?
Fine. Just jump on and kick her into drive.
Wait!
First time on a horse? Definitely video-worthy.
Look at that style, that confident approach!
"As the future champion approaches, the animal humbly yields to its new master."
Whoa!
Look! Alpine has a new trick rider!
What do you call that move?
"The mud dive?"
Whoa!
Hey, Marie, if that's your best rider,
our winning streak seems pretty safe!
Hey, if you're looking up "world's greatest rider," I'm right here.
Actually, I was just looking up "doofus." See, right here.
She got you good, Jonas!
How droll.
Don't mind them.
They're from Ecole Montagne, the riding school just down the road.
They're just trying to get under our skin, with the tournament coming up.
'Course, it doesn't really matter. We always lose anyway.
Usually to them.
You never know. This year could be different.
Statistically speaking, we're bound to win within... Hmm...
Sixty-three years.
Now that I'm on the team, we'll cream those creeps!
Whoa! Ugh!
Yep.
Classic.
Why, hello, Sebastian.
Hello, Popcorn.
Now, run along.
Sorry that took so long, Barbie dear.
Monsieur Etienne can be a bit...
Temperamental at times.
I noticed.
He's worth it. We're hoping he can lead us to our first tournament win
in 11 years.
I'm sure you've got lots of good riders.
We did once,
but frankly, enrollment has been incredibly low these last few years.
So have you found your horse yet?
Every one in this group is from champion stock.
I'm just not sure.
This one seems nice.
Ah, Finian. Excellent choice!
His sire was winner of the Virginia Gold Cup,
so he'll be right at home in America.
You two would make an excellent team.
Hmmm... Maybe.
Ugh.
Ahh!
Huh? Oh, a goat. What's that?
Oh, no, you don't, you grabby goat!
Wakey wakey!
Oh, hi, Barnaby.
You know him? He's eating my blanket!
Yes, he likes wool. Last week he ate all my socks.
It's a miracle he's still alive.
Breakfast in twenty minutes! Hope you like Kartoffelkuchen.
No, no, no, no, no, no, mamselle.
We swoop with the curry comb, not attack. Hmm?
Long curving motions...
Comme ca... And swoop, oui?
And swoop, yes?
Bend the knees and swoop!
Got it. Swoop. Swoop. Bend...
Hey!
Gimme a break! I'm new at swooping!
Perfect! Dash, you're going to be so pretty!
Don't you think so, Chels?
Oh!
I can't wait to get out and feel the wind in my hair.
Ah...
Yipee-ka-yay.
Ow!
O-W.
Hyah!
Ah. Ah. Reign back, Mademoiselle Barbie!
No faster than a walk, please.
We must make certain everyone is riding at the same pace, n'est-ce pas?
Whoa!
Skipper, Stacie. Did you see that?
See what? That horse!
What are you talking about?
I guess... Nothing.
Nothing at all.
- Any dessert? Anything to eat? - No more for me!
Anybody like a cup of tea? Yes?
Now tell me the truth, Barnaby.
Doesn't clover taste better than wool?
I'm glad you agree.
That's the horse!
Elle fait des gateaux
Papa est en bas
Il fait du chocolat
Fais do do, Reynaud
Mon petit frere
Fais do do
T'auras du lolo
Oh. Mademoiselle Barbie, you startled me!
I'm sorry. I was enjoying your singing.
So was Reynaud.
Oh, ha, um, it is nothing. it calms him down.
Monsieur Etienne, may I ask you a question?
About the academy logo?
Logo?
You know, the sign in front? The horse.
Ah, that.
What can I say? It is a horse.
Well, yes, of course. But a very unusual horse, wouldn't you say?
I mean, those markings.
Why the interest?
It's just I don't know, I feel like I've seen that horse somewhere.
That is highly doubtful.
The horse you speak of does not exist.
It doesn't? But, the sign...
ls of a fable of an ancient herd called, "The Majestique."
They were said to roam wild somewhere in these mountains.
The story is that they are descended from a
breed created over a thousand years ago,
especially for the princesses of the Kieburg royalty
and fiercely loyal to them.
They protected them from harm, and the princesses were just
as devoted and protective of them.
A strong fearless breed.
They were said to have such superb jumping skill,
that they almost seemed to fly.
They are known by the strange pink streak in their manes.
The smartest, the fastest, the bravest horses ever known to man!
Many doubt that they were ever real,
since none has ever been caught, or even photographed.
But what about the painting?
Hmm. What of it?
There are also paintings of fairies and mermaids, non?
So, you don't think the Majestique horses are real?
Mmm...
Once, when I was a child,
I thought I saw...
Nonsense!
Foolish twaddle!
You have always believed in fairy tales, Etienne.
Philippe! How dare you defile my stable!
You, you festering boil on a baboon's backside!
And you are the hair of a pig's nostril!
I spit on the toe of your uncle!
I stuff your nose with cabbages!
Uh, hi, my name's Barbie.
I gather you two know each other.
Excusez-moi, mademoiselle.
I am Monsieur Philippe, riding master extraordinaire of L'Ecole Montagne.
Enchante.
I speak up, only because this pig of a dog of a mule,
fills your head with phooey-hooey.
There is no such breed as the Majestique and there never was.
No horse is that remarkable.
They are merely dumb beasts, meant to serve their masters.
And fear the riding crop!
But why do you ask about Majestiques?
Have you...
Seen something?
Me? Um. er...
How could I see something that doesn't exist?
Yes. Of course. Utter foolishness!
Etienne, it is chilly.
Maman says to wear your sweater.
Tell her the soup was yummy.
And how was the baguette?
I did not receive a baguette.
Exactly.
Hmm.
Come on, Finian. Let's go home.
What is it?
Whoa!
Finian, come back!
Oh, boy.
So you are real!
I knew it!
Thank you.
Hmm, my hero.
Again.
Straighten up, mamselle Stacie.
Legs pressed together, weight forward.
Ah, tres bien.
Now pull your horse back to a walk, then stop.
Whoa.
Whoa!
Whoa, whoa!
Don't you know how to whoa?
Non, non, non, mamselle. We do not yank the reins.
You will only make her...
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Oh, les enfants.
Aunt Marlene,
I need a new horse.
Mine is busted.
No, Stacie, Pepper is your horse,
and she chose you for a reason.
Yeah, 'cause she craves my public humiliation.
She won't do anything I tell her to.
Of course she will...
When she wants to.
Hiya!
I know you're here somewhere...
It's all right.
Everything's going to be just fine.
Let me help you, okay?
Wow, you really did get stuck, didn't you?
That must hurt.
Easy girl, easy.
That's it.
Fais do do
T'auras du Iolo
Ma petite soeur
Fais do do
T'auras du lolo
Oh, you're bleeding.
I just want to help you.
It's okay.
I owe you this for the wolves.
You're so majestic.
I think I'll call you...
Majesty-
Okay, one more, Barnaby.
And this time a little more presidential.
Hey, tech girl!
Ever put that thing down?
Oh look, Barnaby, you have a visitor.
Did you come to have your official portrait taken,
monkey DOV?
Ohh! That one will look good on a baboon.
Don't you think?
Ha! You may be good with a tablet,
but I'll bet I can outride you any day.
You're on! I'll bring the bananas.
Right now, I have some work to do on your portrait.
See ya!
Is he looking?
Don't look!
Dinner in a second!
Oh. Chelsea!
Shh. I'm hiding from Dash.
Oh.
Why are we hiding from Dash?
'Cause she keeps eating my hair!
It looks fine to me.
Yeah, but she follows me around everywhere
and nibbles on my pigtails and gets horse slobber all over my head.
I see.
Oh, does your hair smell like candy?
Marshmallow Tresses Shampoo.
My favorite.
It's made with real live marshmallows!
Ah. Well, that explains it.
Dash loves marshmallows, too.
She does?
Oh my, yes.
In fact,
you two have lots of things in common.
She loves pretty ribbons, and things that glitter,
and anything pink.
Perhaps you should give her another chance.
I don't know.
She really, really likes you, Chelsea.
And you know, I'll bet she'd look wonderful in sparkly bows.
You think?
Hmm,
maybe I could pretty her up.
We could start with a manicure and then braid her hair.
Oh...
And then I could use the sparkles and then...
Hmm?
Hmm.
Yeah! Way to go!
I got this.
Excellent form, Marie, as always!
Pity you are too young to compete, hmm?
Mamselle Stacie, you are next. Remember,
you and your mount are as one.
You must be the horse!
Ah!
Now, allez-vous!
All right! Now we're talking!
Oh man, lam so good at this!
Whoa!
Ugh, yuck!
Mamselle Stacie.
Perhaps I did not explain.
You are supposed to jump through the hedge with the horse.
And that's for this year's holiday card.
Hiya!
Bonjour, mamselle. Now, show me what you've found!
It's classical. So boring!
You see in races they put roses on the horses...
I don't care what they're for.
Since Mother left it to us to decide,
I think the theme for the dance should be "Alpine Primroses in Summertime."
I was thinking "Robot Samurai."
What does that have to do with a horse show?
What do you think robot Samurai ride around on,
skateboards?
Really?
You can't put a robot on a horse it would fall off!
Mmm.
Horse!
Ahh!
Whoa!
All right!
Woo-hoo!
Where are you taking me?
Majestiques! A whole herd of them!
Something wrong, Aunt Marlene?
It's nothing, dear.
Have you had your lunch yet?
Something is wrong.
Please tell me. I'm a teenager, so I'll never let this drop.
I'm afraid it's nothing you can help with.
The fact is I may have to sell the academy.
Sell it? But why?
Too many bills, too few students.
I have tried to hold on, but two weeks ago,
I got an offer for the place from Madame Cheynet, of Ecole Montagne.
No doubt Philippe's idea.
He has never forgiven Etienne for coming here.
And if we don't win the tournament prize money, I'll have to accept.
You're not going to do it, are you?
Alpine has been in our family for generations. I was born here.
I'd be crushed to lose it.
But I may have no choice.
They are giving me until Tuesday to accept their offer.
But won't winning the race bring in new students?
Of course, that would be wonderful!
But truthfully, we haven't won a tournament in 11 years.
This year you've got a secret weapon,
the Roberts sisters!
Can you hold off the sale, just until after the tournament?
I can try. But, Skipper, really.
No time to talk! I've got to see a girl about a race!
Way to go, Barbie! Skipper!
That is one awesome horse!
Oh, Skipper, it was amazing! We were flying!
Soaring! This is the horse I've been looking for all my life!
But you can't say a word about her. Not until I say so.
Barbie, something's happened.
Promise you won't!
Pinky pledge!
When exactly are we too old for that?
Never!
Okay, my beautiful Majesty. See you tomorrow. Go on now.
Majesty, I like that.
But look, there's something I really need to tell you.
Lose the academy? That's terrible!
Poor Aunt Marlene.
Exactly. Which is why Alpine has to win this tournament.
I'm even violating my strict anti-involvement policy by entering dressage.
Well that's perfect, you're fantastic at dressage!
And that's why you have to run in the steeplechase.
You riding Majesty would totally demolish the competition!
Skipper, I can't. Etienne is riding for Alpine. It's tradition.
And besides, Majesty needs to stay a secret,
at least till I get her back to Malibu.
A secret? Why?
Because Philippe will recognize what she is and know there must be more like her.
After we leave, I don't want her herd hunted down and broken.
So Majestiques need to stay a fairy tale.
But what about the steeplechase?
What about us winning the tournament for Aunt Marlene?
Look, Etienne is a champion rider.
And remember, there's more than one event.
With you doing dressage, I'm sure Alpine's got everything they need.
Stacie?
You're not practicing for Saturday?
Yeah, I dunno, I'm kinda off horseback riding for now.
Really? But aren't you signed up for the cross-country trial?
Actually,
I was thinking about dropping out of that. It's not really my thing.
Okay, Stacie, what's wrong? Since when don't you like to compete?
Oh, face it, Barbie, I stink at riding.
I just don't get it. I've always aced everything I've tried!
Skateboards, mountain bikes, wakeboarding, skysurfing, motorcross.
So why can't I control a horse?
Stacie, your horse isn't a skateboard.
She's a living, breathing being, with her own feelings.
Yeah. She's made her feelings very clear to me.
Well, maybe you should try to work with her instead of just trying to control her.
Make friends, find out what she wants.
Make friends with a horse? Like what, take her to a movie?
You know what I mean. Just try it.
Oh, and, these sugar cubes won't hurt.
Hi, I'm Stacie! You know, the girl you've been trying to maim?
Here, have some cavities.
Hey!
She likes them! Got any more?
Welcome to the 108th Annual Inter-Academy Equestrian Tournament!
And, as always, we start things off with the perennially popular
pretty pony parade!
Isn't Dash pretty? And we both smell like marshmallows!
You're up next, Skipper. We're all behind you!
Hey, tech girl. Don't tell me you found an app for riding that thing.
No app needed. We're doing this strictly old school.
Next up in the dressage competition,
riding for Alpine, Skipper Roberts on Juniper.
And first place goes to Miss Skipper Roberts of Alpine!
Boo!
Perhaps I should acquire one of those tablets.
Our next event will be the cross-country competition.
Stacie Roberts on Pepper, now heading for the double rails of number seven.
And the jump is good!
Now approaching jump eight, the lighthouse.
Immediately followed by the fickle frank at number nine.
A smooth landing for Miss Roberts and Pepper.
Moving strongly now, and they beautifully adapt to the corners.
Now, jumping over the brush fence at 10!
Uh-oh, a run-out, that'll cost them points.
But they recover nicely and go for the triple bar!
A clean jump. Heading now for the final and most challenging jump, the keyhole!
Okay, we're friends now right? We go through this jump together this time,
not just me.
Pretty please?
A Perfect jump!
And here comes the judges' decision.
First place, Stephanie Coda and King's Cross of Ecole Montagne!
In second place, Stacie Roberts and Pepper of Alpine!
Second place? Not bad. But next year, we hammer them.
And that concludes the opening day competitions,
with Ecole Montagne and Alpine Academy tied for first place.
Tomorrow, the final event, the spectacular steeplechase at Bernwald Racetrack.
And don't forget the inter-academy formal dance tonight, right here at Alpine!
That's the best we've done in years.
What a great day for Alpine!
And a long one at that.
I suggest we all have a little rest before the dance.
Where's my blue pantyhose? My shoes shrunk!
Nobody move. How does my hair look?
You're too little for lipstick! No fair!
Barnaby! My shoe!
You might as well throw him the other one, maybe he can chew it to match.
Um, does this look funny?
Tuck it in!
Turn around!
Much better.
Is that, is that me?
I love it!
Would you like a glass of punch? It's very tasty.
There you go, and one for you. There you go. Would you like some?
Yes? All right.
Oh, how are you?
I know, isn't it beautiful?
Good to see you again.
Good evening, Etienne.
Konnichiwa. That's "hello" in Samurai!
Oh my.
What interesting decor.
I knew you'd love it.
Don't ask.
There we go.
Yes, I was out riding today.
Well, I think that it's going to be quite a bit easier now...
Whoa.
Look, the Odd Squad is staring.
Pretend they're not there.
I love this song! Marie, come dance with me!
Hey, nerd girl. You weren't too bad at the dressage trials today.
Thanks. Boy, that first prize is heavy.
Yeah, yeah. You got lucky.
You, uh, want to dance?
I wouldn't want to step on your little second-place feet.
I'll take a chance.
Whoa. What were the odds of that?
You didn't see that coming?
That is my punch you are drinking, you stuffed sauerkraut sausage!
It's mine, you pompous pickled pudding!
Creampuff!
Bon bon for brains!
Chocolate mousse!
I think I'm losing my appetite.
Oh, Stacie, I'm going out to the corral.
Yeah, yeah, that's nice. Have fun.
I'll be right back.
Chelsea!
Chelsea? Chelsea!
Hang on, Chelsea!
Etienne!
Chelsea!
Chelsea? Chelsea?
Chelsea, can you hear me?
Chels...
Dash! Stop!
I'm okay.
She's okay, just a little shaken. She'll be fine.
Chelsea, why on Earth?
I just wanted to ride a big horse, like you and Barbie and Stacie do.
Oh, Chelsea.
I think you've done quite enough riding for one day.
Let's get you inside.
And Etienne, we'll need to get a doctor to look at your arm.
Thank goodness she's okay.
But what about our horses? They're all gone.
The race! We must go after them!
How? It's dark, and we don't know which way they went.
I can track them.
Jonas, you know how to do that?
I know these hills like Skipper knows her tablet.
My friends said we could use their horses.
Let's go!
We'll call the neighboring farms and ask them to keep a lookout for the runaways.
I'll help!
Come on, this way!
Hmm. What is it?
These tracks...
You see that set of prints?
That horse is coming from a different direction than the others.
Then it joins the rest here.
Huh, it's not wearing horseshoes.
Exactly. Then it appears to lead the herd away, in that direction.
I'm afraid that's it.
The prints lead onto these rocks, and then vanish.
Sorry.
Now what? The race is in a few hours, and Alpine's got no horses.
Aunt Marlene might as well kiss the school goodbye.
Wait! I know where they might be!
Good job, Majesty!
I wonder if she babysits. Four sugar cubes an hour and all the hay she can eat.
That horse...
The one with the pink mane.
What breed is it?
A very special one.
And they're our secret. Okay?
Looks like the steeplechase is still on!
Monsieur Philippe. What a pleasant surprise.
You think you're very clever, don't you? And you! Traitor! Turncoat!
Do not bother returning to L'Ecole!
Mamselle Barbie, I owe you a debt of gratitude.
I believe you have found a place I have searched for since I was a child...
The Valley Of The Majestiques.
Majestiques? But Monsieur, you said they were fairy tales!
That was for my brother's benefit.
I have always known they were real. And worth a king's ransom.
And now, I know they are somewhere on Alpine land.
As you've said, this is Alpine land.
Well, after today's race, this land will belong to Ecole Montagne,
and soon I will have all the time in the world to find them.
Unless, of course, Monsieur Etienne leaves you in the dust.
Oh, didn't you hear? My brother's broken arm will keep him from riding.
But do not worry. Once this land is mine,
I may let you look at the Majestiques...
For a price.
We have to win that race.
Day two of the tournament,
and we're here at Bernwald Racetrack for the concluding event,
the annual 3.2 kilometer steeplechase.
Alpine Academy and Ecole Montagne are tied going into this race.
Aren't Barbie and Skipper coming?
They'll make it here in time! I just know it!
Riding for Centre Equestre, Jason Randall.
Riding for Ecole Montagne, Monsieur Philippe Cheynet, on Hurricane!
You lose again, Etienne!
Ladies and gentlemen, an announcement.
Alpine Academy will not be racing this year.
lam sorry, Marlene.
We tried our best.
As we approach the top of the hour, registration is now...
Wait a moment! There's a late entry!
Riding for Alpine is
Barbie Roberts, on Majesty!
Etienne! Is that...
Yes.
A Majestique.
Easy, now. Easy.
The saddle's not so bad. You'll get used to it.
Whoa, it's okay Majesty.
That's a beautiful horse, Ms. Roberts. It will not be yours much longer.
We will see, Monsieur.
Wow! It's like they're real!
Rider's ready!
The wire is up, and they're off!
Easy,easy. It's all right.
Teacher's Pet takes the lead, Prima Donna in second, Way to Go in third!
Majesty is rearing at the gate.
That's it. Settle. It's okay.
Hiya!
Come on, Majesty. You can do it!
Way To Go moving into the number two spot
as riders head for the first water ditch!
Raclette is down!
You can do this, girl! It's just like the glacier streams!
We love you, Barbie!
Rounding the turn to jump four, it's Creme Brulee and
Way to Go leading the pack, with Prima Donna dropping back,
followed by Teacher's Pet with Hurricane gaining.
Oh, dear. Teacher's Pet has spilled its rider!
Go, you mangy beast!
Hurricane passes Prima Donna and challenges Creme Brulee for second
as they come to the hedge jump.
Majesty still trailing in last place.
What's this? Creme Brulee is out of the race!
That is just plain wrong. Come on, Majesty, let's show him!
Making a late charge, Majesty rockets to overtake Prima Donna!
Way to Go in first. Barbie Roberts on Majesty
continues a spectacular come from behind,
challenging reigning champion Philippe Cheynet on Hurricane for second!
Barbie Roberts is down! The saddle has come off her horse!
It looks like Miss Roberts and Majesty are out of the race!
He can't stop us. Come on, Majesty.
Born free, ride free!
Hurricane now closing in on Way To Go.
Hurricane and Way To Go are neck and neck.
Oh, Way To Go stumbles!
Way To Go at the inside fence refusing the jump.
Philippe Cheynet now firmly in first place.
Just one more jump before another victory for Ecole Montagne.
Alpine and the Majestiques are mine!
Wait a moment. Barbie Roberts is back in the race and gaining fast!
Philippe Cheynet takes the jump!
What's this? Unbelievable!
Barbie Roberts and Majesty down the stretch!
Philippe Cheynet furiously trying to take back the lead.
It's Majesty and Hurricane down the stretch!
And the winner for Alpine Academy is Barbie Roberts on Majesty!
You did it, Majesty, you did it!
Ladies and gentlemen! The overall Tournament Cup goes to
Alpine Equestrian Academy!
It is an outrage! I should have won that race!
I was unfairly distracted!
By what? Your own cheating?
We saw what you did, you penguin's patoot!
And you are the lint in a baboon's belly button!
Here we go again.
Taisez-vous! Ow!
Now go to your room! You are on Ie time out!
But Maman! He started it!
You were magnifique!
Uh, thank you, uh...
Madame Cheynet, the owner of Ecole Montagne.
Bridgette, I won't be needing to sell Alpine.
Felicitations, Marlene.
lam most happy for you.
Maman...
This horse... Thelegendu.
I know. Isn't she beautiful?
Come, mon chouchou. I made soup.
Do I get a baguette this time?
Thank you. I love it.
Here's Stacie's last bag. Popcorn and I packed the rest of her stuff.
Hey, where is Popcorn?
on.
Well, I think that's everything.
I just want to thank you again, Aunt Marlene.
This has been the best summer ever.
No, I thank all of you.
Once Skipper posted her video of the race online,
our enrollment tripled!
I think we'll be teaching riders for many years to come.
At school, I signed up a whole bunch of students
for riding and dressage lessons,
and one wants to learn to play the banjo, but I signed him up anyway.
Well, that's the last of it.
Thanks for helping. You're not a bad guy! Sometimes.
Careful, you almost said something nice to me.
And since you like marshmallow shampoo so much,
I'm gonna send you my next favorite, Scent O' S'mores.
Yeah, me too. And I'm sorry about all those things I said.
You really are a great pony. And just my size.
Okay, I admit it. I'm gonna miss you.
Even though you gave my sister years' worth of embarrassing pictures of me,
you're still a very cool horse.
See you in Malibu, Majesty. I think you're gonna like California.
You have chosen an amazing horse, Barbie.
I am certain you and she will win many, many races together.
Barbie? Aren't you excited?
No. No, I won't do it.
Barbie, what are you doing?
Letting her go. I can't, Aunt Marlene. I just can't.
She belongs here with her family.
I could never take that away from her.
That decision comes from your heart. I think it's the right one.
I'll never forget you. Never. Now go.
If you come back, I know she will come back.
Come on, Barbie!
This thing won't drive itself!
Okay, now, who's got the boarding passes?