Open your eyes. Open your eyes.
Why are you telling me
about this dream?
You said I could tell
you anything I wanted.
Okay.
Anything else you should tell
me?
Nothing you don't already know.
I was about to turn 25...
and I liked eating, sleeping
and making love.
Like everyone else.
You know what everyone does when
they wake up.
OPEN YOUR EYES
- Where are you going?
- Out.
Don't record anymore messages on
my alarm clock.
Why not?
Because.
Because it pisses me off.
Come on, damn it.
- I'll beat you.
- We'll see about that.
Don't pretend you're poor.
You've got three cars
and you always drive me in this
junk.
Come on, I'm in a rush.
I hope you have no commitments.
I'm doing a bunk.
No, but I've got a meeting with
my partners.
Why do you think I'm wearing
this costume?
To show off, which is what you
like.
That's not true.
First of all, did you bang her?
Who?
You were with someone
last night.
Last night? I was alone.
- Why do you care?
- I don't.
You can do whatever you want
with your life, man.
Thank you very much.
Okay, enough. Let's change the
subject.
- Did you bang her?
- I told you.
- I was alone.
- So that means you did.
Is it the one you won't shut up
about?
- Who?
- Nuria.
My God, I can't believe it.
Csar is repeating a woman.
She must be awesome in bed, huh?
- She's not bad.
- Son of a bitch.
You should tell me the secret.
- The secret?
- The Coca Cola formula.
- One of the ones you like.
- Now you're changing the sub...
So, did you get some today?
No!
That's my problem. I'm not
getting any!
And then I'm amused when you ask
them
what they like most about a man.
"He must be smart, he must be
honest,
"he must be likable." Bullshit!
You wouldn't score so much if
you were like me.
That's enough. You're not ugly.
Many would trade their face for
yours.
You're completely normal.
That's it, I'm normal. That
doesn't mean I'm handsome.
- You are handsome.
- I'm acceptable.
When you're alone you're like an
anorexic girl.
They think they're fat, and they
end up going crazy.
Sure. When is a woman going to
claim you
so you'll clear the field for
the rest of us?
Sure.
Why not?
If you ever find the one...
The one doesn't exist. Shit!
How could I miss that?
God's punishment for talking too
much.
You'll see.
- Who are you talking to?
- God.
Do you believe in God?
Don't start with that.
I just asked you a question.
Don't answer if you don't want
to.
I don't believe in God.
Then, how do you
explain what happened?
- What?
- Your face.
There's no
explanation for that.
I think there is.
You think I'm crazy.
I only believe in what I see.
And you haven't let me see your
face yet.
Nor will I.
Do you really think
you're a monster, Csar?
Come on.
- Let me see.
- Shove your hand up your ass!
Calm down, you brat, okay? I'm
sick of your bullshit.
- Leave me alone.
- I'll fix you
- with a few punches.
- Leave me alone!
I can't do my job with you in
here.
Please, leave us alone under my
responsibility.
You're just a daddy's boy who's
always...
My parents are dead, moron!
Now you're making stuff up not
to admit what you did.
Is that true?
What?
That you're a daddy's boy.
My father had a restaurant
chain.
I'm not to blame for that.
When did your parents die?
Fifteen years ago, in an
accident.
- And now you're loaded.
- So they say.
Then I don't understand why you
don't want
a lawyer to defend you.
They claim they can get one of
the best.
But they just want me to stay
here forever.
- Who are they?
- My partners.
Those who've sucked on my blood
since I was a kid.
Now they've got everything.
They've made me incompetent.
That wasn't them. It was me.
Whatever.
Let's see, Csar. Do you know
why you're here?
For wearing a mask, I guess.
No.
You're here because you killed
someone.
Don't you remember?
Tell me.
- Don't you remember?
- Okay, enough!
Everything must be clear if you
want us to get along.
I don't want us to get along!
And that's the solution?
Refusing to talk, locked in
this... sty?
- We're talking now, aren't we?
- After two months.
I've been here for two months
eliciting words from you.
Read the files.
I have, but I want you to tell
me,
if possible, sitting in a chair.
- You'll always be like this?
- I like the floor.
It's the only thing that seems
real.
What about everything else?
Everything else is a lie.
All of this seems like a lie.
Including you.
You're not even wearing a gown.
Do you think I should wear one?
Doctors do.
I took it off so
you'd forget I'm a doctor.
- So you'd like me better.
- Well, it doesn't work.
I don't like you at all.
Okay.
Now we're such close friends...
I have no friends.
Please tell me what happened
that night.
The sooner you talk, the sooner
I'll leave.
Hey.
Congratulations, and all that
stuff people always say.
Partners.
And this girl? Where did you get
her from?
- She tried to steal from me.
- It was my book.
Okay. Csar, Sofa. Sofa, Csar.
- Happy birthday.
- Thanks.
- Here's your present.
- Thanks a lot.
We both bought it.
Then, thanks to both of you.
Stop flirting with her and open
it.
I'd rather open them tomorrow.
Okay.
- Drinks?
- Sure.
I'll take this upstairs.
Hey.
- What are you doing here?
- Congratulations, darling.
Thank you very much.
But I don't recall inviting you
to the party.
Very thoughtful of you.
I've brought you a gift, too.
Aren't you going to open it?
No, thanks. I know what's
inside.
You're different today.
Nuria, it's not at all funny
that you came unannounced.
Or that you went into my room.
Wow.
- Do I have to apologize?
- No.
You have to go.
I understand. I know what's
happening to you.
You don't want anyone to see you
twice with the same girl.
Your reputation would go to
hell, wouldn't it?
You nailed it.
You must have checked out some
hottie.
- Of course.
- Who?
That brunette you were talking
to
a moment ago, right?
She's not bad.
I don't care.
I don't need anyone to see me
with you.
Hold me. Hold me.
Come on, just a kiss.
Just a little.
Come on.
Until when? Next Friday?
I doubt you remember
what a weekend without me is
like.
I'm sorry, I have to attend to
my guests.
Hurry, that brunette's going to
take a while.
She seems to be one of those.
- One of those?
- Yeah.
The ones who can't find the
zipper.
- Hi.
- What do you want?
- To open this.
Hold on. I'll pour some for you.
Since when are you the
bartender?
Don't you know I work in
hospitality?
Is something wrong?
Is it too obvious I'm hitting on
you?
- A bit.
- I just have a little problem.
- A woman's harassing me.
- You don't say.
And I need to bother someone
to get rid of her.
And I'm the lucky one.
Shit! She's there.
- Where?
- Don't look.
- Where is she?
- Look over there.
So yes, sure.
- Sure.
- Yeah.
- Here we are.
Okay.
Pretend we're talking
about something interesting.
You nod, you say yes.
And... okay.
- Nice conversation.
- Very nice.
Especially because I think she's
coming over.
No way.
- I need to use the restroom.
- I'll tell you where it is.
- Look ahead...
- I don't see her anymore.
Right here.
- Come on in, ma'am.
- I'm not going in there.
I will. See you later.
- She's here.
- You're a...
Okay. We're safe.
The downside is there's no
drinks here.
I think you're messing with me
and you just want to hook up.
Well, that too, but it's
secondary.
What matters now is to be safe.
Can't you tell her you're not
interested?
No way! She doesn't care. She
never gives up.
- It must be hard for her.
- Yeah, sure.
What's your major? Dramatic
Arts, like Pelayo?
- For now.
- Set design?
- Interpretation.
- Wow.
- You want to be an actress?
- I am one.
- Is there a problem?
- Well, yeah.
- Aren't you ashamed?
- Ashamed?
Why would I be ashamed?
Actors aren't honest people.
You're capable of showing
feelings you don't have.
Or that you make up, at most.
Right now you may be thinking,
"Jeez, he's so annoying. How
will I get rid of him?"
- You think?
- "And he's got a hotel."
But you're a good actress and
you don't show it.
Hey, Pelayo.
- You caught us.
- Come in.
- How's it going?
- Good. I'm a little wasted.
- Drunk.
- Why are you locked up in here?
Sofa is defending me from a
certain psycho
who's roaming out there.
She seemed dangerous.
- Okay.
- What about you?
I'm drinking. Women don't chase
me.
We're out of liquor.
Want some?
- Shit. I'll go get more.
- Hey.
I'll get some for all of us.
Well, um... I'm leaving.
What do you mean?
I drank too much and I'm not
okay.
Bullshit, Pelayo, this is just
starting.
- It just started for you.
- Pelayo...
you can't go. You're my guest
of honor.
You're a son of a bitch.
- Where's that coming from?
- Are there no other girls?
I go take a piss for a moment,
you start talking to her and...
And what?
And nothing. I don't want to
look like a fool.
Explain right now what the
hell's wrong with you.
Why did you have to hook up with
Sofa of all people?
No one's hooking up with Sofa.
Sure, so I'm blind, right?
You're a bit drunk.
I'm drunk, but I'll tell you one
thing.
I like Sofa very much. I like
her a lot, dude.
In fact, she may be the one.
But if I'd known it would mess
up our friendship,
I'd have told her to fuck off.
- Same here.
- Sure.
Pelayo, where are you going?
- Home.
- Already?
- Yeah, I'm beat.
- Hold on, I'll go with you.
Don't, it's...
It's not necessary.
You're leaving too?
I have to get up early tomorrow.
I can take you home later.
Stay. You're in good hands.
- What's with him?
- He's drunk.
- Did we upset him?
- Of course not.
Are you sure?
She doesn't seem very happy.
Didn't you have to get up early
tomorrow?
I'm doing too much for
you tonight.
- Maybe that means something.
- Yeah, that you're shameless.
It's just a moment.
Enough for my friend Nuria to
give up.
This is my house.
- If you mock it, you're out.
- Why would I mock it?
It's no big deal, but rent's a
bargain.
- You like clowns?
- They're not clowns.
They're mimes.
Pancho!
- I have a cat.
- I hate cats.
They're almost as fake as
actresses.
Said the hotel owner.
How do you pay for this?
Do your parents help you out?
Did you get any acting jobs?
He's nosy. Don't you think,
Pancho?
- I'm an arms dealer.
- No kidding.
I always wanted to see how an
arms dealer lived.
Well, now you know.
How do you want me to tell it?
You wouldn't understand. Not
even I understand it.
She started to make coffee
and I started to snoop around.
And suddenly, I felt
that stupidity apparently, many
people feel.
- I like it.
- What did you feel?
That I loved her. God, I'm
ashamed to even say it.
Sorry, I didn't hear you.
- I said I like your place.
- And I like yours.
We can switch.
I doubt you'd like it so much in
the morning.
Besides, I meant because of the
decor.
I don't know, your place is
more... more personal.
- And warmer.
- Warmer?
- Yeah.
- You thought my house was cold?
- A little.
- Do you think I'm cold?
I don't know.
But my house is. Which is it,
then?
If you expect me to praise you,
you'll wait a long time.
You think you're so clever.
- Maybe.
- You're so wrong.
I don't need you to tell me what
my virtues are.
No, I'm sure you know what they
are.
But you'd like to know that I've
seen them too.
You wish.
I'm not arguing over something
so silly.
That's better.
- You would've lost.
- You think?
I don't want to argue, either.
In fact,
I'll propose the opposite.
- Not to argue?
- To name each other's flaws.
Good.
I hope you're doing right by me.
You've never been depicted more
faithfully.
Okay, mine's ready.
Holy shit.
This is how you see me?
- Was it too much?
- Sign it.
Let me see mine.
It's beautiful.
But it's not a cartoon.
I wanted you to see.
I didn't know you drew so well.
- I'll sell it to you.
- For how much?
Since it's you, I'll settle
for... one kiss.
That smile is going to kill me.
It'd be very wrong for us to
hook up tonight.
- Why?
- Pelayo, remember?
He's your best friend.
He doesn't need to find out.
Besides, he'd do the same.
I see friendship comes first for
you.
It does.
That's why I wouldn't tell him.
Some people claim
they settle for a normal
duration
of their lives.
But "normal"...
means different things
depending on the period.
What are you watching?
I'm watching TV.
was living just 25 years.
Nowadays, that number has
tripled.
- Thus...
- What is he talking about?
I've seen that before.
It's a feature about cryonics.
"Cryo" what?
It's when they freeze you or
something. Like Walt Disney.
Brr! How cold!
Hey, handsome!
Cause a landslide by
being here.
It's not dangerous. It's firm
land,
and it's very solid.
You're leaving?
Home.
I'll leave you my number.
I'll call you tomorrow, anyway.
What for?
Okay, then I won't call you.
Csar.
- What is it?
- Come here.
I'll tell you a secret.
Come here.
Hi, darling.
- You've been following me?
- Of course.
No. I had a feeling we'd run
into each other.
- Okay.
- How was it with the brunette?
Very well. Why?
Your face. I'd say you didn't
sleep with her.
Let me guess.
You didn't, but you don't care,
either.
Is that so?
You have all the time in the
world to win her over.
In fact, you surely made plans
for tomorrow or the day after.
- Brilliant.
- Right? And there's more.
- Tell me.
- I hooked up with someone, too.
But he didn't measure up.
So I was left wanting more.
So?
Until you see Miss Universe
again,
you could do with some fun
yourself.
I think I'd rather go to sleep.
Come on, Csar.
It's your birthday. You deserve
a prize.
Don't insist. I'm going home.
What's wrong, Csar? Are you
afraid?
Do you want some? It's from the
party.
No, thanks.
Play the good boy now.
I don't need a fix to have fun.
I've seen that.
You shouldn't take that, you're
driving.
Suit yourself.
What's happiness to you?
What?
To me, happiness is this. Being
here with you.
Isn't it to you?
I don't know, Nuria.
I'm not in the mood for
significant talks right now.
It's just your mind is
elsewhere.
Isn't that right, honey?
Maybe.
Just one thing bothers me.
What is it?
That you don't know anything
about me.
You just know I'm Nuria and I'm
a good fuck.
Two very important things.
You probably don't even have my
number.
This is a start. I'll see your
place now.
We're almost there.
Tell me, do you believe in God?
No!
- Hi.
How are you?
- How was the ride home?
- Okay.
I had a horrible dream.
That you never saw me again?
Yeah.
I'm leaving your place, heading
to my car,
and it turns out that slut has
been following me.
- Who? That Nuria?
- Yeah.
She tells me, "Do you want a
ride?"
She insists, and I don't know
how to say no,
so I get in her car,
and she starts revving up...
Then, boom!
She commits suicide with me in
there.
- That's awful.
- That's not the worst part.
The worst is my face ends up
completely ruined,
like the Phantom of the Opera.
I couldn't wake up.
I was a monster.
You're a monster anyway.
- Am I?
- Yeah.
I'm a monster too.
Look.
How was your place?
Was there anyone left?
Why would there be anyone left?
There was a party at your place,
remember?
A party?
Dreaming sucks.
That was a nice
dream. A park...
Some kids playing, a woman who
loves you.
Exactly.
Then you wake up and you want to
die.
At first, I didn't even have the
strength to react.
I'd been in a coma for three
weeks.
You were very lucky.
You could've died.
- Like Nuria.
- So what?
It would've been better.
Besides, did you see her body?
No one showed it to me.
You think she survived?
I'm like you.
I only believe in what I see.
Csar, show me your
face, please.
- Why are you asking that now?
- Look...
It's true you were in an
accident.
It's true you were disfigured.
But now you're perfectly fine.
- No.
- Take that off.
Doctors redid your face.
They had no fucking clue!
In the accident, you
not only lost skin
and part of your muscles,
the impact on your head was so
hard,
it caused multiple fractures.
We've held the bone structure
with metallic string,
and over it we've reinserted the
muscles
that could still be salvaged.
That's all very nice,
but I know this.
You've explained it to me 150
times.
But you never tell me when I'm
having surgery.
I've been waiting for over two
months.
You've already had surgery.
Three times.
I wouldn't call this surgery.
I'd call it... well...
I don't even know what to call
it.
Even though the symmetry isn't
perfect,
we want you to understand that
what we did
with your face is, pardon my
honesty,
very hard work.
We can't work on skin that's
pure scar.
No, there has to be a way.
- Which way?
- Seriously?
You're the doctors, aren't you?
A transplant, I don't know!
There's a fibrosis issue,
and if we operate again, there's
a risk
of causing new damage.
We'd need absolute precision.
And that is impossible right
now.
Let's see. I'm no idiot.
Nowadays, people remove their
breasts or get new ones.
They get hair implants.
They change their face, even
their skin color.
You're telling me that in the
wake of the year 2000,
you're not capable of performing
a simple operation
and fix this...
- this shit?
- It's not that simple, Csar.
- Remember that...
- Don't talk to me like that!
Don't treat me like a kid!
I'm not just any patient,
and this isn't Social Security.
I'm willing to pay whatever is
necessary.
You're the boss here.
They say you're the best in your
specialty.
Then make something up, damn it.
Experiment with me.
I've seen patients
who've lost all of their
functions.
Who can't even speak.
At least you can look yourself
in the eye.
What's the point of that?
I want to die
every time I look in the mirror.
Your case isn't so severe.
You just have to learn to accept
yourself.
And who's going to accept me?
Tell that to the people
who look at me on the street!
Are you going to tell everyone
that looks don't matter?
That beauty is inside?
I'd like you to see something.
- What's this?
- A facial prosthesis.
We resort to it in cases of
extreme rejection,
like yours.
This is bullshit.
It's not the best solution.
But it's all we can do
for the time being.
I want a face! Not a mask.
We're not miracle workers.
That's what the fucker told me.
But in the end, they did it.
- What?
- They worked a miracle.
- So it seems.
- "So it seems"?
Things just are or are not. They
either did it or not.
I'm really tired. Why don't you
just go?
I'll be back next Tuesday.
Should I bring you anything?
- No.
- Okay, then. Until Tuesday.
A notepad and a pencil.
But don't say I asked for them.
I don't want to owe them
anything.
Have I changed that much?
Because I can recognize you.
- How are you?
- How am I?
You're playing a part right now,
but I don't know which one.
Your mouth is smiling, but your
eyes are trembling.
Nonsense.
Truth is, you're very good. A
good actress, I mean.
I asked you how you were. You
don't have to answer.
Well, I'm alive.
How do you expect me to be? And
tired.
Tired of waiting for you to
call,
at least to say, "You had really
bad luck, man."
- I've been really busy.
- Bullshit.
I was afraid you'd be
uncomfortable
if I called you.
No, you were afraid you'd be
uncomfortable.
You were afraid you wouldn't be
able to look at me, like now.
That's not true.
Sometimes, I've dreamt of this
moment.
Which moment?
The moment we saw each other
again.
In my dreams, we were just like
now. Like this.
In the park. Although, well...
there was something different.
Was there?
In my dreams, it doesn't rain.
I have to go, Csar.
What are you doing tomorrow
night?
Studying. I've got a lot of
work.
It's Friday tomorrow. We could
hang out.
I don't know. Like I said, I'm
busy.
Okay, then. See you.
Csar!
We can hang out if you want.
If you want.
The client is put
in a maintenance capsule,
while the legal process for his
or her transportation
is worked out.
In the warehouse in Arizona,
United States,
a team of specialists prepares
the body
to be frozen...
which substitutes blood for a
liquid solution
that allows for the preservation
of organs.
The client is put
in the capsule,
where he or she will remain
until medicine
allows for his resuscitation.
Honestly, I'd think it over a
couple of times.
It's a proposal that's hard to
take in.
How should we approach it?
Surely, we find ourselves
in the face of an unprecedented
event.
A new challenge for humankind.
It's understandable that the
first reaction
is that of rejection.
Now we have the means to do it.
We have the technology.
But above all, we have enough
moral maturity
to understand what this step
means
in human evolution,
to look into the future and end
with certain taboos
that no longer make sense.
Inherited from ancient religions
and old, useless memories.
Thanks for being on our show.
Thank you too, for...
- Hey.
- What is that?
- I know, it's a bummer, right?
But I was advised to wear it
because of infections.
Sure.
What's up, dude? What's going on
in your life?
I spend every fucking day
arguing with doctors.
- You should go out more.
- I'm trying.
- What are you drinking?
- Rum and Coke. Want some?
- Okay.
- I'll get it for you.
- I'll go to the restroom.
- Okay.
- Dude, take that off.
- Why?
Because, can't you see? Try as
you might,
you won't be able to hide your
face.
I told you it's so I won't get
an infection.
Sure.
Dude, if I'm embarrassing you,
you can just go.
No one asked you to come.
Sofa asked me to.
What?
She didn't want to be alone with
you.
Why not?
Dude, you're giving her a hard
time.
Because I'm having a hard time!
Tell that to a therapist, or to
me.
You don't have to tell that
to a girl you've only known for
a night.
Is that what she told you?
- That bitch.
- Csar, come here.
Can I have a scotch and Coke?
What scotch?
- Excuse me?
- What scotch?
Why don't you say that
while looking at my face,
motherfucker?
Ballantine's.
- Another one.
- This one's on me.
- Why?
- Because.
Change that mask, dude.
- Hey.
- Where were you?
- Around.
Pelayo went looking for you.
Whereas I was looking for you.
What for?
Nothing in particular.
Just to... buy you a drink.
- Do you want a drink?
- No, thanks.
Is it too obvious I'm hitting on
you?
I just have a little problem.
A woman's harassing me and I
need to bother someone
to get rid of her. Shit!
Shit! She's coming here.
Don't look, don't look.
You just keep talking. Pretend
that we're...
I mean, act like I'm here.
Keep talking... Blah, blah,
blah.
What a nice conversation we're
having.
So, here we are.
Just talking about life...
That's enough, please.
- Where were you?
- Around.
I'm going to go. I'm exhausted.
You guys stay if you want.
This is where I leave you, guys.
I'll drive you.
No, I live close by. I'll walk.
- My bike's right here.
- No, thanks.
- Why not?
- You don't have to.
Don't be so annoying.
- She wants to go by herself.
- Shut up, you're drunk.
I may be drunk, but I'm not an
idiot.
Besides, I'm not drunk.
Seriously, you don't have to
come with me.
- Okay, suit yourself.
- You're the one who's drunk.
We'll call you to hang out some
other day.
Okay.
We could go to the movies.
- More often.
- Okay. Great.
Okay, then.
No, don't kiss me.
I'll intoxicate you with my
drunken breath.
Okay. I'll see you around, then.
Sure. I'll see you around.
I'll see you...
It's not cold at all.
Okay.
- I think I'm going to go.
- Where are you going?
I just remembered I left my bike
somewhere else.
Hold on, I'll go with you.
No, what for? You're almost
home, man.
Come on. See you tomorrow.
Pelayo, hold on a second.
- What?
- It's just...
- I don't know, it's just...
- Dude, you've drank too much.
We'll talk tomorrow.
When I wake up tomorrow, I'll
wish I were dead.
Of course you won't. Get some
rest, you need it.
Pelayo...
You're my best friend, man.
Son of a bitch.
Open your eyes.
Csar.
It's me.
Sofa.
- What are you doing here?
- I'm sorry.
What for?
I love you.
Come here.
What's wrong?
Nothing. I just can't believe
this is really happening.
What about Pelayo?
I don't know. He left with you,
didn't he?
Yeah, right.
Come here.
God. What a feeling.
What do you mean?
Don't you ever feel
like you've already lived a
moment?
- Yes.
- Why do you think that is?
They say it's a glitch in your
brain.
I've been here before.
It usually lasts a few seconds.
Then it goes away.
I don't want it to go away.
I see you haven't wasted time.
It's all I have in here.
Gorgeous. Is it Sofa?
How much longer will I be here?
You can't ever be sure.
I'd never imagined a place like
this. It's a nightmare.
It's a psychiatric correctional
facility.
I shouldn't be here.
I remind you you've been charged
with murder.
- I don't even know what I did.
- Tell me.
Does the name Ellie ring a bell?
Ellie?
Do you know any girl with that
name?
No, why do you ask?
A couple of guards mentioned
that last night you kept
repeating it.
- I must have been dreaming.
- What do you dream of?
- I don't remember.
- It might be important.
Why would it be?
Let's see.
I can prove you didn't know what
you were doing,
but I need an explanation
for all this mess, whatever it
is.
There's no explanation. I told
you the other day.
What did you dream of?
I don't know.
I only remember bits and pieces.
First, I'm in some kind of
office.
A secretary leads me to a study.
There's a picture there of a
sunset and a man.
Then...
I don't know.
I'm shown a bunch of papers.
What papers?
I don't know.
But I sign them.
This office you're in, is it
your company's?
No, I don't think so.
So you've dreamt of a place
you've never been before.
Well, yeah. That happens a lot,
right?
Could those papers be
the ones you signed with the
doctors?
No, the thing with the doctors
was surreal.
Why?
They asked me to go to the
hospital one day.
When I get there, the whole
surgical team is there
to welcome me.
For months...
they had stared at me,
torn between indifference and
helplessness.
Now they were all smiles and
kindness.
That same motherfucker who said
my case was impossible
started explaining something
about a surgery.
They'd brought a new system to
the clinic.
Something groundbreaking.
In just half a month, they said
I could walk out of there
with a fully recomposed face.
You didn't believe them?
Not at first.
I thought it was just a show to
take more money from me.
But they showed me all the
paraphernalia
they had for the surgery.
It seemed like science fiction.
I only saw wires, buttons,
monitors.
Truth is, I never knew
exactly what they would do to
me,
but I thought I had nothing to
lose.
Those people were used
to rhinoplasties, liposuctions,
micro hair grafting,
but my surgery was much more
than that.
In less than a week, my life had
taken
a 180 degree turn.
One night, I was on the floor,
drunk,
wishing I was dead...
and the next morning, my
wishes started to come true.
Like in movies.
Sofa loves me and doctors find
a miraculous formula.
I don't know. It makes sense I
didn't trust them.
Didn't trust who? Didn't trust
what?
- I don't know.
- Life has many turns.
Happiness comes when you least
expect it.
I once met a guy who was
completely alone,
and suddenly, he was married
with two daughters.
Jeez. That's your idea of
happiness?
Well, that depends on each
person.
What's happiness to you?
Don't ask me that kind of
bullshit.
But in those days, you were
happy, weren't you?
So what? My life is shit now.
All I can do is eat, take a
dump, sleep
and dream of my memories.
It's good that you remember.
- How's it going?
- What do you mean?
Don't be silly. You said they'd
remove your plates today.
- And they did.
- So?
Well, my ears are where they
should be.
Csar, don't scare me.
Take the plates off.
You take them off.
But how did they do it?
Hold on.
I just want to tell you that I
love you.
You're going too fast...
considering we met yesterday.
Yesterday?
My birthday was yesterday,
remember?
I met an incredible girl. Her
name's Sofa.
But today I woke up perfectly
fine,
and now I'm with this girl
again.
What is it?
If you want me to move, you have
to insert a coin.
Cling.
It's curious. We never
appreciate
the good moments until they're
gone.
Maybe that's why they're good.
Because we don't stop to think
about them.
Maybe.
What happened with Pelayo?
What is it?
Hold on, man.
- Ready.
- About time.
- Do you want anything else?
- No, thanks.
- How are you, Pelayo?
- Okay.
How are you, Pelayo?
- I'm okay.
- Are you sure?
Believe it or not, I'm not as
screwed up as it seems.
I'm used to you winning all the
time, you bastard.
Besides, Sofa's no big deal.
You said she was the one.
Are you sure?
- I must've been drunk.
- Okay.
Besides, we're friends, right?
You bastard.
Dude, what's with your face?
What?
Damn, your stitches are
bursting.
What?
You're retarded.
No!
What's wrong?
I hate dreaming.
You're tickling me.
What is it?
What are you doing?
- Where's Sofa?
- What?
What did you do with Sofa?
- I'm Sofa.
- You bitch!
- You're crazy.
- Where is she?
In a moment, I'll call the
police.
You'll have lots of trouble if
Sofa doesn't turn up.
So you survived the accident.
What accident?
Whose body was it they found?
I didn't have an accident.
No, it wasn't an accident. It
was attempted murder.
Too bad you didn't see my face
after that, bitch.
Why are doing this to me? What
does it change?
Nothing.
You're the same psycho who
crashed my party
to ruin my life.
I'm the same one you made love
to
a while ago. I'm Sofa.
Don't ever say you're Sofa
again, okay?
Don't ever say that name again!
You won't tell me where she is?
You'll never tell me.
Csar...
I love you.
- Hey.
- What's up?
You may go. I'll continue with
him.
Okay, let's see if I make myself
clear.
- Where were you last night?
- At my house.
I already told him.
At your house... with whom?
With a girl.
The girl I questioned before?
No, that's another one.
I was with Sofa.
The girl I talked to is called
Sofa.
That's what she says, but it's a
lie.
Who is she, then?
- She's... Nuria.
- Nuria?
Nuria who?
I don't know, she never told me
her last name.
Then...
you were at your house with a
girl called Sofa.
- And suddenly...
- I go to the bathroom,
and when I get back, she's in
Sofa's place.
- Where is Sofa now?
- Ask Nuria.
She's posing as Sofa!
Okay.
You don't know her last name?
What's wrong? Who are you going
to believe?
Her or me?
All I can say is that the girl's
papers
are in order. We've let her go.
You let her go?
And I can assure you her name is
Sofa.
Sofa Cueto.
She lives at 2 Quiroz Street,
second on the left.
- No.
- What do you mean, no?
I mean, yes, but that's another
girl.
I'm telling you I know the real
Sofa.
And I'm asking you to tell me
where she is.
Because where law is concerned,
that girl you're talking about
doesn't exist except in your
imagination.
I can't believe this is
happening.
On the other hand,
the girl had signs of having
been beaten up.
She was at my house, posing as
my girlfriend!
For some reason I can't
understand,
she didn't want to press
charges.
I can't believe it.
So now she's the victim.
Listen.
- Do you take drugs?
- God.
We know you underwent
psychiatric treatment recently.
Because I had an accident that
wrecked my face.
She caused it!
From what I see, your face looks
just fine.
Because...
It doesn't matter. I won't keep
talking to you.
Young man.
I advise you to see a
psychiatrist.
What's wrong with you?
What the fuck is your deal?
- What are you talking about?
- If you wanted to dump her,
you didn't have to do all this,
you son of a bitch!
Don't ever touch Sofa again!
She's not Sofa, she's Nuria!
- Nuria is dead!
- Okay.
Calm down unless you want to
spend the night in a cell!
Don't ever talk to me in your
fucking life, asshole.
I don't know what they told you,
but I swear Nuria is more alive
than we are.
They didn't tell me anything,
Sofa did.
Listen to me.
You talked to her on the phone,
right?
- Let go of me.
- She's not Sofa, Pelayo.
Nuria can imitate her voice!
She's got her documents and even
her apartment.
She didn't tell me on the phone,
dumbass.
I just dropped her off at her
home.
And she was just like this girl.
Nice picture, right?
Are you going to tell me that
isn't Sofa, either?
But this is...
Are you pulling a prank on me or
what?
Dude, you're not right in the
head.
I'm not right in the head?
You're the ones who are crazy!
- You're all crazy!
- Let go of me!
God... What's happening?
It's my partners, isn't it?
They paid all of you off. This
is a fucking conspiracy!
Look at you, man.
You never regained consciousness
after the accident.
Motherf...
Are you telling me...
Are you telling me this is the
girl
you ran after that night,
motherfucker?
- Is this the one?
- Yeah!
You stole her from me.
You need a shrink!
Troubles?
I'm not in the mood for any
crap.
There's an explanation for all
of this.
Csar.
Who are you?
You must have seen me on TV.
What do you want?
I'm here to help you. First of
all,
it's very important that you
calm down.
Calm down?
You have to conquer your fears
and regain control.
What are you talking about? I'm
perfectly well, you know?
Who said you're not?
Them, everybody.
They say I'm crazy.
No, no. Of course
you're not crazy.
But what if I told you that
you're dreaming?
- No, no.
- And why not?
Look, I know what's real, and
this is real.
How do you know? You don't know
you're dreaming
- until you wake up.
- I just know it.
My dreams are a lot simpler than
this.
There are no simple dreams.
Look at these people.
They seem to be talking about
their stuff, don't they?
Completely unaware of you.
Yet they may be there because
you wanted them to be.
In fact, you could have them...
help you,
or on the contrary, destroy you.
I want them to shut up, and you,
too.
See?
What's happening here?
Someone tell me the truth, damn
it!
The truth... you may not be able
to bear.
It had to be a setup,
some big joke
to drive me crazy.
They were all conspiring. Nuria,
Pelayo, the police,
- the guy from the bar.
- Who was he?
I don't know.
You say you saw him on TV.
- On what show?
- I don't know.
I don't know, one about freezing
dead people.
Freezing dead people?
Cryonics or something.
Like what they did to Walt
Disney.
I may be able to help you
remember.
Is that a threat?
Lie down.
- What's that?
- A syringe.
Don't worry.
My arm itches.
- It's just a sedative.
- What for?
All of this is a tall tale.
If you had trusted
therapists a bit more,
perhaps now you wouldn't be
where you are.
What's that?
- You're making me nervous.
- You don't have to be afraid.
I'm not afraid.
Stop talking and focus. Come on.
Okay... I'm getting dizzy.
Bye, Csar.
Very well. Now,
let's see if you'll tell me
about that dream.
Dream...
In my dream, it's not raining.
The dream about the office.
- Ellie.
- That's right.
Tell me who Ellie is.
A secretary.
Ellie is a secretary?
She tells me to go in.
They're waiting for me.
Who is?
That French guy from TV.
Hello. Please sit down.
A contract. Ellie.
Csar, who is Ellie?
You won't regret it. Sign here.
What do you have to sign?
Leave it to Ellie.
What have you signed?
What's wrong?
What's wrong, Csar? Why are you
crying?
I'm going to die.
You're not.
- I don't know how many.
- How many what?
Pills.
Hold on. You were taking pills?
I don't know how many I
should take.
You took pills to feel better?
I don't want to...
On three, you're
going to wake up.
One, two...
I thought up until now you'd
told me the truth.
What do you mean?
You said you weren't taking
anything.
Csar, I'm going to ask you one
last time.
- Did you take drugs?
- Jeez.
Why does everyone insist...
Don't make a fuss as usual, and
tell me the truth.
I have to know what you were
taking.
- I didn't take anything.
- Can't you see?
Your brain may have suffered
some kind of disorder
because of the pills.
I didn't take any pills!
You said you did just a moment
ago!
It's just a dream. Why do you
give it
more importance than it has?
Can't you tell apart dreams from
reality?
I can!
Really? Don't make me laugh.
People rising from the dead?
Living people disappearing?
You, turning into the Phantom of
the Opera?
Tell me one thing.
Do you also remember what you
did to Sofa?
- It wasn't Sofa.
- I don't care who she was.
What did you do to her?
Do you remember?
Oh my God.
What are you doing here? I
thought you were a thief.
Who are you?
- I'm Sofa.
- Sofa?
You're not Sofa.
Csar, all of this will be over
soon.
We'll be together again.
You'll forget Nuria and I won't
be afraid of you.
- Then...
- I'll get some water.
Sofa.
Yes, Csar, I'm Sofa.
I'm Sofa.
I want to see you! I want to see
you!
I want to see you!
Sometimes, you dream you're with
someone.
For instance, your father.
And in just a few seconds, he
becomes your mother.
And then... the newspaper seller
from the corner.
And yet, you feel
you're talking to the same
person.
And although you thought you
were home, suddenly,
you realize you're at school...
or in a hospital, or in jail.
Dreams are like that.
And sometimes, your mind behaves
as if in a dream.
Do you know what alienation is?
Don't give me that crap. Tell me
I'm crazy if you want,
but this isn't alienation.
Then what is it? Tell me,
because I don't know.
I don't know what's inside here,
I don't know why you killed your
girlfriend,
I don't know who Ellie
or that man from the TV are. I
know nothing.
That makes two of us.
Will you keep coming after the
trials?
I thought you didn't like me.
What will you testify?
Why are you asking me that?
The first hearing is next week.
Temporary mental alienation.
I think it's the least harmful
for you.
It won't do much good, anyway.
They won't believe me that
easily.
Even I don't believe it.
What do you think?
I think you're very sick,
and you should stay here for a
long time.
Don't worry.
They'll give me 20 years, at
least.
Csar, believe it or not, I care
about you a lot.
Look, kid, I'm interested in
your case.
I'm sorry for what happened.
I've even come to think
someone's gaslighting you.
But I can't and I shouldn't
overstep my role.
- I'm a psychiatrist.
- You don't sound like one.
- What do I sound like?
- My father.
- Lecturing me all day.
- Your father is dead.
That's what I mean.
By the way, what happened to
that happy father
with his two daughters and his
beloved wife?
I don't know. I never saw him
again.
Listen to me. Hire a lawyer.
Bye, Csar.
Bye.
The main Spanish investment,
but the most original and
emblematic.
He's got more
economic presence...
depending on the period.
In the Roman Empire, for
instance, the normal thing
was to live only 25 years.
No!
Who's got the remote? Who's got
the remote?
Give it to me!
It's another way of giving
people
what they've been looking for
for thousands of years.
What's wrong?
There's a computer with internet
access in the Infirmary.
I asked to use it,
but you have to come with me.
Why do you want that?
I know what Ellie is. Let's go!
Hold on!
Ellie isn't a person.
It's a company, damn it.
How do you know?
"Ellie" is actually "I.E."
It's an American company.
What are you doing now?
There's a program online to
trace acronyms.
We'll find information about
I.E.
Shit.
- We have to check one by one.
- Hold on.
Life extension.
Damn it. I have the feeling I've
done this same thing
before.
That's because of a brain
dysfunction,
- a brain glitch.
- No, not this time.
God.
This is it.
The photo you dreamt of?
I can't have dreamt about it
without having seen it first,
right?
Cryonix. It's a cryonics
company.
I'll print it out.
Hold on. I'm lost now.
I don't understand what this has
to do
- with your case.
- Here's the key.
Look. There's a branch in
Madrid.
Okay.
- I'll go take a look.
- No, I have to go with you.
I can't get you out of here.
I know sometimes they
release you under custody.
Make something up so they'll let
me.
- It's not that easy.
- You can do it.
You know more than you're
letting on.
I know nothing. I just have a
feeling.
What is it?
I have to go there, no matter
what.
I'm going to be very clear.
We're not at the hospital
anymore. I'm armed,
and my mission is to stop you
from doing something silly,
so if you do, I'll shoot you in
the ribs.
I've been here before.
- Follow me.
- Let's go.
You've got 20 minutes.
It's all like in my dream.
Hello, good morning. How may I
help you?
We'd like to talk to Mr.
Duvernois.
This is my son.
He's just really shy.
Mr. Duvernois isn't here right
now.
But first of all,
you already know what cryonics
are.
More or less.
Here are some explanatory
leaflets.
You can read them in the waiting
room.
One of my colleagues will be
with you shortly.
Thank you.
"Live limitlessly.
The future is for the
foresighted."
What is this? Some kind of cult?
"Cryonics."
It's the Biostasis or
preservation of humans
under cold temperatures.
Biostasis is the bridge to take
our patients
to a time in the future when
technology
"will allow for their
resuscitation."
You pay to live forever.
Jules Verne was laughed at, too.
Csar, all of this is absolutely
impossible.
How do you know? Have you been
to the future?
This company promises the same
thing the Church has
for centuries.
Immortality. Only instead of
priests, they are quacks.
What's that got to do with you?
You're not cryogenized. You're
alive.
Here's the contract, if you want
to look at it.
The process is very simple.
You can die anytime.
Today, tomorrow or in 20 years.
We don't care about that.
From the moment
you're pronounced legally dead,
Life Extension takes over your
body and takes it
to our warehouse in Arizona.
There, you're frozen at 108.4
degrees below zero.
This is what we call total
suspension,
and it costs $240,000, from
which...
thirty thousand is allocated
to the freezing process,
and the rest is placed in an
investment fund
so the interest can cover the
maintenance costs
and the resuscitation costs when
this becomes possible.
If it becomes possible.
Frankly, we believe
resuscitating dead people
will be possible someday.
- What's this?
- What?
Clause 14. Artificial
perception.
Yes, that's another possibility
we haven't fully developed yet.
Look. This is a life.
Birth and death.
Imagine you suffer from a
terminal disease.
Naturally, you want to keep on
living,
but you don't wish to live in
the future.
You're not interested. You want
to keep on living
your current life, in the
present.
Okay, so you die, we freeze you,
and when we're capable of
resuscitating you,
we commit to make you live...
a dream.
A dream?
We'll reenact everything so it
seems real.
Your family members, your
friends, your city,
the whole world, including this
office.
But it'll be just a virtual
reality.
Besides, we'll make sure you
don't remember dying.
Or signing this contract, of
course.
- How?
- Very simple.
By erasing it from your memory.
Thus, you'll live linearly, as
if nothing had happened.
And you'll live it as you see
fit.
At will.
You will decide at all times.
But... what would happen if
there was a glitch?
What if the dream...
What if the dream became a
nightmare?
Your subconscious can always
play
a dirty trick on you, but...
we're not sloppy, you know.
We're a serious company, and the
VR technology
progresses by leaps and bounds.
Look... honestly,
signing clause 14 is basically
signing up for paradise.
I know it's hard to believe.
But Jules Verne was laughed at,
too, wasn't he?
Excuse me.
Where do you think you're going?
- To the restroom.
- I'll keep an eye on you.
I'm with him.
He's dizzy, there's nothing to
worry about.
Csar, please calm down.
This is a dream.
It's the only explanation.
It's not a dream. What he said
is impossible.
It's impossible now, not in the
30th century!
This isn't the 30th century!
- This is 1997.
- That's what it seems.
- It's what I paid for.
- Listen.
This isn't a dream. Look at me.
If this is a dream, I don't have
a life of my own, I'm a lie!
- You're only in my head.
- No!
- Csar, I'm real.
- How do I know that?
Can't you tell dreams from
reality?
Does this look like a dream?
Tell me, does it?
I'm working very hard on this
case.
I'm risking...
I haven't killed anyone. It's
all a nightmare!
Trust me, damn it!
- It's not a dream.
- They're wrong.
- Who?
- I don't know, damn it.
Those who programmed this
confused Sofa with Nuria!
They're not showing me my real
face!
I'm sick of hearing that. Your
face is perfectly fine.
The guard is right. You act like
a child
hiding behind that mask.
What game are you playing? Take
that off already.
- I don't want to.
- I don't care what you want.
- I want to see you.
- Don't you realize?
It doesn't matter what you see,
but what I see!
It's my dream!
If you say it's a dream again,
I'll have you committed.
Enough of that. Show me your
face now.
You owe me that.
Csar, please look yourself in
the mirror
and tell me if you really think
you're disfigured.
God, why do you insist on seeing
something that's not there?
- You're perfectly fine.
- I'm a monster.
What are you talking about?
Many would trade their face for
yours.
You're completely normal. Forget
normal!
- You're handsome!
- No!
Csar, listen to me. Maybe what
you're going through
- is like anorexia.
- No.
Some girls insist on believing
they're fat,
- and they end up going crazy!
- No!
Csar!
I want to wake up!
Shit!
- Stand still!
- Don't shoot!
It's a nightmare.
Hold on a second, you! You can't
get out of here!
Stop!
Hey, hold on!
It's a dream.
Don't move!
Drop the weapon!
I want to wake up.
- Don't move!
- I want to wake up!
I want to wake up! I want to
wake up!
Antonio.
- Antonio.
- What?
You're crushing me.
I think I shouldn't move,
considering
I've been shot in my back.
How do you know that?
Well...
because...
What the hell is going on here?
- Damn it!
- I told you.
- It's all a dream.
- Shut up.
Okay.
I know what this is.
It's one of those hidden camera
pranks from TV.
Very good, seriously! You've
done an awesome job,
I loved it, but that's enough!
- There's someone there.
- Where?
- Up there, on the rooftop.
- I don't see anyone.
Where are you going?
Come on, Antonio, stop going
round and round.
Otherwise, you'll go crazy.
Hello, Csar.
I think it's about time I
introduce myself.
My name is Serge Duvernois.
I'm a Life Extension
representative.
We met... 150 years ago.
That's nonsense!
Has the entire world gone mad?
There is no world.
Everything that exists is inside
this man's mind.
- Including you and me.
- Sure.
I'll kick your ass and see if it
hurts.
Try it.
They can make you disappear
right now, like every other
person.
And may I ask who "they" are?
They are the company, Life
Extension.
They know everything we're
saying,
they even know what's going
through Csar's mind right now,
an instant after he thinks about
it.
Then tell me.
Why haven't they made me
disappear yet?
It would be virtually incorrect.
Considering you just saved his
life.
"Virtually incorrect"?
Do you think I'm an idiot?
No, on the contrary. You're a
great guy.
And a very necessary character
for Csar.
A character.
Where are you going?
- To look for someone.
- There's no one left.
People are no longer necessary.
Why didn't you wake me up
before?
You just had to ask.
Of course, this was extremely
difficult,
since technically, you weren't
supposed to know
you were dreaming.
Since when?
Remember that day at the club?
That night, when you fell asleep
on the sidewalk,
was the one chosen to make the
connection.
What connection?
The connection
between your real life and your
virtual one.
A connection lasting 150 years,
whose passing you didn't feel
because you were dead and
frozen.
When you woke up, nothing was
real anymore.
We erased what actually happened
from your memory.
What actually happened?
You never saw Sofa again.
And the doctors were never able
to reconstruct your face.
You woke up on that street with
an awful hangover.
You locked yourself up in your
place for months.
Until one day, you learned of
our existence.
You came to the office, you
signed the contract, and...
you killed yourself.
And I paid for this?
I paid for Nuria to be
resuscitated as Sofa?
I paid for my face to be
monstrous again?
I paid to live this nightmare?
You paid to live whatever you
wanted to.
We just added the setting and
the characters.
Your hell was of your own
invention.
I tried to warn you at that bar.
I told you everything depended
on your mind.
I just have to wish for it.
For instance, can Antonio come
back now?
There's no one in the building!
You couldn't have made four
million people disappear!
You've overcome your fears.
If you want, we can give it
another try
and make you like the best of
dreams,
with money, with friends, with
Sofa
or any girl you want.
You just have to ask.
- I don't want to dream anymore.
- It's not a dream!
Csar, listen to me.
This is real. This guy is a
fraud.
Let's go find people on the
street.
Don't listen to him. It makes
sense he acts this way,
but it's all a show. In reality,
he feels nothing.
I feel nothing?
I feel nothing, you son of a
bitch?
What do you know?
Don't listen to him. He's not
real.
Yes, I am real!
I have a wife and two daughters.
His personality was designed so
that he will say
what he's saying right now.
Where are my daughters?
God.
Csar, the company
offers you another chance.
In 1997, it was impossible to
reconstruct your face.
But out there, it's the year
2145.
You wouldn't believe the things
surgery can do.
If you want, you can wake up and
live in the future
like a normal person.
- In the future?
- You have to choose.
How could I wake up?
How would you wake up from your
worst nightmare?
No, Csar, stop listening to
him!
It's all set up by your
partners!
They want you to kill yourself!
He already killed himself once.
It'll be a mere formality now.
I'm going to do it.
Okay. Any wishes before...
you die?
That people out there can read
my mind.
- Who are you?
- I don't know.
Don't suffer anymore. It's all
in your head.
It's all psychological.
Come on, Csar.
What will happen to them once I
wake up?
Extending this goodbye is
useless.
You think they're your friends,
but they're just images.
That man isn't really crying.
I didn't remember that I suffer
from vertigo.
Then don't look.
Goodbye, Csar.
No!
Easy.
Open your eyes.