Don't grieve, Admiral.
It is logical.
The needs of the many outweigh...
...the needs of the few.
Or the one.
I have been and always shall be your friend.
Live long and prosper.
We are assembled here today to pay final respects to our honoured dead.
This death takes place in the shadow of new life,
the sunrise of a new world.
A world that our beloved comrade gave his life to protect.
He did not feel this sacrifice a vain or empty one.
Of my friend, I can only say this:
Of all the souls I have encountered in my travels,
his was the most...
...human.
Honours. Hup!
Space, the final frontier.
These are the continuing voyages of the Starship Enterprise.
Her ongoing mission to explore strange new worlds.
To seek out new lifeforms and new civilisations.
To boldly go...
...where no man has gone before.
USS Enterprise, Captain's Personal Log.
With most of our battle damage repaired, we're almost home.
Yet I feel uneasy. And I wonder why.
Perhaps it is the emptiness of this vessel.
Most of our trainee crew has been reassigned.
Lieutenant Saavik and my son David
are exploring the Genesis planet, which he helped create.
And Enterprise feels like a house with all the children gone.
No, more empty even than that.
The death of Spock is like an open wound.
It seems that I've left the noblest part of myself back there...
...on that newborn planet.
Status, Mr Sulu. On course, Admiral.
Estimating space dock in 2.1 hours.
Very well. Mr Chekov, I'll need a pre-approach scan.
Take the science station, please. Yes, sir.
Uhura... Any response from Starfleet on our Project Genesis enquiries?
No, sir, there is no response. That's very odd.
Scotty, progress report. It's almost done, sir.
You'll be fully automated by the time we dock.
Excellent timing. You fixed the barn door after the horse has come home.
How much refit time till we can take her out again?
Eight weeks, sir. But you don't have eight weeks, so I'll do it in two.
Have you always multiplied your repair estimates by a factor of four?
Certainly, sir. How else can I keep my reputation as a miracle worker?
Your reputation is secure, Scotty.
Mr Sulu, take the Con. I'll be in my quarters.
Sir?
Are they planning a ceremony when we get in?
I mean, a reception? Would you like a hero's welcome?
Well, God knows there should be.
This time we've paid for the party with our dearest blood.
Steady. Steady, boys.
Keep scanning.
I thought you people were reliable. Where the hell is he?
He's been here for some time. Put me on hailing frequency.
Commander Kruge... This is Valkris.
I have purchased the Genesis data. Ready to transmit.
Well done, Valkris.
What the hell is...
Disengage cloaking device!
Transmit data. Now!
Transmission completed.
You will find it useful.
Then you have seen it?
I have, my Lord.
Unfortunate.
Understood.
Thrusters.
What the hell's going on? When do I get paid off?
Soon, Captain. Quite soon.
Success, my Lord... and my love.
You will be remembered with honour.
Fire!
New course. Federation neutral zone.
Feed him!
Yes, my Lord.
Approach Control, this is Enterprise, ready for docking manoeuvre.
Enterprise is cleared to dock. Lock on.
Systems locked.
Spacedock, you have control. Affirmative, Enterprise.
Enjoy the ride, and welcome home. Enterprise confirms.
Acknowledge, doors closed.
Would you look at that!
My friends, the great experiment.
The Excelsior. Ready for trial runs.
She's supposed to have transwarp drive.
And if my grandmother had wheels, she'd be a wagon.
Young minds, fresh ideas. Be tolerant, Mr Scott.
Standby umbilical and gravitational support systems.
Aye, sir, moorings activated, all systems standing by.
Admiral. This is not possible. Mr Chekov.
An energy reading from 'C' deck, from inside Mr Spock's quarters.
I ordered Spock's quarters sealed. I sealed the room myself!
Nevertheless, I am reading a lifeform there.
This entire crew seems on the edge of obsessive behaviour regarding Spock.
Sir, Security reports the door to Spock's quarters has been forced.
I'm on my way. Sulu, continue docking procedures.
Jim...
Help me.
You left me on Genesis. Why did you do that?
Bones!
What the hell are you doing?
Have you lost your mind?
Help me, Jim. Take me home.
Bones, we are. We are home.
Then perhaps it's not too late.
Climb the steps, Jim.
Climb the steps of Mount Seleya.
Mount Seleya?
Bones, Mount Seleya's on Vulcan. We're home... on Earth.
Remember.
Admiral, docking is completed.
Starfleet Commander Morrow is on his way for inspection.
Uhura, get the medics down here! Get them now!
You've all done remarkable service under the most difficult conditions.
You'll be receiving Starfleet's highest commendation.
And more importantly... extended shore leave.
All but you, Mr Scott. They need your wisdom on the new Excelsior.
Report there tomorrow as Captain of Engineering.
With all appreciation, I'd prefer to supervise the refit of Enterprise.
I'm afraid that won't be necessary.
But, sir...
I'm sorry, Mr Scott, but there will be no refit.
Admiral... I don't understand. The Enterprise is not...
Jim, the Enterprise is 20 years old. We feel her day is over.
But we had requested...
We had hoped to take her back to Genesis.
That is out of the question. May I ask why?
In your absence, Genesis has become a galactic controversy.
Until the Federation Council makes policy,
you are all under orders not to discuss with anyone
your knowledge of Genesis.
Consider it a quarantine planet... and a forbidden subject.
To understand the events on which I report, it is necessary to review
the theoretical data on the Genesis device,
as developed by Doctors Carol and David Marcus.
Genesis, simply put, is life from lifelessness.
The device was to be introduced into a pre-selected area
of a lifeless space body, a moon or other dead form.
The device would instantaneously cause the Genesis efect.
Instead of a dead moon, a living, breathing planet now exists,
capable of sustaining whatever life forms we see fit to deposit on it.
So?
Speak.
Great power to control, dominate.
Speak. Impressive.
They can make a planet.
Oh, yes. New cities, homes in the country.
Your woman at your side, children playing at your feet.
And overhead, fluttering in the breeze, the flag of the Federation!
Charming.
Station. Yes, my Lord.
Share this with no one. Understood, my Lord.
We are going to this planet.
Even as our emissaries negotiate for peace with the Federation,
we will act for the preservation of our race.
We will seize the secret of this weapon.
The secret of ultimate power!
Success, my Lord.
We have reached the destination planet at point 035.
Very well, Lieutenant. Helm.
Execute standard orbital approach.
Send a coded message for Starfleet Commander, Priority One.
"Federation science vessel Grissom arriving Genesis, Mutara Sector,"
"to begin research. J.T. Esteban commanding."
Dr Marcus, it's your planet.
Begin scanning, please.
This is where the fun begins, Saavik.
Just like your father, so human.
All units functional. Recorders are on. Scanning Sector 1.
The foliage in fully developed state of growth. Temperature 22.2 Celsius.
Sector 2 indicating desert terrain. Minimal vegetation. Temperature 39.4.
Sector 3, sub-tropical vegetation.
Temperature decreasing rapidly.
It's snow. Snow in the same sector. Fantastic!
Fascinating.
All the varieties of land and weather known to Earth, within hours' walk.
Metallic mass. Close range scan.
A photon tube.
Gravitational fields were in flux. It must have soft landed.
In code to Starfleet:
"Captain Spock's tube located on Genesis surface."
I don't believe it.
What is it?
If equipment is functioning properly, indications are an animal lifeform.
You said there wouldn't be any. There shouldn't be.
Cross referenced and verified. An unidentifiable lifeform reading.
You wish to advise Starfleet, sir?
We don't know what we're talking about here.
Why don't we beam it up? Oh, no.
Regulations state, "Nothing shall be beamed aboard"
"until danger of contamination is eliminated."
Captain, beaming down to the surface is permitted.
If the Captain decides that the mission is vital and reasonably safe.
Please, we must see what it is. Or who.
Absent friends.
Admiral, what's going to happen to the Enterprise?
She's to be decommissioned. Will we get another ship?
I can't get an answer. Starfleet's up to its brass in galactic conference.
No one has time for those who stand and wait.
Sir, about Dr McCoy, how is he?
He's home, resting comfortably, pumped full of tranquilizers.
They say it's exhaustion. He promised he'd stay put. We'll see.
Ah, Mr Scott.
Come.
Sarek!
Ambassador, I had no idea you were here. I believe you know my crew.
I will speak with you alone, Kirk.
Please excuse us.
Ambassador, I would have come to Vulcan to express my deep sympathy.
Spare me your human platitudes, Kirk. I have been to your Government.
I have seen the Genesis information, and your own report.
Then you know how bravely your son met his death.
Why did you leave him on Genesis?
Spock trusted you. And you denied him his future.
I saw no future. Only his body was in death, Kirk.
And you were the last one to be with him.
Then you must know that you should have come with him to Vulcan.
But why? Because he asked you to!
He entrusted you...
...with his very essence, with everything that was not of the body!
He asked you to bring him to us.
And to bring that which he gave you: His Katra. His living spirit.
Sir...
Your son meant more to me than you can know.
I'd have given my life if it would have saved his.
Believe me when I tell you... he made no request of me.
He would not have spoken of it openly.
Then how was...
I must have your thoughts. May I join your mind?
Certainly.
He spoke of your friendship.
Yes.
He... asked you not to grieve.
The needs of the many...
...outweigh...
...the needs of the few...
...or the one.
Spock...
I have been...
...and always shall be your friend.
Live long and prosper.
No.
Forgive me.
It is not here.
I had assumed he mind-melded with you.
It is the Vulcan way... when the body's end is near.
We were separated.
He couldn't touch me.
I see.
Then everything that he was...
...everything he knew...
...is lost.
Please wait.
He would have found a way. If there was that much at stake,
Spock would have found a way.
Yes. But how?
What if he joined with someone else?
Engine Room, Flight Recorder Visual. Star date 8128. 78.
Go.
Ship... out of danger?
Yes.
Back, 0.77.
Flight Recorder Visual, 28. 77.
No! You'll flood the whole compartment!
He'll die. Captain! He's dead already.
Back, 0.76.
Flight Recorder Visual, 28. 76.
You're not going in there! Perhaps you're right.
What is Mr Scott's condition? I don't think that he...
Sorry, Doctor, I have no time to discuss this logically.
Freeze.
Repeat... and augment.
Remember...
McCoy!
One alive, one not. Yet both in pain.
What must I do?
You must bring them to Mount Seleya on Vulcan.
Only there can both find peace.
What you ask...
...is difficult.
You will find a way, Kirk.
If you honour them both, you must.
I will.
I swear.
Transporter Room, stand by to energise.
Aye, sir, energising now.
Grissom to Saavik. We're picking up radiation from the lifeform.
Affirmative, Captain. Our readings are well below danger level.
Exercise caution, Lieutenant.
This landing is Captain's discretion, and I'm the one who's out on a limb.
I'll try to remember that.
There are your lifeforms. These were microbes on the tube's surface.
We shot them here from Enterprise. They were fruitful and multiplied.
But how could they have evolved so quickly?
Saavik...
What is it?
Spock's burial robe.
No, absolutely not, Jim. You're my best officer.
But I am Commander, Starfleet, so I don't break rules.
Don't quote rules to me. I'm talking about loyalty and sacrifice.
One man who's died for us, another with deep emotional problems.
This business about Spock and McCoy...
Honestly, I never understood Vulcan mysticism.
You don't have to believe. I'm not even sure that I believe.
But if there's even a chance that Spock has an eternal soul...
...then it's my responsibility. Yours?
As surely as if it were my very own.
Give me back the Enterprise. With Scotty's help I could...
The Enterprise would never stand the pounding, and you know it!
Then I'll hire a ship. Out of the question, my friend.
The Council has ordered that no one but the science team goes to Genesis.
Your life and your career stand for rationality, not intellectual chaos.
Keep up this emotional behaviour and you'll lose everything.
You'll destroy yourself. Do you understand me, Jim?
I hear you.
I had to try.
Of course.
Thanks for the drink. Any time.
The word, sir? The word...
...is no. I am therefore going anyway.
You can count on our help, sir. Shall I alert Dr McCoy?
Please. He has a long journey ahead of him.
Long time, Doc.
Yeah. Anybody been looking for me?
I have, but what's the use? What'll it be?
Altair water. That's not your usual poison.
To expect one to order poison in a bar is not logical.
Got it.
To your planet, welcome.
I think that's my line, stranger. Oh, forgive.
I here am new. But you are known, being McCoy from Enterprise.
You have me at a disadvantage, sir. I name not important.
You seek I. Message received.
Available ship stands by.
How much and how soon?
How soon is now. How much is where.
Somewhere in the Mutara Sector. Oh, Mutara restricted!
Take permits many. Money more.
There aren't going to be any damn permits!
How can you get a permit to do a damn illegal thing?
Look... Price you name, money I got!
Place you name, money I name, otherwise bargain, no.
All right, dammit! Genesis. The name of the place we're going is Genesis!
Genesis?!
Yes, Genesis! How can you be deaf with ears like that?
Genesis allowed is not! It's planet forbidden!
Look, my backward friend. Genesis may be planet forbidden, but I'm...
Sir, I'm sorry. You don't want to be discussing this subject in public.
I'll discuss what I like! And who in the hell are you?!
Would you like a ride home, Dr McCoy?
If I wanted a ride home, would I be trying to charter a space flight?
How in the hell do you know who I am?
Federation Security, sir.
You're gonna get a nice long rest, Doctor.
Saavik to Grissom. We are definitely reading a second lifeform.
We concur. Proceed with caution, Saavik.
What the hell is going on down there?
Be quick, Admiral. They're moving him to the Federation 'Funny Farm'.
Yes, poor friend. I hear he's fruity as a nutcake.
Two minutes.
Jim!
How many fingers do I have up? That's not very damn funny.
Your sense of humour has returned. The hell it has. What's that?
Lexorin. Lexorin? What for?
You're suffering from a Vulcan mind-meld, Doctor.
That green-blooded son-of-a-bitch.
It's his revenge for all those arguments he lost.
Let me see your hand. This will make you well enough to travel.
Where's Admiral Kirk? With the prisoner.
Get him quickly. Commander, Starfleet, wants him right away.
Keeping you busy?
Don't get smart, Tiny.
Admiral, Starfleet... This man's sick. Look.
Side elevator. Agents on their way up.
Don't call me Tiny.
Unit Two, this is unit One.
The Koyabashi Maru has set sail for the promised land.
Message acknowledged. All units will be informed.
You're taking me to the promised land?
What are friends for?
Mr Scott... Calling it a night?
Yes, sir. Turning in myself.
Looking forward to breaking some of Enterprise's speed records tomorrow.
Good night.
Level, please. Transporter Room.
Thank you. Up your shaft!
Roger, Old City Station at 22.00 hours. All is well.
Understood. All stations clear.
You amaze me, Commander.
A 20-year space veteran, you choose the worst duty station in town.
I mean, look at this place! This is the hind end of space.
Peace and quiet appeals to me, Lieutenant.
Maybe that's okay for someone like you, whose career is winding down.
But me, I need some challenge in my life, adventure.
Maybe even just a surprise or two.
Well, you know what they say. Be careful what you wish for.
You may get it.
Good evening, Commander. Is everything ready?
Step into my parlour, gentlemen.
That's Admiral Kirk, my God. Very good for you, Lieutenant.
But it's damn irregular. No destination orders, no encoded IDs.
All true. What are we going to do about it?
I'm not going to do anything, but you're going to sit in the closet.
Have you lost all your sense of reality?
This isn't reality.
This is fantasy. You wanted adventure, how's this?
The old adrenalin going, huh? Good boy.
Now get in the closet.
Go on. Go on! I'll just get in the closet.
Okay!
I'm glad you're on our side. Can you handle that?
I'll have Mr Adventure eating out of my hand, sir.
And I'll see all of you at the rendezvous. And Admiral...
All my hopes.
As promised, she's all yours, sir. All systems automated and ready.
A chimpanzee and two trainees could run her.
Thank you, Mr Scott. I'll try not to take that personally.
My friends, I can't ask you to go any further.
Dr McCoy and I have to do this. The rest of you do not.
Admiral, we're losing precious time.
What course, please, Admiral? Mr Scott?
I'd be grateful, Admiral, if you'd give the word.
Gentlemen... May the wind be at our backs. Stations, please.
Engage auto systems. Aye. Engaged.
Clear all moorings. Cleared, sir.
One quarter impulse power. One quarter impulse.
Commander, Starfleet, on emergency channel.
He orders you to surrender this vessel.
No reply, Chekov. Steady as she goes, Sulu.
Yellow Alert. Captain to the bridge.
This is the Captain. How can you have a Yellow Alert in spacedock?
Sir, someone is stealing the Enterprise.
I'm on my way.
Yellow Alert. All stations, Yellow Alert.
One minute to spacedoors.
Are you gonna walk through them? Calm yourself.
Sir. Excelsior powering up with orders to pursue.
Yellow Alert.
Status.
All automates ready and functioning. Automatic moorings retracted.
All speeds available through Transwarp Drive.
Incredible machine.
Helm. One quarter impulse power.
Thirty seconds to spacedoors.
Warning, secured spacedoors.
And now, Mr Scott. Sir?
The doors, Mr Scott! Aye, sir, I'm workin' on it.
Danger, spacedoors are closed. Danger.
We have cleared spacedoors.
Full impulse power. Aye, sir.
Standby tractor beam. Tractor beam, on.
If he tries to get away with Warp Drive, he's in for a shock.
Excelsior closing to 4,000 metres, sir.
We'll need everything you have. Warp Drive standing by.
Kirk...
If you do this, you'll never sit in the Captain's chair again.
Warp Speed. Aye, sir. Warp Speed.
Prepare for Warp Speed. Stand by Transwarp Drive.
Transwarp at your command. Full power available.
Execute.
...power available.
Full power available.
Transwarp Drive, maximum velocity in five, four, three, two, one.
Scotty, as good as your word.
The more they overtake the plumbing, the easier to stop up the drain.
Here, Doctor, souvenirs from one surgeon to another.
I took them out of her main Transwarp computer drive.
Nice of you to tell me in advance. You missed the staff meeting.
Your work today has been outstanding.
I will recommend you all for promotion...
...in whatever fleet we end up serving. Best speed to Genesis.
I am Saavik. Can you speak?
The Genesis Wave. His cells could have been regenerated.
Captain, this is Saavik. Come in, please.
Yes, Saavik, go ahead. We have found the life sign.
It is a Vulcan child, perhaps eight to ten Earth years of age.
A child?! How did he get there? It is Dr Marcus' opinion that...
...that the Genesis effect has in some way regenerated... Captain Spock.
Saavik, that's... extraordinary. What would you like to do next?
Request permission to beam aboard immediately.
Does Dr Marcus think there's any chance of radioactive contamination?
No. None that he can detect, sir.
I'm going to advise Starfleet and get instructions.
I'm sure Starfleet would approve. But let's do it by the book.
Standby on this channel. Go.
Starfleet Command, this is USS Grissom on coded channel 98.8.
Come in, please.
Sir, something is jamming our transmission. An energy surge.
Locate!
Sir, it's from astern!
Oh, my God.
Gunner... Target engine only.
Captain, what is happening? We're under attack!
Stand by for evasive.
Fire.
I wanted prisoners!
A lucky shot, sir...
Animal!
Sir, may I suggest... Say the wrong thing, Torg!
There are life signs on the planet. Perhaps the very scientists you seek.
Saavik calling Grissom... Very good.
Grissom, this is Saavik on emergency frequency. Come in, please.
What happened to them?
It would seem the Grissom was destroyed by an enemy attack.
We must go. They will soon come after us.
Estimating Genesis, 2.9 hours present speed.
Can we hold speed, Scotty? Aye, she's got her second wind now.
Scan for vessels in pursuit. Scanning. Indications negative.
Did I get it right?
Great, Bones, just great.
It's time for total truth between us.
This planet is not what you intended or hoped for, is it?
Not exactly.
Why?
I used proto-matter in the Genesis matrix.
An unstable substance which every ethical scientist in the galaxy
has denounced as dangerously unpredictable.
It was the only way to solve certain problems.
So, like your father, you changed the rules.
If I hadn't, it might have been years, or never!
How many have paid the price for your impatience?
How many have died? How much damage have you done?
And what is yet to come?
Bridge, nothing happening here.
This planet is ageing in surges. And Spock with it.
It seems they're joined together. They are.
How long?
Days. Maybe hours.
I'm sorry.
It will be hardest on Spock.
Soon he will feel the burning of his Vulcan blood.
I don't understand. Pon Farr.
Vulcan males must endure it every seventh year of their adult life.
Whoever they are, they're getting closer.
I'll go. No.
I'll do it. Give me your phaser.
Sir, Starfleet calling USS Grissom. A warning about us.
Response? Nothing. As before.
What's the Grissom up to? Will she join us or fire on us?
Chekov, break silence. Send Captain Esteban my compliments.
How are we doing? How are we doing?
Funny you should put it quite that way, Jim.
We are doing fine. But I'd feel safer
giving him one of my kidneys than what's scrambled in my brain.
No response from Grissom on any channel.
Keep trying. At regular intervals.
So it has come.
It is called Pon Farr.
Pon Farr.
Will you trust me?
We are secured from Warp Speed. Now entering Genesis Sector.
Proceed at impulse power.
Vessel entering sector. Yes.
Federation Battle Cruiser. Have they scanned us?
Not yet.
Engage cloaking device.
I'd swear there was something there, sir.
What did you see?
For an instant, a scout class vessel.
Could be Grissom. Patch in the hailing frequency.
Grissom, this is Enterprise calling. Please come in.
Grissom, this is Enterprise calling. Do you read?
Spock!
I've come a long way for the power of Genesis.
And what do I find?
A weakling human, a Vulcan boy and a woman.
My Lord, we are survivors of a doomed expedition.
This planet will destroy itself soon. The Genesis experiment is a failure.
A failure?
The most powerful destructive force ever created.
You will tell me the secret of the Genesis torpedo.
I have no knowledge.
Then I hope pain is something you enjoy.
I ordered no interruptions. But, sir...
Federation Starship approaching. Bring me up.
Grissom, this is Enterprise calling. Do you read?
Grissom, this is Enterprise calling. Please come in.
Battle Alert!
Grissom, this is Enterprise.
Admiral Kirk calling Captain Esteban or Lieutenant Saavik.
Report status. We are cloaked.
Enemy closing on impulse power. Range five thousand kellicams.
Good! This is just the turn of luck I have been waiting for.
Nothing on my scanner, sir. Short-range scan, Mr Chekov.
Put it on visual, Mr Sulu.
Range three thousand kellicams.
Steady. Continue on impulse power.
Range two thousand kellicams.
Stand by to transfer energy to weapons.
At my command.
There! That distortion, see it?
Yes, sir. It's getting larger as we close in.
Firing range, sir.
Gunner...
Target engine only. Understood?
Understood clearly, sir.
Opinion, Mr Sulu. I think it's an energy surge.
Enough energy to hide a ship? A cloaking device.
Red Alert, Mr Scott.
One thousand kellicams and closing.
All power to the weapons systems.
Wait. Wait.
No shields?
If my guess is right, they'll have to de-cloak before they can fire.
May all your guesses be right.
Klingon Bird of Prey. Arming. Fire, Mr Scott!
Good shooting, Mr Scott.
Precautionary, Mr Chekov, shields up.
Emergency power to the thrusters!
Sir, the shield's non-responsive. Scotty?
The automation system's overloaded. I didn't expect combat, you know.
Fire!
Emergency power. Prepare to return fire.
Mr Scott, can you transfer power to phaser banks?
I don't think so. They've knocked out the automation centre.
I've got no control over anything. Mr Sulu?
Nothing, sir.
So... we're a sitting duck.
Ready to fire emergency tube.
Why haven't they finished us? They outgun me ten to one!
My Lord. The enemy commander wishes a truce to confer.
Put them on screen.
This is Admiral James T. Kirk of the Federation Starship Enterprise.
The Genesis Commander himself. A violation of treaty...
...between the Federation and the Klingon Empire,
...your presence here is an act of war.
You have two minutes to surrender your crew and your vessel...
...or we will destroy you. He's hiding something.
We may have dealt him a more serious blow than I thought.
How can you tell that? I trust my instincts.
Admiral Kirk, this is your opponent speaking.
Don't lecture me about treaty violations!
In creating an ultimate weapon, the Federation has become criminals!
It is not I who will surrender, it is you!
On the planet below, I have three prisoners
from the team who developed your doomsday weapon.
If you don't surrender, I'll execute them as enemies of galactic peace!
Who is this? How dare you take prisoners?
Who I am is not important. That I have them is.
You may speak to them.
Admiral, this is Lieutenant Saavik. Saavik!
Is David with you? Yes, and someone else.
A Vulcan scientist of your acquaintance.
This... Vulcan...
Is he alive?
He is not himself, but he lives.
He's subject to rapid ageing, like this unstable planet.
Hello, sir, it's David.
I'm sorry I'm late.
I should've known you'd come. It's true, this planet is unstable.
It's gonna destroy itself within hours.
David, what went wrong?
I went wrong. I don't understand.
I'm sorry, sir. Just don't surrender.
Genesis doesn't work. I can't believe they'd kill us for it.
Admiral, your friend is mistaken, I meant what I said.
And to show that my intentions are sincere, I shall kill one prisoner.
Wait! Give me a chance to talk...
Kill one of them. I don't care which.
Saavik?
David?
Admiral... David is dead.
You Klingon bastard, you've killed my son.
Klingon bastard, you've killed my son!
You Klingon bastard!
There are two more prisoners, Admiral.
Do you want them killed, too?
Surrender your vessel.
All right. All right, damn you.
All right.
Give me a minute to inform my crew.
I give two minutes to you and your gallant crew.
Take every last man, form a boarding party, armed heavily!
They outnumber us, my Lord. We are Klingons!
Once you control the ship we will transfer our flag there
and take Genesis from their memory banks.
Mr Sulu, what is the crew complement of a Bird of Prey?
About a dozen officers and men.
With some of them on the planet.
I swear to you, we're not finished yet.
Bones, you and Sulu to the Transporter Room, the rest with me.
We have a job to do.
Commander Klingon vessel. Prepare to board this ship on my next signal.
No tricks, Kirk! You have one minute.
No tricks. I'm looking forward to meeting you.
To the Transport Room. Success!
Computer, this is Admiral James T. Kirk, requesting security access.
Computer, destruct Sequence One, Code: 1...
1 A...
Computer, Commander Montgomery Scott, Chief Engineering Officer.
Destruct Sequence Two, Code: 11 A 2B.
Computer, this is Commander Pavel Chekov, acting Science Officer.
Destruct Sequence Three, Code: 1 B2B3.
Destruct Sequence completed and engaged.
Awaiting final Code for one-minute countdown.
Code: 000.
Destruct 0.
Destruct Sequence is activated.
Kirk, your time runs out.
All set? Aye, sir.
Commander Klingon vessel, we are energising transporter beam, now.
Transporter, stand by!
My Lord, the ship appears to be deserted.
How can that be? They're hiding.
Yes, sir, but the bridge seems to be run by computer.
It's the only thing speaking. Speaking? Let me hear.
Nine, eight, seven, six...
...five... Get out! Get out of there!
Get out! ...one...
My God, Bones. What have I done?
What you had to do. What you always do.
Turn death into a fighting chance to live.
Planet core readings, unstable. Changing rapidly.
What about surface life signs?
There.
No! Don't touch him!
Bones.
What happened? He gave his life to save us.
Rapid ageing. All genetic functions highly accelerated.
What about his mind? His mind's a void.
It seems, Admiral, that I've got all his marbles.
Is there anything we can do? Only one thing.
Get him off this planet. His ageing is part of what's going on around us.
Klingon Commander, this is Admiral James T. Kirk.
I'm alive and well on the planet's surface.
I know this will come as a pleasant surprise to you.
Our ship was a victim of an unfortunate accident.
Sorry about your crew, but as we say on Earth, "C'est la vie".
I have what you want.
I have the secret of Genesis.
You're gonna have to bring us up there to get it.
Do you hear me?
I'm waiting for you!
What is your answer?
Drop all weapons!
Over there, all but Kirk.
Maltz... Prisoners at beam coordinates.
You should take the Vulcan too. No!
But why? Because you wish it.
Maltz... Activate beam!
Genesis. I want it!
Beam the Vulcan up, and we'll talk.
Give me what I want and I'll consider it.
Fool! Look around you! The planet's destroying itself!
Yes, exhilarating, isn't it?
If we don't help each other, we'll die here!
Perfect! Then that's the way it shall be.
Give me Genesis!
Give me your hand! Kirk!
I... have had...
...enough of you!
Maltz!
Don't! How many more?
Just him, sir.
Bones, help Spock.
We've got to break out of orbit.
You, help us or die.
I do not deserve to live.
Fine, I'll kill you later. Let's get out of here.
Where's the anti-matter inducer? This?
No! This!
That or nothing.
If I read this right, sir, we have full power.
Go, Sulu.
Goodbye, David.
We are clear and free to navigate.
Best speed to Vulcan. Mr Chekov, take the prisoner below.
Wait! You said you would kill me. I lied.
Spock...
For God's sake, talk to me!
You stuck this damn thing in my head, remember?
Remember?
Now, tell me what to do with it.
Help me.
I'm gonna tell you something that I...
...never thought I'd hear myself say.
But it seems I've missed you.
I don't know if I could stand to lose you again.
Ambassador, they are on approach.
They're requesting permission to land.
Permission granted. Tell them...
Tell Kirk we'll be ready.
Mr Sulu, you're on manual.
It's been a while, sir. Here we go.
Retrothrusters.
Sarek is waiting above, sir.
Sarek...
Child of Skon, child of Solkar...
The body of your son breathes still.
What is your wish?
I ask for Fal-Tor-Pan. The refusion.
What you seek has not been done since ages past,
and then only in legend.
Your request is not logical.
Forgive me, T'Lar.
My logic is uncertain where my son is concerned.
Who is the keeper of the Katra?
I am.
McCoy, Leonard H., son of David.
McCoy, Son of David...
Since thou art human, we cannot expect thee
to understand fully what Sarek has requested.
Spock's body lives.
With your approval, we shall use all our powers
to return to his body that which you possess.
But McCoy, you must now be warned.
The danger to thyself is as grave as the danger to Spock.
You must make the choice.
I choose the danger.
Hell of a time to ask.
I'm all right, Jim.
What about Spock?
Only time will answer.
Kirk... I thank you. What you have done is...
What I have done...
...I had to do.
But at what cost?
Your ship. Your son.
If I hadn't tried... the cost would have been my soul.
My father says that you have been my friend.
You came back for me.
You would have done the same for me.
Why would you do this?
Because the needs of the one...
...outweigh the needs of the many.
I have been...
...and ever shall be your friend.
Yes.
Yes, Spock!
The ship. Out of danger?
You saved the ship.
You saved us all. Don't you remember?
Jim.
Your name is Jim.
Yes.