[CROWD CHEERING]
[♪♪♪]
JERRY:
So this is the world.
And there are almost
six billion people on it.
When I was a kid there were three.
It's hard to keep up.
There, that's better. That's America.
See, America still sets
the tone for the world.
In Indiana, Clark Hodd, 13.
The best point guard in the country.
Last week he scored 100 points
in a single game.
Erica Sorgi.
You'll see her in the next Olympics.
In Seattle, Dallas Malloy, 16.
Her lawsuit helped pave the way
for women boxers everywhere.
She's picturing her ex-boyfriend
right now.
[BELL RINGS]
In Indio, California. Art Stallings.
Check out what pure joy looks like.
In Odessa, Texas.
The great Frank Cushman.
This April, 26 teams
will be falling over themselves...
...to sign him in the next NFL draft.
He's my client.
My most important client.
MAN: When are you gonna try?
BOY: I'm trying!
You wanna be a champion?
JERRY: Believe me.
There's genius everywhere.
But until they turn pro, it's like
popcorn in the pan. Some pop....
Darn it! What the heck, coach?
You don't know diddly squat!
- Whoa! You little shit!
JERRY: Some don't.
[MEN GRUNTING ON TV]
JERRY:
I'm the guy you don't usually see.
I'm the one behind the scenes.
I'm the sports agent.
JERRY:
I'll hurt you this year.
- Hey, man. Good to see you.
- Hi.
JERRY: How you doing?
- Fine.
My door's always open
if you want to come and get a real agent.
- Well. thanks.
- You're welcome, Johnny.
I'm gonna go to a meeting right now.
Know who I'm gonna talk about?
You. Because I'd kill for you.
I'm an animal for you.
- We've gotta win Super Bowls.
- I hail you. I hail you.
MAN 1: Jerry, how are you doing?
- Good.
MAN 2:
How much is this gonna cost me?
You and I both know there's
a number you can afford.
So I'm just gonna write it down.
We can move forward from there.
- I can't afford that.
- No one said winning was cheap.
JERRY: Know those photos where
the new player holds the jersey...
...and poses with the owner?
That's me on the left.
Inside that building, that's where I work.
SMI. Sports Management International.
[CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
Thirty-three out of shape agents
guiding the careers...
...of 1685 of the most
finely tuned athletes alive.
- You gotta be tough--
- I have 18 mill....
JERRY:
I handle the lives and dreams...
...of 72 clients and get an average of
264 phone calls a day. It's what I do.
I won't rest until you are
holding a Coke...
...wearing your own shoe,
playing a game featuring you...
...while singing your song
in a commercial starring you...
...broadcast during the Super Bowl
in a game you are winning.
I won't sleep until that happens.
JERRY: It's what I do best.
- Give you 15 minutes to call back.
JERRY:
Now. I'll be honest with you.
I started noticing it a few years ago,
didn't say a word.
REPORTER:
Was the girl 16 or 17?
JERRY: In the quest for the big dollar,
a lot of little things were going wrong.
Listen! There's no proof of anything
except this guy is a sensational athlete.
[REPORTERS SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
Are you Calvin Nack?
Can you sign my card?
You know, I'm sorry, fella.
I can't sign this particular brand of card.
- Only Pro-Jam Blue Dot cards.
- Just wanted an autograph.
JERRY:
Lately, it's gotten worse.
[THUDS THEN CROWD GASPING]
ANNOUNCER:
Oh, he goes down!
WOMAN:
Hi, baby.
DOCTOR:
Do you know your name?
Um....
- [WHISPERING] Steve Remo.
- Um....
WOMAN:
Steven Remo.
REMO: Wait, it's coming.
WOMAN: Steve Remo.
- My name is Steve Remo.
WOMAN: Yeah.
I play for Chicago.
This lady here is my wife.
WOMAN:
Mm-hm. Hi, baby.
REMO: And this is my boy.
And this is, uh....
Uh....
Wait.
- My agent. My agent.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Oh, and I gotta play this weekend, doc.
If I play in 65 percent of my games,
I get a bonus.
WOMAN: Shh.
REMO: I gotta get the bonus.
JERRY:
Okay, Jesse.
- You take care, little guy.
- Mr. Maguire?
- Yeah?
- This is his fourth concussion.
[PAGER BEEPS]
- Shouldn't somebody get him to stop?
- Hey, hey.
It would take a tank to stop your dad.
It would take all five...
...Super Trooper VR Warriors
to stop your dad.
Right?
Fuck you!
[JESSE CRYING]
JERRY: Who had I become?
Just another shark in a suit?
[♪♪♪]
REPORTER 1:--skyrocketing salaries,
and you are one of the guys responsible.
JERRY:
This guy is a sensational athlete.
Two days later, at our corporate
conference in Miami, a breakthrough.
I already have $18 million on the table....
Breakdown? Breakthrough.
BOY: I just wanted an autograph.
JESSE: Fuck you.
DOCTOR:
Do you know your name?
JERRY:
I couldn't escape one simple thought:
I hated myself.
No, no, no. Here's what it was:
I hated my place in the world.
I had so much to say,
no one to listen.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
And then it happened.
[♪♪♪]
It was the oddest,
most unexpected thing.
I began writing
what they call a mission statement...
...not a memo. A mission statement.
You know, a suggestion
for the future of our company.
A night like this
doesn't come along very often.
I seized it.
What started out as one page
became 25.
Suddenly, I was my father's son again.
I was remembering the simple pleasures
of this job.
How I ended up here out of law school.
The way a stadium sounds...
...when one of my players
performs well on the field.
The way we are meant to protect them,
in health and in injury.
With so many clients,
we had forgotten what was important.
I wrote and wrote and wrote and wrote.
And I'm not even a writer.
I was remembering even the words
of the original sports agent...
...my mentor, the late, great Dicky Fox,
who said:
The key to this business
is personal relationships.
JERRY: Suddenly, it was all pretty clear.
The answer was fewer clients.
Less money. More attention.
Caring for them, caring for ourselves
and the games too.
Just starting our lives really!
Hey, I'll be the first to admit...
...what I was writing
was somewhat touchy-feely.
I didn't care.
I had lost the ability to bullshit.
It was the me I'd always wanted to be.
I took it in a bag to a Copymat
in the middle of the night...
...and printed up 1 10 copies.
Even the cover looked like
The Catcher in the Rye.
I entitled it,
The Things We Think and Do Not Say:
The Future of Our Business.
That's how you become great, man.
Hang your balls out there.
Thanks.
JERRY: Everybody got a copy.
MAN: There are dangerous animals...
...and some of them walk on two feet.
They don't want peace
and they're not capable of love.
Society, and that means you
and you and you...
...need protection
from these warped minds.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC
PLAYING ON TV]
Boom!
Hi, this is Jerry Maguire.
Did those manuscripts get--?
MAN:
The mission statements?
- They've all gone out.
- Oh, they did?
- Would you like me to--?
- Oh, no, no. That's fine.
Thank you.
[PHONE RINGING]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
[ELEVATOR BELL DINGS]
[ALL APPLAUDING]
[♪♪♪]
- All right! Yeah!
- Finally, somebody said it.
AGENT 1: Good work, Maguire.
AGENT 2: Yeah, yeah!
Yeah!
AGENT 3:
Unbelievable. Unbelievable.
[ALL CHEERING]
[SIGHS]
JERRY:
I was 35.
I'd started my life.
- How long do you give him?
- About a week.
[SIGHS]
WOMAN: You're with
the sports people on the plane?
Yeah, I'm Jerry Maguire, SMI.
Bobbi Fallon, BPI.
I'm producing the Coke commercials
for the playoffs.
Well, good luck with that.
[BABY CRYING]
Oh, hi.
Hi, my son is really allergic
to the material in the blankets.
- And I was wondering if--
- That's all we have, okay?
[RAY COUGHING
THEN DOROTHY GASPS]
BOTH:
Oh....
- I'm sorry if I was rude just now.
- That's okay.
- We're in it together now.
- Okay.
Why is it so easy to talk with you?
Tell me about your fiancée.
STEWARDESS:
More champagne?
Don't think we're
quite at your pitch yet.
Oh, tell me how you proposed.
Honey, are you all right?
Do you want some juice or something?
Thank you. But we're
hiking up through the pools.
Got the ring in my pocket.
I'm-- I'm a little nervous.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
I'm lagging.
You know, she says to me...
...get this, "Hurry up, klutz."
Well, it bothered me somewhat.
You know, and I got quiet.
Then she got quiet.
And I decide I'm not gonna propose.
The mood is not right.
Why be impulsive?
Now at this point, I know she knows
that I was gonna propose and didn't.
And she knows I know.
- So we check back into the hotel.
- How sad.
But wait. Now, little do I know
that my assistant...
...has assumed that I've now proposed.
So she's gotten the lounge band
to actually play...
..."Here Comes The Bride"
when we walk back in.
BOBBI:
I love that song.
All the football guys
are in the lobby watching.
There's even an ESPN crew.
So I turn to her, sort of grandly say:
"Well, this is me, klutz, asking you...
...goddess of rock climbing, to marry me."
I took out the ring. You know,
I mean, I don't much like big scenes...
...but she said yes
right there in the lobby.
Some of the toughest men
in football wept like babies.
- We're getting married in February.
BOBBI: Oh, Jerry.
You two are gonna be married forever.
[BABY CRYING]
- What's wrong, Mom?
- First class is what's wrong, honey.
It used to be a better meal,
now it's a better life.
Ray?
Ray?!
Come on, buddy!
- High five!
DOROTHY: Ray!
- Oh, God. Ray!
- Excuse me, can I help you?
Jerry Maguire.
I work in your office.
I was on a junket.
I know who you are.
You're Dorothy Boyd. You're in Accounts.
You have the side, middle cubicle...
...with a poster of Albert Einstein's face
morphed on Shaquille O'Neal's body.
That's pretty good.
- What--? What did you lose?
- My son, my mind.
Ray! Ray!
- While I look-- Dorothy. Dorothy?
- Huh?
While I go look for him...
...why don't you grab this curious
gentleman right here?
[GIGGLES]
DOROTHY:
Oh! Oh, thank God. Oh!
You scared me.
You scared me!
- Don't do that again, ever!
- Okay, Mommy.
Ever, ever, ever! Okay? Ever!
JERRY:
Dorothy?
- Oh.
- Take care.
Thank you so much.
I loved your memo, by the way.
- You did?
- Yeah.
Thanks. Uh, actually,
it was just a mission statement.
I think in this age,
optimism like that is a revolutionary act.
- You think so?
- Yeah.
Well, I appreciate that.
Because I didn't know if I should write it.
I mean, it was 2 in the morning.
I don't know.
Some of the stuff I just,
"Whoo!" you know. Ha-ha-ha.
No. That part about
how we should embrace...
...what is still virginal in our enthusiasm--
- Ha-ha-ha.
DOROTHY: Just a second.
--and force open
the tightly clenched fist of commerce...
...and give a little back
for the greater good.
- Uh-huh.
DOROTHY: God, I was inspired.
- And I'm an accountant, you know?
RAY: One, two, three!
- Swing!
- I mean, to respect yourself enough...
- ...to say it out loud.
- Swing!
To put yourself out there
like that, so openly, so nakedly.
- I don't know. It got me.
RAY: Swing! Whoo!
Swing!
DOROTHY: Is this bothering you?
- Whoo!
- No, this is great.
RAY: Whoo!
- This is great.
RAY: One, two, three! Swing!
JERRY: Do you need a ride?
Are you--? You're okay?
- What?
- Do you need a lift?
RAY: Swing!
- Oh, no! Oh. Ha-ha-ha.
Yeah, I'm sure that
would just make your day, huh?
To drive us all the way out
to Manhattan Beach.
Making that left
on little tiny Waterloo Street.
Playing chicken with the oncoming traffic.
Your life flashing before your eyes.
I've obviously had too much coffee, huh?
Ha-ha-ha.
JERRY:
It's no problem.
Oh, there's my sister, Laurel,
to pick us up.
- Thanks.
- Sure.
Ray...
...Dorothy.
Pleasure.
Bye.
[♪♪♪]
LAUREL: Hey.
RAY: Hi, Aunt Laurel.
I'm double-parked, let's go.
Sorry, honey. Is this everything?
These three.
- Come here.
- Dorothy?
Man, whoever snagged him
must be some classy babe.
[JERRY & AVERY
GRUNTING AND MOANING]
Don't ever stop fucking me!
Sooner or later we'll have to stop!
Never been better! Never better!
Never better!
[YAWNS]
Open your eyes.
If you ever want me to be
with another woman for you, I would do it.
I'm not interested in it.
There was a time, yes,
it felt normal for me.
But it was a phase.
A college thing.
Like torn Levi's or law school for you.
Want anything from the kitchen?
I'm gonna get some fruit.
I don't think we need to do...
...the thing where
we tell each other everything.
Jerry, this is what intimacy is.
Oh, don't forget. Tomorrow,
we have dinner with Wade Cooksy.
I know about the bachelor party.
Jerry, your buddy Dooler worked
his ass off to make you a tribute film.
All those guys from the office are coming.
Everybody loves you.
Calm down, relax, act surprised,
and have an amazing time.
Oh, no!
[GRUNTING]
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING
AND PEOPLE LAUGHING]
- Oh, my God. You! You!
- Sorry. Sorry.
Jerry!
- Got you! Ha, ha!
- Good to see you, buddy.
- Hey, college buddy. Congratulations.
- Valhere. Valhere. Thank you.
- For you.
- Thank you.
And this is for you.
Finest cigar my club has to offer.
This is what it's all about, man.
Everybody loves you.
Pisses me off!
[LAUGHS]
Whether you're country,
redneck or a freak...
...young or old, from Moscow,
London or Memphis--
MAN [DUBBED]:
Jerry Maguire.
--will still be the king
of rock 'n' roll to me.
ALL: Ha-ha-ha!
AVERY [ON TV]: Jerry, Jerry. Jerry.
Little black book.
When I think about Jerry,
my heart starts pounding.
- Ah.
- I know Jerry pretty well.
Hi, Jerry, remember me? Ha, ha.
- We still on for lunch tomorrow?
- Yeah.
He was no slouch in bed.
This is the funniest thing I've ever seen.
You guys are crazy I'll see you later.
--good idea that Jerry get married.
He won't be alone.
[♪♪♪]
- He cannot be alone.
- He can't be alone.
WOMAN 1:
He's almost phobic.
I mean, Jerry is great at friendship,
he's just really bad at intimacy.
WOMAN 2: He can't be alone.
WOMAN 3: He can't be alone.
- He can't say, "I love you."
WOMAN 4: You listening, Jerry?
Lies, lies, lies. He's an agent. He lies.
- I love you too.
- Hey, love you too.
WOMAN 5: Love you too.
WOMAN 6: Love you.
I love you, man.
♪ Got a pocket full of rainbows ♪
- I love you.
♪ Mr. Heartache ♪
♪ I've found a way to make him leave ♪♪
Morning, Jenny.
JENNY:
Sorry I missed the bachelor party, Jerry.
WENDY: Good morning.
JERRY: Good morning.
Marcee's already in your office
and she's late for her plane to Phoenix.
Thank you, Wendy.
- Marcee.
- I'm glad to see you...
...finally made it.
Rod is very, very upset.
[BOY YELLS]
- Tyson, no!
- Okay, Mommy.
- Tyson, hello.
- Hello, Jerry. Long time no see!
MARCEE: What did I say, Tyson?
- How can I make your life better?
Jerry, this is humiliating
and I'm pregnant...
...and I'm incapable of bullshit.
- Where is our offer from Arizona?
- Cronin's okay for lunch?
Marcee, this is one of our agents.
This is Bob Sugar.
- He needs to learn to knock.
- Pleasure.
- You've called our house, right?
- I'm sorry to interrupt you guys.
Now I don't know what you do
for your four percent...
...but this man,
my husband has a whole plan, an image.
And when you put him in a waterbed
warehouse commercial? Excuse me...
...you're making him common
when you know he deserves the big four:
Shoe, car, clothing, soft drink.
I know about the four jewels
of the celebrity endorsement.
- Wow.
- I majored in marketing, baby.
And so did my husband.
We came to play!
[CLATTERING]
The dirty man is back!
[LAUGHS]
[DOWN-TEMPO MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
- Hey.
- Hey, buddy.
You okay?
- Fine. What's up?
- Came here to let you go.
- Pardon me?
- Came here to fire you, Jerry.
It's real. You should say something.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
GROUP:
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
Shit.
A crowded restaurant
so there won't be a scene.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪♪
[GROUP WHISTLING
AND CHEERING]
- You ungrateful--
- You should see yourself.
You said fewer clients, you put
it all down on paper. Jesus Christ.
What about me?
You know what I went through?
Knowing I was gonna
have to fire my mentor?
Carrying that around
in my head for a week?
Could you get past yourself for a second?
Jesus!
- You'll lose.
- You wanted smaller.
Oh, I'm over it. Now I want
all my clients and yours too.
Whatever.
[♪♪♪]
[SPEED-DIAL BEEPING
ON CELL PHONE]
[BUSY SIGNAL]
[GRUNTS]
JERRY:
Wendy, bring me my numbers.
[SPEED-DIAL BEEPING]
[LINE RINGING]
[BUSY SIGNAL]
[PHONE RINGS]
- This is Cush.
SUGAR: Cush, it's Sugar.
Look, I'm calling you first...
...because you're the most important guy
in sports.
And I wanna know one thing.
How does that feel to be a legend?
I just wanna play football.
Dad!
MATT: Yeah.
- It's one of the agents.
Wendy, Cushman's line is busy!
Call till you get through.
And please bring me my numbers!
J.J., what's up?
Have you talked to Maguire?
He had a meltdown.
I've talked to Doritos about you.
- It's Martinez.
- They're interested.
Talk to Rick. Martinez.
[SPEAKS SPANISH]
Carlo, right now you pay 25 percent
on your endorsements to SMI.
I would cut my commission by 7 percent.
I don't wanna say it was drug-induced,
but the guy completely freaked out.
I don't know if you want him representing
you. I said my piece. How's your mom?
I'm gonna make this decision
easy for you.
Just what does your heart tell you?
I'm sorry to hear that.
[PHONES RINGING]
AGENT:
I can't believe they fired him. He's gone.
[WHISPERS]
Hey, what's going on?
They fired Jerry Maguire.
Did it at Cronin's.
[PHONE RINGS]
SMI, this is Cleo. Hey!
JERRY: No. Just listen to me.
SMI represents....
[♪♪♪]
I think you're making a big mistake.
That's how I feel.
I'm concerned about your family.
I am concerned about your future.
If you stay here, I don't
know what'll happen.
I'm sorry. I have a long-standing
relationship with SMI.
You know, and I, uh....
Do you think Maguire knows
what it's like to be a black guy?
Bob Sugar? He's, uh....
He's entertaining, funny.
He said I don't know what it's like to be
a black person? I'm Mr. Black People!
Ha, ha. Like I said. I mean,
don't make it harder than it is.
I've got to be honest with you,
this is very personally distressing for me.
I haven't seen you since we were with
that stripper. You remember her name?
MAN: No.
- I do, it was April.
That's my job. To remember the names
of skanks that you bang on the road.
That's what I do. It's not about
the money, I do it all for you.
This is Jerry Maguire.
Still holding for Katarina.
Hey, I'm talking about money, ho!
I gotta tell you-- You know what?
It's been a great day.
Are you in or out? It's not show friends.
It's show business.
You are in.
- That's good.
- Jerry...
...I wanna cry for what
they did to you at SMI.
If we weren't right in the middle
of the Acura deal...
...you know I'd go with you.
Oh, Jerry. Oh, God!
[BEEPS OVER PHONE]
Call waiting.
Who could be calling me now?
- Hi, Kathy Sanders.
- Still me, Kathy.
[CRYING]
Kathy, why are you crying?
Oh. Ha-ha-ha. So you're in?
Rod? Rod, Rod. Jerry Maguire.
How are you doing?
- Jerry Maguire!
- Ha-ha-ha. Yeah, how you doing?
How am I doing?
I'll tell you how I'm doing.
I'm sweating. I'm sweating my contract.
I'm sweating Bob Sugar calling me...
...telling me I'm missing
the big endorsements being with you.
That's how I'm doing. I'm sweating.
No, I-- I hear what you're saying.
That's why I'm calling.
No, no, no.
I hear that you hear what I'm saying.
But do you truly hear what I'm saying?
I hear what you're saying, Daddy.
I think maybe the best thing
is that we get together in person.
[BEEPING]
I'm sorry.
Would you mind holding?
Didn't you tell my wife more attention?
Did you not tell my wife
more personal attention?
I said more personal attention.
Good! We're just getting started...
...on my list of the things
you need to know.
You can take notes if you want to.
I will kill for you, maim for you.
I will rape and pillage for you.
I am a valuable commodity!
I go across the middle.
I see a dude coming at me,
trying to kill me...
...I tell myself, "Get killed. Catch the ball."
Boo-yah! Touchdown!
I make miracles happen.
I just need to know
are you in or are you out?
I'm from Arizona, Jerry.
- I broke Arizona records.
- Rod?
I went to Arizona State!
I'm a Sun Devil, man!
- And now you want Arizona dollars.
- Exactly.
- I understand what you're saying--
- I'm sitting here...
...with an ant problem. I got ants
going up and down my hallway.
My brother Tee Pee's room
is flooded with-- Look at this!
- Rod.
- We got a flood...
...in Tee Pee's room, Jerry. Hang on.
Say hello to Jerry Maguire.
- Rod, listen.
- Hello, brother Maguire.
Hello, Tee Pee.
Jerry, my house is falling apart!
Nobody's looking out for Rod Tidwell.
We don't know where
we gonna live in a year.
And I'm supposed
to be a superstar, man!
Rod, I need a decision.
Are you in or are you out?
You'll be so happy
you stayed with Bob Sugar...
...because I am the fucking terminator!
I am a role model.
I have a family to support! Hear me?
I wanna stay in Arizona.
I want my new contract.
But I like you. Yes, I like you.
My wife likes you.
You're good to my wife.
- I will stay with you.
- That's great. I'm very happy.
- Are you listening?
- Yes.
That's what I'm gonna do for you.
God bless you, Jerry.
This is what you'll do for me--
Are you listening? Jerry?
What can I do for you?
Just tell me, what can I do?
It's a very personal,
very important thing.
Hell, it's a family motto.
- Are you ready, Jerry?
- Ready.
I just wanna make sure
you're ready, brother.
Here it is:
[LOWERS VOLUME
OF HIP-HOP MUSIC]
Show me the money.
[LAUGHING AND RAISES VOLUME]
Show...
...me the...
...money!
Jerry, doesn't that make
you feel good?
- Say it with me, Jerry.
- Show you the money.
You can do better than that! Say it!
- Bob Sugar's on the other line.
- Show you the money.
- No, not you, show me the money.
- Show me the money.
- Louder!
- That's it, but you got to yell!
- Show me the money!
- I need to feel you.
Jerry, you better yell.
Show me the money!
- Say you love this black man.
JERRY: I love the black man!
- Show me the money!
- I love black people!
I love black people!
- Who's your motherfucker?
- You're my motherfucker!
- What you gonna do, Jerry? Unh.
- Show me the money!
Congratulations,
you're still my agent.
Well, don't worry. Don't worry.
I'm not gonna do what you all
think I'm gonna do...
...which is just flip out!
Let me just say as I...
...ease out of the office I helped build.
I'm sorry, but it's a fact...
...that there is such a thing as manners.
A way of treating people.
These fish have manners.
In fact, they're coming with me.
I'm starting a new company...
...and the fish will come with me.
You can call me sentimental...
...but the fish are coming with me.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Okay.
If anybody else
wants to come with me...
...this will be a moment of something...
...real and fun and inspiring...
...in this godforsaken business...
...and we will do it together.
Who's coming with me?
Who's coming with me?!
[MAN COUGHS]
Who's coming with me
besides Flipper here?
This is embarrassing.
All right.
Wendy.
- Shall we?
- Oh, Jerry...
...I'm three months away
from the pay increase.
I....
Okay.
I will go with you.
Dorothy Boyd, thank you.
[♪♪♪]
[WHISPERS]
Right now?
WOMAN: Don't do it.
- Shh!
DOROTHY:
Bye.
We'll see you all again.
Sleep tight.
Bye.
JERRY:
Let's see how they do without us.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
- I'll just--
- Oh. Thank you.
I know this is a bad time, but
you will have a medical program, right?
Oh, sure, yes, medical.
I don't know.
When you think about
what you did, don't panic.
We're gonna be okay.
We're gonna be great.
We're gonna be great!
[ELEVATOR BELL DINGS]
I wonder what he said.
My favorite aunt is
hearing-impaired.
He just said,
"You complete me."
[♪♪♪]
[WOMEN CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
That's an excellent point.
We come to support each other...
...but we don't listen to one another.
Women are taught not to
see each other as good people.
We see each other as enemies.
We compete over men, jobs--
WOMAN 1:
It's true, we compete.
WOMAN 2:
I used to really hate women.
And then I met you guys,
and you're like me.
It's important because
I know you can be my friends.
- What about medical?
- Of course medical.
A single mother can't be frivolous.
If you read what he wrote,
you'd have left too.
And I can always take that job
in San Diego.
- Do you know the cost of child exams?
- Yes, $150.
And that's when he's well.
- Where is Ray?
- Asleep in the living room.
That's wonderful.
Next time you lecture me...
...don't leave my boy in that room
with that divorced women's group.
So I finally, finally
got in touch with my anger.
[WOMEN CHEERING]
What did I do?
AVERY: Function, function.
Forward motion is everything.
Cush saves all.
You go to Texas. You keep
one superstar, and they'll all follow.
- There's no loyalty.
- None.
The first person
who told me that was you.
- I was trying to sleep with you.
- Well, it worked.
And I will not let you fail.
You are Jerry Ma-fucking-guire!
- That's right.
- King of the house calls.
- Master of the living room.
- Okay, okay.
- Okay, this is working.
- You are not a loser.
- Who said anything about "loser"?
- Mistake.
I meant something else.
When do you wanna leave?
MATT:
I'm in the back den, Jerry.
- Hey, you like a bloody beer?
- I'm fine.
Beer and tomato juice. Huh?
I'm fine.
We've spent a lot
of time together, Matt.
You know I care about you
and your son.
You know I'm a straight shooter.
If you stay with SMI--
We decided to stay with you.
Ha! Oh. Okay.
JERRY: I'm not really a hugger. And yet...
- Ha-ha-ha.
- ...I can't let go.
- Ha, ha.
I told myself, "If he shows up,
we stick with him."
- Hey!
- Whoa.
- Hey, Jerry. How's it going?
- Hey, Cush.
How are you, Cush? How are you?
CUSH: You remember Keith?
- Yeah. How you doing?
I want him to go number one
in the draft, and I want him to play.
It'll either be Denver or San Diego.
He'll go number one.
I'll either surf or ski. Ha-ha-ha.
- Denver's where he should be.
- I'll give it everything.
You know I don't do contracts,
but what you do have is my word.
And it's stronger than oak.
[♪♪♪]
[UPBEAT ROCK MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
♪ I was so ♪
♪ Can't-- ♪♪
♪ Me angel ♪
♪ Of the morning ♪♪
♪ She had faith ♪
♪ And she had belief ♪♪
♪ Her heart ♪
♪ Now I'm free ♪
♪ Free fallin' ♪
[LAUGHS]
♪ Yeah, I'm free ♪
♪ I'm free fallin' ♪
Whoo!
♪ Yeah, I'm free ♪♪
[PHONE RINGS]
- Hello.
- Dorothy? Jerry Maguire.
- Hi.
- Is Avery there?
She had to fly to Atlanta.
She had a meeting at the NFL.
Rocks, Dottie. Wait--
Wait-- Oh, God. Oh.
RAY: Jerry.
- Hello? Hello? Hello?
- Sorry, that was my son and the nanny.
- What are they all doing in our office?
- Nanny? I prefer child technician.
- Dorothy?
- Hello?
- Yeah. I had the calls transferred...
...to my house so that I could
go over some of your stuff.
That's fine. Dorothy, we are back.
We are so very, very back.
I resigned Cush. We're set.
- I am so happy for you.
- Happy for us.
Happy for us. Okay, happy for us.
JERRY: Rod, being at the draft
with me is a good idea. Trust me.
No, Rod, just get on the plane
and meet us at the gate, okay?
- Good. We'll see you there.
ROD: God bless you.
Okay, Avery will meet you
at the B-gate at 4:15. Don't be late.
Jerry, do you know the human head
weighs eight pounds?
Did you know Troy Aikman,
in only six years...
...has passed for 16,303 yards?
Do you know bees and dogs
can smell fear?
Oh, I booked Tidwell on the same floor
at the Marriott Marquis.
- He doesn't smoke, does he?
- I don't know.
Did you know the career record
for most hits is 4256 by Pete Rose...
...who is not in the Hall of Fame?
Do you know that my next door neighbor
has three rabbits?
[BOTH LAUGHING]
I can't compete with that.
[♪♪♪]
Okay, so did we go
over everything? Yes?
- Yep.
- Back on Tuesday, right?
Yeah.
Ray, have a good time at school.
Wish me luck.
BOTH:
Luck!
♪ That's the way it's gonna be
Little darlin' ♪
♪ We'll be riding on the horses, yeah ♪
♪ Way up in the sky ♪
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
♪ And if you fall I'll pick you up ♪♪
- Hey, Rod.
- Hey, Jerry--
JERRY:
Cush, how are you, man?
CUSH:
Jerry, we should be selling these.
Terrific. This is my agent,
you might want his autograph. Heh, heh.
Man, my hand's getting tired.
- Excuse me.
- Hey, what's happening?
Are you Hootie?
No, I am not Hootie.
[REPORTERS SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
What is it gonna be,
San Diego or Denver?
CUSH:
I'll surf or ski.
[REPORTERS
CONTINUE SHOUTING]
He'll either surf or ski.
Rod, at last I find you.
What am I doing here?
I feel like I'm five years late for the prom.
Come on. Come with me.
Nobody gives a damn
about me being here.
We're gonna go downstairs
and we're gonna walk through this lobby.
Because I want every media guy,
every player's rep...
...everybody to see you
for what you are:
The best-kept secret
in the NFL.
[♪♪♪]
The most commanding wide receiver
in the game.
You are fast, fierce, wildly charismatic.
You are the man.
You are the man. You ready?
- Let's go.
ROD: Let's walk.
[SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
The fiercest.
You are the man.
- Let's do it.
JERRY: Hi, Mel. How are you?
- Good to see you.
- How you doing? Tom.
- How's it going? Upstairs.
- Where's Cush?
Good thing you were able
to hang onto Cushman.
What'll it be? San Diego or Denver?
We'll know tomorrow.
I want you to meet Rod Tidwell.
- How you doing?
- Arizona, 110 receptions...
- ...1550 yards last year.
- How you doing, baby?
I'd like you to meet Rod Tidwell.
ROD:
What's up, man?
JERRY: Rod Tidwell--
ROD: How you doing?
JERRY:
I want you to meet Rod Tidwell.
MAN: How are you, Rod?
- Good, hey.
- Rod ran for 1150 yards last year.
- That's right.
[♪♪♪]
- Good? Good.
- I'm doing great, baby.
Now I wanna talk about Rod Tidwell.
He's the fiercest wide receiver in the NFL.
MAN 1: Hey, man. How are you?
MAN 2: Nice to meet you.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
I came all that way
just to walk the lobby. Heh.
Yeah. It might have
even worked too.
Yeah? Shit. Let's do that shit again.
[ROD CHUCKLES]
Hey, hey. Stop.
Shooting a Reebok ad down there.
Hey, Jerry...
...where are my endorsements?
Know what I'm saying?
You know, I didn't get no love from
Chevy. I didn't get no love from Pepsi.
Shit. I didn't even get no love
from that little Energizer Bunny.
- I didn't get no love from Nike.
- Rod--
Obviously, I didn't get love from Reebok.
Did I ever tell you
about my Reebok story?
Rod, I gotta get back to Cushman.
Oh, you gotta get back
to your golden paycheck.
But wait. Just, I'll boil it down for you.
Fuck Reebok!
All they do is ignore me. Always have.
Always have.
Know what was great
about you down there?
For about five minutes,
you unloaded that rather large chip...
...that resides right there
on your shoulder.
And you know what?
You let people in.
You were brilliant.
- Brilliant?
- Brilliant.
- Really?
- Now take care, I'll see you tomorrow.
- You're loving me now, aren't you?
- I'm not about love.
I'm about showing you the money!
I-- I was just testing you, Jerry.
But to hear you say that...
...makes me love you, baby. You know?
Jerry, come back!
MATT: How was your flight?
- Good. How was yours?
- Good.
CUSH: Hey, man. What size are you?
BELLHOP:
Twelve and a half.
Grab a couple pairs
of them new shoes by the door.
[MATT CHUCKLING
AND CUSH PLAYING GUITAR]
♪ It's okay to kill fish
'Cause they haven't got no feeling ♪♪
Cush, Matt, we have
a decision to make.
San Diego just came in
with a last-minute scenario. It's big.
- Well, he's got to go number one.
- Oh, he still goes number one.
But San Diego wants to trade up
with Denver. They want him bad.
What happened to Denver?
This stuff happens the night
before a draft. People get crazy.
Let me tell you something.
San Diego, Matt--
[PHONE RINGING]
San Diego is crazy...
...to the tune of seven years
for 30. Signing bonus of 8.
- Should I unplug the phone?
- Reporters, Jerry.
They've been calling all night long.
You just be friendly
and you say, "No comment."
We'll tell the world in 12 hours.
Talking and saying nothing, man.
It is an art I have not mastered.
Well, let me do that....
For you, it's a pleasure.
- [IMITATING CUSH] This is Cush.
- Ha, ha.
SUGAR: It's Sugar. Is Maguire there?
Just sniff if he's there.
[SNIFFS]
Okay. All right, buddy.
Dude, remember.
You're swimming with the big boys now.
You let your dad do all the talking.
Remember I'm the one
that got you the deal you needed.
This is business, not friendship.
You gotta be strong...
...because you're global now.
Worldwide.
Okay, buddy?
I'll see you later. Bye.
JERRY:
No comment.
- He's got it all wrong.
- Hey, it's Cush on the big TV again.
I'm sick of me, already.
I got Cush-lash.
[CUSH PLAYING GUITAR]
♪ Cush-lash, Cush-lash
Cush-lash, Cush-lash, Cush-lash ♪♪
[CHUCKLES]
Now, Matt,
before I go back to Denver...
...I think we should put something down
on paper.
You know, something that says,
"Hey, I'm with Jerry Maguire."
Not right now, Jerry.
Do I know everything
there is to know here, Matt?
You fellas aren't talking
with Bob Sugar, are you?
Apparently, Denver wanted to deal
with him instead of you.
Said who? Sugar?
I'm learning as I go here.
So you empowered Bob Sugar
to deal with Denver behind my back?
I'm sorry. I, uh....
- I love my son.
- I love your son. I love your son!
I brought Denver to 20 million.
Denver deals with me all the time.
You listened to Sugar.
Bob Sugar, Matt, is a child.
You let that snake in the door?
Okay, hey, Matt.
Listen, rookie mistake. You want Denver.
I'll fix this whole thing up for you.
You didn't sign anything
with Sugar, right?
Matt? Tell me you didn't sign.
Tell me you didn't sign because
I'm still sort of moved by your...
..."my word is stronger than oak" thing.
We signed an hour ago.
You were in the lobby
with the black fella.
CUSH:
Sorry, Jerry. I just want to play football.
- What do I do? How do I spin this?
- Oh, honey, it's spun.
What did I do to you?
It's all about you, isn't it?
"Soothe me, save me, love me."
- Would you stop moving?
- I have to finish my job.
Everything's on the fucking run with us.
Everything.
Jerry, you and I are sales people.
We sell.
- Look, I don't--
- It's not "Love me."
It's not "Trust my handshake."
It's "Make the sale! Get it signed."
- There shouldn't be confusion about that.
- Okay.
Jump right into my nightmare.
The water is warm.
Oh, so honestly is outlawed here?
I can't be honest?
Tell you what,
I would prefer loyalty.
What was our deal
when we were first got together?
Brutal truth. Remember?
I think you added the "brutal."
Jerry, there is a sensitivity thing
that some people have. I don't have it.
I don't cry at movies.
I don't gush over babies.
I don't start celebrating
Christmas five months early.
And I don't tell a man who
just screwed up both our lives:
"Oh, poor baby."
That's me, for better or worse.
But I do love you.
- Avery....
- No.
- It's over.
- I didn't hear it.
There's something missing here.
Don't you think?
You have never been alone.
- Listen to me.
- And you can't be alone.
It's over.
No one has ever dumped me.
I'm not trying to make history here.
I did the 23-hour nose route
to the top of El Capitan...
...in 18 hours and 23 minutes.
I can make this work.
No.
Oh, Jerry.
JERRY:
I didn't ever want to hurt you.
[GROANING]
I won't let you hurt me, Jerry.
I'm too strong for you. Loser!
[♪♪♪]
Roll with the punches.
Tomorrow's another day.
Taxi!
You're loving me now, aren't you?
Very much. Taxi!
Is it my imagination
or didn't we arrive in a limo?
The question I have to say to you is this.
And I hope this doesn't come off
too much like I'm a shrink here, okay.
- What's wrong?
- Man, I'm just a big disappointment.
[CRYING]
Jerry, everybody cries on this show.
You're mad you tested positive?
Quit doing blow.
Upset about your baby girl?
Why'd you leave the mother?
I knew her, she was all right.
People like media,
they don't understand...
...what kind of problems and pressures
$54 million comes with.
ROD: This is some bullshit.
- What are you doing with me, Rod?
- What?
- Don't you even see? I'm finished.
I am fucked.
Twenty-four hours ago, man, I was hot.
Now....
I'm a cautionary tale.
You see this jacket I'm wearing?
You like it?
Because I don't really need it
because I'm cloaked in failure!
I lost the number one draft pick
the night before the draft!
Why? Let's recap.
Because a hockey player's kid
made me feel like a superficial jerk.
I ate two slices of bad pizza,
went to bed and grew a conscience!
Well, boo-fucking-hoo.
[SCOFFS]
I got a shelf life of 10 years tops.
My next contract has got to bring dollars
that'll last me and mine a very long time.
Shit, I'm out of this sport in five years.
What's my family gonna live on?
Huh? What you get me.
So I don't wanna hear your shit, Jerry.
I don't want to hear your "Nah, nah, nah.
Oh, I lost Cush and Avery" and shit.
Could I have another drink, please?
Could I--?
Anybody else would have
left you by now.
But I'm sticking with you.
I said I would.
And if I got to ride your ass like Zorro,
you gonna show me the money.
You gonna show me the money.
[SCOFFS]
We together on this. You know
what I'm saying? We gonna be one.
[UPBEAT JAZZ MUSIC
PLAYING ON HEADPHONES]
[GRUNTS]
The both of us! You know?!
Oh, my God.
[♪♪♪]
WOMAN [ON MACHINE]:
You have no messages.
[ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS]
[KEYPAD BEEPING]
[LINE RINGING]
- He's coming over.
- Tonight?
He just lost his best client.
I invited the guy over.
Dorothy, this is not a guy.
It's a syndrome.
"Early midlife,
hanging onto the bottom rung.
Dear God, don't let me be alone. I'll
call my newly long-suffering assistant...
...without medical for company"
syndrome. If knowing that...
...you still want him to come over,
I'm not saying a thing.
Honey, he's engaged.
And for the first time
in my professional life...
...I'm part of something that I believe in.
Okay. But he better not be good-looking!
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Hi.
I'm Jerry Maguire.
Hello. You're just the way
I pictured you.
- I'm her disapproving sister, Laurel.
- Honesty.
- Thank you.
- Mm. Mm.
Thank you. Dorothy!
Dorothy, your boss is here.
Hello.
[CHUCKLING]
- Oh, careful.
- Ho!
DOROTHY:
Hey, you.
- Hi, hi. Thanks for inviting me over.
- Sure.
Where's--? Where's the little guy?
- He's sleeping.
- Oh, yeah. Sleeping.
I'm so glad you're home.
You know, just,
that alone thing is not my specialty.
Oh, my God!
Oh, yeah. Oh, my God.
Well, I broke up with Avery. Heh, heh.
Just, uh....
- That-- Gosh, you know, that's too bad.
- No, it's better...
...because we'll still be friends.
And it's better now than later.
- Sure, sure.
- You know what I mean....
- I'm dying here, aren't I?
- It's a really bad cut.
Just think if I got her
the ring she really wanted.
[LAUGHING]
- Yeah.
- Why don't you have a seat?
I'll, uh....
I'll get some aloe vera for the cut.
- Do you have something to drink?
- Sure.
I heard.
No kidding. I saw the shadow
of curious shoes under the door.
He'd go home with a gardening tool
if it showed interest.
Don't use those.
Use the frosted glasses.
DOROTHY: Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- I warmed up some chicken.
- Oh! That's the girl I love.
I'm not gonna say anything.
I'm just gonna say this:
- You've always been responsible with Ray.
- Don't start.
I don't think it's right for him to wake up
and hear some strange man's voice.
- Some drunken stranger.
- As opposed to 10 angry women?
- Whoa!
- Ow!
Lean forward.
Okay, I've got it.
It's still edible.
Change your shirt.
- Oh.
- Everything's fine.
Hi, Jerry.
Hi, Ray.
Aren't you supposed to be in bed?
- Yeah.
Don't worry, I won't tell.
The human head weighs eight pounds.
[LAUGHING]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
- Jerry Maguire.
RAY: I think it's this one.
ROD: You should
be dreaming about me, baby.
I should be on your mind constantly.
My agent should be thinking,
"Rod Tidwell."
That's when the big dollars
are gonna flow.
That's when we truly
will materialize the kwan.
- Who is this?
You are speaking to the Rod Tidwell.
I need to speak with my agent.
I need to be my agent.
My agent and I should be one.
Are you a football player?
Am I a football player?
I'm a school teacher
about to whomp your ass!
Put Jerry Maguire on the phone!
Just one more thing. You don't have the
luxury of falling for some drowning man.
- Be practical.
- Practical?
Which top? High turtleneck, sensible.
Low V-neck, sexy. Turtleneck, turtleneck.
Don't tell me to be practical.
Do you know what other women
my age doing right now?
They're out partying,
trying to get a man.
Trying to keep a man.
Not me, I'm trying to raise a man.
This one. I've got a 24-hour-a-day
reminder of Roger for the rest of my life.
- I've had three lovers in four years.
- That's not bad.
All of them ran a distant second
to a good book and a warm bath.
Look at me. I'm the oldest
26-year-old in the world.
- Now, how do I look?
- Good.
Yeah? Thanks.
ROD: Seventy-two percent
of new buyers are African-American.
I am African-American.
You talk too much.
Talking is only a primitive
form of communication.
- It was fun talking to you. Bye, Rod.
- Jerry--!
[♪♪♪]
LAUREL: I'll make a sandwich.
DOROTHY: Good idea.
- Ham sandwich.
- I wanna say one thing.
- You do listen to me.
- Well, I love you. Mayo?
DOROTHY: Yeah.
JERRY: --repression, as a religion.
When my daddy retired from
the United Way after 38 years...
...he said, "I wish they'd given me
a more comfortable chair."
RAY: Wait, wait, wait.
And then my dad died.
My mom took me to the zoo,
and I loved the zoo. And--
Wait.
- I want to tell you more about my dad.
- No, let's go to the zoo.
Okay, okay....
You're right. Heh, heh.
It's just my whole life,
I've been trying to talk. I mean...
...really talk.
But no one wants to listen.
You know that feeling?
- They just look at you--
- Let's go right now, let's go to the zoo.
Ray, the zoo, you know--
The fucking zoo's closed, Ray.
[WHISPERS]
You said "fuck."
Yeah, I did. I....
- Is that--?
- [IN NORMAL VOICE] I won't tell.
Well, then I'm gonna
have to take you to the zoo.
[LAUREL & DOROTHY
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
- I gotta go to bed, my mom's coming.
- Ooh, wait, uh--
RAY:
I hear my mom. I gotta go to bed.
- Thanks for listening.
RAY: Sure.
Okay. Drinks, food,
and I called you a cab.
Good idea.
Oh, and we should keep our voices
down. I have a little boy asleep.
Right.
Our company.
Okay, okay. Look. A little....
A little speech before I go.
Do not worry about your future.
You and your son, we, are just fine.
You still have a job.
But let me tell you something
about Jerry Maguire, okay?
You come after me,
and you will lose.
No, because I am a survivor.
I'm a survivor!
Dorothy Boyd, you are
with the Lord of the Living Room.
The King of the Kingdom!
And I am...
...drunk.
We meet again.
[SIGHS]
Here.
Truth?
- Sure.
- I care about the job, of course.
But mostly, I just want to be inspired.
Me too.
What you wrote inspired me.
No, no, no. No, hey.
I'm working with you
because of that memo.
I loved that memo.
It's a mission statement.
[CAR HORN HONKS]
Well....
Sorry about the hand.
Huh?
You know that feeling?
You're not completely
embarrassed yet...
...but you glimpse
tomorrow's embarrassment?
Don't worry about it, boss.
Oh, shit. You said "boss."
- Yeah, I did.
- Now I feel like Clarence Thomas.
- No, don't feel like Clarence Thomas.
- I do. I feel like Clarence Thomas.
- I'm, like, harassing you right now.
- Well, I may not sue. Ha-ha-ha.
- Good evening.
Look, don't worry, okay?
I mean, don't--
We'll be okay because
I am gonna take my one client...
...and we are gonna go all the way.
Because, hey.... I'm back.
Don't worry.
[CHUCKLES]
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
[MAN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[♪♪♪]
[MEN GRUNTING]
- Way to go, Rod. Good catch.
ROD: You can't--
COACH:
All right, good job.
- Gotta talk about his contract, Dennis.
- Meet me at The Crocodile, 8:00.
You bet.
MAN:
Yeah.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
Thank you.
JERRY: Tell me you got lost
on the way last night.
I know you wouldn't do that
to a friend.
- Something came up.
JERRY: It's okay.
$10 million for four years.
- You're dreaming.
- Ten for four. It's a deal.
Look.
- He's got an attitude problem.
- He listens to me. I can help you.
- He's a shrimp.
- A shrimp?
Rod broke every receiving record
you had last year.
I want a prototypical
wide receiver who's 6'3", 220.
Not some guy
who's 5'10" and bitches.
Dennis, I'm asking you...
...for a favor.
I introduced you to your wife.
We've spent Christmases together.
- Holiday cheer. Dennis.
- Jerry, you're reaching.
I'm asking you for a favor. Don't do
this to me. We have history, Dennis.
We got history, all right, Jerry.
You drove the prices up on me for years.
- It's your turn at the back of the line.
- No, no. Dennis, don't--
[♪♪♪]
I started talking with Dennis Wilburn
about your renegotiation this morning.
Talking?
Jerry Rice, Andre Reed, Chris Carter.
I smoked all these fools!
MAN:
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
ROD:
Yet they are making the big sweet dollar.
They are making the kwan.
And you're talking.
- Kwan? That's your word?
- Hell yeah, that's my word.
Some dudes might have coin,
but they'll never have kwan.
What is--?
It means love, respect, community
and dollars. The entire package.
The kwan.
Great word.
- Towel?
- No, I air-dry.
Listen, Rod. I say this
with great respect for you.
But those players you mentioned
are marquee players.
- And this deal where, you know, we--
- Marquee?
Here's what I'm saying. This is a
renegotiation. We want more from them.
Show them your pure joy
of the game.
Bury the attitude a bit,
and show them--
Wait.
- You're telling me to dance.
- No. I'm saying...
...to get back to the guy
who first started playing. Remember?
Way back when you were a kid,
it wasn't just about the money, was it?
Was it?
Do your job.
Don't you tell me to dance!
- Fine.
- Hey. Hey!
- Fine!
- I am an athlete.
- I am not an entertainer!
- Fine!
These are the ABC's of me, baby.
I do not dance, and I do not start
preseason without a contract!
- Fine, fine, fine!
- Jerry, talk to me.
Breathe! Breathe, Jerry.
I am out here for you.
You don't know what it's like
to be me out here for you.
It is an up-at-dawn,
pride-swallowing siege...
...that I will never fully
tell you about, okay?!
God. Help me!
Help me, Rod.
Help me help you.
[LAUGHING]
I'm sorry.
You are hanging on
by a very thin thread.
And I dig that about you!
No contract? I'll help me,
I'll help you, help everybody!
- That's my man.
- Hey, I'm happy to entertain you.
Help me! Help me!
- See you in Los Angeles.
- Jerry. Come on, man.
Hey. See, that's the difference
between us.
You think we're fighting.
And I think we're finally talking.
[♪♪♪]
Unless you love everybody,
you can't sell anybody.
Dennis Wilburn is faxing in the new offer
for Tidwell on Thursday morning.
- He said you'd be happy-- Glad.
- Did he say happy or glad?
Glad. He said glad. Glad.
- Glad is good. Glad is good.
- Yeah.
- Glad's good.
- We could sure use that commission.
Here. I did a rundown
on where you stand financially.
I spent most of what
I had in this condo.
- You don't have to explain.
- Devalued and....
Look, the other night....
Uh, I wanna apologize.
Yeah. What happened there?
We're coworkers.
We can't have atmosphere.
Mm. No. I'm really relieved
that you said that.
You know, the other night,
I was lonely.
I felt you understood something.
- But we've got a company to think about.
- Yes.
I will never take advantage
of you in that way again.
- Good.
- You walked out on a job for me.
This is how I repay you--
Can this be right?
Exactly.
I know this is one of those times when
you need to be alone with your thoughts.
Think about everything that's gone wrong
and how to fix it.
And, you know, just be alone.
Alone. Alone, alone, alone.
Alone.
- You wanna go out to dinner?
- I know a great place.
The guy's a loser so I broke up with him,
and then he started stalking me.
- What is her definition of stalking?
WOMAN 1: Coming over uninvited.
[WOMEN LAUGHING]
"Coming over uninvited"?
So Romeo on your balcony is a stalker?
- Exactly.
WOMAN 2: Oh, stop.
[WOMEN ARGUING
INDISTINCTLY]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Excuse me. Ladies?
Ladies? Hi.
Good evening,
I'm looking for Dorothy Boyd.
She's in the kitchen.
- Laurel. Hello.
- Jerry, hi.
- Where are you taking her tonight, huh?
- You're the nanny?
- Au pair.
- Au pair? I see.
- Yeah.
- Jerry!
Whoa. Hey. Hey.
He likes you.
My goodness. Look, look.
Ray, I've got some gifts for you.
- Do you like presents?
- Yeah, yeah.
Good, all right.
Arizona Cardinals.
It's the team Rod plays for.
- Dropping your laundry off?
- Want a Steelers hat?
LAUREL: For me? Wow.
- I got some things.
- I've got it in gray too.
RAY: Thanks, Jerry.
JERRY: You're very welcome. Oh,
my goodness. Look what I've got here.
This is an energy bar.
This will keep you up all night.
See, that's not a good idea.
I'll take that. Aunt Laurel will eat that.
Hey. It looks like you've got a fan.
Wow. That's more than a dress,
that's an Audrey Hepburn movie.
Yeah. I guess I got a little revved up
at the idea of an evening among adults.
- No offense, buddy.
- Jerry, you meet Chad? Chad, Jerry.
Yeah, we did. Am I dressed okay?
I didn't realize--
[WOMEN CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
Hey, listen, Chad.
Don't let him stay up too late.
Tonight, I'm going to teach Ray here
about jazz.
Good. That'll put him to sleep early.
Heh.
I want to go too.
Oh, no, no, sweetheart, you stay here
with Chad and be good. Give me a kiss.
- Let's go. Seriously, let's go. Let's go.
- Hm? Okay.
- Good night.
Give me a hug.
[♪♪♪]
LAUREL:
Hey.
- Go ahead, I'll meet you at the car.
- Okay.
You just forgot the keys, no big deal.
That is the first time I have ever seen him
kiss a man just like a dad!
- Wasn't that thrilling?
- Yeah, it was.
- He must have been needing that.
- Take it easy.
Don't cry at the beginning of a date.
Cry at the end, like I do.
- You all right? All right.
- Okay, okay.
And don't be a shoulder
for him to cry on either.
- Keys.
- Oh, keys.
Oh, dear.
♪ She'll let you in her house ♪
♪ If you come knocking late at night ♪
♪ She'll let you in her mouth ♪
♪ If the words you say are right ♪♪
[PEOPLE CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
JERRY: Ever since you've met me,
I've been--
[GIBBERING]
[LAUGHING]
It was laziness, my breakup
with Avery. You know that saying?
"It's nobody's fault." It's a lie.
Somebody is always to blame.
You go for it like you do a job.
You work at it.
But maybe love shouldn't be
such hard work.
Yeah, maybe so.
But it's not every day you say goodbye
to a woman like that.
MAN: A song for the lovers?
- No. No, thank you.
- No, no, we work together.
- This is like an office meeting.
But I know what you mean.
It wasn't like my marriage to Roger
was any good, even before....
[MARIACHI BAND
PLAYING IN DISTANCE]
Before?
- Jerry?
- What?
Let's not tell our sad stories.
I'll be back in just a second, okay?
[MARIACHI BAND PLAYING
DOWN-TEMPO BALLAD]
DOROTHY: They sting.
Let Chad catch the bee in the glass.
He won't hurt him. You've got such
a good heart, buddy. I love you.
♪ Your temperamental, moody side ♪
♪ The one you always try to hide
From me ♪♪
[CONTINUES SINGING IN SPANISH]
Well, this would be good night.
Good night.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- See you tomorrow.
- It's a big day.
- Mm-hm.
Well, good night.
Good night.
[♪♪♪]
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
Oops.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
- Let me fix this.
- Good idea.
I think you should not come in.
Or come in.
- Depending on how you feel.
- The same to you.
No.
I have to go in.
I live here.
Right.
I'll come in.
Good.
Are you sure we want to do this?
- Oh, hell, yes.
- Yeah.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- How is he? Did he have a good night?
- Yeah, he's asleep.
- Good.
- How'd it go with sport-boy?
Still going.
- All right.
- Heh, heh.
Chad. How are you?
Treat her right.
- Yeah, uh....
- She's....
- She's great.
- Yeah.
And, uh....
I know this might be a bit awkward,
but I want you to use this.
No, look. God.... Chad. No, no.
This is Miles Davis and John Coltrane.
Stockholm 1963.
Two masters of freedom, playing
before their art was corrupted...
...by a zillion cocktail-lounge performers...
...who destroyed the legacy
of the only American art form:
Jazz.
I've put some Mingus on there too.
- No barriers, no boundaries.
- Chad, I got it.
[JAZZ MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[CHUCKLES]
[LAUGHING]
DOROTHY:
Come here.
You know this is gonna
change everything.
Promise?
What is this music?
[BOTH LAUGHING]
[JAZZ MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING]
[DOROTHY & JERRY LAUGHING]
[CHUCKLES]
[UPBEAT ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
I love getting up in the morning!
I clap my hands and say:
"This is gonna be a great day!"
♪ We salute you ♪♪
Great! Did you really need to do this?
[TOY GUITAR PLAYS TUNE]
I'm getting him up, so don't worry.
What? I'm just waiting for coffee.
I don't care.
- Just tell me one thing.
- No.
- Why--?
- I'm worried.
I'm worried you're putting your faith
in this guy...
...who, because of the way
things are going...
...might not have an emotional marble
in his head.
- Please, if I start talking....
- You "please."
DOROTHY:
What am I for taking the opportunity?
LAUREL: Men are different people when
they're hanging onto the bottom rung.
DOROTHY:
Maybe I am taking advantage.
Does that make me a bad person? Huh?
Look, all I know is I found
someone popular and charming...
...and not so nice to me, and he died,
okay?
So why should I let this guy go? Why?
When everything in my body
says that this one is the one?
LAUREL: Take it easy.
I was just looking for a few fun details.
Oh. Well, why didn't you say so?
Well, I don't know if you're interested
in this one little detail.
- Yeah, what?
- I was just about to tell you....
Uh-huh?
That I love him.
I do! I love him, I love him,
and I don't care what you think.
I love him for the man
he wants to be...
...and I love him for the man
that he almost is.
I love him, Laurel. I love him.
- I love him!
- Hi, Jerry.
Act natural.
Hi.
- Tell me he's not there.
- He's not there.
Oh, God.
- Easy, ladies, easy.
- Coffee, Jerry?
Oh, no, thanks. We bottom-feeders
prefer cereal first.
[LAUGHS]
RAY: Let's have Apple Jacks.
- Apple Jacks? Apple Jacks it is.
Dorothy.
Good morning, darling.
[GIGGLES]
Morning.
RAY: What's going on, Jerry?
- Well, a lot, actually.
We've got a big fax today.
We need this commission, buddy.
Need this commission. Milk?
RAY:
Yeah.
JERRY:
Cheers.
That was really great
of you this morning.
Look, let's just root for a big offer
so we can move out of this room...
...into a real office.
Would you mind? Thanks a lot.
Shit.
1.7 for three years?
Man, we owe more than that!
It's okay. This is how the game
is played. I'll go back to them.
And say what? "Please remove
your dick from my ass"?
- Marcee.
- I'm sorry.
- I'm just a little pregnant right now.
- That's okay. That's okay.
ROD: I feel like crying.
- Let's not take this emotionally.
- We're gonna roll with this problem.
- What are you so calm about?
What do you mean, roll with this
problem? Don't take it emotionally?
You haven't gotten emotional...
- ...enough over this man!
- Well, I disagree.
- Give me Bob Sugar on the phone.
- Marcee....
- You wanna leave me?
- A lot of agents say a lot of shit.
- So, what do you stand for?
JERRY: You wanna leave me?
MARCEE:
What do you stand for?!
How about a little piece of integrity?
There's so much greed in the world...
...I don't know what to tell my son!
Except, "Here.
Have a look at a guy who isn't yelling,
'Show me the money!"'
You know he's broke? He is broke
and working for you for free.
Broke! Broke, broke, broke.
- I'm not as good at the insults as she is.
- No. That was pretty good.
No shit.
Let me show you something.
- Here. Rod, read this.
- Whoa. No, no, no.
I just think that--
I think it's important.
I appreciate this, but....
You should be proud of that.
I still think they should read it.
Tell me what to do. Tell me to
eat lima beans, I'll eat lima beans.
You tell me this is the best we can get,
all we can get--
MARCEE: All we can get?
- I'm talking with my agent.
This is what you're gonna do.
You're gonna reject that shitty contract.
Play out your existing shitty contract,
and you're a free agent next year.
Come on, hey, hey.
Baby, this is us. You and me.
We determine our worth.
Baby, you are a strong, proud...
...surviving, splendid black man.
Marcee...
...you are the shit.
Oh, baby.
- If you get injured, you get zero.
- Won't happen. I'm strong in mind.
- That's right.
- Rod.
- It's a risk.
- You bet on me, like I bet on you.
Huh?
You know? My man!
- You know?
MARCEE: Yeah, you know?
You know, baby?
[♪♪♪]
- Aw, you're so crazy.
ROD: I love you, baby.
MARCEE: Let me kiss that head.
ROD: Come on, girl. Thank you, boo.
Thank you, boo.
[MARCEE KISSING]
I'm taking that job in San Diego.
- Don't even talk about that yet.
- You can't afford me.
You can't afford me, Jerry.
I'll find something fast for Tidwell.
- I refuse to be a drain.
- We'll stay afloat.
We will stay afloat. Don't leave.
- Get on the camel.
- Been on my ass all day.
I told you to put the camera low.
- He's my client.
- Then get him on the camel.
- I'm gonna.
- We don't need a camel.
You got Rod Tidwell.
- It's Camel Chevrolet.
ROD: You see that? That's how I feel.
[CAMEL GRUNTING]
- Do you hear him? He's feeling my pain!
- Get on the camel!
- I'm pulling him from this.
- Not saying that. Just get rid of the camel.
- This isn't what I had in mind.
- You're pulling him?
You're right, let's bounce.
Pulling him? Then you shouldn't
have begged me to hire him.
I know you needed that commission, but
we won't bring Reebok to their knees...
...with no regional Camel ad.
Excuse me, darling.
Can I ask you a question
unrelated to your career?
What, are we gonna be friends now?
What do you know about
dating a single mother?
Plenty. I was raised by a single mother.
Tell me. Because I think after this,
she'll have to take that job in San Diego.
First of all, single mothers don't date.
They've-- Watch yourself.
They don't date. They've been to
the circus. You know what I mean? Heh.
They've been to the puppet show
and they've seen the strings.
- Do you love her?
- How do I know?
What do you mean?
You know when you know.
I'm feeling little-- I don't want her to go.
I've been hanging out at her place a lot.
Wait, wait. That right there, that's bullshit.
You gotta be fair to her.
Single mother, man, that's a sacred thing.
You gotta have the talk.
She loves you. If you don't love her,
you have got to tell her.
The kid's amazing. He....
[ROD CHUCKLING]
I feel you. I feel you, dog.
But a real man wouldn't shoplift
the pootie from a single mother.
I didn't shoplift the pootie.
All right. I shoplifted the pootie.
[♪♪♪]
You know, John Coltrane
once said to Miles Davis....
When you say goodbye to him,
just be cool.
- Okay.
- What's meant to be will be.
You'll still see each other. I'm losing
the only person that ever listens to me...
...and you only listen partially.
- No, no. Quit making me laugh.
- You're doing the right thing.
You need to start your life. He needs
a warm body to cushion the fall.
Check out Exhibit A on the front lawn.
Look at that.
We should hang out.
LAUREL:
I'm almost sympathetic to the guy.
Goodbye.
All right. Goodbye.
Bye.
Listen, you're gonna like it
in San Diego, Ray.
Ray?
[RAY SNIFFLES]
It's gonna be great there.
You'll make a lot of friends.
- I'm gonna see you this weekend.
- Go ahead and go.
Go ahead and go.
- Sure you're okay to drive this?
- This rig? No problem.
- I'll see you this weekend.
- Okay.
Get in the car. Get in the car, Dorothy.
I'll see you in a couple of days,
and I love you.
I love you too.
- What?
- Nothing.
JERRY: I'll see you soon.
DOROTHY: Okay.
Look, if this weekend
should turn into next month...
...and next month turns into whenever,
don't make a joke of your life.
Go back and read what you wrote.
You're better than the rest of them.
You're better than the Bob Sugars.
Don't forget that.
Wait! Wait a second.
No, no! Oh, God.
- We can save on medical, rent....
- Don't listen to him.
What if we stay together?
What if we got married?
- If I said that, would you stay?
- Don't do that. Don't say that unless--
Well, say it if you want to.
Will you marry me?
What are you thinking?
[BOTH LAUGHING]
DOROTHY:
Laurel!
We're getting married.
Mm....
MINISTER: Do you, Jerry Maguire,
take this woman to be your wife?
JERRY:
Not yet.
MINISTER: And do you, Dorothy Boyd,
take this man to be your husband?
DOROTHY:
Almost.
MINISTER:
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
DOROTHY: Okay, sweetie.
ROD: Aw, yeah.
[MARIACHI BAND PLAYING
DOWN-TEMPO BALLAD]
♪ Mother, mother
There's too many of you cryin' ♪
[ALL CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY
AND LAUGHING]
♪ Brother, brother, brother
Far too many of you dyin' ♪
♪ You know we've got to find a way ♪
MAN:
Get down, Ray!
♪ To bring some lovin' here today, yeah ♪
♪ Picket lines, sister
And picket signs ♪
I should go.
♪ Don't punish me
Through brutality ♪
Come on, brother.
Come on and talk to me, brother.
♪ 'Cause you can see ♪
♪ -Oh, what's goin' on
- What's goin' on ♪
♪ -What's goin' on
- What's goin' on ♪♪
We did it.
We sure did.
You fuck this up, I'll kill you.
I'm glad we had this talk.
[ALL CHEERING
AND APPLAUDING]
MARCEE:
Oh, look at them.
Oh. She is so beautiful.
[ORGAN PLAYING
UPBEAT MUSIC ON VIDEO]
I do not believe they have this on tape.
MAN:
Hey, that's my bro.
ROD:
♪ Mother, mother ♪♪
See, now I'm gonna release this
to ESPN.
[MARCEE LAUGHS]
- You think I'm joking.
- No, it's all right. I know where you live.
[LAUGHS]
You didn't have the talk, did you?
Hm?
No.
Well, this definitely
was another way to go. Ha-ha-ha.
Hey, hey. Hey, Dorothy, come here.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. and Mrs. Maguire. Ha-ha-ha.
RAY: Yay! Yay!
- We're gonna have a great season!
Woo-hoo!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
Scotty, Tidwell did four for 36.
TOM: Hey, Jerry.
JERRY: Hey, Tom.
- Jerry.
- Dennis.
- He's having a good game. So far.
- You bet he is.
You're gonna miss him next year.
[MOUTHING]
Loser.
I've got a great team behind me
and I'm loving it. I'm loving life.
[CHEERING]
That's my mo'fo!
[ALL GASPING]
Uh-uh. Come here.
Come here. Why don't you be the first
man in your family not to use that word?
And then we'll let you live.
Now go kiss Daddy, quick.
Come on, now!
Come on, Rod!
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
Now, I saw you limping a little bit
after the first quarter.
Yeah, I--
[MICROPHONE FEEDS BACK]
I sprained my ankle on the ice out there.
It was cold. Twisted my ankle.
REPORTER:
All right. Thanks.
Okay, that went well.
Anybody else here worth talking to? No.
All right, let's get out of here.
- How's your head?
- Bubblicious.
MAN 1: Can you sign?
- Hey.
- How are you?
MAN 2: Hey, Rod.
- How you doing, man?
- Hanging in there. Good game.
That quarterback sucks, man.
He's gonna get me killed.
He's throwing high
and across the middle. I'm worried.
I'm worried I'm getting my brains blown
because you weren't asshole enough...
...to get me my 10 million
three fucking months ago. Shit.
You take care of yourself out on that field,
you hear? You're my entire client roster.
Don't I know this?
Now go home to your wife.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- What are you doing here?
- You could've told me on the phone.
- How about dedication, personal attention?
- You don't want to go home, do you?
- What are you saying?
I'm just trying to talk to you.
How's your marriage, Jerry?
The husband and wife thing,
how is that?
Huh?
- Not everyone has what you have.
- Then why did you get married?
- I'm just asking as a friend.
- You want an answer?
Loyalty.
She was loyal.
I mean, you know,
everything grew from there.
It just...
...grew from there.
- That's an answer.
- That's the answer.
It's not sexy. Shit!
But that's an answer.
"Tell him what he's won, Bob."
"A beautiful marriage!"
[ROD LAUGHING]
Shit!
Well, I'm happy to entertain you,
as always, Rod.
- Shit.
- I-- I have a question for you, Rod.
- Are we really friends?
- Why not?
Friends can tell each other anything
if we have our "friends hats" on, right?
- Yeah, I think so.
- All right.
I'll tell you why you don't have
your $10 million yet.
Right now. You are a paycheck player.
You play with your head, not your heart.
In your personal life? Heart.
But when you get on the field,
it's all about what you didn't get...
...who's to blame,
who underthrew the pass...
...who's got the contract you don't,
who's not giving you your love!
That is not what inspires people.
That is not what inspires people!
Just shut up. Play the game, play it
from your heart. And you know what?
I will show you the kwan. And that's
the truth, man! That's the truth.
Can you handle it?
It's just a question between friends.
[IMITATING ROD]
You know?
[IN NORMAL VOICE] Oh. When they call
you shrimp, I'm the one who defends you!
- I don't wanna be friends no more.
- Fine.
Quit using that word "kwan."
That's my word!
- I'll see you in L.A.
- No heart. No heart?!
I'm all heart, motherfucker!
[♪♪♪]
[GRUNTING]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
MAN:
How many concussions has he had?
But he keeps a brother--
I ain't get no respect. This is bullshit.
I'm making miracles happen.
Oh, you guys. I go to see this
so-called black film the other day, okay?
Honey, no more salt for you.
Your biggest game is coming up.
I don't want you dehydrated
for Monday Night Football.
[TYSON & RAY GIGGLING]
Anyway, 20 minutes of coming
attractions. All black films, all violent.
- Brothers shooting brothers.
- I hate you going to the movies alone.
- Oh, baby.
- My Pisces queen.
Oh, baby.
- I hate seeing movies without you.
- Heh-heh-heh.
- I won't do it anymore, okay?
ROD: Okay.
MARCEE: I promise.
[MARCEE & ROD KISSING]
MARCEE: Ooh, ooh, another one.
ROD: Mm-hm.
MARCEE:
Chee-chee bear.
- Baby.
- Baby!
- Oh, baby.
- Baby.
- Oh, baby!
- Now?
ROD: Baby, baby, baby now!
Baby.
DOROTHY: Ray, it's time to go.
- Come on.
- You got them?
- Hey, you take Visa? Take it!
What were you thinking tonight...
...watching them go through the entire
human emotional experience?
I was thinking,
"I hope he doesn't get injured."
I felt responsible.
Sometimes I can't tell at all
what's going on in your head.
[CHUCKLES]
Ah....
And I really don't know your noises yet.
- Well, when you wonder, ask me.
- Okay, I will.
- I thought I just did.
- Heh.
- Why do you love me?
[DOOR OPENS]
Jerry, can I come in and watch TV?
- In just a minute.
- Just for a few minutes, buddy.
Oh....
[SPORTS ANNOUNCER
CHATTERING ON TV]
[♪♪♪]
LAUREL: Hang in there.
He's not going anywhere.
DOROTHY:
I know.
- Can we talk about something else?
- I don't think so.
I'm incapable of small talk.
But that's why you love me, right?
I'm about personal attention.
This is my life.
I'm available to you
24 hours a day.
Call me anytime. I'll be in Phoenix
tomorrow for Monday Night Football.
I can be in Indiana
by 11:30 Tuesday morning.
Just give me 20 minutes.
I'm not asking for an answer now.
I'll call you tomorrow. Just enjoy your day.
Tell Douglas hello, would you please?
All right, thank you.
Same to you, Marilee. Bye-bye.
Indiana, Tuesday. I'll be there.
It's my fault.
What?
It's not fair to you, this whole thing.
Come here.
Tell me. Let me help.
I took advantage of you.
And the worst of it is I'm not alone.
I did this with a kid.
I was just on some wild ride
where I thought that....
That I was in love enough
for both of us.
I pretended that proposal by the car
was real...
...and it might have
just been a hypothetical.
I did this.
And at least I can do something
about it now.
I'm not a guy who runs.
I stick.
Well, I don't need you to stick.
What do you want?
My soul or something?
- Why not? I deserve that.
- What if I'm not built that way?
- I think we made a mistake.
- No, listen, what if it's true?
"Great at friendship, bad at intimacy."
It's the theme of my bachelor film,
for God's sake.
I know, I watched it.
I sort of know it by heart.
- I don't like to give up.
- Please, Jerry.
My need to make the best of things
and your need to be responsible....
If one of us doesn't say something
about it now, we could lose 10 years...
...being polite.
Let's just call this next road trip
what it really is:
A nice long break.
What about Ray?
Well, you'll be friends.
- Friends?
- Yeah, friends.
- Of course you'll be friends.
- I'll take him to the zoo.
So this break is a breakup?
That's--
Come on, Jerry.
You know this isn't easy for me.
On the surface, everything looks fine.
I've got this great guy.
And he loves my kid.
And he sure does like me a lot.
And I can't live like that.
It's not how I'm built.
[♪♪♪]
♪ She's got a secret garden ♪
♪ Where everything you want ♪
♪ Where everything you need ♪
♪ Will always stay ♪
♪ A million miles away ♪♪
If this is empty, this doesn't matter.
[WHISPERS]
It was just a mission statement.
[SOBBING]
WOMAN:
Put your arms up, please. All right.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
Hey, Rod, buddy. I was wondering
where you were. How's it going?
Get out of here. Go.
- Where's your agent?
- I don't know.
Rod, you belong with the big boys.
You belong with the big money.
- Hey! Hey. Get away from my guy.
- You're fucking Rod Tidwell!
- Hey, Jerry, I was just telling--
- Just go. Flee.
This is a nice moment for you.
I'm gonna let you have it.
Give me a call, Rod.
Say hi to Marcee.
- Thanks for coming.
- I missed you.
What can I say?
You're all I've got.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Frank Gifford
with Al Michaels and Dan Dierdorf.
Welcome to Tempe, Arizona,
Sun Devil Stadium.
The story tonight is the Cardinals.
They are still alive for a playoff spot.
[ON TV]
The reason for that...
...is the outstanding play of Rod Tidwell.
We'll talk about that too.
[CHEERING]
The Dallas Cowboys continue to roll,
they know they're in the playoffs.
Going for a second consecutive
Super Bowl.
Here's the deal. If Arizona
wins tonight and next week...
...the Cardinals will make the playoffs
for the first time in 21 years.
Whoo!
Better not mess up
for Monday Night Football.
What? Everybody knows he gets
nervous for nationally televised games.
GIFFORD: The Cowboys continue
their mission on Monday Night Football.
- Hey, Shannon.
- Hi, Jerry, good game.
- Yeah. Hey, great column this morning.
SHANNON: Thanks.
Fuck you, punk!
[MEN GRUNTING]
Boy, guys, it's a real bruiser
out there tonight.
MICHAELS:
The Cardinals refuse to go quietly...
...into the desert night...
...as their seemingly interminable season
winds down. I'm just trying to be poetic.
DIERDORF:
Wax on, Al. Wax on.
[GRUNTING]
MICHAELS: Ouch!
DIERDORF: A tough hit on Tidwell.
Nothing poetic about that.
I would have taken it for the touchdown.
MICHAELS:
That's his sixth catch of the night.
Split to the right.
Swenson looks that way.
Enough for a first down
at the 19-yard line.
DIERDORF: Another savage hit
across the middle on Rod Tidwell.
MICHAELS:
They are working Tidwell, aren't they?
- Hey. What does Daddy always say?
- It looks worse than it really is.
That's right.
TEE PEE: He ain't gonna have
nothing left. He'll kill himself.
- Can you be quiet?
- What did I say?
Less than two minutes to play.
Dallas leading by three.
Second down and one now
at the Dallas 1 1-yard line.
Swenson backs to pass. A blitz!
And down he goes!
He's sacked for a six-yard loss.
DIERDORF: Good move
coming with the blitz after Swenson.
GIFFORD:
He had too many men in that pattern.
They just did not have enough
to pick up the blitz.
[MEN CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
QUARTERBACK:
90 razor, X-out on one, ready?
ALL:
Break!
All right. Here we go, here we go!
MICHAELS: He had a chance
to get rid of it. Had to tuck it away.
From second and one,
they've now gone to third and seven.
In the waning moments of this game,
Dallas 1 7, Arizona 14.
Tidwell in motion.
Moving back to his left now.
Play fake. Swenson, protected well,
lofts one to the end zone.
Tidwell! Touchdown, Cardinals!
GIFFORD:
Did you see him go up on that ball?
DIERDORF:
He held onto the football.
He's still down on the ground. Tidwell,
upside down, hits the ground hard.
- He maintains control of the football.
MICHAELS: He's hurt too.
DIERDORF: He's not getting up. Look
at the faces of these Cardinals' players.
Oh, my God. Get up, baby.
MICHAELS: The trainer comes
racing out. It's Tidwell's ninth catch.
Oh, my God.
MICHAELS:
He gives Arizona the lead.
Hey!
GUARD:
Hey, hey, hey!
DOCTOR 1: Can you hear me?
DOCTOR 2: Blink! Come on, blink!
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING ON TV]
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING ON TV]
Why are they cutting to a commercial?
Show me what's wrong with my husband.
- Told you he was too small for the NFL.
- Shut up.
- I'm telling the truth. I'm keeping it real!
- Tee Pee, shut up!
[PHONE RINGING]
Can't you be loyal to your brother?
Get the hell out of my house! Get out!
Hello? Hold on.
It's Jerry Maguire.
Punk!
Jerry? Oh, my God, Jerry,
I am freaking out.
- Marcee, he's unconscious.
- Jerry, Jerry.
No, I know. Just stay calm. Keep
the lines open, I will call you back.
There's good doctors on the field.
Just stay calm.
You have to tell me something.
I am freaking here.
Please, we gotta stay calm.
Your family needs you to stay calm.
I know, but my whole life
is this family...
...and it does not work without him!
DIERDORF [ON TV]:
All eyes at Sun Devil Stadium...
...are focused on Rod Tidwell.
MARCEE: I am so sorry about
everything I said about your job.
Just do whatever you can
to get Rod to me, please.
Just do whatever you can.
Please, Jerry.
DIERDORF:
At a time like this...
...you just hope his family
is not watching this.
It could be his neck.
It could be his back.
Blink, baby!
Come on, wake up!
WOMAN:
We love you, Rod!
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[CLAPS]
[♪♪♪]
DOCTOR 1:
Rod? Rod? Can you hear me?
Can you hear me?
Do you know where you are?
DIERDORF:
The trainer's still trying to revive Rod.
You'd love to see some movement.
- Rod?
DOCTOR 2: Let's get him off the field.
- No.
DOCTOR 2: Get the gurney.
Let's get him off the field now.
No, wait, wait. Just let me
enjoy this for a minute.
DIERDORF [ON TV]:
You're looking for any movement.
Is that his head coming up?
GIFFORD:
He's gonna try to get up.
[♪♪♪]
And he is getting up.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Oh, my God. Look at him!
Mommy, he's okay.
[ALL CHEERING]
Oh, my God!
MICHAELS: Everybody's
standing at Sun Devil Stadium.
He's up on his feet
and the crowd loves it.
[CROWD CHEERING
AND HORNS BLOWING]
ROD:
Whoo!
[LAUGHING]
Here's a guy who's has been very
truculent with the media, standoffish....
DIERDORF: We're happy for you.
GIFFORD: He'll get a flag on this.
Who cares!
[ROD CHEERING]
MAN: Congratulations.
- Thank you. Hell of a game.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
Jerry. Jerry. Maguire!
[MOUTHING]
You are gonna pay.
I know. I know.
It's Tidwell. Come on.
[REPORTERS SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
ROD:
Where's Jerry?
You did it.
You did.
Why don't we have
that kind of relationship?
Psh.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
ROD:
Is that your porty or mine?
Dorothy?
Marcee. No, no, no, he's right here.
He's right here.
It's Marcee. She couldn't
get through on your phone.
We did it. I love you.
I love you so much!
[♪♪♪]
Oh! Yeah.
[ROD SOBBING]
I love you!
Whoo!
I love you, Tyson.
I love you, baby.
How's the baby?
How's Katie?
Oh, I love you so much.
No, I'm okay. You know
ain't nothing gonna happen to me.
[♪♪♪]
The problem is, Alice, you were
saying earlier, the biorhythms.
[WOMEN LAUGHING]
I was saying
the neural pathways are set.
And that's why it's hard
for people to change.
That's why behavior
doesn't change very often.
[WOMEN CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
I'm sorry, these stupid holidays
make me feel more divorced.
You know? With the songs,
the constant chocolate-eating....
[WOMEN CONTINUE CHATTERING]
I have a confession to make.
I've listened to you all
tell a thousand sob stories.
I've been very judgmental.
Maybe you're all correct.
Men are the enemy.
WOMAN:
No, they're not the enemy.
But I still love the enemy.
[WOMEN CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
Hello. Hello.
I'm looking for my wife.
Wait.
Okay, okay.
Okay.
If this is where it has to happen,
then this is where it has to happen.
I'm not letting you get rid of me.
How about that?
This used to be my specialty. I was good
in a living room. They'd send me in there...
...I'd do it alone.
And now, I just....
I don't know.
But tonight...
...our little project, our company
had a very big night.
A very, very big night.
But it wasn't complete.
It wasn't nearly close to being
in the same vicinity as complete...
...because I couldn't share it with you.
I couldn't hear your voice...
...or laugh about it with you.
I missed my-- I missed my wife.
We live in a cynical world.
A cynical world.
And we work in a business
of tough competitors.
I love you.
You...
...complete me.
And I just--
Shut up.
Just shut up.
You had me at "hello."
[WOMEN SIGHING]
WOMAN: You know this is the best
talking group I've ever been in.
Your father leaves home on Christmas
Eve, leaves your family all alone.
Your mother had to sweep at a prison
to earn enough money for your tuition.
Your brother loses a leg
in a tragic bass-fishing accident.
There's been a horrific list of things
that have happened to you in your life.
- I'm not gonna cry, Roy.
- Ha-ha-ha. We have some good news.
This has just been handed to me.
A memo, it's signed.
It's a contract, guaranteed.
Arizona Cardinals. Four years.
$11.2 million. You're gonna get to play
in Arizona, where it all started.
What do you think of that?
[SIGHS]
Oh, my God.
[SOBBING]
Whoo! Whoo!
I love everybody.
I love my wife! Whoo! Marcee!
- Baby, I love you.
ROD: I love my kids!
Tyson. My new baby, Katie.
My older brother, who got one leg,
and my younger brother, Tee Pee.
You're militant, but I ain't mad at you.
Nothing but love for you.
I love my teammates.
I'm leaving somebody out here.
- We only have a half-hour show.
- I send love to my offensive line.
- Nice to see you. Congratulations.
- Thank you. How are you?
Hey, Jerry, how you doing? You
remember Troy from the Super Bowl?
We met in '93.
- That's right. I enjoyed your memo.
- Thank you.
- A little slow but you come around.
- We're out of time. About 10 seconds--
ROD: Wait, wait, wait.
Roy, I'm forgetting somebody.
Jerry Maguire...
...my agent.
You are my ambassador of kwan, man.
Rod, thank you so much.
Congratulations. We'll be right back.
[RAY SQUEALS]
JERRY: How did you like the zoo, buddy?
- It was great!
One, two, three. Swing!
BOYS:
Hey, kid, throw the ball.
- Hurry up!
- Come on!
Whoa.
BOY 1: Good throw, man.
BOY 2: Nice throw.
Did you see?
Oh, no. Ha, ha. Let's go.
[♪♪♪]
JERRY: What?
DOROTHY: Nothing.
JERRY: I'm not saying we'll throw him
into the major leagues tomorrow...
...but if he's got natural talent,
pure joy for the game....
I know the right people
that will help develop his talent.
♪ When blackness was a virtue
And the road was full of mud ♪
♪ I come in from the wilderness
A creature void of form ♪
♪ Come in, she said
I'll give you shelter from the storm ♪
Hey, I don't have all the answers.
In life, to be honest,
I've failed as much as I've succeeded.
But I love my wife, I love my life...
...and I wish you my kind of success.
♪ If I pass this way again
You can rest assured ♪
♪ I'll always do my best for her
On that I give my word ♪
♪ in a world of steel-eyed death
And men who are fighting to be warm ♪
♪ Come in, she said
I'll give you shelter from the storm ♪
♪ Not a word was spoke between us
There was no risk involved ♪
♪ Nothing up to that point
Had even been resolved ♪
♪ Try imagining a place
Where it's always safe and warm ♪
♪ Come in, she said
I'll give you shelter from the storm ♪
♪ I was burned out from exhaustion
Buried in the hail ♪
♪ Poisoned in the bushes
And blown out on the trail ♪
♪ Hunted like a crocodile
Ravaged in the corn ♪
♪ Come in, she said
I'll give you shelter from the storm ♪
♪ Suddenly I turned around
And she was standing there ♪
♪ With silver bracelets on her wrists
And flowers in her hair ♪
♪ She walked up to me so gracefully
And took my crown of thorns ♪
♪ Come in, she said
I'll give you shelter from the storm ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
♪ I know the language of your laugh ♪
♪ Tripping over circumstance ♪
♪ I know the story of your walk ♪
♪ I taste the sugar and the salt ♪
♪ I taste and savor your little ways ♪
♪ The colors that you choose ♪
♪ To paint your day ♪♪