Welcome, everyone!
Tonight...
I have something very special.
For years,
I have entertained all of you.
- Have I not?
- Yes.
And some of you,
I have made very rich.
Hell, yeah.
Some...
have made me a little richer.
Time to place your bets.
Yeah.
- The videos.
- What do you think you are doing?
It was my idea.
You will not make a move unless I say.
Understood?
- Then let's begin.
- Yeah!
God, I hate this place.
I'm freezing my balls off out here.
You ain't got no balls.
Don't worry about the cold,
worry about the snakes.
Great, I hate snakes.
- Full gear, boss?
- Yeah. All right, listen up, guys.
We're on the clock. Harrigan, how far?
Alright, just over this ridge line,
we got about two hours' slot.
Hey, Michaels, do everybody a favor
and don't shoot yourself this time.
Check your comms.
Cooper, what're you doing?
No incendiaries, not necessary.
Oh, come on. How about a smoke, boss?
Everyone likes a little smoke.
We do this fast. Get the package,
get out. Simple snatch-and-grab.
Target is Cyrus Merrick, 61,
wanted for extortion, illegal gambling,
attempted murder... the list goes on.
- What's the bounty?
- You know what it is.
Half a million.
Deadly force is not an option, boys.
If we kill him, we don't get paid.
So, aim for the knees.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
Let's grab that payday.
Once I inject the drug,
- we will start the clock.
- Yeah!
I have pulled these two
homeless men off the streets.
No one knows they're here,
and no one will ever miss them.
Lange, you're point. Let's move out.
Copy.
Cooper, Michaels, with me.
Harrigan, Lange, to the right.
Travis, get up on top of this truck
and provide some cover.
On me.
Bargain is 1,000.
Which one will die first?
And how long will it take?
Hey, what you doing? Hey, stop it.
Hey, there's not supposed to be
any operations right now.
Would you get get out of that thing.
Don't kill them. The legs.
Aim for the legs.
Oh, shit.
Let's go.
Let him die, let him die.
Bail enforcement. Everybody on
the ground, hands behind your backs.
Get the laptop, wipe the hard drives
and meet me outside.
Cyrus Merrick, you're wanted
for illegal gambling,
extortion and attempted murder.
You're coming with us.
Fuck you.
11 o'clock!
It's over, Cyrus. Come with us,
and make it easy on yourself.
Easy? Nothing in this life
is easy, bounty hunter.
What have you done, Will?
How are we going
to explain this to the cops?
I understand a deal has been struck
between the defendant and the prosecution.
Yes, Your Honor. Mr. Tanner
has changed his plea to guilty.
Will Tanner.
You've been found guilty
of involuntary manslaughter
and are hereby sentenced
to two years suspended
and five years' probation to commence at
the end of your suspended sentence period.
Mr. Tanner...
I don't like bounty hunters.
We have police for a reason.
Trained professionals whose job
it is to go after the bad guys,
not gun-toting cowboys.
You so much as spit on my sidewalk,
and I will happily throw your ass in prison
for the full two years. Am I clear?
Yes, Your Honor.
I don't want to see you in here again.
I'm done with that life, Your Honor.
We're adjourned.
Dad.
Hey, Dad!
Hey, Dad.
Will?
Yeah, hand me a 3/16.
So, they didn't lock you up after all?
- No, I took a plea.
- You took a plea. You gave up.
- I killed a man, Dad.
- He was a criminal.
Piece of shit murderer.
You could've beat that.
Yeah. If I keep my nose clean,
I don't have to do any time.
- I got off easy.
- Easy?
Easy?
Yeah, you got off easy.
What about the family business?
It took me 30 years to build it.
You and that band of idiots,
took you 10 minutes to tear it down.
- I'm sorry.
- Sorry?
Sorry ain't gonna give me
back my reputation, boy.
Listen, Dad, I came here to tell you
that I can't do this anymore.
I'm out, Dad.
You came here to tell me you're out?
I give my boy the family business,
and he just pisses it away.
I should have known better.
Yeah, I should have known better.
Here we go.
- Thanks, Pop.
- Got it?
Yeah.
You know, Dad, all I want
in life is peace and quiet.
Just... no guns, no fugitives.
Right, right, right.
You never had what it takes, Will.
Too soft.
Too much like your mother.
God, I miss that woman.
Every goddamn day.
Hey, Danni. So you got something for me.
She's not pretty, but she does the job.
- Or has done, right?
- Yeah, I got it.
Sorry the pay's not better.
Tough times, you know?
Yeah. Tell me about it.
So, this place still your dad's?
- I actually own it with him now.
- Oh. Look at you.
- All right, go ahead and check her out.
- All right.
She capable of towing anything?
You're just gonna have
to find out for yourself.
Fair enough.
Not too shabby, right?
You know what, Danni?
I think she'll work just fine.
I'm going to put you on top
of the overtime list.
I don't know what to say.
- Thanks, Danni. I appreciate it.
- No problem.
So, Danni, I'll wait for your call.
Will, come in.
Hey, Danni, go ahead.
We got a breakdown on the Interstate.
Go to bunker 40.
About 10 minutes off, Danni.
Call for a tow?
- Will?
- Michaels? How you been, man?
I'm good. Well, I'm stuck in the middle
of nowhere, but good.
- So, what's going on?
- It just died on me.
I'll tell you what,
do me a favor, jump in there,
turn... turn it over for me
and I'll see what's up.
I think I see the problem.
Sit tight. I'll be right back.
Go ahead and try it now.
Thought the battery was dead,
but one of the contacts was loose.
- You're good to go.
- Thanks.
Look, I passed a little cantina
maybe a mile back.
Buy you a cold one for old time's sake?
Are you kidding me? Let's do it.
I'll see you over there.
Thank you.
- Check that out, Michaels. You see it?
- It's just a drone.
Oh, they're everywhere these days.
They're kids.
Hey, you okay?
Yeah, yeah. No, I'm fine.
You don't look okay.
What's going on?
What the hell's going on?
I have to kill you, Will.
Stay down. Just stay down. Stay down.
He's coming around here.
What the fuck you doing?
- Why are you doing this?
- I don't want to, I have to.
Or they'll kill me and my sister.
Who's gonna kill your sister?
Who threatened you?
Who threatened your sister? Talk to me.
Don't. Don't do it. Stop!
Michaels. Michaels!
So, the victim, Ryan Michaels,
he didn't want to kill you,
but he was trying to kill you.
I know how it sounds, Officer.
But it was self-defense.
You can ask anybody in there.
Friends don't try to kill
each other for no reason.
You've been convicted of manslaughter.
Is that right?
- That has nothing to do with this.
- Answer the question.
Yeah.
I compared the story
and the waitress has video...
Okay. Can you take her inside?
- Am I being charged?
- No.
Witnesses confirmed your story.
You're free to go. For now.
Don't leave the state.
A man died here, Mr. Tanner.
Someone's gotta pay for that.
- Yes, Officer.
- All right.
You can't stay out of trouble
- for 10 goddamn minutes, can you?
- Don't start, Dad.
This guy Michaels, he comes out
of nowhere with "Hey, how you doing?"
And then "Boom!" Tries to whack you
between cervezas? Seriously.
- Yeah, I know, it doesn't make any sense.
- No, it doesn't. Tell me what's going on.
- I don't know.
- Bullshit.
- Why don't you try taking my side for once?
- I'm here, aren't I?
People act out of self-interest,
that's life, true and simple.
Now, this friend of yours
tried to blow your head off.
Which means you did something.
- What did you do, Will?
- I don't know.
Who the hell is that?
- Hey, Will.
- Lange.
Dad, this is James Lange.
He was part of my team.
Yeah, I remember you.
Pretty good with a gun as I recall.
I can hold my own.
It's good to see you, man.
So, what brings you out this way?
Well, I heard what happened
with Michaels.
How did you hear?
It happened an hour ago.
- Word travels fast, you know.
- Show me your hand, shithead.
- Asshole's packing.
- I can explain that.
- Okay, okay.
- Nice and slow.
All right.
- PI.
- So you're a PI now.
It still doesn't answer my question.
- I have an answer for that, too. Okay.
- Slow as you can, little buddy.
I got it. It's a police scanner.
That's all.
They ran your sheet over the air.
I heard the whole thing.
I know why Michaels
tried to kill you, Will.
Take a ride with me.
There's something I want to show you.
Got a bad feeling about this.
Whatever is going on,
you let the cops handle it.
Pop, I know this guy. Come on,
just trust me, all right? Take it easy.
I don't like it.
Come on, let's go.
Did you keep in touch
with Michaels at all?
No. No. We just kind of went
our separate ways, you know?
Yeah.
- Until last night.
- What, you saw him?
Yeah, it turns out we got
something in common.
- And what's that?
- Somebody threatened to kill us.
Threatened to kill you.
What do you...
Who threatened to kill you?
You know, it'll all make sense
when we get there.
Get where? Where are we going?
Where are you taking me?
What you need to worry about
is right here, alright?
Focus on that. See that red circle?
Be there by 5:00
and then it's over.
You're not making any sense.
We're almost there.
Michaels was acting
awful strange. Tense.
Looking up everywhere he was going,
as if he was being watched.
- Just like you.
- Wish it was different, buddy.
Looks like I haven't got
a choice either.
Give me the tally board.
Ladies and gentlemen...
Will Tanner is still alive.
He survived for now.
You gambled.
And you lost.
It's time to make a new wager.
When and where he might die.
Ladies and gentlemen, place your bets!
Lange! What the hell's going on?
Come on, Will.
I'll make it easy on you, buddy.
One to the head, I promise.
Lange, stop.
Why are you trying to kill me?
I was just minding my own business,
trying to live my life.
And this shit, your shit,
lands in my lap!
Will!
Hot damn!
Hey, don't just stand there. Call 911!
Travis. Oh, shit.
Jesus.
Goddamn son of...
He always did have good instinct.
God.
Jesus.
Damn!
You! Behind the rocks!
Drop the weapon, and step out now!
No, lady. Just stay there. Stay there.
Drop the weapon now.
Let me see your hands.
No, no, no. You don't understand.
There's a shooter behind you on the ridge.
Throw the weapon out.
Let me see your hands!
I've just been shot.
You need to stay put, okay?
Well, I got a call about a man matching
your description, shot and killed someone.
So, I'm thinking you're the shooter.
You're wrong. It's not what you think.
You don't understand! Just stay there.
You have five seconds or a whole lot
of heat is coming your way.
- Okay. Nice and easy, okay?
- Nice and easy.
Put it down.
- Step away.
- No, no, no. I got to stay here,
and you need to stay there.
Listen to me. You need to stay there.
Listen to what I'm saying, please!
- Don't move. Don't come any closer.
- I'm going to ask you to shut up!
Listen to me. No. Don't come any closer.
- Don't. Don't.
- I'm coming to you.
Stay where you are.
- Sir, I'm going to approach you.
- You need to trust me.
- No, no.
- I'm going to apprehend you, sir.
God.
That's on you, Will.
Shit.
Get in!
Harrigan?
Shit.
Do you want to live or not? Come on!
Get in. What're you waiting for?
Get in!
- What the hell's going on?
- Don't I get brownie points for saving your life?
- Why is our old crew trying to kill me?
- Easy, big guy.
Calm down.
I'll tell you everything I know.
Will...
You so much as twitch wrong,
and I'll snap your neck.
Sounds fair.
Can we go inside? I could use a drink.
After you.
You want to tell me what you know?
- Who came at you today?
- Michaels.
Then, Lange.
- And Travis up on the rocks?
- Yeah.
A week ago, guess what piece
of shit shows up at my door.
- Raul Baccaro.
- Baccaro.
Cyrus Merrick's number two?
Well, since you smoked Cyrus,
he got promoted to number one.
Worse than Cyrus ever was.
- Well, what did he want?
- I had to do one thing...
Kill Will Tanner.
All right, gentlemen,
I want you to drink more.
And bet a lot more. All right.
Hey, it's good to see you.
Where did you get the idea for all this?
Well...
there's this private event
on an island where...
they force condemned men
to fight to the death.
I remember. They were shut down.
Fools. Playing for pennies.
Letting everybody participate.
The game of life and death
should be a privilege.
Reserved for the elite.
Like yourself, Alexi.
Like all my friends here.
Cyrus always said,
one man's pain is another man's profit.
And the only way to ensure profit,
is to be the one bringing the pain.
Raul must have threatened Michaels
and Lange, too. He had to.
Michaels was supposed
to take you out to the arroyo.
Travis and Lange
would be laying in wait.
- You too.
- Yeah, I played along.
The men here are responsible
for killing Cyrus.
Cooper...
Harrigan, Michaels...
Travis, Lange...
Will.
I only found it fitting
that they be our contestants.
What is that word?
Oh, yeah.
Karma.
You all enjoy.
Lange, he... he gave me this.
He said I had to be here by 5:00.
What does that mean?
Raul said if you get here,
you get to live.
The arroyo was just a starting point.
Along the way? Open season.
Only way out of this is to go
to the cops. Tell them about Raul.
You think the cops
are gonna listen to you?
Michaels is dead. So is Lange.
And now a deputy sheriff. And the only
thing they have in common is you.
You go to the cops, tell them
what you know. That backs up my story.
And then maybe if we're lucky,
if we're very lucky,
there's proof that Raul threatened Michaels
and Lange, just like he threatened you.
I don't wanna shit on your pillow, boss,
but we've got a couple of glaring problems.
First, Travis is still out there wanting
to put a couple of extra holes in your head.
Then there's Cooper. A psycho ex-compadre
who likes burning and blowing shit up.
Doesn't mean Cooper's part of this.
You wanna bet your life on that?
Yeah, I do.
Ladies and gentlemen!
Will Tanner's luck hold on?
Will he survive?
Do any of you have
the stones to bet it all
that Tanner will survive my little game?
Ladies and gentlemen, place your bets!
That's funny!
Place your bets!
Let's go.
What? You got a better idea?
Yeah, I do.
Looks brand new.
Raul gave it to me.
It's clean, no serial number.
Was supposed to use it on you.
- Glad you didn't.
- Don't make me regret that.
What the hell?
Get out! Get out!
Jesus!
Grand on the table, bets all in?
Not yet.
Go, go, go!
Shit.
- Where is my drone?
- Closing in on the target.
Hey, you should be there
when he buys it.
You know, standing over him,
big game hunter-style.
Are you mocking me?
Is that what you're doing?
No, I... I would never.
Merrick built his empire on blood.
He fought and scraped
to earn the respect
of all the people that worked for him.
But I don't.
It's five times greater than anything
he would have ever dreamed of.
Because I honor something
bigger than respect...
fear.
Tell me...
do you fear me?
- Yes, I do.
- Good.
Not good. Not good. We're losing power.
I think he hit the engine.
Come on. Inside, inside!
Clear out, people!
- What? What're you...
- Listen, we don't want any trouble.
But there's some asshole
out there with a rifle.
Yeah? And there's a bitch
in here with a shotgun.
Listen. Listen to me, okay?
We go out there, we're both dead.
Not my problem.
I'm calling the police.
Good!
I'm sorry.
- You see Travis?
- No, I don't see him.
Yeah. I know the guy.
He'll take up a position,
wait for us to pop our heads out.
I'm thinking right up there.
Perfect vantage point.
He can cover the entire front.
Take this.
- Listen, we're sorry about all this, okay?
- Screw you.
Pick up. Pick up. Dad.
- You okay, son?
- Yeah.
Listen... I need your help.
Jesus!
Take cover! Protect the girl.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Just stay down!
Shit.
$10,000. $10,000.
- I want mine!
- Okay.
Gas! Come on!
Come on. Follow me! Stop, stop, stop!
Come with me. Keep your head down.
Keep your head down. Stay right here.
You're gonna be safe. Everything's gonna
be all right. Just keep your head down.
Get into the truck, come on!
No. Gas.
Gas, gas, gasoline! Go, go, go!
Dad. Come on.
Where you been, Dad?
Will, what the hell happened?
Where's Lange?
He's dead. He tried to kill me, too.
Hey, Frank, long time.
Fuck!
Damn it!
Hey, you wouldn't happen to have a flask
or something dangerous on you, would you?
As a matter of fact...
- Here we go.
- You, sir, are still my hero.
That's good, Will.
If all this is true, we got to call in
the big guns, the Feds, maybe.
I got some contacts
we can reach out to in D.C.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
If all this is true... how is anybody
supposed to believe me if you don't?
Son, it is a lot to process.
A lot to process?
I killed two people today, Pop.
- Try processing that.
- Killing a man is hard, I know.
I took over the family business,
tried to make you proud. I fucked up.
I was done trying to be like you.
But here I am.
My father's son.
Shit. Stop!
Easy, easy, easy.
Oh, shit. That's close.
- Guess who this belongs to?
- Cooper.
Hey. Check it out.
What do you think? An invitation?
Yeah. No, thanks.
How about we just get back in the truck
and we pull a u-ey,
- and we get the hell out of here?
- A detour.
He's leading us right into this trap.
You think our good old buddy Cooper
is just, what, gonna let us drive away?
- Worth a shot.
- No, we find Cooper now...
and maybe he'll lead us to Raul.
We find Cooper now,
and we get our asses blown to shit.
What the...
- What the fuck you doing, Dad?
- What's it look like?
Raul doesn't want anything to do
with you. He wants a piece of me.
- So you just go home!
- Not on your life, son.
Let's go.
I did not see that comin'.
Hey.
Are you sure we are in the right place?
What do you think? Yeah.
Yeah, we're in the right place.
Come on. Just watch your step.
You know what? Enough of this shit.
Cooper, I'm here.
Show yourself!
You really think it's a good idea
to poke the bear?
Where you at? Come on!
Shit. Will?
Shit.
Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
A foot in diameter.
This is a nasty mine. Okay.
You're gonna slide your foot back.
But whatever you do,
- don't lift your foot off that pressure place.
- Easy. Easy. Easy.
Just breathe, be calm, all right?
Nice and slow, on three.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
On three. One...
two... Easy. Hold up, hold up.
You got it, you got it.
Easy, easy, easy.
Move your foot back nice and slow.
- Thanks.
- Holy shit.
My money says he's got
this whole canyon rigged.
Oh, shit.
Run!
We're good up here for now.
I'm gonna kill... You heard me, Cooper?
- What happened to poking the bear?
- I'm gonna carve this bear a new asshole.
He's close.
He likes to admire his handiwork.
Harrigan.
Back up.
God!
Cooper? Get out of the truck!
It's over!
Come on, man, get out of the truck.
Get out of the truck!
You shoot, I pull the pin as I fall.
Put the gun down.
Come on, Coop. You don't want to do that.
Put down the grenade.
No. I don't work for you anymore.
You can't tell me what to do.
It doesn't matter who you work for. Put down
the grenade. Come on. We don't have to...
Put the gun down, Will.
No, no, no. Crazy son of a bitch.
- You always were.
- I'm slipping here.
You don't have to... Okay, okay,
hey, hey, hey, hey. Easy, easy.
All right, Coop.
You win.
No gun.
Now it's your turn.
Put down that grenade.
Put down the fucking grenade.
Motherfucker.
Fuck you!
Cooper. You don't have to do this!
Yes, I... do!
I know Raul threatened to kill you.
Yeah. And if it's between you and me,
I choose me every time.
God damn it.
Shit, no way!
Back off. I said back off.
- You don't know everything that's going on.
- Freeze! Hands above your head!
Shit. Great.
Stop!
Slippery little fuck.
Gotcha.
Will?
Will, can you hear me?
Hold on, buddy. Hold on. Easy.
- Give me a first aid kit.
- Holy shit.
Oh, God.
Sucks!
Is he dead?
Closer.
Will. Hang in there, buddy.
Can you hear me? It's his arm.
Hang in there, buddy. Will! Hold on.
- Is Will Tanner dead? Yes or no.
- I'm not sure.
Well, find out!
Move the drone closer! I need to know!
Easy, easy.
It looks like he is still alive.
You're damn lucky.
Wound's a through-and-through.
Bullet missed your vital organs.
These will help with the pain.
You done?
- No, he's under arrest.
- For what?
He's wanted for two murders.
Possibly a third.
Jesus!
Honey, I'm home!
Hey, there, cowboy.
I got a present for you.
Put that down right now!
What, Cooper, you're back
to finish the job?
No. I'm here to help.
Can you walk?
All right. Hey, you.
Stay face down on the ground.
In fact, you guys give me a minute.
I got an idea.
- What the hell did you just do?
- I just bought us some time.
He's bat-shit crazy.
You do realize that, right?
Dead man walking.
Please, Will. Run, hide, bleed.
The longer you live,
the more money I make.
Right up to the moment
someone puts a bullet in your head.
You all right?
- They went that way?
- Yeah, they went over there.
- Why did you come back, Coop?
- You saved my life.
I figured might as well
return the favor.
Look, man.
I didn't want to do any of this.
- Welcome to the club.
- How'd they get to you?
A few nights ago, put a gun in my mouth,
it was either I kill you or they were gonna...
Hold on. Is that my old man in the middle
of the road? Stop the truck.
Jesus, Will. Have you been shot?
I'm fine, Dad. What're you doing here?
Well, I found this in my truck.
Where you dropped it.
So I figured this is
where you were headed.
I also figured I owe you a pop in the mouth
for that sucker punch you gave me.
But seeing as how you're all shot up...
Oh, son of a bitch!
- Okay. I'll call it square.
- Nothing like a father's love.
- Going out there is suicide.
- Yeah, I know, but I'm done runnin', Pop.
This Raul wants me. So, here I come.
I should have believed you
from the beginning.
Listen, I know you say
all your violence is behind you.
But if you come across that bastard, you put
his ass in the ground. You understand me?
- You got it.
- All right. You get in my truck.
- This truck's all over the police scanner.
- Dad, listen. I said you're not part of this.
I'm your father, son.
Look at that. Here we go.
Fuck!
Put me on the board.
- Put me on the board!
- Really?
If Will Tanner survives,
I won't be able to cover the line.
And I will lose everything.
Either someone else kills him...
or I do.
Put it on the board.
Piece of shit.
Son...
I'm here to help, tell me what I can do.
- Nice shot.
- You know it.
Your old man's kind of a badass.
Yeah, he is.
Now, let's get the fuck out of here.
- One more.
- Ladies and gentlemen...
get ready to open your wallets
for a major shift in our festivities.
I am now officially a contestant.
This is it, guys.
This is where the map ends.
Last time I wore one of these,
things didn't go too well, Pop.
Just put it on.
Okay, we'll recon the area and see
what we're dealing with. Stay with me.
Come on, Will. Let's go.
Come here.
Raul knows we're coming, Pop.
- We'll never catch him by surprise.
- Maybe we'll get lucky.
Yeah, 'cause things
have gone great so far.
Well, it's as good a day to die as any.
Yeah, don't say shit like that.
What's wrong with you?
Will, it's your rodeo, little buddy.
Make the call.
All right, guys.
Bring it in and listen up.
Men, take out his backup.
Under no circumstances does anybody
fire on Will Tanner. I alone will kill him.
Yeah, Raul!
Some of you go to the left.
Some of you go to the right.
Circle around, make sure
these other guys are dead!
Yeah!
Come on, Will. Show yourself.
Where are you, Will?
Will.
- Hey there, Will.
- Put your rifle down, Travis.
I said put the rifle down.
Don't... don't do it.
Get down!
All right. Let's go. Go, go, go.
Son of a bitch. Son of a...
- Dad!
- Goddamn son of a...
Here we are. The final game.
Let's finish this, Raul.
It's 5:00. I'm here. Let's end this.
It's actually 5:03.
But either way, you lose.
Come on, boss!
Actually, I should be thanking you.
You gave me an opportunity
and I'm just exploiting it.
In there, high-rollers have been
betting on your life all day.
You're telling me...
people are in there
right now betting on me.
Millions and millions.
A game of life and death.
That's correct.
The only kind worth playing.
People gambling on whether or not
we all kill each other.
That's right.
You're gonna make me a rich man.
You had a good run.
But it's time to cash in.
I had regrets about killing Cyrus.
You, not so much.
Tanner, you're a one-man wrecking crew.
You did what half my force couldn't do.
You should be proud of this boy here.
Thanks a lot. Hey, can I call you Will?
You got a job at the Sherriff's
department anytime you need it.
Thanks, Officer. Thank you, Officer.
- You all right?
- Yeah, I'm all right.
Will, I've been thinking...
I've been thinking about
coming out of retirement.
Oh, God. Don't say it.
- Guys, you all right? We're good?
- Always good, boss.
Hear me out. "Tanner and Son Fugitive
Recovery." What do you think?
- I told you, Pop, I'm out.
- I heard you. You're on. All right.
- I like it.
- Yeah, Frank, I like it too.
- Sounds classy.
- Classy! You hear that?
Classy. He called it classy.