This is Mr Mathison.
He's a doctor.
Are you okay?
An ambulance
is on the way.
Thank you.
Is there a name yet?
Elijah.
Is he supposed to be
crying like this?
May l?
[Shushing]
Can l have him back?
What happened
during the delivery?
Nothing.
it was very quick.
The baby just wanted
to come right out.
There were no problems.
Did you drop him?
Saleswoman.:
What?
Did you drop this baby?
Jesus Christ, no.
inform the ambulance
that we have
a situation.
All right.
Molly.
I've never seen...this.
it appears that your baby
has sustained some fractures
while inside your uterus.
His arms and his legs
are broken.
[Mother Crying]
Conductor Over P.A..:
This is East rail 177.
Next stop, Philadelphia.
[David Grunts]
[Girl Humming]
Kelly.:
Are you alone?
David.: Yeah.
Yeah.
[Train Passes]
Someone left
this magazine.
Want to take
a look at it?
Can l take a look
at that one?
Kelly.: Thanks.
David.:
You like sports?
it's my field.
I represent athletes.
I'm an agent.
David.: Are you looking
for any male
synchronized swimmers?
I'm thinking about
getting into that.
Is that right?
I'm afraid of water.
Think that's a problem?
[Kelly Snickers]
You represent someone
in Philadelphia?
I'm meeting this player
from Temple University.
He's a cornerback.
This kid is 6'1 '',
2 1 0 pounds.
He runs a 40
in 4.3 seconds.
He's gonna be a god.
Do you like football?
Not really.
[Train Passes]
I'm David Dunn.
Kelly.
Hi.
Hi, nice to meet you.
David.: Nice--Nice
to meet you.
How long are you gonna
be in Philadelphia?
I'm married.
David.: Great.
I'm sorry.
David.: What are you
Talking about?
l...
l think you
misunderstood.
What l was, uh...
David.: s-saying--
l know.
l think I'm going
to find another seat.
David.: l...
L didn't mean, uh...
[Train Horn Blowing]
[Music Playing indistinctly
On TV]
Woman.: That's What
he fail to realize.
I look classy, not trashy.
Woman.:
I look classy, too.
What about me?
Don't l look classy?
But I'm afraid
you forgot...this!
Woman.: Andthis!
Male Voice.:
Where has you been, Banana?
Male Voice.: Now
I've got you, Weasel.
Reporter.: Some cars
Are still on fire,
and the debris
is everywhere.
We are not sure
at this time
how rescue personnel Will be
able to get on scene at all.
Second Reporter.:
Lf you're just tuning in,
East rail train number 177
has derailed just outside
Philadelphia.
And We're bringing you
live coverage from Skycam 4.
Reporter.: Yes, that appears
to be a rescue ambulance,
and there are more
behind it.
l can see
on the access road.
l don't know how close they're
gonna be able to get, David.
These are Woods
and, uh, trees.
Uh, it's gonna be a very
difficult?rescue effort.
[Monitor Beeping]
[Person Breathing]
Man.: Hack some
of that off.
Hi.
I'm Dr Dubin.
You're in
the emergency room
in the Philadelphia
City Hospital.
You were in
a serious accident.
Look at me.
How are you feeling?
Okay.
Good.
I'm going to ask you
some questions.
Have you ever had any heart
or asthma problems in the past?
No.
Kidney
or renal problems?
No.
Any allergies?
Where were you sitting
on the train?
Against the window.
in the passenger car?
Yeah.
Where are
the other passengers?
Was your family
travelling with you?
No.
Did you get up
from your seat?
Are you certain you were
in the passenger car?
Yes.
Why are you looking
at me like that?
Your train derailed.
Some kind of malfunction.
They only found
2 people alive so far.
ER Doctor.:
You and this man.
His skull Was cracked open
and most of his left side
Was crushed.
And to answer your question,
there are2 reasons
Why l'm looking at you
like this.
One, because it seems
in a few minutes
that you Will officially
be the only survivor
of this train Wreck.
And two...
because you didn't
break one bone.
You don't have
a scratch on you.
[No Audio]
[Chattering]
[Spoon Clinking
Against Bowl]
David?
What happened...
in New York?
l don't think
l got the job.
David.:
I'm still going, uh...
I'm still moving there.
just...
[Inhales]
Oh, just--just not now.
Good night.
[Bell Tolling]
Priest.:Sara Elaston...
social worker at Broad
and Locust Community Centre.
We pray for your soul.
Kevin Elliot, businessman,
father of 6.
We pray for your soul.
Glen Stevens...
researcher in the area
of leukemia...
at Drexel University.
We pray for your soul.
jennifer Pennyman...
Priest.: third-grade teacher
At Jefferson Elementary.
Wepray for your soul.
[Bell Tolling]
[Man Laughs,
Men Chattering]
Yes?
Is Noel in, ma'am?
No, sir, he is not.
l read about you
in the paper.
What?
l was in
an accident once, too.
A horse almost
trampled me to death.
Wow.
Had him put down.
That's a sad story.
Could you ask Noel
something for me, please?
Proceed.
Would you ask him to check
how many sick days I've taken
since I've worked here?
That the entire message?
Yes, ma'am.
Thank you.
[Thunder]
[Coach Blows Whistle]
Hey, Noel.
Noel.: What, you hit your head
on that train?
Get your brain to start
Working again?
What?
$40.
$40 what?
You're getting
a $40-a-week raise.
That's it.
l checked.
You were right.
You've never taken
a sick day.
5 years, no sick day.
l get it. You want a raise.
Smart way
to make your point.
[Clock Ticking]
[Knock On Door]
Is Joseph okay?
Yeah. He's asleep.
Oh.
Uh...
l wanted to ask you
a question.
it's gonna sound
a little strange,
but, uh, just think about it
for a second, okay?
Okay.
When's the last time
l was sick?
Do you remember?
Um, l don't know.
it's been a while.
l haven't been sick
this year, l know that.
Okay.
Do you remember me
getting sick?
Um...
not a specific day.
What--What's this about?
Audrey, do you remember me
ever getting sick?
In the 3 years we lived
in this house?
In the old apartment?
Before Joseph was born?
Before we ever got married?
l--l can't remember.
Don't you think
that's kind of weird,
not remembering one cold
or a fever or a sore throat?
What do you think
it means?
Um...
l think it means probably
too tired to remember.
No more sitting
in this room.
l let it go on
long enough.
I'm not going
out there any more.
I'm not getting hurt
again.
This was the last time,
l told you.
You can't do anything
about that.
You might fall between
this chair and that television.
lf that's what God
has planned for you,
that's what's gonna happen.
You can't hide from it
sitting in a room.
They call me Mr Glass
at school
because l break
like glass.
You make
this decision now...
to be afraid...
and you will
never turn back.
Your whole life,
you will always be afraid.
[Sniffles]
l got a present for you.
Why?
Forget why.
You want it or not?
Well, go get it, then.
Where is it?
On a bench...
across the street.
Someone's going
to take it.
Then you better
get out there soon.
l bought
a whole bunch.
There'll be one of these
waiting for you
every time you want
to come out here.
They say this one
has a surprise ending.
Adult Eliijah.: This is from
Fritz Campion's own library.
This is before the first issue
of the comic book
hit the stands in 1968.
it's a classic depiction
of good vs. evil.
Notice the square jaw
of Slayer,
common in
most comic heroes.
And the slightly
disproportionate size
of Jaguaro's head
to his body.
This again is common,
but only in villains.
Businessman.: Mm-hmm.
Eliijah.: The thing to notice
about this piece,
the thing that makes it
very, very special
is its realistic depiction
of its figures.
When the characters
Reached the magazine,
they Were exaggerated...
a sal Ways happens.
This is vintage.
Well...
wrap it up.
You've made a considerably
wise decision.
Well, my kid's
gonna go berserk.
Once again, please?
My sonJeb--
it's a gift for him.
Eliijah.: How old is Jeb?
He's 4.
No.
No, no, no, no, no.
You need to go. Now.
[Scoffs]
What--What'd l say?
Do you see any
Teletubbies in here?
Do you see
a slender plastic tag
clipped to my shirt with
my name printed on it?
Did you see
a little Asian child
with a blank expression
sitting outside
in a mechanical
helicopter
that shakes when
you put quarters in it?
No?
Well, that's what you
see at a toy store,
and you must think
you're in a toy store,
because you're here shopping
for an infant named Jeb.
Now, one of us
has made a gross error
and wasted the other
person's valuable time.
This is an art gallery,
my friend,
and this...
is a piece of art.
[Door Opens,
Door Bell Rings]
[Door Closes,
We're by
appointment only.
l got a card
from this store.
Congratulations,
you have a mailbox.
The exhibition
isn't for 2 weeks.
This one was under
the windshield wiper of my car.
Eliijah.:
How certain are you
that you've never
taken ill?
75%.
Eliijah.: Well...
that's not certain
at all, is it?
That's hole
number one.
l'm going to be
extremely skeptical
about all this.
David.:
About all What?
I'm assuming you've
never been injured.
Would l be wrong
in that assumption?
Joseph.:
Dad's been injured.
Is the child
correct?
Yes, sir.
in college,
l was in a car accident.
Eliijah.:
Was It serious?
He couldn't play football
any more.
Eliijah.:
That's hole number2.
That's a big one.
Mr Price,
can we talk about the note
that you left on my car?
Eliijah.: I've studied
the form of comics
intimately.
I've spent a third of my life
in a hospital bed
with nothing else to do
but read.
l believe comics
are our last link
to an ancient way
of passing on history.
The Egyptians drew
on the walls.
Countries all over the world
still pass on knowledge
through pictorial forms.
l believe comics
are a form of history
that someone somewhere
felt or experienced.
Then, of course,
those experiences
and that history
got chewed up
in the commercial machine,
got jazzed up,
made titillating,
cartooned
for the sale rack.
This city has seen its share
Of disasters.
l watched the aftermath
of that plane crash.
l watched the carnage
of the hotel fire.
l watched the news
waiting to hear
a very specific
combination of words,
but they never came.
Then one day l saw a news story
about a train accident,
and l heard them.
''There is a sole survivor,
and he is miraculously
unharmed.''
[Elijah Scoffs]
Eliijah.: l have something called
osteogenesis imperfecta.
lt's a genetic disorder.
l don't make a particular
protein very Well,
and it makes my bones
very low in density.
Very easy to break.
I've had54breaks
in my life,
and l have the tamest version
of this disorder,
type one.
There are type2,
type3, type 4.
Type 4s
don't last very long.
So that's how it popped
into my head.
lf there is someone
like me in the world,
and I'm at one end
of the spectrum,
couldn't there be
someone else
the opposite of me
at the other end?
Someone
who doesn't get sick,
who doesn't get hurt
like the rest of us?
And he probably
doesn't even know it.
The kind of person
these stories are about.
A person put here
to protect the rest of us.
To guard us.
You think my dad's
a real--
Eliijah.: l don't think
anything right now.
lt's apossibility--
one With many holes.
joseph, don't take
another sip of that water.
Go throw it
in the trash.
But, Dad--
Do it now, please.
[Door Opens,
Door Bell Rings]
David.: l see guys like you
All the time in my Work.
[Door Closes,
Door Bell Rings]
You find someone you want
to take advantage of,
you tell them
a fantastic story,
and somewhere in there
you say it--
''l just need
your credit card number...
a small down payment.''
[Scoffs] This morning
was the first morning
that l could remember
that l didn't open my eyes
and feel...
sadness.
[Scoffs]
l thought the person
that wrote that note
had an answer for me.
[Door Opens,
Door Bell Rings]
l'm gonna leave now.
Good luck
with your exhibition.
So, what kind of job
do you have, David?
You said you've met guys
like me in your work.
What exactly is it
that you do?
l work at
the University Stadium.
I'm a security guard.
[Clock Ticking]
[Knock On Door]
Hi.
I've come to a decision.
Okay.
l just want to ask you
something, okay?
And you can be
totally honest.
I'm prepared
for any answer,
and--and it won't
affect me.
Have you been
with anyone?
l mean, since we've
been having problems.
The answer
won't affect me.
l just need to know,
you know?
it won't affect me
either way.
No.
[Sobs]
Sorry, David. Sorry.
Anyway...
my decision is...
[Sniffles]
that l want
to start again.
That l want it to be like
it was in the beginning.
And it's a big deal that you
walked away from that train.
l feel like
it's a second chance.
And if you feel like
asking me out sometime,
it'd be okay.
[Sniffles]
Okay.
[P.A. Announcer
Speaking indistinctly]
Jenkins.:
Dunn.
Go for Dunn.
Jenkins.:
It's Jenkins.
Look, We got a guy over at
gate 17-C With a bogus ticket.
Say she knows you.
He Won't tell me his name.
What's he look like?
Why is it, do you think,
that of all the professions
in the world,
you chose protection?
You are
a very strange man.
You could have been
a tax accountant.
You could have owned
your own gym.
You could've opened
a chain of restaurants.
You could've done
one of 1 0,000 things,
but in the end, you
chose to protect people.
You made that decision,
and l find that
very, very interesting.
Now all l need is
your credit card number.
That last part
was a joke.
[Chuckles]
David.: You're a big
sports fan, are you?
Eliijah.: it's starting
to intrigue me.
it gets heaviest
10 minutes before kick-off.
[Crowd Noise Stops]
[Crowd Noise Resumes]
Man.: Programme here.
Programme.
Rich, why don't
we pat down?
Right.
just give me
a minute.
ls there
a problem?
I'm sorry, I'm gonna
have to search you.
The tall guy in
the camouflage jacket.
Sometimes people
carry weapons in here,
David.: and they
drink too much.
lf the team's
not doing good,
bad things
can happen.
We do pat-downs
Of the crowd
to discourage people
from carrying.
lf he's carrying,
he'll step out of line.
Rich.: Yeah,
to the right up here.
[indistinct Speech
Over P.A.]
David.: Okay.
l got you a seat up
in the yellow section.
it's in the nosebleeds,
but at least
you won't get spit on.
All right.
How'd you know
that guy you bumped
was carrying a weapon?
l don't know.
Maybe it was that camouflage
army jacket he was wearing.
Those guys like to carry
hunting knives and stuff
for show.
You thought he was
carrying a knife?
l thought he was carrying
something, yeah.
But not a knife.
l got a...
picture ofa silver gun
with a black grip
tucked in his pants.
You know, like on TV.
You have good instincts
for things like that?
Like what?
Knowing when people have
done something wrong.
Yeah.
Have you ever tried
to develop it?
l don't know
what you're asking me.
Your skill.
Look, l got to be down on
the sidelines during the game.
You can get to your seat
right down here--
Characters in comics
are often attributed
special powers--
invisibility,
X-Ray vision,
things of that sort.
Okay.
l don't want to play
this game any more.
it's an exaggeration
ofthe truth.
Maybe it's based
on something
as simple as instinct.
But he might not have been
carrying anything.
But he might have been
carrying a silver gun
with a black grip
tucked in his pants.
Jenkins Over Radio.:
Dunn.
l gotta go.
Yeah, l know.
I'll be right down.
One last question.
What?
That car accident
you were in.
Was there anyone else
involved?
Yeah.
My wife Audrey.
She was in the car
with me.
Have a good life, Elijah.
Next time,
try to buy your tickets
at an authorized
sales location.
[indistinct Chatter
Over Radio]
I'm on my way.
Radio Announcer.:
...into the investigation
of train 177
being conducted at the East rail
holding Warehouses.
The city council
Has stepped up plans
to pass a bill...
[Man Coughs]
requiring higher standards
for inspection and maintenance
of all rail transportation
in Philadelphia
and its outlying districts.
[Whistle Blows]
[Crowd Cheering]
Hold up a second!
[P.A. Announcer
Speaking indistinctly]
[Panting]
Eliijah.: l just Want
to ask you something.
Aah!
[Sobbing]
Joseph.: Dad!
Hey, Dad!
Dad!
joseph, do you know how
mad your mother would be
if she knew you were
playing football?
Are you gonna tell?
You want to play
last of the downs?
We got a big guy
like you.
You could play
on opposite sides.
He's Potter's cousin.
He's starting cornerback
at Temple University.
He's going pro
in the draft.
They say he can run
the 40 in 4.3 seconds.
I've heard.
You can beat him, Dad.
Let's beat'em.
I'm gonna go in.
just play one set of downs.
l told them you were great.
Why'd you do that?
just one.
I'm gonna go in. I've
got some things to do.
What things?
I'm gonna work out.
I'll help you.
l don't need--
l can't play, guys!
I'm working out
with my dad!
Man.: Hut!
You're doing good.
Right there! Catch!
All man Brothers.:
I've got to run
To keep from hiding
And l'm bound
To keep on riding
And I've got one more
Silver dollar
How much did you
put on there?
But I'm not gonna
let them catch me, no
Not gonna let'em catch
the midnight rider
You put too much.
That's 250 pounds.
How much can you lift?
That's the most
l ever lifted.
That could've been
dangerous, Joseph.
Why don't you
go upstairs now
and let me finish up, okay?
I'll take it off.
I'll help you right.
[Sighs]
[Moving Weights]
Joseph.: You think you could
have beaten up Bruce Lee?
No.
l mean,
if you knew karate.
No.
What if he wasn't
allowed to kick,
and you were
really mad at him?
No, Joseph.
How much
did you take off?
l lied.
You added?
How much is it?
270 pounds.
Let's put more.
Okay.
David.: Why don't you
move back a little
just to be safe, okay?
[Grunting]
[Breathes Heavily]
More?
You should never
do anything like this.
You know that, right?
David.: What do you do
If something bad happens?
Get Mom.
David.: Right.
[Grunting]
How much did you
put on that time?
[Panting]
All of it.
What else can we use?
[David Straining]
How much is it?
How much is it, Dad?
About 350 pounds.
Physician.: Fracture of the fifth
Metacarpal of the right hand,
as well
as multiple fractures
of the sixth, seventh,
and eighth ribs.
The worst of the injury,
however,
was sustained
to the right leg
in the form of
a spiral fracture.
There were 1 4 breaks.
it simply shattered.
They call me Mr Glass.
Physician.: Who does?
Kids.
Physician.: Ar eyou
All right, Mr Price?
Shall l continue?
Pins Were placed through out
the length of the leg.
The use of a Wheelchair
Will be needed
For a 2-monthperiod.
The use of crutches Will
Follow for 12 to 14months.
Hospital stay Will
range from 5 to 8days
folloWedby9 to 12 months
of physical therapy.
Prescribed medication
for pain management
Will take the usual
forms of morphine drip,
perco cet, darvocet.
Your 1 0:00 is here.
The hospital discharged
him this morning.
Thanks.
Elijah, right?
We're gonna prevent any
substantial atrophy
of your good leg
with this,
and it works
your quadriceps.
Eliijah.: How long
have you been married?
12 years.
How'd you
get together?
[Laughs]
I'm a little nervous
being here.
l ask too many questions
when I'm nervous.
A car accident.
Oh.
Now you're going to have
to tell me more.
[Laughs]
My husband was
a star athlete in college,
and we were
in an accident together.
Our car flipped
on an icy road,
and we were both injured,
and he couldn't play
football any more.
And if that
hadn't happened,
we probably wouldn't
have been together.
How so?
l think we should
talk about your rehab.
You don't have to answer
if you don't want to.
So, tell me more
about the quad machine.
lt prevents
atrophy by...
l couldn't
spend my life
with someone
who played football.
it's pretty much
that simple.
And l don't hate
the game.
l admire the amount
of skill it involves.
And like everyone else,
l was in awe of the way
he played it,
but football,
in many ways,
is the opposite
of what l do.
You're rewarded the more
you punish your opponent.
You know, it's too much
about violence,
and l don't want
violence in my life.
it's not a thing many people
can understand, but...
Anyway,
fate stepped in
with that car accident
and took football
out other equation.
Eliijah.: And everyone lived
Happily ever after.
Sort of.
Eliijah.: What part of
David's body Was in jured?
Who said my husband's
name was David?
[Crowd Cheering]
Woman: Let's just go
to our seats, okay?
P.A. Announcer.:
Ladies and gentlemen...
[Continues Indistinctly]
P.A. Announcer.:
ln the first half..
[Continues Indistinctly]
[Crowd Noise Fades]
[Child Yells,
Crowd Noise Resumes]
[P.A. Announcer
Speaking Indistinctly]
Eliijah.: A 737
crashes on takeoff--
172 die,
no survivors.
A hotel fire downtown--
2 1 1 die, no survivors.
An East rail train
derails
7 1 /2 miles
outside the city--
1 31 die,
one survivor.
He is unharmed.
I've spoken
with your husband
about his survival.
l suggested a rather
unbelievable possibility.
Since then,
I've come to believe
that possibility,
however unbelievable,
Eliijah.: is now
more aprobability.
And what was it
you suggested?
Eliijah.: These are
mediocre times, Mrs Dunn.
People a restarting
to lose hope.
it's hard
for many to believe
there are extraordinary
things inside themselves
as Well as others.
l hope you can keep
an open mind.
Crowd: Defence!
Defence!
Man.:
Okay, here you go.
Thanks a lot.
Excuse me, sir?
Can you step
out of line, please?
We've been having
some problems
with people selling drugs
here in the stadium.
Would you mind
if l check your pockets?
Raise your arms, please.
Come on, raise them up.
l just got here, man.
Can l put my hands
down now?
Man.:
Can l go?
Yeah.
Hope you find them.
Jenkins On Radio.:
Yo, Dunn.
Yeah.
Jenkins.: l just came
into the office.
Your kid Was hurt.
Where is he?
Jenkins.: Some play
Rehearsal at school.
He Wants you
to come down there.
[Woman Speaking
indistinctly]
Boy.:
Is that your dad?
l bet my dad could
beat up your dad.
No. He, uh...
he insisted
we call only you,
though we had some trouble
tracking you down.
l mean, you're not
on our list.
Audrey handles
this type of stuff.
Oh.
What type of stuff?
joseph stuff.
Do l need to put
any smelly ointment
on him or anything?
No, no. it's more
emotional damage--
not--not too serious,
physically.
Nothing like when l sent you
to the hospital.
When was that?
My office
was on the other side
of the building back then.
You don't remember me,
do you?
No, ma'am.
l had red hair.
Nurse.: Well, you Were
a little younger
than Joseph
When it happened.
Did you know
that We changed
the rules of conduct
around the pool
because of you?
The kids
Still tell about it
like it Was some sort
of ghost story.
''Did you know
there Was a kid
nearly drowned in that pool?
He lay on the bottom
Of the pool
for5minutes,
and When they pulled him out,
he Was dead. ''
We let them tell it.
lt help skeep them safe.
You still phobic
Of Water?
Joseph.: it Was Potter
And another guy.
They Were messing
With this Chinese girl
in the dressing room.
You can't let
Bad things happen
to good people,
right?
That's your code, right?
That's
the hero's code.
l tried to make them stop,
but they kept
pushing me down,
and they wouldn't
let me get back up.
l thought maybe
because you're my dad...
l thought
l might be like you.
I'm not like you.
You are like me.
We can both get hurt.
l'm just
an ordinary man.
No, you're not.
Why do you keep
saying that?
[Train Whistle Blows]
Audrey.: Eliijah Price
came to visit me
at the centre today.
jsus.
He didn't do anything.
Hejust...
told me his theory.
That's sad, when patients
get like that.
They lose reality.
Joseph, what the hell
are you doing?
Audrey.:
Oh, my God.
You don't believe.
I'll show you.
You can't get hurt.
That gun's not loaded.
He doesn't know
where l keep the bullets.
Joseph.: ln your
Rookie of the Year trophy.
Joseph,
did you load that gun?
You won't get hurt.
David.:
Eliijah Was Wrong.
Audrey.: When did he
meet Eliijah?
He was with me
when l met him.
Joseph.:
No one believes him.
joseph, listen to me.
Sometimes when people
get sick or hurt
for a long time,
like Elijah,
their mind
gets hurt, too,
and they start
to think things
that aren't true.
He told me what he thought
about your father.
it isn't true.
I'll show you.
Do you remember
the story
about--about the boy
that almost drowned
in the pool?
That was me
they were talking about.
l almost died.
That was me.
- You're lying.
- I'm not lying, okay?
l just didn't
remember it, that's all.
Audrey.: Joseph,
you know your father
was injured in college.
You know that.
You know all about that.
Audrey.:
Don't do it.
He'll die, Joseph.
I'll just shoot him once.
joseph, listen
to what your mot--
[Crying]
Don't be scared.
joseph...
if you pull that trigger,
I'm going to leave.
Do you understand?
l'm going to go to New York.
Y-You're right.
David.:
Lf you pull that trigger,
that bullet is just going
to bounce off me,
and I'm not going
to be hurt,
but then
I'm going to go upstairs
and I'm going to pack
and I'm going to leave
for New York.
Why?
David.: Because l thought
We Were just starting
to be friends for real,
and friends
will listen to each other.
They don't--
And they don't shoot
each other,
d-do they, Audrey?
No shooting friends,
joseph.
David.:Joseph...
you are about
to be in big trouble!
Now, l am your father,
and l am telling you
to put that goddamn gun
down right now!
1 ...
2...
Ohh!
[Breathing Heavily]
[Crying]
Eliijah.: l followed the guy
in the camouflage jacket.
He had a silver gun
with a black grip
tucked in the back
of his pants.
Were you really
injured
in that car accident
in college?
Because l believe
you faked it.
l believe you took
the opportunity
to end your
football career,
no questions asked.
And l think you did it,
of all things,
for a woman.
l guess
that makes sense.
Heh. Football's, what,
Just 1 0 years,
but love...
Hmm. Now,
that's forever.
And that little bit of
sadness in the mornings
you spoke of?
l think l know
what that is.
Perhaps
you're not doing
what you're supposed
to be doing.
David.: Most guns have
a black or silver handle.
l had a 50-50 shot
of getting the colour right.
Eliijah.: That's not
What l Witnessed.
Stop.
Stop messing
with my life, Elijah.
My son almost shot me
last night,
because he wanted
to prove you were right.
Eliijah.: l never said
you couldn't be killed.
l never said that.
My wife was right.
Eliijah.: There have been
3 major disasters,
and you Were
the only one unharmed.
l have been sick.
When l was a kid, l spent
a week in the hospital
getting better
from pneumonia.
l almost drowned.
2 skinny little kids
were fooling around
in a pool dunking me,
and l swallowed some water.
They didn't know it,
and it almost killed me.
Heroes don't get killed
like that.
Normal people do,
right?
l don't need to see you
any more, okay?
Please stay away
from my family.
The Pixies.: She said,
L could tell you stories
That could make you cry
What about you?
Hey, man, it's 20 after.
it's time to choose.
l gotta head.
And she sighed, ahh
l said, l Want
to be a singer
You better not be
Jacking off
to the Japanese comics,
l swear to God.
Let's go, let's sit,
let's talk
Politics
Goesso good With beer
And While We're at it,
baby
Why don't you tell me
one of your biggest fears?
l said, losing my penis
to a Whore With disease
Look, man, l didn't know
you were in a...
Losin' my life
to a Whore With disease
just choose something,
all right?
Excuse me, please?
Audrey:
The baby-sitter's here.
[Whispering]
Should we cancel?
I'm fine.
We can do this
another time.
Don't lie.
I'm fine.
l just got mixed-up.
[Sighs]
How about we just go
for a couple drinks?
Well,
I'm a humble guy
Okay, look, man, I'm just
going to wheel you out.
All right? You can
think about things
outside
on the sidewalk.
l got to get
some chicken in me,
you know
what I'm saying?
I've been tired
l told the tale
of a girl
Shit!
She's a little bit
older than me
Strong legs,
strong face
Voice like milk
Breasts like
a cluster of grapes
l can't escape
her Ways
She raise me
Dude.
Even if you have
no one
Man, l don't care
if you are in a wheelchair.
lf you do that again,
I'm calling 5-0.
And While
We're at it, baby
Man.
You don't Want
to sleep
After setting my loins
on fire
That's it, crackerjack.
You're going to be sitting
your ass in jail now.
I've been tired
How much for this one?
Rust?
Yeah.
As a colour, not as rust.
You know, like...
rust-coloured paint
or wood.
- l didn't know that.
- Mm-hmm.
Um...
mine's still brown.
Okay, my turn.
Favourite song?
Soft and Wet
by the Artist
Formerly Known as Prince.
What?
We're supposed
to be honest.
Soft and Wet.
That's very interesting.
Okay, my turn.
When was the first time...
the thought popped
into your head
we might not make it?
That's not the game.
it's the first date.
There aren't any rules.
[Sighs]
Don't know for sure.
Think carefully.
What about the game?
it's over.
l won.
Look, maybe it wasn't
a specific moment.
Maybe it was a time--
l had a nightmare
one night,
and...
l didn't wake you up
so you could tell me
that it was okay.
l think that was
the first time.
Does that count?
That counts.
Do you knowingly
keep me and Joseph
at a distance?
Yes.
Why?
l don't know.
l just don't feel
right, Audrey.
Something's...
Just not right.
Do you resent us,
David?
[Laughs]
Resent the life
you have?
l mean, there were
a lot of other things
you could've done
after college.
These were your choices.
[Sighs]
You know,
even if it meant
we couldn't have
been together,
l never would've wished
that injury on you.
What you could do
physically
was a gift.
l never would've
wished it to go away.
You know that, right?
You had 2 calls
afterJoseph went to bed.
One came through while
l was on the other line,
but l wasn't talking
too long.
Baby-sitter.: There Was
an emergency With my sister.
She tried to do
Her own perm,
and now she looks like
she stuck her head--
Who called through?
Baby-sitter.:
Um...
someone from New York,
uh, about
a security job.
They Want to hire you.
l didn't know you guys
were moving to New York.
Thanks for telling me.
We weren't all
going to move.
Oh.
l let the answering machine
pick up the other call.
Great.
Look, let's just be
honest here.
We're just
at the beginning,
and l don't expect
you or l to change
the course of where
our lives were headed
because of one date.
And if you do go
to New York,
we can develop this.
We'll just be forced
to take it slow.
And in the end,
l think that's
definitely better.
l mean, this is our second
time around, David.
l didn't expect us to get
carried away, you know.
Then l guess
''congratulations''
is the right thing
to say.
[Door Closes]
[Sighs]
[Thunder]
[Beep]
Eliijah.:
David, it's Eliijah.
it Wasso obvious.
it Was this one issue
that brought it back forme--
Century Comics 1 17.
That's Where this group,
the Coalition of Evil,
tried to ascertain
the Weakness
of every superhero,
because
they all have one,
just like you.
Your bones don't break.
Mine do.
That's clear.
Your cells react
to bacteria and viruses
differently than mine.
You don't get sick.
L do.
That's also clear.
But for some reason,
you and l react
the exact same Way to Water.
We swallow it too fast,
We choke.
We get some
in our lungs, We drown.
However unreal
it may seem,
We are connected,
you and l.
We're on the same curve,
just on opposite ends.
The point of all this
is We now know
something We didn't.
You have a Weakness--
Water.
it's like
your kryptonite.
You hearing me, David?
[Beep Beep]
[Metal Clatters]
[Breathing Heavily]
Huhh!
David.:Audrey?
[Metal Creaking]
Unh!
Hunh!
Aah!
Gotcha.
Come on.
Audrey.
Hey!
You'll be okay.
What happened?
l thought l was...
l thought
l was dead.
Me, too.
[Truck Door Closes]
ls she all right?
l think her leg's broken.
Truck Driver.:
Are you hurt?
Hey, man,
are you hurt?
[Audrey Crying]
[Telephone Rings]
[Ring]
Hello?
David.: l Wasn't injured
in that car accident.
David.
David.: I've never been
injured, Eliijah.
What am l
Supposed to do?
Go to where people are.
Eliijah.: You Won't have
to look very long.
lt's all right
to be afraid, David,
because this part
Won't be like a comic book.
Real life doesn't fit
into little boxes
that Were drawn for it.
[P.A. Announcer Speaking
Indistinctly]
[People Chattering]
There's one
in the first row.
it's--it's
the second one.
Yes. it's
the second one over.
Oh!
Go back
to Africa!
[Tyres Squeal]
Man.: Whoo-hoo!
Hey, what's your name?
[Music Playing Faintly]
l think
you drank too much.
Can l come in?
Who are you?
l like your house.
Can l come in?
What is this?
No. You can't come in.
Are you sure?
What--What are you--
Man.:Aah!
[Object Clatters]
[Flips
Light Switch]
Man.:Aah!
[TV Playing Faintly]
[Heart beats]
[Object Clatters]
[Child Gasps]
[Children Whimpering]
It's okay.
[Children Crying]
it's okay.
Shh, shh, shh.
Shh, shh.
[Raining Outside]
[Thunder]
[Gags]
Oh!
Blaah!
Aah!
Ahh!
Ahh! Ahh!
[Grunting]
l had a bad dream.
it's over now.
David.:
I don't know.
l can't believe
you'd think that.
I'm just asking you.
I'm making
French toast.
Audrey.: I've been thinking
about Eliijah Price.
lf he shows up again,
l think We should
call the police, okay?
Okay?
Okay.
[Whispering]
You were right.
[Classical Piano Music
Playing]
This is one of Johann Davis'
earliest drawings.
See the villain's eyes?
They're larger than
the other characters'.
They insinuate a slightly
skewed perspective
on how they see
the world--
Just off normal.
He doesn't look
scary.
Mm-hmm. That's what
l said to my son,
but he says there's
always 2 kinds.
There's
the soldier villain
who fights the hero
with his hands,
and then there's
the real threat--
the brilliant
and evil archenemy
who fights the hero
with his mind.
Are you
Elijah's mother?
l am.
I'm helping him
with the sale.
Nice to meet you.
I'm David Dunn.
He's spoken of you.
Says you're
becoming friends.
We are.
Looks like
he's doing good today.
I'm very proud of him.
He's come through
a lot in his life--
a couple of bad spells
l thought had broken him.
Mm-hmm.
They were bad...
but he made it.
Yes, he did.
He's kind of
a miracle.
Yes, he is.
I'll tell him
you're here.
Thank you.
it has begun.
Tell me something, David.
When you woke up
this morning,
was it still there?
The sadness?
David.: No.
l think this is
where we shake hands.
[Explosion]
[Crowd Yells]
Woman.:
Did you see it?
[Siren]
[Alarm Buzzes]
l worked in that building
25 years.
l know all its secrets.
Secrets?
Like if there ever
was a fire
on floors
1 , 2, or 3,
everyone in that hotel
would be burned alive.
[Siren]
Passengers aren't
allowed in there.
[People Scream]
Eliijah.: Do you know
What the scariest thing is?
To not know your place
in this world,
to not know
why you're here.
That's...
That's just
an awful feeling.
What have you done?
l almost gave up hope.
Eliijah.: There Were
so many times
l questioned myself.
You killed
all those people.
But l found you.
So many sacrifices...
Just to find you.
jsus Christ.
Now that we know
who you are...
l know who l am.
I'm not a mistake.
Eliijah.:
It all makes sense.
In a comic,
you know how you can tell
who the arch-villain's
going to be?
He's the exact opposite
Of the hero,
and most times,
they're friends,
like you and me.
l should've known
way back when.
You know why, David?
Because of the kids.
They called me
Mr Glass.