[ Hooves Clattering, People
Chattering, Bell Ringing ]
[ Bell Tolling ]
[ Dog Barking ]
[ Knocking On Door ]
[ Dog Whimpering ]
[ Orchestra Tuning Up ]
THERE SEEMS TO BE
AN EXCESSIVE DELAY, WATSON.
WAITING FOR THE PRINCE.
THEY CAN'T BEGIN
UNTIL HE ARRIVES.
YOU KNOW THAT.
"PUNCTUALITY," MY DEAR
FELLOW. PUNCTUALITY.
"THE POLITENESS OF KINGS."
YES, YES, YES, YES.
HE SEEMS TO TAKE A DELIGHT
IN KEEPING HIS SUBJECTS WAITING.
[ Chuckles ]
I SUPPOSE, SINCE AFTER ALL
HE'S ONLY THE PRINCE OF WALES,
WE SHOULD NOT EXPECT
THE SAME DEGREE OF COURTESY.
AND SINCE YOU'RE ONLY
THE PRINCE OF DETECTIVES,
HOLMES,
I DON'T THINK YOU SHOULD
PRESUME TO CRITICIZE A MAN...
WHO ONE DAY WILL BE
THE KING OF ENGLAND.
WELL DONE, WATSON.
YOU'VE CUT ME TO THE QUICK.
[ Laughs ]
ONLY THE PRINCE
OF DETECTIVES, YOU SAY?
PRAY TELL ME, WHO IS THE KING?
LESTRADE, OF COURSE.
[ Both Laughing ]
[ Applauding ]
[ Audience Cheering ]
[ Booing, Whistling ]
[ Booing Continues ]
GOOD GOD.
INSULTING THE PRINCE.
MORE RESPECT IS WANTED.
IF THE PRINCE WANTS
MORE RESPECT,
HE SHOULD
CONDUCT HIS AFFAIRS
WITH MORE DISCRETION.
[ Boos, Catcalls Continue ]
IT'S A DAMNED DISGRACE.
ON THE CONTRARY.
I PREFER BAD MANNERS
IN THE THEATER...
TO ACTS OF VIOLENCE
IN THE STREETS.
HMPH.
GOD SAVE HIS ROYAL HIGHNESS!
- GOD SAVE HIS ROYAL HIGHNESS!
-[ Man Cursing, Indistinct ]
[ Several Men ]
SAVE HIS ROYAL HIGHNESS!
[ Pro-Royal Shouting Increases ]
???? [ "God Save The King" ]
[ Booing, Cheering Fade ]
WELL DONE, OLD FELLA.
YOU SAVED THE DAY.
[ Man Breathing Heavily ]
[ Dog Barks ]
[ Footsteps ]
[ Heavy Breathing Continues ]
[ Growls ]
OH. FLOWER.
[ Screaming ]
[ Choking ]
[ Groaning,
Gasping ]
MURDER IN WHITECHAPEL!
WHITECHAPEL BUTCHER
STRIKES AGAIN!
READ ALL ABOUT IT!
THERE YOU ARE, SIR.
[ Chattering ]
[ Woman ]
WHAT ARE THE POLICE
DOING ABOUT IT?
CABBY! I SAY, CABBY!
WHITECHAPEL BUTCHER
STRIKES AGAIN!
BRUTAL MURDER
INVESTIGATED!
BAKER STREET.
221 "B."
DON'T YOU THINK WE SHOULD
HIRE A CLOSED CARRIAGE
FROM NOW ON, HOLMES?
OH, I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S QUITE INVIGORATING.
STIRS THE BLOOD.
[ Sniffs Deeply ]
NOBODY USES AN OPEN CARRIAGE
IN OCTOBER, AT NIGHT.
I DO.
SPOKEN WITH THE UTMOST HUMILITY,
MY DEAR HOLMES.
THIS MAKES THREE.
THREE?
THESE WOMEN MURDERED
IN WHITECHAPEL.
THERE WAS THAT ANNIE CHAPMAN,
YOU REMEMBER?
AND THEN THERE WAS POLLY--
...NICHOLS.
POLLY NICHOLS, THAT'S RIGHT.
AND NOW HERE'S A THIRD,
AS YET UNIDENTIFIED.
WELL, THERE'S NOT MUCH CHANCE
TO STUDY THE EVIDENCE, OLD MAN.
NOBODY'S ASKED ME.
[ Chuckles ]
POLICE DON'T KNOW
WHICH WAY TO TURN.
NORMALLY, THEY COME TO YOU
WHEN THEY'RE IN DIFFICULTIES.
WHY HAVEN'T THEY DONE SO
IN THIS CASE, YEAH?
ANSWER THAT AND YOU'LL
RESOLVE THE QUESTION
WHICH I MUST CONFESS...
DOES CAUSE ME
SOME CONCERN.
YES, I'M SURE IT DOES.
[ Neighing ]
YES, I SEE THEM, WATSON.
WHAT THE DEVIL?
WHOEVER THEY MAY BE, THEY
HAVE US AT A GRAVE DISADVANTAGE
HERE IN THE STREET.
MM.
[ Door Closes ]
NOT YET, WATSON!
HMM?
LET'S JUST SEE WHAT WE CAN
BEFORE WE ADVERTISE OUR ARRIVAL.
WHO ARE THEY?
WHAT ARE THEY DOING
OUT THERE?
IS THIS SOME NEW CASE OF YOURS
YOU HAVEN'T TOLD ME ABOUT?
REGRETTABLY, NO. I'M SINGULARLY
UNEMPLOYED, AS YOU CAN HARDLY
FAIL TO HAVE NOTICED.
[ Watson ]
HOW MANY OF THEM?
CAN YOU SEE?
FIVE, AT LEAST.
MORE, PERHAPS.
[ Doorbell Ringing ]
WELL, WELL.
WE SHALL KNOW SOON ENOUGH.
SHALL I GO, OR WILL YOU?
NO, NO, YOU STAY HERE.
THEY CAN'T POSSIBLY HAVE
ANY BUSINESS WITH ME.
NOT OLD FRIENDS
OF YOURS, WATSON?
WHAT?
NO OUTRAGED HUSBANDS,
I HOPE?
[ Ringing Continues ]
VERY FUNNY.
WELL, HURRY UP OLD FELLOW,
BEFORE THEY WAKE THE HOUSE!
YES?
BEGGIN' YOUR PARDON, SIR.
IS IT MR. HOLMES?
NO, IT IS NOT.
OH. MIGHT I HAVE A WORD
WITH MR. HOLMES?
AT THIS HOUR OF THE NIGHT?
RIDICULOUS.
SHOW THEM UP, OLD FELLOW.
WE CAN MAKE AN EXCEPTION
IN AN EMERGENCY.
ALL RIGHT, COME IN.
COME IN.
[ Clock Chiming ]
[ Church Bell Tolling ]
AH. WELL,
HOW MAY I HELP YOU?
WE'RE ALL MEMBERS OF
THE CITIZEN'S COMMITTEE, SIR.
THE THREE OF US.
I'M MR. MAKINS,
THIS IS MR. LANIER,
AND MR. COWE.
OH. SHALL THE OTHER
GENTLEMEN JOIN US, OR
WILL THEY WAIT OUTSIDE?
[ Laughs ]
YEAH. YOU'RE RIGHT, SIR.
THERE ARE OTHERS.
YES, I COULD HARDLY
FAIL TO NOTICE.
OH, SORRY, SIR,
IF WE GIVE YOU
A BIT OF A FRIGHT.
TROUBLE IS, WE DIDN'T KNOW
HOW TO APPROACH YOU, SIR.
YOU KNOW, I MEAN, WITH YOU
BEIN' A FAMOUS GENTLEMAN
AND SUCHLIKE.
I SEE.
WHAT IS THE PURPOSE OF
YOUR CITIZEN'S COMMITTEE?
WELL, WE WANT THIS BLOKE
STOPPED WITH HIS KILLING.
WE WANT HIM STOPPED
AND BROUGHT TO JUSTICE.
IF IT WAS THE WEST END,
THE POLICE WOULD HAVE HIM
SHUT AWAY BY NOW.
IF IT WAS RICH WOMEN
TOOK HIS FANCY
IN THEIR PALACES,
AND NOT POOR WOMEN
FORCED ON THE STREETS--
[ Chuckles ]
LOOK, I'LL BE STRAIGHT
WITH YOU, MR. HOLMES.
WE'VE ALL GOT SHOPS DOWN IN
WHITECHAPEL. IT'S ALL RIGHT
IF YOU'RE ON THE MAIN ROAD.
BUT IF YOU AIN'T, WELL,
NO ONE GOES OFF THE MAIN ROAD.
NOT DAY NOR NIGHT, THEY DON'T.
WELL, TO BE HONEST WITH YOU,
TRADE'S FALLIN' OFF
SOMETHING TERRIBLE.
YES. I CAN WELL IMAGINE
THAT PEOPLE MAY BE
A TRIFLE DISCOURAGED.
IT'S BLOODY AWFUL, SIR.
WE MIGHT AS WELL SHUT UP SHOP
UNTIL THIS BLOKE'S...
CAUGHT AND PUT AWAY.
WHICH IS NEVER,
IF WE WAIT FOR THE POLICE.
IT STRIKES ME, SIR,
THEY'D BE GLAD OF ALL
THE HELP YOU COULD GIVE 'EM.
- I'D HAVE TO AGREE
WITH YOU, MR. MAKINS.
- YES, WELL--
UM, I SHALL THINK IT OVER.
IT'S LIKE YOU SAID
YOURSELF, SIR.
IT IS AN EMERGENCY.
WATSON, UMM--
WOULD YOU SEE THE GENTLEMEN
OUT, PLEASE?
[ Sighs ]
SIR, WHEN CAN
WE EXPECT TO HEAR?
U-UH, SOON. SOON.
OH, I-IN THE MEANTIME,
WOULD YOU LEAVE AN ADDRESS
WHERE YOU CAN BE REACHED
WITH THE GOOD DOCTOR?
YOU WILL TRY TO PERSUADE HIM,
WON'T YOU, SIR?
I'LL DO MY BEST.
IF ANYONE CAN PUT A STOP
TO THESE ATROCIOUS CRIMES,
[ Mumbling ]
THAT MAN IS SHERLOCK HOLMES.
[ Sighs ]
IT STRIKES ME AS RATHER ODD
THAT THESE MERCHANT CHAPS...
SEEMED SO RELUCTANT
TO ADVERTISE THEMSELVES.
YOU SEEM STRANGELY
DISINTERESTED, HOLMES.
ALMOST RUDE,
IF I MAY SAY SO.
OH, NOT RUDE, SURELY.
WELL, OLD CHAP--
WHAT SHALL WE DO?
SHALL WE TAKE UP
THE CHASE?
I DON'T SEE THAT WE HAVE
ANY CHOICE. THEY'VE PUT
THEIR TRUST IN YOU.
GOOD, HONEST FELLOWS.
GOOD, HONEST FELLOWS?
HMM. THAT MAY BE.
THE GROUND WILL
YIELD LITTLE TONIGHT.
WE'LL MAKE A START
IN THE MORNING.
[ Sighs ]
HOLMES.
I WISH YOU'D REFRAIN
FROM CLEANING YOUR PIPE OUT
WITH MY HYPODERMIC NEEDLES.
YES, THANK YOU, WATSON.
[ Cat Yowling ]
[ Footsteps ]
'ELLO, DEARIE!
HANDS OFF.
WHAT'D YOU DO THAT FOR?
WHORE.
GIRL'S GOT TO EARN
A LIVING, AIN'T SHE?
WHAT'D YOU DO THAT FOR,
THEN? YOU ROTTEN BLEEDER!
I DIDN'T DO YOU
NO 'ARM, DID I?
[ Horse Whinnies ]
WHOA, THERE. WHOA.
[ Man ]
ARE YOU ALONE?
YES. YES!
COME. IT'S NOT SAFE
ON THE STREETS.
[ Streetwalker ]
OH, GOD BLESS YA!
GIDDAP!
???? [ Violin, Classical ]
???? [ Violin Continues ]
[ Sighs ]
WAKE UP, OLD FELLOW.
[ Groans ]
THERE'S A CAB WAITING.
THE GAME'S AFOOT.
NO TIME TO LOSE.
[ Yawning ]
WHAT IS IT, HOLMES?
AN ANONYMOUS MESSAGE
ADVISING US
OF ANOTHER MURDER.
[ Groans, Yawns ]
WATSON.
STIR YOURSELF.
THERE IS INDEED
SOME URGENCY.
[ Groans, Sighs ]
WATSON?
[ Grunting ]
WHAT? OKAY. OH.
TWO IN ONE NIGHT.
THIS IS GETTING RIDICULOUS.
[ Softly ]
SHERLOCK HOLMES IS HERE.
SHERLOCK HOLMES.
WHAT, HERE?
I WAS WONDERING WHEN
WE'D SEE YOU ON THE CASE.
FULL TIME.
OH, MR. HOLMES.
INSPECTOR FOXBOROUGH.
INSPECTOR.
MY ASSOCIATE,
DR. WATSON.
HOW DO YOU DO, SIR.
WELL, LESTRADE.
IT APPEARS YOU ARE HAVING SOME
DIFFICULTY WITH THIS FELLOW?
I MIGHT BE INCLINED TO BELIEVE
SOME OF THE STORIES THEY'RE
TELLIN' ABOUT THIS BLOKE.
WHAT STORIES?
PEOPLE SAYS HE'S IN LEAGUE
WITH THE DEVIL.
APPEARS, DISAPPEARS AT WILL.
AH, WHEN PEOPLE ARE FRIGHTENED,
THEY TURN TO GOD.
WHEN THEY HAVE NO HELP FROM
HIM, THEY LOOK TO THE DEVIL.
OH, NOTHING I BELIEVE.
YOU'RE A MEDICAL MAN,
DR. WATSON, SO I DON'T
HAVE TO WARN YOU.
JUST THE SAME, PERHAPS
YOU SHOULD PREPARE YOURSELF...
FOR SOMETHING THAT YOU
MAY NOT HAVE SEEN BEFORE.
WHEN YOU FOUND THE BODY,
IT WAS IN THIS POSTURE,
JUST AS IT IS NOW?
YES, SIR.
AND THE INTERNAL ORGANS?
FOR GOD'S SAKE, HOLMES.
IN JUST THIS FASHION?
- YES.
- MUST YOU DWELL ON
THE BEASTLY MATTER?
LESTRADE, YOU SAW
THE OTHER BODY?
YES, MR. HOLMES.
WAS SHE MUTILATED
IN THE SAME WAY?
HER THROAT WAS CUT.
-IS THAT ALL?
- [ Watson ] UGH, SURELY--
IT SEEMS LIKE HE WAS DISTURBED,
ALMOST CAUGHT HIM AT IT.
[ Policeman ]
STAND BY, MEN. COME ON, NOW.
MOVE ALONG.
[ Policeman Continues ]
WHAT THE DEVIL ARE YOU DOING
HERE, HOLMES? WHO ASKED YOU TO
COME MEDDLING IN POLICE MATTERS?
WHO'S RESPONSIBLE? FOXBOROUGH,
DID YOU ASK THIS MAN? LESTRADE?
NO, SIR.
I ASSUMED MR. HOLMES WAS
HERE AT YOUR INVITATION.
HE'S NOT.
I'VE NO USE FOR
HIS SORT OF BLOODY AMATEUR.
"CONSULTING DETECTIVE."
GET HIM OUT OF HERE!
NO NEED TO DISTURB YOURSELF
FURTHER, SIR CHARLES. I DON'T
WISH TO CAUSE DISSENSION.
COME ALONG, WATSON.
WHO IS THAT FELLOW, HOLMES?
SIR CHARLES WARREN.
NEW HEAD BOY,
SCOTLAND YARD.
OH, YES, I REMEMBER.
DAMN FOOL.
LAST YEAR, THOSE RIOTS
IN TRAFALGAR SQUARE.
EXACTLY.
"BLOODY SUNDAY,"
THE PAPERS CALLED IT.
HE WAS EVERY BIT AS RESPONSIBLE
AS THE RADICALS, IN MY OPINION.
WHY DOES HE HAVE TO BE
SO DELIBERATELY ABUSIVE?
AT THE MOMENT, MY DEAR FELLOW,
THERE IS SOMETHING
MORE IMPORTANT
WHICH CONCERNS US,
IF YOU CAN RESTRAIN
YOUR INDIGNATION.
SHAN'T SAY ANOTHER WORD.
[ Cat Yowling ]
[ Dog Barking ]
"THE JUWES ARE NOT...
THE MEN THAT WILL BE...
BLAMED FOR NOTHING."
[ Dog Barking ]
"THE JUWES--"
BLOODY HELL.
[ Warren ] VERY WELL THEN.
GET A REPORT OUT AND SEE ME
BACK AT THE YARD.
[ Foxborough ]
THIS IS IMPORTANT EVIDENCE!
I'M TELLING YOU, NO!
IN AN HOUR FROM NOW,
THERE'LL BE A HUNDRED PEOPLE
PASSING THROUGH HERE.
MORE. IF THOSE WORDS ARE
SEEN, I HAVE A RIOT!
[ Objecting Simultaneously ]
ANY JEW THAT THE MOB CAN
GET THEIR HANDS ON WILL BE
SLAUGHTERED IN THE STREETS.
WITH RESPECT, SIR CHARLES.
WHY DON'T WE COVER UP THE WORDS?
NO.
JUST THE FIRST LINE--
THE ONE WORD "JUWES."
ISN'T THAT ENOUGH?
I'M NOT STANDING HERE
AND ARGUING WITH YOU. I'LL
JUST RUB THIS WRITING OFF!
THERE! RIGHT HERE!
NOW MAYBE I'M DAMNED.
YOU'VE NOT LEFT A WORD.
THE COMMISSIONER OF POLICE
RUBBING OUT BLOODY WORDS
IN LONDON!
THESE DAMNED NEWSPAPERS.
THEY HAVE THE WHOLE CITY
IN A BLIND STATE OF PANIC.
LAST NIGHT, WHEN WE WERE
EXAMINING THE BODY OF THE
UNFORTUNATE CATHERINE EDDOWES--
MM. DON'T REMIND ME
OF THAT, OLD CHAP.
DID YOU NOTICE A WOMAN
IN THE CROWD?
I NOTICED DOZENS OF WOMEN.
WELL, YES, I WOULD EXPECT
THAT OF YOU, WATSON.
BUT ONE PARTICULAR WOMAN.
[ Fork Hits Plate ]
- WATSON?
- [ Sighs ] YES.
LISTEN, WATSON,
[ Sighs ]
WHATAREYOU DOING?
[ Inhales Deeply ]
I'M TRYING TO CORNER
THE LAST PEA ON MY PLATE.
- WHAT'S THAT OBJECT
YOU'RE FOOLING AROUND WITH?
- OH, NOTHING. YET.
- OH.
- [ Clears Throat ]
BUT, UH, AS I WAS SAYING--
ABOUT THE WOMAN--
I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU CAN WORRY
ABOUT SOME WOMAN IN A CROWD,
WHEN YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO BE
CONDUCTING AN INVESTIGATION.
[ Fork Hitting Plate ]
YE-- BUT THERE WAS
A SINGULARLY HAUNTING
QUALITY ABOUT HER.
LIKE SOME WILD CREATURE,
CORNERED.
YOU SQUASHED MY PEA.
NOW YOU'VE GOT IT CORNERED.
YEAH, BUT SQUASHING
YOUR FELLOW'S PEA--
WELL, JUST TRYING TO HELP.
I DIDN'T WANT IT SQUASHED.
I DON'T LIKE IT THAT WAY,
SQUASHED.
I LIKE IT WHOLE.
SO THAT YOU CAN FEEL IT POP
WHEN YOU BITE DOWN ON IT.
WELL, I'M SORRY.
I WASN'T THINKING.
[ Knocking ]
I'LL GET THE DOOR,
OLD FELLOW.
A TELEGRAM FOR YOU, MR. HOLMES.
THE BOY DIDN'T WAIT
FOR AN ANSWER.
AH, WELL, THANK YOU,
MRS. HUDSON. AND GOOD NIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT, SIR.
[ Door Closes ]
AH, MORE FROM OUR
ANONYMOUS ADVISER.
[ Sighs ]
HE INVITES US
TO MEET HIM...
- AT THE ELIZABETH WHARF.
- OH, REALLY?
NO GOOD.
NO ONE HERE.
HMM.
YOU SEE? JUST SOME
DAMN SORT OF HOAX.
[ Holmes ] OUR INFORMANT
SEEMS STRANGELY RELUCTANT
TO REVEAL HIMSELF.
[ Man ] I COULDN'T COMMIT THIS
TO A TELEGRAPH, MR. HOLMES.
[ Watson ]
WHERE ARE YOU?
[ Man ]
IT'S TOO DANGEROUS
FOR THE MAN INVOLVED.
AH, THERE. IN THE BOAT,
UNDERNEATH US.
[ Holmes ]
DANGEROUS FOR YOU,
TOO, I SURMISE.
IF YOU WANT TO KNOW MORE
ABOUT THE RIPPER MURDERS,
I REFER YOU...
TO ROBERT JAMES LEES.
WHERE CAN I FIND THIS LEES?
HE'S PULLING
YOUR LEG, HOLMES.
ROBERT JAMES LEES,
THE ELMS, RIVERSIDE WAY.
[ Clattering ]
THERE'S MORE, MR. HOLMES.
ANYONE THERE?
ANYBODY THERE?
[ Holmes ]
WATSON?
WATSON!
SAW HIM, EH?
RECOGNIZE THE FELLOW?
-NO, BUT THE VOICE
WAS FAMILIAR.
- UH?
THERE'S A QUALITY IN IT
I SEEM TO KNOW.
WHAT ABOUT THIS FELLOW
HE MENTIONED, LEES?
KNOW HIM?
YES, I BELIEVE I DO.
HE HAS SOME REPUTATION
AS A MEDIUM.
GOOD GOD!
DIFFICULT TO SEE HOW
HE MIGHT BE INVOLVED.
AND THAT'S ALL
HE HAD TO SAY.
NO.
- HE SAID SOMETHING
EXTRAORDINARY.
-OH?
A FASCINATING PIECE OF
EVIDENCE HAS BEEN DISCOVERED.
WE MUST NOT LOSE A MOMENT,
IF WE COULD TAKE
ADVANTAGE OF IT.
'ERE, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHO ARE YOU?
I MEAN, YOU HAVE
NO BUSINESS BEIN' HERE.
SHERLOCK HOLMES, MY GOOD MAN.
OH, YEAH?
AND MY ASSOCIATE,
DR. WATSON.
I DON'T GIVE A CUSTARD.
YOU MAY BE ON HIM AND OFF HIM.
IS THIS SHERLOCK HOLMES?
JUST YOU GET YOURSELF
OFF AND OUT OF HERE,
MR. SHERLOCK HOLMES.
THIS IS PRIVATE PROPERTY.
AND YOU ALONG WITH HIM,
DR. BLEEDIN' WATSON!
I SEE YOU TWO
SULKIN' ABOUT!
[ Watson, Indistinct ]
- I THINK I SHOULD CALL
THE POLICE, YOU KNOW?
-DON'T DO THAT, OLD MAN.
WELL, GET GOIN' THEN.
GET OFF.
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
[ Clattering ]
WHY'D THE FELLOW HAVE TO
HIDE HIMSELF LIKE THAT?
AND WHY PASS A MESSAGE
IN SUCH A RIDICULOUS MANNER?
IT WOULD SUGGEST
HE DIDN'T WISH TO BE
SEEN TALKING TO US.
NOBODY THERE TO SEE HIM.
AH, BUT THERE WAS.
WELL, IT'S NEWS TO ME.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
THEY'VE BEEN WATCHING US...
EVER SINCE
WE TOOK UP THE CASE.
THEY'RE WATCHING US
AT THIS VERY MOMENT.
REALLY?
[ Fizzing ]
THERE'S NOBODY OUT THERE.
OH, NATURALLY, OLD MAN,
HE'S NOT GOING TO SHOW HIMSELF.
BUT, AS A PRECAUTION,
WE WILL LEAVE
THROUGH THE GARDEN.
IF THINGS ARE GETTING
DANGEROUS, I DON'T LIKE
YOU TO GO UNARMED, HOLMES.
I KNOW YOU DON'T LIKE
CARRYING PISTOLS, BUT
JUST FOR SAFETY--
WELL, I'M NOT ENTIRELY
UNARMED, OLD CHAP.
IT'S, UM, VERY EFFECTIVE.
ANCIENT INDIAN DEVICE.
USED BY A CULT
OF FEROCIOUS ASSASSINS.
OH, THE THUGGEE.
YES, THAT IS
ONE OF THEIR TRICKS.
I DID SERVE IN INDIA,
YOU KNOW.
OF COURSE YOU DID,
OLD CHUM.
[ Clears Throat ]
[ Glass Smashing ]
[ Dog Barking ]
WHAT IS IT
YOU HOPE TO FIND?
OR SHOULDN'T I ASK?
GIVE ME A MOMENT,
DEAR FELLOW.
SOMEONE HAS BEEN
HERE BEFORE US.
SOMEONE WHO DOESN'T WANT
ANYONE TO SEE THE MESSAGE.
AH YES, HERE, I THINK.
I DON'T SEE ANYTHING.
GIVE ME--
GIVE ME THE BOTTLE, WATSON.
AND THE BRUSH.
MM-HMM.
AND, UH, HOLD
THE LANTERN STEADY.
WHAT IS IT THAT
WE'RE SUPPOSED TO--
OH!
NOW, QUICKLY, WATSON.
TAKE THIS DOWN.
BEFORE THE PLASTER
ABSORBS THE LIQUID.
UH-HUH.
"BLAME FOR NOTHING."
UH-HUH. UH-HUH.
THERE.
"THE... JUWES?"
"ARE NOT THE MEN THAT WILL
BE BLAMED FOR NOTHING."
VERY WELL.
[ Watson ]
WELL, THERE'S THE WORDS,
EXACTLY AS WRITTEN.
AND THE SPELLING?
YES, IT'S VERY ODD,
ISN'T IT?
WHAT DO YOU THINK IT IS?
HEBREW, YOU THINK?
OH, I THINK NOT.
IT MEANS JEWS.
HOW ARE WE
TO UNDERSTAND IT, THEN?
[ Mumbling ]
"JEWS ARE RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE CRIMES."
AND?
[ Chuckling ] AND THEY'RE
NOT GONNA GET CAUGHT.
WRITTEN BY WHOM?
NOT THE MURDERER, SURELY.
WHOEVER WROTE
THIS MESSAGE--
...MAY HAVE SEEN
THE MURDERER.
[ Scoffs ]
YOU'RE INVALUABLE
TO ME, WATSON,
WITH YOUR INSTINCTIVE
GRASP FOR THE OBVIOUS.
[ Chuckles ]
BUT WHY DIDN'T HE GO TO
THE POLICE? WHY DID HE WRITE
THIS RIDICULOUS MESSAGE?
AH, BECAUSE A MAN
MIGHT USE THESE CRIMES
FOR HIS OWN PURPOSES.
IMAGINE A MORE MALIGN
INFLUENCE AT WORK.
"FOR HIS OWN PURPOSES?"
I'M NOT WITH YOU.
I SHALL SMOKE A PIPE OR TWO
BEFORE I RETIRE.
[ Bell Ringing ]
VERY WELL.
I'LL KEEP YOU COMPANY.
NO, NO.
NO, OLD CHAP.
WE ARE GRAPPLING
WITH A DARK INTENTION,
AND I HAVE A SENSE OF
SOME VAGUE OUTLINE.
NO, THANK YOU.
I WOULD PREFER
MY OWN COMPANY TONIGHT.
WELL, OF COURSE.
IF YOU FEEL
IT'S NOT WANTED.
[ Clock Chiming ]
E-EARLY IN THE MORNING,
OLD FELLOW,
WE HAVE A PRESSING NEED
TO MEET WITH ROBERT LEES.
I UNDERSTAND
YOU KNOW SOMETHING OF
THE WHITECHAPEL MURDERS.
I HAVE SEEN THE MAN
KNOWN AS JACK THE RIPPER.
GOOD GOD!
[ Scoffs ]
[ Train Whistle Blowing ]
I WAS SITTING HERE,
READING, WHEN I WAS OVERWHELMED
WITH AN INTUITION OF A MAN...
AND A YOUNG WOMAN.
BUT DID YOU NOT
GO TO THE POLICE?
YES.
AND THEY TREATED HIM
AS A RAVING LUNATIC.
IT IS AN EXPERIENCE OUTSIDE
THEIR OWN, SOMETHING THEY CANNOT
ALLOW THEMSELVES TO ACCEPT.
DO YOU ACCEPT IT?
I HAVE BEEN WITNESS
TO MUCH STRANGER EVENTS.
WELL, THE FOLLOWING EVENING,
JUST SUCH A MURDER TOOK PLACE.
- THE WOMAN'S NAME
WAS ANNIE CHAPMAN.
- [ Sniffs ] STUFF!
I HAVE SEEN HIM AGAIN,
MR. HOLMES.
ANOTHER VISION?
NO.
NO, THIS TIME IN PERSON.
[ Chattering ]
[ Street Vendor Hawking,
Indistinct ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
STRANGE STORY INDEED.
BUT YOU'VE SEEN
MORE OF THIS MAN,
HAVE YOU NOT?
- MADAM, I'M SORRY.
-[ Footsteps ]
EXCUSE ME, MA'AM.
MR. HOLMES, SIR CHARLES
WOULD LIKE TO SEE YOU.
HE WAS MOST INSISTENT.
I APOLOGIZE FOR
THE INTERRUPTION, MA'AM.
I HAD NO CHOICE.
WELL, THANK YOU BOTH
FOR YOUR HOSPITALITY.
I KNOW
WE SHALL MEET AGAIN.
[ Door Closes ]
GOOD LORD.
IT'S MAKINS!
YOU RECOGNIZE
THIS MAN, HOLMES?
YES, I DO.
YOU WON'T DENY
YOU WERE IN HIS EMPLOY.
I'M IN MY OWN EMPLOY, SIR.
THIS MAN, AND OTHERS,
INQUIRED AFTER MY SERVICES.
I HAVE GIVEN THEM
NO REPLY AS YET.
DON'T PLAY GAMES WITH ME!
YOU'RE RUNNING
WITH THE FOXES.
AND YOU KNOW THEIR
COLORS FULL WELL.
IF I TAKE CORRECTLY
THE MEANING OF YOUR COLORFUL
METAPHOR, SIR CHARLES,
YES, I AM AWARE THAT
MAKINS WAS A RADICAL,
OR REVOLUTIONARY, TO BE EXACT.
- I SAY, HOLMES.
- SO! YOU ADMIT YOUR PART
IN THEIR CONSPIRACY.
THEIR TREASON!
THAT'S DAMN NONSENSE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, SIR?
STEADY, OLD FELLOW.
I BELIEVE SIR CHARLES
MEANS TO ARREST ME.
ARREST YOU?
SHERLOCK HOLMES,
GUILTY OF TREASON?
THAT'S ABSURD!
NOT TREASON, WATSON.
MURDER.
PRECISELY.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
FALLING-OUT YOU HAD
WITH YOUR SLIMY FRIENDS,
BUT I CAN PLACE YOU
AT THE SCENE
OF THE MURDER.
AND DON'T BE TOO CERTAIN
I WON'T DISCOVER
YOUR TREASONOUS PLOTTING.
SIR CHARLES?
I'LL HAVE PLENTY OF TIME WHILE
YOU'RE SITTING IN NEWGATE JAIL.
THERE'S THAT FELLOW
FROM THE DOCKS.
HE MUST HAVE SEEN
EVERYTHING THAT HAPPENED.
YES, I THINK RESCUE IS
AT HAND, AND I DON'T BELIEVE
THE COMMISSIONER LIKES IT.
QUICKLY, WATSON.
I WANT TO EXAMINE
THE WOUND.
HOLMES, WHY WOULD
RADICALS HIRE YOU
TO CATCH A MADMAN?
YES, WHY INDEED?
FOOD FOR THOUGHT.
WHY FEED US INFORMATION
IN SUCH A BIZARRE FASHION?
MORE IMPORTANT STILL,
WHO KILLED MAKINS, AND WHY?
HOW DID YOU KNOW
THEY WERE RADICALS?
MM, SWORD-STICK.
OH, NO MAGIC, WATSON.
I SIMPLY MADE INQUIRIES
AT WHITECHAPEL.
THAT MADE YOU SUSPICIOUS?
NO, IT WAS MAKINS.
A BAD ACTOR, WITH
HIS EXCESSIVE CIVILITY.
AND THEN LANIER'S
RESENTMENT OF RICH LADIES
AND THEIR PALACES.
IT IS FORTUNATE
FOR YOU, MR. HOLMES, THAT
THE DOCK GUARD WAS SO DILIGENT.
OH, I TAKE IT THEN,
WE'RE FREE.
FOR THE MOMENT, YES.
SIR CHARLES WOULD LIKE
TO SEE YOU IN HIS OFFICE
IMMEDIATELY.
DON'T PROVOKE HIM.
HE IS DETERMINED TO
HAVE YOU OFF THIS CASE.
HE'S A DANGEROUS MAN.
HE HAS MANY SECRET FRIENDS.
SO GO CAREFULLY.
"SECRET FRIENDS."
[ Inhales ]
CURIOUS EXPRESSION.
[ Door Opens ]
I WARN YOU, HOLMES!
IF YOU PURSUE THIS MAT--
SO--
WHAT THE--
FORGIVE THE SLEIGHT OF HAND,
SIR CHARLES.
IN THE PURSUIT OF CRIMINALS,
ONE LEARNS THEIR DEVICES.
I SAY, HOLMES, WHAT IS
THIS MUMBO JUMBO?
THE HANDSHAKE AND THE RING,
WATSON, ARE ARCHAIC RITUALS...
PRESERVED BY
THE 33rd DEGREE MEMBERS OF
THE SECRET ORDER OF FREEMASONS.
WE ARE NOT
A SECRET ORDER.
YOUR EXISTENCE
IS NO SECRET.
YOU RITUALS AND MEMBERSHIP
ARE SECRETS YOU GUARD
AS CLOSELY AS YOU MAY.
WHICH IS WHY YOU REMOVED
THE WRITING FROM THE WALL.
I AM RESPONSIBLE FOR THE SAFETY
OF THE PEOPLE OF THIS CITY.
AND THEIR RIGHT TO GO
SAFELY ABOUT THEIR BUSINESS.
- DOES THAT INCLUDE THE RIGHT
TO MURDER AND MUTILATE?
- YOU FOOL!
JEWS WOULD HAVE BEEN SLAUGHTERED
IN THE STREETS IF I HAD NOT HAD
THOSE WORDS REMOVED.
DO YOU KNOW THE THEORY
GIVEN GREATEST CREDENCE
AMONG THE COMMON PEOPLE?
THAT THIS IS
A BLOOD RITUAL.
CARRIED OUT BY SOME JEW
WHOSE RELIGIOUS FERVOR...
SENDS HIM OUT IN SEARCH
OF PROSTITUTES...
TO OFFER AS A SACRIFICE
TO HIS GOD.
IF THOSE WORDS HAD BEEN SEEN,
NOT A JEW WOULD HAVE BEEN SAFE!
THEIR HOUSES AND THEIR SHOPS
WOULD BE DESTROYED.
NONSENSE, WARREN.
THE WRITING HAD NOTHING
TO DO WITH THE JEWS--
YOU KNOW THAT.
YOU DID NOT REMOVE THAT
WRITING TO PROTECT JEWS
AGAINST ANTI-SEMITIC RAGE.
THE JEWS--
OR "JUWES"--
REFERRED TO ARE FROM
YOUR OWN SECRET SOCIETY...
OF THE LOYAL ORDER
OF FREEMASONS.
WE-- WELL,
"BENEVOLENT SOCIETY."
[ Bell Pealing ]
WE ARE NO DANGER--
THIS IS NOT THE KIND OF
PALTRY, SORDID EPISODE...
YOU'RE ACCUSTOMED
TO MEDDLING IN, HOLMES.
AND YOU DO SO
AT GREAT RISK TO YOURSELF.
GOOD DAY.
YOU SEE.
I CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT
THAT PECULIAR GESTURE
OF YOURS WAS ALL ABOUT.
I COULDN'T MAKE
HEAD NOR TAIL OVER IT.
IT GAVE SIR CHARLES PAUSE.
YOU SHUT HIM UP!
QUITE A GOOD THING, TOO.
[ Chuckling ]
I DON'T KNOW WHICH CAUSED HIM
THE GREATER ANXIETY:
THE FACT THE I KNEW
THE SECRET SIGNS,
- OR THE POSSIBILITY THAT
I, TOO, MIGHT BE A MASON.
- MEANING WHAT, EXACTLY?
THESE ARE THE SIGNS
WHICH ARE EMPLOYED
BY FREEMASONS.
IN THEIR CEREMONIES.
TO ESTABLISH
EACH OTHER'S RANK.
BUT HOW ARE
THE MASONS INVOLVED?
AH. WHOEVER WROTE
THAT MESSAGE...
IS A MASON--
OR A MAN LIKE MYSELF,
WHO HAS MADE A STUDY
OF THEIR PRACTICES.
YOU MEAN HE ACCUSES THE MASONS?
HE WANTS US TO BELIEVE THAT
JACK THE RIPPER IS A MASON?
- OH, COME ON, HOLMES.
- I KNOW.
I'VE FORMED NO OPINION
EITHER WAY, WATSON.
BUT THE JEWS-- OR "JUWES"--
AGAINST WHOM THE ACCUSATIONS
ARE BEING MADE,
WERE THREE MEN WHO
MURDERED THE GRAND MASTER,
BUILDER OF SOLOMON'S TEMPLE.
OH, REALLY?
ACCORDING TO MASONIC RITUAL.
"AND THEIR NAMES WERE
JUBELA, JUBELO...
AND JUBELUM."
HENCE, JEWS OR JUWES.
THE THINGS YOU KNOW, HOLMES.
[ Chuckles ]
OH, WHEN THEY WERE
BROUGHT BEFORE SOLOMON,
THEY CONFESSED TO THEIR GUILT.
AND JUBELA SAID,
"O THAT MY THROAT
HAD BEEN CUT ACROSS."
AND, UH, JUBELO SAID,
"O THAT MY LEFT BREAST
HAD BEEN TORN OPEN,
"MY HEART AND VITALS TAKEN,
THROWN OVER MY LEFT SHOULDER."
AND JUBELUM SAID,
"MY BODY SEVERED IN THE MIDST."
GOOD GOD. THAT POOR WOMAN'S
BODY WAS MUTILATED
IN JUST THAT SAVAGE WAY.
NOW, ASSUMING THAT THERE IS,
AS YOU SAY, SOME CONNECTION
BETWEEN THOSE...
GHASTLY MURDERS
AND THE MASONIC RITUAL,
IN WHAT WAY WERE THESE
WRETCHED WOMEN INVOLVED?
WELL, ASK THEM. HMM?
WHAT?
WELL, THEIR FRIENDS.
WE HAVE TO ASK THE LIVING,
OF COURSE. WE COULD
HARDLY ASK THE DEAD.
THAT'S A RELIEF.
I THOUGHT FOR A MOMENT
YOU WERE GOING THE SAME WAY
AS ROBERT LEES.
TALKING TO THE DEAD.
[ Clears Throat ]
WELL,
WHILE YOU'RE MAKING
YOURSELF FAMILIAR WITH
THE DEAD WOMAN'S FRIENDS,
I SHALL ENDEAVOR TO...
[ Liquid Pouring ]
[ Glass Clinks ]
INGRATIATE MYSELF WITH
SAID ROBERT LEES.
HMM, GOOD LUCK, HOLMES.
[ Children Chattering ]
[ Coughs ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Coughing Continues ]
MORNING, GUV.
[ Coughs ]
[ Coughing ]
HELLO, LOVE.
OH. MADAM DIDN'T TELL ME
TO EXPECT NO CHIMNEY SWEEP.
YOU-- YOU FETCH HER DOWN
AND SHE'LL TELL YOU.
I'LL DO NO SUCH THING.
HERE I AM
AND HERE I STAY.
I'VE COME
TO SWEEP THE CHIMNEY.
BUT WE'RE NOT READY FOR YOU!
YOU HAVE TO COME BACK.
YOU FETCH THE MISSUS.
[ Coughing ]
WHAT'S GOING ON DOWN HERE?
MRS. LEES, I DO APOLOGIZE
FOR TROUBLING YOU
IN THIS MANNER.
WHO ARE YOU?
I-- I ADOPTED
THIS DISGUISE...
TO SPARE YOUR HUSBAND
ANY FURTHER INCONVENIENCE.
HOW DARE YOU TRY AND TRICK
YOUR WAY IN TO SEE MY HUSBAND.
WELL, I REALLY WANTED
TO SEE YOU, MRS. LEES,
AND, IF YOU WOULD ALLOW ME,
TO SPEAK BRIEFLY
WITH YOUR HUSBAND.
YOU SEE THE DANGER
YOU HAVE PUT HIM IN.
AND HE HAS NOTHING
TO DO WITH THIS.
YES.
AND I WILL ABIDE
BY YOUR DECISION.
- BUT I SAY ONE THING--
- I WILL NOT BE SWAYED,
MR. HOLMES.
IF YOUR HUSBAND CAN
HELP ME FIND THIS MAN...
AND PREVENT ANY MORE
OF THESE ATROCIOUS CRIMES,
DO YOU HAVE
THE RIGHT TO DENY ME?
HMM, WE WERE...
DINING AT HOME,
AND SUDDENLY...
[ Train Whistle Blows
In Distance ]
I KNEW THAT
HE HAD KILLED AGAIN.
[ Train Passing ]
[ Holmes ]
AGAIN, YOU WENT TO THE POLICE.
YES.
THEY WERE MORE INCLINED
TO LISTEN THIS TIME.
I WAS ABLE TO...
GIVE THEM...
DETAILS THAT
NO ONE COULD HAVE KNOWN.
THEY ASKED ME TO TRACK HIM...
FROM THE SCENE OF THE CRIME.
[ Lees ]
I COULD FIND
NO IMAGE OF HIM THERE.
THERE, WHERE HE HAD
COMMITTED THIS BRUTAL MURDER.
THEY GAVE ME A-A PIECE OF
THE MURDERED GIRL'S DRESS.
AND I-I COULD FIND
NO SENSE OF HIM.
AND THEN THE INSPECTOR
GAVE ME SOMETHING QUITE TRIVIAL,
UNCONNECTED PERHAPS.
THE STEM FROM
A BUNCH OF GRAPES.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?
BUT YOU WERE THEN
ABLE TO SENSE THE MAN.
YES. HE-- HE WAS THERE.
I MEAN, IT WAS
AS IF HE WAS THERE.
I HAD MERELY TO FOLLOW HIM.
THERE.
IMPOSSIBLE.
[ Holmes ]
DID YOU GO INTO THE HOUSE?
[ Lees ] WE DID.
YOU CONFRONTED THE MAN.
HOW DID HE RECEIVE YOU?
THE INSPECTOR SPOKE WITH HIM.
[ Train Whistle Blows
In Distance ]
HE WAS NOT IMPRESSED
BY MY INTUITION.
HE HEARD US OUT POLITELY,
REMINDED US HOW LATE IT WAS,
[ Train Passing ]
AND THEN HE SUGGESTED
THAT IT WOULD BE BETTER
IF WE LEFT.
YOU'VE BEEN MOST CAREFUL
NOT TO MENTION THE MAN'S
NAME, HAVEN'T YOU?
I REALIZE HOW PERSUASIVE
SIR CHARLES CAN BE.
HE CAME HERE.
HE THREATENED MY HUSBAND
IN HIS OWN HOME.
NO. I CAN'T EXPECT YOU
TO BREAK YOUR WORD.
MR. HOLMES,
I HAVE THE STRONGEST
INTUITION CONCERNING YOU.
I SENSE SOME DANGER,
[ Train Passing ]
CLOSE AND THREATENING.
[ Train Whistle Blows
In Distance ]
I HAVE A SENSE OF IT MYSELF.
[ Chattering ]
IT AIN'T FAIR. EVERYBODY'S
GOING ON LIKE IT'S OUR FAULT--
LIKE WE'RE TO BLAME.
LIKE AS IF WE'D GO OUT AND LOOK
FOR HIM, EGG THE BLEEDER ON
TO CUT HER BLOODY THROAT.
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO GO
ASKING ABOUT POLLY FOR?
WHAT'S SHE GOT TO DO WITH YOU?
WRITING ABOUT HER,
DON'T YOU KNOW?
WRITING FOR THE NEWSPAPERS.
YOU DON'T WANT TO WRITE
NOTHING BAD ABOUT POLLY.
DON'T INTEND TO, NO,
BUT IT SEEMS TO ME
THAT A DEAL MORE...
IS WRITTEN ABOUT THE MURDERER
THAN ABOUT HIS VICTIMS.
THAT'S TRUE.
IT'S TRUE, ISN'T IT?
LIKE HE'S IMPORTANT
AND THEY AIN'T.
PRECISELY.
IF ANYBODY THOUGHT
ABOUT THE LIKES OF US,
WE WOULDN'T HAVE
COME TO THIS.
UH, ONE THING, UH,
POLLY NICHOLS,
WAS SHE FRIENDS WITH
ANY OF THE OTHER WOMEN?
[ Watson ]
HMM?
[ Whistle Blows ]
[ Woman ] OH!
TALK TO MARY IF YOU WANT TO
KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT OLD POLLY.
MARY. UH, WHAT'S
HER OTHER NAME?
MARY KELLY.
WHERE COULD I FIND HER?
YOU WON'T FIND HER
ROUND HERE NO MORE.
SHE THINKS HERSELF
A CUT ABOVE US.
TOFFEE-NOSED SLUT.
UH, YOU KNOW WHERE
I COULD FIND MARY KELLY?
COME OVER 'ERE.
I'LL TELL YOU ALL ABOUT HER.
EXCUSE ME, LADIES.
BETTER KEEP YOUR MOUTH CLOSED,
YOU LITTLE SLUT.
DON'T BOTHER WITH HER.
SHE DOESN'T KNOW MARY.
COME ON.
SIT DOWN.
CHEAP TARTS.
THEY'RE JEALOUS
'CAUSE I'M YOUNG,
AND I GET ALL THE BLOKES.
GOT ALL ME OWN TEETH.
THAT'S WHY.
WHAT DO YOU WANT
WITH MARY KELLY ANYWAY?
HER TEETH'S FALLEN OUT TOO.
NOT LIKE MINE.
HAVE A FEEL.
OH, NO.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH, BUT--
OH, COME ON, LOVE.
I WON'T BITE YOU.
SEE? FIRM AS A ROCK.
YES, REMARKABLE.
OH, GOD.
OH, BLOODY HELL.
OH. JUST ONE LOOSE.
- WHAT ARE YOU STARING AT?
- OH, I-- NOTHING.
ARE WE GONNA
SIT HERE ALL DAY?
WELL, THERE'S
NO HURRY ACTUALLY.
NOT FOR ME EITHER.
I JUST THOUGHT MAYBE, UH--
YES, WELL, UM--
NOW, SUPPOSE I'M LOOKING
FOR THIS YOUNG WOMAN,
THIS PARTICULAR YOUNG WOMAN.
THERE'S PLENTY OF OTHERS.
YES. AND SUPPOSE I SAY...
I'M LOOKING FOR
THIS PARTICULAR YOUNG WOMAN.
UM, UH--
COME WITH ME.
WE CAN'T TALK HERE,
IF YOU TAKE MY MEANING.
OH, YES, YES.
I SEE WHAT YOU MEAN.
[ Clucking ]
NEAR HERE THE RIPPER
COMMITTED HIS FIRST MURDER.
YOU'VE GOT HIM ON THE BRAIN.
CAN'T TALK OF NOTHING ELSE.
I'M BOUND TO
TALK ABOUT HIM.
IN THERE?
WANT MARY KELLY?
I'M TAKING YOU TO HER.
YES, BUT, UM--
HMM.
COME ON.
I RECKON THAT'S WHY
YOU COME DOWN HERE,
ALL YOU TOFFS.
YOU WANT TO
TALK ABOUT HIM--
WHAT HE DONE.
GET A LOT OF TOFFS
COMING DOWN HERE, DO YOU?
ALL KINDS.
OF COURSE, TALK'S ALL THEM
BLOKES IS GOOD FOR.
NOT LIKE YOU.
COME ON. THIS WAY.
UH, SHE LIVES AROUND HERE,
DOES SHE, MARY KELLY?
LOOK. I'LL TELL YOU STRAIGHT.
I DON'T KNOW THIS MARY KELLY.
YOU-- BUT YOU PROMISED.
YOU SAID--
[ Whistles ]
WHAT'S THAT FOR?
AHA.
AND WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THAT'S MY WOMAN YOU GOT THERE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING WITH HER?
AN OLD GEEZER LIKE YOU,
WITH A FINE LADY
OF YOUR OWN AT HOME...
WAITING FOR YA,
WORRYING ABOUT YA,
AND YOU DOWN HERE,
MESSING ABOUT WITH MY WOMAN.
NOW, YOU WOULDN'T LIKE ME
TO GO AND VISIT YOUR WIFE,
NOW, WOULD YOU?
I SEE. SO IT'S
THAT OLD GAME, IS IT?
WELL, YOU'VE CHOSEN
THE WRONG VICTIM,
MY GOOD MAN.
WE'LL SEE WHAT THE POLICE
HAVE TO SAY ABOUT THIS.
[ Blows Whistle ]
[ Grunts ]
GOOD OLD DANNY.
[ Groaning ]
STAY THERE, YOU PIMP.
WHAT'S THE TROUBLE HERE?
[ Watson ]
THANK GOODNESS. JUST IN TIME.
HE'S JACK THE RIPPER.
[ Man Groaning ]
WHO, HIM?
HE GRABBED ME, AND HE WAS
GONNA SLIT MY BLOODY THROAT...
WHEN MY MATE PULLED HIM OFF
AND THEN HE ATTACKED HIM.
JUST A MINUTE.
THAT OLD FELLOW? HE COULDN'T
RIP MY OLD GRANDMOTHER.
I RESENT THAT.
HE'S THE RIPPER.
YOU BETTER ARREST HIM,
OR I'LL SCREAM
AND BRING OUR MOB.
YOU'LL DO NOTHING OF THE SORT.
YOU TRYING TO GET HIM KILLED?
COME ALONG. WE'LL SORT
THIS OUT DOWN THE STATION.
YOU'RE MAKING A GRAVE ERROR.
SERVES YOU RIGHT,
YOU OLD FART.
THANK YOU.
HEY. GET OFF!
I HAVEN'T DONE ANYTHING!
LEAVE ME ALONE!
[ All Chattering ]
[ Keys Jingling ]
[ Key Clattering In Lock ]
WELL, WELL.
[ Laughs ]
HERE'S A PRETTY MESS
YOU'VE GOTTEN YOURSELF
INTO, OLD CHAP.
FOR GOD'S SAKE, HOLMES.
[ Groans ]
WHAT'S TAKEN YOU SO LONG?
WELL, I CAME WITH ALL SPEED
AS SOON AS I HEARD.
NOW, HE'LL BE RELEASED
INTO YOUR CUSTODY, MR. HOLMES.
YOU'LL BE RESPONSIBLE
FOR HIS FUTURE GOOD BEHAVIOR.
YOU UNDERSTAND NOW?
"GOOD BEHAVIOR."
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YEAH.
LEARNED YOUR LESSON, DOCTOR?
DON'T PLAY THE SILLY
WITH US, LESTRADE.
MY BLOKES TELL ME
YOU PUT UP QUITE A STRUGGLE.
I GAVE A GOOD ACCOUNT OF MYSELF.
I'M CERTAIN HE DID.
[ Chuckles ]
MR. HOLMES, MY ADVICE
TO YOU IS THAT YOU
TAKE HIM HOME...
AND YOU SEE THAT
HE'S NOT LET GET
INTO ANY MORE MISCHIEF.
EH?
OH, COME ALONG, WATSON.
FOR GOD'S SAKE.
[ Watson ]
DAMN THE FELLOW.
DIDN'T IT OCCUR TO YOU
THAT SOMETHING WAS AMISS WHEN
I DIDN'T COME HOME LAST NIGHT?
CALM YOURSELF, OLD MAN.
I WASN'T HOME MYSELF.
I HAD SOME BUSINESS TO--
THEY WERE READY
TO TEAR ME TO PIECES.
YES. ALL RIGHT.
COME, WATSON. ALL WE NEED
IS TO TAKE YOU HOME AND
GET YOU A GOOD MEAL AND REST.
I'M PERFECTLY FIT.
READY FOR ANYTHING.
[ Laughs ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
NOW, I DON'T BELIEVE THE WOMAN
WHO GAVE ME ALL THIS TROUBLE
EVEN KNEW MARY KELLY.
KELLY.
YES. MARY KELLY.
FRIEND OF POLLY NICHOLS.
THE PEOPLE WHO LIVED
IN THE DISTRICT DIDN'T SEEM
TO WANT TO TALK ABOUT HER.
THAT'S GOOD, WATSON.
THAT'S VERY GOOD.
NOW, POLLY NICHOLS.
VICTIM NUMBER ONE.
SHE WAS MURDERED HERE.
VICTIM NUMBER TWO,
ANNIE CHAPMAN,
WAS MURDERED HERE.
A CONSIDERABLE
DISTANCE APART.
THOSE TWO AND MARY KELLY--
HEAVEN KNOWS WHERE SHE LIVES--
THEY KNEW EACH OTHER.
THE THREE OF THEM WERE
VERY OFTEN SEEN IN A TAVERN
IN DORSET STREET.
THAT'S ANNIE CHAPMAN,
MARY KELLY AND POLLY NICHOLS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
NOW WE COME TO, UH,
ELIZABETH STRIDE.
THAT'S VICTIM NUMBER THREE.
LIZ STRIDE.
MURDERED THERE.
SHE WAS, UH,
CALLED LIZ, "LONG LIZ."
A TALL GIRL.
FOREIGN. SHE WAS
MARRIED TO-- OR RATHER,
SHE LIVED WITH A MAN...
WHOSE NAME I DON'T KNOW,
BUT THEIR ADDRESS
WAS DORSET STREET.
YOU SURPASSED YOURSELF, WATSON.
NOW, THESE FEW WOMEN,
LIVING WITHIN A FEW STREETS,
ALL KNOWING
EACH OTHER, THAT'S MORE
THAN COINCIDENCE, SURELY.
EXCELLENT, WATSON.
YOU'RE AN INSPIRATION.
BUT I HAVE MORE WORK FOR YOU.
YEAH?
I NEED YOUR HELP TO FIND
THE MAN LEES SOUGHT OUT.
DIDN'T LEES TELL YOU?
NO. HE WOULDN'T
TELL ME HIS NAME.
SIR CHARLES WARREN HAS
PUT HIM IN FEAR FOR HIS LIFE,
BUT I HAVE A NOTION
OF HIS ADDRESS.
STUDY THE MEDICAL DIRECTORY.
WE'RE LOOKING FOR A DOCTOR.
MORE PRECISELY, A PHYSICIAN.
THERE'S A LIST OF STREETS
WHICH YOU MUST PAY CAREFUL
ATTENTION TO ON MY TABLE.
- DON'T DASH OFF. WAIT FOR ME.
- WE'RE TOO CONSPICUOUS.
WE MUST TAKE SEPARATE PATHS.
AT LEAST TELL ME
WHERE YOU'RE GOING.
I'M GOING TO PAY MY LAST
RESPECTS TO CATHERINE EDDOWES.
I FEEL SHE WILL BE
MORE HELP TO US NOW
THAN WHEN SHE WAS ALIVE.
ALL RIGHT.
[ Bell Tolling ]
???? [ Bagpipes ]
[ Drums Beating ]
[ Tolling Continues ]
???? [ Bagpipes Continue ]
[ Drumbeats Continue ]
[ Horse Whinnies ]
[ Metal Clattering ]
[ Metal Scraping ]
[ Scraping Continues ]
MARY KELLY?
STAY AWAY.
I GOT A KNIFE.
I'LL STICK YA.
I WANT TO HELP YOU.
MY NAME IS SHERLOCK HOLMES.
WHY, WHAT DO YOU
WANT WITH ME?
I MUST TALK TO YOU.
WHERE CAN WE GO?
[ Sobbing ]
THE STREETS ARE SAFE
AS ANYWHERE ELSE.
OTHER PEOPLE
COME LOOKING FOR ME.
YESTERDAY THERE WAS
THIS OLD BLOKE ASKIN' AFTER ME.
YOU CAN TRUST ME.
I CAN'T TRUST NO ONE!
[ Gasps ]
OH. OW.
[ Gibbering ]
WHAT HAVE I DONE FOR THIS?
[ Sobbing ]
I KNOW THAT SOMETHING'S
FRIGHTENING YOU.
WHAT IS IT? TELL ME.
I WANT TO TELL SOMEONE.
[ Panting ]
AS LONG-- AS LONG AS
SOMEONE KNOWS--
SOMEONE ELSE.
TELLME.
NO.
I TOLD--
I TOLD ANNIE CHAPMAN
AND THEY DONE FOR HER.
[ Hoofbeats Approaching ]
[ Whinnies ]
DID YOU TELL
POLLY NICHOLS?
DID YOU KNOW POLL?
YOU TOLD HER, DIDN'T YOU?
NO.
[ Sobs ]
JESUS. I--
[ Breathing Erratically ]
YES.
[ Sobs ]
[ Hoofbeats Approaching ]
SHE-- SHE WAS WITH ME OFTEN.
[ Horse Whinnies ]
THEY MUST HAVE SEEN US.
THEY? WHO ARE THEY?
WHY ARE THEY LOOKING FOR YOU?
WHATEVER YOU'VE DONE,
WHATEVER YOU KNOW,
THERE'S NO REASON TO FEAR ME.
AYE, NO. THE BABY.
BABY?
SHE GAVE HER TO ME.
SHE SAID,
"LOOK AFTER HER."
SHE? WHO?
ANNIE.
ANNIE CHAPMAN.
ANNIE CROOK.
WELL, THEY TOOK HER...
[ Cat Meowing ]
AND SHUT HER AWAY.
UH--
BUT THEY DON'T DARE
TO KILL HER. THEY HAVE TO
KEEP HER SHUT AWAY.
WHERE HAVE THEY TAKEN HER?
FOR ALL THAT,
EDDY STILL LOVES HER.
EDDY?
HE WOULDN'T
LET THEM KILL HER.
OH, SWEET JESUS.
I'M SO FRIGHTENED.
[ Hoofbeats Approaching ]
WHERE CAN I FIND
THIS ANNIE CROOK?
I DON'T KNOW.
SHE WAS AT
ST. CHRISTOPHER'S,
BUT SHE'S
OUT OF THERE NOW.
THEY TOOK HER.
[ Horse Whinnies ]
[ Whimpers ]
HELP ME.
WON'T YOU PLEASE HELP ME?
COME, MARY. I'LL TAKE YOU
SOMEWHERE WHERE IT'S SAFE.
I CAN'T SLEEP NO MORE,
FOR FEAR THEY'LL FIND ME
WHEN I'M NOT WATCHING.
[ Hoofbeats Approaching ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Bell Tolling In Distance ]
[ Groans ]
WELL, WELL.
THANK GOD YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
I DON'T SEEM TO BE ABLE
TO RECALL ANYTHING.
I'M NOT SURPRISED.
YOU MAY HAVE SUSTAINED
A SLIGHT CONCUSSION.
WHAT THE DEVIL WERE YOU UP TO?
[ Chuckles ]
WELL,
THERE WAS A WOMAN.
[ Watson ]
MM-HMM.
WHAT HAPPENED TO HER?
WELL, LESTRADE TOLD ME
TO EXPECT SOMETHING DRAMATIC,
BUT HE DIDN'T PREPARE ME
FOR SOMETHING QUITE
SO DOWNRIGHT STUPID.
FOXBOROUGH.
WHOEVER IT WAS
WAS TRYING TO MURDER YOU.
IT WAS NO ACCIDENT.
YEAH. BUT THERE WAS
A YOUNG WOMAN. I REMEMBER.
I WANT YOU TO REST
FOR A WHILE, HOLMES.
I SAW THE CAB,
AND I SAW YOU,
BUT I--
I DIDN'T SEE ANY WOMAN.
I'M SURE THERE W--
WATSON DISCOVERED
SOMETHING, REMEMBER,
THAT YOU MIGHT
FIND USEFUL.
IT'S GOOD OF YOU
TO SAY SO, HOLMES.
IT WAS THAT THREE
OF THE MURDERED WOMEN...
HOLMES, PLEASE.
HAD, UH, A COMMON LINK.
THEY ALL FREQUENTED
A TAVERN IN DORSET STREET.
DORSET STREET.
THE BLACK HORSE?
YES, THAT'S THE ONE.
SHOULD YOU REQUIRE FURTHER
INFORMATION ABOUT POLLY NICHOLS,
I WAS TOLD ONE SHOULD
SPEAK TO A MARY KELLY.
- AND THAT WAS THE WOMAN.
- YES?
I WAS TALKING TO HER
WHEN THE HANSOM RAN ME DOWN.
YES. I HAD
AN INTUITION THAT...
SHE MIGHT BE AT THE CENTER
OF THIS PATTERN OF EVENTS.
I'LL SET MY MEN
TO LOOK FOR HER AT ONCE.
MARY KELLY, YOU SAY?
YES.
OH, FOXBOROUGH.
OH, I'M SORRY.
WOULD YOU CARE
FOR ME TO WAIT?
UH, NO. ON THE CONTRARY.
WITH THE ASSISTANCE
OF THE GOOD DOCTOR,
I SHALL PURSUE
MY OWN LINE OF INQUIRY.
[ Sighs ]
HOLMES!
YES?
YOU'RE ALWAYS DASHING OFF
WITHOUT TELLING ME WHERE YOU'RE
GOING OR WHAT OUR OBJECTIVE IS.
ST. CHRISTOPHER'S HOSPITAL,
OLD FELLOW, LOOKING FOR
A WOMAN NAMED ANNIE CROOK.
OH. NOW WE KNOW.
DID YOU HAVE MUCH LUCK
WITH THE MEDICAL DIRECTORY?
OH, YES.
UH, TOO MUCH,
I'M AFRAID.
I FOUND THE NAMES OF NO LESS
THAN A DOZEN PHYSICIANS
IN THE GENERAL AREA.
A MERE DOZEN? I THOUGHT
THERE WOULD HAVE BEEN
AT LEAST A HUNDRED.
HOLMES, TO ME, IT'S
INCONCEIVABLE THAT ANY PHYSICIAN
COULD BE REMOTELY CONNECTED...
WITH THESE ATROCIOUS CRIMES.
YOU MUST NOT ALLOW LOYALTY
TO YOUR PROFESSION...
TO PREVENT YOU DISCOVERING
THE TRUTH, MY DEAR FELLOW,
NO MATTER HOW UNPALATABLE.
WELL.
ILLUSTRIOUS NAMES INDEED.
THANK YOU.
I'M ONLY TOO SORRY,
DR. WATSON,
THAT I HAVEN'T BEEN
ABLE TO GIVE YOU ANY
MORE POSITIVE INFORMATION.
ON THE CONTRARY,
YOU'VE BEEN
MOST COOPERATIVE.
THANK YOU
VERY MUCH, DOCTOR.
DOCTOR, MR. GREGORY.
ANNIE CROOK ISN'T HERE.
OH, COME, COME, WATSON.
I TOLD YOU THAT.
BUT WHERE IS SHE?
IT'S NO EASY MATTER
PERSUADING THESE JOHNNIES TO
TALK ABOUT THEIR PATIENTS.
I'M SURE YOU DID
AN EXCELLENT JOB.
TOLD THEM SHE WAS
A SERVANT OF THE FAMILY
WHO'D COME TO LONDON.
PROMISED MY MOTHER
I'D LOOK HER UP.
YES. YES.
WELL, I TRUST
YOU WEREN'T TOO INVENTIVE
IN YOUR MENDACITY.
BUT, COME, WATSON,
A SIMPLE STORY, PLEASE.
I'M DOING MY BEST.
WHERE IS ANNIE CROOK?
A BROKEN NECK AND SCAPULA.
YES, YES, WATSON.
[ Clears Throat ]
OH, YES. ANNIE CROOK.
UH, THEY TOOK HER
TO A HOSPITAL NEAR READING.
ACCORDING TO WHAT THE DOCTOR
SAYS, IT'S MORE LIKE AN ASYLUM.
SHE'S STILL THERE?
IN HER PHYSICIAN'S OPINION,
SHE'LL BE THERE
FOR THE REST OF HER LIFE.
IT SEEMS THAT
THE POOR WOMAN IS, UM, INSANE.
HER PHYSICIAN IS,
BY THE WAY--
YES. SIR THOMAS SPIVEY.
GOOD GOD.
ONE OF THE COURT PHYSICIANS.
YOU KNEW ALREADY.
WELL, THE NAME IS
ON YOUR LIST, WATSON.
AND I HAVE BEEN COMPILING
ANOTHER LIST OF MY OWN.
I CAN'T KEEP PACE.
THERE IS A PARTICULAR
VARIETY OF GRAPE, WATSON.
GRAPE.
SPECIALLY IMPORTED FOR
THOSE WITH THE MOST
DISCRIMINATING OF TASTES.
AND AMONG THE PEOPLE WHO
PLACE AN ORDER FOR THEM--
SIR THOMAS SPIVEY.
THE ONLY NAME WE FIND
ON BOTH OUR LISTS.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING
IT'S A COURT PHYSICIAN?
TO BE SURE, WATSON.
TO BE SURE.
I'VE BEEN EXPLOITED,
OLD FELLOW, BY THE VERY PEOPLE
FOR WHOM WE ARE SEARCHING.
IT'S TIME
WE TURNED THE TABLES.
[ Whistle Blows ]
[ Watson ]
THIS WOMAN WE'RE ABOUT TO VISIT,
THIS ANNIE CROOK,
SHE HAD A DREADFUL ACCIDENT,
NOT UNLIKE YOURS.
IT SEEMED LIKE
SUPERFICIAL INJURIES AT FIRST,
AND THEN THINGS
TOOK A TURN FOR THE WORSE,
AND SIR THOMAS DECIDED
TO HAVE HER COMMITTED.
[ Holmes ]
YES. ODD.
VERY ODD.
WHY IS THIS WOMAN
SO DAMNED IMPORTANT
TO YOU, HOLMES?
AT THE MOMENT, I'M AS MUCH
IN THE DARK AS YOU,
BUT I DRAW YOUR ATTENTION
TO THE PECULIAR CIRCUMSTANCES
OF THE MAN WHO IS FOLLOWING US.
THERE'S NOBODY FOLLOWING US.
IT IS TO THAT PECULIAR
CIRCUMSTANCE THAT
I DRAW YOUR ATTENTION.
OH.
[ Chuckles ]
YOU MEAN, WHY NOT?
EXACTLY.
AH. AH, YES.
[ Man ]
WHOA THERE.
[ Whinnies ]
DRIVE ON.
COME ON. GIDDAP.
GIDDAP. GIDDAP.
[ Neighing ]
[ Hinges Squeak ]
[ Whispers ]
LEAVE ME ALONE TO TALK WITH
THE GIRL AS LONG AS YOU CAN.
UH-HUH.
[ Key Clattering ]
[ Door Squeaks ]
PLEASE TRY NOT TO
DISTURB THE OTHERS.
[ Moaning ]
[ Moaning Continues ]
SHE HARDLY SEEMS TO KNOW
THAT WE'RE HERE.
WELL, I'M QUITE SURE
THAT SHE DOESN'T,
DR. WATSON.
IT'S A STRANGE PHENOMENON.
SHE HASN'T SPOKEN A WORD
IN SIX MONTHS.
HAS HER CONDITION
DETERIORATED,
WOULD YOU SAY?
SINCE SHE FIRST CAME HERE?
OH, YES. YES. MARKEDLY.
[ Watson ]
I'D VERY MUCH APPRECIATE
A GLANCE AT HER RECORDS.
-IS THAT POSSIBLE?
- YES. YOU'LL FIND THEM
INTERESTING, I THINK.
YES. I'M SURE I WOULD.
YOU'LL EXCUSE US.
[ Woman Moaning ]
[ Door Hinges Squeaking ]
[ Muttering ]
[ Key Clattering ]
[ Muttering Continues ]
ANNIE.
I'M A FRIEND.
MARY SENT ME.
MARY KELLY.
DO YOU REMEMBER HER?
MARY'S FRIGHTENED,
ANNIE.
SHE'S FRIGHTENED
FOR HER LIFE.
I'D LIKE TO HELP HER,
BUT I CAN'T...
TILL I KNOW WHY
SHE'S FRIGHTENED.
[ Pencil Scratching ]
[ Women Murmuring ]
[ Murmuring Continues ]
EDDY.
WHERE?
[ Laughs ]
HE SENT YOU?
EDDY SENT YOU.
YOU.
I KNEW.
I KNEW...
HE WOULD SEND--
HE WOULD COME FOR ME.
HMM.
[ Chuckles ]
NO. MARY SENT ME.
MARY.
MARY...
YES.
SENT YOU?
HOW?
THEY WON'T LET ME SEE.
THEY?
MARY DOESN'T KNOW.
WELL.
NOBODY KNOWS.
WHY? WHY WON'T THEY
LET YOU SEE MARY?
MY BABY.
IS MY BABY SAFE?
MARY, KEEP MY BABY SAFE.
DON'T-- DON'T...
LET... THEM HURT--
NOW, WHY WOULD THEY
WANT TO HURT YOUR BABY?
AH.
WHY DO THEY KEEP YOU HERE?
DANGER. FOR THEM.
EDDY SAID--
HATE ME.
ANGRY WITH HIM.
AND THE BABY--
HE SAID,
"WHEN THEY KNOW--
KILL."
THEY?
HE...
WHO ARETHEY?
BROUGHT ME HERE.
I DON'T BELONG HERE.
YOU CAN SEE.
[ Woman Moaning ]
CAN'T YOU SEE?
[ Moaning Continues ]
I'M NOT CRAZY.
THEY ARE ALL CRAZY HERE.
I WON'T STAY HERE.
I WON'T LET THEM KEEP ME.
I WILL FIGHT THEM,
AND I'LL MAKE THEM--
HELP ME.
WHY DO THEY KEEP YOU HERE?
WHY DOES EDDY LET THEM
KEEP YOU HERE,
IF HE LOVES YOU?
HE LOVES ME!
[ Women Murmuring ]
[ Woman Whining ]
[ Whining Continues ]
HE LOVES ME.
DIDN'T HE MARRY ME?
DIDN'T WE HAVE A BABY?
- HE LOVES ME!
- WHY DOES HE LET THEM
KEEP YOU HERE?
[ Screams ]
I DON'T KNOW!
[ Women Yelling, Whining ]
[ Annie ]
OH!
[ Yelling, Whining Continue ]
BUT I HAVEN'T SEEN HIM.
THEY WON'T
LET ME SEE HIM.
THEY-- HE DOESN'T
KNOW WHERE I AM.
UH, THEY TELL HIM I RAN OFF,
I TOOK THE BABY,
I DON'T LOVE HIM.
I'M GOING TO
MAKE TROUBLE FOR HIM.
I LOVE HIM.
THEN HE MUST BE TOLD
WHERE YOU ARE.
DON'T LET THEM
HURT ME ANYMORE.
I WON'T TELL,
AND THEY HURT ME.
YEAH. THEY HURT ME.
WHY DO THEY WANT TO HURT YOU?
WHAT DO THEY WANT TO KNOW?
THEY WANT MY BABY.
AND I KNOW THEY'LL
HURT MY BABY IF I TELL.
OH, GOD IN HEAVEN.
BUT I CAN'T TELL.
I DON'T KNOW.
I SAY THAT,
AND THEY HURT ME.
PLEASE, DON'T
LET THEM HURT ME.
ANNIE.THEY.
WHO ARETHEY?
TELL ME, PLEASE.
I CA--
I TOLD THEM.
[ Gasps ]
MARY.
I... GAVE MY BABY...
TO MARY
FOR SAFEKEEPING.
I TOLD MARY
TO KEEP MY BABY SAFE.
[ Key Clattering ]
[ Door Opens ]
I TOLD THEM.
[ Annie ]
TOLD THEM.
WHAT THE DEVIL
ARE YOU DOING?
TOLD THEM.
THERE--
YOU HAVE NO BUSINESS
KEEPING THIS WOMAN
IN RESTRAINT.
HOLMES.
WHO ARE YOU?
SHE NEEDS CARE--
DESPERATELY NEEDS CARE.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Man ]
SHE HAS EVERY CARE.
WATSON, WE MUST
TAKE THIS WOMAN
FROM THIS HELLISH PLACE.
[ Watson ]
HOLMES,
YOU CAN'T DO THAT.
SHERLOCK HOLMES.
TH-THIS WOMAN CAME HERE
OF HER OWN FREE WILL.
SHE HAS NO FAMILY
TO CLAIM HER.
IT IS THE OPINION
OF HER PHYSICIAN...
AND THE BOARD THAT SHE SHOULD
STAY HERE UNTIL SUCH TIME--
[ Yells ]
HOLMES,
FOR GOD'S SAKE.
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Women Screaming, Yelling ]
[ Woman Cackling ]
[ Screaming, Yelling Continue ]
[ Train Whistle Blows ]
HOLMES.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
I KNOW YOU DON'T WANT
TO TALK, BUT IT DOES HELP
SOMETIMES, YOU KNOW.
I HATE TO SEE YOU
UPSET LIKE THIS.
[ Holmes ]
THE HEIR PRESUMPTIVE.
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
THE DUKE OF CLARENCE.
"EDDY," SHE SAID.
OH, GOD.
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
I NOW KNOW WHY
WE WERE NOT FOLLOWED.
THEY THOUGHT ANNIE CROOK
WAS HOPELESSLY INSANE.
THEY NEVER COUNTED ON
HER COURAGE...
AND HER EXTRAORDINARY WILL
TO PROTECT HER CHILD.
IT'S TOO LATE FOR ANNIE NOW.
AND I FEAR IT WILL BE
TOO LATE FOR MARY KELLY...
IF WE DON'T FIND HER
THIS VERY NIGHT.
WE MUST SAVE HER.
[ Train Whistle Blows ]
FORGIVE ME, WATSON.
I CAN SPARE NO THOUGHT
FOR ANY OTHER MATTER.
[ Foghorn Blows ]
[ Hoofbeats Passing ]
[ Man Yelling In Distance ]
[ Foghorn Blows ]
[ Whinnies ]
[ Man Yelling In Distance ]
ANY NEWS OF
THE KELLY WOMAN?
NOT A WORD, SIR.
WE'VE GOT EVERY MAN WE CAN
WALKING THE STREETS.
IF ANOTHER WOMAN'S
MURDERED TONIGHT, I SWEAR--
WHERE'S FOXBOROUGH?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
HE'S GONE OFF
ON HIS OWN SOMEWHERE.
HE'S A FUNNY BLOKE. CAN'T
GET HIM TO STAY IN ONE PLACE.
COME ALONG, WATSON.
OH, SIR. DID YOU
HEAR ABOUT SIR CHARLES?
HE CHUCKED IN THE SPONGE.
GIVEN UP.
GONE HOME.
WOULD YOU BELIEVE IT?
YES, I BELIEVE IT.
HIS FAILURE REFLECTS AS MUCH
ON YOU AS ON HIM.
WARREN WOULD NEVER HAVE BEEN
ABLE TO PERVERT JUSTICE...
HAD ANY ONE OF YOU
STOOD UP AGAINST HIM.
ABSOLUTELY.
SIR CHARLES RESIGNS?
I FIND THAT BAFFLING.
NOW MARY KELLY.
THEY SHOULD KNOW SOMETHING
AT THE BLACK HORSE TAVERN.
THAT'S PRECISELY
WHERE WE'RE GOING, WATSON.
OH.
[ Whinnies ]
[ Heavy Breathing ]
[ Footsteps ]
[ Man Laughing ]
[ Men Singing ]
NO!
[ Whimpering, Moaning ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Dog Barking ]
[ Clattering ]
[ Moans ]
NO.
[ Sobbing ]
[ Screams ]
NO!
[ Dog Barking ]
YOU'RE AWARE THAT
WE'RE BEING FOLLOWED.
YES.
FOR SOME TIME NOW,
I THINK.
[ Foghorn Blows In Distance ]
YES. OF COURSE.
I SUPPOSE IT WOULD BE
FOOLISH TO OFFER YOU--
[ Clears Throat ]
COME.
AH.
[ Footsteps ]
[ Dog Barking In Distance ]
WALK AHEAD OF ME.
[ Barking Continues ]
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
[ Scoffs ]
MR. HOLMES. GOOD.
WHERE IS MARY KELLY?
WE'RE ALL SEARCHING FOR HER.
I'VE GOT MEN IN EVERY HOUSE.
YOU HAD HER, FOXBOROUGH,
AND YOU LOST HER
INTENTIONALLY.
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
WHAT ON EARTH
ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
WHY HASHE
BEEN FOLLOWING US? HUH?
IT MAY SURPRISE YOU
TO LEARN, WATSON,
[ Bell Tolling ]
THAT THIS IS OUR
MYSTERIOUS INFORMANT.
UH-HUH?
USING HIS AGENTS
MAKINS AND LANIER...
TO DELIVER MESSAGES
TO STEER US INTO
WHICHEVER DIRECTION HE CHOSE.
- YOU'RE INSANE.
- NO, INSPECTOR.
[ Bell Tolling ]
YOU ARE THE HEAD
OF A RADICAL MOVEMENT.
I HAVE PROOF.
REST ASSURED.
YOUR CAREER AT
SCOTLAND YARD IS FINISHED.
DO YOU WANT HIM
TO GET AWAY WITH IT?
DO YOU WANT MARY KELLY
BUTCHERED LIKE ALL THE OTHERS?
YOU DON'T CARE A DAMN
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENS
TO MARY KELLY,
OR ANY OF THE OTHER
PATHETIC WOMEN.
WELL, PERHAPS THAT'S TRUE.
PERHAPS
THEY'RE NOT IMPORTANT.
EXCEPT INSOFAR AS THEY SHOW...
THIS GOVERNMENT'S ARISTOCRATIC
CONTEMPT FOR THE PEOPLE
AND HOW THEY SUFFER.
IF YOU, SHERLOCK HOLMES,
CAN'T SEE THE CORRUPTION
AROUND YOU,
THEN PERHAPS SOME PEOPLE
DO HAVE TO DIE IN ORDER
TO EXPOSE IT.
OH, YOU'D LET THEM ALL DIE.
YOU'D LET MARY KELLY DIE.
YES, BY GOD,
I'LL LET HER DIE.
BUT IF YOU FIND THE KILLERS,
AND IT CAN BE SHOWN...
THAT MY SUPERIORS
IN THE GOVERNMENT
HAVE CONCEALED EVIDENCE,
IF YOU CAN EXPOSE
THEIR LIES,
THEIR ABUSE OF POWER,
THEN PERHAPS WE CAN--
WE CAN BRING THIS DECADENT
MONARCHY TO ITS KNEES.
HE'S OUT OF HIS SENSES.
HE DOESN'T KNOW
WHAT HE'S SAYING.
YES, HE DOES, WATSON.
HE KNOWS FULL WELL.
HE KNOWS EXACTLY
WHAT HE'S DOING.
A MAN DEVOID OF
CONSCIENCE, AS GUILTY
AS THE MURDERER HIMSELF.
SHE TRUSTEDYOU,
MR. HOLMES.
SHE CAME OUT OF HIDING
BECAUSE SHE TRUSTEDYOU.
SO, IF THEY GOT HER,
IT'S BECAUSE SHE TRUSTED
GOD-ALMIGHTY SHERLOCK HOLMES.
- FOXBOROUGH, STAY AWAY FROM ME.
-THEY USED YOU.
WE USED YOU.
YOU DID EXACTLY WHAT
WE WANTED YOU TO DO.
IF SHE DIES, AND YOU
COME UNDER MY HAND,
EXPECT NO MERCY.
YOU HAVE MY WORD ON IT.
A RADICAL
IN SCOTLAND YARD?
TERRIFYING.
HOLMES,
WHAT DID YOU MEAN
WHEN YOU SAID-- OH.
HOLMES, WHAT HE SAID
ABOUT THE GOVERNMENT BEING
INVOLVED, THAT CAN'T BE.
I'M AFRAID IT IS.
[ Horse Whinnies ]
HOW HIGH UP?
[ Whinnying Continues ]
PERHAPS TO THE THRONE.
WHAT?
[ Metal Clatters ]
[ Fire Crackling ]
[ Squeaks ]
- [ Sizzles ]
- AAH!
I'M SO SORRY, OLD MAN.
AFTER THEM. GO ON.
I'M ALL RIGHT.
[ Panting ]
MAY I SUGGEST
YOU TAKE THIS?
[ Chuckles ]
[ Horse Whinnies ]
AAH!
[ Footsteps ]
[ Groans ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Blows Whistle ]
[ Police Whistle Blowing ]
[ Police Whistle Blows
In Distance ]
[ Gagging ]
[ Gagging Continues ]
HEY! HEY!
[ Groans ]
[ Panting ]
WATSON.
[ Holmes ]
HELP WATSON.
[ Door Opens ]
- GENTLEMEN. MR. HOLMES.
- PRIME MINISTER.
I THOUGHT IT WOULD BE
BETTER WE SHOULD MEET HERE.
WE CAN BE SURE OF PRIVACY.
"SECRECY" WOULD PERHAPS BE
THE MORE APPROPRIATE WORD.
SHALL WE AGREE
UPON "DISCRETION"?
YOU HAVE ALREADY SPOKEN
TO THE HOME SECRETARY.
I HAVE INDICATED SOMETHING
OF THE MATTER TO HIM, YES.
I HAVE SUMMONED YOU HERE
BECAUSE YOU HAVE
MADE STATEMENTS...
WHICH AFFECT THE VERY
EXISTENCE OF THE SOCIAL ORDER
OF THIS COUNTRY.
LET ME MAKE IT PLAIN.
WHAT IS AT STAKE WILL NOT
PERMIT UNCONSIDERED ACTIONS,
NOR INJUDICIOUS STATEMENTS.
WE SHALL TAKE ACTION IF WE MUST.
AND I CAN ASSURE YOU
THAT ACTION WILL BE EFFECTIVE.
THE SEQUENCE OF EVENTS,
PRIME MINISTER,
CONVINCE ME
OF YOUR ABILITY TO
TAKE EFFECTIVE ACTION.
YOU HAVE ME
AT A DISADVANTAGE, MR. HOLMES.
I THINK IT MIGHT BE BETTER
IF YOU TELL US YOUR STORY
IN YOUR OWN WAY...
AND PERMIT ME TO BE
THE JUDGE OF WHETHER
IT IS TRUE OR NOT.
YOU MAY TAKE IT
TO BE TRUE, SIR.
THE FIRST LINK IN
MY CHAIN OF CIRCUMSTANCES...
IS A WOMAN
BY THE NAME OF ANNIE CROOK.
I SEE YOU RECOGNIZE
THAT NAME, HOME SECRETARY.
IN OTHER CIRCUMSTANCES THAT
WOULD SURPRISE ME, SINCE SHE
IS A WOMAN OF THE LOWER CLASSES,
HARDLY LIKELY TO AFFECT
THE LIFE OF ANYONE SO POWERFUL.
YOUR IRONY IS OUT OF PLACE.
YOU WOULD BE WISE, MR. HOLMES,
TO RESIST
THE TEMPTATION TO CONDESCEND.
PRIME MINISTER.
HOW DOES ANNIE CROOK
CONCERN ANYONE HERE?
I FOUND HER.
SHE TOLD ME SOME FRAGMENTS
OF HER PATHETIC STORY.
SHE MET HER LOVER...
FIRST AT THE HOUSEHOLD
WHERE SHE WAS EMPLOYED.
SHE FELL IN LOVE WITH HIM.
HE WAS INFATUATED
BRIEFLY WITH HER.
WITH HER GENTLENESS,
HER BEAUTY AND HER INNOCENCE.
[ Man ]
AND IN THE FACE OF
THIS CONGREGATION--
HE WENT THROUGH
A FORM OF MARRIAGE,
AND SOON AFTER,
TIRED OF HER, HE LEFT.
SHE BORE HIM A CHILD.
THIS MUCH WAS DONE
WITHOUT ATTRACTING NOTICE.
AND THEN, WHEN THE EXISTENCE
OF THE CHILD WAS DISCOVERED,
AND ITS RELIGION--
CATHOLIC--
THE GOVERNMENT
SUDDENLY BECAME CONCERNED.
[ Prime Minister ]
YOU MUST FORGIVE ME,
MR. HOLMES.
I HAD EXPECTED AN ACCOUNT
OF MORE SIGNIFICANCE.
HOW CAN ALL THIS AFFECT
THE GOVERNMENT OF ENGLAND?
YOU EXAGGERATE, SURELY.
HER LOVER, HER HUSBAND,
HOWEVER YOU MAY CALL HIM--
HER SEDUCER--
WAS HIS GRACE, THE DUKE
OF CLARENCE AND AVONDALE,
ALBERT VICTOR CHRISTIAN EDWARD,
EARL OF ATHLONE,
THE HEIR PRESUMPTIVE
TO THE THRONE OF ENGLAND.
KNOWN AS EDDY TO HIS
MORE INTIMATE ACQUAINTANCES.
AN INDISCRETION,
MR. HOLMES.
HARDLY A CRIME.
[ Prime Minister ]
CERTAINLY NOTHING SO SERIOUS...
AS TO WARRANT
ALL THIS PASSION.
WELL, NOT A CRIME.
NOT YET, PRIME MINISTER.
AN INCONVENIENCE.
YET YOU YOURSELF MADE IT
KNOWN IT WOULD BE PREFERABLE
IF THE WOMAN--
INDEED, THE PROBLEM ITSELF--
DID NOT EXIST.
[ Holmes Narrating ]
AND ONE MAN AMONG THE MANY...
WHO WAS PRIVY
TO THE PRINCE'S INDISCRETION...
TOOK ON THE FILTHY WORK.
AND THAT SAME MAN DREW ANOTHER
INTO HIS HIDEOUS CONSPIRACY,
BY PERSUADING HIM THEY HAD
THE OFFICIAL SANCTION
OF THE HIGHEST IN THE LAND.
THEY SOUGHT OUT ANNIE,
AND THEY DECEIVED HER...
BY PROMISING TO TAKE HER
TO HER BELOVED EDDY.
IT WAS A SIMPLE MATTER
TO ARRANGE.
SHE WAS TAKEN TO HOSPITAL.
FROM THAT HOSPITAL SHE WAS
REMOVED TO ANOTHER PLACE,
MORE DISTANT, MORE SECURE.
ALONE.
ABANDONED BY HER LOVER.
TORMENTED AND CONFUSED,
THEY FORCED HER TO TELL THEM
THAT SHE HAD GIVEN HER CHILD
TO A FRIEND FOR SAFEKEEPING.
AND THE SEARCH FOR MARY KELLY
AND THE PLOT FOR HER DISPOSAL
HAD BEGUN.
OHH.
THEY SEARCHED.
NOTHING WOULD STOP THEM.
THEY SEARCHED FOR MARY.
THEY SEARCHED FOR THE CHILD.
[ Holmes Narrating ]
IN TERROR FOR HER OWN LIFE,
MARY SHARED THE SECRET
OF THE ROYAL INDISCRETION.
AND, IN DOING SO, SEALED
THE FATE OF HER FRIENDS.
THEY MURDERED ANYONE
WHO MIGHT HAVE KNOWN
OF THE CHILD.
THUS WAS BORN THE MYTH
OF JACK THE RIPPER.
POLLY NICHOLS,
ANNIE CHAPMAN,
LIZ STRIDE...
AND CATHERINE EDDOWES...
WERE SLAUGHTERED AND
THEIR DEATHS DISGUISED
AS THE WORK OF A MADMAN.
AND TO MY EVERLASTING REGRET,
I LED THE MURDERERS...
STRAIGHT TO MARY,
THE ONE WOMAN
THEY HAD SEARCHED FOR
SO LONG AND IN VAIN.
FIRST, SHE ESCAPED.
[ Holmes Narrating ]
THEN...
[ Screams ]
NO!
SHE DIED.
BUT SHE DIED
WITHOUT REVEALING...
THE VERY THING
THEY NEEDED TO DISCOVER.
[ Screams ]
NO!
WHERE TO FIND THE CHILD.
[ Man Yells ]
AND SO THE VICTIMS
AND THE CRIMES.
WHAT OF THE CRIMINALS?
IT REMAINS FOR YOU TO PROVE
THESE ALLEGATIONS, MR. HOLMES.
[ Prime Minister ]
AND I'M CURIOUS TO KNOW HOW FAR
YOU WILL PRESS YOUR ACCUSATIONS.
I DON'T BEGIN WITH YOU.
I BEGIN WITH A MAN
WHO IS ALREADY DEAD.
[ Holmes ]
WILLIAM SLADE,
PRIME MOVER IN
THESE ATROCIOUS CRIMES,
WHO SET THEM ON
FROM SOME MISGUIDED LOYALTY
TO THE ROYAL FAMILY HE SERVED,
OR AS A HIDDEN AGENT
IN THEIR CAUSE.
[ Holmes ]
I ACCUSE SIR THOMAS SPIVEY,
THE CELEBRATED PHYSICIAN,
WHOSE HOSPITAL TOOK ANNIE CROOK
AND DROVE HER INTO MADNESS.
A MAN WHO PRESCRIBES ETERNAL
INCARCERATION FOR A WOMAN...
SIMPLY BECAUSE
SHE WAS SEDUCED,
MADE PREGNANT
AND DELIVERED OF A CHILD;
WHO, ACCORDING TO ARCHAIC
RITUAL, BUTCHERED HIS VICTIMS.
I ACCUSE A MAN WHO HAS
NO PLACE IN THIS WORLD
OR THE NEXT.
YOU ACCUSE,
BUT IT IS PROOF
WE NEED, MR. HOLMES.
WE'VE HEARD
THIS TRAGIC STORY NOW,
BUT WHAT IS YOUR LINK
WITH ANNIE CROOK?
WHERE IS YOUR PROOF?
YOU HAVE NO PROOF.
ONLY SURMISE
AND WILD CONJECTURE.
I HAVE PROOF.
I HAVE PROOF THAT A WOMAN
WAS CYNICALLY TAKEN
IN MARRIAGE.
I HAVE PROOF
OF THE HUSBAND'S NAME;
THAT A CHILD WAS BORN.
I HAVE PROOF THAT THE WOMAN
WAS COMMITTED TO AN ASYLUM
BY ORDER OF SPIVEY.
I HAVE PROOF OF EVIDENCE
SUPPRESSED BY YOU, SIR CHARLES.
EVIDENCE
WHICH SEEMED TO ACCUSE...
A MEMBER OF THE SACRED ORDER
TO WHICH YOU ALL BELONG.
YOU ARE ALL FREEMASONS.
YOU, PRIME MINISTER.
HOME SECRETARY.
SIR CHARLES, YOU.
AND SPIVEY-- ALL MASONS.
AND IN DISCOVERING
THE INVOLVEMENT OF
A FELLOW MASON,
YOU WERE SWORN TO PROTECT
HIM IN HIS CRIMINAL INTENT.
THEN YOU ACCUSE US!
OF COMPLICITY IN MURDER?
NO, PRIME MINISTER.
YOUR SUGGESTION WAS ENOUGH
TO PROMPT THESE MEN TO ACTION.
WHAT WAS DONE
WAS ALL DONE IN YOUR NAME.
I SHALL NOT
DEBATE THAT WITH YOU.
THERE ARE LARGER ISSUES HERE
THAN YOU CAN UNDERSTAND.
DON'T PRESUME
TO JUDGE US, HOLMES.
I KNOW WHERE MY DUTY LIES:
IN THE PROTECTION
OF THE MONARCHY.
THERE IS NOT NOW,
NOR HAS THERE EVER BEEN,
A DANGER TO THE MONARCHY.
THAT THOUGHT EXISTED
ONLY IN THE MINDS OF
THE THREE MEN IN THIS ROOM!
YOUR INTRIGUE SIMPLY SERVED
THE DISAFFECTED RADICALS,
WHOM YOU FEAR.
VERY WELL, MR. HOLMES.
SLADE'S DEAD. SPIVEY IS INSANE.
SIR CHARLES--
HIS CAREER IS RUINED.
WHAT SORT OF RUIN
DOES HE FACE?
WILL THE MASONS
PUNISH OR REWARD HIM?
HE KEPT FAITH WITHYOU.
YOUR OATH OF FELLOWSHIP
BINDS YOU TO SUPPORTHIM.
WHAT SHALL I TELL THE QUEEN?
YOU SURELY DON'T SUGGEST
THAT HER MAJESTY IS
IN ANY WAY INVOLVED.
I CANNOT EASILY BELIEVE THAT.
- YOU HAVE MY WORD!
- I WOULD PREFER
SOME MORE RELIABLE AUTHORITY.
IN THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
I SHALL IGNORE YOUR
OFFENSIVE ATTITUDE.
IF I SEEM TO BE
OFFENSIVE, PRIME MINISTER,
YOU MAY TAKE IT I AM OFFENDED!
YOUOFFEND ME.
SHALL I RESIGN?
WOULD THAT SATISFY YOU?
YES,RESIGN.
AND IF I HAD THE MEANS,
I WOULD COMPEL YOU.
YOU KNOW WHAT
YOU RISK, MR. HOLMES.
THE RUIN OF YOUR OWN SOCIETY...
AND THE SUBSTITUTION OF
A RADICAL, ANARCHIST IDEOLOGY.
I CARE NOTHING ABOUT THAT.
YOU'RE ALL THE SAME TO ME.
YOU, PRIME MINISTER,
FOXBOROUGH AND THE RADICALS--
ALL OF YOU EQUALLY TO BLAME.
GOD KNOWS, IF I COULD
PROVE YOUR COMPLICITY,
I WOULD NOT HESITATE,
BUT I WAS NOT A PARTY
TO YOUR SECRET COUNCILS.
ONLY YOU KNOW TO WHAT EXTENT
YOU ARE RESPONSIBLE.
FOR THE MOMENT, HOWEVER,
AS LONG AS THE CHILD IS SAFE,
YOU HAVE MY WORD
I SHALL KEEP SILENT.
BUT IN THE EVENT
SHE IS HARMED IN ANY WAY,
I WILL MAKE PUBLIC
EVERYTHING I KNOW.
THE WHEREABOUTS OF THIS CHILD
ARE UNKNOWN TO US.
WE ARE SATISFIED
THEY SHOULD REMAIN SO.
AND ANNIE CROOK...
MUST BE SET FREE.
UNHAPPILY, SHE IS ALREADY FREE.
THE NIGHT AFTER HER MEETING
WITH YOU, MR. HOLMES, SHE DIED.
HOW? DIED.
[ Prime Minister ]
SHE TOOK HER OWN LIFE.
FREE?
I WISH I HAD SOME REASON
TO BELIEVE YOU.
HOW MAY I CONVINCE YOU?
EVEN IF YOU COULD
CONVINCE ME,
IT'S TOO LATE.
IT'S TOO LATE
FOR ANNIE CROOK.
SEPARATED FROM HER CHILD,
DRIVEN TO DESPAIR...
AND DEATH.
YOU CREATE ALLEGIANCE...
ABOVE YOUR SWORN
ALLEGIANCE TO HUMANITY.
YOU WILL NOT FEEL FOR THEM...
OR ACKNOWLEDGE THEIR PAIN.
THERE LIES THE MADNESS.
WELL. WELL, MR. HOLMES.
REMEMBER YOU HAVE PROMISED
TO KEEP YOUR SILENCE.
OUR BUSINESS IS FINISHED.
FINISHED.
PERHAPS FOR YOU,
BUT NOT FOR ME.
I WILL ALWAYS HAVE
THE DEATH OF MARY KELLY
ON MY CONSCIENCE.
AND YOU, PRIME MINISTER,
WILL HAVE THE DEATHS OF ANNIE...
AND ALL THOSE TRAGIC WOMEN...
AND THEIR AGONY...
ON YOURS.
????
[ Paper Rustling ]
COME AWAY, HOLMES.
COME AND SIT DOWN.
WE'VE UNMASKED...
MADMEN, WATSON.
WIELDING SCEPTERS.
REASON RUN RIOT.
JUSTICE HOWLING AT THE MOON.
BUT, HOLMES, YOU DID
MUCH MORE THAN ANY OTHER MAN
COULD HAVE ATTEMPTED.
AND THERE'S... STILL DECENCY.
ANNIE CROOK AND MARY KELLY...
DYING TO PROTECT A CHILD.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
THERE IS DECENCY.
AND IF NOWHERE ELSE,
IN THAT BATTERED
BREAST OF YOURS.
HMM.
I THINK,
IF YOU WILL ALLOW ME,
I WILL PLAY NOW FOR A WHILE.
"IF YOU WILL ALLOW ME."
THANKS FOR THAT.
YES, HOLMES, PLAY.
???? [ Violin ]
[ Inhales Deeply ]
[ Exhales ]
???? [ Violin Continues ]
[ Dog Barking ]
[ Barking ]
???? [ Violin Ends ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]