##[Rock]
#Lights out tonight
Trouble in the heartland #
# Got a head-on collision
Smashing in my guts, man #
#I'm caught in a crossfire #
# That I don't understand #
#But there's one thing
I know for sure, girl #
#I don't give a damn #
#For the same old
played-out scenes #
#Baby, I don't give a damn #
#For just the in-betweens #
#Honey, I want the heart
I want the soul #
#I want control right now #
# You better listen to me, baby #
# Talk about a dream
Try to make it real #
# You wake up in the night
With a fear so real #
# You spend your life
waiting for a moment #
# That just don't come #
# Well, don't waste
your time waiting #
#Badlands
You gotta live it every day #
#Let the broken hearts stand #
#As the price you've gotta pay #
#Keep pushin 't till it's understood #
#And these badlands
start treating us good #
# Workin' in the fields #
# That'll give you a back burn #
# Workin' 'neath the wheels #
#Hell, you get your facts learned #
#Baby I got my facts #
#Learned real good right now #
# You'd better get it straight, darlin'#
#Poor man wanna be rich #
#Rich man wanna be king #
#And a king ain't satisfied
Till he rules everything #
#I wanna go out tonight #
#I wanna find out
what I got #
# Well, I believe in the love
that you gave me #
#I believe in the faith
that can save me #
#I believe in the hope
and I pray #
# That someday it may raise me #
#Above these badlands #
# You gotta live it every day #
#Let the broken hearts stand #
#As the price you've gotta pay #
#Keep pushin' till it's understood #
#And these badlands
start treatin' us good #
# Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa #
[Horn Honking]
##[Guitar]
##[Saxophone]
How about a kiss in the sun?
How about not a kiss
in the sun?
Why not?
It's very romantic.
Oh, Mr. Romance. Great.
Hey, Mom!
- What?
- You forgot what we
gotta do this morning.
Jesus, who's that?
My son. Did I?
The school, the clinic,
the blood run.
It's today, Mom.
Oh, shit.
Wait a second.
What's going on?
I gotta do a million things
with my kid.
You got things to do?
What about us?
[Woman] We can get together
some other time.
[Motorcycles Approaching]
What the hell have I
been doing for five hours?
I don't know.
[Man #2] I don't think so.
I just gave her
a ride home.
Wait a minute.
Mom.
I'm sorry.
Hey, look.
I just gave her
a ride home.
[Groans]
Okay, okay. All right.
Hey, Rock.
Yo, Red.
This the one you
been looking for?
No, I already got
two Steve Garveys.
I told you that
wasn't the right one.
Thanks anyway, Red.
He's trying to find, uh,
Ruby Walters.
Rube Walker,
card number 108.
108. Brooklyn Dodgers.
[Together] 1955.
Good year.
Seems like yesterday.
You say that
about everything, Red.
Everything does.
I seen you
grandstanding for her.
I was protecting her.
Where the hell were you?
Here comes Mom.
You got the lease?
I got everything else.
Ah, shit.
I told you it
was Rube Walker.
You said...
Shut up. Let's get goin'.
We're late.
What's the matter?
You never saw anybody from
the planet Vultern before?
Mom.
Beep, beep-beep-beep.
Yes, uh, may...
Never mind.
Uh, wait a minute!
Ma'am!
Hi. I'm here to register
my son for the ninth grade.
Well, uh, Mrs...
No "Mrs."
I'm Rusty Dennis.
This is my son Rocky.
Please, sit down.
We're running a little bit late.
So could you move it along?
This is a public junior
high school, Miss Dennis.
There are
special schools...
with wonderful facilities
that might be more appropriate
for his needs.
Do you teach algebra
and biology and English here?
- Of course.
- Those are his needs.
Perhaps I should speak
to the boy's father.
Perhaps you should
speak to the pope too.
He'd be a lot easier to find.
Under the circumstances,
I do feel that for the good of
my students as well as your son,
I'm going to need
some additional information...
Mr. Simms, you know what?
Don't jerk me around.
I'm not in the mood.
I've had a real
crappy day so far.
First I find out we're in the
wrong school district. I gotta
come play pussyfoot with you.
This is a copy of our lease,
this is a copy of
Rocky's birth certificate,
and this is his last
report card from
Stevens Junior High School...
where he was in the top
five percent of his class.
And I got some additional
information for you. My lawyer's
name is B.D. Higgins.
He's told me of my rights.
If you give me shit, he's gonna
drag your ass into court.
Don't worry, Mr. Simms.
I look weird, but
otherwise I'm real normal.
Everything will be cool.
Thanks a lot.
See you next week.
Mom.
What?
We have a lawyer
named B.D. Higgins?
Yeah. Bulldozer.
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
Hey, you're a lawyer, Doze.
Bullshit rules!
Whoo-hoo!
## [Humming]
Okay.
Cranium circumference:
67 centimeters.
Sixty-seven centimeters.
Last one, kid.
Yeah.
All right, Billy.
Mandible:
32.5 centimeters.
Mandible: 32.5.
That's good news.
Let me measure yours.
Rocky, since
your last checkup
in April,
your jaw measurement
only increased
1/8th of an inch.
Wow! I'm cured.
I'm healed. I can go home now.
It's the water in Azusa.
Picture time!
He knows this routine
better than we do.
Oh, wait.
Hold on a second.
Rocky, you look great.
I wanna get
my hair perfect.
You look fine, Rocky.
Okay, shoot.
Okay.
How's your mom,
Rocky?
She's great.
Stand still.
Oh, sorry.
Turn now.
Why don't you fill me
in on this, Doctor?
[Woman]
The patient was
first diagnosed...
[Together]
With craniodiaphyseal
dysplasia...
at four years of age...
You can turn around.
When it was discovered
that calcium was depositing
at an abnormal rate...
Calcium.
My pal calcium.
Throughout his skull.
- And what have we learned
about this disorder?
- It's extremely rare,
one in approximately
22 million births.
Twenty-two million.
- How was it first described?
- I know.
They call it "lionitis"...
means "look of the lion."
You new around here?
Yes, I am. Cause?
It's caused by two
recessive genes...
and happens to the offspring
of normal parents.
His mother had
an uneventful pregnancy,
didn't ingest any chemical
substance or teratogen
during gestation.
That means it wasn't
my mom or dad's fault.
- Hello, Rocky.
- Hey, Doc Rudinsky.
Good to see you again.
How's it going?
Our data on this patient
supports your article in
the New England Journal...
How are you feeling
today, Rocky?
Good. How are you feeling?
Ehh. You still have
those headaches?
Yeah. They've been
getting pretty bad lately.
Hmm. Is your mother still
using the same method?
Yeah.
Uh, what methods
are those?
Well, she talks to 'em,
and they go away.
No medication?
Nope.
We're ready now, Doctor.
You can get
dressed now, Rocky.
See you later, Doc.
Do you have
any questions?
When you gonna invent one
of these things so a guy's rear end
isn't always hanging out?
Excuse me.
May I see these?
I'd like to do the follow-up
counseling with that
patient's mother myself.
Now there's a great idea.
Wouldn't you agree, Doctor?
Oh, definitely, yes.
[Woman Over P.A.]
Dr. Cameron, pick up line two.
Dr. Cameron, line two.
Uh, Mrs. Dennis?
What?
I'm Dr. Vinton.
I need to talk to you
about the test results.
All right.
Hey, Mom.
Hey, babe.
Why doesn't
he wait outside.
What for?
So we can talk.
Talk.
It's about the
test results... on him.
Oh, him.
Him, by the way,
has got a name,
so if you got some information
for him, I suggest
you give it to him.
You don't understand.
No, you don't understand.
He's got a cheeseburger waiting
with his name on it, so I
suggest you hurry this along.
Well, as you know, plastic
surgery is not an option...
until the skull stops
thickening, and there's
no evidence that it will.
The cranium
is growing at such
an accelerated rate,
creating pressure
on the spinal cord
to such an extent that...
the prognosis
is not good.
We, uh, feel that
life expectancy is...
[Together]
Three to six months.
You're not really gonna give us
that life expectancy
number again, are ya?
You know, for 12 years
I've been listening
to you guys bullshit.
First you told me that
he was retarded, then you said
he was gonna be blind and deaf.
Then you told me he'd never
be able to do anything
regular kids could do.
If I had dug his grave
every time one of you geniuses
told me he was gonna die,
I'd be eatin' fucking
chop suey in China by now.
Anything else?
Bye.
##[Rock]
[Indistinct Shouting]
Looks like it's time
to get Dozer to give blood.
Take your stick.
Never has before.
Here comes Dozer's
welcoming committee.
Come on now, Doze.
Red Cross needs some blood.
Come on. It's only
gonna hurt for a second.
[Indistinct Shouting]
Go on, Dozer! Run!
[Woman]
Hey, Rusty!
Look who's here.
The prodigal son returns.
Hey, Rocky.
Ben, when did
you get back?
Yesterday.
He's looking good.
Yeah.
Better than he acts.
Oh, well.
How's your dad?
He was great.
Great for you,
shitty for me.
Here it goes.
Usual crapola's starting.
Watch your mouth.
Hey, you got baseball cards.
I just started
collecting those.
Me too.
You did not just start.
You didn't tell me
Ben was coming home.
It's a surprise to me too.
You happy about it?
Not especially. He's acting
just like his father.
I think the only reason
he's back is his father didn't
wanna pay the bills anymore.
Of course, 18 months
out of 16 years...
doesn't seem like a hell
of a lot to me, but...
Well, who needs them,
you know?
If you take their money,
you gotta take their shit.
The doctor say the usual?
Screw him. He eats everything
that ain't tied down.
That Ben's getting
a real smart mouth on him.
It's the age.
They think they
know everything.
Good slap upside the head,
and he don't know everything.
I never hit Rocky.
I don't believe this, Ben.
You don't even have
a Steve Garvey.
A Steve Garvey,
for Christ's sake.
I do.
I must have left it
at my dad's in Michigan.
You probably lost it.
Garvey's batting
.325 this year.
He's an important card.
You gotta have a Garvey.
Really?
Yeah.
Well, do I have
anything you want?
Nah, we better forget it.
You know, I feel
really bad about this, Ben.
We grew up together.
I should just give you
my Steve Garvey.
You know, I will,
for anything you got.
Anything, like this one.
Who the hell's
"Rubie" Walker?
I think that's
an old Dodger before
they came out to L.A.
Yeah? Well, I'll take it.
My grandpa likes them.
[Man]
Come on, Doze.
Red Cross needs blood!
[Indistinct Shouting]
Take another stick.
Hey, you remember
we used to talk about
riding Harleys across Europe?
Yeah, I remember.
Well, I had been planning
on going by myself,
but now that you're back...
Yeah. That'd be great.
Anything to
get out of school.
[Man]
Get that big fag!
[Indistinct Shouting]
[Rocky]
Wow, puppies. Oh, cool.
Look at that one.
Can I pet him?
- Take your pick.
- [Rocky] Hi, puppy.
Now he was born
for you, Rocky.
I gotta ask my mom.
Come on, Ben.
Be right back.
I'll save him
for ya.
Try this.
And what's so special
about this, John?
Now this little baby
is dusted with angel wings.
Mom?
What?
I gotta show
you something.
Wait a second.
Am I interrupting
something?
What do you want?
Well, this lady's got
these really cool puppies.
You seen 'em, Doze?
No puppy. No dog.
Why?
'Cause you never
talk to the cat.
You don't feed the goldfish,
the bird or the rabbit.
I'll feed the dog. I promise.
Read my lips, Rock.
No.
[Men Shouting]
[Man]
There he is!
Go get him!
What's with the big guy?
Is he a dummy
or something?
Dozer just doesn't
like to talk.
Oh.
Hey, well, show her
the other stuff.
Take your pick.
Don't let them bother you.
I mean, my mom's
a pain in the ass also.
[Motorcycle Approaching]
I don't believe this.
What?
It's Gar.
[Ben]
Oh, yeah.
Come on.
[Man]
Hey, look,
it's Gar.
Is that Rocky's dad?
No. I was married
to Rocky's dad.
Who the hell is that?
Just a guy
I used to know.
Damn, it's good
to see you.
Where have you been?
Been on the road.
Damn, you're gettin' taller.
She must be pouring that
health food shit into you.
She is.
Don't cut yourself.
Thanks.
You been okay?
Yeah.
Still planning
a Europe run?
More than ever.
We were just talking about this.
God, this is so weird.
Yeah, isn't it?
How's everybody
else doin'?
Like who?
Like Grandma
and Grandpa.
They're okay. They don't
get around much anymore
'cause it's such a long drive.
We moved, you know.
Oh, yeah?
She talks about you.
Yeah, I'll bet she does.
[Chuckles]
Go on. Benny's waiting
for you.
Get out of here.
I'll see you later.
See you later, Gar.
See ya, Rock.
Hey, mama, toss me a beer.
T.J.
Gar.
Aren't you gonna
introduce me to your lady?
Yeah.
Angel, this is Gar.
Give him a kiss.
Handshake will do.
You sure?
[Giggles]
[Indistinct Shouting]
[Man]
That a way, Dozer.
Get 'em.
[Man #2]
Way to go, Dozer.
[Cheering]
All right.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Hey, Dozer.
##[Radio: Slow Rock]
Good night, Mom.
Good night, babe.
Good night, Bone.
Good night, buddy.
Clunk.
Beautiful.
Marseilles.
Marseilles, Marseilles,
Marseilles, Marseilles.
##[Continues Faintly]
[Whimpering]
Oh, my God.
Hey, puppy.
Look at you.
Bone?
Dozer?
Yeah.
Scooch over.
I'm gonna make
that fat bastard
eat 30 pounds of dog food.
Trouble is,
he'll probably love it.
[Blender Whirring]
[Woman Over Radio]
# Each night before you
go to bed, my baby #
[Motorcycle Approaching]
Hey, Rock, honey,
your limo's here.
#And tell all
the stars above #
Will you turn that
stuff down, Mom?
Okay.
##[Volume Decreases]
I don't wanna go, Mom.
Then don't go.
But I gotta go.
Then go.
This is... This is easy
for you to say, Mom.
You're not the one
who's gonna be going
to some school...
where kids are gonna run
in the other direction when
they see you, making fun of you.
Yeah? When they stop
running and making fun,
they'll get to know you...
and think you're terrific,
just like at your other school.
You know, it takes time
for people to get to
like each other.
I don't know why you think
it should be different
for you.
[Chuckles]
But I am different, Mom.
Yeah. You're more
beautiful on the inside
than most people.
Anybody can't see that...
Screw 'em.
Right. Spoken like the true
son of a redheaded woman.
## [Hums]
#Your sister Rose
is dead ##
You're weird, Mom.
Get out of here.
Hey, Dozer.
Thanks, Doze. No, no, no.
I gotta do this alone.
Have a good day.
[Boy] Hey, kid, why don't
you take off your mask?
[Boys Laughing]
[Indistinct Chattering]
[Bell Ringing]
[Teacher]
All right.
Well, welcome back,
ninth graders.
[Class Moans]
[Chuckles]
Okay.
Now, we have two
new students with us
in homeroom this year.
First, we have
Miss Nancy Lawrence.
Where are you, Nancy?
[Boy]
[Girl] Hi, Nancy.
[Wolf Whistle]
Wow! Thanks a lot.
Our other new student
is Mr. Rocky Dennis,
also in the back.
[Chuckles]
Wow. Thanks a lot.
[Class Chuckles]
See you later.
Bye.
Dempsey, Eric.
Locker number 137.
Combination: Right 46,
left past 46 to 16,
right to four.
Got it all?
Mm-hmm.
Dennis, Rocky.
Locker number 138.
Combination: Left 22,
right past 22 to 12,
left to nine.
You're not
writing it down.
Don't need to.
[Indistinct Chattering]
[Boy]
He looks like Frankenstein.
[Boys Chuckling]
What's the matter? Haven't
you guys ever seen anybody
from the planet Vultern before?
Beep, beep-beep.
That guy's weird, man.
Cut it out, guys.
Forty-six, four, five.
Dick wack!
Is it stuck?
No.
Eric, you're taking
forever. Excuse me.
I lost the goddamn combination.
That's okay.
Try right 46,
left past 46 to 16,
right to four.
Huh?
Right to 46,
left to 16,
to four.
[Bell Ringing]
We got enough candy here
to feed an orphanage.
I'll sell mine at school.
What?
More money for the trip.
Oh, yeah. Hey, maybe
I'll sell some of mine.
[Man Over Radio]
# Good golly, Miss Molly #
#Sure like to ball #
# Good golly, Miss Molly
Sure like to ball #
Come on, come on.
Let's dance.
Hey, Red!
Hey, Rocky,
what a haul.
I got you a present.
You got a Baby Ruth
in there?
For you, man.
Anything for your diet.
How's the kids?
What's to drink?
Hi!
[Man]
Party time.
#Mama, Papa, told me
Son, you better
watch yourself #
#If they knew about Miss Molly
I'd have to watch
my pa myself #
# Good golly, Miss Molly #
- Hey, Rock.
- Hey, Gar!
# When you're rockin'
and a-rollin'#
Thanks. Take this in your room
and open it up.
Okay. Thanks.
Oh, I forgot.
Red slipped me a fiver
for the strongbox.
How much we got saved
in here now?
Thirty-one bucks.
Plus the six we got
for baby-sitting tonight.
Plus the five Red slipped me.
So we got 44.
Forty-two.
Yeah.
Whoa!
Check this out.
Tear that old sucker
off the wall.
Let's put this thing up.
I am really getting
into this now.
I wish we could just get out
of here and go tomorrow.
Me too.
Wow. You know, Gar always
said the best run was
right here across Europe.
He rode across
all by himself.
You should get some
of those little things...
Map tacks.
Right.
I want to go to every place
I've ever read about,
all those great cities
our relatives came from.
Not mine, Rock.
We're Americans.
Only the Indians were
Americans first. The rest of us
come from somewhere else,
like Paris, maybe,
or London...
or Rome,
Vienna, Barcelona...
Oh, yeah.
Like my grandparents...
are from Hungary or
Budapest or something.
Budapest is in Hungary, Ben.
No kidding.
Is it?
##[Continues Indistinctly]
That jacket's the only thing
of yours that's ever gonna be
on my bed again.
Okay with me, baby.
What the hell did you
come back here for anyway?
Winters are
too cold back East,
and I wanted
to see... Rocky.
Can someone tell me how
the Trojan War began?
Those lightbulbs
over your heads
are blinding me.
[Class Chuckles]
Okay, Rocky.
Give it a shot.
Well, there was this
huge wedding, right?
And all the beautiful
goddesses in the world
were invited,
all except
for this one goddess.
She got really pissed off.
That's the fact part.
Now, the myth part goes that
she sent this golden apple...
that said,
"For the most beautiful,"
to the wedding,
and this dude named Paris
was supposed to judge
who should get the apple.
Right? Kind of like
a Miss Goddess contest.
He's the only judge.
He was a lucky guy.
Of course, all the goddesses
wanna get picked, right?
So one of 'em
goes up to Paris and says,
"Look, man, if you pick me,
I'm gonna give you this
really hot wench named Helen."
Except Helen was already
married to someone else.
Didn't matter.
Paris saw her and flipped out
because she was
just so beautiful.
She had a perfect body
and this face...
a face that could launch
a thousand ships.
Somebody said that.
So anyway, her old man
had this huge, hollow,
wooden horse built,
and puts all his armies into it,
and wheels it over to Troy,
and says,
"Hey, man, we got a present
for you. Open the gates."
They open the gates,
wheel in this horse and say,
"Wow. Big horse."
And they all fall asleep.
Nighttime comes,
and the horse opens up,
and all the armies come out,
and then...
[Imitates Scraping]
And that's how
the Trojan War began.
Something like that.
[Class Chuckles]
- Thank you, Rocky.
It was very impressive.
- Thanks.
Now, along those lines, class,
let me read you something
from a book that's not...
Not bad, Dennis.
How about helping me?
What do you mean?
Tutor me.
This guy almost
flunked me last year.
It's gonna cost ya.
Huh?
Three bucks an hour.
Three bucks?
Hey, I don't work
for free.
Better pay the three bucks,
cheapskate. You need all
the help you can get.
Thanks a lot.
##[Radio: Rock]
##[Stops]
##[Radio: Slow Rock]
Hi, Mom.
Hi.
Oh, Mom. I got an "A"
on a poem I wrote
in English class.
You've been a busy
little boy, haven't you?
Want me to read it to you?
Why not?
Are you going out
again tonight?
Yeah, but go ahead
and read it.
I'm listening.
Okay.
"These things are good:
[Turns Faucet On]
Ice cream and cake,
a ride on a Harley,
seeing monkeys in the trees,
the rain on my tongue,
and the sun
shining on my face.
These things...
These things are a drag:
Dust in my hair,
holes in my shoes,
no money in my pocket,
and the sun
shining on my face."
Is that it?
Can I talk to you
for a minute, Mom?
I said I was going out.
You're always going out.
I told you
to take down the tree.
What's wrong, Mom?
You've been acting like
you hate me for a whole week.
What did I do?
You didn't do the dishes.
I'll do the dishes later.
Do the goddamn dishes now.
Don't go out tonight.
I wouldn't do that again
if I were you.
I hate you going out
all the time and coming home
wasted out of your mind!
It's none of your
goddamn business!
You're my mother!
Yeah? Well, you're
not my warden!
I can't hack this. You're
always watching me, telling me
how to live my life.
I never tell you
how to live your life.
The fuck you don't!
What's this? What do you
call these? I found these
all over the house.
They were planted everywhere
but in my goddamn
Christmas stocking!
I don't want you
taking drugs!
Don't!
How could you do that?
I hate you.
All you care about
are these stupid cards.
All you care about is
getting loaded and laid.
[Door Slams]
[Car Engine Starts]
[Man]
#Well, the night's busted open #
#These two lanes will take us
anywhere #
# We got one last chance
to make it real #
# To trade in these wings
on some wheels #
# Climb in back
Heaven's waiting down on the tracks #
# Oh, oh
Come take my hand #
# We're riding out tonight
to case the promised land #
# Oh, oh, oh
Thunder Road #
# Oh, Thunder Road
Oh, Thunder Road ##
[Car Doors Close]
[Rusty Chattering
Drunkenly]
You wanna
shut the door?
What, were you
born in a barn?
[Groans]
[Panting]
##[Rock]
[Rocky Groans]
What's the problem?
Shut up. It's my kid.
Wait for me.
I don't wait for nobody.
Then get the hell out.
No problem, baby.
No problem.
Mom. It hurts.
Where does it hurt, baby?
In the back, mostly.
All right, pick something.
I'm sorry about
what I said today.
Pick something.
I can't think, Mom.
It hurts.
Don't think.
Just pick something.
Uh...
The trip with Ben.
How?
Boat.
Okay. Now see it
and tell me.
Uh...
Tramp steamer, big,
black.
Has a red bottom,
and paint's all
chipping off.
Yeah.
Me and Ben on the deck.
We're cleaning
something.
Uh...
The sky's blue.
It's a bit cloudy.
And the ocean, it's dark.
Come on.
Smells good.
Uh, we leave to Spain
in the morning.
Mm-hmm.
I check the bikes.
Tell me about the bikes.
Uh, mine's a 74-inch
Shovelhead...
Mm-hmm.
With a suicide shift,
bright red,
Mm-hmm.
Ape hangers
shoulder high.
Now what are you gonna do?
Make myself well.
Good night, Ma.
[Man Over Radio]
#Down on bended knees #
# Oh, begging
please not to go #
#And think of all
the love we share #
#And all the fun we had ##
You okay?
Yeah.
Thanks for last night.
Gar called this morning.
Said he wants to take
you to the carnival.
Are you coming?
Maybe.
It's okay, baby.
I'm sorry about yesterday.
Yeah. I'm sorry about
your baseball card.
That's okay. I have
two others just like it.
You little shit.
I liked your poem, Rock.
I just get scared
for you, Mom.
Ah, don't be.
It's bad for you.
I can handle it, Rock.
What if somebody deals you
bad stuff, or what if
you take too much of something...
What are you, the director of
the Inland Valley Chemical...
No.
Dependency Center.
Yeah.
I get scared something's
gonna happen to you...
Well, don't. Just lay off.
[Sighs]
Jesus Christ, okay.
Okay what?
Okay, I will cut it...
down.
Promise?
I said so, didn't I?
Don't push it.
All right. I used to be
a good swinger
when I was young.
##[Calliope]
Bumper cars!
I saw this amazing
74-inch Harley Knucklehead.
We better
check it out.
Yes!
Gar, you gonna
go on this?
Wouldn't miss it, kid.
All right.
Mom, you gonna ride?
No, babe. You go ahead.
[Inaudible Dialogue]
Hey, Rusty. Look what
Dozer won for you.
Hey, Doze,
it's great.
I can use this for
after-dinner mints.
Hey, let's ride
those bumpers.
Yeah!
Anybody else
wanna go ride 'em?
No. Let the boys play.
Uh, you can ride, kid,
but I can't take the blame...
for what happens
to retard here.
I can't take the blame
for what happens
to you, can I?
Huh?
Take the tickets.
[Sighs]
##[Continues]
Mom!
Babe, this remind you
of anything?
Yeah. A bunch of guys
running around in circles.
Uh-huh.
Goin' nowhere.
[Rusty]
Yeah, except my Rocky.
Can I have
a small lemonade, please?
How would you like
something nice
to wash down with that?
No, thanks, John.
Real high-quality stuff.
I promised my kid.
You promised your kid?
I like that.
I'm gonna put that with
"I promised my parole officer"
and "I promised my wife."
Put it anywhere
you want to, John.
You know where to find me.
[Beeping]
[Electronic Whirring]
[Hysterical Laughter
Over P.A.]
Watch it.
[Indistinct Shouting]
Did you see
where Mom went?
Yeah.
Don't worry.
Have a good time.
[Screams]
[Chuckling Continues
Over P.A.]
Hey, Babe.
There's something
I've been wanting to give you.
You picked a hell of a time.
I can't take that, Red.
That's your good luck charm.
I kind of think of you
as my good luck charm, Babe.
Well, if you put it that way.
Will you wear it?
Sure.
Okay.
There.
Sentimental old bastard,
aren't you?
Yeah.
Hey, you guys.
Are you in here?
[Chuckling Continues
Over P.A.]
Shit.
Get any dope
for me, lady?
I didn't get any.
Yeah?
What, you don't
believe me?
Should I?
Hey, I...
Oh, check it out.
Mirrors.
Whoo!
Thanks.
Hi, Rocky.
[Indistinct Chattering]
[Woman]
I'm getting dizzy.
Ben.
What?
Look at me.
Huh?
Get behind me
and look at me.
Whoa.
Get my mom.
What?
## [Soft Rock]
Rusty, how about
one of the old numbers?
It's okay with me, Red.
Rock, what do you think?
What?
Little Egypt.
[Woman] Yeah!
[All Cheering]
[Middle Eastern Sounding
Percussion]
[Hooting, Cheering]
Whoo!
[Hooting Continues]
Ladies and gentlemen,
step right up.
See Little Egypt do her famous
dance of the pyramids.
##[Guitar Strumming]
She walks, she talks.
She crawls on her belly
in the dirt like a reptile. Wow.
You gotta love her for doing this.
She's my mom.
Put your hands together
for Miss Rusty Dennis.
[Banging]
##[Guitar Strum]
# He went and bought himself a ticket #
##[Bouncy Guitar Strum]
#And he sat down
in the very first #
[All Singing]
# Row #
#They pulled the curtain down #
#And then they put
the spotlight way down #
[All Singing]
# Low #
# Little Egypt came out struttin'
wearin' nothin' but a button and a #
[All Singing]
# Bow #
# Singing, "Yeah!" #
#Yeah #
Whoa.
[Rock] Hey, Gar.
[Gar] Hey, Rock.
#Yeah #
# She had a ruby in her tummy #
#And a diamond big as Texas
on her #
[All Singing]
#Toe #
Whoa!
# She took her hair down and she did
the hootchy-kootchy real #
[All Singing]
# Slow #
#When she did her special number
on the zebra skin #
# I thought she'd stop the #
[All Singing]
# Show #
# Singing, "Yeah!" #
#Yeah #
# She did a triple somersault
and when she hit the ground #
#Aah #
# She winked at the audience
and then she turned around #
#Aah #
# She had a tattoo of a cowboy
tattooed on her spine #
#Aah #
# Saying, Phoenix, Arizona 19... #
[All Singing]
# 49 #
- Good year.
- [Banging]
#Well, let me tell you, people #
# Little Egypt doesn't live here any #
[All Singing]
# More #
#She's too busy moppin'
and taking care of shoppin' at the #
[All Singing]
# Store #
[Both]
# 'Cause they got seven kids #
#And all day long
they crawl around the #
[All Singing]
# Floor #
[Both]
# Singing #
Where are you going?
[All]
#Yeah #
I'm going where you ain't been.
That's where I'm going.
[All Singing]
#Yeah #
You ain't going nowhere.
[Cheering]
- Come on. Let's go.
- Come on, Rusty.
Sing another one.
[Cheering]
[Whistle Blows]
[Pistol Fires]
You know, you did
a terrific job with
the decorating committee, Rocky.
Thanks.
You going to the prom?
I don't know.
Hi, Rocky.
Howdy.
How are finals going?
Pretty good, Mr. Simms.
I had a great idea for you.
How about a couple of weeks
at summer camp?
[Chuckles]
I don't think so,
Mr. Simms.
I'm saving up
for something else.
It wouldn't cost you a cent.
A friend of mine
is a director of the camp
for the junior blind,
and he could use a C.A.
For the July session.
What's a C. A?
Counselor's aide.
You help the counselors
with the little kids,
and you get
to go free.
Little blind kids?
Most of em.
Hey, Rocky. I got an "A"
on my algebra test.
- You owe me 14 bucks.
- I got Roy Campanella for you.
It's a deal.
I tutor him.
Oh.
Well, how about
the camp, Rocky?
I don't think so, Mr. Simms.
My mom kind of needs me here.
Somehow, Rocky,
your mother's never given
me the impression...
that she can't take
care of herself.
Well, that's not what I meant.
I kind of organize things
for her.
You know, just kind of
keep things together.
Yeah. I guess
you probably do.
Well, will you at least
think about it?
Okay, I'll think about it.
Good.
Bye-bye.
You okay, Rock?
##[Radio: Rock]
Hi, baby.
Mom, what would you
think about me
if you were a girl?
That's a toughie,
but let me see.
I don't know. I'd think
you're pretty cute.
I like guys with red hair.
I wanna talk to another
plastic surgeon.
One said you couldn't
do anything until
your bones stopped growing.
I know.
Well, what is that, Rock?
Two years at the most? We've
been doing this for 16 years.
Don't you understand
anything, Mom?
It's girls!
[Door Slams]
##[Rocky's Radio Playing Loudly]
#I done my best
to live the right way #
#I get up every morning
and go to work each day #
#But your eyes go blind
and your blood runs cold #
#Sometimes I feel so weak
I just wanna explode #
#Explode and tear
this 'ol town apart #
# Take a knife
and cut this pain from my heart #
#Find somebody itching
for something to start #
# The dogs on Main Street howl #
# 'Cause they understand #
#If I could wrench one moment #
#Into my hands #
#Mister, I ain't a boy
No, I'm a man #
#And I believe
In a promised land ##
##[Jukebox: Rock]
#In Birmingham
they love the governor #
# Ooh, ooh, ooh #
#So now we all did
what we could do #
#Now Watergate
does not bother me #
#Does your conscience
bother you, tell me true #
Will you give me a beer?
#Sweet home Alabama #
# Where the skies
are so blue #
#Sweet home Alabama #
#Lord, I'm coming home to you
Here I come #
#Alabama ##
[Inaudible Dialogue]
[Door Closes]
[Rusty]
Come on.
Now, wait.
I don't want to wake up...
oh, shit...my old man.
Shh. Shh. Come on.
This is serious.
Rocky? Rocky, honey,
come on. Wake up.
You got a guest.
Come on, Screech.
Come on, boy.
Geez, what happened
to your face?
W-W-What do you want?
The lady brought me here.
Oh, my God.
Oh, I don't believe
she did this.
[Sighs]
Well?
- Well, what?
- What do you want?
You don't happen to have
a Carl Furillo, do you?
Huh?
No, it's just a joke.
Do you wanna sit down?
Mind if I smoke?
How old are you?
Nineteen.
How... How much do you get?
Depends.
Oh, yeah, sure.
Well, how-how much
for a basic?
Twenty-five.
Is that it?
You need a business manager.
No, thanks. I already
got one of those.
Why is your map
all stuck with pins?
Those are all the places
I'm gonna go.
I'm going to Seattle,
Washington.
Yeah?
Yep, as soon
as I get enough money.
Seattle?
Yeah, I got a sister
that lives there.
I get postcards.
It's real wet and clean.
What happened
to your face?
I used to do
a lot of drugs.
No shit?
No, I'm...
I'm just kidding.
Oh.
[Chuckles]
Where the hell
have you been?
Getting something for Rocky.
Uh-huh.
And me.
I hope it was worth
that 40 bucks you took
out of my jeans.
I remember a time
when you weren't above...
copping a couple bucks
for some snort.
I've grown up since then.
Forty bucks?
You want to take it
out in trade?
Are you all right?
Mm-hmm.
You know, my mama used
to say some people were
born with no place to go.
I don't believe that.
Then how do you explain
all the rotten things
that happen to people?
I don't know.
You know, Lorrie,
I hope you don't
mind me saying this,
but I think you got
a really shitty attitude.
It's pretty negative.
[Chuckles]
It is, huh?
Yeah. And if you think
like that, then things
will only get worse.
When something
bad happens to you,
you gotta remember something
good that's happened.
Like what?
Well, I got a bunch
of em that I use.
Like the time that we
all went down to Mexico,
or the way my grandma's
kitchen smells.
I don't think I have any.
Everyone's gotta have
at least one, for Christ's sake.
Well, maybe the time...
Nah, I don't know.
Lorrie, I hope you don't think
that I don't like you
or anything, 'cause I do.
You're really pretty
and nice and stuff.
It's just that
I thought it would be...
with someone that I was
in love with, you know?
You know what?
I just thought of one.
Yeah?
Yeah.
When I was in fifth grade,
we had to paint
these pictures...
of a pine tree
with snow on it.
Mine was the best one.
The teacher, she put it
on the wall by the door...
where all the kids
could see it.
She put a big
gold star on it.
And all the kids
saw it.
[Sighs]
[Rocky Chuckles]
You want some
more toast, Lorrie?
I gotta go to work.
Oh, Gar. Can you give her
a ride to the bus stop?
Yeah, sure.
Come on, Lorrie.
Bye.
Bye, Rocky.
Mom?
[Shuts Blender Off]
Do I look like
a freak to you?
No.
You've always been real big
on telling me my face doesn't
matter, but it does, doesn't it?
You think that I can't
even get a girl to like me
unless you pay for her.
That's not true.
Bullshit!
Bullshit yourself.
Lots of young guys
got problems getting girls.
What if I was your dad
and I did the same thing?
I'd hate that too.
I'm sorry, you know.
Maybe I was wrong.
Goddamn right you were.
But it had nothing
to do with your face.
Bullshit, Mom!
Rock, where
are you going?
[Screen Door Closes]
[Man]
Hey, Rocky!
[Man #2] Rock.
Hey, Rock,
how's it going?
Hey, Rock.
[Screech Whines]
You know, Rock, your mom
sometimes does the wrong thing
but for the right reason.
You always
stick up for her, Gar.
And then she
pisses you off
and you split.
Then you come back.
It's all so nuts.
Yeah.
First time I met your mother,
she was workin' behind a bar,
drawin' beer.
She had to wear
this cheesy little
two-piece thing.
I could tell
she hated it.
Takin' a lot of shit
from a lot of assholes.
I asked to take her home.
She said she was
gonna get her kid
and have his picture taken.
You know,
at one of those stores.
I said I'd ride her
and her kid on the bike.
She liked that.
Well, she came out of
your grandma's house with you.
[Chuckles]
You must have been five,
maybe six.
Well, I nearly shit.
I mean, you didn't look like
your regular kid, right?
Well, we get down
to the store.
She's standin' in line
with the rest of the mothers
and their little kids,
and all the mothers
and little kids
are starin' at you.
Pretty soon it's your turn.
She puts you up
on this big red block,
and the guy
taking the pictures
nearly shits.
You're just sittin' up there
with your nose runnin',
this big damn smile
on your face.
[Sighs]
And I looked
over there at her,
and... I never saw
a woman more beautiful...
than the way
she was lookin' at you.
Jesus!
[Chuckles]
## [Harmonica]
Hey, Screech.
Come here.
Here comes Rocky.
I'm not goin'.
Why?
I don't have
anything to wear.
Oh, I've got
the same problem
all the time!
[Laughing]
Hey, it's my
goddamn graduation.
It may not mean much
to you guys, but it's
a big deal to me.
Better remember
who you are, boy.
You ain't no citizen
like that friend of yours.
What's that kid's name,
the one with the letters
on his shirt?
Eric.
Like him. What's the matter with
your jeans, for Christ's sake?
I can't wear jeans
to my graduation, Garth.
Oh, bullshit, Rock.
Get me another beer, and we're
goin' to your graduation.
What?
Get me another beer.
Now.
We all chipped in,
and Gar picked it out.
But you gotta wear it.
[Man]
Now, that's a point.
[All Laughing]
Well, what do you say?
Thank you, everybody.
[Man]
You're welcome, Rock.
Better go
get it on.
[Laughing]
[Simms] Now, before we send
our junior high school students
on to senior high,
we would like to acknowledge
some of our stars.
An academic achievement award
in English...
is presented to
Caroline Meyers.
Whoo!
All right, Caroline!
And for academic excellence
in mathematics,
- Rocky Dennis.
- [Cheering]
[Screaming]
Whoo!
Way to go!
Thank you.
You may as well
stay here, Rocky.
For achievement
in history,
Rocky Dennis.
Way to go, Rock!
All right!
Go get 'em, Rock!
[Whistling]
And...
for academic excellence
in science,
Rocky Dennis.
Rocky Dennis!
Uh, that's my family.
There's Rocky.
See you later.
Have a nice summer, Rocky.
[Whispering]
Have a nice summer.
Hey, boogie!
Congratulations!
You made it, Rocky.
All right, man.
You made it.
I graduated.
Finally.
Way to go.
Finally you graduated.
Thank God.
I... I'm...
r-real...
p...
proud...
of... y-y-you...
R-R...
Rocky.
Thanks, Doze.
[Sobbing]
[Tires Screech]
[Horn Honking]
[Horn Honks]
Stop there!
Grandma! Grandpa!
[Tires Screech]
[Engine Revving,
Tires Squealing]
Mom?
Are you up?
Yeah. Yeah.
Mom, they're here.
Well, bring 'em in.
Morning, Gar.
Come on.
Mornin', Rock.
[Tires Squealing]
Why don't you try
playin' this one straight?
Give your old man
a chance.
What a terrific idea.
Why didn't I think of that?
Mm-hmm.
Go ahead. I'll be out
as soon as I put on
my wings and halo.
I wanna get
a picture of that.
Hey!
[Laughing]
Honey boy.
Hey, Grandma.
Are you gonna
try out for the Knicks?
Look how tall
he's getting, Evelyn.
Hey, come on.
I can't believe it.
Fast, fast.
Come on. Quick.
Stop. Abe, stop.
That's a boy.
You'll pull out your back
and you'll exhaust the boy.
Hey!
[Laughs]
So, show us
the new house, eh?
Abe, don't start anything.
You promised. Abe.
Yeah. All right. All right!
Come on in.
Hello, Abe.
Son of a bitch.
Look who's back here.
Gar!
I didn't know you were back.
I want to
show you my dog.
That's all you need
around here
is a damn dog.
Does she have any cleanser?
Now, Evelyn,
that's not your job.
I just want
to give her a hand.
Okay.
I'm not gonna do anything.
He's all right,
that mutt.
Hey, that's terrible.
Come here.
What?
This hole.
This hole in
your infield here.
That is real terrible.
Wow! My God!
Oh, shit. I mean,
whoa, Pee Wee Reese?
Huh?
Yeah, well, you just
consider that a belated
graduation present.
Oh, Grandpa!
Ha. Say, why don't you go
show the dog to your grandma.
Well, okay.
Come on, Screech.
[Screech Barks]
Hi, Pop.
Well, there she is.
Yeah. Lookin' like
a million, eh?
You look great too,
Pop.
Ehh.
Hey, Ma, wanna do
the windows next?
Gramps?
Oh.
All right.
Pee Wee.
I've been looking
for that one for years.
I found him a couple months ago
in a store, sittin' there
waitin' for me.
Oh, he's beautiful.
[Laughs]
Ah, Pee Wee. [Laughs]
Well, Abe,
how's it feel
to be retired?
Ah, it's
driving me crazy.
Man's only as good
as his last day's work.
How long are you stayin', Pop?
Hey! Already she's
tryin' to get rid of us!
[Laughs]
No, Pop, I thought I'd make you
something nice for lunch.
You cookin'?
No orderin' out?
No, I got a roast.
You like roast.
Yeah. I couldn't chew it
the last time, but...
I thought the roast
was delicious.
[Mouthing Words]
So, uh, what are
they learnin' you
in school, Rocky?
Oh, same old stuff.
Math, history, science.
Yeah. First you get
a good education.
Then you get a job
with some security.
I always tried
to tell that
to your mother.
She never went for
the old 9-to-5 though.
What was it
you used to say, Rusty?
You were more the, uh...
The freelance type, Pop.
[Guffaws]
Yeah, the freelance type, eh?
[Laughs] Yeah. I got her
a job interview one time
down at the gas company.
Lou Cappesio's brother.
What the hell was his name?
Anyway, she shows up
in this kooky outfit...
with her hair all the way up
to here and these little lines
painted under here.
Looked like she had a couple
of spiders under her eyes.
- Yeah, you remember that,
Rusty, huh?
- Yeah, I remember, Pop.
I remember.
The guy's name was Vinnie.
He wanted to give me the job.
He also wanted to give me
a little early bonus
right there in his office.
So I took him up on the bonus,
and then I told him
to shove the job up his ass.
Florence!
[Gar Chuckles]
Rocky, find out what time
the game's on the tube,
will ya?
Usually it starts
at 2:30, but I'll check.
Whoa!
Mom! Grandpa got me
tickets to the Dodger game.
Could I go?
Yeah.
All right.
Check it out.
Come on, Rocky.
Let's move it out.
Lasorda's gonna need
all the help he can get.
Bye, Mom.
See ya, Gar.
See ya, Rock.
He tried, honey.
He really tried.
It's okay, Mom.
Anyway, I'm glad
Gar is back.
Don't you wanna
wave good-bye?
No, I don't.
[Radio]
#... a little wild one #
#And she brings you
only sorrow #
Bye!
#All the time
you know she's smilin'#
# You'll be on your knees
tomorrow, yeah #
# You go back, Jack
do it again #
# Wheel turnin'
round and round #
# You go back, Jack
do it again #
If you're gonna get
wasted on that crap,
I ain't gonna
hang around here
and baby-sit ya.
[Scoffs]
You must be confusing me
with somebody who gives a shit.
Must be.
You know this
is not gonna work.
I'm doing things to please you,
and I'm gonna end up
hating you for it.
Oh, come on, baby. You and
your old man been going
through this shit forever.
Got to you again,
didn't he?
Got you ready
for one of those
two-hour screamers.
Gets you to a place
where I wanna put you
through a goddamn wall.
Go ahead. Put me through
the goddamn wall then.
Why should you be any different
than any other guy
I've been with?
[Door Slams]
[Motorcycle Engine
Starts]
[Sound Of Engine
Fades]
Come on out,
or we're coming in
to get you!
Well, what are you
waiting for, Bonaro?
You and Madigan
lost your nerve?
[Gunshots]
[Horn Honks]
Just the lock.
There's a girl
in there.
[Shotgun Blast]
Dan, you should be
covering me. Let me
go in first.
[Dan]
Knock it off!
Keep him talking.
[Bonaro]
Barney!
Look what I got.
Send the girl out.
She can't help you.
[Barney]
How do you know?
I might get bored!
Oh, come on, Barney.
She has nothing
to do with this.
Let's talk.
Florence, is...
[Barney]
The mayor here yet?
No, sorry, Barney.
He couldn't make it.
He's busy with the budget.
[Gunshots On TV]
[Woman Screaming]
[Bonaro]
Dan. Dan!
[Sighs]
[Car Door Closes]
Florence?
[Car Engine Starts]
[Horn Honks]
Sergeant, get these
people out of here.
Clear the way!
[Door Closes]
[Car Door Closes,
Car Drives Away]
You're gonna be
all right, Dan.
Thanks, Commissioner.
Save your strength. You'll be
at the hospital in two minutes.
[Bonaro] I'd like to go
with him, Commissioner.
Go ahead.
[Sighs]
What'd you do today, Mom?
Some smack?
A couple ludes?
That was some promise
you made me.
In front of Grandma
and Grandpa too. Why?
Why do you do this, Mom?
Well, I'm not gonna hang around
all summer for this.
I'm going to a camp
where everybody's blind.
[Chuckles]
That'll be a break.
Who's gonna take care of things?
You. You're gonna have to
take care of things, Mom,
including yourself.
That'll be
something new, won't it?
[Door Slams]
##[Radio: Rock]
#And very much in control
She was the first time
I met her #
#Even though she was
dancing in a dive #
##[Continues]
Come on, kids.
Let's get it together.
Hi, Dewey!
How are you?
Kevin, turn off
your radio, all right?
[Dewey] All right.
Come on. Summer, can you
get 'em over here, please?
Uh, who's getting
the luggage?
Oh, this is great, isn't it?
Move around there
a little bit.
Hey, you. Take that
mask off so I can see
who I'm talking to.
Well, I'll try, but it
ain't gonna be easy.
[Grunting]
Oh... Gee, I'm sorry.
I really thought
it was a mask.
It's okay.
It happens all the time.
No big deal.
Hey, Dewey.
[Whispering]
Rocky.
Rocky Dennis?
Uh, hi.
Hi, Rocky.
I'm Norm Kaplan.
Hi.
Glad to have you with us.
Walter Simms has told me
a great deal about you.
Excuse me, but Jake
wants to see you
in the kitchen.
Okay, Rocky, put your gear
over there. Then give Dewey
a hand over there. Okay?
Okay. Thanks.
All right, boy.
[Rocky Groaning]
[Groaning, Panting]
Make myself... well.
[Exhales]
Make... myself... well.
Go, Ben.
All right, Ben.
Swing!
[Cheering]
[Man Announcing Over P.A.]
Down the third base line.
Throw to first.
He's safe at first.
Almost there, guys.
Haven't missed too much.
[Crowd Cheering]
Hey, Kevin.
How's the caboose
doin' back there?
Fine.
All right.
[Announcer]
Bobby Smith on the mound.
He goes into the windup.
It's a drive down
the third base line. Yeah!
[Cheering]
Bases loaded.
They held him up at third.
Here we go.
We have Abby
up at bat next.
[Dewey Announcing]
Releases. Fastball,
down the middle.
Swing!
Whoa!
[Cheering]
[Bell Jingling]
Runners at first
and second.
Good shot.
Bobby Smith on the mound.
We have Alex at the bat.
He goes into his windup.
Fastball. Alex swings.
It's a miss!
[Horse Whinnying]
Oh, close though.
We have the bases
loaded with two outs.
One strike.
Bobby Smith, on the mound
for the Bombers.
The Bloomfield
Bombers.
We have Alex at the bat.
He goes into a windup.
A knuckleball
down the middle.
It's going...
Hi.
Strike right down the middle.
Let's hear it for Bobby.
Oh, yes, Christie.
Lucky shot, Bobby.
[Dewey Announcing,
Indistinct]
Down the middle. Pitch.
Swing. Whoa!
I'll tell you, last year
he struck out 18 batters
in one game.
He can be bad, folks.
He can be bad.
- Who's that?
- Hi.
- My name is Rocky.
Hi, Rocky.
I'm Diana Adams.
- Dennis. Rocky Dennis.
- You a camper, or...
Yeah. I'm also
a counselor's aide.
That's neat.
You look like Alice.
You know, in Wonderland?
- No. What's she look like?
- You.
Great. That's a big help.
You wanna hand me
that bridle?
[Dewey Announcing]
He's in a quick windup.
Releases.
Fastball, down the middle.
Into center field.
[Dewey Continues,
Indistinct]
Great. Thanks.
Oh, no, this is a halter.
A bridle's leather
and has a bit.
- Has a bit of what?
- No.
A bit is a metal piece that
fits into the horse's mouth.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Of course.
Thank you.
Don't know, uh,
much about horses, do you?
Well, I ride motorcycles.
Ah. I love horses.
I got one at home.
- Where's your home?
- San Marino.
Where do you live?
[Triangle Ringing]
Azusa.
- Are you starving?
- Huh?
I'm starving.
Could you take me to lunch?
[Chuckles]
Sure. Great.
Great.
Okay, Maria.
He's ready.
Okay. Fine.
Thanks.
Yeah.
No, here.
I'll take your elbow.
Okay.
Diana...
of the woods.
What's that?
She's some
famous goddess.
The huntress,
I think.
[Chuckles]
I couldn't hit a barn
with an elephant.
[Rocky Laughs]
That's funny.
Thanks.
[Laughing]
## [Harmonica]
[Phone Ringing]
[Ringing]
Yeah. Rusty?
What?
Oh, shit!
What's the matter?
Rusty.
[Motorcycle Approaching]
##[Radio: Rock]
Gar, I can't, um,
write a letter to Rocky,
and I miss him.
You need sleep,
Rusty.
No, no.
Come on.
You help me.
You help me write
the letter. Please?
Dear Rocky: Um,
I miss you, and...
you're away at camp.
You're not in your room,
and... and I miss you, and...
[Sniffles]
And I'm sorry
that I was bad.
And, oh, Screech is here,
and Gar is here,
and I love you.
Love, Mom. Love, Mom.
With little kisses.
Have you got that, Gar?
Yeah, yeah.
I got it all.
[Sobs]
Okay.
I got it.
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
[Sobs, Exhales]
[Diana] You okay
back there, Rocky?
Fine.
[Whinnying]
Ho, ho, ho.
On your right,
we've got some chaparral.
It's covering
the rolling green hill.
Uh-huh.
It ain't just your forest
green we're talkin' here.
It's kind of
a misty, grayish green.
Rocky, I've been blind
since I was born.
I don't know green.
You don't know green.
People have tried
to explain colors to me,
but I just...
I don't understand them.
Anyway, go on.
Huh. Well, up above,
we got some,
some white clouds.
[Chuckles]
It's okay.
White. I'm sorry.
Some... Some clouds.
They're... They're billowy.
Rocky, I don't know
billowy either.
This is
very strange.
I think we're
pullin' over here.
Whoa. Let's stop!
Whoa!
Whoa, mule.
Hyah. Thanks, Pete.
Whoa. I got ya.
Okay, Rock.
Thanks.
Boy, I can't wait to tell
Eric and Ben about this.
Yeah?
Who are they?
Eric's my friend from school.
Uh-huh.
Ben's my friend
for life.
Let's sit down here. Yeah?
I have a friend like that.
Anne Marie. Yeah.
Me and Ben are gonna ride
motorcycles across Europe.
Yeah? Wow.
That's so neat.
My parents
are so overprotective.
My mom is very...
modern.
Yeah? Did she
name you Rocky?
Yeah. My real name
is Roy.
Roy?
When I was a kid,
I used to like
to rock back and forth
in the crib.
So she started
calling me Rocky.
I like that.
Hey, you two.
There's one apple left.
You guys wanna share it?
Yeah.
Thanks. Thanks, Maria.
Here. I'll cut it
in half.
I wanna
show you something.
Rocky, what do you look like?
Describe yourself to me.
Well, it's too bad you've
never seen any pictures
of the Greek god Adonis,
'cause I kinda look like him.
Wow, he was supposed
to be gorgeous.
He was. Uh, we are.
Here.
Geez.
See the star?
Five-pointed star
is supposed to be lucky.
Diana,
I don't look like Adonis.
I've got
this real strange disease,
and it makes my face
look real unreal.
Come on, Rocky.
Don't be a chicken.
You look pretty good to me.
My mom says that I
look like a lion.
She... She says that I was
a lion in a past life
or something,
and it got left over.
That's funny.
[Maria]
Hey, you two.
Show us your pearly whites.
Great.
[Shutter Clicks]
Hey. Sorry.
Is now a good time?
Sure, Rocky.
- Now's a good time.
- Thanks.
Wait. Okay.
I have to go.
Let me help you.
Okay. What are
you doing, Rocky?
Wait a minute.
Hold on a second.
Have you no patience?
No.
Right up here.
Now, sit down.
It's a ledge.
Sit up. Right there.
Okay, now hold out
your hands. Ready?
Wait right there.
What is this?
This...
Hold on a second.
There's a... Ooh.
Oh. Wait a sec.
Wait a second.
Right here. Great.
Okay. Ready?
This is blue.
No. What?
Ah, it's freezing!
It's blue?
This... is green.
Rocky, I think I understand.
Hold on a second.
Hold on, hold on.
Shit.
Oh, sorry, Diana.
That's okay.
I say it all the time.
You do?
Yeah.
Okay,
put those down.
Now, this is red.
Aaah!
[Chuckling]
Oh, my God.
It's red?
And when it cools down...
When that cools down,
it'll be pink.
Rocky, I understand!
Okay.
Hold on a second.
This... is billowy.
Wow.
And this...
is beautiful.
Rocky.
# When I
feel that somethin'#
#I wanna hold your hand #
#I wanna hold
your hand #
#I wanna hold your hand #
#I wanna hold
your hand ##
[Cheering]
#Is there anybody
going to listen to my story #
#All about the girl
who came to stay #
#She's the kind of girl
you want so much #
#It makes you sorry #
#Still you don't regret
a single day #
Man, do I have
a great one to use now.
What?
A great thought.
My mom taught me
that when things get rotten,
I should remember
a good memory.
Tonight sure is a beaut.
Does it work?
Oh, yeah.
Can two people use
the same memory?
#And she promises the earth
to me and I believe her #
#After all this time...##
[Tapping On Microphone,
Feedback Squealing]
Okay, campers,
ten seconds to New Year's.
Nine, eight,
Eight,
seven, six, five, four,
three, two, one!
Happy New Year!
[Bells Jingling]
[Cheering]
##["Auld Lang Syne"]
#Should auld acquaintance #
# Be forgot #
#And never brought to mind #
#Should auld acquaintance
be forgot #
Happy New Year, Diana.
#And days #
Happy New Year, Rocky.
# Of auld lang syne #
#For auld lang syne #
Well, um, aren't you
gonna kiss me?
#My dear #
#For auld lang syne #
# We'll take a cup
of kindness yet #
#For auld lang syne ##
[Cheering]
[Bells Jingling]
Bye. Come back again
next year.
Okay, great.
Bye, you guys!
See you later, Diana.
[Diana]
Bye, Robert.
See you guys later.
Oh, how are you?
Daddy!
How are you?
Mmm!
Oh, God.
I missed you.
Mom?
Oh, I missed you
so much!
[Diana]
I missed you too.
The boy I told you about.
Rocky?
Oh. Right.
Rocky!
He's somewhere around here.
I don't know where he is.
I just... Rocky?
Rocky.
Yeah.
Hi.
Oh. Mom, Dad,
this is Rocky Dennis,
the boy I told you about
on the phone.
Uh, Rocky
was voted best buddy
and friendliest camper...
at the camp awards
we had.
- That's... That's wonderful.
- Yeah.
Well, uh, we'd better
hit the road, honey, huh?
Wanna beat
the traffic.
- Yeah.
- Nice meeting you, Rocky.
- Yes. Come on, honey. Let's go.
- Just a minute.
I want to say good-bye.
Bye, Rocky.
Bye.
Call me, okay?
I will.
I wanna kiss you,
but my parents
are watching.
I understand.
Bye.
[Sighs]
You damn son of a bitch.
[Horn Honking]
[Horn Honks]
[Shouting]
[Laughing]
Whee!
You look great!
You look great.
Hey, Doze.
Hey, Gar.
How ya doin'?
Rock. Good to see you.
Good. Where's
your stuff?
Over there. Thanks, Doze.
Hey, Rock.
Oh, it's my buddy.
How's it goin'?
Hey, Babe.
Miss me?
Hi, sweetie. Mmm.
He looks good,
doesn't he?
Looks great.
Mom, I have
some great news.
- Me too.
- You first.
I quit.
I'm clean as a whistle.
Yep.
All right, Ma.
Yeah, I even called
the drug rehab twice.
- What'd they say?
- Well, I hung up.
[Laughing]
Well, it's a start.
Well, what about your news?
Well, it's no big deal.
I met a girl. We're goin' out.
Ow-ooh!
Tell us!
Well, her name
is Diana.
Yeah? Yeah?
And she's beautiful.
She's got long blond hair.
All right.
[Wolf Whistle]
She rides horses
and she's beautiful
and she's smart...
and... she loves me.
Well, what's not
to love, baby?
##[Rock: Radio]
Hey, Rock?
Rocky.
You look real pretty
today, Mom.
Why, thank you.
You know, I've called Diana
every day since I've been back,
and her mom always says
that she's not there.
You think that's
kinda weird?
I don't know.
Rocky, what's happening?
Hey, Ben.
Hey, babe.
What's happening?
Rocky, I-I gotta
talk to you.
Okay.
You want some cake?
No.
You sure?
My mom made this.
It's actually
pretty good.
Thanks.
Okay.
Want something to drink?
Mm-mmm.
How 'bout a noose
to hang yourself?
What's the matter, Ben?
I've been wanting
to tell you this
for a while.
Well, what?
Rock, I'm goin' back
to my dad's in Michigan.
He got me a job there.
It's great money.
Well, when you
comin' back?
I'm not comin' back.
What do you mean, Ben?
I'll go nuts
if I have to stay here.
I mean, my mom, the school.
So I quit.
Look, I can work back there.
I'll be makin' 7.50 an hour.
What about the trip?
I'm sorry, Rocky.
Look, you can
keep the money.
I don't want
the frigging money.
I want to go to Europe.
What about our trip, huh?
Huh?
How can you do this?
This is all we've talked about
for a year.
- It's all you talked about.
- That's bullshit, man!
- You talked about it too,
and you know it.
- I know I did.
- I'm sorry. I didn't mean that.
- You never know what you mean,
do you?
You know why?
Because you are stupid!
[Scoffs]
You are so stupid, Ben!
Rocky.
I'm gonna show you
how stupid you are.
Rube Walker, man!
I conned you
out of Rube Walker!
- Rocky, take it easy.
- No more, Ben.
No more taking it easy!
I am...
Rocky, stop it!
Get out of here, Ben.
[Radio DJ]
That was Gary U.S. Bonds,
"Dear Lady Twist."
Here's Little Richard.
##[Piano]
#Slippin' and a-slidin'
Peepin' and a-hidin'#
#Been told
a long time ago #
#Slippin and a-slidin'
Peepin and a-hidin'#
#Been told
a long time ago #
#I've been told, baby
you've been bold #
#I won't be
your fool no more #
# Oh, big conniver
Nothin' but a jiver #
#I done got hip
to your jive #
# Oh, big conniver
Nothin but a jiver #
#I done got hip
to your jive #
[Muttering]
#Slippin and a-slidin'
Peepin and a-hidin'#
#I won't be your fool
no more, ow #
Hello. Mrs. Adams?
Is Diana there?
Rocky Dennis.
D-Do you know
where she is?
D-Did you...
Did you tell her
I've called?
It... Okay, thanks.
Good-bye.
##[Continues]
[Grunts]
[Bangs Table]
# Oh, Malinda
she's a solid sender #
[Sobbing]
# You know
you'd better surrender #
# Oh, Malinda
she's a solid sender #
Baby, don't cry.
# You know
you'd better surrender #
[Sobbing]
#Slippin and a-slidin'
Peepin and a-hidin'#
#I won't be
your fool no more ##
Look.
There's that guy
I heard about.
If that's a mask
he's wearing, I sure
wish he'd take it off.
I'll take my mask off
if you take your mask off,
you son of a bitch!
What's the matter?
Red died this morning.
Babe called from the hospital.
She said he'd been sick
for a long time.
Never told anybody.
Babe was with him
when he kicked off.
##[Accordion]
##[Continues]
## [Blues]
May the wind be always
on your face, brother.
[All]
And the breath of a sweet woman
on the back of your neck.
For the cold nights,
Red, you old bastard.
Stay fried, Red.
Red.
I told you not to give it
to me, didn't I?
Get down.
21 guns, Red.
[Gunshots]
One, two, three...
## [Bluesy]
Four, five, six.
Hang on a second, Red.
[Gunshots]
Seven...
eight, nine, ten.
[Groans]
You okay?
Yeah.
We okay?
Yeah, ma. We're okay.
[Man Yelling]
[Gunshots Continue]
And 18.
Adios. Arrivederci, man.
You gonna throw something
in the grave?
I don't wanna say
good-bye to Red.
He's not over there anyway.
He's everywhere now.
It's like he used to say, Mom.
Nobody ever really dies.
##[Country Blues Rock]
Ma?
We're out here.
I gotta go
somewhere, Ma.
Where you goin',
Rock?
I just got somethin' to do.
I'll be back.
Don't worry.
No, Screech, stay.
[Horse Whinnying]
Oh, God.
Diana?
Rocky?
Hi, Diana.
Hi, Rocky.
Anne Marie,
this is Rocky.
Oh...
Hi.
Um, you wanna
excuse us and just
take Copper for me?
Yeah.
Come on.
Let's talk.
Why didn't you call?
I called you.
You never called me back.
And I made you tapes,
and I never
heard from you.
Oh, Rocky,
my parents.
I knew it.
I thought you'd
forgotten me.
I thought you
had forgotten me.
I guess they don't want me
to get hurt, 'cause I never
stop talking about you.
Huh.
And I have to go away
for next semester.
Where?
I'm leaving
on Monday.
The school has
really good programs
for the blind.
Here.
It's in Santa Barbara.
Oh.
Let's sit down.
I'll write.
I'll send you tapes.
Oh, Rocky,
I've missed you.
I don't want to go.
[Chuckling]
Are you laughing
at me?
Oh, God, no.
It's just that here it is,
the most rotten time
in my whole life.
You're goin' away,
and I hate my school,
and the trip
to Europe is off, but...
Rocky, no.
No, you see,
but it's okay.
That's what's
kind of funny.
It doesn't matter.
It's okay now,
'cause I know that
you still love me.
I do.
I really do.
I wish we could run away
and be together
all the time.
No. We can't
run away, Diana.
I know.
But we can sorta
run away in our minds.
We can remember.
Camp and the mountains
and the ocean.
And colored rocks
and billowy cotton.
[Chuckles]
Yeah.
And New Year's Eve.
Especially
New Year's Eve.
Yeah.
And right now.
[Sighs]
We'll always
be together, Diana.
Even when...
we can't be together.
Oh, Rocky.
##[Guitar, Harmonica]
Haven't seen the old number
in a long time, Rock.
How 'bout it, Rusty?
Good idea.
Hey, I'm up for it
if he is.
No, I'm feeling kind of
tired tonight, Stickman.
Oh, come on, Rocky, Rusty.
[Woman]
Oh, come on, you guys.
[Man] Yeah, let's see it.
[Red]
Come on. Sing a number.
You okay, babe?
My head hurts
a lot tonight, Mom.
I'm gonna throw these bums
out of here early.
You go to your room
and make yourself well.
Go on.
How 'bout it, Rusty?
You gonna sing?
Nah.
[Stickman]
What about that other one?
Yeah, sing the other song.
I don't want to.
Gar.
How ya doin', kid?
[Red]
Good night, Rock.
##[Guitar, Harmonica
Continue]
[Whining]
[Pin Clinks In Dish]
[Pins Clinking]
Mom?
It hurts.
Yeah, honey.
I know.
Come on, Screech, come on.
Why don't we just
go back to bed?
It's okay with me.
I gotta go do
this thing.
I'll be back soon.
All right.
I'll wait for you.
[Phone Ringing]
See ya later.
[Radio DJ]
"Do It Again, "Steely Dan.
Now here's "Ripple."
[Ringing]
Yeah. No, he's not here.
He's at school.
Yeah, I'm sure.
What do you mean
he's not there?
Yeah. Okay, thanks.
#If my words
did glow #
# With the gold
of sunshine #
#And my tunes were played
on the harp unstrung #
# Would you hear my voice #
# Come through the music #
# Would you hold it near #
You aren't going
to get a scholarship if you stay
in the sack all day, are you?
You had a Spanish test,
didn't you, Rocky?
Afraid of a little
Spanish test? Huh?
[Sniffles]
You're cold.
Well, you've got
your covers off of you.
Don't pull this shit
with me, Rocky!
Do you hear me?
Wake up.
Come on, baby.
Make yourself well.
Rocky, wake up.
Oh, God!
#Ripple in still water #
# When there is
no pebble tossed #
#Reach out your hand #
[Sobbing]
#If your cup
be empty #
#If your cup is full
may it...#
# That was not made #
#By the hands of men #
# There is a road #
#No simple highway #
#Between the dawn #
#And the dark of night #
#And if you go #
#No one may follow #
[Sniffles]
# That path is for #
# Your steps alone #
[Crying]
[Sobbing, Gasping]
# You who choose #
# To lead must follow #
#But if you fall #
# You fall alone #
#If you should stand #
# Then who
is to guide you ##
Now you can go
anywhere you want, baby.
#Born in the U.S.A. #
#I was born in the U.S.A. #
#I was born in the U.S.A. ##
[Rocky's Voice]
These things are good:
Ice cream and cake,
a ride on a Harley,
seein' monkeys
in the trees,
the rain on my tongue,
and the sun shining on my face.
These things
are a drag:
Dust in my hair,
holes in my shoes,
no money in my pocket,
and the sun shining on my face.
##[Rock]