Sursa file: Casanova (2005)_2.srt
(Music)
Bowto the board!
- This is the boy.
Born here in the workhouse.
Moved to the parish farm.
Nine years old today.
Time to be moved back here.
What's your name, boy?
Oliver Twist.
- Boy! Listen to me!
You knowyou are an orphan, l suppose?
- What's that?
You knowyou've got no father or mother
and that you were brought up...
by the parish, don't you?
- What are you crying for?
l hope you say your prayers every night?
Pray for those who feed you...
and take care of you, like a...
like a Christian?
Well, you have come here to be educated...
and to be taught a useful trade.
(Music)
Learn from the boy next to you.
Learn to pick out the oakum.
What's oakum, sir?
- Stop asking so many questions!
Oakums are fibres you unpick
from the old rope then it's used again...
for ships of Her Majesty's Navy.
You're serving your country.
Now get on with it!
(Music)
Tom, give it a rest,
we're trying to sleep!
Can't sleep! Too hungry!
- We're all hungry.
Yes, but l'm frightened.
- Frightened? Why?
Why? l'm so hungry l'm frightened
l'll eat the lad that sleeps next to me.
Oh Lord God, all the blessings
of this generous and bountiful meal...
that you has placed before us,
we give thanks. Amen.
(All)
Amen!
(Music)
Please, sir, l want some more.
What?
- Please, sir, l want some more.
Fetch the Beadle!
Begging your pardon, sir.
Oliver Twist has asked for more.
For more?
Do l understand that he asked for more
after he had eaten his supper?
He did, sir.
That boy will be hanged.
Woah.
L5 and a boy? Woah, woah!
When l says woah, it means woah!
Healthy apprentice...
for L5!
Chimney sweeping is a nasty trade.
- Yes, young boys have been smothered...
in chimneys before now.
- That's because they damp the straw...
before they light it in the chimney
to make them come out again.
Damp strawmakes smoke,
smoke sends the boy to sleep...
and that's what he wants.
Boys are very lazy, gentlemen,
but there's nothing like a good blaze
to make them come out in a run.
When they get stuck in the chimney...
roasting their feet makes 'em struggle
to extricate themselves. Yeah!
l suppose he's fond of chimney sweeping.
- He dotes on it, Your Worship.
Oh well, l will sign the indentures
to make him...
Mr... Mr Garmfield's apprentice.
My boy, my boy!
You look pale and alarmed.
What's the matter?
Please, sir, please, sir...
- What is it, my boy?
Please, sir, don't... don't...
Go on my boy, don't what?
- Please don't send me away...
with this dreadful man, sir.
- Oh of all the designing artfuls...
that l've ever seen!
- Hold your tongue, Beadle!
Did Your Worship speak to me?
- Yes, hold your tongue.
We refuse to sanction these indentures.
Take the boy away and treat him kindly.
He seems to want it.
l have just taken the measures of the
two women that died last night, Mr Bumble.
You'll make your fortune, Mr Sowerberry.
- Oh you think so?
The prices allowed, are very small.
- So are the coffins.
By the way, you don't know anybody
who wants a boy, do you?
Liberal terms, Mr Sowerberry,
liberal terms!
As you are to meet your newmaster,
pull that cap off your eyes.
Hold your head up, sir.
Dry your eyes, sir.
Ah ha! ls that you, Bumble?
- Well, what else, Mr Sowerberry?
l brought the orphan, Oliver Twist
So this is the orphan. is it?
Mrs Sowerberry, will you have...
the goodness to come here a moment,
my dear?
Oliver Twist! How comes an orphan
to have a name at all?
l invented it. - You, Mr Bumple?
Aye, Mr Sowerberry.
l name all our foundlings
in alphabetical order.
The last was S, Swibble l named him.
This was a T, Twist l named him.
Next one as comes will be Unwin,
and the next Wilkins,
and l've got names ready all through
the alphabet, right up to Z.
You're quite a literary character, sir.
- Well, well.
Prhaps l may be.
- Mrs Sowerberry, this is the orphan...
from the workhouse.
Dear me, he's very small!
- But he'll grow, Mrs Sowerberry.
Yes, l dare say he will,
on our food and drink!
Workhouse boys always cost more
to take than they're worth!
Get downstairs, you bag of bones.
Here, Charlotte, give this boy some
of those cold bits...
that were put by for the dog.
You don't mind sleeping among the coffins,
l suppose? Well, it doesn't matter...
if you do or don't,
you can't sleep anywhere else.
(Music)
(Noah)
Open the door, will you?
You the newboy?
- Yes, sir.
How old are you?
- 10, sir.
l beg your pardon, sir, did you knock?
- l kicked.
Did you want a coffin, sir?
- You don't knowwho l am, l suppose?
No, sir.
- l'm Mr Noah Claypole,
and you're under me.
So take down the shutters!
l saved a nice little bit of bacon for you
from the master's breakfast.
ln the corner with you
and be quick about it.
They want you to mind the shop.
Do you hear?
Do you hear, workhouse? ln the corner!
- Oh go on, Noah! Let the boy alone.
They am alone.
Why everybody's let him alone?
His mother, father and all his relations
has let him alone.
So he needs someone who don't!
Supper! Aren't you done yet?
l've never known such an idle boy!
Get down them stairs!
Mr Sowerberry! Supper.
l've had a thought, my dear.
- Had a thought, you want to be careful,
Mr Sowerberry, you'll get brain fever!
- lt's about young Twist.
What about him?
- Avery good-looking boy.
He will be! He eats enough!
- There's an expression of melancholy...
in his face, my dear,
he would make a delightful mute, my love.
l don't mean a regular mute
to attend grown-up funerals, my dear,
but only for children's practice.
Look at him. Look at him!
Aworkhouse boy and a sneak!
Look at him!
Mark my words, l'll see him hung!
lt can't be too soon.
Workhouse, how's your mother?
She's dead.
- Oh. What did she die of, workhouse?
Oh, you're going to cry, workhouse?
What set you off?
- Not you.
Not me, eh?
- No, not you.
And you'd better not say anything
about my mother.
Better not? About your mother?
Well, l'm very sorry and l pity you
very much, but you must know, workhouse,
your mother was a regular
right-down bad 'un.
What did you say?
- A regular right-down bad 'un.
lt's a good thing she died when she did
or she'd be hard-labouring...
or transported, or hung.
Which is most likely, isn't it, workhouse?
Help! He'll murder me!
Help! Get off!
For God's sake, help me!
He's murdering me! Get off of me! Ow!
- Got him out! Out with him!
Get the door, Charlotte, shut him in!
Very violent indeed, sir.
And the Mrs said,
if Mr Bumble can spare the time,
then Mr Bumble's to flog him,
'cause the matter's out.
ln there!
- Oliver?
Let me out of here!
- Do you knowthis here voice, Oliver?
Yes!
- Ain't you afraid of it, sir?
Ain't you trembling while l speak, sir?
- No!
He must be mad!
- lt's not madness, ma'am, it's meat!
Meat, ma'am, meat! You've over-fed him!
lf you'd kept this boy on gruel
this would never have happened.
- Dear, dear! This comes of being liberal.
What's all this?
- Oliver Twist has turned violent, sir.
Look what he's done to my eye, sir.
(Knocking)
Nowthen, nowthen!
You're a nice young fellow, ain't you?
He called my mother names!
- Well, and what if he did,
you little ungrateful wretch!
She deserved what he said, and worse!
She didn't! lt's a lie!
Do something, Mr Sowerberry!
He called me a liar.
Do something!
(Dog's barking)
(Music)
l...
l beg your pardon, miss,
but would you be so kind...
Get off my land!
We don't want beggars here!
Go on! Get off!
l'll put the dog on you!
l haven't much,
but you're more than welcome to it.
Be careful, it's hot.
Seeing you gave me such a turn!
My eyes ain't what they were, but...
l just thought for a moment...
Why are you on the road at all,
a little mite like you?
Where are you headed?
- London, ma'am.
London?
Oh dear, oh dear, oh dear.
(Music)
(Unintelligible)
Hello, my man! What's your game?
You're not from these parts.
Where are you from then?
l've been walking 7 days.
- 7 days?
Cor! l expect you want grub,
and you shall have it. l'm at a low
watermark myself just at the moment,
but l'll fork out and stump.
Come on, up with you, on your gins!
Bye the bye, my name is Jack Dawkins,
better known as the Artful Dodger.
Oliver Twist.
Why are you known as the Artful Dodger?
That's why.
Got any lodgings? Money?
l suppose you want some place
to sleep tonight, don't you?
(Music)
l suspect you were walking so long
to get away from the beak?
What's that mean?
- Don't you knowwhat a Beak is?
A bird's mouth, isn't it?
- You are green! A Beak's a magistrate.
Where've you been all your life?
Name?
There's two of you! Who's he?
- A newpal.
Where did he come from?
- Greenland. ls the old man there?
Upstairs!
This is him, Fagin,
my newfriend, Oliver Twist.
Well, well, Oliver Twist!
l hope l have the honour
of a more intimate acquaintance!
We're very glad to see you, Oliver. Very.
Dodger, take off the sausages...
and let's make a space at the table
for Oliver.
You're staring at the pocket
handkerchiefs, ain't you, my dear?
There's a good many of them, isn't there?
We just got them out ready for the wash.
Yes, Gawd almighty!
Hot!
Nowthen, Oliver! What you must have
is a hot tin and water.
Warms the cockles. Hurry, drink it quick
'cause these gentleman wants the tumbler.
Such a nice lad! l have the feeling
he'll turn out a hard worker.
Yeah, a hard worker.
Oliver.
Oliver?
Clever dogs!
Clever dogs.
Ah, fine fellows.
Ah, fine fellows!
Fine fellows,
fine fellows.
Fine fellows.
What do you watch me for? Why are you
awake, what have you seen? Speak out boy,
quick, quick or l'll eat you alive.
- l was only going to sleep here, sir.
l'm very sorry if l have disturbed you.
- Another way...
Of course you were asleep, my dear.
You're a brave boy, Oliver.
Did you see any of those pretty things?
- Yes, sir.
They... they're mine, Oliver,
my little property...
for my old age. lt's our secret.
Do you understand, my dear?
- Yes, sir.
Can we go up now, sir?
Yeah!
l hope you've been at work this morning,
my dears! Good boys!
What you got, George?
- A couple of pocket books.
George, l don't know, George...
Not as heavy as they might be,
but very neat...
and nicely made.
lngenious workman, ain't 'e, Oliver?
lndeed, sir.
- And Charley, what have you got, my dear?
Wipes!
- Wipes? Oh!
They're very good ones. Oh, very.
You haven't marked them well.
The marks should be picked out
with a needle. We'll teach Oliver...
howto do it. Shall us, Oliver?
- lf you please, sir.
You'd like to make pocket handkerchiefs
as easy as Charley Bates, wouldn't you?
Yes, if you're teaching me, sir.
- l never met anyone so green!
Nowthen boys! The game!
We're showing Oliver
howto make pocket handkerchiefs.
You'd like to play a game, wouldn't you?
- Yes, sir.
(Music)
What's the time, guv?
- Bedtime! 8 'o' clock.
Playing the game were we, Fagin?
- As is our custom, my dear.
He's new?. Who is he?
- Oh, this is Oliver.
Oliver, here's our very good friends
Beth and Nancy.
See, Dodger, you wanna learn from 'im!
He's got manners, 'e 'as.
A proper gentleman.
- We popped in through that cold inside.
As is your custom, my dear.
Charley!
Come on, Oliver, join us.
Or don't you sit with the common folk?
Nowyou want to be careful of this lot,
they'll have you picking pockets...
... cleaning out the marks,
just what we was teaching him, my dear?
Yes, sir.
- Yes, sir?
You knowwho you're talking to, do you?
- What's your mother got to say...
about you being here, Oliver?
- l haven't got a mother. l'm an orphan.
You're in the right company then.
Come on, l'll teach you howto play.
lt's called Spec or Speculation.
Three cards each, and if the winner
turns up, it's trumps.
This is a pleasant life,
ain't it, my dear?
When l go out, sir?
- Soon.
Soon.
Let's see what you've learned.
Would you like that?
Oh yes, sir.
See if you can take this out...
without my feeling it.
ls it gone?
You're a clever boy, my dear!
l never saw a sharper lad.
Here's a shilling for you.
Make the Dodger and Charley your models.
Especially the Dodger, my dear.
He'll be a great man himself,
make you one too! You go on this way,
you'll be the greatest man of the time.
- Oh...
Thank you very much, sir.
(Music)
Thief! Your handkerchief, sir!
Stop, thieves!
Thief!
Stop him! Thief!! Stop, thief!
He didn't deserve it!
- Where's the gentleman?
There's the gentleman! ls this the boy?
- Yes, l'm afraid it is.
Afraid it is! Did you hear him?
- He's hurt himself...
Here, l did that, sir!
Hurt my knuckle against his mouth.
But l stopped him!
- Get up!
lt wasn't me, sir, it wasn't me!
- Oh course it wasn't, it never is!
Now get up! - Don't hurt him!
Oh no, sir, l won't hurt him.
This way gentlemen.
- What's next?
That is my name and address, sir.
- Officer, who is this fellow?.
My name, sir, is Brown...
- Hold your tongue! What is this fellow...
charged with?
- Oh no, he's not charged, Your Worship,
he appears against the boy.
- Before l'm sworn l must beg...
to say one word...
- Hold your tongue, sir!
l will not, sir!
- Hold your tongue this instant!
You're an insolent, impertinent fellow.
How dare you bully a magistrate!
Swear! l'll not hear another word.
- ''l do solemnly swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth and nothing but the truth,
so help me God.''
Now, what's the charge against the boy?
Hold your tongue! Where is the policeman?
What is this? Are there any witnesses?
- None, Your Worship.
The boy is ill.
- Oh yes, l dare say!
Come along you vagabond, none of your
tricks here. What's your name?
What's your name, you hardened scoundrel.
Officer, what's his name?
What's your name boy?
- ... some water...
He says his name is Sam Waters.
- Where does he live?
Anywhere he can, Your Worship.
- Stuff and nonsense!
Don't try to make a fool out of me!
- No, l think he really is ill...
l knowbetter, or my name's not Fang!
Stand away, Officer, he's shamming!
He stands committed for three months,
hard labour of course. Clear the office.
Stop, stop, stop, don't take him away!
- What is this, who is this?
Turn this man out!
- l will not be turned out. l will speak!
l sawit all! l own the bookshop.
l demand to be heard!
Well, what have you got to say?
- lt was not this boy!
Who was it then?
- The robbery was committed by two others
while the gentleman was reading. l saw
that this boy was perfectly amazed by it.
Why didn't you come before?
- l hadn't a soul to mind the shop.
Reading you say? A book l suppose?
- Yes, the very one he has in his hand.
Well, dear me l forgot all about it.
- Well, you're a nice one.
To prefer a charge
against an innocent boy!
l consider, sir, that you have obtained
that book under very suspicious,
disreputable circumstances. Bookseller,
do you want to press charges...
against this fellow?.
- Certainly not!
You may think yourself fortunate that the
owner of the book declines to prosecute.
The boy is discharged. Clear the office!
Clear the office! Clear the office!
Next case!
- Move along, sir, just move along!
There's a good gentlemen...
Call a coach. l'm sorry.
Got one, sir
- Thanks.
Will you drop me off?
- Of course!
lf you could just take his head, sir?
Where to, sir?
Pentonville.
- Pentonville.
Where is he? What's become of the boy?
Speak out or l'll throttle you..
The trags have got him.
Let go of me, will you?
Who pitched this here at me? Who done it?
Bullseye, come here you sneaking wally!
What are you stopping outside for?
Lay down!
What are you up to, Fagin?
You'll treating the boys again?
l wonder they don't murder you?
l would if l was them.
Don't speak so loud!
You seem out of sorts, Bill.
Give us a drink,
and mind you don't poison it!
Good stuff...
- So, Dodger, what's it all about?
The newboy. Come out with us
before he was rightly up to it.
Got nailed by the traps.
- You see, Bill, l'm afraid...
he may say something which will get us
into trouble.
You're blowed upon, Fagin, in a bad time!
And l'm afraid, you see, Bill,
that if the game was up with us
it would come out rather worse for you
than it would for me, my dear.
There's only one thing for it,
someone's got to find out at the office...
what's being done to him.
Somebody's got to get hold of him somehow.
l ain't going in no police office!
- Ah, Harry, the very thing,
Beth will go, won't you my dear?
- l'm blessed if l will!
Nancy, my dear, what do you say?
- lt won't do.
There's no use in trying it on, Fagin.
- What do you mean by that?
Why you're just the very person for it.
Nobody knows anything about you!
And as l don't want them to neither,
it's rather more no than yes with me.
She'll go, Fagin.
- No, she won't, Fagin!
Can l help you, Miss?
- l'm looking for my little brother.
Nowwho would he be?
- Lovely little boy. Lovely manners.
Gentle as falling snow.
- We don't get many of those.
l think you'll be wanting Mr Fanscourt.
George. This here young lady is looking
for her brother. l think he's the one...
who fainted and managed to get away.
- Oh yeah, a gentleman took him away.
What gentleman? What gentleman?
- Well...
Lives in Pentonville l believe.
No wait, wait, wait.
His card's here somewhere.
Thank you, sir
(Music)
Mr Brownlow! Mr Brownlow!
There's something in him
that touched my heart, Mrs Bedwin.
l can't explain it.
- l feel the same, sir.
Who is he? What is he?
You knownothing of him.
He had a fever. What of that?
Bad people have fever sometimes.
l knew a man in Jamaica who was hanged
for murdering his master.
He had a fever 6 times.
- l knowthere is goodness in him.
How do you knowit?
- Goodness and innocence.
l knewit the first moment l sawhim.
- He'll deceive you! Let you down...
at the first opportunity like all your
other good and innocent causes.
lf that boy's good and innocent,
l'll eat my own hat, sir!
How do you feel my, dear?
- Very happy, sir.
l'm very grateful to you, indeed, sir.
- Good boy.
Have you given him any nourishment,
Bedwin? Any slops?
Not slops, sir. Broth.
- A couple of glasses of port wine...
would have done him a great deal
more good, wouldn't they, Sam?
My name is Oliver, Sir.
- Oliver?
Oliver what? Oliver Waters?
- No, sir, Twist. Oliver Twist.
Why did you tell the magistrate
your name was Waters?
l never told him so, sir.
- You did not?
No, sir.
You're not angry with me, are you, sir?
- No, no!
Queer name: Oliver Twist.
There are a great many books,
are there not, my boy?
There are a great number, sir.
l never saw so many.
Howwould you like to growup
a clever man, and write books? Hm?
Think l would rather read them, sir
- Wouldn't you like to be a book writer?
l think it would be a better thing
to be a bookseller, sir
You have said a very good thing!
Well, well!
We won't make an author of you while
there's an honest trade like...
bookselling or brick making to turn to.
- Are you going to send me away, sir?
No, my dear child, you need not be afraid
that l'm going to desert you,
unless you give me cause.
- l never will.
l hope not, because l feel strongly
disposed to trust you.
l don't have to wear those again.
- So you will, my dear.
There.
Hello. What's that?
- This is young Oliver Twist!
the bookseller's boy brought a package.
- Stop him! There's some books to go back.
ls that the boy with the fever?
- That's the boy!
No sign of him, sir.
- Oh dear, l'm very sorry for that.
Some books must be returned tonight.
- Why not send Oliver with them.
He'll be sure to deliver them safely.
- Yes, do let me take them,
if you please, sir! l'll run all the way.
You shall go, my dear.
Ask Mrs Bedwin to showyou the way.
And Oliver...
- Yes, sir?
Give the bookseller this.
Money l own him.
l won't be long, sir.
Howlong do you think it'll take him?
- You really expect him to come back?
You don't?
- With a L5 note in his pocket? No.
l do not. lf ever that boy returns
to this house, l'll eat my own head, sir.
And yours!
(Music)
Oh, my little brother!
lt's a miracle!
l've found him, l've found him!
Oh, Oliver, Oliver!
You're such a naughty boy...
to make me suffer such distress
on your account.
What's the matter, ma'am?
- He run away from his parents.
Hard-working respectable people. Joined
a set of thieves and bad characters.
Broke his mother's heart.
- The wretch! Go home you little brute.
l haven't got any parents!
l'm an orphan and l live in Pentonville!
Oh hear him howhe braze it out!
- What, young Oliver?
You come home to your poor mother.
- l don't belong to them!
l don't knowthem! Help! Help!
- Help, help? l'll give you ''help, help'',
you little wretch. And these books...
have you been stealing them, have you?
Eh? You little villain.
That's right you give it to him.
Only way to bring him to his senses!
l will, Missus!
Come with me you little wretch!
lt'll do him good.
Look at him, Fagin!
Look at his togs, Fagin!
Delighted to see you looking so well,
my dear! Why didn't you write, my dear,
and say you was coming?
We'd have got something warm for supper.
Hello, Fagin. What's that? That's mine!
- No, no, my dear. Mine, Bill, mine.
You shall have the books.
- lf that ain't mine and Nancy's...
then l'll take the boy back again.
- This is hardly fair, Bill.
Hardly fair, is it, Nancy?
- Hand over l tell you! Give it here,
you avarice old skeleton, give it here!
That's for our share of the trouble.
Not half enough neither! You may keep
the books if you're fond of reading.
lf you ain't, sell them!
- They're very pretty! Beautiful writing,
isn't it, Oliver?
- Send them back!
They belong to Mr Brandle. Send them back!
The books and the money. They'll think...
l've stolen them. Please send them back!
- The boy's right. You're right, Oliver,
you're right!
They will think you've stolen them!
Fetch the police! Fetch the police!
- Keep back your dog, Bill,
it'll tear the boy to pieces!
- Serve him right!
Fetch the police! Fetch the police!
- Step aside...
or l'll split your head against the wall.
- l don't care! That child shan't be...
torn down by the dog
unless you kill me first!
Bullseye! Get on! Bullseye!
(Music)
So you wanted to get away, my dear,
did you? Wanted to call for the police,
did you? We'll soon cure you of that!
l won't stand by and see this done, Fagin!
You've got the boy, what more do you want?
Keep quiet, Nancy, or l'll quieten you
for a good long time to come!
Oh you're a fine one for the boy
to make a friend of!
God Almighty help me, l am. He's a thief,
a liar, a devil, all that's bad...
from this night forth. Ain't that enough
for the old wretch without blows?
Come, come we must have civil words...
- Civil words?
Civil words, you old villain?
l thieved for you when l was a child...
not half as old as this!
- lt's your living.
Yes, and you're the wretch that drove me
to it and who will keep me doing it...
until l die.
Dodger, Charley, put Oliver to bed.
- Best to take them clothes off first.
They're too good to sleep in.
- Charley's right, this here suit...
cost more than fourpence ha'penny.
l never felt such lovely stuff.
l'm willing to lay odds that this is
the same stuff the Queen wears on Sundays.
Quick get him in, take it off.
Lift him up! Up he goes!
Get them shoes off!
Here's a something for your luncheon,
my dear.
Shall we have a little chat, Oliver?
Shall us?
l expect you'd welcome the sound...
of a human voice again, eh, my dear?
Do you knowwhat l consider
the greatest sin in the world, my dear?
lngratitude.
Yet for your guilty off. lngratitude
We took you in, we cherished you, if we
hadn't you might have died of hunger...
and how do you repay us? You run away,
you cry out for the police,
you cause us great anxiety and expense.
There was a lad once just like you,
l was a father to him and he ran away...
just like you and he went to the police
and can you guess howhe ended up?
They hanged him at the Old Bailey.
Certain evidence was made available,
not all of it precisely true,
but all of it necessary to provide
for my safety and that of my friends.
Poor boy! Hanged!
lt's a terrible thing, hanging, Oliver.
Dawn, the gallows,
the rope, the noose. And you don't always
have to be guilty, you see, Oliver?
They hang you for anything these days.
Because they're so very fond of hanging.
But if you do as you're told
you'll be very good friends here.
You must feel free
to walk about now, Oliver.
Yes, feel free.
Yo, Oliver?
- Yes?
l'd like you to assist me
in my toilet straightaway.
Will you do that for me, my man?
- Alright, l'll be glad of the company.
There's a good fellow. For a start-off
would you pan in my trotter cases?
ln plain English, clean my boots.
What a pity he ain't a prig.
- He don't knowwhat's good for him.
l suppose you don't knowwhat a prig is?
- Yes, l do it's a...
it's a thief. You're one, aren't you?
- Yes, l am.
And so we all are, down to the dog,
and he's the downiest one of the lot.
And the least given to peaching!
- He wouldn't so much as bark in a box...
for fear of committing himself.
- He's an out and out Christian he is!
Why don't you put yourself under Fagin?
You'll make a fortune out of hand.
Like the old gentleman in Pentonville.
Big house that. l had a peep at it l did.
Nice inside, was it?
- Yes, and l slept in a proper bed...
in my own room.
- Good stuff on the walls?
Yes, indeed.
- Put yourself under Fagin...
and you'll be able to retire to a property
just like that. And do the genteel.
No, he's scared he'll come to be scragged.
- l don't knowwhat that means.
lf you don't take pocket handkerchiefs
and watches, Ollie, some other cove will.
And you have the same right.
- To be sure, to be sure!
lt's your life in a nutshell, my dear.
Take the Dodger's word for it,
he understands the catechism of his trade.
Cabby!
l've come from Bill.
- For?
No harm.
- l don't believe it.
lf l could help you l would,
but l've not the power.
Now l've promised him you'll be good
and silent. lf you're not,
you'll only do yourself harm and me too.
Did he come quiet?
- Like a lamb.
Sit down!
And let me read you a lecture.
You knowwhat this is?
- Yes.
Well, then.
This is powder.
That here's a bullet.
And this is a little bit of an old hat
for watted.
Nowit's loaded.
- Yes, l can see it is.
lf you speak a word when you're out of
doors with me unless l speak to you,
this loading will go in your head
without notice. So,
if you do make up your mind to speak
without leave, says your prayers first.
The short and long of what you mean is:
if you're crossed by him,
you'll prevent him from ever telling
tales afterwards by shooting him...
through the head and you'll take
your chances swinging for it.
That's it! Women always put things
in the fewest words. Supper, Nancy!
Then a snoozer before starting.
Aha! My pal Bill!
The door's open, come in!
Don't make such a row!
Showus a glim, Toby.
- Barney, a glim! Showthe gentleman in!
Barney?
- Wake up first, if convenient!
Mr Sykes! Come in, sir, come in!
Bill, my boy! Glad to see you.
Who's this?
- Only the boy.
One of Mr Fagin's lads?
- Yeah. lt's time.
Right. Barbaras for me, Barney.
They're loaded.
- Good.
The Persuaders?
- Got them.
Keys. Centre bits.
Darkies.
Nothing forgotten? Ah!
He's alright.
(Music)
l can't, l can't!
- You will!
lt's Mr Brownlow's house.
Have mercy on me! Don't make me steal
from him! Have mercy on me!
Come here!
- For God's sake...
Shut it! Get up,
or l'll strewyour brains on the grass.
(Music)
l'm putting you through there.
Go to the front door and unfasten it.
l can't. There's a bolt on the top.
l can't reach it.
Well, stand on a chair or something.
Just do it.
(Music)
To the door.
To the front door, damn you!
Who's there?
Mrs Bedwin? ls that you?
Save me! Save me, save me for God's sake!
Help!
Help! Police!
Give him here.
Damnation howhe bleeds!
- ls he hit bad?
He's gotta be hit worse!
Give me a pistol.
- Why?
We've got to get rid of him
or he'll squeal. We've got to do him in...
here, here, down here by the river.
- Bill, Bill!
Bill!
- Help, help!
Bill?
- Help!
Snap.
Well! How are you, Fagy?
Scarce, scarce! Where's Bill?
He's bleeding!
- What happened?
All in good time. l can't talk business
until l've eat and drank.
That's it.
- Where's Bill?
Produce the sustenance if you please!
He scares!
The crack failed.
- l smelt that. For the last time...
l'm asking, where's Bill?
Put him to bed. Give him a nip of gin.
The boy was about to blow on us, Fagin.
He was seen.
- Seen? Who was see him?
Two old ones. He shouted out,
Bill lost his head, fired his pistol...
And hit the boy?
- l don't know. lt was two shots.
Only one was Bill's. We made a run for it.
l had hold of the boy and Bill fell.
Fell. Was he hurt?
- No! Last seen he was swimming to London.
Bullseye.
l told you not to bring a soul here,
and nowyou've brought the devil.
You said to fetch him! His fever's high,
he don't remember nothing.
You're not well, are you, Bill?
How do you feel today?
l'm as weak as water. Get us a drink.
What evil wind has blowed you here?
You, Bill, you. You said we need to speak!
What have you done with him? Where is he?
- Safe and sound.
The Dodger's minding him.
They're as close as Cain and Abel.
What about the boy, Bill?
We don't want anyone peaching on us,
do we? And as long as that boy's alive,
we're as good as hung.
- So what's to be done?
Nothing.
- Nothing?
Not till l'm better.
- Then what?
Then l'll do for him.
- How, Bill? Where?
Somewhere l'll find a river and drown him.
- The boy's weak, Bill.
He was wounded.
He can hardly stand let alone walk.
When he can walk tell me, l'll fetch him.
Now get out of here!
- Yes.
Yes.
Bill, you're right.
lt's for the best.
l'm burning up. Give me my physic,
where's my physic?
You look like a corpse come back
to life again. What's the matter?
Nothing.
What do you look at me so hard for?
What are you thinking of?
- Of many things, Bill. What's in that?
l'll tell you what it is. lf you haven't
caught the fever then there's...
omething more than usual in the wind,
and something dangerous too!
Give me my physic l say!
l ought to have cut...
her throat three months ago.
The fever's coming.
Here, it'll make you feel better.
Sit down.
Put on your own face or l'll alter it
so you won't knowit again.
(Music)
Wait.
- Yes?
Yes?
- Does Mr Brownlowlive here?
What do you want? Go round the back.
- l have information about Oliver Twist.
ls he alright? ls he safe?
Where is he?
- l will only talk to Mr Brownlow.
He's not here.
- The boy is innocent, tell him that.
Where is he?
- Safe.
But he may not be for long.
- Where is he?
Give Mr Brownlow a message. Tell him
to meet me on Sunday at midnight...
on London Bridge.
And if l'm not there...
tell him to come the next night
and the next. l'll be there. Tell him.
There, my dear, you look as good as new!
How do you feel?
- Tired, sir.
Well, it is long after midnight.
Shortly you'll sleep a good sleep.
But my meaning was,
how do you feel in yourself, Oliver?
Better, thank you, sir.
Only for the ache in my arm.
Come sit.
l have the very thing for such pains
as yours, my dear.
Undo the bandage.
Oh!
lt's a nasty wound!
But my magic will do the trick,
you'll see, my dear.
This remedy is as older than time,
yes my dear.
Older than time.
lt was handed down from father to son,
father to son and it comes from...
Who can say where?
Thank you, sir, thank you.
For your kindness.
l will always remember it.
Well, yeah.
Always? Yes, always, my dear.
But who knows howlong that will be?
An hour this side of midnight.
Dark and heavy it is too.
A good night for business this.
- Ah, what a pity, Bill, my dear,
there's no one quite ready to be done.
- So when will the boy be well enough
to go on his travels then?
- Like l say, Bill, in a day or two.
lt's a pity, for l'm in a humour too.
Does me good to hear you.
You're not yourself tonight, Bill, eh?
Quite like yourself.
- Well, l don't feel like myself
when you lay that wicked old claw
on my shoulder, so take it away!
Hello, Nance. And where's the girl
going to this time of night?
Not far.
- What answer's that? Where are you going?
l say ''not far.''
- And l say ''where?''
And l say ''nowhere!''
- Then l do, ''nowhere!'' Sit down!
l'm not well. l want a breath of air.
- Put your head out the window!
There's not enough there,
l want it in the street.
Then you won't have it!
There!
Now stop quietly where you are, will you?
Do you knowwhat you're doing?
- Do l knowwhat?
You talking me in that way?
- You drive me on to something desperate.
Nowlet me go! This minute, this instant!
- No!
Tell him to let me go, Fagin! lt'll be
better for him. Do you hear me?
l hear you.
And if l have to listen to you for half
a minute longer, the dog will have such...
a grip on your throat he'll be tearing
some of that screaming voice out!
What's come over you, what is it?
- Bill, let me go!
Let me go!
You don't knowwhat you're doing!
For only one hour!
- Cut my limbs off one by one...
if l don't find the girl stark raving mad!
Get up! Get up!
No!
And stay there!
- What a precious strange girl that is!
You may say that, Bill!
- Why do you think she took it into her...
head to go out tonight for, do you think?
- Obstinacy, l suppose.
l thought l'd tamed her of that
and she's as bad as ever.
l think she's got a touch of my fever
in her blood and it won't come out.
Well, if she's taking that way again,
l'll let her a little blood,
without troubling the doctor!
Well, now she's on the other tack!
Goodnight. ln two days, Bill...
come for the boy.
Bring him down. He should fall and break
his neck without anyone seeing it.
Showhim a light.
What is it, Nancy, dear?
The reason for all this?
What do you mean?
- That matter just now.
You have a friend in me Nance,
a staunch friend. You knowme well, Nance.
l knowyou well. Goodnight.
Trouble.
Dodger!
ls something up?
l...
l want you to do a piece of work for me
that requires great care and caution.
What is it?
l ain't going in no police office.
Not the smallest danger in it,
not the smallest. l want someone dodged.
Who? An old one?
- Ayoung one.
Who is she?
- One of us
Who? Nancy?
What's she been up to?
- l'm not sure she's been up to anything,
that's why l want her dodged.
l want to knowto whom she talkes.
l want to knowwhere she goes,
what she sees, what she says.
Nancy. l don't know.
She's a good 'un is Nancy.
A pound, my dear. One whole pound.
Mr Brownlow?.
Yes.
l'm afraid to speak to you here.
Come away! Followme!
This is far enough.
Why we can't speak up there?
l told you l'm afraid. l may be followed.
l am here because you told my housekeeper
that have some information...
concerning the boy Oliver Twist.
- So l have.
Tell me!
- He's being held by the devil.
And he's handing him over to another one
who means to...
l must knowmore.
ls it someone close to you?
Well, it is, well, it ain't...
- These men whoever they are,
must be delivered up by you.
- Bad as a life as he has led,
l've led a bad life too
and l will not turn upon him.
The other...
Fagin. He has the boy.
- Fagin?
Find Fagin. - Where is he?
Spitalfields.
That's all l'll say. l've said too much.
No one must ever knowwho told you.
Promise?
- l promise. Tomorrow l will put...
the matter before the police.
- No! You must do it tonight.
Just say Fagin and the traps will know...
- The traps?
The police.
- What can l do to serve you?
Nothing. You can do nothing.
l'm past all hope, indeed
Take this as a reward.
- No, l've not done this for money.
God Bless You. Goodnight!
Never, never say who told you.
You ok, chief?
What a shame it is! With his face he could
pick old ladies pockets in churches.
His face could be a fortune.
Are you changing your mind?
- No.
No. What has to be done has to be done.
- Fagin!
What's got into you Dodger?
- l have to see Fagin alone.
No, you can speak in front of Bill.
- No, l can't.
Yes, you can speak, Dodger, tell us!
- Nancy...
What about Nancy?
- l had him dodge Nancy.
What do you mean?
- Tell us, Dodger, you followed her?
Yes, to London Bridge.
- And what? What at London Bridge?
She met an old 'un, a gentleman, and...
- And...
Speak, will you!
- She peached!
She told him Fagin had Oliver!
And the old man wants to go to the traps.
Now, tonight.
Let me go! let me out!
Don't speak to me, it's not safe!
You won't be too violent, Bill?
Quick, boys! Every second the traps
could be at the door!
Quick! Quick! Quick!
(Music)
Bill? What's the matter?
Bill, why do you look like that at me?
lt's enough light for what l've got to do!
- What have l done?
Speak to me!
- You know!
You were watched tonight.
Every word you said was heard.
l never said your name, Bill. Never!
Never! Bill, Bill...
God have mercy!
Nance?
(Music)
Hello, Fagy! Hello, lads!
What's the news, Tony, what's the news?
- l have it here, Fagin.
lt's all in ''The Chronicle''.
You're in it. Bill's in it,
Oliver's in it.
- ''The Chronicle''? Fancy that!
You're famous, Fagin!
- Read it!
''More information has reached
a correspondent concerning the foul...
and bestial murder that took place
in Spitalfields and which has shocked...
and appalled the citizens of London.
lt is believed that the victim,
a young woman, nowidentified as Nancy,
was brutally beaten to death
by one William Sykes,
a well-known dangerous villain.
The motive is as yet unclear,
but your correspondent has learned...
that the murdered woman had informed
on her associate and on an...
infamous fence, Fagin,
who is nowwanted for the abduction
of a young boy Oliver Twist.
Neither Fagin nor Sykes are presently
in custody, but the police are engaged...
on searching for them
throughout the city and beyond.
Sykes, according to the police
is usually accompanied...
by a fierce white dog.''
How about that, eh?
(Bill whistles)
Come! Come back here!
We're going back to London.
l have people to speak to.
Get to France.
Damn me we'll risk it.
Bullseye?
Don't you hear me when l whistle?
Have you gone deaf or something?
Come here.
l ain't going to harm you.
Come here, Bullseye.
Stop it.
Bullseye!
Bullseye! Bullseye!
Get back here! Get back here!
Damned!
lt's his dog! lt's his dog!
Here, boy! Here!
There is a child in danger,
lnspector Blather, but you only seem...
interested in apprehending this man Sykes.
Your concern should be for the safety...
of the boy.
- Allowme to say, sir;
this is our usual way of doing business.
My thinking is this...
lf we get Sykes we get Fagin
and if we get Fagin...
Look, sir, we found the dog!
Are we going to sit here all night
waiting for the traps to find us?
He's right, we should do another flit.
(Knocking)
The traps!
What?
- lt's him!
Don't let him in!
- We must.
Go on!
Don't leave us in the dark!
(Music)
Damn you all!
Have you nothing to say to me?
Only safe for us to stop here, Bill.
- lf it's safe for you it's safe for me.
ls it...
The body, is it buried?
(Bullseye's barking)
Dodger, let him in quick.
Dodger! Do as l say!
Don't come near me, you monster!
You're my witnesses,
l'm not afraid of him.
And if they come here after him l'll give
him up. l'll tell them you're here!
He may kill me if he likes, but if l'm
here l'll give him up, if he was to be...
boiled alive, so l would!
- What, you young...
Take your hands off me!
Help, he's here! He's here, quick!
Help! Come on please!
Damn you all!
Do your worst, l'll cheat you yet!
Bill, no! He's our bargaining tool!
- Not yours, Fagin, mine!
Hold your fire, men!
- l'll let the boy go!
l'll let him drop! Don't shoot at me
or l'll let him go!
(Music)
We must give chase, sir!
Grab it! Grab it!
(Music)
(Mrs Bedwin)
Oliver! Oliver!
Oliver!
Here he is, sir.
- Come along my boy,
Mr Grimwig has something to say to you.
Do the honours, Mrs Bedwin.
- Nowthen young man, l confess...
l misjudged you. Truth to tell,
l was afraid your benefactor...
would make me eat my hat!
But he's a good friend...
and has pardoned me.
- And one for Oliver.
And you too.
- Oh l don't know as l should, sir.
You must!
- So l'll take the liberty,
if you'll allowme to salute you.
To Sam Waters.
Oliver Twist.
- Oliver Twist.
To Oliver Twist, yes
Oliver! My child, what's the matter?
Why are you so sad?
Are you certain, Oliver,
that you wish to go through with this?
Yes, sir.
Yes?
ls the young gentleman to come too, sir?
lt's not a sight for children, sir.
lt is not, indeed, my friend.
But this child has seen this man...
in the full career of his success
in villainy and it is his wish,
even at the cost of some pain and fear,
that he should see him now.
18!
(Fagin prays)
Don't be frightened. Fagin?
- That's me, an old man, my lord.
Avery old man.
- There's somebody here wants to see you.
What right have they to butcher me?
- Speak to him now, quick if you please.
He gets worse as time goes on.
- Fagin?
You are kind to me.
- l'll be kind to you.
l'll be kind again.
l'm not afraid.
- Oliver!
Let me whisper to you.
Get me my box, Oliver,
with my pretty things
for my old age in.
They're yours, yours!
- Yes, yes.
But shall we say a prayer together first.
Say only one upon your knees with me
and we can talk all morning.
Oliver, Oliver, you can say...
l'll give give you all the pretty things.
All yours.
Oh God, forgive this wretched man!
- That's right, that's right.
That'll help us on, if... if... if...
l shake and tremble
as we pass the gallows,
don't... don't say goodbye carry on.
Down, down, down.
Have you some more to say?
- Nothing more.
You better leave him.
- Pastor, pastor, pastor...
Pastor, pastor, pastor...
(Music)
Aceasta subtitrare a fost ajustata folosind programul Time Adjuster.
www.geocities.com/irekz/TA