[alarm beeping]
[birds singing]
[woman on phone]
Laura, it's fine, I'll see you
at the office.
I'll be there soon.
-[man] Morning, Chip.
-Hey, man!
-Morning, Laura.
-Morning, Frank.
Oh! I heard you pulled out
all the stops to save
the Peterson account.
They'll have to make you
partner now.
I hope so. There's a lot
of changes I'd like to make.
Like getting you that raise
you should've gotten last year.
Congratulations, Laura.
You did it.
Oh, I'd like to review the
contract one last time, Fiona.
Laura, it's perfect,
they've signed it. It's done.
-They've signed it? Already?
-Yes, it's time to celebrate.
So as your boss,
I am ordering you to brag.
Tell everyone how you did it.
Well, Mr. Peterson might run
an international corporation,
but he's a local
businessman at heart.
I explained the opportunity
in local expansion
and persuaded him not to sell.
Local expansion worth
250 million.
[man] Wow.
[employees applauding]
He wanted what was best
for the community.
I just helped him to see that.
Laura, you're always
so modest.
It's all thanks
to my lucky charm.
Because the long hours
and late nights
had nothing to do with it.
On an entirely
different subject,
what do you know
about Graham Finley?
Graham Finley,
billionaire, highly educated,
international property
developer,
terrible at coconut toss.
I told you that I grew up
in Sapphire Cove until I was 12.
Your idyllic childhood
on a tropical island.
How could I forget?
I grew up with the Finley's.
His grandson Chip was
my best friend.
We lost touch though.
-Ah. That explains it.
-Explains what?
Why there's a billionaire
in my office.
Waiting for you.
[Fiona] Mr. Finley.
Laura Price.
My goodness. All grown up.
Mr. Finley, it's
so wonderful to see you again.
I remember when you
and my grandson
filled my Mercedes with seaweed.
So it's a bit late
for "Mr. Finley" now.
Please.
Well, I've heard
all about your achievements
from Mrs. Wilde here.
The valedictorian.
A portfolio
of high-profile clients.
A promotion waiting
in the wings.
You've certainly made your mark
since leaving Sapphire Cove.
Well, it's not as
impressive as your legacy
but I'm not finished yet.
That's the Laura I remember.
Ambitious and determined.
You may not have noticed, Laura,
but I've gotten old.
I'm 85 soon.
85 is a significant
milestone, Mr. Finley.
You see, I am CEO
of the company
until the day I choose
to step down or...
Or your 85th birthday,
whichever comes first.
Whichever comes first.
The mandatory
retirement clause.
Retirement clauses
are notoriously difficult
to outmaneuver.
Oh, it's much too late
for any of that.
My son was not a good fit.
But it's not too late
for my grandson.
I want to name Chip my successor
because it's my last chance to
keep my business in the family.
So he needs to sign on the
dotted line before I turn 85.
Laura can draw up
a contract immediately.
Good, because I need
you to take it to him
and get him to sign it.
We don't have a lot of time here
and he can be a little stubborn.
You're the only one
he's ever listened to.
She'd be delighted to take
the contract to Chip.
Of course. Where exactly
is Chip living these days?
Well...
Sapphire Cove?
Now? I can't go now.
It's been forever.
I haven't spoken to Chip
since I was a kid.
I didn't even know
what he looks like.
Well, don't over
complicate it.
You fly over, find Chip,
get the contract signed
and you'll be back
in a few days.
Fiona, I have
so much work to do,
I'm going to be working late
as it is.
Why don't you take Owen?
You two can spend some time
together before the big day.
Actually, we decided to push
the date back again.
Again?
I know... We've been so busy.
Besides, I thought that
I would hear about
the partnership soon.
We're still in talks.
It's down to you and Simon.
-Simon?
-Mmm-hm.
He brings in big clients.
That means big money.
But what about my local
business plan?
Yeah, yeah, they loved it.
More face-to-face time
with clients,
protect small businesses.
They ate it up.
But at the end of the day,
money talks.
Graham came to you for a reason.
He really thinks
you can persuade Chip.
Bringing in a client
like Graham Finley
might just be the edge you need.
-Do you think so?
-I know so.
Besides, there are worse places
to end up
than on a tropical island.
Fine print is my specialty.
Yeah, alright, fantastic.
Honey, I am so sorry.
I'm so snowed under right now.
What were we talking about?
We were talking
about Sapphire Cove.
Yes, yes, your hometown.
I haven't been there
since I was a kid.
But this work thing
kind of popped up
and I thought that maybe
we could go there together.
Once I get this contract signed
then we can just relax for once
and it might be nice.
I don't know, honey. I could
really use the extra hours
around the office right now.
I just have to go there
and get Chip Finley to sign
this contract in person
and then if all goes well,
I might get the whole
Finley account.
You will get the whole
This is the big leagues now,
honey.
Look, I know you love
all that charity work
you're doing, but...
Giving smaller clients more
time isn't exactly charity work.
It's what legal representation
is meant to be about.
Honey, remember, we're sharks.
And think of this Finley
account as your prey.
We are always hunting.
Keeping our eye on the prize.
And then when
it's in our sights...
...that's when we pounce.
Well, let's hope
that Chip Finley
isn't too hard to hunt down.
You'll be great.
[pilot] Welcome
to Sapphire Cove
where the local time
is 8:02 a.m.
Welcome to Sapphire Cove.
If you make your way
down to the pier,
our captain is waiting
to take you to the hotel.
The captain?
After you.
[Laura] Well, this is one way
to get around.
Sure beats rush-hour traffic.
-First time to the island?
-Uh... No.
But it's been a very long time.
Well, better late than never.
Let me guess. Lawyer.
Oh! That obvious?
Not everybody gets so dressed
up to come on vacation.
Right. Well, my turn.
You must be... the captain.
[scoffs] Lucky guess.
-Dude...
-What?
-Your shirt!
-Oh! Oh.
[Chip]
You could've told me earlier!
There we go.
[man] Welcome to the Royal
Hotel. Mind your step.
[woman] Welcome. Sparkling wine?
[mumbling]
Hi. How are you?
So have a good trip.
If you can, treat yourself
to a pair of sandals.
I hear they're much more
comfortable than heels.
I might just do that.
Thank you.
And if you need someone to
take you around the island,
we do offer guided tours.
Actually, you might be
able to help me...
-Yoo-hoo.
-What?
Anybody home?
-Welcome drink, ma'am?
-Oh. Thank you.
Take the bag!
[Laura] Thank you.
When you book at
the front desk ask for Chip.
Chip?
[woman 2] This way, please.
Your bag will be delivered
straight to your room.
"Dear Laura... A little taste of
the high life. Enjoy. Fiona."
Where's the Wi-Fi password?
-[knock at the door]
-[Gem] Laura?
-I haven't seen you in so long.
-Gem!
When I saw your name
on the reservation,
I couldn't believe it.
You came back.
I did. It's been forever.
Gosh, look at you all
fancy and grown-up.
Oh, yes, well,
as assistant manager
of the Royal Hotel, please
do not hesitate to let me know
if there is anything I can do to
make your stay more enjoyable.
Oh, I love this suite, by
the way. It is my favorite.
It's magnificent. I mean,
this whole resort is incredible.
Oh, that's right.
You didn't live here
when it was getting built.
Well, it's all courtesy
of Finley developments.
[giggles] We have
so much to catch up on.
There is a ton to do
around the island
and of course Graham's birthday
celebration's this weekend.
It is the event of the summer
and I have my eye on
the general manager position.
So if all goes well...
You'll get a promotion?
Ah, that's exciting.
You are staying longer
than three days, right?
This is just a short trip.
Oh, so you're not here
for Graham's party?
Actually, I'm here
to see Chip.
Oh! Oh.
What does "oh" mean?
You don't have a contract
with you, do you?
Maybe.
-Let's get you a coconut.
-Oh!
[Gem] Do you remember how Chip
was when we were kids?
As a 12-year-old? Sure.
Stubborn, sweet.
Always took it badly
when he lost at coconut toss.
I'm sure he's grown up
since then.
Eh...
I did see him on the boat
from the airport
and he looked pretty
grown up to me.
-Mmmm,
-He didn't recognize me though.
You two always had
a thing for each other.
-Oh, please, we were 12.
-I know!
Anyway, I think you'll find
the new Chip and the old Chip
have a lot in common.
What's your strategy?
Well, I guess if he's the old
Chip then I better be
the old Laura.
And if he still doesn't
recognize me
then we've got an advantage.
Should we have some fun with
him like old times?
Definitely.
[Chip] Come on. You got this.
Big throw.
Ooh! That's too bad.
That's too bad. Guess it's my
turn. All right. You'll get it.
-Hey, Chip.
-Hey. Oh!
Showing the legal eagle
around, are you, Gem?
I got good news for you.
You're in luck.
Just in time to see me beat
Karavi at coconut toss again!
Can't wait.
He's certainly the
same old Chip.
Yep.
You've lost your heels
already. Island life suits you.
Let's do this.
All right. Here we go.
[indistinct]
-[Gem] Woo!
-Boom. All right.
Thanks very much, thank you.
Thank you very much.
You ready for this?
I guess we should go
get a contract signed.
Let's do it.
You win some, you lose some.
Good game, buddy.
Oh, you must be here
for that island tour.
She's not here for a tour.
Actually, your grandfather
is my client.
He asked me to bring you this.
Ha-ha.
Well, that's too bad.
I'm sorry you came all
this way,
but I have no interest in
becoming the next CEO
of Finley Developments.
You sure I can't convince
you to just read it?
Look, I'm sure you're
very good at what you do,
but if all those lawyers
my granddad sent over
can't get me to even
look at it,
I'm afraid you're
wasting your time.
Thanks for coming.
Mmm? What's this... what's this
game you're playing here?
This game?
Only the greatest
game in Sapphire Cove.
This is coconut toss.
Why, you want to take on the
undefeated champion himself?
Oh, I mean, that's tempting,
but this looks way too
complicated for me.
All right, well, suit yourself.
Enjoy the island.
I tell you what,
I'll make you a deal.
I will play you at coconut toss
and if I win,
you have to hear me out.
And if I win?
Oh, I will tear up this
contract right in front of you.
[laughs] Oh, you
got yourself a deal.
-All right.
-I'll set it up.
OK.
Laura, Chip's gotten really
good at this game.
Good thing I got
my lucky charm.
So the rules are simple,
but the game gets a little
harder as you go along.
You hit a coconut, you go again.
You miss, the other person
gets a shot.
Whoever hits the most
wins the game.
So ladies first. It's only fair.
Ooh.
-[Laura] Whoo!
-Wow.
Good... good shot.
I mean, I heard that the first
one is the easiest.
-Mmm, good shot.
-So...
[Laura] Yes.
-Beginners luck?
-Yeah, I'll say.
[crowd exclaims]
[Chip] Nice shot!
-Who is this girl?
-You'll see.
-Oh! Yeah!
-[applause]
Whoa!
Ladies and gentlemen,
has the unbeaten Chip Finley
finally met his match?
The question on everyone's mind
is will the newcomer
topple the undefeated Chip
Finley's coconut-toss reign?
Would you stop?
[Gem]
If you can't stand the heat,
get out of the fire.
Hey, you, are you sure
that you have not played
this game before?
You know what?
I might have played it once or
twice as a kid. Can't be sure.
You're a lawyer, right?
Is it too late to renegotiate
the bet?
I'm thinking if I lose... Hmm...
I hear you out at a candlelit
dinner under the stars.
-[chuckles]
-Yeah?
Well, I'm not sure that
my fiancé would appreciate that.
Ah-ha. So that
would be a no, right?
Well, no pressure, then.
I mean, you know, big shot and
all. So don't miss.
[cheering and applause]
That's not possible.
Nobody ever hits that shot.
-Undefeated champion, hey?
-I don't understand.
The only person that ever
defeated me at this game is...
Laura? Laura Price?
[both] Surprise.
-I'll have my people
talk to your people.
-Oooh!
No, it's... Oh, that thing
I said. Hang on. Wait a minute.
Hey. Hold up.
Just thought I'd say sorry
for that whole candlelit dinner
with me thing.
-That's embarrassing.
-It's fine. We're old friends.
It's nice to see you again.
You too. Look at you.
Miss Big City Lawyer.
Guess those mock court battles
with me came in handy, huh?
Ha, huge help!
Along with, you know,
a four-year
undergraduate degree,
followed by law school
and then passing the bar exam,
but this is certainly
where it all started.
Your parents must be proud.
They are. Though they
want me to become partner.
Well, Dad does.
-Is he a nice guy?
-My dad?
I mean the guy who put
that ring on your finger.
What did you say his name was?
Ah... Owen. He's really
great. He's a nice guy.
We met at
a Bar Association dinner.
Ooh, power couple, huh?
You could say that.
What about you? Anyone special?
There was once but it's...
It didn't work out.
I guess my expectations
were too high.
-How so?
-Oh, I don't know.
I guess I thought the person
I'd end up with would be
like my best friend.
It's stupid.
Anyway, my work keeps me here
and as you can imagine,
there are not that many
fish in the sea.
Well, you do have a boat.
A captain can sail anywhere
to find love, right?
Yeah, look, the whole
captain thing is really just to
keep the bills paid.
You're worried
about paying your bills?
You do know
that your grandfather
is on the cover
of Business Collective?
It's important to me
that I make my own
way despite my last name.
Besides, I got a side project
that's important to me.
A side project?
I'm building homes for people
who would otherwise
not have a place to call home.
Right, so you are continuing
the family trade!
Not exactly.
It's a charity thing
so it doesn't
have the same profit margin
as Finley developments
would like.
Not quite, it's not worlds
apart, though.
You sure you have no
interest in becoming CEO?
I've thought about it. A lot.
And the answer is no.
Are you sure?
'Cause it sounds like
a life-changing opportunity.
Exactly.
Well, I'll go arrange my
flight home, then.
All right! Forget that.
What are you doing tonight?
-Emails, I imagine.
-No, not anymore.
So Gem's parents are
coming to dinner tonight
and you have to come.
Come on!
If Mrs. B knew you were here
and I didn't invite you to
dinner, she'd never forgive me.
So you do want to take me
to dinner?
No, no, this is strictly
professional.
This is professional.
But hey, if you want to break
Mrs. B's heart, I mean...
So you'd tell on me?
You told Mrs. B that
I broke her kitchen
window back in the day.
You did break her
kitchen window.
-Yeah, but I was gonna fix it.
-With what? You were nine.
I had a whole plan involving
duct tape and cardboard.
It was gonna be great.
It was like a MacGyver thing.
All right. Well, I better
go back to the hotel
and send some emails then if
I'm going to make it to dinner.
-You're gonna come?
-But this contract conversation
is not over, Chip Finley.
Not by a long shot.
OK, I don't think we need
to bore everyone
with all these details.
You should have seen
his face, Mom,
he was shocked when she
beat him at coconut toss.
Oh, Chip, how could you
not recognize Laura?
You two were inseparable
when you were kids!
She's changed a lot since
I last saw her.
-Here she is.
-[gasps]
-Laura!
-Mrs. B! Mr. B! You look great.
-Great to see you, Laura.
-Oh, hello.
My girl, I'm not sure I've ever
seen you with your hair brushed.
That was so long ago.
Theodore, hi,
this is my friend Laura.
The welcome speech was scheduled
to begin five minutes ago.
Right. Of course. I have the
perfect speech all planned out.
Tick tickety tock.
That's my boss. I better
bring you to your table.
Let me know if you need
anything, OK?
Drinks are on me.
-This is the best bit.
-Good evening, everyone.
Welcome to Drift Restaurant.
The sky is putting on quite
the show for us this evening.
Over to the east,
we have the constellation
of the beautiful
maiden Andromeda.
Legend has it
she was rescued
from a sea monster by the brave
warrior Perseus, son of Zeus.
After turning
the monster to stone,
they rode away on his
white-winged horse Pegasus
and lived happily ever after.
And the gods placed
them in the night sky
as a reminder to all of us
to follow our hearts.
Enjoy your dinner.
[applause]
Just beautiful.
Your drinks.
Oh. Thank you.
[Chip] Thanks.
So, Laura, are you here for
Graham's birthday celebrations?
[Chip] Oh, Laura's
a corporate type now,
she's only interested in the
bright lights in the big city.
I can still see that
wild child in there.
Oh, well, Chip is correct.
I do have to head back
to San Francisco right away.
Well, can't we convince
you to stay?
It would be just like old times.
I would love to stay
but this is a work trip and
I need Chip to sign a contract.
-Are we talking about a
Finley Developments contract?
-Mm-hmm.
Well, good luck
trying to get him to sign.
-That is exactly why I'm here.
-[Mr. B] Oh?
But Chip doesn't want to be
the CEO of his grandfather's
billion-dollar business,
so... going to have to
cut my trip short.
Contract and a guilt trip.
Lucky me!
Think of it as a two-for-one
deal just for you.
How's everything?
Oh, just like old times,
Laura is telling on me.
Of course she is.
It's so nice to have you here.
I wish I could join you all
but my boss is
breathing down my neck.
He's already criticizing
my flower arrangements.
Tick tickety tock!
So are we ready to order?
[indistinct chatter]
[phone line rings]
[Owen on phone]
You've reached Owen.
If you want to email me at
owen.fredericks
@gcmandassociates.com,
that would be fantastic.
Hi, honey. Just checking in.
It's late there.
I hope you're not working
too hard.
Anyway, just thinking of you
and I'm missing you.
[phone chimes]
-Owen?
-[Fiona] Laura. How's it going?
Oh, Fiona! Hi. Well, get this.
So apparently Graham's
been trying
to get Chip to sign this
contract for years with no luck
so this might be a little
bit harder than we thought.
Could I extend my trip
by a few days?
Get in the game, Laura.
The partners are thrilled that
Graham has come to us for help
but you know as well as I do
that if this goes well,
he'll bring in
the entire account.
You know, Graham champions
small businesses,
perhaps we could present
my local business plan to him.
Just focus on getting Chip to
sign that contract.
[Laura] Right. Yes.
Maybe there is a different angle
that I can work.
[Fiona]
I really don't care how you
do it, just get it done.
Keep me updated. Good luck.
I'm gonna need
more than just luck.
Sapphire Cove Town Hall.
Last night was so nice.
I really don't want
her to go yet.
-She only just got here.
-I'm sorry, Gem.
I'm not signing my life away
just so you can keep her here.
Can't you just pretend
you're interested
so we can catch up properly?
I'm just as happy
to see her as you are.
But she's not here to catch up,
Gem, she's here to work.
So give her some work to do!
She spent all
evening on her phone,
she's probably got plenty
to keep her busy. Give me that.
-I mean work that keeps
her here.
-Huh?
You are not leaving tomorrow.
-Chip.
-Hey.
I've been looking over your
charity's business records.
Where on earth
did you get those?
Do you remember
Penny Michaels?
Braces, pigtails,
allergic to oranges?
Well, guess who works
at Sapphire Cove Town Hall?
That can't be legal.
Look, you have done
an incredible job
with your charity.
But have you considered
what you could do
with the resources
at Finley Developments?
Hmm.
Come on,
you would be unstoppable.
-Unstoppable? Please.
-Yeah.
My father spent years trying
to convince the company
to try something new before
giving up and moving away.
He realized that those suits
are only in it for themselves.
There's probably something in
that contract that makes me
a little more than a puppet.
You haven't even read
the contract.
I have not.
You might be surprised at how
much freedom you would have.
[Chip] I doubt it.
You know what?
No, you're right. I'm sorry.
That would be a crazy amount
of work,
running a company and a charity?
I mean, you're already
busy enough as it is
here with your little tugboat
and playing coconut toss.
All right, hang on a second.
I could run Finley developments
if I wanted to.
I just don't want to. It's true.
In fact, you remember that
seashell jewelry business
I used to have?
Those sold like hot cakes.
I mean, sure, that was
some good pocket money,
but I think you
might find that being CEO is
a little bit more time consuming
than collecting sea shells.
All right, just because
I know how to relax,
doesn't mean I can't work hard.
I'm not a workaholic like you,
but I can throw on a suit
and get things done.
I look great in a suit.
Probably.
I'm not a workaholic.
You've been here less
than 24 hours
and all you've done
is send emails.
In fact, you're the only
person that I know
to ever cut a vacation short to
go back to work.
-That is not true! I have fun.
-Really?
-Yeah.
-Like what?
-Like I read books.
-Ooh! Books!
What kind of books?
Like, books about justice
and great battles
between right and wrong.
Do you mean law books?
-Yes.
-That's what I'm talking about.
[chuckles triumphantly]
Law books! You know what?
I'll read that contract
the minute you remember
how to have fun.
Is that a deal?
What?
I'll relax. Sure. I'll lie
by the pool. I'll get a tan.
I'll even leave my phone alone.
You read that contract.
-Yeah, OK, I was just...
-Come on!
[exclaims] One page.
Excuse me?
I will read one page for
every fun thing that you do.
OK? You know what?
I'm not just talking about
like, regular like,
lying-by-the-pool fun.
I'm talking
about real activities
like hiking and snorkeling
and horseback riding.
-I am not horseback riding.
-Oh, you're not?
Oh, well,
that is a deal breaker.
We tried. Gem, we tried.
Don't tell me I didn't try.
Laura, this is perfect.
Come on.
OK!
What's that?
OK, I will ride a horse.
But I will not sign
a liability waiver.
You got a deal.
[woman on phone]
Mm-hm. What's next?
We are going to keep
article 3.1
and we'll replace articles 4.7
and 12.2, thank you.
And could you send through
my updated itinerary?
-[woman] Sure.
-[knock at door]
Hold on. Come in.
Ready?
Now is not a great time.
Oh. Here I was thinking you
wanted me to read that contract.
But if it's not a great time
then I guess...
Did I say "not a great time"?
I meant now is the perfect time.
[Chip] Oh, sounds perfect.
[chuckles]
I'm sorry, Kelly. I'm gonna
have to cut this short.
[Chip] All right,
let's go snorkeling.
Are you sure this is safe?
I don't think my travel
insurance covers snorkeling.
Seriously? What's happened
to you? It's perfectly safe.
We used to do this all the time.
When we were 12.
I don't go in the ocean very
much anymore, Chip.
There's no waves.
There's no sharks.
It's not jellyfish season
and the pirates called
to say they're having a barbecue
today so you're safe. Come on.
For the contract.
♪ She takes me back
when I feel the sun ♪
♪ And I find myself singing
the same old song ♪
♪ And I find myself singing ♪
♪ The same old song ♪
♪ Yeah, it all comes back when
it starts to feel like summer ♪
That was incredible!
That coral reef is so beautiful.
Did you see all those
tropical fish?
[sighs] I never get to do
stuff like this.
That's what we call that
island magic, remember?
You don't get to snorkel
in San Francisco?
Not without catching
hypothermia.
I've missed this island.
It missed you.
Strawberry?
Thanks.
You're gonna read
that contract now?
Uh-huh.
Oh, well, you might
want to wipe your hands.
Oh.
[chuckles] Really?
I read, you relax.
That's the deal.
Got it. Relaxing.
[Chip] See, this is what I'm
talking about.
Some of these suits
have spent so long in the office
they've forgotten what
it's like in a work site.
We need more engineers
in the boardroom.
We need more engineers?
Are you gonna sign it?
No. No.
I mean, "they," obviously.
I'm just doing this for Laura.
We need to humor her.
Uh-huh. So what's your
plan for tomorrow?
I need to think of more
activities to do.
Do you think she'd
enjoy fishing?
She used to like fishing, right?
Sure. Lawyers are known
for their fishing skills.
Or hiking?
Maybe you're going above
and beyond
to keep a certain
someone interested.
Ha-ha, funny. No, Gem,
it's not that.
She is doing her part
so I am doing mine. That's all.
It was you that told me
to keep her here.
-I'm doing this for you!
-OK.
And, you know, this is for
old time's sake. That's all.
Sure. For old time's sake.
[Laura] We never get weather
like this in San Francisco.
-I know. It's so nice.
-[phone buzzes]
Ooh! I just got the itinerary
through. And it's official.
I will be here
for Graham's birthday.
Oh! Please never leave.
We have to get you a dress.
Yeah, I mean, how are the plans
for the birthday celebration
coming along?
I'm getting there.
But there's still a lot to do.
I just want everything
to be perfect for Graham.
Although, I am more
worried about Theodore.
He's impossible to please.
-Hmm.
-Hey, hey! I got a blast
from the past for you.
Wow! Where did you
find that thing?
The old shed! And I picked
out the perfect fishing spot.
I hope you have
your lucky charm
because you're gonna
need it to catch a fish.
-Lucky charm?
-Oh, nothing. Let's go.
This way.
[sighs]
How long is
this gonna take?
You're the worst.
You got somewhere better to be?
Well, I don't have high
hopes for lunch.
Well, at least you're
off your phone.
[phone chimes]
Thank you.
So is this your standard
Monday morning?
Yeah, kinda, I guess.
Why, this isn't part of your
regular routine?
I would be on my third
coffee by now.
My job is more of a 7:00 till
7:00 then a 9:00 till 5:00.
Do you love it?
Being a lawyer?
Yeah. I do.
Although, I wish I could
help people more.
I want to be able
to pick my own clients
and choose the cases I take on.
What cases would you choose
if it were up to you?
-Well, don't laugh.
-Scout's honor.
I want to help
small businesses
who need extra support
but they can't always afford it.
Sounds kinda hard in
a big commercial law firm.
Yeah, it isn't easy which
is why I'm working so hard
to become partner so that
I can call all of the shots.
Well, some of them at least.
That's the Laura I know.
Ambitious. I like it.
Wow. You're right. This is
really spectacular.
Oh, come on.
I'm sure you and Owen have
plenty of spectacular moments.
Yeah, I mean, we don't
really do stuff like this.
Like what?
Like have fun?
No, we have a serious
relationship.
We talk about legal precedents
and make financial plans,
and, you know, grown-up stuff.
I'm happy for you.
You love him and that is
the beginning...
And the end of everything.
I love that quote.
[reel clicks]
Chip!
-[reel spins]
-Get it. Get it. Come on!
-We've got something!
-You got it?
-Yeah.
-Reel it in. Let's go.
There you go.
Theodore. What do you think
of the new menu board?
I thought I'd spruce it
up before the party.
You don't like it?
Needs more flowers.
More flowers?
Yeah, I can do that.
-Fish and chips for lunch?
-Sure. If you're cooking.
-[gasps]
-Chip.
Tickety tock!
Hope you're ready
for your next adventure.
Meet you in 30 minutes.
Chip, I don't have
time for an adventure.
You always used to have time
for adventures, come on.
Let's make it an hour.
I need to make some phone calls.
Yeah, I do have a contract
I have to not read.
OK, fine.
Where should I meet you?
-[exclaims] By the palm trees!
-What palm trees, Chip?
You'll find them.
That's Chip for ya.
[phone line rings]
-[Fiona] Laura!
-Fiona. Hi.
I gotta be quick
but I have a plan.
It's a little unorthodox and I'm
not sure how long it will take,
-but I'm making progress.
-[Fiona] Good!
Could you report back
to the partners
and let them know that
I will make this happen.
[horse whinnies]
[Fiona] Laura?
-Horses?
-Contract?
-Fiona, I have to go.
-[Fiona] But we need to...
Princess Andromeda,
meet Pegasus.
Uh-huh. So that must make you
Perseus, son of Zeus?
Yeah, but I'm really
only a demigod.
-Oh. Hello.
-Come on.
Come on, buddy.
-[Laura] So, tell me something.
-[Chip] Hmm?
[Laura] Why on earth
did Graham think
that I could make you
change your mind?
[Chip] Don't know.
You know Granddad.
Once he gets something in
his head, it's hard to shake it.
I guess he wants
what's best for me,
it's just he thinks I'm wasted
running my charity.
You two are both as stubborn
as each other.
Why didn't you
ever leave the island?
-Seriously?
-You know what I mean.
Why didn't I go chasing
my dreams in the big city?
Sure. Why not see what
the world has to offer?
You forgot what it
was like growing up.
I was just the lonely kid
in the big house
and my dad was away
more often than not.
You left, Gem went to school
on the mainland.
It seemed like everyone
was just leaving.
You know, staying on the island
is like the only thing I felt
like I could control, you know?
I didn't realize things were
that hard for you.
Yeah, well...
This island, the people,
it's made me who I am.
I want to get back to that
however I can.
Oh, hey, do you see this
triangle of land up there?
I'm trying to get to the bottom
of who owns it.
The land rights are ancient
and the council won't release it
until we find the landowner's
relatives,
which is impossible
so there's still a few families
on the island who desperately
need homes.
So I was hoping
to get that land for them.
I love that.
I hope you understand
I have obligations here
that I can't abandon
for some big company
who doesn't care
about the little guy.
You're not your grandfather,
Chip. You're you!
This would be Chip's company
with a different way
of doing things.
-I don't know.
-Things can change.
Just like that.
Hey, come on. Yo, no! No fair.
-[Laura] Come on!
-[Chip] Ya! Come on!
-[Laura] Let's go! Let's go!
-[Chip] Come on!
[Chip] Come on... [indistinct]
Let's catch her!
-[Laura] Catch up, Zeus.
-[Chip] I'm trying.
[Chip] Giddap. Come on!
-[Chip] Giddap. Come on, boy.
-[Laura] Come on, come on!
[Laura] Whoa!
[Chip] Whoa, boy! Whoa.
I am so happy
that we did this.
It almost looked like
you were having fun.
Maybe a little.
Sure you don't have
time for adventures?
OK, you got me. Thank you.
Anytime.
[thunder rumbles]
Come on.
[phone chimes]
[Owen] Yeah, sure, Michael.
review the wording.
Honey, hi.
Oh, did I wake you?
Yeah, it's midnight here.
Everything OK?
My client has
a paper trail a mile long,
I was trying to get
on top of it.
How's everything with you?
How's Emerald Rocks?
[scoffs] Sapphire Cove.
Actually, I had
a really great day.
Hey, you know what we should do
when we go on our honeymoon?
-What's that?
-We should go horseback riding.
Ha! That's hilarious.
-Oh, you're serious!
-It's just a thought.
Honey, no, no,
I'm not into that.
-You know that.
-Why not?
It's fun and adventurous.
How about you go horse riding
and I'll take the pictures.
Yeah, it was just a thought.
[thunder rumbles]
[Owen]
Hey, about the wedding...
How do you feel about
pushing the date back again?
Again? Owen,
this is the third time.
I know.
But the board has invited me
to a retreat that weekend
and you know how important those
retreats are for networking.
I just... [scoffs]
Laura, I just need you to hold
on a little bit longer, OK?
We'll set a date
as soon as you get back.
[sighs] I don't know.
Owen, I...
I think I need a break.
Just being back here,
it's given me some time
to think.
About us. Our future.
About what I want.
I think I need some time
to work things out.
-[door opens]
-[man] Hey, meeting's in five.
Uh... understood.
[man]
Everyone's in the boardroom.
Look, play it the way you want.
Work the scenarios
through for you
and let me know where
you stand on it all, OK?
OK.
[thunder rumbles in distance]
[phone ringing]
[rain falls]
Thanks, I'll get the broom.
-Hey, get any sleep last night?
-Not really.
Wild storm.
Is everything OK down here?
Just tidying up.
Some big branches came down.
There's been a little damage
to Mom and Dad's place.
Oh, my gosh! Are they OK?
Oh, yeah, just waiting on
a status report from Chip.
-Speaking of...
-[Chip] Hey.
-How's the house?
-Nothing too serious.
A drainpipe got pretty beat up.
A few other things.
-But it will be OK.
-OK.
-Morning, Laura.
-Morning.
I'm glad everything's OK.
If Mom happens to be baking,
can you bring me back
some banana bread?
-Banana bread. Got it.
-Please? Thank you.
Oh, let me help you with that.
Um, I'm gonna grab my tools
and get started.
[Gem] James, can you
get the ladder?
Sounds like a lot of work.
Yeah. That looks
like a lot of work.
It's nothing that can't wait.
I can help.
All right, then.
But no fun, all right? I'm
done reading for a little bit.
No fun. Promise.
[scoffs] OK.
Thank you.
Oh, and if you could just
give me a ham... Hammer.
You always were one step ahead.
Why don't you two
take a break?
Thank you.
It's very good of you
both to do this.
It's my pleasure, Mrs. B.
Besides, we got most
of the materials
leftover from the build.
You're a good man.
Well, come inside when
you're ready for lunch.
Thank you.
So you built this house?
I guess I did.
Mr. And Mrs. B had
a little financial trouble
after he hurt his back
and, well, they've
done so much for me
that it was
the least I could do.
Besides, it proved
to be a good prototype
for the next few builds.
Wow.
Do you like it?
Chip, this is my dream house.
You wait till you see inside.
-You've built four of these?
-That's right.
I mean, I would've built more
except it's hard
to gather the funds.
-Come on.
-What's so funny?
You talk about
building up funds
like you don't have
a billion-dollar company
waiting for your signature.
OK, I know this is
simplifying things
but look at what you've built.
There is no reason
that the charity
couldn't be integrated
into the company.
You could do both.
I don't think anyone's
ever tried
so hard to convince me
of something before.
You must really think
anything is possible.
Anything is possible.
[sighs]
This is beautiful.
I always thought they'd end
up together.
Everyone did.
He was never the same
after she left.
[clears throat] And this is
the living room and kitchen.
[Laura] Oh, wow, your home
is just gorgeous.
Thank you.
Oh, and Gem
requested some banana bread.
Oh, well, are
we ready for lunch?
-Yup.
-Yes. Please.
[Mrs. B] Thanks, Laura.
That deed to our old house has
been giving me grief forever.
Oh, it's no trouble at all.
These things can be
a nightmare to deal with.
Yeah, not to mention having to
travel to the mainland
for this kind of thing.
It's such a bother
and expensive.
You mean there's no law
firm in Sapphire Cove?
No, not since
Mr. Martin retired.
Oh.
Okay, I think we're
nearly done out here,
just have to attach that support
beam to the retaining wall.
-Right?
-Retaining well? Really?
What? He offered!
Yeah. It's really not a problem.
It'll only take a minute.
I can help. Ow!
-Oh, hey, you all right?
-Yeah, just a splinter.
Oh, yeah, that, oof,
that is a doozy.
You mind if we finish tomorrow?
I should probably take her
to the hotel, first-aid kit.
You should get that removed
for sure.
You're onto something, I think.
Let's go.
Very funny.
I just had your safety
in mind, that's all.
-Oh, thank you.
-Careful now.
-Not feeling faint, are you?
-I think I'll survive.
Okay, let me get that for you.
Can't be careful.
-Why, thank you.
-Mm-hmm.
Ow!
-Oh! Oh, right, are you sure?
-Oh, come on!
You're gonna make it worse.
Gonna have to amputate.
-Thank you.
-You OK?
I'm OK.
-Chip.
-Yeah?
Banana bread.
Save some for Gem or
she'll never forgive me.
Thank you Mrs. B.
-Thank you.
-Hey!
See you soon.
Get out here. Come on!
Got it. I think I...
Almost.
OK. Here we go.
I would usually do this myself,
it's just...
it's my right
hand and I'm right-handed.
It's OK. Stay still.
-Ow.
-Got it. You all right?
You know, I think this is
the first time
that I've seen
you without your phone.
Ha. Yeah, it's kinda nice
not being tied to the office
for once.
Not bad.
Hey, do you... Do you
remember when we were kids
and we buried that treasure
chest with my necklace in it?
I spent three months'
allowance on that necklace.
Hey, you remember
we made that map
so we wouldn't forget
where we put it too?
Did you ever...
I don't know,
think about digging it up?
I, uh, almost did.
I was gonna dig it up,
get that necklace and...
come find you
in San Francisco.
Really?
Yeah.
But then I thought,
"She's probably got someone
who cares for her very much
and has got her a nicer,
better necklace
and she will have
forgotten all about me
and my silly fishing
rods and treasure maps."
Chip...
-Yeah?
-[Owen] Laura.
-Owen?
-Surprise.
What are you doing here?
-Oh!
-Oh. I missed you!
After we talked, I realized
I had to come out here
and apologize in person.
I've been so focused on work
that I've started to lose
sight of what's important.
I don't want to lose you.
Oh, and I got some case notes
I'd love you to take a look at.
-Who's this?
-Owen, this is Chip.
-Chip Finley.
-Hey.
Oh, congratulations.
-Oh.
-CEO of Finley Developments.
-Do you have representation?
-Uh...
My firm's known for helping
out big players, that's all.
-I haven't signed it yet...
-We haven't really worked
out any of the details
of the contract so...
I'm just kidding.
Of course you're gonna go
with Laura's firm.
OK.
-It is nice to meet you, Owen.
-Likewise.
And I should probably
get this back to reception.
We should have dinner.
Chip, you're free tonight!
-[Laura] Oh, no, we don't...
-No, I insist.
Dinner. Great. I will see
if Gem can make it too.
That would be... great.
OK.
My little shark.
In her natural habitat.
Mom and Dad are really
lucky to have you guys.
Thank you for
helping them today.
That's OK. And Laura, she was
a real pro with getting
that broken drainpipe repaired.
-You helped repair a drainpipe?
-She sure did.
She's not even the worst
apprentice I've ever had.
Oh, apprentice, is it?
I feel like I at least deserve
a promotion to supervisor or...
Do you? No, I mean,
and, look, if you hadn't
eaten the banana bread,
-then maybe you could have.
-I knew there was banana bread!
I don't believe you just
told on me.
-What?
-[Laura] Gem, I am sorry.
I was injured.
I needed the sugar.
[Chip] That's not even
the right finger!
Anyway, Laura,
she was a real trooper.
You're a lucky man, Owen.
I should have married her
the moment I saw her.
Which is why
I've made a decision.
Laura, I want you to marry me.
Yeah, we've done
this bit, remember?
At the Law Society Ball?
No, I want to get married here.
Now. In Emerald Rocks.
-[both] It's Sapphire Cove.
-Whatever.
I can talk to management.
I'm sure they can organize
something in a day or two.
Nothing outrageous.
Small but classy.
Family and friends won't be here
but we can have a party when
we get back to San Francisco.
Yeah, Owen,
I just don't think...
Chip could walk
you down the aisle.
-[Chip] Hmm?
-Yeah, what do you say, Chip?
-Hmm? Oh...
-How spontaneous.
-More drinks.
-[waiter] Right away.
I don't think that Chip
would be really want to...
Who are we fooling?
You know, I was in my office
the other night after we had
our talk
and I suddenly thought,
"Laura has been with me
through some of the toughest
cases I've ever had.
She's smart, she's gorgeous.
She's one heck of a lawyer.
She's a keeper."
You must really
like the island, Owen.
I mean, you've only been here
a few hours,
but your first impressions
must be... impressed.
Absolutely. I don't think
I could live here, though.
[Chip] Island life wouldn't
work for you?
-Feels a little small for me.
-Oh.
But hey, different strokes
for different folks.
-[phone chimes]
-Oh!
Excuse me. I gotta get this.
Yeah, this place is nice.
We should do it here.
Hit me. Yeah...
Hey. Listen, slow down.
He seems nice.
[Chip] Oh, yeah,
he seems very nice, Laura.
I mean, you know, not for me,
but like he says,
different strokes
for different folks.
He's not usually like this.
-I think he's Jet lagged or...
-Jet lagged, yeah.
You know, I did realize
something, though.
He can't handle life
on a small island
and I can cannot be
a corporate big shot.
Might be OK for some people.
But that life will never be me.
I mean, there's nothing wrong
with wanting to push yourself.
I do push myself, Laura.
I'm just not gonna be pushed
into being a suit like that.
But I'm sure you guys
will be very happy.
Wow.
I'm going to leave now.
Good night.
Well, do you want to talk
about what just happened?
No.
What? This is madness.
How were we supposed to know
he had a bank account
in the Cayman Islands?
-Yeah, I agree we need a
realistic approach.
-Thanks.
Let's unpack it
when I get back.
One day! I'm gone one day
and the whole thing falls apart.
I tell ya... [sighs]
What's wrong, honey?
What's going on?
I thought you'd be
happy to see me.
-Granddad?
-Oh, Chip. Listen to this.
I was not expecting
you back yet.
It's a letter you
and Laura wrote
apologizing for stealing
banana bread.
"Dear Mrs. Bailey...
We regret the theft occurred
and wish to apologize
wholeheartedly
on behalf of our evil twins.
We really hope that
we are still allowed
to hang out with
our best friend Gem.
We promise to mow your lawn
for the entire summer.
Sincerely, evil twins,
Chip and Laura."
It's not really
a good time right now.
What are you doing here?
I flew in early for the
birthday celebrations.
-And I thought I just...
-Hide from all your friends?
Something like that.
I see you've been fishing.
Those rods must be
a million years old.
I took Laura out.
Oh, yes, and how
did it go there?
Granddad, could you just
stop with the contract?
I know it's your birthday soon
and I know you want me to sign,
but I'm sorry, I'm not your guy.
Well, now you've
brought it up,
I've said it before and I'll say
it again, you are the right man.
We went through this with Dad.
Remember how that turned out?
You are not your father.
And things were
very different then.
It's a completely different
company now.
A company you can be
proud to run.
This company is your future.
What's happened, Chip?
People change.
Things change.
And Laura?
I wondered whether the two
of you had hit it off again.
You two were always
so happy together.
Well, it's not like that now.
I mean, we...
She has a fiancé.
Who literally just arrived here
and he wants to marry her
on the island tomorrow.
-And did she invite him here?
-No. He surprised her.
Did he?
Well, things change.
I gotta go.
Things change.
I want my husband to be
my best friend.
Someone that I can have
adventures with.
I feel like our careers have
taken priority over everything.
Over us.
It's all we ever talk about.
Take away the work and...
what's left?
Well, I can change.
I can work less.
It's not about you, Owen.
It's me.
I'd stopped being myself.
I guess it took me being back
here to realize who I truly am.
I'm sorry.
[Karavi] It'll be alright,
buddy. I promise.
Karavi, can you check that
the linen has arrived, please?
And that the kitchen got the
vegetable and the herb order?
-It's almost time to open.
-You got it, boss.
Is there, like,
a dessert-related emergency
that I haven't heard of?
I'm just checking options
for Graham's party.
-He likes chocolate, right?
-Uh... Does he like chocolate?
-Try this.
-Mmm...
Are you still reading that?
Figured out how to get
the engineers into
the board meetings yet?
Yeah, I'm not signing it.
-[Owen] Chip.
-Mmm.
I'm glad I caught
you before I left.
Left? Heading out so soon?
I thought you and Laura would
be planning your big day?
Laura and I have decided to
take a break.
An indefinite break.
-Oh.
-I'm so sorry to hear that.
Yeah, Laura's a great girl.
And she deserves to be happy.
And to be honest, she seemed
pretty happy last night
talking about banana bread
and fixing a drainpipe with you.
I don't think I've ever
seen her that happy.
Anyway, take care, Chip.
You too.
[knock at door]
Come in.
I heard what happened.
How are you?
May I suggest an action plan?
One, we eat these cakes.
Two, we go to the spa
and take advantage
of my staff discount.
Three, just breathe.
[breathes deeply]
I feel like I could
just float away.
That was the best massage
I've ever had.
[sighs]
This is exactly what I needed.
-Thanks, Gem.
-You're welcome.
Well, I cannot believe
Graham's birthday celebrations
are tomorrow.
I think I have everything
under control.
Graham's birthday
and the deadline to
get the contract signed.
What will you guys do?
I truly don't know.
He seems so stuck.
I just wish I could
make this decision about the
contract easier for him.
He'll never
leave the island.
If only there was a way
he could do both.
That's it.
I mean, we couldn't do it
all at once but we could do it.
Gem, that's brilliant!
Always happy to help.
[taps keys]
[object clatters]
Laura? You awake?
Chip, what are you
doing down there?
I, um, wasn't sure that
you'd want to speak to me.
Would you want to come
on a sunrise hike with me?
That sounds like an adventure.
It is an adventure.
I'll be right down.
Hey, um, Laura, I'm really
sorry about the other night.
What you've done with your
career, what you've become,
it's really impressive.
Sometimes I... I wish
I was more like that.
Anyway, I'm sorry.
It's OK.
I'm kind of realizing
that work isn't everything.
I guess being back
on the island gave me
a different perspective
on things.
I kind of feel like
I'm home again.
Something about this place,
I guess, just...
This island just
helps people see clearly.
-Must be that island magic.
-Must be.
[Laura]
Home isn't a place.
It's a feeling.
And, you know,
I'm starting to realize
what you've been saying about
not wanting to leave this place.
So I've had an idea.
Oh, more reading. Great!
Yes, but I've added in
a new condition.
If you accept the role as CEO,
company headquarters will
be moved to the island.
That way, you don't
have to move away
-and you can keep your charity.
-Laura...
It could take a year or two,
but I think that this
would work.
What do you think?
I think I'm running
out of excuses.
I'm surrounded
by CEOs and directors
and board members all day long,
I know a leader when I see one.
You want to use your influence
to make the world
a better place.
Not for personal gain.
Do you know how rare that is?
It sounds like someone I know.
Did you work
on this all night?
Yeah. Well, I am
a bit of a nerd so...
No.
You're incredible.
[footsteps approach]
-[man] That was worth the hike!
-[woman] Yeah, it was.
-[man] Coming through.
-[Gem] Let's go. Let's go.
Lots to do, people.
[Karavi] Important DJ stuff
coming through.
[Gem] Sam, can you go and load
the truck?
[Laura] Any more
adventures planned for today?
[Chip] You'll have
to wait and see.
[man] Watch your back.
Oh, thank goodness you are here.
I really need help.
-Is everything OK?
-Barely.
The flowers arrived and they
were supposed to be
tropical centerpieces,
but they arrived like this.
I'm so busy overseeing
everything.
Is there any chance that you
would mind...
-Making some centerpieces?
Yes, sure. We would love to.
-Yeah.
You're the best.
Where have you two been anyway?
Chip took me on a hike
and we watched the sunrise.
Oh, how romantic.
Oh, no, I wouldn't say
that it was romantic.
Me neither. They got those
mosquitoes and, and...
-Yeah, it rained.
-And it rained a little and...
A lot.
OK. Just get started.
-Ow.
-[workers chatting inaudibly]
So what do you know
about flower arranging?
Oh, don't worry,
I'm very experienced
in the flower
arranging industry.
-There.
-So you have no idea
what you're doing either.
Not at all.
-OK. This.
-[phone chimes]
-Uh... That's you.
-Oh! Oh!
It's the office.
Today's the deadline.
Fiona. Hi.
-[Fiona] She's alive.
-Yes. I am. I'm sorry.
I've been, uh... distracted.
I have some news for you.
-[Laura] Oh?
-The partnership.
Simon isn't
in the running anymore.
Oh!
Send that contract through
with Chip's signature
by 5:00 p.m.
and the partnership's
as good as yours. Understood?
-Yes.
-[Fiona] Good.
So, everything all right?
I got the promotion.
I just need to send them
the signed contract.
[clears throat]
I guess it's
time to make a decision.
Chip, can you help
Karavi move that chair, please?
-Yeah.
-Laura, I need you
to lay the table cloths,
move those centerpieces.
And tell me everything's
gonna be OK.
-Everything's gonna be OK.
-Great.
Wait, are you OK?
Not really.
But I will be. Come on.
So by 1900 hours, you all
need to be in formation one
circulating drinks and canapés.
And then at 1930,
you'll move to formation two
for dinner service.
This is gonna be the greatest
night this resort has ever seen.
-Understood?
-[all] Yes, ma'am.
[woman] Sir...
I mean, copy that.
We're almost there.
But it has to be perfect.
But why? It's not like your
promotion's riding on it.
-[Karavi] You'll look great
in a suit.
-[Gem] Yeah, thanks.
-[Karavi] Yeah?
-OK, yeah, that sounds great.
Ooh!
-Oh.
-[Chip mumbling]
Hey, let's run the lighting
and sound check.
Now?
But it's not even dark yet.
Yeah. Just go with me on this.
Hey, Chip, Laura,
we need to
do a lighting check.
Can you stand in
on the dance floor?
Please? It's really important.
Cue lights.
Cue sound.
[gentle music plays]
Guys, come on. Dance.
♪ Blue skies all the way ♪
With each other!
♪ We laugh, we joke, we sing
What a beautiful day ♪
♪ Not a cloud in our sight ♪
♪ Such an adventure,
my baby... ♪
I think it's working.
♪ Water's crystal clear... ♪
So, gonna be partner.
You really want this?
I mean, it's everything
I always wanted.
Years and years of hard work.
It's the dream.
Yeah, OK, I get that.
And it will let you
make a difference?
For starters, I will be able
to call all of the shots.
You don't have
to jump through hoops.
That's good.
Will it make you happy?
I don't... I don't know.
I've really loved being home.
Well, don't worry.
As a beautiful girl once said,
"Home is a feeling,
not a place."
So, I'm sure you'll be happy
wherever you are.
I just...
I just wish it was here.
♪ You take me
to the highest heights ♪
♪ Let's stay here
I think we might ♪
Well, what about you?
Are you ready to be
the Chip Finley
that you were destined to be?
Honestly... honestly,
I don't know.
Then let's just be here.
Right now.
Not knowing
what to do.
Together.
♪ Feeling so high, yeah ♪
♪ Feeling so high,
cloud nine ♪
[door clanks]
You OK, my boy?
Aren't you supposed to
be greeting your guests?
Oh, I thought I'd
take a moment of peace
before the schmoozing starts.
Today's the deadline.
What did you decide?
Laura added a clause.
What do you think of that?
Moving the headquarters,
I see. Fine.
Should have done that years ago.
What about Laura continuing
to provide our legal services?
Agreed!
-And...
-And I have quite a lot
of thoughts
about moving forward.
I'm not gonna be pushing
the same old agenda
that's been driving Finley
Developments all these years.
I want to change things.
I'd say the company
is ripe for a restructure.
I trust you, Chip.
I always have.
You've never wavered
from your beliefs.
And I want you to
make this company
exactly what you
think it needs to be.
It will be your company.
Your rules. That's my wish.
You know what?
[chuckles]
Happy birthday, Granddad.
I'll try to make you proud.
You already do.
It's almost 1900 hours.
Formation one, everyone.
It's go time.
[phone chimes]
If you're calling
for an update,
I'm afraid I don't have one
for you.
[Fiona] Laura, are you kidding?
You did it.
-He signed it?
-[Fiona] Yes. He signed it.
Chip is the new CEO
of Finley Developments.
They've sent through
the contract.
It was a bit stained
and ripped up.
What happened out there?
Never mind. It doesn't matter.
He signed it.
Congratulations, Laura.
Welcome to the partnership.
Thank you, Fiona.
That's... wonderful.
Now, we need to get you back
to San Francisco. Tonight.
We need to organize
that buy-in ASAP
now that you're
an equity partner.
-[Laura] Tonight?
-Yes. Is there a problem?
[sighs]
[inaudible party chatter]
-Hi.
-Welcome.
[upbeat Latin-style music plays]
-Cue Champagne top-ups.
-[man] Copy that.
Karavi, let's turn
the music up just a touch.
[volume increases]
-Whoa!
-Hmm?
Tell the chef to lighten up
on the seasoning.
Any word on our
guest of honor?
[woman] The Eagle has landed.
I repeat. The Eagle has landed.
[woman] Happy birthday, Graham.
-You look very dapper.
-Good to see you both...
[Graham] Together.
-Excuse me.
-Of course.
There's my boy.
You look like a man on
the way to great things.
You don't scrub up so bad
yourself, Granddad.
Laura!
I can see the island
has been treating you well.
Happy birthday, Mr. Finley.
Yes, this has been exactly
what I needed.
-I can't stay...
-Laura, I...
I hear congratulations
are in order.
You are looking at the new
CEO of Finley Developments.
-OK, Champagne now.
-[woman] Copy that. 10-4.
-Oh!
-Thank you.
Congratulations, Chip.
Perfect.
Thank you, Laura.
I knew you'd convince him.
No doubt they're expediting
your promotion as we speak.
Yes, they want me to hit
the ground running,
something about
an equity buy-in.
This evening, in fact.
They've booked me on
the last flight out tonight.
Tonight?
[Laura]
I'm afraid I can't stay.
I'd better go pack my bags.
Have a lovely evening.
[upbeat music plays]
[man on radio] 30 minutes
till dinner service, everyone.
30 minutes.
-Hi.
-[Mrs. B] Hi.
Hi!
[chattering]
-Coming through! Whoo-hoo!
-Cha-cha-cha!
Good evening, Theodore.
-Have you welcomed the VIPs?
-Yes.
And complementary fruit baskets
have been sent to their rooms.
Does the DJ know to keep to
the pre-reviewed song choices?
He does,
though I have this music
override button
if necessary.
[dance music plays]
I've also ensured that all
of Graham's favorite items
are on the menu
and the drinks and canapés are
on constant rotation
until dinner begins.
And the lighting is set to dim
at precisely 8:00 p.m.
right before the fireworks.
Well, it seems that you've
managed everything perfectly.
Almost.
It appears that you're wearing
an incorrect name tag.
I think this
is more appropriate.
[laughs]
[Gem] Oh, you won't regret this!
[dance music plays]
Are you really going to
let her leave like that?
You know, I read the contract
to get closer to her,
but now that I've signed it,
I pushed her away.
The contract is not the only
reason I brought her out here,
you know.
After all these years,
the one thing I've learned is
that work isn't everything.
You love her. And that's...
The beginning
and the end of everything.
She's leaving, Granddad. Again.
She hasn't left yet.
She's a high flying, big-city
partner at a law firm now.
And you're the new CEO of
a billion-dollar company.
Your worlds are not
that far apart anymore.
You just have to do
what feels right.
Here.
And I found this in the shed.
[Chip] That's our old
treasure map. The necklace.
Maybe the old days are exactly
what Laura needs.
Oh, Granddad.
I need a shovel.
Oh!
Your taxi will
be here any minute.
Chip will be so sad
that he missed you.
The party was perfect.
You are amazing.
I always knew you'd make
general manager.
And it's better this way.
With Chip.
I just can't believe
you're leaving now.
I'm gonna miss you so much.
-[phone chimes]
-I have to take this.
-Okay.
-Bye, Gem. I miss you already.
Bye.
Fiona.
[Fiona] Let me know as
soon as you land.
Because we need to get straight
into the paperwork.
We've got your promotion
announcement
and marketing
materials to finalize.
And of course,
we want to introduce
our newest partner
to our marquee clients.
There's gonna
be some late nights
and early mornings involved.
Actually, the first thing
I'd like to do
is implement
my local business plan.
[Fiona] Politics first, Laura.
You gotta meet the new CFO of
Parker Industries immediately.
Then we need to wine
and dine Gibson Incorporated.
They're a new kid on
the pharmaceutical scene
and they are shopping
for a new legal team
and that's just for starters.
Now that you're partner, you
gotta jump through a few hoops.
Hoops?
[Fiona]
It's partnership politics.
You know how these things work.
[driver] Sapphire Cove Airport,
miss?
[panting]
[all]
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
[applause]
Perfect.
Gem. Have you seen Laura?
She wanted to say goodbye.
She couldn't find you anywhere.
She's gone.
Oh, did you just dig that up?
Oh, Chip.
[Laura] It wasn't in there.
How did you know that?
Because it's always been here.
I don't understand. How?
When we buried the treasure
chest, I went back.
I couldn't bear
to leave without it.
Without something
to remember you by.
So you've been wearing it
all these years?
It's my lucky charm.
Chip, I'm done jumping
through hoops.
I want to start my own
law firm.
Here. On the island.
I want the sunsets.
And horseback riding
and adventures.
And I want my best friend
to be there beside me.
What do you think?
You're my best friend.
And I love you, Laura.
I love you too.
Cue fireworks.
[upbeat music]
♪ You're the light of my life
Oh-oh ♪
You're my tropical sunrise ♪
♪ You're the light of my life
Oh-oh ♪
♪ Forever and always
You light up my life ♪
♪ You're the light of my life
Oh-oh ♪
♪ You light up my life
You're my tropical sunrise ♪
♪ You're the light of my life
Oh-oh ♪
♪ Forever and always
You light up my life ♪
♪ Everybody feels
the rain sometimes ♪
♪ But we learn to be OK ♪
♪ When we're in the dark,
it's sometimes hard to see ♪
♪ But love
it shines for you and me ♪
♪ So this little love of mine ♪
♪ I'm gonna let it shine ♪
♪ This little love of mine ♪
♪ This little love of mine
I'm gonna let it shine ♪
♪ Let it shine,
let it shine, let it shine ♪
♪ Nobody can shine every day ♪
♪ We need the clouds
to give us shade ♪
♪ Just because it's dark
doesn't mean that's where
we'll stay ♪
♪ Tomorrow will
be a brand-new day ♪
♪ So this little light of mine
I'm gonna let it shine ♪
♪ This little light of mine
♪ Let it shine,
let it shine, let it shine ♪
♪ This little love of mine
I'm gonna let it shine ♪
♪ Let it shine
Let it shine, let it shine ♪