Raining Cats and Frogs
Directed by Jacques-Remy Girerd
Voice: Antonio Laciga
Voice: Raily Chaluncu
Voice: Ikwli Cerenkov
Grandpa!
Mom, come on
Mom, we will be late!
Oh, where is grandpa?
In the toilet
Grandpa, are you here?
Grandpa, I know you are here
Child, what do you want to do? We'll be late
Don't call "grandpa" so many times
I have told you.    Mom, he won't come
Alright, come on, Ferdinand
Why can't you let me be quiet?
We must go to Lamotte, you promised
Billimidi, you are right, I forget!
Let's go, mom
We go first
Wait for me
Tom, Juliette
Go up, we will be faster
Run
Full speed!
Hurry, grandpa! Do you know what time is it?
Don't call "grandpa", call papa
Papa! I can't, you are too old!
Little bastard
I'm not your real father,
but I bring you up
Now you are my son
Don't be angry, grandpa, I love you
I think so, too
He hates me calling him grandpa
It's normal, don't forget you are our son
Do you call me grandma?   That's different, you are young
Tom! What are you talking about?
Do you hear what the little bastard said? Ferdinand
I hear nothing
The weather doesn't change, it's still sunny
In the following days,
it's not cloudy, nor windy
The peasents worry about the low precipitation...
Louise, you won't believe...
I've filled the gas
Am I great?
Dear, promise me to be careful, understand?
I'm so worried leaving you
They! They are coming!
Hey Lili! Hey, Children
Hurry up, they've gone
Why should I trust you?
It's not my fault, Lili
I will shout  You always do that
Here you come! Great
Is it here, Lini, where crocodile is missing?
Yes, I'm glad to talk with Louise
It's the first time he comes to Africa
Will you see me there?
So many crocodiles...
I'm too worried
Oh, dear, it's alright
No, dear, it's alright
Lini, be careful in the crocodiles
Unless you are bad to them
It's not so simple
My grandma saw a crocodile eat a whole giraffe
The whole giraffe
Don't say it, you scare me
We are alright, don't worry
You look after Lili and beasts
How can I thank you?
Whom you should worry about is yourself
Come here
Come on, dear
Don't be afraid, Louise
You can sleep at ease
I will look on her as my child
You are really great
Ok, let's go, Louise
Thanks again, we owe you
Alright, we are neighbours
We will look after all the things
Goodbye, child
Kiss, Lili
Be docile, we'll be back soon
Bye, mom
Let's go, Louise
Wash the behind of ears...
Keep warm when sleeping
Bye, papa, bye, mom, drive carefully
Wait, wait
Wait, bring this, Louise
It's convenient on the ship
Don't know when it works
Thank you, Mr. Ferdinand
Africa, we are coming!
A speed boat that brings crocodile...
Old Lini is nervous
How did I say to them?
Tell them our results
You must go, meeting tomorrow evening
Ok, I'm leaving
Don't be pinned  Whom do you think I am?
Do you remember the results?
I remember it clearly.  Even decimal part?
Yes, I remember the decimal
Then you tell us...
You should go now, it's an important meeting
Do you know where is it?
We know it's far away, but it's your
responsibility going there
We have no choice in such a meeting
Are you sure of the results? Of course
We've done 20 times.  Sure
Oh, if we have no choice...
My grandma's soul!
Soul of life!
Let milk out!
Seems no use
Pour off like a water column, not drops!
I won't do it any more!
Grandpa
What are you doing?
Repair the tube of tractor
I have a nail. But I don't know where is it
I used it this morning
Look, it's a good patch
Just a little glue, like new one
It's easy to use, ok
Grandpa, you looks funny, so young
Tom...
Looks like ant
Lili, put it down, it's no use
Don't fill any more! It will explode!
No, grandpa, you said it's good
Although so¡­
I think it should be
Let's see if it explode
Grandpa, I may continue filling
Enough: "grandpa"
And we are not making balloon!
You bring the eggs, ok?
For battercake...yeah, battercake!
I run faster than you!
What's it upside? Don't look
Grandpa said it's danger.  Dranger?   Yes...
Lili. Are you crazy
Don't do that! Go down! you don't follow...
We will be scolded   Let it be
I can't grasp it,  happy now?
Don't grasp any more!  Not funny     really?
blocked
Children
I myself see the eggs today?
We are coming, Juliette will go down soon
The pond of pine? 38
The pond of owl? 38, too
The pond of justice? 41
The cave of factory? 39
The pond of old Berthier? 40
The pond of snake?
Rock valley? 41
The pond of the bridge of the nigoles? 40
Without doubt, these figures messure up
Just small discrepancy
It will rain 40 days and 40 nights after plenilune
That's tomorrow night!
The rain will pour down, water in the rivers rises
Soon it will go up to the bank
Then it will be the terrible flood
Water continues to go up
Do you hear?
That's another Niagara
My god
Who wants the last egg cookie?
I eat enough
Me, too
So do I, thank you, Juliette
Can you play guitar for us?   Good idea
Just like last time, let me digest first
No, now, grandpa!
You will sleep later
Grandpa!
Play, Ferdinand
So they can sleep
You two want me to play for you?
Let me sing "old sea house" for you
We left Porto Rico
in the evening of Saint-Malo
There was 8 people in the ship
Our leak tub
Tides up, tides down
What do we take?
Barrels of  Rum and bags of Coco
We set off from San Diego
Straits is low and plain
Do you hear?
They, they have no other way
Damn
They are dying, like others
We can warn them
How can they trust us?
We are just frogs
Look, Tom! Grandpa's enemy
Who are they?
Potato pesticide
Why does one ride on another?
They are making love.  Can't you see?
What's "make love"?
I'm not your sex abecedarian
Ask your mother, go, wait!
Brave!  My beetle
I still have feeling, I'm not dead
Do you wound?  No, I'm alright
Well done.   What did you say?
Well done,  I want to...
Can you speak?  Are you surprised?
Yes, a bit
Let's talk about something else.   Wait, little guy
I have something important to tell you
I don't believe!   A speaking frog?
Wait! Come back!
I told you, it's no use
Stop! Tom, don't be silly
Come on, you will see it
They can speak, I heard them talking
Poor Tom
Speak, or she will regard me as cheater
Ok, we speak, listen
Do I cheat you?  No, they can speak
Listen!
It's nothing
Catastrophe is coming
The following 40 days and nights
Flood?   Yes, flood
It's no difference for us, but you...
If you don't act fast, you all will die
Die? We dp,  so do you and other people
Flood will drown animals, forests and farms...
It will drown all the city, the toppest mountain
Is it drown the sky?
Yes, drown the sky
Everything drown
No time
What shall we do?
Oh, I have no idea
Can you help us?
Sorry, we can't, we are just frogs
But we can forecast weather
Hurry, I can't help you
Now it's your problem
We must tell grandpa, come on, Tom!
Come on! Don't hide here
Grandpa!
Mom! Juliette
You are safe!
We succeed!
Anger of heaven quiets down
I don't know you, but¡­
You said!
When shall we eat?  I'm hungry
40 days isn't long, who believes it, captain?
Roger that! We look after you
Don't expect any miracle
But things on the tub can help us get through it
Let's wait for it, stand aside!
Be careful!
How is it?
28 tons of potato!
Potato! Potato!
Incredible, we are saved
in such a tub
Can we eat the potato the old man mentioned?
Of course, I like it most
But I'm so hungry that I can eat a brick now
If you say so
Ah,  nausea!
You should make it cooked! You cooked it and then eat?
Which cave do you dig?
If someone ask, you don't know
Ok, Ok, ok, lumme
Do you see the two bacons behind us?
Am looking
I'm thinking what will they react to it
We certainly should pay attention to them
Excuse me, captain
Herbivore like potato, they are happy
But for us, carnivore, how could we eat potato?
Is there anything for us on the menu?
I'm thinking about the problem.  Let me think
Sheep are shivering in front of wolives
When cats prey, rats shiver
Creeping animals like to eat hoptoads
They live together
It's not easy
Everything must be changed
Or our lives will be deteriorated
If you don't oppress your aspirations
then we no longer exist
We can't survive
If you don't oppress your aspirations
For carnivore, it's natural
To eat Herbivore
It's standard rule
If you deny, you are madman
Before the flood
It's unblamable
But now everything must be changed
Or lives will die out
We can't survive
Wait, captain!
You mean we can't eat meat?
Nor a piece of chicken?
Nor a piece of chicken!
I know potatoes are difficult for you,
but it's the only way
We all need to survive
Be patient
Blood won't last long
We are the only survivers,
just like Noah's Ark?
I'm not clear, I can't see anything else
If nobody remains on the earth,
whom will you marry with?
I won't tell you even if I know the answer
You are so...
I know whom I will marry with
There is something strange there
Where? A black thing on the water
You are right
A wood or something
No, wait
chelonian! Are you sure?
A large chelonian!
I go to tell grandpa!
Hurry, she is in the wrong direction
What's up? She saw chelonian
Grandpa! Tom! Hurry
She grasps the life buoy!
I bet they will get it on the ship
What's up? You know!
You are allergic to chelonian, by the way
Can't you move there?
It's fine there! How can I?
No space
If that's your opinion
I just explain it
Don't you see I'm blocked?
What a bad mood are you today!
I'm sorry
I think we are too late
Poor grandpa, is she really dead?
Look¡­
She has no fim
Somebody attacked her
Little chelonian, open your eyes
Open your eyes
She isn't dead, she is still alive
She is still alive
Stand aside
Give her some fresh air
Where am I? We save you
You are in our ship
What's matter with you?
Crocodile¡­
Everywhere
I just left
I'm too tired
Can't you see she is hungry?
Bring her something to eat, come on
You saved me
Let her stay alone
She need rest
When shall we find the continent, grandpa?
No one can tell
It takes some time to absorb the water
I hate this.   So do I
I can't wait the absorbability
Can't you try some spells, Juliette?
I like it, but never use it
A falling star, make a wish, Tom
I know, I hope flood retreat earlier
Idiot, it's no use when you say it out
Where does falling star come from?
You know it, my child
Space is not empty
There are many gravels and rocks
floating around the earth
Some are large, others are small
They are called meteorite
Sometimes
When the earth cross them
Falling stars are very fast
They rush to the space, abrade and fire
Just like a match
So they radiate?  Smart child...
No, these falling stars have a secret
Billions years ago
When the first falling star cross the universe
Arrive in our planet
Some strange things happened
Just like space is makeing love
with the earth
These maculas were produced
Bring us the first seed
That's how it begins
We are all offsprings of
the great falling star
Are you feeling better?
Yes, I come back
We shouldn't leave you alone like that
You are so kind, dear, how old are you?
Me? I'm 9
And you?
You are very old, aren't you?
Not too old
what are they talking about, mom? No¡­
They are talking about me
Don't be nervous, I will cut your ears
Done
You can go now
Don't look at these foxes
Just look at him when he passes by
In low rock
Whose claws is the strongest?
It's us, carnivore
Who are the gangsters in the grouind?
The guys over there
Calm down
Who can provide it to you?
All the tigers and men
Is it you, Tom? Yes
Where is Lili? She has new friend
She doesn't play with me any more
Sometimes, girls need a space for themselives
They need to talk about something we don't care about
My god! It's so small
The sky is low
Pass me the two-handed hammer.
Here you are, Grandpa
Thanks
Come in, ok?
Where, now still
Breakfast is ready, come and eat!
Potato again
Only potato
Can I eat yours? Be my guest!
Nor do you
What's the matter?
We all have potatoes
Are you just wasting them?
You all do that, I can't believe it
I just don't believe it
I really don't believe it
As you know, after all, they are only carnivore¡­
Carnivore maybe not
They do according to what we said
or we all eat
Be happy, Lili  So are you
The potatoes are so delicioius
My ancestor¡­
What are she doing? Want to become a bakemeat
Spirit of the earth
Small potato¡­
She just cries    Is that bakemeat?
Curse
Wrong again
I really don't know why    It never works
I just have no power
Usually it's so funny¡­
when your magic is wrong
Don't laugh at me
It was useful at my grandma's time
I feel your way of doing it
I hate crocodile too
They kill all my family
I'm the last surviver
Look! That's what I remain
Three small eggs
I took them away
Before the damned crocodile eat them
It's really a nightmare
These food make them mad
Destroy all the movable things
Even if there is human on the ship
Really horrible, they are mad
Really incredible, I decide to go away
Luckily, I find a life buoy
You know those news
Some people are still on the ship
My papa! My mom!
What's up?
I see
I know your feeling
Cry
Come on, cry , Lili
Many people died of the flood
Maybe we are just wandering surviver
But¡­ I think¡­
Poor little thing, poor us
I feel too bad
Come on, come on¡­What have we become?
Don't cry in front of the children
Come on, we talk about it in another place
Louise¡­Lini¡­They are all kind people
What remains in our world?
What do we have, what will we dream of?
Nothing! Nothing
You can't say that, the world won't end
Just think for a while¡­
How long will our nightmare be?
1 year, 10 years, 100 years!
No one can tell it
Time is lapsing
But I believe, one day
The flood will go away
Flood goes away, then our lives restart
Are you sure? No
I can't ensure anything
Yes, I can ensure one thing
That is: I love you forever
Our lives will never end
Roger?
Have you ever thought of...?
Sometimes, in the morning
What do you think of?   Death, idiot!
Death¡­
Why do you want me to think now?
Do you hear they said we are the only surviver
The only surviver?
What do you think it is after someone is dead?
After death?
How could I know?
What a question! I'm not soldier!
Make sure those things
Say, flood retreats¡­
Flood retreats? It's over then!
What do you mean?
We are waiting
What can I say? Nothing!
I just say, flood retreats
When you find something funny, tell me
Isn't the flood retreat funny?
Oh, my head¡­
When shall we go to
the same ship as the idiot stays?
What did I do?
Is that a problem?  No,  I find out
You know,  my parents are dead, too
I was too young
I think it was in a war
I can't remember now
Anyway he adopted me
I knew his parents
They were in the same ship as his father
So Juliette and I
decided to adopt the little sailor
Will you adopt me?
Do you remember we have promised to your
parents to look after you
we will keep the promise
Will you keep the promise, too, Grandpa?
I look after all the people who call me Grandpa
It's my honor
Even if I hope these people don't call me like that
Ferdinand, seems your family is becoming larger
I use the rear teeth to eat these potatoes
They burn like fires in my stomach
I feel so terrible!
Do you want your stomach to continue aching?
You will die without meat
There are many on the tub
Nobody will miss one or two chick
No matter who are you, you forget one thing¡­
That's the rule of captain
We have no right
Who do you think are you?
Can he change the natural law?
When do you see that carnivores don't eat meat?
Shut up!
Pass me a piece of barbecue
Better half-cooked
Do you think can you?   Of course, see my great work
Engine's power
will drive the shovels
Then we can move!
Am I smart?
At that time, it is a real ship! Real one
My papa is deft, too?
He is the high-class mechanician
Compare with him, I'm an outsider
I always see on the bridge
But he is already with engine
He is very familiar with his things
He can disassemble a engine in minutes
Help!
What's the matter?
Don't do that! Let me go!
They want to eat her!
Let her go right now!
My hoof, I can't beat them
Ain't you mad? Ain't you crazy?
I really can't believe! You want to destroy each other?
No, captain
Do you know why, we are hungry!
We need meat, that's it
Deepfry potato¡­We can't afford it
Whatever.  Do you need pea to improve your intelligence?
We lived through relying on miracle
Now you want to destroy anything!
Want to destroy our chance of survival!
Unless I'm dead!
Enough!
We've got so many troubles
I will put you into prison¡­
In the tub
Be careful of your leg, too
I hate you! You are ruffians
Selfish people
Who let me lose it?
He should pay for it
They will rebel
The space is much larger now.  Are you dreaming?
I'm not dreaming
How could you say that?  Idiot
I do say you are dreaming      How can?
My god! Don't speak, you make me nervous!
Poor guy, you are scared
I never scare
The appearance of grandpa is in time.    Right
I will lose my life if it's late
These bastards!  We need to be care of them
Little goat, set your teeth
Are you ok?   Yes
I'm more lucky than you
I've heard about your parents
Yes, they are dead
Like others
When shall we attack?
Be careful! You can't badger with captain
Let me get rid of him first
Do you still remember what are we looking for?
Of course
They are in the ship, I see them,   hide
Hope so, others are angry
We can't stop them any longer
Relax! We can't fall short of success for lack of a final effort
Trust me, I have an idea
You go
I will inform you
Damned bell! I never see such a monster!
Who brings flashlight?
I can't see anything, why should I give it to him?
Chelonian!
Have you get in touch with crocodiles?
Me? Are you crazy?
We saw you send them signal
You see nothing, but I see everything
Captain leads crocodiles to here
I'm coming to warn you
Do you want to know what did he say?
Don't say
Let him say
You know who is the chief instigator
Of course!
I believe this is what you hope
But now captain
wants to devote you to get peace
We shouldn't get carnivore any more
You make him sleepless
I heard him say so   The old bastard!
Are you sure what are you saying?
I swear, we carnivores must hold together
Then what shall we do?
No other ways
Who strikes first prevails
As long as we get rid of captain
you have chicks to eat
And babecue, crus
You won't be hungry any more!
We can win easily!
We can't live through it...
With the damned potatoes!
Right, guys?
Enough, follow me!
This way
What¡­
What's the matter?
My god!
Night attack!
As expected!
Let me out, damn it
Let me out!
You guys refuse to mend your ways despite of repeated admonition!
Take off this thing!
Get it out of my head! You idiots!
Everything is peace, old guy!
Juliette! Mom!
Help!
We catch him!
Lumme, I can't believe
All are here
Lock them all! I will tell my Grandpa!
The old guy is not around now
What do you want?
His foolish ship, useless guitar...
And useless madness
Old gaot! What happened to my parents?
Do you really want to know? Yes, come on!
They went to hell
even without a goodbye!
Loser!
It's our new captain
Calamity is coming¡­     We are dead
Don't worry, Lili, she will pay for it
That chelonian¡­
She said, even if I make friend with her
But she won't make friend with me
I don't know how to do
I didn't think that she will bring so many trouble
It will be alright, Lili, who can know that in advance?
We must hold together now
Chick! What do they want to do?
Chick¡­Chick¡­
They are epilating...
Epilate chick?
I won't let this happen
We can't help, they are already crazy
We can't help?   It's easy to say
How could you do? You are just a child
I will let you know who is child
Let's go, Lili
Be careful!
hum, guys?
How is the feeling of being dominator?
Your troubles are over!
You can enjoy your lives!
Now you are the no. 1! No. 1!
Chick, braise it now
It will be delicious food after 5 minutes?
Incredible!
Our young friends run away
And are scared
No, we are not scared!
But you are an old witch!
What? Old witch!
Right! Say it again, slug
I hate these dirty things!
You can't do that! Can I!
Don't quarrel, baby
What happened over there?
Don't have a finger in the pie
Do you hear?
My wife and I want to know
What happened here?
If you don't shut up
The next one to braise is elephant nose!
I'm dead
It's really funny!
Braise elephant nose¡­
Chelonian soup is better!
Don't speak, Roger, don't forget you are allergic
Friends, listen to me!
We ged rid of captain, well
His wife goes with him, very well
But¡­children are still here!
They are danger
You can't trust human
They will fight back one day
Oh, what's your suggestion?
Let's get rid of them, quickly
It's easy to say.  How to do?
No idea?
We can¡­   No!
Continue, say it out
You mean, we can¡­
We can¡­
Yes! Eat them
Right
Eat them! We can eat them
Eat them!    Are you crazy?
We can't do that.   They are just children
You are really crazy
If cats don't agree, that's too bad
Wait¡­
We all can express his own opinion
Let's vote.   Who is against?
No,  I really can't do that.   Don't let me do it
Please
Only this?   What do we do it for?
Me
The faster, the better
I agree with tortoise's opinion, it's too dangerous
Or we all will regret
Maybe it's wrong¡­
6 disagree, 1 agree
Now it's clear
Tomorrow morning¡­
Curtain
Ferdinand, come back to me
Don't let me sink
Wake up
Ferdinand! Open your eyes
I'm scared
What are you thinking? Frances
Don't ask me! What's up?
It's terrible
They are right, we are carnivores
Poor guy, you've forgot it
Sausage skin, soup and Juliette's knee¡­
No, but we can't¡­
They bring you in, Bernard
We meet in their home and love each other there
Isn't that meanless?
Of course not
I never guess
Do you know what do I bring?
Do you assume they treat your cat like that, too?
Yes¡­No¡­
You are right
For centuries, human has persecuted us
We tortoises
They hunt up our shell
our eggs, our body and meat
Look, what remains in my arm?
We are cut bit by bit
Day after day, then head¡­
Before crabs and gnawer see bird eat us up¡­
We suffered for weeks like a live food wearhouse
All the family died
So that they can use our shell¡­
to make combs
We endure it silently
We don't say a word
We all shut up our mouths
But it's over
Over
Flood makes my dream come true
Listen to the curse:
Revenge
I will kill you all
All of you
With flashlight¡­
Crocodile will come, too
No one will survive
Perfect weapon
My small nuclear bomb
I'm really sorry about you
One more thing¡­
Eggs
They are not mine
They are crocodiles'
They are crocodiles' last ones
These idiot can't lay eggs in the water
They need dry earth
The flood makes no dry earth
I stealed their last eggs
They will vanish forever
Only me, me
Nothing can stop me
Uncover the thing on the mouth
Red alert
Crocodiles are coming
Crocodiles
Attack
Here, my beauty
Here
Cheer up
Crocodiles
Attack
Guys, he is on the crocodiles side
Damn it!  We are cheated
Listen everyone
We have to think a way out
I will try to start the engine
Start, Tom
The problem is¡­
I don't know how to do
They are coming
Gete, it's bad
Come on, they are coming
Come on
Lovely crocodiles, you have many delicious food
I have to lesson the tortoise
I will eat her
I don't know how to start it
Thigh, ass meat and filet
And pig mouth¡­ Go in, dear
They catch up with us
Godmother bless us
Start, the old rubbish
Continue! Start
It turn to another direction
Shift
What are you doing?
We are now putting us into their mouthes
Stop
Retreat
We are advancing to them
Retreat, Tom
We are still not safe
They are still following us
Accelerate, Tom
I've tried my best
Still there?
I can't see,  I'm too scared
Action
You will be feed for crocodiles
Go to hell
But what¡­
What's the matter with me?
You are here, Ferdinand!  You are back
You are here
Hope Basti go to heaven!  What's that?
That's our barn!  Our ship
Attention
Here
They are ramming toward us
I can't hold any more,  you are too heavy
What do you see downside?
They are behind us
I can't grasp it, the ship shakes too much
It will explode
It's bad.     We've found the reason
Party is here
Continue, crocodiles
Now they are all yours
It's they who steal your last eggs
Your children, your offspring
Falderal
You are here now, of course you will lie
To fool you
Think a way out, she needs help
You know I'm allergic to tortoise
I can't believe
That's what you are worrying about?
Called pachyderm?
Ok!   obey you     If I have spots, don't complain
Your eggs are all here
I can help you find them
But at first, eat up all the dogmeat in the ship
Let me go, you idiot! Let me go
my shell
He divests of my shell
He divests of tortoise's shell
Murderer
Give back my shell
What's that?  where do you get there eggs?
You are really crazy, they are mine
They are stolen from crocodiles'
Nonsense!   They are my eggs
They come from my ovary
I'm the mother
Don't you see?   She has penis
She is male
She cheats us!
Yes,  actually,  for tortoise¡­
male tortoises lay eggs
Impossible.  Only female can lay eggs
that's girl's job
Think other things
Guy.   It's impossible
She just want to deal with us!   Wait
I can explain   Then explain
Ok, female tortioses lay eggs
But my situation is¡­
Dregs
Calm down¡­   Don't do that to me
Control yourself    I can't
To be honest, I can't
My shell
What shall we do?
Cut his tongue and let him shut up
No, it's too simple      Now he must be punished
Let those crocodiles eat him!
Do you want him?
You bet we want!
wait! Let's cut him first
Cut him into pieces to make a soup!
Good idea!
Revenge!   Go to hell!
Stop!
Stop!   Everybody stop!
Tom! Lili!
Let me go there!  Are you ok?
Children¡­
Do I meet a hero?
Mom!
Are you ok?   Are you wounded?
I love you too much
Ok?  Shall we punish him now?  Punish him?
You mean, kill him?
How could we do others?
You are beyond redemption!
Who gives you the power?
Come on, tell me are you judge?
Death penalty? Come on, explain to me!
They are right,  let it be
Don't do that,  it's complicated enough
You idiots, look at yourselives
Your answers are just brutality and violence
What do you get from it?   A cut of slug?
you are nothing!
Captain, what do we want to say is¡­ sorry
We don't know what's wrong with us
Your apology is the last thing I need
Do you know who are you?   Yes
Pilgarlic   You are weak!
Consider it for yourself!
Look, how fool you are!
make all the things messy!
Thanks god, nobody dies!
Actually¡­
What?  Actually?
The chicken problem¡­
Which problem? Which chicken?
We are very hungry¡­  I don't believe
I don't believe!   abhorrent!
You really bring the cookie
What else can I say?
What can I say?
I have nothing to say
I have nothing to say!
There are not many people on the ship
Now we won't see hen, cock, chick and eggs any more
Our chances of living become smaller and smaller
Life is weak
We need each other
How can we let them believe this?
It's that chelonian, papa   she is evil
She actually is very evil
She feed crocodiles with us
She said it's revenge
Nothing can prove revenge is right
Seems they are crazy!
When you light up the fire of violence¡­
You never know how to extinguish it
He isn't wrong!
It's a worse thing
Thanks
Don't forget this forever, children
Do you see the trailer, papa?
I could drive it very well before
You are smart
I am also good without your help
Let's talk romorrow morning
Go to sleep
Good night, papa
Papa¡­it's the second time
Now you call me "papa"?
I must get used to it
Go, little baby
papa!
My lovely son
When the sun rises from my sail
Morning wind blows on my face gently
Telling me a beautiful¡­
tale of sea sailor
If I have a son¡­
A lovely boy
to cherish, that will be so good
If I have a son¡­
A child¡­
who lives for love
A child who lives for love
we get along with each other, don't we, Lili?
Yes, Tom
Whom will you marry with?
Guess
I don't know, do I know her?
Maybe¡­
I don't want to now
Let's play "yes or no"
Yes   You lose
Why?   You said "yes"!
No    You lose again!
It's unfair   We haven't start yet
Lili
Come on! Big cat is giving birth to little cat!
It is actually the same as his father
The same
Classified by texure
Texture!
These guys' head is abnormal
He is still young
What names shall we give them?
Children will name them
I don't know either
Mistin Gady
I believe it's a girl's name
He should be called Barcod
I will teach him to fight
The last one is Noah
We have no better choice
Shall we have a look?
May I move over?
What are you doing over there?
Nothing    We just want to see what happened
How do you come in?
From the sides
We are always being forgot
after we landed, we think¡­
land? From the sides?
Wait!   Stand aside!
Stand aside!
He said stand aside!
Damn it! It freezes!
Anchor     We've arrived!
we are saved!
Be quiet!
Shut up!
Sh!
Listen¡­
Good evening everyone
After 3000 miles of rushing about
Glad to see you
And no water anywhere
Mom, papa
Sweetie
My baby!  I thought you were dead
dead?  We?  You can't kill Lamotte
We seems very strong
You don't know how important he is to us
Don't do that  Now we are here
What are we doing in here, peach?
How are you?
I thought I can't see you any more
We are really lucky
Your father always want to do the shortcut
Lili, Louise! How you¡­
My god, where have you been?
Anyway, we are back again
How did you get through the flood?
Flood?   Which flood?
Do you want to fool me?
We just pass the catastrophe, don't we?
Which catastrophe, Mr. Ferdinand?
It rains all the time
The flood is very large, Louise¡­
Really absurd!
They are joking with us!
Don't joking with us
Let's drink, ok?
Do you have france Pastis?
What are you waiting for?
Old Lamotte doesn't change¡­
Do you see the time?
No, why do you ask that?
Past sleep time
It's a special day today
Let's make a leading card
2 hours past
Now it's midnight!
Midnight?    Oh?  It's the first time, Danis¡­
Will they kill us, won't they?
Sleep at ten,  we all agreed
Now you change your mind
You blow hot and cold everyday
I'm not changing my mind, I just follow the intuition
Your intuition can't substitute for sleep
Then go to sleep!  Only me alone?
Ain't you serious
Then shut up
We are happy
You change your mind,  yes
Only fool doesn't change
Are you refering to me, Roger?
No, how could I refer to you
I'm sure you are refering to me
I'm absolutely not
Really?   Of course not¡­
Dear, in your mom's life
I feel that you don't love me any more
Oh, why do you think so?
Tell me, you love me because you need me
Of course I do
Say, I never heard it    Don't do that¡­
You know I do
No need to say that
Look, in another word, you don't love me
What are you thinking about?
Ok, I love you
Are you happy now?
The End!