Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Go, go.
Alright, let's go, guys.
Hey, hey.
Can you check again?
Yeah, sure.
I'll go check for you.
Oh, no.
Hey, Chief!
We're in trouble!
Chief!
Adul.
Take his hand, will you?
I want to go home.
We have to find higher ground
to escape the water.
This way, sir.
Nothing we can do tonight.
They have to stay in the cave...
for now.
I'm sure the coach
will take care of the boys
I can't hold my breath long enough.
It's too far.
There's no way we're getting out.
I'm scared.
Don't worry, okay?
Someone is going to find us.
No one is going to...
Don't lose hope just yet, guys.
Of course, someone will find us.
Good morning. One iced coffee, please.
Did you hear about the boys?
What boys?
The 12 boys that got stuck in the cave.
The Wild Boars Football Academy.
They haven't come out yet.
- How did you know about that?
- Everyone is talking about it.
Today, I'm calling upon all of you.
If you can help,
wait outside of your house.
We will go help the rescuers
at Tham Luang cave.
Stay home, Granny has to go now, okay?
Please, goddess Nang Non,
help the kids come out of the cave.
Don't worry.
- He should be able to help.
- Yes.
Here, sir.
Where is he?
Over there, sir.
- Welcome.
- Good morning.
This way, please.
Hello. Yes, I'm back.
I know.
They haven't come out yet?
Excuse me.
This is Mr. Tan Xiaolong from Peaceland
Foundation, sir.
Hello.
Do you have a map of the cave complex?
I'm sorry, we don't have that.
It's confidential.
If he's a foreigner, I think you should go
to that tent over there.
And I also teach how to use rebreathers
I'm sure everyone in the country...
is closely following this story...
about the disappearance
of the Wild Boars football team.
- There're so many obstacles...
- Yes, it's raining constantly.
So the water level became very high...
Down a bit more.
Yes it's Pooyai Tun, Baan Laem.
Oh, Professor Adisorn?
The boys stuck in Tham Luang cave.
Yes, I saw the news.
It's really sad.
Yes, our PVC Turbojet pumps?
But I already sold them all.
Let me think. I don't know...
if I have any left,
or can borrow from anyone.
I'll go check now.
Coach, why is the water coming up so high?
You said it would go down.
The water has to rise up first
before it goes down.
We should turn the torch off.
Save the batteries.
Oh, right on time. Come, come.
Let's put the pump on the truck.
Can we get two on each side?
Alright, hurry.
Fantastic.
That's it.
Mai, help them lift it into the truck.
The boys have been in there
for too long already.
Yes, that's it.
Yes, Pooyai Tun.
Councilor, the pumps that you
ordered from me...
for the 9,000 rai flooded rice fields.
Do they still work well?
Yes, they still work well.
This is a Thai Navy SEALS operation.
We can't let the foreign divers in.
Please excuse me.
The water has risen too much.
I cannot take responsibility
for your safety.
Princess Nang Non and the stable boy
were in love with each other.
But her father, the king, was very angry.
So he ordered his soldiers to kill him.
How sad for Nang Non.
Did she really stab herself
with her hairpin?
This water is her blood.
Right when she stabbed herself...
the blood wouldn't stop.
Then became the water in here.
Guys.
Before we entered...
Did anyone remember to pay respect to her?
It's just a legend. Don't think too much.
I'm sorry.
Please let me go home.
Good morning.
Where are you from?
Professor Adisorn contacted me
to bring my PVC Turbojet pumps
to help the kids.
Okay, okay.
I can't let in vehicles without a permit.
You have to park outside.
- Could you help me to get in, please?
- Alright, back up, sir.
I brought water pumps. Who do I talk to?
- ...they can't be used.
- But they came with the truck.
- The lines are just not long enough...
- Good morning, sir.
Hold on. Can I help you?
I came all the way
from Baan Laem, Petchaburi.
We manufacture Turbojet pumps
and sell them all over the world.
- You mean water pumps?
- Yes, Turbojet.
I really want to help the boys.
Do you have a permit?
No, not yet.
I don't know who to contact.
Okay, listen.
First, you have to get a permit
at the Department of Disaster Prevention
or the Provincial Administration Office
so you can be involved
in this mission, sir.
Could someone take me there?
Sorry, I have to take this call.
Hello, sir?
Lottery tickets, anyone?
Pooyai Tun? Are you Pooyai Tun?
- Yes, that's me.
- Hello, I'm Professor Adisorn, sir.
So good to finally meet you.
I've spoken to everyone.
They won't let us in.
There are a lot of procedures.
I talked to them about the water pumps.
Can you wait for a bit?
No one will give us a badge.
Do you have one?
Here. Take mine first.
- Thank you so much.
- Yes. I will see you up there.
- I'm coordinating with the higher-ups.
- Okay, that's great.
Do you have any number 13s?
No, they're all gone. I only have 9s.
Ok, I'll take one.
Here, some water.
I have a badge.
Hey, Mai.
With these small size pumps the cave
will never be dry.
Yes, Pooyai. If it comes out like this,
it will never be dry.
We can put our pump right there.
Professor, you need to understand me.
If the documents are incomplete
someone has to be responsible.
Please listen to me, sir.
The pumps you're using right now
are not sufficient, sir.
I've brought the best person
in the country to you.
If you give Pooyai's water pumps a try
and if they don't work,
I'll take them all back, sir.
Then why don't you take your smartass
back to your hometown.
We manufacture PVC Turbojet water pumps
that are lightweight but very powerful.
I really want to help the kids
in the cave...
Have you tried contacting the governor?
No, not yet. I don't know where to go.
At the Provincial City Hall, sir.
How do I get there?
I have no idea where to go.
So you've been in the cave
and you are one million percent confident?
- Yes, a million percent.
- How so?
We have to set up the Turbojet pumps.
To drain the water as fast as we can.
So we can reach the inner chambers.
So what's your take on the current set up?
To be honest it's like a child peeing...
Is it true that you're the reincarnation
of the stable boy?
Fifty-fifty.
Do you think you'll be able
to help all the kids?
Let me take a look first.
Professor Adisorn
Professor Adisorn is calling again.
You're not going to answer it?
Lek, I cannot contact Pooyai at all.
He doesn't answer his phone.
Who is it?
Pooyai, can you come back, please?
Please come back to help my nephew.
I'm begging you.
How do we know
if they are going to let us in?
I'm going to find a way to talk to them.
I do not want my nephew to die.
Okay...
Well, we'll see.
Please.
We did it, Lek.
We did it.
Dear goddess Nang Non,
please help me save the kids.
I'm hungry.
Very hungry.
Coach, what can I eat?
Hey.
Did you hear a chicken?
There are no chickens in caves, silly.
What are you going to eat, when we're out?
My mom's pork larb.
Auntie Lek's papaya salad.
KFC.
Of course, chicken as always.
Breast or drumstick?
- Drumstick.
- Breast.
Drumstick.
Coach.
Can you take us to KFC again?
So, I've talked to every department.
They haven't given approval.
There's no way those small pumps
can drain the cave.
I've tried everything, Pooyai.
I'll gather all the relatives
to petition the governor!
So Pooyai Tun can bring his pumps
to help the kids.
Lek, calm down.
We have to wait.
We don't have a solution.
What can I do?
We'll have to wait.
Hello, Councilor Neng?
We've got 10 of your pumps
ready to deliver.
But they have not approved us, councilor.
A friend of mine
works for the Royal Foundation.
He is going to let us borrow their truck.
That's brilliant.
Pooyai!
You're amazing.
I'm so happy.
Hey, be careful, guys.
Bring it inside.
Be careful.
Steady, be careful.
Slowly.
This way, this way.
Electrician, please turn on the switch!
Mai, are the pumps
in chamber three set up yet?
Yes, they are.
We are running two at the same time.
We can see the tunnel entrance now.
The British divers are suiting up.
Great. Can you take me to the tent?
I can't walk properly.
Coach.
What is it?
I'm thirsty.
Come. I'll take you.
Careful.
Slowly, be careful.
Walk slowly, don't rush.
Hey, what's that sound?
What sound?
I don't hear anything.
You really didn't hear it?
Hey, quiet!
The 12 boys
of the Wild Boars football team
and their coach have now been found alive.
Nom Sao Slope,
where the kids were found...
is three km away from the cave entrance.
Nong.
They've found the boys.
This good news is like a miracle.
Option two, they can pump the water
out of the cave as much as they can.
But this method could take four months
until the monsoon season is over.
- Good afternoon, Chief.
- Good afternoon.
Mae Bua, please sign here.
Fill in your account number.
Your total is 13,169 baht.
You will receive it within two months.
I won't take it, Chief.
Please take it, Mae Bua.
You've sacrificed so much.
It's really not a big deal.
Isn't that right, everyone?
Our rice crops might be ruined
but we can always replant them, Chief.
But the trapped boys...
I just want them to get out alive.
This is the government's money
for helping the boys.
There's no way I would take it, right?
I won't take it, sir.
Me neither.
Me too.
Smile, handsome.
Show me two fingers.
Excellent.
This is not something that ordinary
recreational divers can comprehend,
It is extremely complex and requires
specialized equipment
and very specialized training
I'm not very optimistic...
...here to support the divers
in the rescue mission.
May good luck be with us.
Let's bring those boys home.
Excuse me, sir.
I'm ready.
Have you got a buddy yet?
Not yet.
Let me speak to the chief.
Go wait over there.
Sir.
What's up?
Saman is free and wants to come with us.
Sure.
You and Sam can take oxygen tanks
to chamber four.
Alright.
Good luck.
He approved.
We are the second ones to dive.
Hand them down.
Sergeant Sam, Sergeant Dum.
Good luck.
Sam.
Give me the tanks. I'll do it.
You can start heading back.
Do you have enough air left?
Yes, I do.
Okay?
Yes, sir.
Sergeant Dum, that's enough...
Sergeant Sam has already done his best.
Sergeant Dum, calm down.
Bring the stretcher.
Calm down.
Give me a hand.
One, two, up...
Going in was fine but on the way back...
As for the deceased...
his name was Sergeant Saman Kunan
We are trained to work
in risky conditions at all times.
Even if we lose a team member
it's something that we
have to face all the time.
We will not lose courage.
Our team will stay strong.
For our brothers and sisters
who sacrifice their lives for us
we will not let their deaths be in vain.
The governor is coming.
By all accounts, civilian cave divers
are the ones with the experience
needed for this type of circumstance.
It seems that the Thai military are
working with the Americans
and British divers
to rescue the 12 boys and their coach.
From the third chamber
to the cave's entrance
our people will be in charge.
Beyond the third chamber
to where the kids are
the foreign teams will be in charge.
Right now, we have four Thai Navy SEALs
and a doctor with the kids.
The U.S. diver came to say goodbye
and told me he'd been transferred.
Will you still have the chance to go in?
I don't have a dive buddy right now.
I'm not sure what's going to happen.
Coach.
Who would you suggest to leave first?
Nick,
Note,
Tle,
and Mark, sir.
They all live the farthest.
They have to ride their bikes very far.
At 10:00 AM this morning,
rescuers, cave divers
and cave specialists...
13 people in total...
have entered the cave...
to carry out the extraction of the kids.
These two British divers
are going inside today.
First one...
Jim Warny,
10:00 AM.
Connor.
Mae Bua!
The Wild Boars are coming out!
They're coming out.
We have successfully rescued two
of the boys from the cave.
The rescue mission is in full swing.
Here we are.
What we see here are the ambulances
carrying the boys out.
The rescue started
at 10:00 AM this morning.
...but I can guarantee that we have
rescued four Wild Boars already.
I must apologize for not answering
all the questions...
Today, we're offering oblation
to the goddess Nang Non.
We pray for the 13 kids
trapped in the cave to come out safely.
We have just received confirmation that
a fifth boy
has been rescued from the cave.
Coach. We're out safe already.
Lift him in.
Wait a moment, not yet.
Take it easy.
Keep your hands down, okay?
Stay still, please.
I'm going to take the blindfold off.
Then you can slowly open your eyes.
Slowly now.
Very slowly.
Slowly.
Open them slowly.
Give me the pillow.
Stay lying down.
No need to worry.
You're safe now.
Do you remember your friends' names?
You remember anything?
Remember anyone?
Ti... Ti...
- Titan.
- Titan, right?
Everyone is safe now.
No need to worry, alright?
Stay still, please.
Everyone is safe.
Everyone is safe now.
Don't worry.
We're helping everyone out.
Relax.
You'll see them all soon.
Everybody is safe.
Prepare 10ml of oxygen...
Relax.
Breathe slowly.
Breathe in deeply.
Thank you very much.
Thank you so much.
We've accomplished something
that no one expected we could do
for the first time in the world...
we succeeded.
So happy.
One of the relatives from Petchaburi...
she was crying.
She was crying...
So...
She was crying. Wanted you to go back?
To go and help...
She believed in me...