Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
THE GIRL WITH THE DRAGON TATTOO
BASED ON STIEG LARSSON'S NOVEL
Today the verdict was delivered
in the Wennerström case.
The publisher of Millennium
Magazine, Mikael Blomkvist, -
- has been accused of libel -
- by successful businessman
Hans-Erik Wennerström.
Blomkvist had accused Wennerström of
gun-running and other serious felonies -
- amounting to over 60 million kroner.
The Swedes have never agreed
on Mikael Blomkvist.
His supporters claim
he's the last bastion -
- of a journalism with ideals.
But Blomkvist's long career -
- as a watchdog may now be over.
In the case of
Wennerström versus Millennium, -
- the accused Mikael Blomkvist is
found guilty on 6 out of 8 counts.
The accused is sentenced to
three months in jail -
- and will pay damages of 150,000
kroner to Hans-Erik Wennerström.
You have to stop people
like Kalle Blomkvist -
- who sniff around in other people's
business due to political differences.
- How will you celebrate?
- No comment.
There he is.
- What's it like to be found guilty?
- Wonderful.
Can you continue
your work as a reporter?
- Cheers, everybody. Merry Christmas.
- Cheers. Merry Christmas.
- Cheers.
- How do we appeal the verdict?
We support you
one hundred per cent, Micke.
But we have to do something.
Our advertisers are losing trust.
- We won't win it back by appealing.
- But it'll buy us some time.
- No appeal. It's over.
- Millennium's future is at stake.
The faster this ends,
the better for Millennium.
I don't want
to play devil's advocate, -
- but it might be a good idea
if Mikael took leave from Millennium.
Till this thing's blown over.
Merry Christmas.
Wait, Micke.
- They're in shock.
- Only Janne dares to speak the truth.
- I was set up. I'm a problem.
- We just have to find a way.
It's empty in here.
I haven't written a single word
for months now.
Do you understand?
WENNERSTRÖM
KNOCKS OUT BLOMKVIST
GOING TO PRISON
Damn.
We don't normally introduce
the researchers to our clients.
But your client is special to us,
so we'll make an exception.
- It's much appreciated.
- But I must warn you.
- Lisbeth is a pretty odd girl.
- What do you mean by odd?
Make no mistake.
She's the best researcher we have.
Good morning, Lisbeth.
Good morning.
Dirch Frode.
Transcripts of text messages.
E-mails. Bank statements.
How did you get access
to all this?
You order the goods.
I deliver them.
What can you tell me
about Blomkvist?
- It's all in my report.
- The short version.
Blomkvist was nicknamed after fictional
boy detective Kalle Blomkvist -
- when he foiled
a bank robbery in the eighties.
He's a public figure without any big
secrets. Read all the news clippings.
- But he does have secrets?
- Everyone has secrets.
To what extent is he affected by
the crisis at Millennium?
- Financially, I mean.
- Why don't you just read the report?
Miss Salander,
is there anything you'd like to add?
What's your personal take on him?
There's something fishy
about the Wennerström case.
What do you mean?
There's more to the case?
I'm researching Blomkvist,
not doing his job.
I'd just like to hear
your personal opinion.
Blomkvist's totally clean.
I didn't find anything on him.
I don't think he faked any evidence
against Wennerström.
I think he was set up.
Why didn't you ask me?
- No lawyer could save me.
- I know. I read the verdict.
I didn't want to involve you.
But you could've asked me.
I'm your sister.
- I know.
- I'm glad.
I'm already in the gutter.
Why drag the family down with me?
And you're going to prison.
It's insane.
The secret to good meatballs
is to wet your fingers.
When you roll them,
rub your hands together.
Shit. Will you answer it, please?
- Hello, this is Micke Blomkvist.
- You little rascal.
- This is Mikael.
- Mikael Blomkvist?
- Yes. Who's this?
- My name's Dirch Frode.
I'm a lawyer and I have
a client who'd like to see you.
- It's Christmas. What is it about?
- My client will tell you himself.
Call Millennium after New Year's Eve.
My client doesn't like waiting.
- Who's your client?
- Henrik Vanger.
From the Vanger Group?
My client would be very grateful
if you'd come.
Listen, it's Christmas,
and it's been a hell of a week.
I promise
you'll find it interesting.
Blomkvist!
Henrik lives on the island of Hedeby,
a mile or two from Hedestad.
The bridge is the only link
to the mainland.
In the old days, the Swedish
business elite came here.
Now it's just Henrik and his
housekeeper Anna who live here.
Thank you for coming, Mikael.
Frode's call was pretty unusual.
- Are you hungry? It's lunchtime.
- No thanks. Let's get started.
- I'm going back again today.
- Right. No lunch then.
Do you remember her?
It's Harriet Vanger,
my brother Gottfried's daughter.
You've met her.
This girl?
Your father worked for me
during the summer of 1965.
He was a mechanical engineer at
the plant and lived in a cottage here.
You and your mother
came for visits -
- during the weekends.
Harriet looked after you.
You often played
down there by the water.
I remember her.
- Harriet.
- I never had any children of my own.
Harriet was the apple of my eye.
An incredibly smart girl.
She was like a daughter to me.
What happened to her?
- I believe she was killed.
- Killed?
This is the Vanger family, Mikael.
My family.
September 22nd, 1966. On that day
the family gathered in this house -
- for the yearly board meeting.
30 small-minded
and greedy people -
- fighting for
the biggest slice of the cake.
One of these people...
...killed Harriet.
Harriet was 16 years old.
It was Children's Day.
She'd been to Hedestad to
watch the parade in the main street.
This picture
was in the local paper.
She returned to the island
around two o'clock.
She wanted to see me, but...
...I was too busy
with the meeting.
How was she killed?
Nobody knows.
She just disappeared.
You're well prepared.
I've been thinking about
that day for 40 years.
That's what I call preparation.
Quarter after two there was a serious
road accident on the bridge.
A fuel tanker full of gas
crashed into a car.
The tanker
was blocking the bridge.
It spilled gasoline
all over the place.
Nobody could pass the tanker.
Everyone had to stay on the island.
By chance,
a photographer caught this.
Look at the window.
This is the last picture
taken of Harriet.
Officer Morell from Hedestad Police
was in charge of the investigation.
He found this film
and had the photo blown up.
Since then nobody has seen her.
We waited for her at dinner,
but she never turned up.
- Hello?
- Lisbeth Salander?
- Who's this?
- It's the probation department.
I'm calling to tell you
you've got a new guardian.
I already have one.
Your current guardian
has had a stroke -
- so I've had to find you
a new one.
I'm glad we could meet
even though it's Christmas.
It's a little unfortunate -
- that Palmgren had such a relaxed
attitude towards guardianship laws.
I see you were allowed
to control your own finances.
- There haven't been any problems.
- No, maybe not.
But as your guardian, I'm legally
and financially responsible.
So I'm to blame if you suddenly
can't come up with your rent.
I work.
I earn my own money.
Yes, I can see you work for
Milton Security...
- What do you do?
- I make coffee and photocopies.
This is what we'll do:
From now on your pay will be deposited
into a new account that I administer.
Each month you'll get a small amount
for personal necessities, -
- but all other expenses have to be
approved by me. Okay?
How do you look after
your personal hygiene?
What do you mean?
With all those rings.
Don't you get infections?
Do you have a boyfriend?
No.
Have you ever had sex?
I'm 24.
I can either write down
that you are cooperating, -
- or that you are causing problems
and being difficult.
And then your life'll get harder
very quickly.
So how many people
have you had sex with?
- Two.
- Two?
200.
No. 2,000.
- 200,000. Are we done now?
- What kind of sex do you have?
Any special preferences?
What if she simply ran off?
You have to keep the accident in mind.
The bridge was closed for 24 hours.
That's the only way off the island.
So Harriet disappeared
when nobody could leave.
It was only the next day we started
thinking there might be a crime.
But then the bridge was open and the
killer could've disposed of the body.
She could have drowned,
killed herself.
We dragged for her body. We had
tracker dogs and divers everywhere.
Even today,
when I go for a walk, -
- I catch myself looking for her.
When Harriet was eight,
she gave me a birthday present.
A framed bluebell
from 1958.
After that she gave me
a new flower each year.
1966.
The year Harriet disappeared.
We're going to the attic.
Amazing.
Every damn year, I receive
a framed flower on my birthday -
- from some far corner
of the world.
- Who do you believe sends them?
- Harriet's killer.
You don't know my family. You don't
know what they're capable of.
Harriet was my favorite. That made her
the ideal victim for those -
- who wanted more power
in the Vanger Group.
They wanted to crush me.
I'm 82 years old.
The police gave up long ago.
I'll end up going to my grave
without knowing.
Help me by giving it one last try.
- Why me?
- I've followed your career.
You're a damn good reporter.
Persistent.
I'm not asking you to solve
the mystery. Just try.
You've six months before
you have to serve your sentence.
You've devoted 40 years to...
I'll pay you handsomely.
You'll be well off.
You've got nothing to lose.
Nothing's waiting for you
in Stockholm.
"Mikael Blomkvist resigns from
Millennium's board -
- and will no longer
work for the magazine."
Did you write this press release
without talking to me?
Only I could make that decision.
What now?
I'll work for Henrik Vanger.
Henrik Vanger?
I see. So now you're working for
the big capitalists?
It's not for the Vanger Group.
You're gonna stay there?
In Hedestad?
Have a nice trip.
Come on, motherfucker!
What are you looking at?
- What the fuck?
- What are you doing, damn bitch?
That bitch is going down.
- Fucking bitch!
- Get her down!
- The bitch is fucking crazy.
- Come again, you cunts!
Come on.
Shit.
What do you think?
- I can save the hard drive.
- Good.
And the rest?
You have to go shopping.
- How did it happen?
- Never mind.
You stink of beer.
You think you smell
like you just took a shower?
You can borrow my old computer.
I'm using it for back-up,
so it has to stay here.
Welcome to Hedeby.
Wonderfully refreshing
with this icy weather.
You didn't want to stay in the main
building. I hope you'll like it here.
If it gets any colder,
the pipes will freeze.
Then you'll have to
come to me for water.
Oh, there you are.
Just leave it there.
It's some of the stuff I've collected
over all these years.
There are photographs.
Police reports.
News articles.
Even some of Harriet's belongings.
Well, it's a start.
You were a beautiful babysitter.
What happened to you?
Keep Sweden pure!
We are the Swedish
National Socialists -
- and the Aryan race
can't do without us!
All in all, the Vangers are a
pretty unpleasant bunch.
Most of us hate each other,
but are forced together by business.
My brother Harald lives in there.
We don't get along, to put it mildly.
Your brothers Richard and Harald
joined a Nazi group in the 30's.
I see...
You already know about that.
Gottfried was a member of
the Hitler Youth.
All three were Nazis.
Yes. And fanatics, at that.
Richard died in the
Finnish Winter War.
Harald has turned into a bitter,
old man. He never leaves the house.
Harald's daughter Cecilia
is currently in Scotland.
Cecilia and Harald
are not on speaking terms.
Martin lives up there.
Harriet's brother.
He took over
the Vanger Group after me.
Hi.
Well, well. If it isn't the
famous Kalle Blomkvist.
Just call me Mikael.
Then I know who you're talking to.
I'm eager to hear why on earth -
- you are to spend six months
in this godforsaken place.
Martin's and Harriet's father,
Gottfried, -
- led a miserable, alcoholic life
with his wife Isabella.
I've never seen a woman be as bad
a mother as Isabella was to Harriet.
I stepped in and took
Harriet and Martin under my wing.
And that's all of the Vangers
who live here.
On that day, even more joined us.
Cecilia's sister Anita
who died from cancer.
- Greger Vanger and Ulrika Vanger.
- Wait a minute.
Who do you suspect?
Nobody.
And everybody. That's where you
come into the picture.
Dear Diary. Today I got this diary
from my dear uncle Henrik.
A kind, but busy, man.
He's finally home from his travels
and brought me this diary.
I'm by myself in my dad's cottage.
Anita will be here soon.
So you're the one
sniffing around in family matters?
Hell, you scared me.
Cecilia Vanger.
Henrik said you'd be here.
- Mikael Blomkvist.
- I recognize you from the papers.
- What have you found?
- Harriet's Bible.
She was often up here
with my sister.
- Anita?
- Yes.
The summer before she disappeared.
- Odd, seeing that her father died here.
- Gottfried died here?
He was drunk and fell into the lake.
They found him the next morning.
Just down there.
It happened the year before
Harriet disappeared.
Henrik said you were traveling.
I had to come home
in order to hide Harriet's body.
We weren't allowed to be here
when we were kids. It was off-limits.
Thanks.
Dear Diary. It's fall now.
The weather's getting colder.
Magda 30112.
Sara 32016.
BJ 32027.
LJ 31208.
Mari 32018.
I don't understand
why Henrik hired you.
To be honest, neither do I.
With all respect,
there's nothing to find.
It's been nearly 40 years.
You found Harriet's diary
in her dad's cottage.
- The diary didn't help us one bit.
- What about the phone numbers?
- They were a complete mystery to us.
- But 32 is...
32 could be Hedestad.
30 is Norrbyn's area code.
But the names
and the numbers don't match.
- Did you call them up?
- We did. We even tried backwards.
We switched them, removed numbers.
We tried everything.
In the report, she's described as
withdrawn and religiously inclined.
Was that your impression?
Who isn't withdrawn at that age?
But, yes. She kept to herself.
Anita, her cousin, knew her the best.
Anita is Cecilia Vanger's sister.
And Anita is dead.
She died many years ago.
Harriet was my first case.
I've thought about it
every day for nearly 40 years now.
I'm retiring this summer. It's only
now that I'm able to let it go.
There is no answer.
You'll only breathe life into
Henrik's obsession.
Give it up before you become
obsessed yourself.
What are you working on?
- Who's this week's victim?
- Nobody.
Still that reporter?
I thought you were done with him.
Why do you keep at it?
It's a bit slow.
A new computer?
- Yes, I need 20,000.
- Why do you need a 20,000 kroner PC?
- So I can play, surf the internet.
- You often surf the internet?
Do you chat?
Know what, Lisbeth?
I can't just hand you 20,000.
- Not just like that.
- How hard can it be?
Why can't I
look after my own money?
Hit me. Come on.
That's what you want, isn't it?
Hit me.
If you give me any kind of trouble,
I'll make sure -
- you spend the rest
of your life in a closed ward.
I know all about your mental problems
and your violent background.
Don't get me wrong, Lisbeth...
I'm more than happy
to give you the 20,000.
But, you know,
any business transaction -
- is built on trust.
I have to feel that I can trust you.
Can I trust you, baby?
Can I trust you, Lisbeth?
Can I trust you?
If you're nice to me...
If you're nice to me,
I'll always be nice to you.
- It's only 7,000.
- More than enough for a computer.
What are you looking at?
You said it was a photographer
from the paper that shot the parade.
Yes, he covered both the parade
and the accident.
The old part of the archive
is a jumble.
We haven't digitized it.
It's still kept in negative folders.
20... 30...
...40, 50, 60...
A photographer uses
between two and ten rolls a day.
Probably closer to ten
on Children's Day.
Here. September 1966.
I only need the hour
of the parade.
- Knock yourself out.
- They're not sorted?
If you're lucky,
they might be chronological.
You don't happen to have
a negative scanner and a light table?
This is the first lead in the case
in 39 years.
It's a start.
It's more than that.
Look.
You get my drift?
Something catches her eye.
What is it that frightens her?
Her killer.
He was somewhere here.
Harriet's killer is standing
across the street.
- Coffee, Mikael?
- What have you found so far?
I must've read...
...several thousand pages. People
have worked on this for 40 years.
To be perfectly honest, -
- I haven't found a thing.
Shouldn't you be in Stockholm
trying to appeal your verdict?
- Give it a break.
- You give it a break.
- Mikael's old enough to...
- I was set up.
An old class-mate gave me a tip
concerning Wennerström's company.
It was a good story.
Good enough to nail him.
So you'd think.
Yes, because suddenly there was
an even better story -
- about fraud and gun-running
amounting to 60 million kroner.
Wennerström's name was all over it.
So far, so good.
Until I wrote the story.
Then all my sources disappeared.
And all of the documents and evidence
turned out to be forged.
Fake?
So it was an attempt to lure you away
from the real scandal?
It was too good to be true.
Do you want something that really is
too good to be true?
Single malt. 21 years old.
To hell with all the troubles
of the past. Cheers.
- Cheers.
How about one last glass of wine?
I think I've had more than enough.
- Thanks for a nice evening.
- Is it because of the investigation?
Because of my secretive family?
- What do you mean?
- It could be me. Right?
I guess I'm also
on your list of suspects.
- Bjurman.
- It's Lisbeth.
- What do you want?
- I need more money.
- We'll talk about it.
- I need it now.
Welcome.
Come on in.
- I just want my money.
- You'll get your money.
Thanks for your last visit. I hope
you enjoyed it as much as I did.
I won't give you a blowjob
every time I need money.
Is that right?
Then what do you want?
Do you want me to call
the probate department and say -
- you've trespassed
and you're threatening me?
Then we'll see how quickly
you're back in the psychiatric ward.
So?
That's much better.
Like that.
Come here.
Come on.
No!
I've got... a rule for you to learn.
If you put up a fight...
Are you a good girl?
Are you a good girl now?
NORSJÖ CARPENTERS
My husband died many years ago.
So it's just me left.
He worked there as a carpenter
for 24 years.
They made everything
from clothes pegs to closets.
He built that cabinet.
And the lamp, of course.
More cake?
Do you recall if you were in Hedestad
in September 1966?
Hedestad...
- In '66.
- Yes, in '66.
- Oh, it was our honeymoon.
- Wonderful. Do you have snapshots?
We went camping.
It was all the rage back then.
It was our best holiday together.
But I guess honeymoons
often are.
- But do you have some snapshots?
- I sure do.
Who doesn't save the photos
from their honeymoon?
In the early years,
my husband and I hiked a lot.
My husband was a skilled hiker.
We hiked for miles.
He wasn't exactly romantic.
Now, let's see.
Hedestad...
Look.
So beautiful.
Even if the photo
doesn't do the sunset justice.
Let's see. Here's something.
- There was a parade.
- Do you?
What are you doing here?
I'm on my way out.
You've misunderstood the rules.
You have to make an appointment.
Do you hear me?
Let me go.
Do you hear me? Let me go.
Do you like being tied up?
Or is your only turn-on
tying other people up?
It's great.
Did you choose it yourself?
You didn't?
I think it's perfect.
You know that show where politicians
get busted by candid cameras?
We've got those cameras at work.
I had one in my bag
last time I was here.
Welcome.
I just thought you'd make me
give you a blowjob.
But you're sicker
than I imagined.
It goes on for two hours. Consider the
reaction of the police and the media.
Enjoy.
Thanks for your last visit. I hope
you enjoyed it as much as I did.
I won't give you a blowjob
every time I need money.
Is that right?
Then what do you want?
I'll tell you how we'll do this.
You just nod.
I'll look after my own account.
You'll have no access.
I control my own finances.
You got that?
Each month you write in your report
that my behavior is perfect.
Better than ever before.
In exactly a year, you'll apply for
the termination of my guardianship.
I'll send you further instructions.
You can never contact me again.
If you do, I'll send copies of
the video to the police and the press.
The same thing happens,
if I'm in an accident -
- or if you break my rules.
You got that? Good.
I've never done this before.
Lie still or it'll get messy.
Lie still.
I'M A SADIST PIG
AND A RAPIST
...during the last year...
...an avid interest in religion.
SEND
The guy in the blue sweater.
I can't get his picture sharp.
I can't do a thing about it.
It's so out of focus.
- Are you sure?
- Positive. I've tried everything.
Okay, thanks for trying.
Wasp...
Harriet's phone numbers.
Book of Leviticus...
"If a woman
approaches an animal..."
"If a woman approaches an animal
to have sexual relations with it, -
- kill both the woman and the animal."
"Their blood
will be on their own heads."
Mari 32018.
Magda 30112.
Leviticus,
Chapter 1, Verse 12.
"...she is to bring two doves
or two young pigeons, -
- one for a burnt offering
and the other for a sin offering."
BJ 32027.
"A man or a woman...
"A man or a woman who is a medium
or spiritist among you -
- must be put to death.
You are to stone them."
Must be put to death.
Frode! What's going on?
It was Henrik.
He just collapsed.
- We'll keep you informed.
- Thanks.
It's a heart attack.
He's having emergency surgery.
What are his odds?
They're talking about a bypass
so it's serious.
- You want coffee?
- No.
I think you should
go on with your investigation.
- Have you assigned someone else?
- No, only you.
Someone by the name of Wasp
has hacked into my computer.
I've received an e-mail with copies
of one of my own documents.
So this person must have
gained access to my hard drive.
Do you know anything about this?
No...
No, but I think I've got
a good idea -
- who it might be.
Just stay in bed.
Lisbeth Salander?
- Who are you?
- You know. May I come in?
I've read your report.
Thrilling stuff.
Particularly that you stole my files.
The police would find that intriguing.
They also ought to know that you
are still hacking into my computer.
If you remove those papers,
I'll take off the chain.
What do you want?
- Hi.
- Everything all right?
- What do you want?
- You got any coffee?
How much do you know
about my assignment?
The 40-year-old murder
of a 16-year-old girl.
Until today I wasn't even sure
that she was killed.
Then you directed me to
the Biblical references -
- about women
who should be killed.
- And?
- It's the most important clue so far.
- I need your help.
- I'll pay good money.
- I've already got a job.
You work as a professional hacker, -
- but send me an e-mail
I can easily trace.
Why?
Huh?
So he'll live?
Can I visit him?
Lisbeth Salander's here.
Okay, Frode.
Talk to you soon. Thanks.
If a woman approaches an animal
to have sexual relations...
As we've been sharing files lately,
I assume you're up to date.
I am.
You know... What if these quotes
don't have anything to do with God?
What if it's a code?
Sara Witt was found murdered
in her family's barn -
- outside Vilhelmina in 1962.
Sara? What else does it say?
"Between 2 and 3 am,
the victim was lured..."
"The woman's body was mutilated,
possibly in a religious ritual.
The police won't disclose
any more details."
Mutilated, possibly religious...
Did they find the killer?
No. The case was never solved.
- It's a wild guess.
- I know.
- How far is it to Vilhelmina?
- Too far on a motorcycle.
What are we waiting for?
- You want to drive?
- Why?
- I haven't driven since my divorce.
- Then it's about time.
Why do female names
always bring you to porn sites?
What are you doing?
I'm getting the computer to search
all the newspaper databases.
Let's go to the barn.
They couldn't sell the farm
after what happened.
It's been empty ever since.
This is where she was found?
Yes. Her husband found her.
It was horrific for him. Horrific.
She was lying right here.
In this booth.
Bound and tortured.
Were the animals also harmed?
How did you know?
"If a woman approaches an animal
to have sexual relations with it, -
- kill both the woman and the animal."
- It might be a coincidence.
- Yes.
Goddamn, Lisbeth.
If the others also fit...
I've found an old TV program.
A program from 1999
about a murder in Dalarna.
Go on.
"In the series 'Swedish Murders' comes
the case of Magda Lovisa Sjöberg -
- from Dalarna."
Magda...
"A brutal murder puzzle from
November 1954 that baffled the police."
Didn't we have a Magda reference?
Leviticus,
Chapter 1, Verse 12.
"He is to cut it into pieces...
including the head and the fat."
"And the priest shall arrange them...
on the burning wood on the altar."
That was verbatim.
You quoted it word for word.
As far as I know, Magda's body
was found after only six hours.
By a farmer who saw
the smoke from the fire.
He thought it was
some kids having a party.
Someone cut out fat from the body.
That's right. They found remains
of fat together with the head.
Awful.
What the hell?
Relax!
I just wanted to wake you up.
We're there.
Can I come in?
Here's your bag.
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm okay.
I can't find anyone
who fits the initials BJ.
But LI could be Liv Ingvartsson.
A prostitute who disappeared in Ånge
and was found on a building site.
What was that quote again?
"...she is to bring two doves
or two young pigeons, -
- one for a burnt offering
and the other for a sin offering."
"The priest will make atonement
for her, and she will be clean."
Ånge... That's quite a few miles
in the direction we came from.
I think I've found another one.
A 17-year-old girl from Uppsala.
- When?
- 1964.
"The Mari murder empties the streets".
"Killer still on the loose".
There.
Now we've got Sara, Mari,
Magda and Liv. Four murders.
Now we only need BJ,
who's been circled.
Harriet can't have known them.
Liv was murdered in 1949. Harriet was
born in 1950. What's the connection?
She listed women who'd been killed
and she disappeared.
Harriet must've known
who the killer was.
What is it?
Somebody's been here.
The pictures have been touched.
The Bible is pointing in another direction.
- Look.
- What the hell?
Someone has been curious.
I'll buy a new lock tomorrow.
Lisbeth...
do you have a photographic memory?
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to upset you.
It's fantastic if you do.
I wish that I had it.
Damn, you gave me a scare.
What is it?
What are you doing?
Are you sure it's a good idea?
- Are you leaving?
- Good night.
- Good morning.
Did you sleep well?
- I'm updating Henrik. Want to come?
- I hate hospitals.
But that's...
But that's totally absurd.
You've found out more
than I'd hoped for.
Just concentrate on getting well.
I'll keep you updated.
Regarding the last reference...
- The last name.
- BJ.
Ask Morell if he can help you.
Morell!
I'll be damned!
Five murders!
It wasn't phone numbers.
If it's any consolation,
it wasn't me who cracked it.
We haven't found the last woman
with the initials BJ.
She's circled as if she's particularly
important. It's the last reference.
If there's a woman with these initials
who died in the 40's, 50's or 60's, -
- we've got to find her.
Do you realize what this means?
If the first murder
took place in 1949, -
- the man who's been sending
Henrik flowers is now very old.
It reduces the number of
suspects considerably.
Mikael. We're glad you could make it.
Welcome.
Harald couldn't make it.
He's hunting deer.
To what do I owe the honor?
Have you read
the local paper recently?
I've been out of town.
They're coming out with quite
an interesting series -
- on your exile here on Hedeby.
BLOMKVIST'S YOUNG NEW GIRLFRIEND
- And?
- We don't like it.
Henrik is dying.
My private life has nothing to do
with my assignment for Henrik.
It reflects on everyone
in the Vanger Group.
Haven't you done enough harm? Do you
have to give Henrik a heart attack -
- by picking over
my daughter's death?
- Maybe it's about time you gave up.
- What do you mean?
You're making matters worse
by coming here with your whore.
Don't use that tone, Mom.
But maybe you should take a break now.
It's been a pretty hard deal.
- I'm needed here.
- Mikael, as your friend...
Excuse me, but I have something
to say. Henrik signed a contract.
As long as he lives,
it cannot be cancelled.
So whether Mikael likes it or not,
he has to continue.
I'm sorry that it had to be
so dramatic.
- Why are you wearing Harriet's necklace?
- What do you mean?
Harriet was wearing it when she
disappeared. Now you're wearing it.
What are you trying to say?
Are you accusing me?
Just tell me
where you got it from.
I inherited it from Anita.
It never belonged to Harriet.
Anita, your sister?
Hi, Micke.
Everything all right?
Anita is Harriet.
I was mistaken. It's not her.
What are you talking about?
They both looked after me that summer.
It's Anita's necklace.
Yes, it's Anita.
Shit, those two were so alike.
- What do we know about Anita Vanger?
- Harriet's cousin and closest friend.
They were together each summer.
She had no alibi, but wasn't a suspect.
Right after Harriet's death,
she moved to London to study.
She had a brilliant career, but died
from breast cancer when she was 37.
She died 20 years ago.
She didn't tell Morell
it was her in the window.
- Maybe she had something to hide.
- Maybe she was covering for the killer.
Hi, Plague. I need help.
Will you run a check on Anita Vanger?
- Plague?
- If there is anything, he'll find it.
- What happened?
- Some idiot shot at me.
- Did you see who?
- No. Shit.
We must be very close now.
And someone doesn't like it.
Give me my cell phone.
We have to call the police.
- What can they do?
- Go get it.
Then I'm out of here.
Let's not jump to
any conclusions.
It could be a hunting accident.
If it's not a hunting accident,
then you're not safe here.
I think you should go home.
At least for a while.
Ever since I came here,
everyone keeps asking me to leave.
Anything new on BJ?
We didn't find a BJ in the system.
But we'll keep on searching.
Two cameras outside
and fire in here -
- connected to sensors.
I've got the cottage covered.
Fantastic.
I take it you don't want to go home?
No.
So now we've got it on tape?
Yes.
It's already on the internet.
- What are you doing?
- Sorry?
- Go sleep in your own bed.
- I want to be close to you.
Okay, but I want to sleep.
What has happened to you?
How did you turn out this way?
You know everything about me.
I don't know shit about you.
Not a damn thing.
That's the way it is.
- Who is it?
- Morell.
I've found the last one.
Rebecka Jacobsson,
nickname Bea.
BJ.
That's why we didn't find her.
"A man or a woman who is a medium
or a spiritist among you...
...must be put to death.
You are to stone them."
It's her.
- Where was she killed?
- In Karlstad.
But that's not the interesting part.
Rebecka worked for the Vanger Group
until her death in January 1965.
As a secretary for Gottfried Vanger.
Gottfried died before Harriet disappeared.
So it wasn't him.
But we've got to check if she knew
other members of the Vanger family.
- Hold on.
- What?
Rebecka and Sara are Jewish names.
- Magda...
- Magdalena.
Mari, Maria. But Liv?
Liv means Eve. I bet that
Liv Ingvartsson was Jewish as well.
Racist murders. It fits with the
pseudo religious rituals.
But what about Harriet?
Harriet died because she
discovered a pattern.
How the hell could we miss it?
They're Jewish names. There were
three Nazis in the Vanger family.
Only one was still alive
when Harriet died.
Harald.
Who happened to be hunting
when you ran alone in the woods.
The first murder
took place there in 1949.
Then Dalarna, Vilhelmina,
Uppsala, Karlstad.
If Harald has been there,
he's left traces.
- What do you mean?
- The Vanger Group accounts.
Business travels. There must be
evidence. Restaurant and hotel bills.
You think he got a tax deduction
for murder?
Well, I know about businessmen.
Even if we can prove he's been
everywhere, it's not enough.
- Maybe he's hunting now.
- You suggest we break into his house?
We need to go
back quite a few years.
89... 89...
We need the accounts
from 1949 until 1966.
Thank Henrik for his old-fashioned
business practices.
Otherwise, they would've been
shredded long ago.
Well, there they all are,
knock yourself out.
Miss Salander,
what exactly have you found so far?
Thank you, that was all.
IN THE NAME OF THE FÜHRER
I BESTOW...
What in God's name are you doing here?
Answer me!
Take it easy.
You're gonna write about me
in your damn communist magazine?
I'm leaving now. Don't shoot.
You broke into my home,
so I'm free to kill you.
What the hell is going on here?
- Freeze!
- Drop the gun, Harald.
- Come on, drop the gun.
- It's none of your business!
Drop the gun. Drop it.
Are you okay?
How the hell could Gottfried have
such a wuss of a son?
Harald...
No.
- We've got to call Morell.
- We can call him from my place.
Harald's not going anywhere.
Come on.
Gottfried?
Gottfried.
Uppsala 1964!
January, February...
Wasn't there a group photo?
What the fuck?
It can't be true.
Blue sweater...
What the fuck?
Shit.
Feeling better now?
- He gave me a hell of a scare.
- You don't mess with Harald.
What were you doing in his house?
Harriet discovered a handful of
murders from the 40's to the 60's.
We know she found a pattern
the police didn't know about.
We believe that's why
she was killed.
But that...
It sounds totally insane.
We've found a pattern
regarding the victims.
They've all got Jewish names.
Well, Harald isn't exactly crazy about
Abraham's kin.
No. So I went to his house
to see if I could find anything.
- And?
- Well, what do I know?
He turned up so soon.
But he didn't exactly act innocent.
If Lisbeth can track down his
travel activities from the accounts, -
- we've got evidence against him.
Bills, invoices.
She's going through everything.
Very well. I'll call the police.
Try Morell.
What were you doing at Harald's?
There, there.
Scream as much as you want to, Mikael.
Scream as much as you can.
You think anyone'll hear you?
We both know how it's
going to end for you.
Why?
Why what?
- All of this.
- Why not?
I do what every man dreams of.
I take what I want.
How many women after the first?
I don't know. I've lost count.
I had a girl in that cage
when we were dining upstairs.
Those kinds of women disappear
all the time. Nobody misses them.
Whores, immigrants.
What do you do with them? What about
the references? The mutilations?
That was my father's project. He mixed
his hobby with race and religion.
But it was a mistake.
You shouldn't leave the bodies behind.
I take them for a trip in my boat
and then I drop them into the sea.
Mikael?
Mari was my first.
64.
You were 16 years old.
It was Dad, Gottfried, who taught me
how I should strangle her.
It's sick.
It's mainly for the sex.
When I put them down, it's only
a logical consequence of the rape.
You can't leave any witnesses.
Even though I have to admit
I love seeing their disappointment.
- Disappointment?
- When they realize they'll die.
It doesn't really fit into
their scheme of things.
They always think
I'll show them mercy.
It's a fantastic moment -
- when they realize
they're not going to get away.
When the eyes...
...switch off and die.
You'll experience that yourself.
And your sister? What did it feel like
when your sister's eyes died?
- Harriet disappeared.
- You want me to believe that?
Believe whatever the hell you want.
I would have enjoyed killing her.
But she disappeared.
Just like you'll disappear.
Do you want some water?
Yes, please.
Thanks.
You see...
you're just like everybody else.
It only takes a simple, human gesture
to ignite the small hope -
- that I might let you go after all.
Right?
Take it easy. It'll be quick.
I'm mostly looking forward to
your little girlfriend.
Come on, motherfucker.
Are you okay?
Fuck!
I can't...
I can't move.
Help me.
Please help me.
- Where's Martin?
- He's not coming back.
What do you mean?
He drove to his death.
- He's finished.
- Are you positive?
What the hell did you do?
He died in a car accident.
We don't know anything. Okay?
Blomkvist!
- What the hell happened here?
- The cellar.
What happened out there?
He didn't die in an accident, did he?
Damn, Lisbeth.
His father taught him to kill
when he was 16 years old.
That would make anybody
sick in the brain.
Don't make him into a fucking victim.
He nearly killed you.
He was a killer and a rapist
and he enjoyed it.
He had the same chances as everyone
else. You choose who you want to be.
He wasn't a victim. He was an
evil motherfucker who hated women.
How did he die?
He burned to death.
- Could you have saved him?
- Yes.
- But you let him burn.
I would never have done that, Lisbeth.
But I understand why you did it.
I don't know what you've been through.
But I almost died in that cellar -
- and you saved my life.
Whatever it is you've been through, -
- you don't have to tell me.
I'm just glad you're here.
Thanks.
For the first time in my life
I feel old.
- We're not finished yet.
- What do you mean?
- Harriet wasn't one of Martin's victims.
- What are you saying?
Martin didn't kill Harriet.
Lisbeth?
Two women bear the name Anita Vanger.
One of them died in London.
The other one lives in Australia.
First entry into the country in 1966.
Harriet?
Harriet Vanger?
Everything's all right?
Yes. You and your cousin babysat me
when I was a small boy.
But I'm here on behalf of
Henrik Vanger.
Does he know I'm alive?
Not yet.
I'm here to visit Agneta Salander.
- Who can I say it is?
- Her daughter.
Her daughter?
Are you Agneta's daughter?
I'm sorry, it's just...
I've never seen you before.
Hi, Mom.
Mom?
It's me. Lisbeth.
Lisbeth...
Are you Lisbeth?
I wanted to come
a long time ago.
You look so different now.
- Do you have kids?
- No.
A boyfriend?
There is someone...
...but you should never fall in love.
You know that better than anyone.
Right, Mom?
I should have picked
a better father for you.
Let it be, Mom.
It was you he harmed.
Mom...
Come in.
Mikael. Welcome back.
I've got a nice surprise. Promise me
you won't have a heart attack.
With all the pills
I'm popping at the moment, -
- I think it's physically impossible
to have a heart attack.
Harriet?
Forgive me.
I'm sorry.
I was 14 when Dad raped me
for the first time.
A year later he took me
to his cottage.
Then Martin joined in.
They abused me again
several times after that.
One day I'd had enough.
Dad was drunk as usual.
He reeled off Bible verses and boasted
about all the women he'd killed.
I took the oar and hit him hard.
I pressed him under the water
till it got still.
Then I pushed the boat out
to make it look like an accident.
But when I turned around...
...Martin was there.
Martin treated me even worse
than Gottfried.
You sent him to a boarding school
in Uppsala, -
- but on Children's Day
he came back.
I was terrified
it would start all over again.
And then you went to Anita?
Anita helped me get out of here.
When the bridge was opened,
she drove the car.
I was in the back seat
under a blanket.
I've been thinking of you
all these years.
I sent you the framed flowers -
- because I wanted to tell you
that I was out there somewhere.
So I was sad to hear Mikael say
what you'd read into them.
If you hadn't sent them,
you wouldn't be sitting here now.
No.
Lisbeth, it's me again.
Call me if you hear this.
I hope you're doing okay.
Call me.
You've got a visitor.
Thirty minutes.
I'm so happy to see you.
Here.
- What's this?
- A bit of reading.
- Don't you want to sit down?
- I just wanted to give you that.
I've only got
a month and a half left.
EVERYBODY'S GOT SECRETS
Wennerström's empire resembles
a living, breathing organism...
Reporter Mikael Blomkvist,
who served a prison sentence -
- for libelling the tycoon
Hans-Erik Wennerström -
- now accuses Wennerström again.
In the magazine Millennium, -
- Blomkvist accuses Wennerström
of using his companies -
- to commit serious financial crimes.
- Why are you going after him again?
- It makes you wonder.
- What will happen to Wennerström?
- There's an empty cell now.
Blomkvist describes a financial
empire based on Third World cartels.
Cartels involved in
drug trafficking and gun-running.
There he is!
Cheers!
The wanted tycoon Wennerström -
- was found dead this morning
in an apartment in Marbella, Spain.
A cleaning lady found
the 44-year-old tycoon.
According to the police,
it was suicide.
There's no suspicion of...
The police have now examined
all of Wennerström's bank accounts.
It appears that a large sum
has been withdrawn -
- from an account
in the Cayman Islands.
Several million Swedish kroner
has been withdrawn.
Police are now investigating
an unidentified woman -
- who was caught on a
surveillance camera.
Lisbeth...
Subtitles: Malene Hollnagel
Scandinavian Text Service 2009
THE GIRL WITH THE DRAGON TATTOO