McNAlR:
Mr. Adams!
There you are.
Didn't you hear me
call you, Mr. Adams?
You could've shouted
down something, saved me
climbing up four flights.
A man that likes to
talk as much as you do,
l'd think. . .
What do you keep coming
up here for, Mr. Adams?
Afraid someone's
going to steal our bell?
(CHUCKLES)
Well, don't worry.
Been here more than 1 4 years,
and ain't been carried off
once. (LAUGHS)
Better get yourself
back down to Congress,
Mr. Adams.
Getting ready to vote,
and they said
they couldn't settle
such an important question
without Massachusetts
being there.
l can just imagine.
All right, what burning issue
are we voting on this time?
On whether or not to grant
General Washington's request
that all members
of the Rhode lsland Militia
be required
to wear matching uniforms.
Oh, good God.
l have come to the conclusion
that one useless man
is called a disgrace,
that two are called
a law firm,
and that three or more
become a Congress.
And, by God,
l have had this Congress.
For 1 0 years,
King George
and his parliament
have gulled, cullied
and diddled these colonies
with their illegal taxes.
Stamp Acts, Townshend Acts,
Sugar Acts, Tea Acts.
And when we dared
stand up like men,
they have stopped our trade,
seized our ships,
blockaded our ports,
burned our towns,
and spilled our blood.
And still this Congress
refuses to grant
any of my proposals
on independence
even so much as
the courtesy of
open debate.
Good God, what in the hell
are you waiting for?
Sit down, John
Thomas, for God's sake,
listen to me.
For God's sake
John, sit down
l've had enough of you, sir.
Sit down, John
For God's sake,
John, sit down
Someone ought to
open up a window
Will you listen to me
and forget the window?
lt's 90 degrees
Have mercy, John, please
It's hot as heII
in Philadelphia
Someone ought to
open up a window
l say vote yes
Vote yes
Vote for independency
Someone ought to
open up a window
l say vote yes
Sit down, John
Vote for independency
Someone ought to
open up a window
No, no, no!
Too many flies,
too many flies
But it's hot as heII
in Philadelphia
Are you gonna
open up a window?
Can't we compromise here?
Vote yes
No, too many flies here
Oh, for God's sake,
John, sit down
Good God.
Consider yourselves fortunate
that you have
John Adams to abuse,
for no sane man
would tolerate it.
John, you're a bore
We've heard this before
Now, for God's sake,
John, sit down
l say vote yes
No!
Vote yes
Vote for independency
Someone ought to
open up a window
l say vote yes
Sit down, John
Vote for independency
WiII someone
shut that man up?
Never!
Dear God.
For one solid year
they have been sitting here.
A whole year!
Doing nothing !
l do believe you've laid
a curse on North America
A curse that we here now
rehearse in Philadelphia
A second flood,
a simple famine
Plagues of
locusts everywhere
Or a cataclysmic
earthquake
l'd accept
with some despair
But, no,
you've sent us Congress
Good God, sir,
was that fair?
l say this with humility
in Philadelphia
We're your responsibility
lf you don't want to
see us hanging
from some far off British hiII
lf you don't want
the voice of independency
forever stiIIed
Then God,
Sir, get thee to it
For Congress never will
You see, we piddle,
twiddIe and resoIve
Not one damn thing
do we soIve
Piddle, twiddle and resolve
Nothing's ever solved
ln foul, fetid, fuming,
foggy, filthy
Philadelphia
Someone ought to
open up a window
Oh, shut up.
MAN 1: l now call Congress'
attention to the petition of
Mr. Melchior Meng,
who claims $20 compensation
for his dead muIe.
It seems
the animal was employed
transporting luggage
in the service of Congress.
MAN 2: The question, then,
would appear to be
one of occasion.
For if the muIe
expired not while carrying,
but after being unloaded,
then clearly
the beast dropped dead
on its own time.
Oh, good God.
They may sit here
for years and years
in Philadelphia
These indecisive
grenadiers of Philadelphia
They can't agree on
what is right and wrong
or what is good or bad
I'm convinced
the only purpose
this Congress ever had
was to gather
here specifically
to drive John Adams mad!
You see, we piddle,
twiddIe and resoIve
Not one damn thing
do we soIve
Piddle, twiddle and resolve
Nothing's ever solved
In foul, fetid,
fuming, foggy, filthy
Philadelphia
WOMAN:   John, John
ls that you
carrying on, John?
Oh, Abigail, Abigail,
l have such a desire to
knock heads together.
ABlGAlL: Then why
in heaven's name
do you stay there?
Come home to Boston, John.
lt's only 300 miles.
lf you left tonight,
you could be here
in only eight days.
How can l do that, Abigail?
l'm no further along now
than l was
when l first came here.
l know, my dearest. l know.
But that's because you make
everything so complicated.
lt's all quite
simple, really.
Just tell the Congress
to decIare
lndependency
Then sign your name
get out of there
And hurry home to me
Our chiIdren
all have dysentery
LittIe Tom
keeps turning blue
Little Abby
has the measIes
And l'm coming down
with fIu
They say
we may get smallpox
Madam, what else is new?
Abigail, in my last letter,
l wrote you
that the king had
collected 1 2,000
German mercenaries
to send against us.
l asked you to
organize the ladies
to make saltpeter
for gunpowder.
Now, have you done
as l asked?
No, John, l have not.
Well, why have you not?
Because you neglected
to tell us
how saltpeter is made.
By treating sodium nitrate
with potassium chloride,
of course.
Oh, yes, of course.
Will it be done, then?
John, l'm afraid we have
a more urgent problem.
More urgent, madam?
There's one thing
every woman's missed
in Massachusetts Bay
Don't smirk at me,
you egotist
Pay heed to what l say
We've gone from
Framingham to Boston
And we cannot find a pin
"Don't you know
there's a war on"
Say the tradesmen
with a grin
Well, we will
not make saltpeter
Until you send us pins
Pins, madam? Saltpeter.
Pins.
Saltpeter.
'Peter.
Pins.
'Peter. 'Peter.
Pins. Pins.
'Peter!
Pins.
Done, madam, done.
Done, John.
Hurry home, John.
As soon as l'm able.
Don't stop writing.
lt's all l have.
Every day,
my dearest friend.
TiII then
I am
As I ever was
And ever shaII be
Yours
Saltpeter
John
Pins
Abigail
MEN:   For God's sake, John
Sit down
JOHN: Franklin !
Franklin !
Where in hell are you?
l see you hiding
behind that tree.
lt won't do you any good.
Damn it, this is no time
for playing games.
Franklin,
l have been looking
everywhere for you.
Where in God's name
have you been?
Right here, John,
being preserved
for posterity.
Do you like it?
lt stinks.
As ever,
the soul of tact.
Well, the man's
no Botticelli.
And the subject's
no Venus.
Franklin,
where were you last night
when l needed you?
You should have heard
what l suffered in there.
l heard, all right.
Along with
the rest of Philadelphia.
Lord, your voice
is piercing, John.
Well, l wish to heaven
my arguments were.
My God, Franklin,
when are they going to
make up their minds?
With one hand
they can raise an army,
dispatch one of
their own to lead it,
and cheer the news
from Bunker's Hill.
And with the other,
they wave the olive branch,
begging the king for a happy
and permanent reconciliation.
Fat George has
declared us in rebellion.
Why in bloody hell
can't they?
John, really? You talk as if
independence were the rule.
lt's never been done before.
No colony has ever broken
from the parent stem
in the history of the world.
Damn it, Franklin,
you make us sound
treasonous.
Do l?
Treason, eh?
Treason is a charge
invented by winners
as an excuse for
hanging the losers.
l have more to do
than stand here,
listening to you
quote yourself.
No, that was a new one.
Damn it, Franklin,
we're at war.
To defend ourselves,
nothing more.
We expressed our displeasure,
the English moved against us,
and we in turn
have resisted.
Now our fellow
congressmen want to
effect a reconciliation
before it becomes a war.
Reconciliation, my ass.
The people want independence.
The people have read
Mr. Paine's Common Sense.
l doubt very much
Congress has.
That's true.
John, why don't you
give it up?
Nobody listens to you.
You're obnoxious
and disliked.
l'm not promoting John Adams.
l'm promoting independence.
Evidently, they cannot help
connecting the two.
Even your own cousin.
And if Sam Adams
can't put up with you,
nobody can.
You're getting at something.
How can you tell?
All right,
out with it, Franklin.
What new intrigue
are you cooking up?
Let someone else
in Congress propose.
Never!
(SlGHS)
Why? Who did you
have in mind?
l don't know.
l really haven't
given it much thought.
You sent for me, Benjamin?
Never.
Hello, Johnny!
Richard.
Uh, Johnny and l
need some advice.
lf it's mine to give,
it's yours, you know that.
Thank you, Richard.
As you know,
the cause that we support
has come to
a complete standstill.
Now why do you
suppose that is?
Simple.
Johnny here is
obnoxious and disliked.
That's true.
Now, what's the solution,
l wonder?
Get somebody else in
Congress to propose.
Oh, Richard,
that's brilliant.
Wasn't that
brilliant, John?
Brilliant.
Yes. Now the question
remains, who can it be?
The man that we need
must belong to a delegation
publicly committed
to support independence.
And at the present time,
only Massachusetts,
New Hampshire
and Delaware have
declared our way.
And Virginia.
Don't forget
Virginia, Benjy.
Oh, Richard, l haven't.
How could l?
But strictly speaking,
while Virginia's views
on independence
are well known,
your legislature
in Williamsburg
has never
formally authorized
its delegation
here in Congress
to support the cause.
Now, if we could
think of a Virginian
with enough influence
to go down there
and persuade
the House of Burgesses. . .
Damn me if l haven't
thought of someone!
Who?
Me.
Oh, why didn't l
think of that?
l'll leave tonight.
Why, hell, l'll leave
right now, if you like.
l'll just stop off
in Stratford long enough
to refresh the missus,
and then
straight to the matter.
Yes, sir.
l really have to compliment
you on your judgment, Johnny.
Whoa, boy. Steady.
You've come to the one colony
that can get the job done.
Virginia, the land
that gave us our glorious
Commander in Chief,
George Washington,
will now give the continent
its proposal on independence.
And when Virginia proposes,
the South is bound to follow.
And where the South goes,
the middle colonies go.
Gentlemen, a salute.
To Virginia,
the mother of
American independence.
lncredible. We're free,
and he hasn't even left yet.
What makes you so sure
you can do it?
My name is
Richard Henry Lee
Virginia is my home
My name is
Richard Henry Lee
Virginia is my home
And may my horses
turn to glue
If I can't deIiver
up to you
A resoIution
on independency
For I am FFV
The first family
ln the sovereign colony
of Virginia
Yes, the FFV
The oldest family
ln the oldest colony
in America
And may the British
burn my land
If I can't deIiver
to your hand
A resoIution
on independency
You see, it's here a Lee,
there a Lee
And everywhere a Lee, a Lee
SociaI...
Lee
PoIiticaI...
FinanciaI...
Lee
NaturaI...
InternaI...
Lee!
ExternaI...
FraternaI...
Lee!
EternaI...
The FFV
The first family
ln the sovereign colony
of Virginia
And may my wife
refuse my bed
If I can't deIiver
as I said
A resoIution
on independency
Spoken modest-Lee.
God help us.
He will, John. He will.
They say that God in heaven
is everybody's God
Amen !
I'II admit
that God in heaven
is everybody's God
But l tell you, John,
with pride
God Ieans a IittIe
on the side of the Lees
The Lees of old Virginia
You see,
it's here a Lee, there a Lee
And everywhere a Lee, a Lee
Here a Lee, there a Lee
And everywhere a Lee
Look out!
There's Arthur Lee,
Bobby Lee
General Light-horse
Harry Lee
Willie Lee, Jesse Lee
And Richard H
That's me!
And may my blood
stop running blue
If I can't deIiver
up to you
The resoIution
on independency
Yes, sir, my God,
it's here a Lee, there a Lee
Come on, boys,
join in with me!
Here a Lee, there a Lee
When do you leave?
Immediate-Lee!
Here a Lee, there a Lee
When will you return?
Short-Lee!
Here a Lee, there a Lee
And I'II come back
triumphant-Lee!
Here a Lee, there a Lee
Everywhere a Lee, a Lee
Forward
Ho
That was the most
revolting display
l have ever witnessed.
They're a warm-blooded
people, Virginians.
Oh, not him, Franklin. You.
You and your
infernal obsession
for deviousness.
lf you'd come
straight out
and asked the man,
he'd have been gone
a half hour ago.
Yes, and he'd have been
doing us a favor.
Cheer up, John.
At this very moment,
sitting straight
in the saddle and in
full gallop for Virginia.
And our women are serene
Oh, good God.
FuII-bosomed
Full-bosomed, Benjy
Everyone a queen
Why they are Lees, damn it
Lees of old Virginia!
Yes, sir, by God,
it's here a Lee, there a Lee!
C'mon, John, step lively
Here a Lee, there a Lee
Everywhere a Lee, a Lee
Everywhere a Lee, a Lee!
Forward, ho
Uh, excuse me.
Yes?
l'm Dr. Lyman Hall,
the new delegate
from Georgia.
l'm Andrew McNair,
congressional custodian.
lf you'll be
wanting anything at all,
just holler out "McNair"
as all the others do
and there won't be
too long to wait.
Where does the Georgia
delegation belong?
Oh, they mill about over
there in that corner,
near the two Carolinas.
(SNAPPlNG FlNGERS)
lt's after 1 0:00.
l was told Congress
convenes at 1 0:00.
Well, they'll be
wandering in
any time now, sir,
with Old Grape and Guts
leading the pack.
Old who?
HOPKlNS: McNair!
Grape and Guts.
'Nair!
Fetch me a rum.
Mr. Hopkins, you'll be
pleased to meet
Dr. Lyman Hall.
l don't need a doctor,
damn it.
New delegate from Georgia.
Well, why didn't you
say so?
l'm Stephen Hopkins,
old delegate
from Rhode lsland.
McNair, fetch two rums.
Oh, l fear it's
a little early in the day.
Nonsense.
lt's a medicinal fact
that rum gets
a man's heart started
in the morning.
l'm surprised
you didn't know that.
Speaking as the oldest man
in the Congress,
l can tell you. . .
Uh-uh. Ben Franklin is
older by almost a year.
Rum !
Tell me, Doctor.
Where does Georgia stand
on the question
of independence?
RUTLEDGE:
With South Carolina,
of course.
HOPKlNS: (LAUGHlNG)
Neddy, good morning.
Neddy, come over here
and shake the hand of
Dr. Lyman Hall of Georgia.
Dr. Hall, this here is
Edward Rutledge from. . .
Whichever Carolina
he says he's from.
God knows l can't
keep them straight.
lt's a pleasure,
Dr. Hall.
Your servant,
Mr. Rutledge.
You've met the long
and the short of it now,
Doctor.
Neddy here is just a lad.
He's the youngest of us.
Except for Ben Franklin.
McNair!
Your rum !
Well, where did you go
for it, man? Jamaica?
Well, now,
come along, Dr. Hall.
l know you must be anxious
to meet your colleagues
from the South.
Doctor, may l present
to you Joseph Hewes.
This is Dr. Lyman Hall,
the new delegate
from Georgia.
An honor and a pleasure,
gentlemen.
Uh, where do you
stand on independence,
Dr. Hall?
l'm here without
instructions, Mr. Hewes,
able to vote my own
personal convictions.
And they are?
Personal.
Now, Dr. Hall,
the Deep South speaks
with one voice.
lt's traditional.
Even more, it is historical.
Enter Delaware.
(SPEAKlNG LATlN)
Speak plain, Rutledge.
You know l can't follow
a word of your damn French.
lt's Latin,
Colonel McKean,
a tribute to
the eternal peace and harmony
of the Delaware delegation.
What are you saying, man?
You know perfectly well
that neither Rodney nor l
can stand
the sight of this louse.
Now, Thomas. . .
Gentlemen, please.
This is Dr. Lyman Hall
of Georgia.
Caesar Rodney.
An honor, sir.
Sir.
George Read and
Colonel Thomas McKean.
RODNEY: Dr. Hall. . .
Your servant.
l wonder if l might
speak to you
for a moment in private.
By all means.
McNair!
l'm coming ! l'm coming !
Help me. l'm stuck.
Tell me, sir,
would you be a doctor
of medicine or theology?
Both, Mr. Rodney.
Which one can be of service?
By all means,
the physician first.
Then we shall see
about the other.
(CHUCKLES)
l shall call at
your convenience, sir.
l trust, Caesar,
when you're through
converting the poor fellow
to independency
that you'll give
the opposition
a fair crack at him.
(CHUCKLlNG)
You're too late, John.
Once l get them,
they're got.
Dr. Lyman Hall of Georgia,
Mr. John Dickinson
of Pennsylvania.
An honor, sir.
Your servant, sir.
Tell me, Doctor.
Where do you stand
on the question of. . .
lndependence?
Treason.
l've no stomach for it.
Ah ! Then be careful
not to dine with John Adams.
Between the fish
and the souffle,
you'll find yourself
hanging from an English rope.
Your servant, sir.
Oh, Judge Wilson, forgive me,
but how can anyone see you
if you insist on standing
in Mr. Dickinson's shadow?
James Wilson,
also of Pennsylvania.
Sir.
An honor, sir.
FRANKLlN: Good morning.
Good morning.
Good morning, ladies.
Steady, steady.
MAN: Make gangway, sir.
Make gangway!
Good morning,
Mr. Wilson. Good morning.
Watch where
you're going, damn it.
Over there.
McNair, get me
out of this thing.
Watch out for my foot.
Good morning, all.
Morning, Ben.
ALL: Morning, Ben.
Here you are.
Two coppers apiece.
Now, straight back
to jail with you.
Good morning, Stephen.
All right, Benjamin.
(GROANS)
Dear God.
What are you staring at?
Haven't you ever seen
a great man before?
Good Lord, sir.
Do you have the honor
to be Dr. Franklin?
Yes, l have that honor.
Unfortunately, the gout
accompanies the honor.
Been living
too high again, eh, pappy?
Oh, Stephen, l only wish
King George felt like
my big toe all over.
(LAUGHS)
McNair! Fetch a pillow
and two more rums.
Well, Franklin,
where's that idiot Lee?
ls he back yet?
l don't see him.
Softly, John. Your voice
is hurting my foot.
One more day, Franklin.
That's how long
l'll remain silent,
not a minute longer.
That strutting popinjay
was so damn sure of himself.
He's had time to bring back
a dozen proposals by now.
Tell me, James.
How do you
explain the strange,
monumental quietude
that Congress
has been treated to
these past 30 days?
Has the ill wind
of independence
finally blown itself out?
Well, if you ask me. . .
For myself, l must confess
that a month free
from New England noise
is more therapeutic
than a month in the country.
Don't you agree, James?
Well, l feel. . .
Mr. Adams, pray look
for your voice, sir.
lt cannot be far,
and God knows we need
the entertainment
in Congress.
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
Congratulations, John.
You just made your greatest
contribution to independence.
You kept your flap shut.
One more day, Franklin.
Then l shall do
the proposing.
Gentlemen, the usual morning
festivities concluded,
l will now call
Congress to order.
Mr. Thomson.
The Second Continental
Congress meeting
in the city of Philadelphia
is now in session.
7 June, 1 776,
the 380th meeting.
Sweet Jesus!
The Honorable John Hancock
of Massachusetts Bay,
president.
Thank you,
Mr. Thomson.
Mr. McNair.
The stores of rum
and other drinking spirits
are hereby closed
to the colony of Rhode lsland
for a period of three days.
Yes, sir.
(MEN RAPPlNG ON TABLES)
Johnny, you can't do that.
Sit down, Mr. Hopkins.
You've abused the privilege.
(MEN LAUGHlNG)
The chair would like
to take this opportunity
to welcome
Dr. Lyman Hall of Georgia
to this Congress,
and hopes he will make
the best of it.
My God, it's hot.
The secretary
will read the roll.
All members present
with the following
exceptions.
"Mr. Paine, Mr. Gerry,
Mr. Samuel Adams
of Massachusetts,
"Mr. Morton of Pennsylvania,
"Mr. Wythe and
Mr. Richard Henry Lee
of Virginia."
And the entire delegation
of New Jersey.
l'm concerned over
the continual absence
of one-thirteenth
of this Congress.
Where is New Jersey?
Somewhere between
New York and Pennsylvania.
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
Thank you very much.
Dr. Franklin,
have you heard anything?
Your son resides there.
Son, sir? What son?
The royal governor
of New Jersey, sir.
As that title
might suggest, sir,
we are not in touch
at the present time.
Yes. Well. . .
Now for the weather report,
Mr. Jefferson of Virginia.
Mr. Jefferson !
Present, sir.
May we hear
about the weather?
As if it weren't
speaking for itself.
Eighty-seven degrees
of temperature,
thirty-point-aught-six
inches of mercury.
Wind. . .
From the southwest
for the rest of the day.
And tonight. . .
Tonight l'm leaving for home.
On business?
Family business.
Give her a flourish for me,
young feller.
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
Whoa!
"From the Commander,
army of the United Colonies
to New York,
"dispatch number 1 , 1 37."
Ah, sweet Jesus!
"To the Honorable Congress,
John Hancock, president.
"Dear sir,
it is with grave apprehension
that l have learned this day
"of the sailing from Halifax,
Nova Scotia,
"of a considerable force
of British troops
"in the company of
foreign mercenaries
"and under the command
of General Sir William Howe."
"There can be no doubt
that their destination
is New York,
"for to take
and hold this city
and the Hudson Valley beyond
"would serve to
separate New England from
the rest of the colonies,
"permitting both sections
to be crushed in turn.
"Sadly, l see no way
of stopping them
at the present time,
"as my army is
absolutely falling apart.
"My military chest
is totally exhausted.
"My commissary general
has strained his credit
to the last.
"My quartermaster
has no food, no arms,
no ammunition,
"and my troops are in
a state of near mutiny.
"l pray God
some relief arrives
"before the armada,
but fear it will not.
"Your obedient,
"G. Washington."
Mr. President!
Colonel McKean.
Surely we have
managed to promote
the gloomiest man
on this continent
to the head of our troops.
Those dispatches
are the most
depressing accumulation
of disaster, doom and despair
in the entire annals
of military history.
Colonel McKean, please!
What?
lt's too hot.
Well, l suppose so.
General Washington
will continue wording his
dispatches as he sees fit.
And l'm sure we all pray
he finds happier thoughts
to convey in the near future.
Mr. Thomson,
are there any resolutions?
Dr. Josiah Bartlett
of New Hampshire.
"Resolved,
that for the duration
of the present hostilities,
"the Congress discourage
every type of extravagance
and dissipation,
"elaborate funerals
and other
expensive diversions,
"especially all
horse racing, gambling,
"and other forms of
sinful activity, which. . ."
Fire wagon !
(ALL CLAMORlNG)
Where's the fire?
Can anybody tell?
Looks like
the Pemberton House.
lt couldn't be.
lt's brand new.
lt might be the city tavern.
Bite your tongue, man.
LEE: Whoo-hoo!
Benjy, l'm back!
l'm back, Johnny!
Richard, lad,
welcome back.
(LEE WHOOPlNG)
Lee, is it done?
First things first. Tom !
Tom ! Tom, your little
bride wants to know,
"When's he coming home?"
l leave tonight.
Never mind that, man.
ls it done?
Done? Why, certain-Lee.
Mr. President, l have
returned from Virginia with
the following resolution,
"Resolved, that these
united colonies are,
and of a right ought to be,
"free and independent states,
"that they are absolved
from allegiance to
the British Crown,
"and that all political
connection between them
"and the state of
Great Britain is,
"and ought to be,
totally dissolved."
Hear, hear!
Mr. President,
l second the proposal.
The resolution
has been proposed
and seconded.
The chair will now
entertain debate.
Mr. Dickinson.
Mr. President.
Pennsylvania moves,
as always,
that the question
of independence be
postponed indefinitely.
l second the motion.
Judge Wilson,
in your eagerness to be loved,
you seem to have forgotten
that Pennsylvania
cannot second its own motion.
Delaware seconds.
You would, you lousy wart.
The motion to postpone
has been moved and seconded.
Mr. Thomson.
On the motion to
postpone indefinitely
the resolution
on independency
or proceed with the debate,
all those in favor
of debate say "yea,"
all those for
postponement say "nay."
New Hampshire?
New Hampshire favors debate,
and says yea.
New Hampshire says yea.
Massachusetts?
Massachusetts,
having borne the brunt
of the King's tyranny. . .
(ALL CLAMORlNG)
Yes, l said tyranny!
Massachusetts now,
and for all time, says yea.
Massachusetts says yea.
Rhode lsland?
Mr. Hopkins?
Where's Rhode lsland?
Rhode lsland is out
visiting the necessary.
After what
Rhode lsland's consumed,
l can't say l'm surprised.
We'll come back to him,
Mr. Thomson.
Rhode lsland passes.
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
Connecticut?
While Connecticut has,
till now,
been against this proposal,
our legislature
has instructed me
that in the event
it is introduced by
any colony outside
of New England,
we could not any longer
withhold our support.
Connecticut says yea.
Hear! Hear!
New York?
New York
abstains courteously.
New York abstains.
Courteously.
New Jersey?
Absent, Mr. Secretary.
New Jersey's absent.
Pennsylvania?
Pennsylvania,
for the 24th time, says nay.
Pennsylvania says nay.
Delaware?
Delaware, as ever
for independence, says yea.
Delaware says yea.
Maryland?
Maryland would
welcome independence
if it were given,
but is highly skeptical
that it can be taken.
Maryland says nay.
Virginia?
Virginia, the first colony,
says yea!
Virginia says yea.
North Carolina?
North Carolina
respectfully yields
to South Carolina.
South Carolina?
Mr. President,
although we
of South Carolina have
never seriously considered
the question of independence,
when a gentleman proposes it,
attention must be paid.
However,
we in the Deep South,
unlike our friends
in New England,
have no cause for impatience
at the present time.
lf at some future date
it becomes the wish of
all our sister colonies,
to effect a separation,
we will not stand in the way.
But for the time being,
South Carolina
will wait and watch.
The vote is nay.
North Carolina. . .
Says nay.
Yes, Mr. Hewes. l know.
Georgia.
Mr. President,
Georgia seems to be split
right down the middle
on this issue.
The people are against it,
and l'm for it.
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
However, l'm afraid
l'm not quite certain
whether representing
the people means
relying on their judgment
or on my own.
ln all fairness,
until l can figure that out,
l'd better lean
a little on their side.
Georgia says nay.
Rhode lsland?
Second call, Rhode lsland !
Rhode lsland !
HOPKlNS: l'm coming !
l'm coming !
Hold your damn horses.
We're waiting on you,
Mr. Hopkins.
Well, it won't kill you.
You'd think the Congress
would have its own privy.
All right,
where does she stand?
Five for debate,
five for postponement,
one abstention
and one absence.
So it's up to me, huh?
Well, l'll tell you.
ln all my years,
l never seen,
heard nor smelled an issue
that was so dangerous
it couldn't be talked about.
Hell, yes!
l'm for debating anything.
Rhode lsland says yea.
HANCOCK: McNair,
get Mr. Hopkins a rum.
McNAlR: But you said. . .
HANCOCK: Get him the whole
damn barrel if he wants.
The chair now declares
this Congress a committee
of the whole
for the purpose of debating
Virginia's resolution
on independence.
Mr. Dickinson.
Well, now,
you've got your way
at last, Mr. Adams.
The matter may
now be discussed.
l confess
l'm almost relieved.
There's a question
l've been fairly
itching to ask you.
Why?
Why what, Mr. Dickinson?
Well, why independence,
Mr. Adams?
Well, for
the obvious reason that
our continued association
with Great Britain
has grown intolerable.
Well, to whom,
Mr. Adams? To you?
Well, then l suggest
you sever your ties
immediately.
But please be kind enough
to leave the rest
of us where we are.
For myself,
l have no objection at all
to being part of
the greatest empire
on Earth,
to enjoying its protection
and sharing its benefits.
Benefits?
What benefits?
Crippling taxes?
Cruel repressions?
Abolished rights?
ls that all England
means to you, sir?
ls that all the pride and
affection you can muster
for the nation
that bore you?
For the noblest,
most civilized nation
on the face of this planet?
Well, would you
have us forsake
Hastings and Magna Carta,
Strongbow and Lionheart,
Drake and Marlborough,
Tudors, Stuarts
and Plantagenets?
For what, sir?
Well, tell me. For what?
For you?
Some men are patriots,
like General Washington,
and some are anarchists,
like Mr. Paine.
Some even are
internationalists,
like Dr. Franklin.
But you, sir. . .
You are merely an agitator,
disturbing the peace,
creating disorder,
endangering
the public welfare.
And for what?
Your petty little
personal complaints.
Your taxes are too high.
Well, sir, so are mine.
Come, come, Mr. Adams.
lf you have grievances,
and l'm sure you have,
our present system
must provide
a gentler means
of redressing them
short of revolution.
Yes, that's what he wants.
Nothing less
will satisfy him.
Violence, rebellion,
treason.
Now, Mr. Adams,
are these
the acts of Englishmen?
Not Englishmen, Dickinson.
Americans.
No, sir. Englishmen !
Please, Mr. Dickinson,
must you start banging?
How is a man to sleep?
Forgive me, Dr. Franklin,
but must you start speaking?
How is a man to stay awake?
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
We'll promise
to be quiet, sir.
l'm sure everyone prefers
that you remain asleep.
lf l'm to hear myself
called an Englishman, sir,
l assure you l prefer
l'd remained asleep.
Oh, now, what's so terrible
about being called
an Englishman?
The English
don't seem to mind.
Nor would l,
were l given the full
rights of an Englishman.
But to call me one
without those rights
is like calling an ox a bull.
He's thankful for the honor,
but he'd much
rather have restored
what's rightfully his.
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
When did you first notice
they were missing, sir?
Fortunately,
the people of these colonies
maintain a higher regard
for their mother country.
Higher, certainly,
than she feels for them.
Never was such
a valuable possession
so stupidly
and so recklessly managed
than this entire continent
by the British Crown.
Our industry discouraged,
our resources pillaged.
Worst of all,
our very character stifled.
We've spawned
a new race here,
Mr. Dickinson.
Rougher, simpler,
more violent,
more enterprising,
less refined.
We're a new nationality.
We require a new nation.
Well,
that may be your opinion,
Dr. Franklin,
but, as l said,
the people feel
quite differently.
Now, what do you know
about the people, Dickinson?
You don't
speak for the people.
You represent only yourself.
And that precious status quo
you keep imploring
the people to preserve
for their own good
is nothing more than
the eternal preservation
of your own property.
Mr. Adams,
you have an annoying talent
for making such
delightful words
as "property" sound
quite distasteful.
ln heaven's name,
what's wrong with property?
Perhaps you've forgotten
that many of us first came
to these shores
in order to secure
rights to property,
and that we hold these rights
no less dear than
the rights you speak of.
Yes. So safe, so fat,
so comfortable
in Pennsylvania.
And what is this
independence of yours
except the private grievance
of Massachusetts?
Why is it always Boston
that breaks the King's peace?
My dear Congress,
you must not adopt
this evil measure.
lt is the work of the devil.
Leave it where it belongs.
ln New England.
Brother Dickinson,
New England has been
fighting the devil
for more than 1 00 years.
And as of now,
Brother Sherman,
the devil has been
winning hands down.
Why, at this very moment,
he's sitting right
here in this Congress.
Don't let him deceive you.
This proposal is
entirely his doing.
lt may bear Virginia's name,
but it reeks of Adams,
Adams and more Adams.
Look at him.
Ready to lead this continent
down the fiery path
of total destruction.
Oh, good God !
Why can't you acknowledge
what already exists?
lt has been more than a year
since Concord and Lexington.
Damn it, man,
we're at war, right now!
You may be at war.
You, Boston and John Adams.
But you will never
speak for Pennsylvania.
Nor for Delaware.
Mr. Read, you represent
only one-third of Delaware.
The sensible third,
Mr. Rodney.
Sit down, you scurvy dog,
or l'll knock you down.
(DOG BARKlNG)
Sit down, all three of you !
McNair, do something
about that damn dog !
And here, fetch me a rum.
Get that dog first!
Rum, rum !
l only got two hands.
(ALL CLAMORlNG)
Christ, it's hot!
Please do go on, gentlemen.
You're making the only breeze
in Philadelphia.
Mr. Adams,
perhaps you could
clear up something for me?
After we have
achieved independence,
who do you propose
would govern in
South Carolina?
The people, of course.
Which people, sir?
The people of South Carolina
or the people
of Massachusetts?
Why don't you
admit it, Neddy?
You're against
independence now
and you always will be.
Aye.
Gentlemen,
you refuse to understand us.
We desire independence. Yes.
For South Carolina.
That is our country.
And as such, we don't
wish to belong to anyone.
Not to England
and not to you.
We intend to have
one nation, Rutledge.
A nation of
sovereign states, Mr. Adams.
United for our
mutual protection,
but separate for
our individual pursuits.
Now, that is what
we have understood it to be,
and that is what
we will support.
As soon as
everyone supports it.
Well, there you are,
Mr. Adams.
You must see
that we need time.
Time to make certain
who we are
and where we stand
in regard to one another.
For if we do not determine
the nature of the beast
before we set it free,
it will end
by consuming us all.
For once
in your life, Wilson,
take a chance.
l say the time is now.
lt may never come again.
Your clock is fast,
Mr. Adams.
l say we're not yet ripe
for independence.
Not ripe?
Hell, we're rotting
for want of it.
Gentlemen, please,
what in God's name
is the infernal hurry?
Why must this question
be settled now?
What's wrong with now,
Mr. Chase?
General Washington
is in the field.
lf he's defeated,
as it now appears,
we'll be inviting
the hangman.
But if, by some miracle,
he should actually win,
we can then declare
anything we damn please.
The sentiments of
North Carolina precisely.
Has it ever
occurred to either of you
that an army needs
something to fight for
in order to win?
A purpose? A goal?
A flag of its own?
Mr. Adams,
how can a nation of
only 2 million souls
stand up to an empire
of 1 0 million?
Think of it. 1 0 million.
How do we compensate
for that shortage?
lt's simple, Mr. Chase.
lncrease and multiply.
How's that?
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
We will more than
compensate with spirit.
l tell you, there is
a spirit out there
among the people
that is sadly lacking
in this Congress.
Yes, of course.
Now it's spirit.
Well, why didn't
l think of that?
No army, no navy,
no arms, no ammunition,
no treasury, no friends,
but, bless our soul, spirit.
Mr. Lee, Mr. Hopkins,
Mr. Rodney, Colonel McKean,
Dr. Franklin.
Why have you joined
this incendiary little man,
this Boston radical,
this agitator,
this demagogue,
this madman?
Are you calling me
a madman, you. . .
You fribble!
You and your
Pennsylvania proprietors,
oh, you cool,
considerate men,
you hang to the rear
on every issue,
so that
if we should go under,
you'll still remain afloat.
Are you calling me a coward?
Yes. Coward !
Madman !
Landlord !
Lawyer!
Stop it! Stop it!
This is the Congress.
Stop it, l say!
The enemy's out there.
No, Mr. Rodney,
the enemy is here.
No. l say he's out there.
England.
England closing in,
cutting off our air.
There's no time!
No air.
Dr. Hall.
Colonel McKean.
Aye. lt's the cancer.
But he should go home.
A man should die
in his own bed.
John. John Adams.
l'm here, Caesar.
l leave you
a divided Delaware.
Forgive me.
l'll take you home,
Caesar.
l'll be back
within the week.
Mr. President,
South Carolina
calls the question.
What's that, Mr. Rutledge?
l said, Mr. President,
South Carolina desires
to end the debate
and calls the question
of independence.
Delaware seconds.
Thank you.
(ALL CLAMORlNG)
(GAVEL POUNDlNG)
Gentlemen, please!
The question has been
called and seconded.
The secretary
will record the vote.
Franklin, do something.
Think.
l'm thinking,
but nothing's coming.
All those in favor
of the resolution
on independence
as proposed by
the colony of Virginia,
signify by saying. . .
Mr. Secretary.
Will you please read
the resolution again?
What?
l've forgotten it.
Now, Benjamin. . .
"Resolved, that these
united colonies are,
"and of a right ought to be,
free and independent. . ."
(DOOR OPENS)
Excuse me. ls this
the Continental Congress?
Yes, l can see
that it must be.
lt's all right.
We found it.
We've been looking
for you everywhere,
you see.
Someone told us
that you might be
at Carpenters' Hall
and someone else
suggested Library Hall,
and. . .
So, finally,
we asked a constable. . .
HANCOCK: Excuse me, sir,
but, if you don't mind,
the Congress is
about to decide
the question of
American independence.
Oh, how splendid.
That means
we're not too late.
These gentlemen are
Mr. Francis Hopkinson,
Mr. Richard Stockton,
and l'm the Reverend
John Witherspoon.
We're the new delegates
from New Jersey.
New Jersey?
(ALL CLAMORlNG)
Dr. Franklin,
l regret that l must be
the bearer of
unhappy tidings, sir,
but your son, the royal
governor of New Jersey,
has been taken prisoner
and has been moved
under guard to the colony of
Connecticut for safekeeping.
ls he unharmed, sir?
When last l heard,
he was. Yes, sir.
Well, then
why the long face?
l hear Connecticut
is an excellent location.
Tell me.
Why did they arrest
the little bastard?
(MEN LAUGHlNG)
Our, uh. . .
New Jersey legislature
has recalled the old
delegation to this Congress
and has sent a new one.
Quickly, man,
where do you stand
on independence?
Well, haven't l
made that clear?
No.
Well, l suppose l haven't.
But that's the reason
for the change.
See, we've been instructed
to vote for independence.
Mr. President!
Massachusetts is now ready
for the vote on independence,
and reminds the chair
of its privilege
to decide all votes
that are deadlocked.
l won't forget, Mr. Adams.
The chair takes
this opportunity
to welcome
the New Jersey delegation
and appoints
the Reverend Witherspoon
congressional chaplain
if he will accept the post.
With much pleasure, sir.
Very well.
Mr. Thomson,
you may now proceed with
the vote on independence.
All in favor of
the resolution
on independence
as proposed by
the colony of Virginia,
signify by saying. . .
Mr. President.
Pennsylvania moves
that any vote in favor
of independence
must be unanimous.
What?
l second the motion.
Judge Wilson !
Oh, my God.
Delaware seconds,
Mr. President.
No vote has ever
had to be unanimous,
Dickinson, and you know it.
Yes, but this one must be.
On what grounds?
That no colony be torn
from its mother country
without its own consent.
Hear! Hear!
But it will never be
unanimous, damn it.
lf you say so, Mr. Adams.
lt has been moved
and seconded that
the vote on independence
must be unanimous
in order to carry.
All those in favor,
signify by saying yea.
ALL: Yea!
One, two, three,
four, five, six.
Six colonies say yea.
Against?
MEN: Nay!
One, two, three,
four, five, six.
Six colonies say nay.
Mr. Secretary, New York
abstains courteously.
Mr. Morris,
why does New York
constantly abstain?
Why doesn't New York
simply stay in New York?
Very well.
The vote is tied.
The principles
of independence
have no greater
advocate in Congress
than its president.
That is why
l must join those
who vote for unanimity.
Good God, John !
What are you doing?
You've sunk us.
Now, hear me out.
Don't you see that any colony
who opposes independence
will be forced to fight
on the side of England?
That we'll be setting
brother against brother,
that our new nation
will carry as its emblem
the mark of Cain.
l can see no other way.
Either we all walk together,
or together we must
stay where we are.
The man's from
Massachusetts.
HANCOCK: Very well.
Proceed, Mr. Thomson.
THOMSON: A unanimous vote
being necessary to carry,
if any be opposed
to the resolution
on independence
as proposed by
the colony of Virginia,
signify by. . .
Mr. President.
Oh, for heaven's sake,
let me get through it once.
Mr. President.
l move for a postponement.
Postponement?
l wish you the same
luck l had with it.
Mr. Adams is right.
We need a postponement.
On what grounds?
Mr. President,
how can this Congress
vote on independence
without a written declaration
of some sort defining it?
What sort of declaration?
Ah, well, you know,
listing the reasons
for the separation,
our purposes, goals,
so forth, so on.
Ditto, Ditto.
Ditto, ditto,
et cetera, et cetera.
We know those, don't we?
Oh, yes, good God,
we know them,
but what about
the rest of the world?
Certainly we require
the assistance
of a powerful nation
such as France or Spain.
And such
a written declaration
would be consistent
with European delicacy.
Come now, Mr. Adams.
You'll have to do
better than that.
Answer straight.
What would be its purpose?
Yes. Well. . .
To place before mankind
the common sense
of the subject
in terms so plain and firm
as to command their assent.
(CHUCKLlNG)
Mr. Jefferson,
are you seriously suggesting
that we publish a paper
declaring to all the world
that an illegal rebellion
is, in reality, a legal one?
Mr. Dickinson,
l'm surprised at you.
You should know that
rebellion is always legal
in the first person,
such as "our rebellion."
lt's only
in the third person,
"their rebellion,"
that it is illegal.
Mr. President,
l second the motion
to postpone the vote
on independence
for a period of time
sufficient for
the writing of a declaration.
lt has been
moved and seconded.
Mr. Thomson.
All those in favor of
the motion to postpone,
signify by saying yea.
MEN: Yea!
One, two, three,
four, five, six.
Six colonies say yea.
Against?
MEN: Nay!
One, two, three,
four, five, six.
Six colonies say nay.
Mr. Secretary, New York
abstains courteously.
Mr. Morris, what in hell
goes on in New York?
l'm sorry, Mr. President,
but the simple fact is that
our legislature has
never sent us explicit
instructions on anything.
Never?
That's impossible.
Mr. President,
have you ever been present
at a meeting of
the New York legislature?
They speak very fast
and very loud,
and nobody listens
to anybody else
with the result that
nothing ever gets done.
l beg the Congress' pardon.
My sympathies, Mr. Morris.
The vote again being tied,
the chair decides in favor
of postponement.
So ruled.
A committee
will now be formed to
manage the declaration.
Said document to be written,
debated, approved by
the beginning of July,
some three weeks hence.
At which time,
Virginia's resolution
on independence
will finally be voted.
ls that clear?
(SOUNDS OF APPROVAL)
Very well. Will
the following gentlemen
serve on
the Declaration Committee,
Dr. Franklin?
Gladly.
Mr. John Adams?
Yes.
Mr. Sherman?
Mr. Livingston?
Right.
And, of course, Mr. Lee.
Oh, excuse me,
but l must be returning
to the sovereign
colony of Virginia
as l have been asked
to serve as governor.
And therefore l must
decline respectful-Lee.
(LAUGHlNG)
Very well, Mr. Lee,
you're excused then.
l suppose we could leave it
a four-man committee.
Just a moment.
This business
needs a Virginian.
Therefore l propose
a replacement.
Mr. Thomas Jefferson.
No. Mr. Adams. . .
Very well, Mr. Adams.
Mr. Jefferson will serve.
l'm going home, too,
to my wife.
Move to adjourn !
Wait.
l second.
Mr. Hancock,
l haven't seen her
for six months.
Moved and seconded.
Any objections?
l have objections.
l have lots of objections.
So ruled !
Congress stands adjourned !
John, l need to see my wife.
lt's all right.
Come along, come along.
No. l'm going
home tonight.
Of course you are.
Of course.
McNair, some rum
up to my office.
Oh, don't worry, Tom.
Let me handle it.
l'll get Adams to write it.
l don't know.
He had a funny look
on his face.
He always does.
JOHN: All right,
gentlemen,
let's get on with it.
Which of us will
write our Declaration
of lndependence?
Mr. Adams,
l say you should write it
To your legal mind
and briIIiance we defer
Is that so?
Well, if I'm the one to do it
They'll run their
quill pens through it
I'm obnoxious and disIiked
You know that, sir
Yes, I know
But l say you should
write it, Franklin, yes you
HeII no!
Yes, you, Dr. Franklin, you
But...
You!
Mr. Adams, but, Mr. Adams
The things l write
are only light extemporanea
l won't put politics
on paper, it's a mania
So l refuse to use the pen
in Pennsylvania
Pennsylvania
Refuse to use the pen
Mr. Sherman,
l say you should write it
You are never
controversiaI as it were
That is true
Whereas if
I'm the one to do it
They'll run their
quill pens through it
I'm obnoxious and disIiked
You know that, sir
Yes, I do
So l say you should
write it, Roger, yes, you
Good heavens, no
Yes, you, Roger Sherman
You!
But...
Mr. Adams, but, Mr. Adams
I cannot write
with any style
or proper etiquette
I don't know
a participle from a predicate
l am just a simple cobbler
from Connecticut
Connecticut
A simple cobbler, he
Ah.
Mr. Livingston,
maybe you should write it
You have many friends
and you're a diplomat
Oh, that word
Whereas if
I'm the one to do it
They'll run their
quill pens through it
He's obnoxious and disIiked
Did you know that?
I hadn't heard
So l say you should
write it, Robert, yes, you
Not me, Johnny
Yes, you, Robert Livingston
You!
But...
Mr. Adams, dear Mr. Adams
l've been presented
with a new son
by the noble stork
So l am going home
to celebrate and pop the cork
With aII
the Livingstons together
back in oId New York
New York
Livingston's
going to pop a cork
Mr. Adams
Leave me aIone
Mr. Jefferson. . .
Mr. Adams, l beg of you.
l've not seen my wife
these past six months.
"And we solemnly declare
that we will
preserve our liberties,
"being with one mind
resolved to die free men
rather than to live slaves."
Thomas Jefferson,
"On the Necessity of
Taking Up Arms," 1 775.
Magnificent.
You write 1 0 times better
than any man in Congress,
including me.
For a man of only 33 years,
you possess a happy talent
for composition
and a remarkable felicity
of expression.
Now, then, sir.
Will you be a patriot
or a lover?
A lover.
No.
But l burn, Mr. A.
So do l, Mr. J.
You?
You do?
John.
Who'd have thought it?
Mr. Jefferson
Dear Mr. Jefferson
l'm only 41 ,
l still have my virility
And l can romp
through Cupid's grove
with great agility
But Iife is more than
sexual combustibility
Jefferson, stop right there.
'Bustability
CombustibiIi...
Quiet!
Now, you'll write it, Mr. J.
Who will make me, Mr. A.?
l.
You?
Yes.
How?
By physical force,
if necessary.
lt's your duty, damn it.
Your duty!
Mr. Adams
Damn you, Mr. Adams
You're obnoxious
and disIiked
That cannot be denied
Once again
you stand between
me and my lovely bride
Lovely bride
Oh, Mr. Adams,
you are driving me
to homicide
Jefferson, stop right there!
Homicide
Quiet!
The decision is yours,
Mr. Jefferson.
Do as you like with it.
We may see murder yet
Damn the man.
God damn the man.
Sorry.
Pardon me, sir.
Step aside. Step aside.
How are you?
Franklin.
Jefferson !
What is that racket?
Latest thing
from Europe, John.
lt's called music.
l came here
hoping to hear a pen
scratching, not a bow.
Jefferson !
l know you're in there!
Ah ! Jefferson,
are you finished?
Well, is it written yet?
Well, you've had
a whole week, man.
ls it done?
Can l see it?
"There comes a time
in the lives of men
when it becomes necessary
"to advance from
that subordination
"in which they
have hitherto. . ."
This is terrible.
Where's the rest of it?
Do you mean to say
that it is not yet finished?
No, sir.
l mean to say that
it's not yet begun.
Good God !
A whole week.
The entire Earth
was created in a week.
Someday you must tell me
how you did it.
Disgusting.
Look at him, Franklin.
Virginia's most famous lover.
Virginia abstains.
Well, cheer up, Jefferson.
Get out of the dumps.
lt'll come out all right,
l assure you.
Now, get back to work.
Franklin, tell him to
get back to work.
l think he's asleep.
(SNORlNG)
Wake up, Franklin !
Hello! And whose
little girl are you?
John, who is she?
JOHN: His wife.
l hope.
What makes you think so?
Because l sent for her.
You what?
Well, it simply
occurred to me that
the sooner his problem
was solved,
the sooner our problem
is solved.
That's good thinking, John.
Good thinking.
Madam, may l present myself?
John Adams.
Adams.
Oh, and Dr. Franklin.
The inventor of the stove.
Jefferson, kindly
present me to your wife.
She is your wife, isn't she?
Well, of course she is.
Look at the way they fit.
Come along, John,
come along.
Franklin,
where are you going?
Come along, John.
Come along where?
There's work to be done.
Obviously.
Good God. You don't
mean to say that. . .
l mean,
they're not going to. . .
ln the middle of
the afternoon?
Not everybody's
from Boston, John.
lncredible.
Well, goodbye, John.
Uh. . . Uh. . .
Franklin?
Have you eaten?
Not yet, but. . .
l understand
the turkey's fresh
at Bunch of Grapes.
Well, the fact is
l have a rendezvous, John.
l'd ask you along,
but talking
makes her nervous.
Yes, of course.
lncredible.
(SCOFFS)
Abigail?
l'm very lonely, Abigail.
Are you, John?
As long as you were
sending for wives,
why didn't you
send for your own?
Oh, now, don't be
unreasonable, Abigail.
Now I'm unreasonabIe.
You must add that
to your list.
List?
The catalog of my faults
you included
in your last letter.
Oh, they were fondly
intended, madam.
That l play at cards badly?
A compliment.
That my posture is crooked?
An endearment.
That l read,
write and think too much?
An irony.
That l'm pigeon-toed?
Well, now
there you have me, Abby.
l'm afraid you are
pigeon-toed.
Please. Come to Philadelphia.
Please come.
Oh, thank you, John.
l do want to,
but you know now
it's not possible.
The children
have the measles.
So you wrote.
Tom and little Abby.
Only now it's
Quincy and Charles.
And it appears the farm
here in Braintree
is failing, John.
The chickens and the geese
have all died.
The apples never survived
the late frost.
How do you suppose
she managed to get away?
Well, the winters
are softer in Virginia.
And their women, John?
Fit for Virginians, madam,
but pale, puny things
beside New England girls.
John.
l thank you for that.
Abigail,
how goes it with you?
Not well, John.
Not at all well.
I Iive Iike
a nun in a cIoister
Solitary, celibate
I hate it
And you, John?
Ugh !
I Iive Iike a monk
in an abbey
Ditto, ditto
I hate it
Write to me
with sentimentaI effusion
Let me reveI
in romantic iIIusion
Do you still smell of
vanilla and spring air?
And is my
favorite lover's pillow
StiII firm and fair?
What was there, John
Still is there, John
Come soon as you can
to my cloister
l've forgotten
the feel of your hand
Soon, madam, we shall walk
in Cupid's grove together
And we'll fondly survey
That promised land
Till then, till then
I am as I ever was
And ever shaII be
Yours
Saltpeter
John
John?
John !
Hmm?
What?
What are you doing
down here?
l thought you'd be up there,
cracking the whip.
Oh, well, the shutters
are still closed.
My word ! So they are.
Well, as the French say. . .
Oh, please, Franklin !
Spare me your bawdy mind
first thing in the morning.
Dare we call?
A congressman dares anything.
Go ahead.
Me?
Your voice is more piercing.
Oh, John, look at her.
Just look at her.
JOHN: l am.
She's even more magnificent
than l remember.
Of course, we didn't see
much of her front last night.
(SHUSHlNG)
Good morrow, madam.
Good morrow.
ls it the habit in
Philadelphia for strangers
to shout at ladies
from the street?
Not really, but. . .
And for men of your age
it is not only unseemly,
it is unsightly.
Uh, excuse me, madam,
but we met last evening.
l spoke to no one
last evening.
lndeed, you did not.
Nonetheless,
we did present ourselves.
This is Mr. John Adams.
l'm Dr. Benjamin Franklin.
The inventor of the stove.
Please! l know your names
very well, but. . .
Well, you said
you presented yourselves
last night?
lt's of no matter.
Your thoughts were
well-taken elsewhere.
Oh.
My husband is not yet up.
Well, then shall we
start over again?
Won't you join us?
Yes, of course.
Well, no wonder
the man couldn't write.
Who would think
of independence
married to her?
l feel an absolute fool.
That's good for you, John.
l tell you, Franklin,
it's positively indecent.
John, they're young
and they're in love.
Not them, Franklin. Us.
Standing down here,
waiting for them to, uh. . .
Well, what will
people think?
Don't worry, John.
The history books
will clean it up.
Well, it doesn't matter.
l'll not appear in
the history books anyway.
Only you.
Franklin did this
and Franklin did that,
and Franklin did
some other damned thing.
Franklin smote the ground
and out sprang
George Washington,
fully grown
and on his horse.
Franklin then
electrified him with his
miraculous lightning rod
then the three of them,
Franklin, Washington
and the horse,
conducted
the entire revolution
all by themselves.
l like it.
l beg your pardon, gentlemen.
lt is indeed an honor
to meet the two
greatest men in America.
Certainly the greatest
within earshot anyway.
l'm not an idle flatterer,
Dr. Franklin.
My husband
admires you both greatly.
Then we are
doubly flattered,
for we admire very much
that what
your husband admires.
Uh, did you
sleep well, madam?
Hmm?
Huh !
Oh. Uh. . .
Well, l mean,
did you lie. . .
(SCOFFS)
Damn it, you know
what l mean.
Yes, John, we know
what you mean.
Tell us about yourself.
We've heard precious little.
What's your
first name?
Martha.
Martha!
He might at least
have told us that.
Your husband
doesn't say very much.
Most silent man
in Congress.
l have never heard
him utter three
sentences together.
Not every man's
a talker, John.
Yes, it's true, you know.
Tom is not a talker.
Oh, he never
speaks his passions
He never speaks
his views
Whereas other
men speak volumes
The man I Iove
is mute
In truth
I can't recaII
Being wooed
with words
At aII
Even now
Oh, don't stop,
madam.
No. Tell us,
how did he win you?
And how does he hold on
to a bounty such as you?
Well, surely you've noticed
that Tom is a man of
many accomplishments.
Of course.
Author, lawyer,
statesman, architect,
farmer.
And still one more that
l hesitate to mention.
Don't hesitate, madam.
Don't hesitate.
No, tell us.
What else can that
redheaded tombstone do?
He plays the violin
He tucks it
right under his chin
And he bows
Oh, he bows
For he knows
Yes, he knows
That it's
hi-hi-hi-diddIe diddIe
'Twixt my heart,
Tom and his fiddIe
My strings
are unstrung
Hi-hi-hi
Hi
I am undone
The violin, madam?
I hear his vioIin
And l get
that feeling within
And l sigh
Oh, l sigh
He draws near,
very near
And it's
hi-hi-hi-diddIe diddIe
And goodbye to the fiddle
My strings
are unstrung
Hi-hi-hi
Hi
l'm always undone
That settles it, John.
We're taking up the violin.
Very well, madam.
You have us playing
the violin. What happens next?
Next, Mr. Adams?
Yes. What does
Tom do now?
Why, just what
you'd expect.
We dance.
Dance?
Dance? lncredible!
One, two, three.
One, two, three!
JOHN: Who's playing
the violin?
John, really?
John, you can dance.
We still do a few
things in Boston, Franklin.
Hi-hi-hi
Hi
When heaven
caIIs to me
Sing me
no sad elegy
Say l died
Loving bride
Loving wife,
loving life
For it was
hi-hi-hi-diddIe diddIe
'Twixt my heart,
Tom and his fiddIe
And ever 'twiII be
Hi-hi-hi
Hi
Through eternity
He plays
the vioIin
He plays the violin
JOHN: Look! Look, Franklin,
he's done it. He's written it.
"Dear Mr. Adams,
l am taking my
wife back to bed.
"Kindly go away.
Your obedient,
T. Jefferson."
lncredible!
(CHUCKLlNG)
You know, perhaps
l should have written
the declaration
after all.
At my age,
there's little doubt
the pen is mightier
than the sword.
For it's
hi-hi-hi-diddIe diddIe
And God bIess
a man who can fiddIe
And independency
Hi-hi-hi
Hi
Ya-da-da-da-da
Through eternity
He plays the violin
VioIin
THOMSON:
Pennsylvania, Delaware,
Maryland, Virginia's absent,
and North Carolina,
South Carolina and Georgia.
And what follows
is a complete
and up-to-date list
of all the committees
of this Congress,
now sitting, about to
sit or just having sat.
"A committee formed
to investigate a
complaint made against
"the quality of yeast
manufactured by Mr.
Henry Pendleton's mill
"designated as
the Yeast Committee."
"A committee
formed to consider
the most effective method
"of dealing with spies
"designated as
the Spies Committee."
"A committee
formed to think,
perhaps to do,
"but in any case, to gather,
to meet, to confer, to talk,
"and perhaps even to resolve
that each rifle regiment
"be allowed at least
one drum and one fife
attached to each company,
"designated as the
Drum and Fife Committee."
"A committee formed to. . ."
Where is that committee?
What do you think of it,
Doctor? Democracy?
What Plato called
"a charming form
of government
"full of variety
and disorder."
l never knew Plato had
been to Philadelphia.
(LAUGHS)
Ben, l want you
to see some cards
l've gone and
had printed up.
Ought to save everybody here
a lot of time and effort,
considering the epidemic
of bad disposition
that's been going
on around here lately
"Dear sir, you are,
without any doubt,
a rogue, a rascal,
"a villain, a thief,
a scoundrel and
a mean, dirty,
"stinking, sniveling,
sneaking, pimping,
pocket-picking,
"thrice double-damned
no-good son-of-a-bitch."
And you sign your name.
What do you think?
l'll take a dozen
right now.
A-ha! Here it is.
"A committee formed
to answer all congressional
correspondence,
"designated as the
Congressional
Correspondence Committee."
All right, Franklin,
enough socializing.
There's work to be done.
Good morning, John.
What?
Good morning.
Oh. Good morning,
good morning.
Now then,
let's get to it.
Get to what?
Unanimity, of course.
Look at that board.
Six nays to win over
in little more than a week.
"A committee formed
to consider the problem
of counterfeit money
"designated as the
Counterfeit Money
Committee."
Oh, God ! What. . .
All right, John,
all right.
Where shall we start?
Well, what about
Delaware?
Sad thing to see them
on the wrong side
after all this time.
Any news of Rodney?
Yes. McKean's back.
Thomas!
"A committee formed
to study the causes
"of our military
defeat in Canada."
Thomas,
how did you
leave Caesar?
ls he still alive?
Aye, but the
journey to Dover
was fearful
hard on him.
He never complained,
but l could see
the poor man was
suffering terrible.
But you got him
safely home.
l did,
but l doubt he'll ever
set foot out of it again.
That leaves you and Read
split down the middle.
Will he come over?
l don't know.
He's a stubborn
ignoramus.
Work on him.
Keep after him till
you wear him down.
Look, John,
face facts, will you?
lf it were just Read
standing in our way,
it wouldn't be so bad,
but look for
yourself, man.
Maryland, Pennsylvania
and the entire South.
lt's impossible!
Well, it's impossible
if we all stand around
complaining about it.
To work, McKean !
One foot in front
of the other!
l believe l put
it a better way.
Never leave off
until tomorrow. . .
Shut up, Franklin.
But what good will it do?
You know Dickinson.
He'll never give in.
And you haven't
heard the last of
Rutledge either.
Never mind about them.
Your job is George Read.
Talk him deaf
if you have to,
but bring us
back Delaware.
There's a
simpler way.
What?
This'll break
the tie.
All right, John,
who's next?
"A committee
formed to keep secrets
"designated as
the Secrets Committee."
Pennsylvania
and Maryland.
Now, l suggest
you try to get your
own house into order
and l'll take a crack
at old vacant-face.
Lord, look at him
stuff himself.
Ah, Mr. Chase!
How about it, Chase?
When are you coming
to your senses, man?
Please, Mr. Adams,
not while l'm eating.
Mr. Wilson, sir?
lt's time to
assert yourself.
Tell me something.
When you were a judge,
how in hell did you
ever make a decision?
The decisions l made
were all based on
legality and precedence.
But there is
no legality here
and certainly
no precedent.
Because it's a
new idea, you clot!
We'll be setting
our own precedent!
No, Mr. McKean.
No, no, no!
Damn your
eyes, Read !
You come into this
world screaming "no,"
and you're determined
to leave it the same way,
you slimy worm !
The Congress is
waiting on you, Chase!
America is waiting !
The whole world is waiting !
What's that? Kidney?
Leave me alone,
Mr. Adams!
You're wasting
your time.
lf l thought we
could win this war,
l'd be at the front
of your ranks.
But you must know
it's impossible.
You've heard General
Washington's dispatches.
His army has
fallen to pieces.
Washington is
exaggerating
the situation
in order to arouse
this torpid Congress
into action.
Why, as chairman of
the War Committee,
l can state for a fact
that the army has
never been in
better shape.
Never have troops
been more cheerful.
Never have soldiers
been more resolute.
Never have training
and discipline
been more spirited.
Oh, good God.
(BELL RlNGlNG)
HANCOCK: May we have
your ears, gentlemen?
Mr. Thomson
has a dispatch.
"From the Commander,
army of the United
Colonies in New York,
"dispatch number 1 , 1 57,
"to the Honorable Congress,
John Hancock, president.
"Dear sir,
it is with the utmost despair
that l must report to you
"the disorder
and confusion
"that reign in
every department."
Oh, sweet Jesus!
"The Continental soldier
is as nothing ever seen
"in this or any other century.
"He is a misfit,
ignorant of hygiene,
"destructive,
disorderly
"and totally
disrespectful of rank.
"Only this last
is understandable,
"as there is an incredible
reek of stupidity
amongst the officers.
"The situation
is most desperate
"at the New Jersey
training ground
in New Brunswick
"where every
able-bodied
whore in the. . ."
Whore?
"ln the colonies
has assembled.
"There are constant
reports of drunkenness,
"desertion, foul language,
"naked bathing in
the Raritan River,
"and an epidemic
"of the French disease."
"l have placed
this town off-limits to
all military personnel
"with the exception
of officers.
"l beseech the Congress
to dispatch the War
Committee to this place
"in the hope of
restoring
"some of the order
and discipline we need
to survive.
"Your obedient,
"G. Washington."
That man would
depress a hyena.
(LAUGHlNG)
Well, Mr. Adams,
you're chairman of
the War Committee.
Do you feel up
to whoring,
drinking, deserting
and New Brunswick?
There must be
some mistake.
l have an aunt
who lives in
New Brunswick.
(LAUGHlNG)
You must tell her to
keep up the good work.
Come, come, Mr. Adams.
You must see
that it's hopeless.
Let us recall
General Washington
and disband
the Continental Army
before we're
overwhelmed.
Yes, indeed. The English
would like that, now,
wouldn't they?
Why not ask
them yourself?
They ought to be
here any minute.
And when they
hang you, Mr. Adams,
l hope you will
put in a good word
for the rest of us.
Face facts,
Mr. Adams.
A handful of drunk
and disorderly recruits
against the entire
British Army,
the finest
musket men
on Earth.
How can we win?
How can we even
hope to survive?
Answer me
straight, Chase.
lf you thought we
could beat the Redcoats,
would Maryland say
yea to independence?
Well, l suppose. . .
No supposing.
Would you or
wouldn't you?
Very well,
Mr. Adams.
Yes, we would.
Then come with me
to New Brunswick
and see for yourself.
MAN 1 : John, are you mad?
You heard what
Washington said.
lt's a shambles.
MAN 1 : They're pushing
you into it, Johnny!
What do you say, Chase?
MAN 2: Go ahead, Sam.
lt sounds lively
as hell up there.
All right.
Why not?
And maybe
it'll be
John Adams
who comes
to his senses.
Mr. President,
the War Committee
will heed General
Washington's request.
A party consisting of
Mr. Chase, Dr. Franklin
and myself will
leave immediately.
ls that. . .
ls that satisfactory
with you, Dr. Franklin?
Wake up, Franklin !
You're going to
New Brunswick.
Like hell l am.
What for?
The whoring
and the drinking.
All right, Chase!
Move all that lard.
Not a moment to lose.
Left, right, left, right.
Left, right, left!
Mr. McNair, all this
talk of independence
has left a certain
foulness in the air.
My friends and l
would appreciate it
if you could
open some windows.
Well, what about
the flies?
The windows,
Mr. McNair.
Open the windows,
close the windows.
Sweet Jesus!
Oh, say, do you
see what I see?
Congress sitting
here in sweet serenity
I could cheer,
the reason's cIear
For the first
time in a year
Adams isn't here
And look, the sun
is in the sky
A breeze is blowing by
And there's not
a single fly
l sing hosanna
Hosanna
Hosanna, hosanna
And it's cooI
Come, ye cool,
cool, conservative men
Our like may never
ever be seen again
We have land,
cash in hand
Self-command,
future planned
Fortune thrives,
society survives
ln neatly
ordered Iives
With weII-endowered wives
Come sing hosanna
Hosanna
ln our breeding
and our manner
We are cooI
Come, ye cool,
cool, considerate set
We'll dance together
to the same minuet
To the right,
ever to the right
Never to the left,
forever to the right
Let our creed
be never to exceed
Regulated speed
No matter
what the need
Come sing hosanna
Hosanna
EmbIazoned on our banner
ls keep cool
To the right,
ever to the right
Never to the left,
forever to the right
Hands attach,
tightly latch
Everybody match
l have a new dispatch
"From the Commander,
army of the United
Colonies in New York,
"dispatch number 1 , 1 58,
"to the Honorable Congress,
John Hancock, president.
"Dear sir, l awoke
this morning to find
that General Howe
"has landed 25,000
British regulars and
Hessian mercenaries
"on Staten lsland,
"and that the fleet,
under the command
"of his brother,
Admiral Lord Howe,
"controls not only
the Hudson and
the east rivers,
"but New York Harbor,
"which now looks like
all of London afloat.
"l can no longer,
in good conscience,
"withhold from the
Congress my certainty
"that the British
military object
"at this time
is Philadelphia.
"Happy should l be
if l could see the means
of preventing them,
"but, at present,
l confess l do not.
"How l wish l had never
seen the Continental Army.
"l would have
done better to retire
to the back country,
"and to live in a wigwam.
"Your obedient,
"G. Washington."
What we do, we do rationally
We never, ever go
off half-cocked, not we
Why begin till we
know that we can win
And if we cannot win,
why bother to begin?
We say this game's
not of our choosing
Why should we
risk losing?
We're cool, cool men
Mr. Hancock,
you're a man
of property,
one of us.
Why don't you join
us in our minuet?
Why do you
persist in dancing
with John Adams?
Good Lord, sir,
you don't even
like him.
That is true.
He annoys me quite a lot
But stiII I'd rather trot
to Mr. Adams' new gavotte
Why? For personal glory?
For a place in history?
Be careful, sir.
History will brand him
and his followers as traitors.
Traitors,
Mr. Dickinson?
To what?
The British Crown or
the British half crown?
Fortunately, there are
not enough men of property
in America
to dictate policy.
Perhaps not, but don't forget
that most men with nothing
would rather
protect the possibility
of becoming rich
than face the reality
of being poor.
And that is why
they will follow us. . .
To the right,
ever to the right
Never to left,
forever to the right
Where there's gold,
a market to behoId
Tradition that is oId
ReIuctant to be boId
l sing hosanna
Hosanna
In a sane
and Iucid manner
We are cool !
We're the cool,
cool, considerate men
Whose like may never,
ever be seen again
We've got land, cash in hand
Self-command, future planned
And we'll hold to our gold
Tradition that is oId
ReIuctant to be boId
We say this game's
not of our choosing
Why should we risk losing?
We're cooI
CooI
Cool, cool men
How'd you like
to try and borrow
a dollar from
one of them?
You want some
more rum, General?
General?
Lord, l ain't
even a corporal.
Yeah, well,
what's the
army know?
(LAUGHlNG)
Here, son.
There you go.
Sit down, gentlemen.
The chair rules it's
too damn hot to work.
Well, General,
what's it like
out there?
You probably
know more than me.
Sitting here?
Sweet Jesus,
this is the
last place
to find out
what's going on.
l'm aiming
to join up.
What are you
talking about?
You don't have
to join up.
You're in Congress.
What's that
got to do with it?
Well, you don't
see them rushing off
to get killed, do you?
They sure are great
ones for sending others,
l can tell you that.
Hey, who sits here?
Caesar Rodney
of Delaware.
Where are you from,
General?
Watertown.
Now where's that?
Massachusetts.
Well, then you
belong over there.
But be careful.
There's something
about that chair
that makes a man
awful noisy.
(CHUCKLlNG)
You seen any fighting?
Sure did.
l see'd my two best
friends get shot dead
on the very same day.
And at Lexington
it was, too.
Right on the
village green.
When they didn't
come home for supper,
their mamas
went down the hill
looking for them.
Mrs. Lowell,
she found Timothy.
Right off.
But Mrs. Pickett. . .
She looked near half
the night for William.
He went and
crawled off
the green
before he died.
Mama, hey, Mama
Come looking for me
I'm here in the meadow
By the red maple tree
Mama, hey, Mama
Look sharp
Here I be
Hey, hey
Mama, look sharp
Them soldiers,
they fired
Oh, Ma, did we run
But then
we turned round
And the
battle begun
Then I went under
Oh, Ma, am l done?
Hey, hey
Mama, look sharp
My eyes are wide open
My face to the sky
ls that you l'm hearing
ln the tall grass nearby
Mama, come find me
Before I do die
Hey, hey
Mama
Look sharp
l'll close your eyes
My Billy
Them eyes
that cannot see
And l'll bury you
My Billy
Beneath the maple tree
And
Never again
Will you whisper to me
Hey
Oh, Mama
Look sharp
(GAVEL BANGS)
HANCOCK:
The secretary will
now read the report
of the Declaration
Committee.
Mr. Thomson.
"A declaration by
the representatives
"of the United
States of America,
"in general
Congress assembled.
"When in the course
of human events
"it becomes necessary
for one people
"to dissolve
the political bands
"which have
connected them
with another
"and to assume among
the powers of the Earth
"the separate
and equal station
"to which the
laws of nature
"and of nature's
god entitle them,
"a decent respect
to the opinions
of mankind
"requires that
they should declare
the causes
"which impel them
to the separation.
"We hold these
truths to be self-evident,
"that all men
are created equal.
"They're endowed
by their creator
"with certain
inalienable rights,
"that among these are
life, liberty and
the pursuit of happiness,
"that to secure
these rights. . ."
Jefferson ! We're back,
and we've got Maryland.
That is, we will,
as soon as Chase
gets through telling
the Maryland assembly
what we saw
in New Brunswick.
He's in Annapolis
right now,
describing a
ragtag collection
of provincial
militiamen
who couldn't
drill together,
train together
or march together.
But when a flock
of ducks flew over
and they saw
their first meal
in three full days,
sweet Jesus, could
they shoot together!
lt was a slaughter.
A slaughter.
They're reading
the declaration.
Good God !
How far have
they gotten?
"To render the military
independent of
"and superior to
the civil power."
". . .independent of
and superior to. . ."
Nothing to fear.
lt's a masterpiece.
l'm to be congratulated.
You?
For making him
write it.
Oh, of course.
lt's a masterpiece, l say
They will cheer
every word, every letter
l wish l felt that way
I beIieve I
can put it better
Now then attend
as friend to friend
Our DecIaration
Committee
For us l see immortality
ln Philadelphia City
A farmer, a lawyer
And a sage
A bit gouty in the leg
You know,
it's quite bizarre
To think that
here we are
Playing midwives
to an egg
Egg? What egg?
America. The birth
of a new nation.
lf only we could
be sure
of what kind of
a bird it's going to be.
Tom has a point.
What sort of bird
shall we choose
as the symbol of
our new America?
The eagle.
The dove.
The turkey.
The eagle.
The dove.
The eagle!
The eagle.
The turkey.
The eagle is a
majestic bird.
The eagle
is a scavenger,
a thief and
a coward.
A symbol of
over 1 0 centuries
of European mischief.
A turkey?
The turkey is
a truly noble bird.
Native American.
Source of sustenance of
our original settlers.
An incredibly brave
fellow who will not flinch
at attacking a regiment
of Englishmen
single-handedly!
Therefore, the national bird
of America is going to be. . .
The eagle!
We're waiting for
the chirp, chirp, chirp
Of an eaglet being born
Waiting for the chirp,
chirp, chirp
On this humid Monday morning
In this
congressional incubator
God knows
the temperature's
hot enough
To hatch a stone,
let alone an egg
We're waiting
for the scratch,
scratch, scratch
Of that tiny little fellow
Waiting for the egg to hatch
On this humid Monday morning
In this
congressional incubator
God knows
the temperature's
hot enough
To hatch a stone
But wiII it
hatch an egg?
The declaration
will be a triumph.
l tell you, a triumph.
lf l was ever
sure of anything,
l'm sure of that.
A triumph.
And if it isn't,
we've still got
four days left
to think of
something else.
The eagle's going
to crack the sheII
Of the egg
that England laid
Yes, sir, we can
tell, tell, tell
On this humid Monday morning
In this
congressional incubator
And just as
Tom here has written
Though the shell may
belong to Great Britain
The eagle inside
belongs to us
And just as
Tom here has written
We say, "To hell
with Great Britain"
The eagle inside
belongs to us
". . .and to do all
other acts and things
"which independent
states may of right do.
"And for the support
of this declaration,
"we mutually pledge to
each other our lives,
"our fortunes and
our sacred honor."
Thank you, Mr. Thomson.
The Congress has
heard the report
of the Declaration
Committee.
Are there any here
who wish to offer
alterations,
deletions, amendments
to this declaration?
Mr. President!
(CLAMORlNG)
Gentlemen !
Gentlemen, please!
Colonel McKean,
l saw your hand first.
Mr. Jefferson,
it's a funny paper
you've written, Tom,
but somewhere in it,
you mention Scottish
and foreign mercenaries
sent to destroy us.
Scottish, Tom?
That is in reference
to a Highland regiment
which stood
against us
at Boston.
lt's more likely
Germans wearing kilts
to disguise
their being there.
(LAUGHlNG)
l ask you to
remove the word
and avoid
giving offense
to a good people.
Mr. Jefferson?
The Reverend. . .
Witherspoon.
Mr. Jefferson,
nowhere do you mention
the Supreme Being.
Now, surely this
was an oversight,
for how could we hope
to achieve a victory
without His help?
Therefore,
l most humbly suggest
the following addition
to your final sentence.
"With a firm reliance
on the protection of
Divine Providence."
Mr. Jefferson?
Mr. Read.
Among your charges
against the king,
Mr. Jefferson,
you accuse him
of depriving us
of the benefits
of trial by jury.
This is untrue, sir.
ln Delaware, we've
always had trial by jury.
ln Massachusetts,
we have not.
Well, then l suggest
that the words
"in many cases"
be added.
Mr. Jefferson?
"ln many cases"?
Brilliant!
l suppose every time
you see those three words,
your puny chest
will swell with pride
over your great
historical contribution.
lt's more memorable
than your
unprincipled
whitewash
of that race
of barbarians!
Race of barbarians?
(ALL SHOUTlNG)
Why, l'll have you. . .
Colonel McKean,
Mr. Read, that's enough !
Mr. Hopkins.
l've no objections,
Johnny.
l'm just trying
to get a drink.
l should've known.
McNair, get him a rum.
Mr. Bartlett.
Mr. Jefferson.
l beg you to remember
that we still have
friends in England.
l see no purpose
in antagonizing them
with such phrases as. . .
"Unfeeling brethren"
and "enemies at war."
Our quarrel is
with the British king,
not the British people.
Be sensible, Bartlett.
Remove those phrases,
and the entire paragraph
becomes meaningless.
And it so happens
that it's one of the most
stirring and poetic
of any passage in the
entire document. Now. . .
We're a Congress, Mr. Adams,
not a literary society.
l ask that the entire
paragraph be stricken.
Mr. Jefferson?
Good God.
Jefferson, when are
you going to speak up
for your own work?
l had hoped that
the work would
speak for itself.
Mr. Hancock?
What is it,
Mr. McNair?
l can't say
l'm very fond of
"The United States
of America"
as a name
for a new country.
(ALL SHOUTlNG)
l don't care what
you're fond of,
Mr. McNair.
You're not a member
of this Congress!
Mr. Sherman.
Brother Jefferson,
l noted at least
two distinct and
direct references
to the British Parliament
in your declaration.
Do you think
it's wise to alienate
that august body
in light of
our contention
that they've never
had any authority
over us anyway?
This is a revolution,
damn it!
We're going to have
to offend somebody.
Brother Hancock!
(ALL SPEAKlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY)
John. John.
You'll give yourself
an attack of apoplexy
if you're not careful.
Have you heard what
they're doing to it?
Have you heard?
l heard.
And, so far,
that's just
our friends.
Can you imagine
what our enemies
will do?
HANCOCK: The word
"parliament" will be
removed wherever it occurs.
They won't
be satisfied
till they remove
one of the "F's"
from Jefferson's name.
Courage, John.
lt won't last
much longer.
Mr. Dickinson.
DlCKlNSON: Mr. Jefferson,
l have very little
interest in your paper,
as there's
no doubt
in my mind
that we've all but
heard the last of it.
But l am curious
about one thing.
Why do you refer
to King George
as a tyrant?
Because he
is a tyrant.
l remind you,
Mr. Jefferson,
that this tyrant
is still your king.
When a king
becomes a tyrant,
he thereby
breaks the contract
binding his
subjects to him.
How so?
By taking away
their rights.
Rights that
came from him
in the first place?
All except one.
The right to be free
comes from nature.
And are we not free,
Mr. Jefferson?
Homes entered
without warrant.
Citizens arrested
without charge.
And in many places,
free assembly
itself denied.
No one approves
of such things,
but these are
dangerous times.
Be careful,
Mr. Dickinson.
Those who give up
some of their liberty
in order to
obtain a little
temporary safety,
deserve neither
liberty nor safety.
Mr. Wilson.
Do we in Pennsylvania
consider King George
a tyrant?
Well, l don't know.
He. . .
Oh. Uh. . .
No. No, we don't.
He's not a tyrant.
ln Pennsylvania.
There you are,
Mr. Jefferson.
Your declaration does
not speak for us all.
l demand the word
"tyrant" be removed.
THOMSON: Very well.
Just a moment,
Mr. Thomson.
l do not consent.
The king
is a tyrant
whether we
say so or not.
We might as well
say so.
But l already
scratched it out.
Then scratch it
back in.
(CLAPPlNG)
JEFFERSON:
Put it back, Mr. Thomson.
The king will
remain a tyrant.
Mr. Hewes.
Mr. Jefferson.
Nowhere do you mention
deep-sea fishing rights.
(ALL CLAMORlNG)
Oh, good God !
Fishing rights!
How long is this
piddling to go on?
We have been here
for three full days.
We have endured,
by my count,
85 separate changes,
and the removal of
close to 400 words.
Now, would you
whip it and beat it till
you break its spirit?
l tell you
that document
is a masterful expression
of the American mind !
lf there are
no more changes,
then l can assume
the report of the Declaration
Committee has been. . .
Just a moment,
Mr. President.
Look out.
l wonder if we might prevail
upon Mr. Thomson
to read again a small
portion of Mr. Jefferson's
declaration.
The one beginning
"He has waged cruel war."
"He has affected. . .
He's combined. . .
"He's abdicated. . .
He's plundered. . .
"He's constrained. . .
He's excited. . .
He's incited. . .
"He's waged cruel war."
Here it is.
"He's waged cruel war
against human nature itself
"in the persons
of a distant people
who never offended him,
"captivating and
carrying them
"into slavery in
another hemisphere,
"Determined to
keep open a market
"where men should
be bought and sold,
"he has prostituted his. . ."
That will suffice,
Mr. Thomson.
l thank you, sir.
Mr. Jefferson,
l can't quite make out
what it is you're
talking about.
Slavery, Mr. Rutledge.
Oh, yes.
You're referring to us
as slaves of the king.
No, sir. l'm referring
to our slaves.
Black slaves.
Why didn't you
say so, sir?
Were you trying to
hide your meaning?
No, sir.
Just another
literary license, then.
lf you like.
l don't like at all,
Mr. Jefferson.
To us,
in South Carolina,
black slavery is
our peculiar institution,
and a cherished
way of life.
Nevertheless,
we must abolish it.
Nothing is more
certainly written
in the book of fate
than that these
people shall be free.
l am not concerned
with the book of fate
right now, Mr. Jefferson.
l'm more concerned
with what is written in
that little paper there.
That little
paper there
deals with freedom
for Americans.
Oh, really?
Mr. Adams
is now calling our
black slaves "Americans."
Are they, now?
Yes, they are.
They're people
and they're here.
lf there's any
other requirement,
l've never heard of it.
They are here, yes,
but they are not people,
sir. They are property.
No, sir.
They are people
who are being
treated as property.
l tell you, the rights
of human nature
are deeply wounded
by this
infamous practice.
Then see to your
own wounds,
Mr. Jefferson,
for you are
a practitioner!
Are you not?
l have
already resolved
to release
my slaves.
Then l'm sorry,
for you've
also resolved
the ruination of
your personal economy.
JOHN: Economy.
Always economy.
There's more to this
than a filthy purse
string, Rutledge.
lt's an offense
against man and God.
HOPKlNS: lt's a
stinking business,
Mr. Rutledge.
A stinking business.
ls it really,
Mr. Hopkins?
Then what is
that l smell
floating down
from the North?
Could that be
the aroma of hypocrisy?
For who holds the
other end of that filthy
purse string, Mr. Adams?
Our Northern
brethren
feeling a bit tender
toward our slaves.
They don't
keep slaves.
Oh, no.
But they're
willing to be
considerable carriers
of slaves to others.
They're willing.
For the shilling.
Or haven't you heard,
Mr. Adams?
Clink, clink.
MoIasses to rum
To sIaves
Oh, what a
beautifuI waItz
You dance with us
We dance with you
In moIasses and rum
And sIaves
Who sail the ships
out of Boston
Ladened with
BibIes and rum?
Who drinks a toast
to the lvory Coast?
Hail Africa,
the sIavers have come
New England with Bibles
And rum
And it's off with
the rum and the BibIes
Take on the slaves,
clink, clink
Then haiI and
fareweII to the smeII
Of the African coast
MoIasses to rum
To sIaves
'Tisn't morals,
'tis money that saves
ShaII we dance
to the sound
Of the profitable pound?
In moIasses and rum
And sIaves
Who sail the ships
out of Guinea
Ladened with
BibIes and sIaves?
'Tis Boston can boast
to the West Indies coast
Jamaica, we brung
what ye craves
Antigua, Barbados
We brung Bibles
And sIaves
Gentlemen, you mustn't think
that our Northern friends
see our black slaves
as merely figures
in a ledger.
Oh, no.
They see them as
figures on a block.
Look at the faces at
the auctions, gentlemen.
White faces on
African wharves.
Seafaring faces.
New England faces.
"Put them in the ships."
"Cram them in the ships."
"Stuff them in the ships."
Hurry, gentlemen.
Let the auction begin.
Ya-ha, ya-ha-ma-cundah
Gentlemen, do you hear?
That's the cry
of the auctioneer.
Ya-ha, ya-ha-ma-cundah
Slaves, gentlemen!
Black gold!
Living gold!
Gold from Angola!
Guinea, Guinea, Guinea!
BIackbirds for saIe
Ashanti, Ibo, Ibo, Ibo!
HandIe them!
FondIe them!
But don't finger them!
They're prime
Ya-ha, ya-ha-ma-cundah
For the love of God,
Mr. Rutledge, please.
MoIasses to rum
To sIaves
Who sail the ships
back to Boston
Ladened with gold
See it gleam
Whose fortunes are made
in the triangle trade
Hail slavery,
the New England dream
Mr. Adams,
l give you a toast
Hail, Boston
Hail, Charleston
Who stinketh
the most?
JOHN: Mr. Rutledge,
please!
Mr. Hewes.
Dr. Hall.
Don't worry, John.
They'll be back.
Aye, to vote us down.
CHASE: Adams! Franklin !
lt's done. l have it.
And the Maryland
Assembly's approved it.
l told them about
one of the greatest
military engagements
in history
against a flock of. . .
What's wrong?
l thought. . .
You'll have
to forgive them,
Mr. Chase.
They just suffered
a slight setback.
And after all,
"What is a man profited
"if he shall gain Maryland
and lose the entire South?"
Matthew, Chapter 1 6,
Verse 26.
McNair.
Oh, l know.
The flies.
No.
The rum.
Well, what are we
all sitting around for, hmm?
We're wasting time.
Precious time.
Thomas, l want you
to ride down into Delaware
and fetch back
Caesar Rodney.
John, are you mad?
lt's 80 miles,
and he's a dying man.
No, he's a patriot.
(SCOFFS) John,
what good will it do?
The South's done us in.
And suppose they
change their minds?
Can we get Delaware
without Rodney?
God ! What a bastardly
bunch we are.
Stephen,
l want you to. . .
l'm going to the tavern,
Johnny.
lf there's anything
l can do for you there,
let me know.
Chase.
Bartlett!
What's the use,
John? The vote's
tomorrow morning.
There's less than
a full day left.
Roger.
Face facts, John.
lt's finished.
l'm sorry, John.
We have no choice,
John.
The slavery clause
has got to go.
Franklin, what are you saying?
lt's a luxury we can't afford.
A luxury?
A half million souls
in chains,
and Dr. Franklin
calls it a luxury.
Maybe you should've
walked out with the South.
You forget yourself, sir.
l founded the first
anti-slavery society
on this continent.
Don't wave
your credentials at me.
Perhaps it's time
you had them renewed.
The issue here
is independence.
Perhaps you've
forgotten that fact,
but l have not.
How dare you
jeopardize our cause
when we've come so far!
These men,
no matter how much
we may disagree with them,
are not ribbon clerks
to be ordered about.
They're proud,
accomplished men.
The cream of their colonies.
And whether
you like it or not,
they and the people
they represent
will be part of
this new nation
you hope to create.
Now either learn
how to live with them
or pack up and go home.
ln any case,
stop acting like
a Boston fishwife.
Good God.
What's happened to me?
John Adams.
The great John Adams.
What have l come to?
Law practice down the pipe.
Farm mortgaged to the hilt.
At a stage in life
when other men prosper,
l'm reduced to
living in Philadelphia.
Philadelphia.
(SlGHS)
Abigail,
what am l going to do?
ABlGAlL: Do, John?
l need your help.
You don't usually
ask my advice.
Yes, well,
there doesn't appear to be
anyone else right now.
Very well, John.
What is it?
The entire South
has just walked out
of this Congress,
George Washington
is on the verge
of total annihilation,
and the precious cause
for which l have labored
these several years
has come to nothing.
And it seems
that l'm obnoxious
and disliked.
Nonsense, John.
That l am unwilling
to face reality.
Foolishness, John.
That l'm pigheaded.
Ah, well, there you
have me, John.
I'm afraid
you are pigheaded.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, yes.
Oh, Abby.
Has it been any kind
of a life for you?
God knows
l haven't given you
very much.
l never asked for more.
After all,
l am Mrs. John Adams.
That's quite a lot
for one lifetime.
ls it, Abby?
Well, think of it, John.
To be married to the man
who is always the first
in line to be hanged. . .
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Yes. The agitator.
Why, Abby?
You must tell me
what it is. l. . .
Well, l have always
been dissatisfied.
l know that.
But lately,
l find that l reek
of discontentment.
lt fills my throat
and it floods my brain.
(SlGHS)
Sometimes l fear there
is no longer a dream,
but only
the discontentment.
Oh, John.
Can you really know
so little about yourself?
Can you think
so little of me
that you'd believe
l'd marry the man
you've described?
Have you forgotten
what you used to say
to me? l haven't.
"Commitment, Abby.
"Commitment.
"There are only
two creatures of value
on the face of this Earth.
"Those with a commitment,
"and those who require
the commitment of others."
Do you remember, John?
Yes, l remember.
McNAlR: Mr. Adams!
Mmm.
Are you up there,
Mr. Adams?
What do you want?
There's a delivery
down here for you.
What is it?
Where did it come from?
Who sent it?
Compliments
of the Concord Ladies'
Coffee CIub
And the Sisterhood
of the Truro Synagogue
And the Friday Evening
Baptist Sewing Circle
And the Holy Christian
Sisters of St. CIaire
All for you
John
I am as I ever was
And ever shaII be
Yours, yours, yours
Yours
Abigail, what's in these kegs?
Saltpeter, John
McNair!
McNair, go out and
buy every damned pin
you can find in Philadelphia.
Pin?
What sort of pin?
Well, l don't know.
Whatever the ladies
use for their sewing.
Franklin, Jefferson,
what are you all
sitting around for?
Didn't you hear
a word l said before?
Oh, never mind
about that.
Now, here's what
l want you to do.
John, l'm not even
speaking to you.
lt's too late
for that, damn it.
There's work to be done.
Jefferson,
go find Rutledge.
Don't come back until
you've worn him down.
Now, you're both
Southern aristocrats.
lf he'll listen
to anybody,
he'll listen to you.
Franklin,
out of that chair!
What good is the South
if you can't deliver
Pennsylvania, hmm?
Talk to Wilson.
Get him away
from Dickinson.
That's the only way to do it.
Go on, now, both of you.
John. . .
Time's running out,
damn it.
Now move.
l'm still
from Massachusetts, John.
You know where l stand.
l'll do whatever you say.
No.
No, you're the president
of Congress.
You're a fair man, Hancock.
Stay that way.
(FOOTSTEPS)
Tell me, Mr. Thomson,
out of curiosity,
do you stand
with Mr. Dickinson,
or do you stand with me?
l stand
with the General.
Well, lately,
l've had the oddest
feeling that he's been
writing to me.
I have been
in expectation
Of receiving a reply
On the subject of
my last 1 5 dispatches
ls anybody there?
Does anybody care?
"Your humble
and obedient. . ."
"ls anybody there?
(SCOFFS)
"Does anybody care?"
Does anybody see
what I see?
They want me to quit
They say,
"John, give up the fight"
Still to England, l say
Good night,
forever, good night!
For I have crossed
the Rubicon
Let the bridge
be burned behind me
Come what may
Commitment!
The croakers all say
we'll rue the day
There'll be hell to pay
in fiery purgatory
Through all the gloom,
through all the gloom
l can see the rays
of ravishing light
And glory
ls anybody there?
Does anybody care?
Does anybody see what l see?
I see fireworks
l see the pageant
and pomp and parade
l hear the bells ringing out
I hear the cannons roar
I see Americans
AII Americans free
Forevermore
How quiet,
how quiet the chamber is
How silent,
how siIent the chamber is
ls anybody there?
Does anybody care?
Does anybody
see what I see?
HALL: Yes, Mr. Adams.
l do.
Dr. Hall.
l didn't know anyone was. . .
l'm sorry if l startled you.
l couldn't sleep.
And in trying
to resolve my dilemma,
l remembered something
l'd once read.
That a representative
owes the people
not only his industry,
but his judgment.
And he betrays them
if he sacrifices it
to their opinion.
That was written
by Edmund Burke,
a member of
the British Parliament.
Good night,
Mr. Adams.
Good night.
FRANKLlN:
It's never been done before.
No colony has ever broken
from the parent stem
in the history of the world.
DlCKlNSON:
lf you have grievances,
and l'm sure you have,
our present system
must provide
a gentler means
of redressing them
short of revoIution.
FRANKLlN: We've spawned
a new race here.
Rougher, simpler,
more violent,
more enterprising,
Iess refined.
THOMSON: "My quartermaster
has no food, no arms,
no ammunition,
"and my troops are in
a state of near mutiny."
DlCKlNSON: No army, no navy...
THOMSON: "l pray God
some reIief arrives
"before the armada,
but fear it wiII not."
DlCKlNSON: ...no arms,
no ammunition,
no treasury, no friends.
RUTLEDGE: And when
they hang you, Mr. Adams,
l do hope you'll
put in a good word
for the rest of us.
RODNEY: England closing in,
cutting off our air.
There's no time!
JEFFERSON: To place before
mankind the common sense
of the subject...
FRANKLlN: The issue here
is independence.
Perhaps you've lost
sight of that fact,
but I have not.
THOMSON: "We mutually pledge
to each other our Iives
"our fortunes
and our sacred honor."
ABlGAlL: Can you really know
so little about yourself?
Very well.
The Congress will now
vote on Virginia's
resolution on independence.
(DOOR OPENS)
(SlGHS)
Thank you for coming,
Caesar.
God bless you,
sir.
The secretary
will call the roll.
And l remind you, gentlemen,
that a single "nay" vote
will defeat the motion.
Mr. Thomson.
New Hampshire?
New Hampshire
says yea.
Massachusetts?
Massachusetts
says yea.
Rhode lsland?
Rhode lsland
says yea.
Connecticut?
Connecticut
says yea.
New York?
Mr. Secretary,
New York
abstains courteously.
New York abstains.
Courteously.
New Jersey?
New Jersey
says yea.
Pennsylvania?
Mr. Secretary,
Pennsylvania
is not ready.
Please come back
to us later.
THOMSON:
Pennsylvania passes.
Delaware?
Just a moment.
Delaware,
by majority vote. . .
Aye.
. . .says yea.
Delaware says yea.
Maryland?
Maryland
says yea.
Maryland says yea.
Virginia?
Virginia
says yea.
Virginia says yea.
North Carolina?
North Carolina yields
to South Carolina.
South Carolina?
Well,
Mr. Adams?
Mr. Rutledge.
Mr. Adams,
you must believe
that l will do
what l promised to do.
What is it you want,
Rutledge?
Remove the offending passage
from your declaration.
lf we did that,
we would be guilty
of what we ourselves
are rebelling against.
Nevertheless remove it,
or South Carolina
will bury now and forever
your dream of independence.
John, l beg you,
consider what
you're doing.
Mark me, Franklin,
if we give in
on this issue,
posterity will
never forgive us.
That's probably true,
but we won't hear a thing.
We'll be long gone.
Besides, what will
posterity think we were?
Demigods?
We're men, no more,
no less,
trying to get
a nation started
against greater odds
than a more generous God
would have allowed.
First things first, John.
lndependence. America.
lf we don't secure that,
what difference
will the rest make?
Jefferson,
say something.
What else is there
to do?
Well, man,
you're the one
that wrote it.
l wrote all of it,
Mr. Adams.
There.
There it is, Rutledge.
You have your slavery.
Little good may it do you.
You now vote,
damn you !
Mr. President,
the fair colony
of South Carolina
says yea.
South Carolina
North Carolina
says yea.
Georgia?
Georgia
says yea.
Pennsylvania, second call.
Mr. President,
Pennsylvania regrets
all of the inconvenience
that such distinguished
men as Adams,
Franklin and Jefferson
were put to
just now.
They might've kept
their document intact
for all the difference
it will make.
Mr. President,
Pennsylvania says. . .
Just a moment.
l ask the delegation
to be polled.
Dr. Franklin,
don't be absurd.
A poll, Mr. President.
lt's a proper request.
HANCOCK: Yes, it is.
Poll the delegation,
Mr. Thomson.
THOMSON:
Dr. Benjamin Franklin.
Yea.
THOMSON:
Mr. John Dickinson.
Nay.
THOMSON:
Mr. James Wilson.
Judge Wilson?
There it is,
Mr. Wilson. lt's all
up to you now.
The whole question
of American independence
rests squarely
on your shoulders.
An entirely new nation
ready to be born
or to die at birth,
all on
your say-so.
Which will it be,
Mr. Wilson?
Every mapmaker in
the world is waiting
for your decision.
Come now, James.
Nothing has changed.
We mustn't let
Dr. Franklin create
one of his confusions.
The question
is clear.
Most questions are clear
when someone else
has to decide them.
lt would be a pity
for a man
who's handed down
hundreds of wise decisions
from the bench
to be remembered only
for the one unwise decision
he made in Congress.
James, you're keeping
everybody waiting.
The secretary has
called for your vote.
Please.
Don't push me, John.
l know what you
want me to do.
But Mr. Adams is correct
about one thing.
l'm the one who'll
be remembered for it.
What do you mean?
l'm different from you, John.
l'm different from
most of the men here.
l don't want
to be remembered.
l just don't want the
responsibility.
Yes, well, whether you
want it or not, James,
there's no way
of avoiding it.
Not necessarily, John.
lf l go with them,
l'll just be one among dozens.
No one will ever remember
the name of James Wilson.
But if l vote with you,
l'll be the man
who prevented
American independence.
l'm sorry, John.
l just didn't
bargain for that.
And is that how new
nations are formed?
By a nonentity
trying to preserve
the anonymity he
so richly deserves?
Revolutions come
into this world
like bastard children,
Mr. Dickinson.
Half improvised
and half compromised.
Our side
has provided
the compromise.
Now Judge Wilson
is supplying
the rest.
James.
l'm sorry, John.
My vote
Mr. Secretary,
Pennsylvania says yea.
The count
being 1 2 to none
with one abstention,
the resolution on independence
is adopted.
lt's done.
Mr. Thomson,
is the declaration
ready to be signed?
lt is.
Then l suggest
we do so.
And the chair
further proposes,
for our
mutual security
and protection,
that no man
be allowed to sit
in this Congress
without attaching
his name to it.
l'm sorry, Mr. President.
l cannot,
in good conscience,
sign such a document.
l will never stop hoping
for our eventual
reconciliation with England.
But because,
l regard America no less
than does Mr. Adams,
l will join the army
and fight in her defense
even though l believe
that fight to be hopeless.
Goodbye, gentlemen.
JOHN: Gentlemen of
the Congress,
l say yea, John Dickinson.
(KNOCKlNG TABLES)
(lNDlSTlNCT CHATTERlNG)
Very well.
Are there any
objections to
the declaration
being approved
as it now stands?
l have one, Mr. Hancock.
You, Mr. Adams?
Yes. Uh, Mr. Jefferson,
it so happens that
the word is "unalienable,"
not "inalienable."
l'm sorry, Mr. Adams,
but "inalienable"
is correct.
l happen to be
a Harvard graduate,
Mr. Jefferson.
(LAUGHTER)
l attended William
and Mary, Mr. Adams.
(LAUGHTER)
Gentlemen,
please!
Mr. Jefferson,
will you yield to
Mr. Adams' request?
No, sir. l will not.
Oh, very well. l withdraw it.
Oh, good for you, John.
(LAUGHTER)
l'll speak to the printer
about it later on.
(SlGHS)
Very well, gentlemen.
We're about to brave the storm
in a skiff made of paper.
And how it shall end,
God only knows.
MAN: That's a pretty
large signature, Johnny.
So Fat George
in London can read it
without his glasses.
(LAUGHTER)
All right,
step right up,
gentlemen.
Don't miss
your chance
to commit treason.
ALL: Ooh.
Hancock is right.
This paper is our passport
to the gallows.
But there's no
backing out now,
for if we do
not hang together,
we shall most assuredly
hang separately.
(LAUGHTER)
ln my case,
hanging won't be
so bad.
One snap
and it'll be all over,
just like that.
But look
at Read there.
He'll be dancing
a jig long after
l'm gone!
(LAUGHTER)
Gentlemen, forgive me
if l don't join
in the merriment,
but if we are
arrested now,
my name is still
the only one
on the damn thing !
(LAUGHTER)
"From the Commander,
army of
the United Colonies in. . ."
Army of the United
States in New York,
"dispatch number 1 ,209,
"to the Honorable Congress,
John Hancock, president.
"Dear sir, l can now report
with some certainty
"that the eve of battle
is near at hand.
"Toward this end,
l have ordered
the evacuation of Manhattan
"and directed our
defenses to take up
"stronger positions on
the Brooklyn Heights.
"At the present time,
my forces consist
"entirely of
Haslet's Delaware Militia
"and Smallwood's Marylanders,
"a total of 5,000 troops
to stand against
"twenty-five thousand
of the enemy.
"And l begin to notice
that many of us
"are lads under
1 5 and old men,
"none of whom
could truly be
called soldiers.
"One personal note
to Mr. Lewis Morris
of New York.
"l must regretfully report
"that his estates have
been totally destroyed,
"but that l have taken
the liberty of
transporting Mrs. Morris
"and eight of the children
to Connecticut and safety.
"The four older boys
are now enlisted in
the Continental Army.
"As l write these words,
"the enemy is plainly in sight
beyond the river.
"How it will end,
only Providence can direct."
"But, dear God,
what brave men
"l shall lose
"before
"this business
"ends.
"Your obedient,
"G. Washington."
Very well, gentlemen.
McNair.
Go ring the bell.
Mr. President.
Mr. Morris.
To hell
with New York.
l'll sign it anyway.
Thank you, Mr. Morris.
(MEN RAPPlNG ON TABLES)
Stephen, sit down.
No.
l want to remember
each man's face as he signs.
Very well.
Mr. Thomson.
New Hampshire.
Dr. Josiah Bartlett.
Massachusetts.
Mr. John Adams.
(BELL RlNGlNG)
Rhode lsland.
Mr. Stephen Hopkins.
Connecticut.
Mr. Roger Sherman.
New York.
Mr. Lewis Morris.
New Jersey.
The Reverend
John Witherspoon.
Pennsylvania.
Dr. Benjamin Franklin.
Delaware.
Mr. Caesar Rodney.
Maryland.
Mr. Samuel Chase.
Virginia.
Mr. Thomas Jefferson.
North Carolina.
Mr. Joseph Hewes.
South Carolina.
Mr. Edward Rutledge.
Georgia.
Dr. Lyman Hall.