The following program is brought
to you in living colour.
Tonight, we have Evel Knievel.
He's probably
the only man in history
that has become very wealthy
by trying to kill himself.
It's true.
He's somewhat of a legend.
He does incredible stunts
with motorcycles.
He has broken, I guess,
more bones
than anybody in history.
Yet he keeps at this.
Let's meet the gentleman.
Here is Evel Knievel.
I grew up in the 70s.
And Evel Knievel was the 70s.
He captured my imagination
like no one else.
Some of you
may have seen this film before.
This is a jump you made
at Caesar's Palace. What happened?
The motorcycle landed short
and ripped the handlebars
out of my hands.
I bounced for 60 yards
into the Dunes parking lot.
God...
you're an incredible man.
I didn't think of him
as a daredevil.
I thought of him
as a superhero.
No one ever went for it
like that before.
He invented that.
Since then, it has taken off
in a major way.
That's such a large part
of our culture now.
He inspired all that.
But, there will never
be another Evel.
I've been called a lot of things
by a lot of people,
crazy man, or con man.
But when you head down
that long white line
you better have made your peace
with God and know what you are doing
because a con man
ain't gonna get there.
I didn't know...
the story of the man.
And it was, you know,
pretty complex.
California judge has ordered
motorcycle stuntman Evel Knievel
to serve out the rest
of a jail sentence behind bars.
I'm a grown-ass man and...
some of the stuff
is tough to reconcile.
It's a crazy story.
It's just fast, faster,
and disaster.
LOUD MUSIC
♪ Friends say it's fine.
Friends say it's good.
♪ Everybody says
it's just like rock'n'roll.
♪ I move like a cat,
charge like a ram,
♪ sting like a bee.
♪ Babe, I wanna be your man.
♪ Well, it's plain to see
you were meant for me, yeah!
♪ I'm your boy,
your 20th century toy.
MUSIC CONTINUES
I was a member of the sportscasters
association of Los Angeles.
We used to have monthly meetings
on a Thursday
at a place called Red Tractors.
Everybody who was anybody came.
Tommy Lasorda,
Billy Jean King, was there,
Muhammad Ali
when he was Cassius Clay
first made his appearance here.
They were legitimate athletes
in their chosen professions.
All of a sudden there was this
commotion on Ventura Boulevard.
There was this nutcase going up
and down doing wheelies.
I didn't know what a wheelie was
until they explained it to me.
People didn't do wheelies
up and down the road.
That was crazy,
on a rear wheel of a motorcycle,
going 80 miles per hour
going waaa...
Everybody stopped
and would go "Ohh, look at that!"
Even the hard-bitten sports
announcers of that day and age
were taken aback by this guy,
who of course turned out
to be Evel Knievel.
If you told me
he was going to be world famous
I would say you're nuts.
If you are going to try
and understand Evel,
you got to go back
to his childhood.
His parents split up and left town.
So he was basically raised
by his grandparents.
Grandma and grandpa
did the best they could do.
He was just rambunctious, I guess.
Maybe he didn't have that attention
as a young boy when he needed it.
Truth is, Bobby was kind of angry
with his father
because he didn't get
to stay with him.
That's what I think.
He wanted to be with his father.
We were up at my grandma's house.
He and I were wrestling around.
I punched him in the mouth.
He lit on the back of his head.
I said "Bobby..." And nothing.
I thought
"Oh my god, I killed him."
And instantly
he had these wild eyes
because he knew what had happened.
Across the kitchen
there was a door that was
slightly open, the pantry door.
He ran at that door
and slammed it shut with his head.
That half stunned him again.
He turned around sitting down
and he pointed at me.
He said
"Did you see that?
"Nobody can hurt me.
You can't hurt me."
"Nobody can hurt me."
I think
growing up in Butte, Montana
without a father would...
would be hard to handle,
I would think.
Butte, Montana
was just a tough-ass mining town.
When the mines were going full
the bars were open 24 hours.
There was a lot of prostitution.
There was about 3000 whores
at that time.
There was just miners
drinking and fighting
You had to learn to cope in Butte.
Sometimes
coping meant with your fists.
You fought.
You stood up like a man.
You were taught that.
That's part of the Butte credo.
You just don't back down.
Knievel was a fighter
from the get go
even during grade school.
He would get a little obnoxious
at times.
You'd have to settle him down.
Well, you couldn't dare him.
If you'd dare him, he'd do it.
I remember
when Bob got his first motorcycle.
I don't know
why he had two tyres.
He always rode around
on the back one.
You never knew what he was gonna do
with that motorcycle in town.
He would be riding it all over
raising hell with everybody.
He liked to have the cops chase him.
You couldn't catch him on a bike
when you were in a patrol car.
One day
I go run up to the store.
Who's up there?
Big bad Knievel, you know.
He was a character.
I was scared
but I was kind of flattered.
"Gee, he is paying attention to me."
Then one day
he said "You are gonna marry me."
The story is
that he kidnapped her.
I don't know
if he kidnapped her or not.
That might have been something
they were planning together anyhow.
Who knows?
Yeah, I guess I was kidnapped.
I was just walking home from school
that day
when he said
"Get in the car."
I don't know it was just...
something just almost
overtook me and...
He drove me down to Dillon and...
danged if
we didn't get married there.
He had some weird ideas
about how life should be lived.
He thought that he should
be at the top of the heap.
That's why he did the stuff
he did to make money.
He'd run it
if there was a shady side to it.
He was happier if there was
something shady about it.
He made up his own job.
Actually, he started working
as a security officer at night.
He had a route
and used to go around
at 2 o'clock,
3 o'clock in the morning
and check all
the different establishments.
You'd pay him to be sure
the doors were locked.
If you didn't pay him
you might be robbed within a month.
He broke into my place.
He might've got 40 or 50 dollars
or like that but... nothing big.
Yeah, he ran a racket.
No question about it.
The police called me up
and told me
that there was a known safe-cracker
in town.
I knew they were talking about Evel.
He was a crook.
A con-man I guess you'd call him.
At the age of 19
he starts a semi-pro hockey team...
and convinces the Czechoslovakian
national team
to come to Butte to play them.
(Laughs)
And the Czechs kill them.
Like smoke them 22 to 3.
But I don't think
Evel was that upset about the score.
I think he left in the middle
of the second period
and the money disappeared.
There was no money to pay them.
Draw your own conclusions. Where did
the money go?
Butte likes people who bounce up
against the edges of the envelope.
They're forgiving
about some criminal activity.
But they don't particularly
like criminals.
He had three kids at the time.
Threw all of his burglar bags
in the river
and decided to go straight.
So Knievel gets this job
selling insurance
for Combined Insurance Company.
It was run by this guy,
W. Clement Stone,
who wrote a book called 'Success
Through a Positive Mental Attitude'.
I feel happy.
I feel terrific.
I think it really
changed his thinking drastically.
He was that way to begin with
and it just intensified it.
He was a legendary salesman.
When he was selling insurance
he was selling insurance,
and he was selling a lot of it.
I remember he went
to the mental hospital...
I think it was Deer Lodge.
And he wrote two hundred and
seventy-one policies
in this hospital...
mental hospital.
It was a super record.
Nobody had written
that many policies in a week ever.
He talked to the president
of the company at that time
and said "I'll break every record
in the company.
"Every single one that exists.
"You make me a Vice President
after I do that."
And Mr. Stawn says "Sorry,
that isn't going to happen."
Well, Knievel didn't like that.
So he picks up his family and
moves to Moses Lake, Washington
where he gets a job
selling Honda motorcycles.
He was making a good living at it
but it wasn't good enough for him.
He says "I think
I need to do something... weird.
"Some kind of a stunt
"so it'll get people to come down
here and see the motorcycles."
So he had this crazy idea
about doing this jump.
He says "I'm gonna jump
over cougars and rattle snakes."
I said "You got to be kidding me!"
My part
in that mountain lion jump was
I wore a white coat like a doctor
and Evel introduced me
as a veterinarian,
which was a crock of bull
but...
So he brings them down
and put the cougars underneath.
They are scared to death.
They won't come out.
They were like kitty cats.
But the snakes! Holy Christ!
We put them
in a big refrigerator carton
and they were pissed off!
He goes around the track
and then he goes up the ramp...
The minute he went up in the air
I could see he wasn't gonna make it.
My god,
he was about three feet short.
His back Tyre
hits a refrigerator carton.
The snakes go
flipping into the crowd.
Talk about people
running and getting out of there.
Jesus Christ! (Laughs)
The poor guy from Vantage
wants us to help catch his snakes!
I says you gotta be kidding me!
He just rode back on his motorcycle
and went up the jump
and waved at the crowd.
He didn't care about the snakes.
People started talking to him -
"What can you do next?"
And he started
thinking about that kind of stuff.
That's when he come up with the idea
of starting a stunt show.
I told him
"They are going to eat you up, boy.
"You'll never make it."
I was a bartender at Marty's Bar
in Orange, California.
And this fella comes in
sits at the end of the bar
and we start talking.
Well, he's a motorcycle daredevil.
He had jumped rattle snakes.
He wants to do
a big ramp-to-ramp jump.
He said people will go wild.
He just convinced me.
Somehow, I was able
to get two pickups,
a tractor, and a 40-foot trailer.
The logo on the side was
"Evel" Knievel
and His Motorcycle Daredevils.
The name Evel came
from his wild years in Butte.
He was given that name by the cops.
He was in jail
with a guy named Knawful.
They said "Well, better lock up
the doors. Pretty good tonight.
"We got an awful Knawful
and an evil Knievel in here."
He heard that and liked that.
He changed it to E V E L
because he didn't want
to sound too evil.
He got a bunch of people
working with him.
Good guys like Sweet Savage
and Eddie Mulder
and Klesh Fargo.
So he started
thinking up different stunts to do.
The flaming boards...
we'd soak them in gasoline
and light it on fire.
And he'd hit that first board
and just go...
Boom! The sparks!
The stuff would fly in the air!
Then...
Boom, hit the second one!
The sparks would fly!
Boom! Hit the third one,
the forth one and the fifth one!
Somehow Bob got this midget,
Butch Wilhelm, and
talked him into joining the show.
Bob said "He will do everything
I do in miniature."
And he would crash
on every single one.
So it looked like
when Bob was going to make his jump
something terrible
is going to happen.
He was such a crazy son of a bitch.
He'd do these stunts
and he never tried them before.
One time he had a motorcycle run
at him at about 60 miles per hour
and he jumped up,
but he didn't jump high enough.
And the motorcycle hit him
and flipped him over.
He was sprained from his waist
to his ankles.
I think at that point he decided
he was going to stick
to jumping with the motorcycles.
The equipment my dad jumped on,
compared
to what is going on today...
unbelievable.
The thing weighed 500 pounds.
It'd be like jumping a dump truck
over all those cars.
But he'd do it anyway.
I was the speedometer for Evel.
I'd stand there
and watch him and say
"You're going fast enough"
or "You're not going fast enough."
I guess you'd call it guesswork.
Bob jumped further and further
with each show.
The only thing is...
those stands were not full,
not by any means.
How do you convince people to come
to a sport they never heard of?
We were 52,000 dollars in debt.
Bob kept spending money
we didn't have.
That's when I decided
I had to leave.
Of course, then he saw
that he didn't need the team.
He went on his own.
Now, it would just be him
looking for his big break.
TV: Spanning the globe...
"Spanning the globe to bring you
the constant variety of sport."
For years, I caught myself
singing it in my sleep.
"The thrill of victory
and the agony of defeat."
TV: And the agony of defeat!
"The thrill of victory
and the agony of defeat."
And they always showed that skier...
where you never knew,
the word was he died.
The crash, that's what you remember
from the Wide World of Sports.
TV: The human drama
of athletic competition!
I remember the crazy stuff
they would show once in a while.
Skate-boarding
was on Wide World of Sports.
I remember that.
TV: ABC's Wide World of Sports...
We were in the business
of sports theatre.
Sports was drama.
Sports was a story.
I loved it. I covered some
of the weirdest things myself,
whatever brought in an audience.
America loved it.
TV: The human drama
of athletic competition!
Everybody rushed home from church
and watched ABC's Wide World
of Sports at one o'clock.
That was the biggest show on TV.
TV: ABC's Wide World of Sports!
Evel knows that the motorcycle race
at Askot Speedway is featured
on Wide World of Sports.
So he fast-talks the owner
into letting him do his thing.
Before we get back to racing
I'd like to introduce to you
a most unusual young man.
This is Evel Knievel.
His specialty in sports
is to take a motorcycle,
jump over a ramp
and leap through the air 90 feet.
That's what he's going
to try to do today,
over 15 automobiles.
You're trying 15 today?
The parachute is ready.
The motorcycle is ready.
And I'm ready.
I'm not gonna miss a day.
He is set to go.
He'll build up speed
as quickly as he can.
Here he goes!
And makes it!
A beautiful leap
as Evel Knievel gets the roar of
approval of the crowd here.
Here we are at this Wide World
of Sports' biggest race of the year,
biggest track race of the year.
And I won it.
I won the race.
You think anybody remember it?
No!
They know Knievel.
They remember Knievel out of that.
Not me.
I rode 100 laps,
rode my ass off.
So Evel got his foot in the door.
Now, he's gonna knock it down.
If you could think of the most
outrageous thing you could do
what would it be?
It would be jump the fountain
at Caesar's Palace.
I don't know where it came from.
How a guy would go
down Caesar's Palace strip,
look at the fountains...
what was he thinking?
Where did that come from?
Evel wants to do this stunt
in Vegas.
But no one knows
who the hell he is.
So he switches into hustler mode.
This guy called every news outlet,
told them that Evel Knievel,
famed stunt motorcyclist
was gonna jump Caesar's Palace
come Saturday morning. Be there.
So then he calls Jay Sarno,
the guy who runs Caesar's.
Each time, he would call
as a different person.
Each time,
he would mispronounce his own name.
I told him my name was Larson,
I was with Sports Illustrated.
I said "You ever heard
of Evel Nievel?"
He said "Evel Nievel?
Who the hell is this Evel Nievel?"
I waited two more days,
called him back up
and said "It's Dennis Houlan
from Wide World of Sports.
"Do you know Evel Knievel?"
He says
"Evel Nevel? Evel Knievel?
"Who is this crazy guy?
Everyone is calling me up about him.
"I think we have a deal with him,
I don't know. Call back." (Laughs)
AUDIENCE LAUGHS
Like a lot of his stunts
Caesar's Palace was one of those
that he dreamed up and sold
before he even knew
it was possible.
Then on the day
he's got the crowds there.
He doesn't know
if he can make it.
He's just got to go for it.
I talked with him for a while
before he jumped.
He was very unsettled
about the jump.
You could tell he was nervous.
He was making runs at the ramp.
We could hear the motorcycle.
We could hear the crowd.
Then the doorman...
got on the phone
and told us what went on.
My god,
that was horrible.
I thought he was dead.
I was horrified
to watch my friend
look like a rag doll.
I don't think he was unconscious.
But he was hurting.
So off to the hospital we went.
He had a broken wrist,
two broken ankles,
crushed his pelvis...
Then somehow, word gets out
that he is in a coma
and might not make it.
He told that story.
But he wasn't in a coma.
I flew down there.
It hadn't been but like two days
since he had the wreck
and he was awake
when I walked in the hospital room.
He had the press come in there
and play it up -
"Oh I'm about to die.
"I don't know
if I'm going to make it."
This is Knievel.
This is what he did.
He played it up right to the end.
Pretty soon
the crash footage was everywhere.
We saw him jump Caesar's Palace.
We saw that fall and his body
flopping and his head hitting...
all of the agony of that
and the broken bones.
That piece of film was amazing.
To see him go over and over
and roll all the way up
to the wall...
that's one of the great pieces
of footage of all time.
He was national news
all over the place.
He became instantly famous.
This guy somehow captured
what America needed.
He came along at the right time.
There was a certain cynicism
throughout the country.
Society was changing.
You had corruption in government.
Well, I'm not a crook.
The country had been battered
by many years of war.
America was coming apart
at the seams.
♪ Must be the season of the witch.
We were a little down on ourselves.
Along comes this kid
from Butte, Montana,
who showed us who we were
and wanted to be again.
♪ He wears red, white and blue,
stars and stripes, too. ♪
I guess we were looking
for some sort of a hero.
We had Superman and Batman...
But this guy was the real thing.
♪ Evel Knievel
For God and country too
Most motorcycle people wore black.
That is what Evel wanted to change.
That's where the red, white,
and blue letters came from.
He wore red, white and blue
because he was patriotic.
He loved his country.
But he also saw that it would
give him a boost with his image
and people were respecting him more.
He came out of those mounts in
his star-spangled suit and his cane.
And he said
"I am going to face death."
He opened the door
and invited people
to buy a ticket to watch truth.
For that disenchanted,
disillusioned generation,
where you didn't trust anybody
because even the president lied
here's a guy...
he's gonna risk everything.
He did it! Wow!
He did it! Yeah!
There was three TV stations
back then.
When Evel was on ABC
everyone knew it.
That's what you did that night,
is watch...
That's what you talked about
for the next few weeks afterwards.
He was so popular
that out of the top ten-rated
Wide World of Sports shows
in the 37 years of the show
he holds seven of them.
TV: Motorcycle daredevil,
Evel Knievel!
He was the talk of the world.
He was the greatest reality show
before reality shows existed.
Are you scared before a stunt?
Do you have fear?
I am not scared.
When I go out for that jump
I must say I have some concern
but I don't think
I've ever been afraid of anything.
If I know something is going to
happen, I try and train myself
to where I have complete control
over my mind and my body.
I relax when I hit instead
of freezing up and being scared.
He said to me "You know
what I was really good at?
"Was the take-off.
"You know what I was bad at
was the landing."
But he said
that it was the bad landings
that's what brought the crowds out.
Bobby used to say
nobody wants to see me die
but they don't want to miss it
if I do.
ANNOUNCER: Just to go up that ramp
and take a look at the distance
that he has got to hurdle
aboard his Harley Davidson machine...
He knew that if he wasn't perfect
when he left that ramp,
something awful
was going to happen
between the time he left there
and came down way over here.
If he told you he was going
to do something, he'd do it.
Even if he knew
it was going to kill him.
You were always the question of...
whether or not
he might not make it alive.
I would think my dad would die
every time he jumped.
It was stressful.
It was hard on us.
If he crashed
and got hurt
then he'd go out
and gonna do it again.
Everyone says "He's nuts.
He got hurt the last time."
Doctors, especially surgeons,
have been amazed
at how I can keep going.
He had recuperative powers
that were beyond normal people.
They'd say "You'll have this cast
for eight weeks" and... (Laughs)
He would take it off in three.
This may look
like just some abstract plumbing.
But this is actually the right hip
and right femur of Evel Knievel...
I think I have probably
become immune to pain.
I've learned to live with pain
for so long that I think...
what would hurt an average person
doesn't hurt me so much.
When we were growing up and my dad
broke bones and he was in pain
he never bitched about it,
he never complained about it.
No, no, I'll be all right.
I'm gonna jump some more.
He accepted that
that's what he had chosen to do.
It's something
he just had to deal with.
That's the way he dealt with it.
To be something,
a little extra special,
no matter what I want to do,
if I like to do it.
To be a champion, to be the best.
Even though I have been hurt
so many times.
And live
like a lot of people do,
live in a...
a Grey twilight world,
these kind of people
don't even know victory or defeat
because they have never
tried anything.
This is something
I feel compelled to do.
And I am going to do it.
I had sort of been brought along
the way of a teen idol.
Mm-mm!
I had enough star power going but
I kept trying to toughen up my act.
I thought "God, if I could
get a really good Western
"or a good action movie..."
I was looking for a sort of
modern-day Western character,
who would that be?
I remember seeing the footage
from Caesar's Palace.
I thought "Yeah, that's the movie."
In my mind, there was only one guy
that could do this right.
John Milius,
he had written 'Dirty Harry'
'Jeremiah Johnson'
and of course later
'Apocalypse Now'.
Milius just wrote it as if
he was writing for 'Patton'.
It had this sort
of mythic sound to it.
It has got this man
who thinks he is a gladiator.
I was excited to show Evel this.
He tells me to come meet him
in Hollywood
at the Saharan Motel,
that was up on Sunset.
He's been up all night,
got another huge wound,
kotex pads all in there.
He's lying there
like a pasha in a bad motel.
That's when it all got crazy.
He took a bottle of the Wild Turkey
and I heard the snap of the Turkey.
He drank half that thing down
and he said "Siddown".
I said "We've got a great script"
"I want you to read it."
He said "You read it."
I said "Well, I have read it.
"I really love it.
I think it's great."
He said
"No, I want you to read it to me."
I just didn't want
to read the script.
It was crazy, the idea of me
reading the script to him.
But he was dead serious
and I saw this gun.
He put it right to my head.
I thought he means this.
This is really real stuff.
My performance
on reading that script
was the best I've ever given.
I probably should've gotten
an Academy Award.
Ladies and gentlemen,
you have no idea
how good it makes me feel
to be here today.
It is truly an honour
to risk my life for you,
an honour.
Before I jump my motorcycle
over these 19 cars
and I want you to note
there is not a Volkswagen
or a Datsun in the row.
Evel was not happy with it,
I don't believe.
From what I understand
talking to him
I don't believe he was at all happy
with George Hamilton in that.
I don't think Evel appreciated me
climbing into his leathers
and getting on his motorcycle.
But what happened is,
by osmosis,
when he went to see it
in the theatre,
when he came out
he was saying these things.
They were extraordinary words
coming out of his mouth
that John had written for him.
They told the Wright Brothers
to fly was impossible
and they probably
told Neil Armstrong
to walk on the moon was impossible.
They said that Shephard and Glenn
would never get around the world.
They said that Armstrong
wouldn't step on the moon.
He was using a writer's words.
This is the Evel he's become.
I'm all alone
when I jump those ramps.
There's only two things that
keep the rest of them from doing it,
that's fear and
the big hole in the middle.
As long as I can stand alone
and be the best at what I am doing
I am going to continue to do it.
He created a character
named Evel Knievel
and then he tried to live the part.
He never broke character.
He had the Evel Knievel persona.
That's what he presented
to the world.
We don't want guys in Grey hats.
We want black and white.
Evel represented that.
He definitely thought of himself
as the guy in the white hat -
the good guy.
If I look like I'm rigging up for a
trip to outer space, you are right.
Nobody should ever ride a motorcycle
without a helmet.
I never do.
He was...
somebody who was seeking
what many of us do in our own way,
that's recognition.
If you get into his background
you can understand that.
He wanted identity,
he needed that.
He just wanted to be loved.
♪ I wonder how you're feeling.
♪ There's ringing in my ears. ♪
Thank you very much.
It is a pleasure to be back here
in Portland, Oregon.
On behalf of my sponsors,
the Mack Truck Company,
the Harley Davidson Motor Company
and the Bucyrus-Erie Crane and
Steam Shovel Company in Milwaukee...
My dad...
he invented the licensing business.
How many people can you think of
that had their names on products
before Evel?
There was a few.
But he really elevated the art
of the licensing business.
He had to deal with everyone,
Mac Truck,
Harley Davidson...
But that's not the one I remember.
TV: This is Evel Knievel
and his stunt cycle.
He's the only rider to do so many
stunts... Mid-air somersaults!
Evel Knievel has become a legend
in his own lifetime.
When Ideal came out
with the Evel Knievel toy
the president of Ideal
called me aside and said
"This is going
to be a really big item for us."
TV: It's the Evel Knievel rally.
For me, there was only one
action figure when I was growing up
and that was Evel Knievel.
It was as cool as you
could possibly get at the time.
It came with the motorcycle
you could wind up.
You wind it up and stop...
and it takes off
You wind it up
and keep building this suspense.
You don't know
what is going to happen
but you know its gonna blow up
and it's not going to be pretty.
But you're lucky that this toy is
Evel Knievel because he can take it.
That's awesome!
Wow... Go Evel!
TV: The Evel Knievel stunt cycle
comes with figure, winder,
GT wheelie stand and front flip bar.
New from Ideal.
The toy sold out.
I would say
he made more money off of Ideal Toy
than he did off any of his jumps.
I was with him one time,
he showed me two royalty cheques.
Both of them were for at that time
half a million dollars each.
Both of them! Two cheques!
I told him "Well, you made it.
You're on the pinnacle.
"You said
you were gonna be a millionaire.
"You are a millionaire."
It was an amazing time.
The money was rolling in
by the millions.
Everywhere he went
he went first class.
Yeah, my dad liked to spend money.
All of a sudden,
there's five Ferraris,
two Learjets, five other airplanes.
He'd get a boat.
He'd need a bigger boat.
How about a yacht?
How about another yacht.
With helicopters on top. (Laughs)
He had Evel Eye I
painted on the side of it.
He's no easy rider.
He's proud of the material things
his money can buy.
His Cadillacs,
his 140,000-dollar
luxury-appointed van...
He took me into his office
and opened up a huge safe.
And there was a gold plated
full-sized motorcycle!
But you know what?
You could hardly see it
because it was covered in cash
like it had been thrown in there
like confetti.
He built a big beautiful home
on the 18th green
with this huge iron gate
with a great big E K
right in the middle of it,
it was the actual handle.
For Butte, Montana,
that was the stuff.
If I'm risking my life for it
I'm gonna spend
every damn dime of it!
Yeah, my dad had an affinity
for clothes.
He liked to dress with flair.
When he would walk into a store
and see a sweater that he liked
he would buy one in twenty colours.
Come on with me,
I'll take you on a tour
of my office and my dressing room
and show you what you can buy
with a few dollars
if you are willing
to jump a motorcycle over 19 cars.
Evel was very flashy.
He walked with a cane
with diamonds.
His jewellery had diamonds
and he had gold all over.
He always loved Elvis.
They traded the belt buckle
and the key.
My dad was a big fan of Liberace
for being a showman.
All the money in the world
can't buy your way into heaven.
It can't buy your way out of hell.
It was made to be spent right here.
I'm gonna have the best clothes,
best boots, best diamonds,
best cars, trucks, motorcycles,
booze and women
on the face of this earth
just as long as I can keep going.
When he came into money
and fame and fortune
it's like women became almost
an equal part of his thrust
from day to day.
Part of it was that women were
extraordinarily attracted to him.
I know because
he and I would go out drinking
and, hell, they'd line up.
He'd pick the prettiest one.
He's unbelievable.
He's got more fire in him.
He'd turn the hat trick
half the time
because I'd see him do three a night
for a week while I was there.
Hang on.
Come on, back in the seventies
every woman
wanted somebody like that.
I was always mad
because he was maybe cheating
on my mom.
♪ I'm the other woman...
Linda was Aces. Aces.
She was the nicest woman
that he could've ever married.
She stood by him and a lot of times
he didn't treat her right.
Hey, good looking.
You going swimming again?
He didn't hide anything.
That's probably
where I get a little upset with him.
He'd come home with
a little lipstick on his collar.
I'd get a little ticked off.
I'd like to take you out
to dinner somewhere
in a real nice quiet little spot,
get you swacked
and take you home some place.
(Laughter)
I think
"I married this guy!"
I don't know, I just... (Sighs)
You just don't leave that man
unless he wants you to. (Laughs)
Let's say I died
and landed in heaven.
I'm there, okay?
I'm sitting there in a white robe
on a hard marble slab
next to JFK, Martin Luther King
and some poet,
what the hell would Evel Knievel have
to say to any of those guys?
I couldn't carry on an intelligent
conversation with them.
I want to go
to my own kind of heaven...
It's got draft beer
that doesn't make you fat,
it's got a lot of beautiful girls
like you running around
and my wife won't get mad
if I go out with them.
He was okay before
he became Evel Knievel and then...
People just can't handle that fame.
Some of them.
He's... a small town guy
from a small town.
And he, in...
really in the span of seven years
became one of the most famous
people in the world.
I think that he...
he forgot how to be Bob.
When he became Evel
it's like the world
took him away from us.
If you want to be in this business,
be the best in the world
and wear a red, white and blue
Number One on your back
you have to be man enough
to handle the consequences.
ANNOUNCER: King of the daredevil,
number one,
Evel Knievel!
Evel was on top of the world
but he was starting
to lose his grip a little.
That thing with the Hell's Angels
didn't help.
Evel was at odds
against the Hell's Angels
and the biker image.
He used to talk
about the Hell's Angels a lot,
always putting them down.
They're murderers, thieves,
or drug dealers...
I mean these guys are dogs.
They belong in penitentiaries.
He must of got through to them.
They got pissed off.
San Francisco was one
of their main areas.
The announcer was the guy
that started the whole thing
when he introduced Knievel
he said
"If Knievel makes this jump tonight
"he's going to set the Hell's Angels
back 100 years."
Wrong thing to say.
He barely made that jump,
came back around,
and I noticed...
a couple of Hell's Angels
have come out onto the floor.
This Hell's Angel grabbed him -
well, I'm... I'm hoofing it.
The Hell's Angel threw him down.
Just when I got there.
I give this guy a body check
and he folded like...
just went out.
Well, then the war started.
Hell's Angels come
bowling over there.
The people come out of the stands
and started beating on them.
They put two of those Hell's Angels
in the hospital.
After the Cow Palace incident
Evel got a little bit paranoid.
He said "Do you have a gun?"
I said
"Yeah, I got a couple of them."
He says "Those Hell's Angels,
you didn't know,
they're gonna walk in here
with a shotgun."
And he says
"I got to be ready for them."
The man had crashed numerous times.
Of course, it's gonna add up
mentally and emotionally
in your head.
It has to.
ANNOUNCER:
Watch that right shoulder.
Broken right there,
the right collar bone.
INTERVIEWER: Are you afraid?
If I am,
I'm not gonna tell you about it.
Why?
I've been concerned.
I'm Evel Knievel, honey.
I'm not supposed to be afraid.
He was constantly being tormented
with the thought of...
You're not gonna make this one.
You're gonna die at this one.
So he is doing everything he can
through alcohol,
through being flamboyant,
through being... crude or whatever
to get these thoughts
out of his head.
But they were eating his lunch.
Evel, you're shaking a little bit.
Well, if you did what I did
you'd be shaking, too.
I could see it in his eyes
sometimes when he'd come back by to
ask me if he was going fast enough.
I could see the fear in his eyes.
I knew he was scared, but...
he would never say no.
He'd go ahead and do it.
The medicine that he was taking,
the drugs he was taking
for his pain
plus he was drinking
he became just schizo...
I mean, paranoid.
He got paranoid
about protecting his stuff,
paranoid about who he let in.
We'd be talking and
almost as if he was schizophrenic
he'd flip and become ugly
about things.
I had to stand two guys down,
who wanted a piece of him.
They wanted a piece of him
because he was being an asshole,
he was being a jerk.
I'm the guy who's just
trying to keep the peace.
I'm the guy protecting
the troublemaker from the good guys.
You know,
and I thought I can't do this.
It's really interesting
when you are a man like Evel Knievel
and you've created this myth.
Once you're defined
it's hard to live up to it.
He was always reselling
what he had already sold.
How do you get any better than that?
How do you get any bigger?
Throughout his life
he was insatiable.
Even when he was the most famous
daredevil that ever lived
he wasn't satisfied.
He had to make another
half a million dollars on a jump.
He had to find one more woman
prettier than the last.
He couldn't satisfy himself.
He had to do something else.
He had a friend
and they were at the bar, talking.
This fella just made a comment
"What's your next thing?"
I think he said
"The Grand Canyon?"
Of course
that started wheels turning.
One of the favourite pictures
of my dad
is he is on the rim
of the Grand Canyon.
There's these two
Navajo Chiefs there.
My dad is pointing at the other side
of the Grand Canyon
and they're just looking at him
like this man is crazy.
My dream was
to jump the Grand Canyon.
The Secretary of Interior
told me that I could.
I took his word for it.
Then he changed his mind.
So I told him to go get hosed
and I bought my own canyon,
Snake River Canyon,
State of Idaho.
The only way
they will get me out of the air
is to shoot me out
with an anti-aircraft gun
because I am gonna go.
Believe me.
The jump across the canyon
will be approximately a mile.
It's somewhere between 1000
and 1500 feet to the bottom.
As you can see, Pete,
this motorcycle
is unlike any motorcycle
you've ever seen in this world.
These rockets put out
about 90 pounds of thrust apiece.
Knievel's original concept
was to take a motorcycle,
put a rocket on it.
And that's impossible.
The necessity required
that he make a rocket vehicle.
Our partner was Bob Treaux.
He was known
as the father of steam rocketry.
That was our answer for getting
Evel Knievel over the canyon.
Basically, building a hot water tank
and uncorking it and let it go.
This machine is powered by steam.
Steam is the most reliable source
of power we have in the world.
It'll go from zero
to 350 miles per hour
from a dead stop
in eight seconds flat.
This super stunt
billed as the death defying
event of the century
will be viewed
by almost two million people
most of them watching
on closed circuit movie screens.
I'd like to say to you
what Evel Knievel says
wherever he goes, whatever he signs.
If he were talking to you right now
he'd say
"Hey Jim, happy landings."
When there was an event
of any magnitude during that period
I'd probably get the first call
to do the promotion.
I remember the first time
I saw Evel Knievel
he showed up on Ventura Boulevard
doing wheelies on his motorcycle.
That's when I first met him.
But I really didn't know him until
we did the Snake River Canyon Jump.
I had control
of the publicity and promotion.
For a brief moment
of our dull mundane life
here is a man
who vicariously we can live through.
I thought
what he was doing was exciting.
It's never hard
to sell something you believe in.
And I believed in it.
We did a 30-day tour,
which was my idea,
to do press conferences
at, like literally, 90 airports.
ANNOUNCER: When Knievel flies
into town each day
on his two Learjets
his pilot Whacha Macallum
and his co-pilot
wear crimson crushed velvet
dinner jackets.
You ought to see our socks
and underwear.
Every day was a... party.
There were close to 2500
press credentials given out.
It was bigger than any Ali fight.
And I did them all.
Bigger
than a presidential entourage.
Don E Branco was in charge
of all the logistics.
I was a concert promoter.
I did acts like The Stones,
The Doors, The Who...
Then Evel comes along
with a pay per view closed circuit -
this was the biggest event
of its kind
in the history of entertainment.
The unknowns were magnificent.
This Sunday a daredevil hustler
named Evel Knievel
will try to cross a canyon
in Idaho riding a rocket.
If he makes it
he will be many times a millionaire.
If he doesn't, he'll be dead.
He was a hero of mine
in many ways.
I was a little crazy.
He was a whole lot crazy.
You just had to dig his courage.
It just didn't seem to me
that courage would be enough.
(Laughs) Chucky...
It looks a lot further
than I thought a mile would look.
It was the kind of stunt
where you would actually see
probably a man kill himself.
It was so audacious.
It was so daring.
It was so almost impossible
in many ways
but for his confidence.
What about the G-forces?
When you start something that is
going to be going 350 miles per hour
aren't you gonna be knocked out?
Yes, but I'll wake up,
see the other side of the ground
way over there
or wherever the hell I'm at
and I'll pull a rip cord
and open a parachute
beyond that sky sight.
You're going to be unconscious
while you're up in the air?
To 2000 feet,
I probably will be, yes.
You have to regain
your consciousness.
That's right but I can do that.
I'll do it.
Evel had no training.
He had no training
for pulling Gs like a centrifuge
or even in an airplane.
Zero parachute experience.
He had a dead-stick kind of thing
that was spring loaded.
If he passed out
and let go of the handle
the parachute would come out.
Go!
NEWSREADER: There were three of
the steam-powered skycycles built.
The original called the X1
was tested without a pilot
about three weeks ago.
It ended up
at the bottom of the canyon.
That was a test shot.
We made some mistakes.
If I'd been in it
I'd've ended up dead.
But I don't think
that's going to happen.
What the press did not know
was that the first one
was designed to fail.
We purposely
underpowered the rocket
so it wouldn't make it
to the other side.
He wanted it as a promotional thing.
He wanted it to crash in the water
and let people see that.
Eventually we did convince Evel
to do a real test.
But he'd only do it
if it was done in secret.
So the press wouldn't get
any pictures of it or anything.
We thought it would make it.
But there was a problem
with the parachute.
It deployed early.
It also landed right
in the middle of the river.
Knievel was there to see that.
I saw it.
I was wondering at that time
what was going through his mind.
I was thinking to myself
that he maybe was looking
at his mortality
and thinking...
this may not be such a good idea.
However, give him credit,
he was going through with it.
At this point
we're batting zero for two.
And the world is watching us.
I mean, I felt that.
CROWD: You'll make it!
You will!
He became more and more surly.
Screeching orders at everybody
that he could.
He belittled little people.
He was just mean.
About a week out
is when we started sensing things
not going our way with the press
because the press
is up here living now.
The press started
seeing the real Evel.
Do one thing.
For me.
I do not ask for your respect.
I demand it.
Shelly gathered everybody
around Evel's trailer.
And said "Why don't you have him
stand up so we can see him?"
Because there was a big crowd
of people there.
Evel heard that
and came out and...
I said "Have a smile on your face."
I don't smile at anybody.
Alright, get him out.
Get him out! Out!
Go on get out of here!
That's when he came down the stairs
with his cane.
He grabbed my camera.
He's a pretty strong guy.
Grabbed my camera
and started pushing me back
and whacking me and the camera
with his cane.
Are you going to apologize to
that cameraman for roughing him up?
I wouldn't apologize.
And if I see the son of a bitch again
I'll throw him out of here.
How's that?
As hard as we tried
a lot of Evel's true temperament
came out to the press.
I think you should apologize.
I want to straighten you out.
Number one,
I was in the skycycle all day.
Number two, you were a guest
in my press area.
Understand that?
And so was he.
Number three,
when I've been up there all day
and the blood's come out of my legs
and my feet and gone to my head
and I come down
and want to get some rest
and get along with you people
You don't tell me
to come out and stand up and smile.
If I want to come out
and try and get along with you
you should at least allow me
to sit down and smile.
So tell him
I said to kiss my ass!
There was a point where we were
all sitting around and saying
"This guy's a jerk.
He's just a jerk!
"He's a bully,
he's a bore...
"What are we doing here?"
The rest of the press can now
thank you because I'm going to leave.
How's that, boys?
People started coming in
and it started getting crazy.
Every biker in the United States
that didn't have a job was there.
You'd have umpteen
different motorcycling groups,
none of which you'd invite
to your house for dinner.
They're having a good time.
Everyone gets loose around here.
You could say
it was like a Woodstock
but the evil twin of Woodstock.
It was like, not a happy... flower
children sitting around in the rain.
Those guys were...
they were really rough.
Wackos with tattoos
all over their bodies
drinking beer
and screwing in public
and all kinds of...
It was bedlam.
Roach clips! Reefers!
Hash pipes!
Come get them while they're hot!
They had a marching band from
Butte High School that was there.
It was...
not a place for a B High
marching band to be that day.
I'd have to say.
Right when we pulled in
there was a man and woman naked
having sex right there
under a tree.
I saw all the people
that were drinking,
smoking pot and...
They were pretty wild.
BAND MUSIC
We fired up the band.
It's like the whole place arose.
Oh they... the crowd went wild.
Yeah, absolutely.
They were totally prepared
for a celebration.
The crowd just started mingling
and wanted to play our instruments.
They tugged and pulled.
Next thing we know
we're separated
a good 100 yards away
from the rest of the band.
So we were basically
fighting for our lives
as far as I was concerned.
At that point, they just
stuffed my tuba full of everything,
beer bottles, popcorn,
peanuts, rocks...
I pulled a bra out of there...
I never played a note.
We also had with us
the drill team.
The drill team,
their name was the Purple Bees.
A good friend of mine,
they tore her dress right off.
They totally tore her dress off.
I guess we all thought of this
as something different
than it was really gonna be.
The crowd were given beer.
When the beer was closed up,
that's when it got kind of rowdy.
They actually rolled
the beer trucks over,
the semis over on their side,
shot the locks off
and everyone was walking through
the camps with cases of beer.
Next thing you know
they took the outhouses.
They took them down,
started dumping them over
and they lit them on fire.
The place was absolutely
out of control at that point.
Things got as bad as it could
get bad without somebody dying.
That's as simple as that.
Just as bad as it could be.
I can hear out in the darkness...
I can hear the girls being raped.
I can hear fights going on.
I can hear gunshots going off.
There was nothing I could do.
Finally, I reach the point
where I said "I'm gonna
call the National Guard in."
I called them up
and he says "Don, I'm sorry.
"Our men are split up. I can't
come out there and help you.
"You're on your own, son."
I hung up that phone
and I felt like crying.
ANNOUNCER: There were more
than 33,000 paid admissions.
As you can see
they needed control.
They were perilously close
to the edge of the canyon,
some 600 feet straight down.
What I was concerned about is
that there was this canyon.
This killer canyon in front of you
and they put up
a standard cyclone fence.
I mean, You'd just push it
and it'd fall over.
I thought to myself
"Everybody's gonna rush
to that edge of the canyon
"to see what happens."
You're gonna have people
pushing from behind.
Like the lemmings in the sea
they're gonna go
right over the edge.
(Laughs) I thought
it was pretty ironic
that Donny solved
the security problem.
He went down to where
the Hell's Angels were camped
and hired them to come up
and provide security for us.
I went there
and explained what I'll do.
"I've got 1000 dollars in cash.
"I want you to guard the fence
"and keep people
on that side of the fence."
The guys said
"Are you bull-shitting me?"
I said "Am I gonna bull-shit
with you guys here?"
"Okay, you got a deal, mister."
(Laughs)
"OH SAY CAN YOU SEE" PLAYS
On the morning of the jump
I looked at him
and I saw a very pensive,
very reflective, very quiet man.
He didn't look comfortable.
I don't know
why he would look comfortable
climbing into a tin can
to fly over a canyon.
ANNOUNCER: There is Bob Treaux
himself, the chief engineer,
testing the wind.
The 50-mile-an-hour wind
was not the right direction.
We recommended to Knievel
that he delay the launch.
I says "Bob, I don't think
you ought to do it."
I think this is crazy.
I think this thing
isn't gonna make it.
He says "I can't back out now.
Too much has been said.
"They'd call me a coward"
he says. "I'm not gonna do that.
"I'm going and that's it."
I've got a team behind me
with Mr. Treuax.
And all the boys
that are 100 percent and...
I think we'll do it.
I wish
the wind wasn't blowing so hard
but I think we'll do it.
There was no braggadocio.
There was no bravado.
As the time counted off
he said to his family
"Lets pray."
Yeah, I remember when my dad
brought me in the trailer
and the truck...
(Sniffs)
The whole family...
and he hugged me
and says "I love you."
He didn't know
what was gonna happen.
He was like "God, take care of me."
Linda and the children
were crying.
Specially, the little girl.
Yeah, that was
a very sobering moment.
Suddenly, I realized...
"Have I had a hand
in getting a man killed?"
ANNOUNCER: There he goes up the ramp
towards the launch site
and towards the vehicle.
He's being introduced
to the crowd now.
I've never been afraid in my life
of dying.
I think a man was put on this earth
to live.
Not just to exist.
Today is the proudest day
of my life.
I'm living a dream
they thought could never be done
but it'll be done.
WHISTLES AND CLAPPING
And then...
instead of a roar
a silence, an eerie silence
fell over the crowd
because this guy truly
might be going to his death.
HEROIC MUSIC
Evel got out of the crane
and into the skycycle.
The whole time
patriotic music is being played
and at that time
even I got emotional a bit.
Fecundo and I strapped him in,
and got a couple of pictures
of him in the cockpit.
He looked a lot different than
he did when we started this project.
His hair was Grey
and he was real serious.
We had a big clock.
Ten seconds...
nine seconds...
eight, seven...
you look at the audience,
no one is even breathing.
Five...
four...
ANNOUNCER: Three, two, one...
Immediately, something failed.
It fizzled.
It went down like a bullet.
ANNOUNCER: There's fire.
The main shute's out.
There she goes.
It's going to crash.
Just missed the rocks,
thank god!
David, I can't see anything.
I had my camera.
I was taking click click click...
Chhhhhh...
right into the canyon.
I turn around and the first fence
just goes flat, shwoop!
It was a stampede.
That's exactly what it was.
I saw bikers pluck people
out of the sky.
It was right out of a movie.
ANNOUNCER: Robert Craig Knievel
has appeared
to have landed in the Snake River.
Evel definitely tried to get out
but he couldn't.
David, I am very scared.
I thought he was gone.
"They're not gonna get to him
in time. He's gonna drown."
There was people running up
looking over the edge.
Linda was scared
and the boys were scared.
I thought my dad was dead.
I was screaming, crying.
I got into my helicopter,
got over the canyon,
and there...
from the muddy banks
on the side of the river...
was Evel waving.
I said this:
"Thank god,
that son of a bitch is alive."
ANNOUNCER: Evel Knievel
is standing in the boat and waving.
He is alive and well.
I know the well-wishers
are anxious...
Walking towards that helicopter...
He's on the ground now
and he's being mobbed by the crowd.
What happened, Evel?
I don't know what happened.
It's just... I think...
Evel?
I don't know.
I just can't say.
I'll have to let Bob
and the fellas examine it.
Bob, what happened?
Well, this right here is the cover
to the parachute canister.
It obviously came loose
much too soon right on the pad.
What happened was that...
it went up and I knew immediately
the chute had been deployed.
It came off because of a mechanical
problem with the design.
You didn't do a damn thing.
The can is still on the thing.
It blew up right there
on the launch.
Blew up by accident?
Yeah, it was our fault.
That's what has been determined?
Its not your fault.
It's the canister's fault.
We should have run one more test.
It was clear to me, or to us
that it was a mechanical failure.
But there was another story
being banded about
back at the press tent
that perhaps, Evel had released
the chute early.
I told people
that that's what happened.
When I went to the press tent
after the jump
the press was asking for me
to make a statement.
I told the press
that his hand came off of the bar.
I really liked the rocket crew.
They were a bunch of nice guys.
I knew that the MO...
of how he treated people.
Nothing was ever his fault.
I told people
that that's what happened.
If by chance that took a little bit
of pressure off of the rocket team
so be it.
So it got out
that it was Evel's fault.
But the nagging question remains...
Was this the legitimate attempt
of a brave man
or was it
the great rip-off of 1974?
Then, the press tore him up.
Cause they think
that he, along with me,
had perpetrated a fraud.
Hero or hustler?
Or for Americans,
are those the same thing?
It was Evel Knievel
against the Snake River Canyon
and the canyon
was the sentimental favourite.
Evel would have liked his jump
to be huge front page news.
But it was overwhelmingly squashed
by the big news of the day,
which was the pardon of Nixon
by President Ford.
That was a major transition
in the country.
Maybe...
maybe he had outlived his novelty
because I think people might of
gotten tired of listening to it.
And that's when
he came back to Butte.
He was... I don't know
if he was depressed or what.
(Sighs) He just...
I thought sure
he's just give up after that
and say "Well, I'm done."
MUSIC AND WHISTLING
♪ England swings
like a pendulum do... ♪
He had never been to England before.
He thought
"A new crowd, a new group,
"I can snow them a little more
than I can the Americans.
Yeah, they hadn't heard
the Teddy Roosevelt speech...
"Be good to your parents,
wear a helmet..."
ANNOUNCER: Evel Knievel is alive,
well, and back in action
in the famed old Wembley Stadium
in London, England
for a jump that will be made
over thirteen London buses.
When he arrived in London
he had only sold 3,000 seats
for a 100,000 seat stadium
and he was in trouble.
There was some press there
to meet him.
He looks at the press
and what did he do?
"I'm so glad to be here in England
"where we came
and won the war for you."
("English" accent) Oh?
And they start writing.
He knew his job, which was
to get people in Wembley Stadium.
We drove around London
just making friends.
How you doing? What's your name?
Stephen...
ANNOUNCER: So the Yankee pied piper
collected the young and the old
and led them all
to Wembley Stadium.
80,000 people showed up
to watch the man do it.
So we walked
into the arena of Wembley,
where the buses were lined up.
He said "I can't do that."
"What do you mean,
you can't do that?"
I said
"Pull a few buses out of there.
"Come on.
It won't hurt a thing to do that."
I go over and grab our producer.
I said
"Doug, Evel says he can't do that."
He really didn't think
he was going to make it.
I went over to talk to Evel,
talk him out of it.
He was in a trailer
and I knocked on the door.
He said "Ah no, I'll give it a go.
I'll give it a go."
He's always
"I'll give it a go."
He was right.
He couldn't make it.
ANNOUNCER: Here's Evel Knievel!
Evel, one has to wonder
after Snake River
one has to wonder why you continue?
Well...
I... sometimes think
that maybe I should quit
but you always want
to keep going and...
I'm proud of that red, white and blue
Number One I wear on my shoulder.
I want to keep it on.
I'm glad you're here today.
I've never had an accident
while you're around.
Good luck.
Thank you, Frank.
Well, he told me earlier
outside of the jump at Caesar's
Palace where he was severely injured
this will probably be the most
difficult jump he has ever made.
Hurt himself in Indio in 1967,
Caesar's Palace...
Will he go?
And he will go.
SOUND SLOWS DOWN
It was almost eerie though.
The motorcycle was ghostly.
It was tumbling after him.
Then, eventually, it landed on him.
He's down and he is hurt.
Oh my god!
The man you see leaning over him
that is John Hood,
his chief mechanic.
I knew
he's got to be hurt on this one.
I kneeled down
and said "Are you okay?"
I got his helmet off
and he said "Help me up."
And he wanted the microphone.
I want to stand up.
Help me up.
He wants to talk.
He's gonna talk.
Ladies and gentlemen...
of this wonderful country...
I've got to tell you
that you are the last people
in the world
who will ever see me jump
because I will never, ever,
ever jump again. I'm through.
That crash was one of the worst
as far as injuries would go.
He broke his hand, back...
re-broke his pelvis.
After Wembley, I went home to edit.
Phone rang.
"Hello Doug, Evel..."
He's calling me
from his hospital room in London.
"Doug, you can't use that quote."
"What do you mean, Evel?"
"You can't use that quote.
"Where I said
I wouldn't jump again."
I said "Oh, why?"
"Because I may jump again!"
When the jump was over
in London
I said
that I would never jump again.
That was the pain in my body
overpowering the brains
I'm supposed to have in my head.
I will jump again.
But 13 is an unlucky number.
This time
I'm gonna jump 14 buses.
Somehow he gets the idea
"I'm not gonna go out with a crash.
"I'm gonna go back
to the United States
"and I'm gonna jump 14 buses."
That's just who he was.
You can't do it, say you're the best
in the world and fall off
and get up and say
"I quit."
Not if you're an Evel Knievel,
you can't.
TV: The Kings Island Family
entertainment centre
located just outside
of Cincinnati, Ohio,
is jam-packed with people,
who have come to watch Evel Knievel
out of retirement.
Here he comes right now.
Robert Craig Knievel.
A lot was riding on this jump.
It was a different Evel.
I mean
he actually did practice jumps.
I'm gonna go, Frank.
There's no wind gonna stop me,
not even a hurricane.
It was a very gutsy jump.
The doctors told him
"Don't ever do that again."
One little slip, wrong thing
and he'd probably be paralysed.
ANNOUNCER: Total concentration now...
getting the bike off the approach
ramp and onto the landing ramp...
...and he's not hesitating,
he'll go...
Busted the motorcycle
right in half, Frank.
Boy, it did come apart,
didn't it?
It wasn't an idea of mine.
I know.
Thank you.
This motorcycle
is the finest machine in the world
as far as I am concerned.
It broke in half
but it held me up.
All I can say is
thanks to Number One,
thanks to Harley Davidson
you've been so good to me
through the years.
I would like to tell all of you
something though.
As far as I am concerned
I have jumped far enough.
Today I am going to walk away
from here with you.
I feel like being a professional,
that's what I'm gonna do.
Kings Island was the longest jump
of his career.
It was the biggest television
audience he ever had.
It was the highest rated episode
of Wide World of Sports ever.
He did some small jumps after that
but he never went that big again.
Kings Island was...
the gunfighter
putting away his pistols.
If you're on a bike
you'd do stupid shit.
But you'd do stupid shit
in the name of Evel Knievel.
I thought that's why you had a bike.
I didn't know
you just rode bikes around.
I thought
the whole purpose of bikes
were to hit things
and fly off of them.
We'd line up the neighbour kids
and see who could jump
more neighbours
without landing on them
and things like that.
But we just dreamed
of having a motor between our legs.
I loved just going down steps.
I crashed all the time.
Like, yeah, you're gonna be like
Evel Knievel, but not as good.
There's no way that a youngster
is not going to want
to try to do what his hero does.
I don't think
there is anything wrong
with a kid
wanting to be an Evel Knievel
any more than
wanting to be an OJ Simpson
or Frank Gifford,
any kind of a professional athlete.
Do you view him as a hero?
Yeah.
Yeah, he's one
of the greatest heroes.
He was a hero to so many kids.
But his own son was his biggest fan.
This is Robbie.
Look at the little guy go.
Wouldn't you know it would be
the young one that would steal it.
He's the one that has got
to have the longest wheelie.
He totally saw me in him.
It was like,
I'm gonna be you, Dad.
And the legend continues.
I'm gonna jump the fountains
at Caesar's Palace
before I end my career.
That was for you, Dad.
Yeah, Robbie broke
all of his dad's records.
Hell, he could jump 14 buses
with no hands!
But Robbie was jumping
on lighter more powerful bikes
that were designed for jumping.
He could jump
farther and longer than Evel.
But it didn't matter.
Robbie couldn't tell a story.
He was...
he was not a showman.
Knievel was the ultimate showman.
A guy could sing longer and louder
than Elvis Presley.
But who gave a damn?
He was Elvis Presley.
My dad was Evel Knievel.
AUDIENCE LAUGHTER, APPLAUSE
Even when
Bobbie wasn't jumping anymore
he still wanted
to be in the spotlight.
He had to find other things to do
to get himself attention.
One of his projects was Hollywood.
♪ Viva, viva, Knievel...
In the end, there was one guy
that was meant to be Evel Knievel.
And that was Evel.
Evel had a movie star quality
about him.
There's no doubt about it.
Not when he tried to act.
Look at you.
You're trying to destroy yourself.
If you don't believe me
here's the proof.
I'm not gonna let
you commit suicide around me.
He performed for the audience.
But when it came
to the acting part
I guess there's a difference.
That was too far!
Stop it!
Alright...
Any way you want it, man!
Stop it!
Once it came out, yeah
it was a movie
that wasn't really well received.
♪ Viva...
I guess the exciting part
is the jump, huh.
We've got the Melindas
on the high wire
and the medallists on the edge
of the canyon on a motorcycle...
When I knew I was gonna take
on the Snake River Canyon event
I decided something
very important...
that I would write a book.
In legacy,
that people could read
about the Evel Knievel promotion
of the Snake River Canyon.
Knievel was my fifty-fifty partner
and he says
"Don't forget, just tell the truth."
So with permission
I carried an audio cassette recorder
during the Evel Knievel tour.
If you listen to the tape
you can form your own opinion.
And so when I wrote my book
I kept out a lot of things,
stuff that I would never
write about
cause, remember,
when the book was coming out
I was still protecting his image.
Evel's attorney,
he checked everything.
Told me
that it had Evel's approval
in writing.
Then the book was published.
I was at Evel's compound one day.
He throws me this book.
He says "Here keep this.
It'll be worth some money someday."
I open it up.
Here's all his footnotes in there.
The first part of the book,
X-rated Evel.
He writes in there
"Constitutes adultery."
Right from the get go
you could tell he was mad.
It just starts and you can tell
that the farther it gets in the book
the madder he got.
"This is a lie and not accurate.
"Lies... lies... lies."
I read the book
and said
"Yeah...
what's the problem?"
"He could've said
a lot more worse stuff."
I read the book a couple times.
I didn't see anything in it bad.
Nothing.
It was very factual.
Very, very, very factual.
I think that Shelly, who wrote it,
was accurate.
And...
it made him really mad.
I was on the 20th Century Fox lot.
All of a sudden
I saw Evel
with a big smile
coming at me loping along.
I was actually glad to see him.
The book was out.
I was like maybe I can even talk him
into doing some promotion with me.
I said "Hey, Evel."
And all of a sudden, my hands...
they were held behind my back.
They tell me it was two men.
It may have been one.
It may have been two.
And he...
He came at me
with a bat...
an aluminium baseball bat.
He said "I'm gonna kill you,
you son of a bitch."
I did everything I could
to defend myself.
I remember putting my hand up
and said "What are you doing?
What are you doing?"
I was fighting for my life.
He was whaling on me
and then I passed out.
NEWS: Knievel came to court
accompanied by his wife Linda
and his attorney.
The 38-year-old daredevil
faces charges of felony assault
in the baseball bat attack
on television executive
Sheldon Saltman.
Knievel could
have gotten away with it.
He could've if he'd just stopped
being Knievel for ten minutes.
It was a very interesting hour
at Division 91 on Municipal Court,
in which Evel Knievel
fired his attorney
and entered a plea of guilty.
He fires them
and says to the judge
"Judge, I did it
and I'd do it again.
"Do what you will with me."
You know,
this old frontier justice thing.
In Butte, Montana,
you settle things out
in the street.
You don't settle them
with lawyers.
Evel always settled it
with his fists
or sometimes a tool helped.
Not with a baseball bat.
That's not Butte.
I never knew of anybody in Butte
that did that.
If I did not think there was
a much stronger judge someday
that I will stand before called God
than the judge I stood before
in that courtroom
in Santa Monica, California
I would have killed
that lousy little bastard.
I broke his arms with a baseball bat,
which is what I think he deserved.
I'll guarantee you one thing,
he doesn't write
anything else about me.
AUDIENCE LAUGH
But I'm...
I think I was a sophomore
in high school at the time.
I was not proud of my dad
for doing that...
at all.
Stuntman Evel Knievel
got a jail sentence yesterday
for beating his former press agent
with a baseball bat.
NEWS: The judge told
the 39-year-old motorcycle daredevil
that while, as a judge,
he found Knievel's admission
of guilt as refreshing
at the same time,
Rafiti said,
long ago we abandoned
frontier justice in California.
With that Rafiti sentenced Knievel
to six months in jail
and three years probation.
The judge is a good judge
and he's a fair judge.
Of course
when he was in jail...
it was like,
I think in his own way...
he played it as a game.
So he's in jail
but he's on work release.
So he's only in there at night.
He would have his chauffeur
pick him up every morning
and take him to the bar.
NEWS: Knievel believes
in sharing the wealth.
So this morning
he hired a dozen limousines
to transport his fellow
work-release inmates to their jobs.
Putting him in jail,
he got more press...
than anything else.
There was no end to the shenanigans
that guy would pull.
NEWS: The inmates were amazed.
But the authorities
were not so enthusiastic.
Well, the judge got pissed.
He revoked Evel's
work-release privileges.
I was pissed off at him.
He started believing the hype
that he was totally impervious,
that he could get away
with anything.
I don't think he thought
about the public.
Maybe if he did, he thought
that's what they expect of me.
The Ideal Toy company, which
manufactures the Evel Knievel toys,
says it has already
lost 1.6 million dollars
since Evel Knievel
went into the county jail.
We had a meeting at Ideal
the next day or the day after.
(Sighs) I said, you know...
We don't sell toys of murderers...
or gangsters, or stuff like that.
And, so therefore, we are going to
suspend sales in the United States.
NEWS: On the toy front
it may not be a merry Christmas
for daredevil Evel Knievel.
The contracts were cancelled.
He lost a lot of money.
Yep.
It all started coming apart.
♪ Anymore it doesn't matter...
NEWS: Knievel says his experience
in jail was a good one.
But it has set him back financially.
I hated to see him lose
everything he worked for...
in ten minutes.
When it was falling apart
it fell apart very quickly.
The cars, the boats...
The Learjets, Ferraris, everything
to go down the drain...
That was hard.
The house that we all loved
got repossessed
because my dad didn't pay
the property taxes.
The bank came and got it.
The IRS sold it.
We loaded up all the furniture,
everything of any value,
from the saddles to guns...
We would just bring so much
out at a time.
We'd have a garage sale.
The arc of the skycycle is
like what happened to his career.
He was at the pinnacle.
Then he destroyed
his whole life.
I just dropped out of site
and played golf.
I just completely withdrew
from the public.
When I met him
he was at a bit of a low point...
He was kinda just getting by...
hustling golf...
he might make a couple hundred here,
a couple hundred there.
He lived day to day at that time.
He didn't keep the fact that
he was married a secret or anything.
In two weeks, I packed up
what I wanted to take with me
and we went on the road.
I just let it go at that.
The heck with it, you know.
After 38 years of somebody
telling you what to do.
I didn't like him...
I didn't like him.
♪ Nobody wins.
You could see
that his health was declining.
He was getting worse
all the time.
He had a hip replacement,
a pelvis reconstruction,
a spinal fusion,
a liver transplant...
seven or eight bouts
of staph infection.
I have hepatitis C and I got it
through blood transfusion.
My doctors told me
five years ago
that I didn't have
five years to live.
I'm taking it one day at a time.
I really felt sorry for him.
I did, really.
I said "You're really hurting."
♪ If you're gonna be dumb
you gotta be tough
When you get knocked down
you gotta get back up
I ain't the sharpest knife
in the drawer
But I know enough to know
If you're gonna be dumb
you gotta be tough
Then the 90s come around.
Motorcycle jumping was just one part
of this whole new huge thing
called action sports.
Its amazing how quickly
the sport's progressed.
This multimillion
motorcycle jumping,
skateboard riding, surfing industry
has definitely come a long way
from daredevils to professionals.
In 2006, I was able
to land the first double backflip
on a dirt bike.
No one ever thought
that was possible.
The bikes have evolved.
The riding has evolved.
They have coaches,
schools, camps.
But the spirit will never die.
Evel was the one that
set our foundation for the future.
The thing about the Knievels
that's really captivating
inspiring to all of us
is the showmanship side of it.
I stay awake at night
and I dwell on how to do what I do
in the biggest and grandest way
and continue this legacy.
Fire!
That's deadly! Oooh!
The extreme sports
or action sports,
whatever it's
commercially referred to,
is definitely a result
of the way Evel dreamed in the 70s
and how he wanted
to push the limits.
You can do stunts on television?
Evel had to make his jumps.
The stunts I do
I know they are gonna fail.
Mat Hoffman and I
did a tribute to Evel.
Hello, I'm Johnny Knoxville
and I'm about
to back-flip this bike.
I think we should push the limits,
get some of our friends together,
set some records
and just celebrate Evel's life.
So we did.
Ow!
I broke my dick...
in that tribute.
Oww... oww...
You okay?
Oh, yeah, I feel great.
No really...
I tore my urethra.
Thanks a lot, Evel.
Yeah, I've definitely been compared
to Evel Knievel.
I think
that is because of the fact
that I have had some big crashes.
I figured I'd see how far
I can fly the Harley Davidson
in honour of Evel Knievel.
When Seth Enslow did that
record-breaking Harley Davidson jump
he dedicated it to Evel.
When Robbie Madision set the world
record for distance bike jumping
over an entire football field
he did it on the 40th anniversary
of Evel's Caesar's Palace jump.
Evel Knievel was always
in the back of my mind.
It wasn't like
we had forgotten about him.
We didn't really know
what he was up to.
People started
asking what he was up to.
ANNOUNCER: The one and only OG...
Evel Knievel!
It was great to see a new generation
understand how important
he was to us.
Somehow we raised his profile again
but he deserved that all along.
He greatly appreciated that
the kids paid their respects to him.
They did.
And he was amazed by that.
Don't ever forget,
you can fall many times in life.
But you will never be a failure
as long as you try and get up.
I think
my dad liked his role
as an elder statesman
at the end of his life.
He thought it was really cool.
And where he deserved to be.
Deservedly so.
I'm looking forward to seeing
what happens in the next 20 years
if I'm so lucky to live that long.
I've had to have a hip replacement,
a complete hip replacement.
I had to have a...
Guys, I'm really having problems.
Why don't we...
Please.
After a lifetime
of injuries and surgeries
the thing that really kicked his ass
was lung disease.
If you'd asked him
"Would you rather have lived
this long, Bobby
and been this sick
"or died at the end of the ramp?"
I think he would have chosen
the end of the ramp.
The last couple of years
of his life were hell.
He was having trouble breathing.
Being in that living hell...
he put his life in perspective.
I think he probably thought
a lot about the things he'd done
and thought about how badly
he treated some people.
He was preparing for the end
on every level.
He righted a lot of wrongs
with people
because he felt like
that was important.
It became important to him.
He told me he'd led a life that
he was ashamed of in a lot of ways
and he was just trying to talk to
the people that he truly...
that truly meant something to him
was the way he put it
and he put it right.
He said to me
"I was so sick."
He said "I was just a sick person
with women... so wrong."
I said "Oh Dad,
it's so good to hear you say that."
He tried to make amends with people
at the end and that's great.
But it's kind of tough
to put the toothpaste back
in the tube at that point.
He caused a lot of hurt.
Well, it was the first time
I ever heard him say "I'm sorry."
He was pretty much
on his deathbed... yeah.
He just said "I'm sorry."
That was it.
You know...
the most important thing
in life...
that really counts
is your scorecard with God.
The real Bob Knievel,
the Bobby Knievel,
that's the guy I knew
and that's the guy that I loved.
That's the guy that
was emerging back out of the slime.
And... I was moved by it.
I talked to him
the night before he died.
He said
"You gotta do me a favour"
and I says "Okay, what?"
And he says "Say a prayer for me
once and a while."
I said "Okay, all right."
He says "I'm worse than you think."
I was on the phone with Evel.
He started coughing.
The phone dropped.
He went unconscious.
So that was it.
But it was hard.
I wasn't ready.
But, he was ready.
And that's what was important.
You just never thought
that Evel was gonna die.
You know, he was indestructible
and then...
It just reminded you
that he was human.
I didn't lose the daredevil.
I lost this little kid,
who at one time
I thought was my brother.
That's the indelible Knievel to me.
I still think he's a superhero.
Yeah, I know
a more complete story now.
Some of the stuff
is really hear-breaking.
But to me...
what he did
transcends that.
Most of us
don't take chances in our lives.
Most of us aren't willing
to lay it on the line
like he was.
What my dad did,
nobody is ever gonna do again.
But there is a little Evel
in all of us.
I guess I'd like to have him
remembered as...
a man, who,
when he was down, got back up.
He never quit.
I think in fairness to him
we should not remember
the evil that Evel did.
Instead, he should be remembered
for the good things he did.
In times of stress
I believe that somebody on a white
horse in a white hat will arrive...
that's the American way.
Life's pretty tough.
Life can be pretty fucking tough.
And...
you need your heroes, man.
He used to always say to me
"That canyon
has not moved one inch.
"And I do not see a long line
of daredevils waiting to jump it."
Captions (c) SBS Australia 2016