Previously
on  Queen of the South...
How do you feel about Miami?
What's not to like?
I would like you to run it.
René was like a son to me.
Whoever did this will pay.
Emilia's not here.
But I know where to find her.
I can't be honest with you.
There are things
that you don't know
and I can't see you anymore.
You don't mean this.
I do.
Judge came by my office today.
Teresa, he wants you dead.
I just want you to know.
I'm all in.
Lafayette killed Tony.
I'm so sorry
for your loss, Teresa.
Was it Elias?
No.
It's a local matter
that I'm handling.
Now that South Florida
is secured,
I would like you
to introduce me to your cousin,
Kostya, in New York.
Kostya is a very cautious man.
It's rare that he meets
somebody face to face.
He doesn't trust people
outside his circle.
I understand that.
I do not think you do, Teresa.
If Kostya pays you
a surprise visit...
He's the last person
you will ever see.
Set it up, please.
Yeah.
Respectfully, T. rex,
we just took over Miami.
Boaz's still working out
the kinks.
We're on shaky ground there.
Why move so fast
with the Russians?
Momentum.
If we expand with Kostya
as our partner,
we will be seen as strong.
Have we heard from Javier?
He's tying some loose ends.
It's just a couple
more miles ahead.
You're the only person
she wanted to talk to.
She tried to call you
just before
Randall pulled her
from the truck.
It was Randall who killed her?
Does all the dirty work.
Why did they take Emilia?
My cousin René was murdered.
They thought that
she had something to do with it.
She was a good person.
She had nothing to do with that.
Whatever you wanna do to him...
He deserves.
Did you find my son?
Not yet.
Went by Mendoza's bar.
She's hired herself an army.
No quiet way to get to her
unless we bring 'em all in.
Mendoza's smart enough
to cover her ass.
And we have no idea
what she's got on us.
Let's not poke the bear
until we have to.
And when we do,
we'll keep our hands clean.
Marcel will get the job done.
She won't see him coming.
I did come across something
that might give us an edge
on Mendoza.
Looks like she's got herself
a new business partner.
Woman, two heavies--
never seen her before.
Interesting.
Get acquainted.
Show her some of our
southern charm.
Happy to.
I know you want payback
for your godson's murder,
but I just wanna make sure
that darkness
isn't blinding you.
-Have you changed your mind?
-No.
But once we do this,
there's no going back.
Teresa, we're all in this game.
We all got blood on our hands.
You killed Bobby.
I took Birdie.
You and I got past that.
Maybe you can do the same thing
with the Judge.
He's kept us under his thumb
for too long.
I'm done with that.
Aren't you?
Absolutely.
How you wanna do it?
Lafayette's dirty,
but he's still a judge.
That means he can bring law
enforcement down on our heads,
and I'm not just talking
local law enforcement.
Feds, DEA...
I know.
We can make his death look like
a result of his own crimes.
Show the world
who Lafayette really is--
a corrupt killer.
Once he's exposed,
the cops and politicians
in his pocket
won't risk
investigating his death.
Let's get on with it.
It's a good plan, Teresita.
We catch the Judge
with his pants down.
He'll never see us coming.
He always seems to be
a step ahead of us.
This time, he can't be.
We need to talk about George.
He's angry.
Thinks we let Dumas off the hook
for Birdie's death.
We cannot have any loose cannons
right now.
The hit on the Judge
is dangerous enough.
I know.
I'll talk to him.
Maybe we should ask Boaz
to send some backup from Miami.
No.
Miami's not settled.
Boaz needs his men there.
Any word on Javier?
Not yet.
Is it up here?
Yeah.
What do y'all want with me?
You don't have
to be scared, Gina.
You know
who I am.
Ms. Mendoza's
a close friend.
We want to make you
an offer.
-Offer?
-Yes.
One of
Ms. Mendoza's men saw
Judge Lafayette
visit you.
Yeah, he comes to see me
same time every Wednesday.
Good.
That's today.
Is he always alone?
I know Lafayette
is very powerful.
He trusts me.
Kinda treats me like a pet.
I was doing time
for solicitation.
The Judge got me out
on early parole,
so he lets me know
every chance he gets
that he can send me back
whenever he wants.
You're a pet in a cage.
I hate him.
Gina, if you help us,
all that money is yours.
This is your chance
to get away from him.
We're offering you a new life.
We're gonna make it
look like a drug deal
gone wrong.
Gina.
All you have to do is
put this in his suit jacket.
Okay.
All right.
Pote will hide in your house.
Once Lafayette arrives,
you need to make him
comfortable.
Act like everything is normal.
Pote will take care of him.
Nothing will happen to you.
You promise?
Take the money
and go as far away as you can.
You think she can handle it?
She'd better,
or Lafayette's gonna come at us
with everything he's got.
Hello?
Davis, buddy,
where you been
hiding yourself?
You can't just disappear
on your daddy like that.
He's been worried sick.
I doubt that.
But he should start worrying.
Told that girl's boyfriend
that you murdered her.
I showed him where--
I showed him
where the body is.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Okay, Davis.
-Slow down.
-No.
He has kept me drugged
and tried to convince me
that I was crazy.
He thinks he plays
by different rules.
Not anymore.
Hang tight.
Oh, no.
Cecil, you are not gonna waste
the little time we have
talking business on your phone.
I do concur with
your decision, baby.
Primo,  what's up?
Better get your ass
to Miami, cabrón.
Life is good here.
I'm on the next flight
to New Orleans.
No,  primo.
Javi...
What the devil's got into you?
Not that I'm complaining.
Dale!
-Go!
So Dumas' men
killed Birdie, huh?
I saw it on his face.
We were at war
with them, George.
It's over now.
I need to know that
you're focused.
It's not just about Birdie.
These Russians that you're
trying to get in bed with--
they are the nastiest,
most ruthless sons of bitches
that walk the Earth.
Are you sure you wanna
take that risk?
There's only one way
to be safe in this business--
to become powerful enough
that no one can touch you.
So New York and the Russkis--
that's some kind of
exit strategy?
It's also the center of finance,
a place where we can
become legitimate quickly.
Is it done?
Okay.
Pote missed.
-Close the bar.
-Oh, god damn it!
Toss the bar!
We rolled up the distillery.
No coke.
No guns.
No money.
Looks like she's in the wind.
Now, looks can be deceiving,
especially with Mendoza.
Keep kicking rocks.
Roaches run from the light.
Okay, well,
it isn't much to look at,
but I figured
that's kinda the point--
hide in plain sight.
-It's perfect.
-Great, okay.
Well, I rented out all the rooms
so you won't have
any lookie-loos,
and your stuff is in room number
12 if you need to freshen up.
Thank you.
I'll take you there.
Okay.
-Listen, Kelly Anne.
This war with Lafayette--
it's really bad.
I would like you to go and stay
with Chicho's mom in Uptown.
I'm not going anywhere.
This is my family.
I know it is.
But Teresa needs your help
with the business,
not with a gun.
Okay.
You be safe, you hear me?
I will.
Where you been, cabrón?
I know why the Judge
tried to kill you, patrona.
Better start talking.
I killed René...
The Judge's nephew.
We got into a fight
in the bathroom at the bar.
Hid his body
in the trunk of his car...
Set it on fire.
Randall found some evidence.
He took Emilia.
She must have lied
to protect me, patrona.
I think
she told him
you ordered the hit on René.
And they killed her.
You got Tony killed!
You almost got Teresa killed!
Now you will die, cabrón!
Wait!
Don't let this hijo de puta
out of your sight.
Javier saved my life.
He risked his own
trying to protect me.
He's been as courageous
as James.
But he lied to your face.
And so did James.
He wasn't exactly a saint.
At least Javier--he lied
to protect the woman he loved.
I told you
not to leave him alone!
Javi ain't running.
He's a cartel soldier.
He knows he disobeyed the boss'
orders and lied to her to boot.
Look, he's good
with whatever you decide.
We'll need him.
Lafayette is coming for us.
Not to mention Boaz runs Miami.
Killing his cousin--
that's gonna
set his hair on fire.
For now, he lives.
Dumas was right.
I should make peace
with the Judge.
Ms. Mendoza, what a coincidence.
You were just on my mind.
I know you think
I ordered your nephew's death.
I didn't.
One of my men just confessed
to killing René
in a fight at my bar.
You'll forgive me
if I find that hard to swallow.
You tried to kill me
and killed my godson.
Both of us lost family.
I would like to try to find
a way to put this behind us.
I'm open to mending fences
once you hand your man
over to me.
I won't allow that.
I've indulged you, Ms. Mendoza.
I've let you and all the
riffraff in your organization
walk around my city
like you belong here.
And it appears my reward
for not showing you my teeth
is you forgetting your place,
little lady.
Well, let me tell you something.
If you don't hand over your man,
I will hand you your head.
I don't respond to threats.
It's not a threat.
It's a promise.
-Teresita,
what you told the Judge is true.
Whether Javier lives or dies,
it's up to you.
What do you wanna do, Teresita?
I've done everything
Lafayette demanded.
I've paid him a lot of money.
If I do this now,
where does it end?
He knows you're after him now.
He'll just keep hitting us.
Then we'll hit him harder.
-That means hitting cops.
-Dirty cops.
-Murderous thieves.
-Maybe.
But they're his own
private army.
He runs this town.
Even if we win,
we're gonna lose a lot.
They'll lose more.
Patrona.
This city has been
our private Eden, Marcel.
Mendoza is an invasive species.
She's putting down roots.
You wanna cut her out.
I need your answer.
Are you with me?
Of course.
You're the devil I know.
You know where she is?
Yeah.
She's holed up with her people
at a safe location.
Cedric and my crew--
they're sitting on her now.
-They'll help your boys out.
-No, Randall can handle it.
No.
I'm sorry, Judge.
I'm not taking any chances
this time.
My boys'll make sure
that nothing goes wrong
with the hit on Mendoza.
This war ends today.
I did the recon.
Teresa Mendoza's here.
How many men are with her?
Four.
The place is isolated.
Only one way in or out.
-So we got 'em boxed in--
-And outnumbered.
Like shooting fish
in a barrel, man.
Let's not start
stroking each other just yet.
Get your boys together.
Fall back!
Dumas set us up!
He's running away!
Hey, we get 'em all?
Almost.
What the hell, man?
Hm?
Why'd you do Birdie that way?
Birdie?
I was just
following orders, man.
Mm-hmm.
I'm a soldier, same as you.
-Kay?
She was a civilian.
I know.
It was messed up.
See, but you do this,
it all starts up again.
Okay?
It's Lafayette.
So now you're a cop killer,
Ms. Mendoza.
Those men weren't cops.
I learned early on
how dangerous it is
to underestimate you, hm?
So I bought myself
a little insurance.
Do tell me.
Have you spoken to your
Russian friend lately?
Say hello, darling.
Hello, Teresa.
They grabbed me from my hotel.
His cop shot two of my men.
Is the picture
becoming clear now?
Do you know who
she's connected to?
Oh, I have a pretty good idea.
They will hunt you down
and kill you.
They don't care who you are.
And you'll be right there
beside me, darling.
Mutually-assured destruction--
unless you give me
my nephew's killer.
I expect an answer
by midnight.
-Patrona.
You know what you have to do.
Está bien.
It didn't have to be like this.
If you trusted me,
I could've protected you,
but now I can't.
Working with you, patrona...
I owe that to you.
Salud.
They're here.
Let them in.
Everybody just breathe easy.
Hands where I can see 'em.
You're not here as the law.
You know why I'm here,
Ms. Mendoza.
Let's put an end to all this.
I'll see you
on the other side, brother.
I was right, patrona.
We were crazy to think
we would have
something different
in this life.
Let's go.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Oh, Davis,
you had me worried sick.
You tracked my phone?
I know you're angry,
but I forgive you.
You can come back home.
You forgive me?
You defied me, Davis,
but you showed fortitude
I didn't know you had.
-It gives me hope.
-Hope for what?
That you're more like me
than I thought.
-Go to hell.
-Judge.
We need to wrap this up.
You were tricked, son.
Mendoza's man,
the one you confided in--
he's the man
who murdered your cousin.
You're lying.
You'd say anything to me.
Mendoza handed him over
to me herself.
He's the reason
that sweet girl died.
But don't you worry.
He gonna get
what's coming to him.
Let's do this, pendejo.
What's he saying, Randall?
He's saying,
"Let's do this, pendejo."
Gotta admire a man who welcomes
his own firing squad.
Nothing personal, amigo.
I actually kinda liked you.
Randall!
The shoot-out
in Metairie took the lives
of six decorated officers,
including the head
of the anti-gang strike team,
Detective Randall Green.
Police at this time
are calling it
a gang-related incident.
Randall is dead.
-Javier.
-Mm.
He fought to the end.
I'm sorry you were
pulled into this.
I know how much
this has cost you.
Do not think I am ungrateful.
The good news is that
you have his attention.
The bad news...
is that you have his attention.
So we are in business
with Kostya?
Yes.
For better or for worse.
Thank you.
The Judge is down,
but he's not out.
As long as he's breathing,
he's gonna be a problem for us.
If he loses his power,
he's just a man.
Any man can be killed.
Dave?
My son.
Son?
Oh, God.
What have I done?
Taza said there's
a new sheriff in Phoenix
that's cleaning up corruption,
so he's gonna need more money
for bribes.
-Send it.
-Okay.
-How's Miami?
-It's a little bumpy.
Boaz had to dispose
of a few dealers
that were causing problems.
You were smart
to keep extra men there.
What about the new bankers?
I'm still checking references,
but I did make a list of new
businesses to clean our money,
and I'm looking into
making an investment
on the waterfront property
as well as some
commercial real estate.
Great.
Thank you.
Happy to help.
I'm gonna get to that meeting,
but that suit is baller.
Thank you.
It's okay, Luis.
I heard there was an explosion
in front of your bar.
You okay?
Yes.
Thank you.
You know,
they said you were
in the hospital.
I was gonna come, but...
I wasn't sure you'd want me to.
I'm glad you didn't.
I spent the last month
putting all the pieces together
of what went down
between you and me.
I know you're not just a
bar owner or
a tequila distributor.
Tell me the truth.
I run a drug cartel.
Are you serious?
Every minute
you spend with me...
You're in danger.
I need you to go away.
Don't come back.
You lied to me.
Yes.
Everything else--
was it a lie too?
No.
Phoenix, Atlanta, Miami.
Now, New York.
We doubled our operation
in three months.
That's a lot to keep an eye on.
Ain't no risk it, no biscuit.
You staying?
I'ma stick around.
Make sure you're good
with the Russkis.
Hey, you might need me.
I know Chewy does.
Whatever you need
to tell yourself, cabrón.
George, call a doctor.
My God, James.
What happened to you?
They're coming for you.
Renewed for Season Five!!!