♪♪ [ Orchestra: Classical, Slow Tempo ]
♪♪ [ Continues ]
♪♪ [ Singing Opera In German ]
♪♪ [ Singing Continues ]
♪♪ [ Man Singing In German ]
[ Ramirez's Voice ]
Remember, Highlander.
Remember?
[ Wind Blowing ]
Free men of the planet, hear me.
We gather together in
secret for the last time.
You suffer under the yoke of General
Katana's rule for the last time.
And you stand without a
leader for the last time.
Will you lead us, Ramirez?
No, I'm not your leader.
But because I see with
eyes different from yours,
I see a man...
with a great destiny before him.
Who is he?
Show him to us!
Let him show himself.
[ Electricity Crackling ]
YES. You.
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
We are now as one.
How do we start?
Not we. You.
And you start with Katana.
[ Explosion ]
General Katana's attacking!
[ Crowd Shouting ]
♪♪ [ Woman Singing In German ]
[ Ramirez's Voice ]
Remember the rebellion?
The cause is still just...
and still yours.
[ Explosions ]
Break ranks!
Get more men!
♪♪ [ Orchestra: Opera Continues ]
[ Swords Clanging ]
My friends in here remind
me of you and Ramirez.
So deadly in their own
environment, yet...
[ Chuckles ]
so tame and servile in mine.
Maybe they're just waiting.
Waiting for what?
For you to get careless.
Ah.
Maybe they are.
But as of tomorrow, waiting won't
be an option for you, will it?
You sure?
[ Squealing, Bones Cracking ]
[ Laughs ]
♪♪ [ Orchestra Continues ]
Let's get on with it.
The punishment for rebellion is death.
Judge them guilty, and I'll
execute them here, now.
You forget yourself, General Katana.
As you well know, for many years we have
exiled those rebels and criminals...
who, like you, possess
this unholy immortality.
Therefore, I sentence you
both to this same exile—
an exile into the future.
- What?
- Silence, General Katana!
In that distant future, you will face
other Immortals in trial by combat...
from which only one can survive.
And, as is your way,
you will die only when your
head is cut from your body.
- Will we be together?
- Well, not at first.
But we are joined in a way
that can never be broken,
not even by death.
When you need me, you'll
only have to call my name.
I'll always find you.
Finally, the last one to
survive will have a choice.
Choice? What choice?
Grow old and die in the future...
or return here with his
freedom and faith restored.
[ Muttering ]
Priests.
Now go, and remember,
there can be only one.
[ Electricity Crackling ]
[ Both Groaning ]
Okay, Mr MacLeod, the show is over.
[ Chuckles ]
I thought so too, Charlie.
I really did.
[ Thunderclap ]
♪♪ [ Program Theme ] Good evening and
welcome to TSC's nightly report.
Today's satellite readings
from above the shield...
confirm that highly dangerous
levels of ultraviolet radiation...
continue to bombard the planet in
the absence of the ozone layer.
But here below the shield
we are protected and safe.
At a press conference held earlier...
the corporation's chief financial officer,
David Blake, denied growing rumors...
of a management shake-up.
Alan Neyman, president of TSC,
was unavailable for comment...
and he seems increasingly isolated.
[ Dial Tone Beeps ]
Shield Corporation.
May I help you?
Alan Neyman, please.
Who may I say is calling?
Tell him it's a friend.
Tell him it's MacLeod.
Please hold.
Thank you.
I'm sorry. He's not accepting
any calls at the moment.
Any message?
No, no message.
Thank you for calling.
Thank you.
Hey, grandpa!
You got some change for
the oxygen machine?
Hey! Hey, you cheap fuck!
You deaf or what?
You.
You're MacLeod, aren't you?
So what?
Yeah, right. So what?
Okay, okay. Come on.
We're out of here!
- Let's go!
-- Come on, guys! Forget it!
Let's go! Move!
What was that?
What was what?
I heard something.
I'm calling it in.
Security.
[ On Headset ]
I heard something. You see anything?
I don't see nothing.
Could be fish.
Fish live in the lake.
Not in this lake.
Yeah? Well, I've seen 'em.
It was a fish.
[ Man ]
Come on, Louise. Let's do it.
Here it is.
[ Beeping ]
[ Seal Bursts ]
We've got 30 seconds to
get a clear reading.
- [ Beeping ]
- I'm going into the computer.
- Blue alert!
[ Shouting, Chattering ]
-- Check your monitor!
- Three-zero-point-four-four!
-- [ Beeping Continues ]
- Impossible. Radiation levels can't be normal.
- Go to red!
-- [ Alarm Blaring ]
Come on, Louise. Keep moving.
But you don't know what this means.
You can tell me about it later.
Go, go, go!
Shoot! Shoot!
[ Alarm Continues ]
Let's split up!
♪♪ [ Lounge Jazz ]
[ Man ] ♪ A hurricane hits ♪
♪ Your house is gone ♪
♪ The parakeet flies away ♪
♪ You don't get the raise
you've been counting on ♪
♪ Got gamblin' debts to pay ♪
♪ But you're in— ♪♪
What now, gentlemen?
Isn't that your friend
MacLeod, General?
He's getting older,
but he's still alive.
I know that! I'm not blind!
Good. Then you can also see that
he hasn't made his choice yet.
He still has time to come back to us.
Wonderful.
[ Katana ]
Corda! Reno!
Where are you?
There you are.
I want you to leave for
the future immediately.
Find MacLeod and kill him.
But I thought you said MacLeod
was mortal and will never return.
Do me a big favor, Corda.
Don't think.
He's an old man now.
He'll be dead in a couple of weeks.
I don't care.
Find him for me. Kill him.
[ Katana ]
It's so hard to get good help.
[ Cackling ]
♪♪ [ Pop, Faint ]
♪ Oh, it's a perfect, perfect ♪
♪ Perfect world ♪
♪ My beautiful world ♪
♪ It's a perfect world ♪♪
[ Coin Clatters ]
[ Man ] ♪ One dream, one soul ♪
♪ One prize, one goal ♪
♪ One golden glance ♪
Hey, Jimmy.
Hey, Mr MacLeod.
How you doing?
Good. Good.
All right, all right.
Ousceva?
Ousceva.
[ Laughs ] ♪♪ [ Continues ]
Here you go.
[ Male Announcer On TV ] Good evening.
Reports have just come in of a terrorist
attack on the Shield Control Center.
According to information
available at this time,
the group calling themselves Cobalt...
successfully made an attempt
to enter Shield Control...
for propaganda purposes.
The Shield Corporation
had this comment.
What Cobalt is doing is insanity.
Any tampering with the
shield of any kind...
endangers the lives of every man,
woman and child on the planet.
Cobalt is known to be headed by
environmental terrorist Louise Marcus...
who led the raid and remains
at large at this time.
Pretty girl.
♪♪ [ Continues ]
♪ Is this a kind ♪
♪ Of magic ♪
[ Chorus ] ♪ It's a kind of magic ♪
♪ There can be only one ♪
You're a good boy, Jimmy.
Well, bottoms up.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
Hey! Are you MacLeod?
Hey, I asked you a question.
Are you MacLeod?
Yes, I am.
Great. I always wanted to meet the
guy that turned the world to shit.
He saved our lives, if you ask me.
I'm not asking you.
Okay. What do you want?
Did you ever think about that
before you covered the sky with that puke?
- Who are you?
- Me?
I'm nobody. All right?
I work all day and my life stinks...
and it's your goddamn
fault, you old bastard.
Don't turn your back on me!
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
There are some people in this world...
who know when to stop...
and some people who don't.
Which kind are you?
Okay, Miss Nobody, you're out of here.
Come on, come on—
Come on! Come on!
You're gone.
I'll see you again.
Anytime.
Oh, Jesus.
Why do they always pick my place?
Know what I'm saying?
I'm sorry, Mr MacLeod.
No problem, Jimmy.
No problem.
Watch out!
Son of a bitch!
Are you all right?
Yeah. Yeah, I'll be fine.
You just hang in there, Mr MacLeod.
I'll be right back.
Hey, you! Come back here!
I'm talking to you!
Maybe I should get this one.
[ Beeping ]
What was that?
[ People Chattering ]
What the hell was that?
[ Electrical Pulses ]
Oh, no.
Not again.
[ People Chattering ]
♪♪ [ Rock: Muffled, Indistinct ]
Mr MacLeod?
Yes?
I'm Louise Marcus.
Terror is a dangerous
business, Ms Marcus.
I'm not a terrorist.
Well, whatever you are, Ms Marcus,
you'll have to excuse me.
I had some very disturbing news.
Did somebody die?
Unfortunately not.
Good-bye, Ms. Marcus.
You know, I used to read about you.
You had such great
passion for the world.
I admired you.
I can see that's all gone now.
You're nothing but a tired old man.
More than you know.
Oh, no, you don't.
The world is dying, MacLeod.
I need your help.
Please get out of the car.
No way.
Suit yourself.
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Horn Honks ]
Listen, MacLeod, when I broke in tonight,
the numbers and figures I saw didn't add up.
Something's wrong, and Blake's
trying to cover it up.
- What do you want me to do?
- Help me.
I can't. Not now.
What happened to the MacLeod
that everyone believed in?
That was 40 years ago.
I'm an old man.
- [ Groaning ]
- Are you all right? What's the matter?
You gotta go.
[ Tires Squeal ]
[ Corda, Reno Yelping, Cackling ]
Who are they?
I don't know.
[ Distorted ]
MacLeod!
Was that just a lucky guess?
Wait a minute.
What are we doing?
Get in there.
Don't make a sound. In here?
You've gotta be kidding.
Come on!
Let me have him.
But I want him!
It's my turn.
MacLeod!
You're going to die!
[ Panting ]
Ramirez!
My old friend Ramirez!
[ Cackles ]
[ Hisses ]
[ Metal Bar Clanks ]
Thank you!
[ Siren Wailing ]
- [ Cackling ]
- [ Grunts ]
[ Groans ]
[ Train Horn Blows ]
[ Yells ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Horn Blowing ]
[ Screams ]
[ Electricity Crackling ]
[ Groaning ]
MacLeod.
[ Yelping ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Cackling ]
[ Mouthing Words ]
[ Groans ]
[ Yelling ]
[ Tires Screech ]
I hate to say good-bye, Highlander!
Why?
Are you going somewhere?
Hey, pal, you got a light?
Thanks.
[ Cackling ]
Come on.
Come on!
Ramirez!
[ Groaning ]
Alas, poor Yorick.
[ Electrical Pulses ]
I knew him, Horatio.
A fellow of infinite jest.
Ah!
[ Audience Chuckling, Murmuring ]
[ Ramirez ]
Well, now.
Alas, poor Yorick.
I knew him, Horatio.
Actually, the name is Ramirez.
- Will you get out of here.
- Excuse me?
A fellow of infinite jest,
of most excellent fancy.
Forgive me for interrupting
your conversation but--
He hath borne me upon his
back a thousand times.
Now, how abhorred in
my imagination it is.
My gorge rises at it.
Here hung those lips...
that I have kissed I know not how oft.
Sir, whatever you gentlemen felt for each
other when your friend was still alive...
is certainly none of my affair.
What's your fucking game, shithead?
[ Audience Laughing ] Shithead?
What's a shithead?
Get off the stage!
[ Audience Continues Laughing ]
[ Laughs ] My apologies!
Enough of this useless banter.
I shall be on my way and leave
you to converse with your skull.
Farewell, dear shithead.
Farewell.
[ Cheering ]
Rather glad the magic works.
[ Horn Honking ]
So much for the horse and cart.
[ MacLeod ] Louise.
Who are you?
I'm Connor MacLeod
of the Clan MacLeod.
And I cannot die.
I'm Louise Marcus from
Flagstaff, Arizona.
Let me just see if I
can get this straight.
You're mortal there, but
you're immortal here...
until you kill all the guys
from there who have come here,
and then you're mortal here.
Unless you go back there...
or some more guys
from there come here,
in which case you become
immortal here... again.
- Something like that.
- Of course.
It would be something
like that, wouldn't it?
Quite a night.
Tell me about it.
Think I do this every Saturday night?
Let's say it's a kind of magic.
That's not what I was talking about.
So, what do you want me to do?
You built the shield. Maybe you can
figure out what's going on up there.
What are you saying?
Something is being kept very, very quiet.
Even your old pal Alan
is on a tight leash.
I couldn't get anyone to listen to me.
So you started Cobalt.
Got your face on national TV.
Well, of course.
Somebody had to get
people's attention,
start asking questions,
find out the truth.
Someone like you?
No, damn it!
Someone like you.
Excellent threads, dude.
Shithead.
[ Chattering ]
May I help you, sir?
I would like a suit of clothes.
And why not, indeed?
We are the oldest gentlemen's
tailor in Scotland.
Well, then, I've come
to the right place...
since I am, without a doubt, the
oldest gentleman in Scotland.
Well, if you say so, sir.
Well, let's get started.
I have a long journey ahead
of me and limited time.
I'm afraid sir still
doesn't understand.
A suit may take several
weeks to complete.
I'm afraid sir damn
well does understand...
and sir would like a
suit of clothes by 3:00.
♪♪ [ "William Tell Overture" ]
There is nothing like a challenge
to bring out the best in man.
With our compliments, sir.
Thank you, Roy.
Can we arrange a limo for you, sir?
A limo?
Yes, to take you to the airport.
Airport?
You did say you had a long
journey ahead of you.
Yes. Well, I believe the
fastest way is still to fly.
To fly.
Yes, of course.
[ Louise ]
Have you ever seen a blue sky?
Sure.
What was it like?
It was--
It was the deepest blue you ever saw.
But it was more than that.
White clouds suddenly
turning dark with rain.
[ Sighs, Chuckles ]
And the smell of grass
after the storm.
Red leaves in fall.
Snow in winter.
It was beautiful.
And we thought it would last forever.
I wish you could have seen it.
So do I.
I'd like to,
just once before I die.
[ Katana ] Ah, yes.
Yes.
I guess if you want something done,
you have to do it yourself.
[ Male Announcer ] It's the wackiest
show on TV— The Psychic Cook.
Step into the paranormal pantry
with the special guest ghost...
and prepare meals from
beyond the grave.
Spooky sauces to ghostly goulashes--
It's a whole lot of fun!
The Psychic Cook, weekdays at 5:00.
Brought to you by Xenon,
the world's highest grade
of non-emission gasoline,
available at service
stations everywhere.
Only $55 a gallon.
[ Mutters In Foreign Language ]
It happens again!
[ Passengers Screaming, Shouting ]
[ Electricity Crackling, Faint ]
[ Grunts ]
That was great! Yes!
[ Yells ]
[ Exhales ]
Where the hell am I?
[ Laughs ]
This sure doesn't look
like Kansas, does it?
[ People Screaming ]
Godzilla! Godzilla!
[ Passengers Exclaiming ]
[ Blows Landing ]
[ Woman ]
Oh, my God!
[ Woman Gasps ]
Oh, God.
[ Man ]
Did you see what he did?
Look out!
You're a little one, aren't you?
[ Grunts ]
[ Chuckles ]
Bet you've always wanted
to drive one of these, huh?
Me too.
Hi!
- [ Groans ]
- [ Chuckles ]
- [ Chortling ]
- [ Yelling ]
Yes!
- [ Passengers Screaming ]
- [ Yelling ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Screaming ]
Give me more!
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Screaming ]
Let's have some fun!
Oh, my God!
Last stop.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Beeps ]
[ Coughs, Sighs ]
Can't even make a decent
cup of coffee anymore.
You always use too much water.
- Mac?
- Alan.
Where the hell have you been?
I'm so glad you're here.
So many things have happened.
We must talk.
Okay.
Good God.
You look fantastic.
What have you been doing?
Working out?
Have you had a face lift?
Something like that.
Do you remember
the dreams we had?
Remember the day?
[ Man's Voice ] Good evening. Only a few months
now until the ozone layer is completely gone.
A team of international scientists
led by Dr Alan Neyman...
and supervised by Connor MacLeod...
work around the clock.
This may be the last
chance for planet Earth.
This is TSC.
We are standing by for shield launch.
[ Camera Shutter Clicking ]
They'll remember this day
for a thousand years--
The day we protected the
planet from the sun.
[ Man On P.A. ]
All personnel please leave the area.
We are starting the final countdown.
We are starting final countdown.
[ Man #1 ] TSC, this is Florida Control.
All power for the shield—
[ Man #2 ] All systems are go.
Please run final checks on all shield power elements.
[ Man On P.A. ] All personnel please leave the area.
We are starting the final countdown.
[ Man #2 ]
TSC, this is Houston Space Control.
Satellite is in final receiving position.
You can start final countdown.
Stand by. This is it.
Roger, Control.
We are standing by.
This is it!
Florida Control, this is TSC.
The December shield installation
is ready to receive.
To all power sources around
the world, this is TSC.
We are ready to receive.
[ Man On P.A. ] Launch minus 10
Ten seconds and counting.
Okay, boys, let's make this a good one.
The world is watching.
[ Man On P.A. ]
Four, three, two, one.
Ignition!
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
What a day.
What a great day.
It was a great idea, wasn't it, Mac?
It still is.
But you don't know what's happened.
[ Alan On lntercom ]
It's wonderful.
Alan— Come here.
Let me show you.
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
Come on.
[ Typing ]
[ Door Opens ]
Forgive me, Alan.
I didn't realize you got in this early.
Not usually,
but we got to talking.
Forgive me.
David Blake, Connor MacLeod.
Oh, yes, of course.
I'm afraid I'd forgotten
you were still alive.
Always.
Something on the computer?
Oh, no. No, no.
Nothing I won't remember.
I hope so.
Alan, as long as we have you here, we might
just as well get off to an early start.
Fine.
My office?
All right.
Mr MacLeod, I'm terribly sorry
to have to break this up.
But I trust you can
find your own way out.
Sure.
Take care of yourself, Alan.
By the way, how is the shield business?
Never better.
It must be great to have every country
in the world as your customer.
Actually, Mr MacLeod,
we prefer to think that we protect
the population of the planet...
from death by solar radiation.
It is a rather unique service.
Don't you agree?
As long as it's necessary.
Meaning?
Maybe one day the ozone
layer will repair itself.
That would indeed be a great day
for the human race, wouldn't it?
But it really makes no
difference anymore...
since you built the
shield to last forever.
Nothing lasts forever.
[ Chuckling ]
♪♪ [ Rock: Man Singing, Indistinct ]
♪♪ [ Continues On Earphones ] My name's Jerry
Pritchard, man. What do they call you?
It's quite comfortable back here.
Rather like a coffin.
Right. People in this town, they'd
kill you for a nickel, man.
- Hey, cabbie, you want some?
- Get the fuck away from my car!
Scumbags! Scumbags!
Really.
You're in the music
business, aren't you?
Call it a hunch.
I knew that.
So you're in the music business, man.
That's cool.
I wish I was in the music business.
My sister was in the music business.
You should meet her.
I think you'd get along.
- Stop now.
- What? Here?
- Now.
- This is good.
This is a good place to stop.
Goddamn! Whoo!
Shit! Fuck! Yeah!
[ Katana ]
I'll get out here.
Oh, wow!
[ Laughing ]
Yeah!
Out of control!
You and my sister, man—
Forget it!
I should introduce you two.
You could sit around and...
compare tattoos or something, man.
You're crazy!
What next, man?
Central, this is Jerry Pritchard!
Hello? Hello? Shit, man.
I should have stayed in school.
Central, hello? I've got—
Just take it easy, all right?
Come on— Come on.
Central! Central!
Shit, man.
Put all this on my tab.
And, Jerry, add a little
something for yourself.
[ Air Hissing ]
Yes.
Forgive me asking yet again,
but how do we remain so high
above the Earth with safety?
By drinking!
[ Laughing ]
♪♪ [ Fanfare ]
Welcome to your Transatlantic flight.
Please fasten your seat belts.
In the unlikely event of a
loss of cabin pressure,
oxygen masks will drop
from the ceiling.
Place it over your mouth and
nose, and breathe normally.
In case of fire, please do not panic.
Place smoke hood over your head
and crawl to your nearest exit.
Thank you for flying with
us, and enjoy your flight.
Ah.
My kind of town.
[ Electrical Pulses ]
I'm waiting, MacLeod.
Come to me.
[ Shouts ]
I'm waiting!
But on the contrary, Virginia,
all of the most beautiful
women had dark hair.
Helen of Troy, Cleopatra,
Nefertiti, Joan of Arc,
to name but a few.
In fact, it's well known that
the dark-haired ladies...
like to sit— [ Whispering ]
[ Giggling ]
Would you like to order something?
Thank you.
May I have some water, please?
Of course.
Something else for you, sir?
No, thank you.
I never eat anything I cannot identify.
Ah. Thank you.
That's not entirely true, of course.
[ Giggles ]
[ Woman's Voice ] Forgive me, my
husband, for leaving you so soon.
I'm so scared, Connor.
I wanted to stay and love you.
The sun is killing us.
Help the ones that are still alive.
Hold my hand.
Promise me, Connor.
Anything.
Promise me you'll do
something to stop this.
Aye, love. I will.
[ Gasping ]
[ Exhales ]
I love you.
[ Muffled Groaning ]
[ MacLeod ]
It was all going to be so good, so clean.
And for one brief moment, it was.
I used to wish you were here to see it.
But not anymore.
Not after what it's become,
what it's done to us.
[ Clapping ]
Bravo. Bravo.
Excellent.
I always did admire a man
who could talk to the dead.
It's so good to see
you again, MacLeod.
The remains of your mortal wife?
So frail.
So very dead.
At least she's at peace.
Peace is highly overrated.
Things don't change, Katana.
I like that.
After all these years,
you're still a jerk.
What do you mean?
After all this time, I was ready
to kick back, grow old and die.
You changed everything.
And now I'm back to square one.
Immortal... again.
[ Bell Tolling ] So, Katana, let's
see who goes back after all.
[ Priest Praying In Latin ]
Mmm.
I rather like this place.
It's got atmosphere.
I just might stay.
Get off!
Remember the golden rule, Highlander.
We must never fight on holy ground.
And this...
is holy ground.
[ Praying Continues ]
Ashes to ashes,
dust to dust.
If you don't take it out and
use it, it's going to rust.
[ Wind Blowing ]
On three!
Break!
Red 36, Blue 21!
Hike! Hike! Hike!
[ MacLeod's Voice ]
Ship's log: The Rosemary.
The men are all gone now,
God rest their souls.
I alone have come back from the dead...
again.
Who knows how long I
will continue to drift--
days, months, years?
As of this day--
September 6, 1853—
Captain MacLeod no longer exists.
Will this never end?
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Wings Flapping ]
[ Man Screams ]
[ Both Grunting ]
[ Katana Groans ]
Not bad.
[ Groans ]
[ Yells, Grunts ]
[ Grunts, Laughs ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Neck Cracking ]
Nicely played, MacLeod,
but the game's not over yet.
[ Bones Cracking ]
[ Groans ]
[ Yells ]
[ Katana Laughing ]
What happened to you?
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
Who is the girl in the painting?
That was Heather--
my first wife.
We lived in Scotland in 1542.
What was she like?
Full of love. Full of life.
Till the end.
I held her in my arms when she died.
An old woman.
I still loved her.
And the other?
That's Brenda— my last wife.
She looks lovely.
She was.
She died in New York, 29 years ago.
That's a long time to be alone.
You get used to it.
Do you really?
No.
What is it?
Oh, no. Not again.
Go upstairs.
Damn.
Greetings, Highlander.
You called?
Incredible.
What took you so long?
They could have killed me.
Don't be ridiculous.
You've remembered almost
everything I taught you.
I've had a lot of practice lately.
There's no substitute for experience.
What experience?
You've been dead for 500 years.
- So?
- Watch it!
Watch what?
"Watch what?"
The sculpture!
That's a sculpture?
Now you are being ridiculous.
Remember, MacLeod— you called me.
Hmm?
[ Laughing ]
To magic.
Magic works.
It's nice to see that some things have
actually improved over the years.
Is this private?
[ Ramirez ]
Not necessarily.
This is Juan Sanchez
Villa-Lobos Ramirez,
my old friend and teacher,
visiting from Scotland.
Visiting most unexpectedly
from Scotland.
This is Louise Marcus.
Watch it.
She's wanted by the police.
I didn't realize the police
had such good taste.
So, you two have known each
other for a long time.
Seems like an eternity.
Please don't bother, Alan.
Every time you turn that thing on it
just gets printed out in my office.
And yes, yes, yes,
yes, yes, yes, yes' yes,
that includes your little computer
conversation with MacLeod the other day.
Besides, what good could
you possibly do, old man?
What do you mean?
Oh, I don't know.
How about for starters that there simply
isn't enough energy on the planet...
to take down the shield
without killing us all?
If I'm going too fast, slow me down, but
I think you should know this all, Alan.
I mean, you designed the thing.
You and this... MacLeod.
But that was only in case
the shield was threatened.
[ Laughing ]
Well, that's funny, Alan!
'Cause I was under the impression that
that's precisely what had happened.
But it really doesn't
matter now, does it?
So why don't you and I try and relax.
No tears.
Because it's business as usual—
forever.
You have allowed yourself
to become a traitor, Alan.
And as I think you know, we have
a fabulous place for traitors.
Don't we?
Gentlemen,
I can now assure you that Cobalt
will no longer be a problem.
In fact, earlier today...
the Shield Police were once
again able to stop an attempt—
Hi.
Excuse me, but I do believe
that you'll find...
the costume party is
in another building.
This happens to be a meeting,
[ Groans ] and no one interrupts
a meeting of the corporation.
The corporation.
What luck.
You see, I've come to
join the corporation.
And here you all are.
Oww.
Where do I sign up?
Oh, I think I've had enough of you.
Good-bye, Attila.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Gunshots ]
Ah!
[ Chuckling ]
Yes, indeed.
That was brilliantly done.
Bravo.
Yes!
You know, guys,
this is no way to treat your
number one draft choice.
Hey.
[ Gasping ]
[ Bones Cracking ]
[ Grunts ]
Partners.
I believe you cannot run a
business without partners.
Right.
This is a business, isn't it?
Oh, yes, it is.
Ah.
We like to think of it
as a good business. Mmm.
What exactly is it that you want...
partner?
The Highlander.
Right.
Wilson, could we get on the
Highlander thing as soon as possible?
[ Electrical Pulses ]
MacLeod.
You created that monstrosity?
Why?
It was necessary at the time.
[ Scoffs ]
So was Noah's flood, but that
at least served its purpose.
Cleansed the Earth from evil
and gave it a fresh start.
Thirty-three degrees,
26 minutes north latitude.
That's where Neyman said
there was a system failure.
Meaning what?
Meaning we can go above the shield.
We will still require a
longitude, won't we?
MacLeod.
Alan Neyman's been taken to Max.
Max? Who's Max?
A high-security prison.
MacLeod.
Your time is now!
[ Electrical Pulses ]
[ Woman's Voice On Intercom ]
You have entered a restricted area.
Please identify yourself immediately.
I am Juan Sánchez Villa-Lobos Ramirez,
chief metallurgist to King Philip II
of Spain, and I am at your service.
This is Checkpoint One outside
of security installation Max.
Identify yourselves.
Hey, take it easy, man.
First time in the desert.
Which way to Vegas?
Okay, jerk-face.
Stay put, and we'll come get you.
Hit it, dude!
[ Tires Screeching ]
[ Man ] ♪ Rockin' ♪
♪ Rollin' through ♪
♪ And here we go ♪
Get ready. Here it comes.
♪♪ [ Continues, Indistinct ]
Hi.
You won't shoot me, will you?
I mean—
Oh, thank you.
I was just hitching a ride...
and then these two
guys grabbed me and—
Oh, my.
And threw me in the trunk and—
Oh, shit.
Hello. I'm Dr. Sonny Jackson, and
I've looked over your report.
As near as I can tell, you have
a few bruises and lacerations,
but I think you'll be
okay in a day or so.
Thanks. How about them?
No way. They were both dead
before the car stopped.
I'm amazed they got
as far as they did.
Gosh, I've never seen
a mess like that.
They must have taken about
a hundred bullets or so.
Excuse me. 108.
112, myself.
Come on. You're not counting
that little scratch, are you?
Scratch? What are you talking about?
It passed right through me.
[ Ramirez ] And just look
at my splendid waistcoat.
[ Both Groan ]
Wait a minute.
You guys-- You boys are—
You guys are... de-- Wh—
Larry!
All right, these tunnels run
along both sides of Max...
and they end up at the same place.
They both have security rooms,
and Neyman's in one of them.
So we should split up, and we'll
meet back together at the end.
You take this way.
Let's go, MacLeod.
No more. No more!
No more!
Alan.
Oh, my God.
[ Groans ]
Please.
Listen. Other coordinate—
Six degrees, 42 minutes west.
You can get through the shield there.
You must see for yourself.
Mac?
Yes?
We did the right thing to build it.
Yes, we did.
[ MacLeod ] I won't forget you.
[ Louise ] MacLeod.
[ Katana ]
How very touching.
You don't have to worry.
No one gets out of Max.
But you said nobody
would get in either.
Who's that?
Louise Marcus.
The head of Cobalt.
A powerful enemy, I'm sure.
It doesn't matter now,
because they're both dead.
Don't let the door close!
Holy shit!
-Just stay back!
- I can help!
No, you can't— not this time!
[ Shouts ]
Most people have a full measure of life.
And most people just watch
it slowly drip away.
But if you can summon it all up...
at one time,
in one place,
[ Whimpers ]
you can accomplish something...
glorious!
My time here is over.
You must go and search out Katana.
It'll take the power of you
both to destroy the shield.
Will I ever see you again?
Who knows, Highlander?
Who knows?
Go.
Show time.
Come on.
Outstanding!
[ Exhales ]
Time for your bitch to die!
Whatever happens, don't stop.
What?
[ Yells, Grunts ]
[ Grunting Continues ]
MacLeod!
[ Screams ]
[ Screaming, Whimpering ]
No!
[ Laughing ]
I'm fine. I'm fine!
Oh, great.
[ Electricity Pulsing, Crackling ]
Let's go.
[ Louise Grunting ]
MacLeod! MacLeod!
Hold on!
That's it! Come on!
Life is going to be quite
predictable without MacLeod.
[ Glass Ball Shatters ]
Aren't we getting just a
little overconfident, partner?
You are betting on me, aren't you?
Oh, yes.
You see, I always play the favorite.
[ Explosion ]
[ Electrical Pulsing Crackling Continues ]
[ Wind Blowing ]
Alan was right.
The shield's got to come down.
There is only one way.
I haven't any idea where they are.
I mean, for God's sake, they dropped
off the screen almost 24 hours ago.
Everybody's got to be someplace.
Relax. At this point in his life,
he's a man with a mission.
And all his roads lead to me.
Right. I understand that.
But I do beg to differ.
What if he did get to
Neyman before he died?
And what if he did
get the coordinates?
What of it?
Well, just maybe...
they could figure it out--
about the ozone layer.
And if that's the case—
Well, suffice to say that the company
would be spiraling into Chapter 11.
Will you be quiet?
It's MacLeod.
Looks as though you
fucked up, eh, partner?
You really think so?
Well—
Maybe.
[ Screaming ]
Then again, maybe not.
That's very cute.
[ Yells ]
[ Both Grunting ]
Come on!
[ Screaming ]
[ Groaning ]
There can be only one.
[ Gasps ]
[ Ramirez's Voice ] It'll take the power
of you both to destroy the shield.
- MacLeod!
- [ Screaming ]
[ Ramirez's Voice ]
Most people have a full measure of life.
And most people just watch
it slowly drip away.
But if you can summon
it all up at one time,
in one place,
you can accomplish something...
glorious.
♪♪ [ Rock ]
♪ Maybe I'm wrong and
I should know better♪
♪ To trust easily ♪
♪ I don't know ♪
♪ But I've waited so long ♪
♪ And I need to believe
that there must be a way ♪
♪ And I know ♪
♪ I've got one dream ♪
♪ That keeps me hangin' on ♪
♪ One dream ♪
♪ Over and over♪
♪ One dream that love will find a way ♪
♪ Find a way Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Mmm ♪
♪ Whoo ♪
♪ Yesterday's gone ♪
♪ And all that remains of the past ♪
♪ Is this memory ♪
♪ But it takes love that is strong ♪
♪ And a heart that is willing ♪
♪ To stand a little pain ♪
♪ We gotta live for today ♪
♪ One dream that keeps me hangin' on ♪
♪ One dream ♪
♪ Dream it over and over♪
♪ One dream that love will find a way ♪
♪ Find a way, yeah ♪
♪ One dream That's all
that I'm livin' for♪
♪ One dream Dream it over and over♪
♪ One dream that love will find a way ♪
♪ Find a way Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Ooh, yeah ♪
♪ Yesterday's gone ♪
♪ And all that remains of the past ♪
♪ Is a memory ♪
♪ But it takes love that is strong ♪
♪ And a heart that's willing ♪
♪ To stand a little pain ♪
♪ Ooh, yeah, yeah, now ♪
♪ One dream that keeps me hangin' on ♪
♪ One dream ♪
♪ Over and over♪
♪Just dream it ♪
♪ One dream ♪
♪ That love will find a way ♪
♪ I know I, I know I ♪
♪ One dream ♪
♪ That keeps me hangin' on ♪
♪ Over and over♪
♪ Ooh, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ One dream that love will find a way ♪
♪ One dream ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Gonna find a way ♪
♪ Love will find a way ♪
♪ One dream that keeps me hangin' on ♪
♪ One dream ♪
♪ Over and over♪
♪Just remember, one dream ♪
♪ One dream that love will find a way ♪
♪ I know I, I know I ♪
♪ One dream ♪
♪ One dream that keeps me hangin' on ♪
♪ Over and over♪
♪ Ooh, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ One dream that love will find a way ♪
♪ One dream ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Gonna find a way ♪
♪ Love will find a way ♪
♪ One dream that keeps me hangin' on ♪
♪ One dream ♪
♪ Over and over♪
♪ I got ♪
♪ One dream that keeps me hangin' on ♪
♪ One dream ♪
♪ Over and over♪♪
♪♪ [ Continues ]
♪♪ [ Fades ]