Orson Fortune...
...that is a sexy name.
As a private contractor,
you posses a unique set of skills.
Promo Bonus 300%. Bonus Langsung setiap hari
Gabung sekarang di mantulbanget.net
Situs dengan Winrate terbesar di Indonesia
What's that?
Power nap.
You said it was clear.
I said the front was clear.
Ahhh.
Front, back. Right, wrong.
Right, wrong.
Anyway. Shall we?
So what we got?
Something rather nasty has been stolen.
We have to stop that
from getting onto the open market.
Who's the buyer?
Greg Simmonds.
The billionaire arms dealer?
A lot of very serious faces up here,aren't there?
You can't catch this fishwith conventional lures.
I'm sorry?
The lure being?
Danny Francesco.
The movie star?
Greg Simmonds’ favorite movie star.
And how do we get him?
Blackmail.
Ruse de gurre.
Very good.
Carry on.
The world needs youfor your greatest role yet.
Who are you?
I'm your new manager.
There’s a sensitive and awkward situationbetween you and your sister-in-law.
I actually love my sister-in-law.
Yes Danny. You made that quite evident.
No need to be nervous.
No reason to be nervous.
They’re only killers.
You're an actor. Act.
OK, I'm ready.
Let's go to work.
Will someone pinch me, please?Is that Danny Francesco?
What's next for you?
I'm playing a mysteriousself-made billionaire.
You just described me.
Shadow me. Do whatever I do.
Whatever I do do.
Whoever Greg was buying fromwas amongst you last night.
The Ukrainians.
I can get inside the Ukrainians.
I hope you take them to dinner first...
...before you get inside of them...
...sexually.
(man screaming)
Shhh.
They're going to kill you now.
Well, shoot ‘em first then.
Tidy.
What happened?
He recognized you.
Orson Fortune...
...that is a sexy name.
Cover's blown.
We’re burned.
What do I do?
The movie star is going to melt.
You stop Danny Francesco.
You stop Greg Simmonds!
You let me worry about that.
Promo Bonus 300%. Bonus Langsung setiap hari
Gabung sekarang di mantulbanget.net
Situs dengan Winrate terbesar di Indonesia
What are you gonna do with that?
I’m gonna shoot at them, Danny.
So you weren't seen by anyone?
Yes.
That's a yes, you weren’t seen by anyone?
Or a yes, you were seen by someone?
Yes.