Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
Hey, get up.
It's time to check the buoy.
Come on, Josh.
Oh, no.
So you regret
proposing to my sister?
What I regret is letting you
plan my engagement party.
I know.
Here, get this into you.
It's my great-gran's
hangover remedy.
Oh!
Smells like shit.
Oh, God.
You're spilling it.
You know, once you get
past the gag reflex,
- it's actually not that bad.
- Yeah.
Rory...?
I'll check the buoy.
Oh, my sister's down the beach.
She wants to show you something.
Rory: Looks like it's gonna be
a busy one. Want a hand with that?
What, you're actually gonna
get wet today?
Make a bit of a change, wouldn't it?
Hey.
I bet you've never seen one of these.
What is it?
Wow.
Were you looking at my butt?
No.
- No?
- Maybe.
Aww.
You look terrible.
Thanks.
It's your brother's fault.
But you smell nice.
You always smell nice.
Are you ready
to leave all this behind?
Where you go, I go.
Well, there won't be places like this
in Singapore.
Oh, we'll come back.
Lifeguard:
Shit.
Shark! Shark!
Get help!
Go get help!
Rory!
Get everyone out of the water!
Joe, give me a hand.
Rory!
No!
- Shark!
- I can't hear you.
- What?
Give me your hand.
Rory!
I got you. I got you.
No.
No!
Along with
the yearly southern migration
of the humpback whales
along the East Coast waters,
"Surfline" surfing spokesman
Jeff Tripp said
people should be very vigilant
this time of year,
as we've seen large gatherings
of sharks in the waters
following the whales
along the coast.
Now, what they're doing
is hunting the whale calves
and bait fish
surrounding the migration.
So if you are heading to the beaches,
please observe the signs
and swim only between the flags.
Great whites are expected
in the area over the next month.
And now, on a brighter note,
it's been a picture-perfect day
here on the East Coast
with blue skies
as far as the eye can see.
No signs improving
for the sailors
and the windsurfers, however.
We seem to be hit
with the doldrums,
which means there are
no surface winds.
We gotta move to the car park.
Can't stay here.
Yes, please.
- Hey.
- Jessup come by yet?
- Not yet. You're safe.
Good morning, by the way.
Yeah.
Why are we stopping here?
- Hey, Kyle.
- Shh.
You're bad.
-Hey.
Shut up.
What are you doing here?
You scared me.
Happy anniversary.
You remembered.
11 months, baby.
It's not very much. It's just a song
playlist for when we go to Sydney.
Thank you. Thank you.
Ooh, and...
happy anniversary
to you too.
- Tell me you didn't steal these.
- Oh, Ryan.
Yeah, okay, okay, put them back.
But then I have nothing to give you.
Doesn't matter.
It's the thought that counts.
Put them back, okay?
Come on.
Oops, I hope we're not
interrupting anything.
You know, that's a really cool jacket.
Thanks.
Bet it's got lots of pockets, huh?
Mind if we take a little peek?
She's gonna pay for it.
Just take it out of my paycheck
if you don't believe me.
Paycheck?
You're living in a dream world, kid.
You're fired.
And you shoplifting,
destruction of property.
I've already called the cops.
Did you see all those birds this morning?
There must have been thousands.
You know, there were crows
and magpies and everything.
When did you get back?
Tina, this is what you want?
Josh, this is
Oh, Jesus.
Josh, look at you.
Go clean yourself up.
No, not the customer bathroom.
I got the call.
Oh, shit.
Whoa! Hello.
You starting to hear something
stirring around that head of yours?
The office is at the back of the store.
Cash pickup's in 10 minutes,
so you've got five to get out.
When this is done,
we're straight.
My brother's clean
and I don't want to ever see
your face around him again.
You understand me?
Whatever you say.
I want her charged this time.
She didn't steal this.
This is hers.
We both know you're not gonna
go through with it.
Just stop, because I'm this close.
To what?
Arresting me?
Yeah, real A-plus parenting, Dad.
- Jaimie, you're too smart to--
- Oh, you just dropped
to a C-minus due to lack of originality.
Okay, okay, what about this?
I'm gonna process you this time.
You can spend the day in lockup.
And what do you think that's gonna do?
Maybe it's the wake-up call you need.
Piss off.
What do you think your mother
would have thought about all of this?
Piss off!
Put that on.
That's it.
- Thanks.
- Great.
What the?
Give me the money.
Shit, man, there's no money in the safe.
All right, just take it easy, okay?
You see?
Where is it?
Do you want a separate bag for that?
Hey, drop that fucking gun...
-...or I'll do this bitch!
Where's the money?
You I said,
put the guns down!
Put 'em down!
Thank you.
My dad was totally--
Your dad's right, Jaimes.
Not you too.
I lost my job today
because of you.
Who cares?
You hated that job anyway.
I care. I care.
Well, if it's that important
to you,
I'll go get your
stupid job back, then.
- Jaimie, just--
- No. Watch.
Oi! Freak boy
from history class, right?
You, get here.
- Get here.
- No.
You, get over there.
Stay back.
- No.
- Stay back.
Do as you're told.
What the fuck did you do?
Josh.
Get back.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Don't be a hero, mate.
Stay back.
Tina.
No!
Stop it.
What was that?
What?
Down! Down!
- Come on.
Oh.
I should know, I built the store.
Hurry up. This way.
Come on, come on!
Go! Run!
Hey!
Over here!
Have you seen anyone?
Anyone else?
Anyone?
I need help.
Anybody?
Help!
- Hey.
- Here.
Where's Tina?
Jesus Christ.
Can you help him?
I don't know what to do.
- Just calm down.
- Can you help him?
Calm down.
What the hell's happening?
What just happened?
We gotta get him
out of the water.
Help me lift him
onto this shelf.
I need you to go and find
anything you can to wrap this leg--
towels, electrical tape--
I don't care.
Okay.
Dad? Dad!
My God. Jaimie!
Dad?
- Jaimie.
- Dad!
Here, give me your hand.
Jaimie.
Da--
Dad.
How did you get out?
I was in the car.
I was in the car park, and...
Ryan Ryan--
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God,
Ryan's still in the car park.
- Forget it, kid.
- Ryan's still in the car park.
Forget it.
If it's flooded up here,
they've had it down there.
Tina?
Tina!
Okay, I need your help.
I need you to help
your dad, okay?
Put your hands here
and keep pressure on his leg.
Can you do that for me?
You'll be fine.
Tina.
Tina. Hey.
You're okay.
Look at me.
What what happened?
Where are all the people?
Hey, come on.
Here, give me your hand.
- Help me. Help me.
- Okay, okay.
- Help me.
- Calm down. Calm down.
Help!
We're trapped!
- Someone get us out of here!
- Is anyone there?
- Anyone? Anyone?
- Help!
Somebody help us, please.
Did you hear that?
- Did you hear that?
- Shh. Stop talking.
Where did it go?
Do you hear it?
Not when you don't shut up.
Well, excuse me for helping, Kyle, really.
It's behind you.
Yeah, you find that noise.
You find it.
Good boy, Bully.
Good boy.
Shit.
Fuck. Fuck.
Fuck.
Can anybody hear me?
Hello?
Is anybody there?
Oh, fuck.
Oh.
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
Are you ready?
We've got to get out of here.
We can't stay here.
We've got to get help.
What--?
Oh, shit.
Don't let him
out of your sight.
The water's still rising.
No, no, it can't be.
The whole bloody town
must be flooded up there.
No, it's not.
Look, they're gonna come for us.
They know we're down here.
They're gonna come for us.
That's assuming there's
someone still up there to come.
- You, this is all your fault.
- Not mine, boy, not today.
Today Mother Nature saw us all
as sinners down here.
Why don't you just shut up?
He can't swim anywhere with this leg.
I'll stay here.
You guys find a way out
and bring a rescue team back.
What? No, Josh, wait.
Well, how do we get out?
With the car park flooded,
that leaves only
the loading bay storeroom
and the front entrance.
Josh, you cannot stay here, okay?
You know as well as I do
this is gonna bring aftershocks with it.
It's gonna bring more--
More waves, I know.
So you'll have to be quick.
Okay, well, Steven and l
will check the front.
I'll take the loading bay.
I don't think so.
- Bob?
- Yep.
You go.
Okay.
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
How could you not have
charged your phone?
I can't do everything, Kyle.
God, why didn't you charge it?
Uh, because it's not my phone.
Oh, well, then where is your phone?
Hello.
Oh, well, that's much better.
- What is it, Bully?
Why are you growling like that?
Because he's a fucking retard.
That is not funny, Kyle.
You're not a retard, Bully.
What the hell was that?
I have no idea.
What's that?
Where did it go?
Get everyone
out of the water.
What?
Get everyone out of the water now!
What's happening?
Tina!
Out of the water now!
- Can't get out that way.
- Hurry!
It's blocked.
Out of the water!
Quick, swim.
What's going on?
Tina, Steven, get out of the water!
Collins?
Tina, hurry!
Where is he?
Where did he go?
- Oh!
- Shit.
Jaimie, get back.
Help me!
Please help me!
Shit.
Where did it go?
Did you see it?
What the hell could do that?
What is in here?
There.
Give me your hand.
Ow, my hand.
Jesus Christ.
- That had to be five feet.
- What had to be five feet?
- Six.
- Six? What do you mean, six?
Six feet from the tip
of the dorsal to the tip of the tail.
So what the hell does that mean?
It means there's a 12-foot
great white shark in here.
Fuck!
- I can't see anything.
- Just keep calm, babe.
We have to get out of this car.
I can't stay here much longer.
Give me your shoes.
Excuse me?
Well, I need something with a point
to break the windscreen.
Give me your shoes.
Are you crazy?
These are $300 Gucci.
They're gonna get wet anyway.
Just give me your shoes.
- No.
- Heather, give--
- I'm not giving you my Gucci.
They're not Gucci.
Um, clue you gave them to me
for Christmas last year,
and you said that they were
$300 Guccis.
Um, clue I know I did,
and they're not.
You bought me fake Gucci.
You wouldn't have known
if I didn't just tell you.
I can't believe you.
Fake Gucci?
Just give me your shoes.
What are you doing?
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Hey! Hey, over here.
Freak boy? Is that you?
Jesus Christ, I never thought
I'd actually be happy to see you.
Yeah, no shit. Did you find
anyone? Is there anyone else?
There's bodies everywhere.
There's no one alive.
Well, did you check
the ramp?
It's all jammed up.
I can't get through.
You got a phone
or something in there?
Uh, no.
Holy shit, Kyle. Kyle!
What? What?
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Oh, shit.
It's okay.
- I think it's gone.
Oh, shit.
Oh, man,
this is not happening.
This is so not happening.
You you're a cop, right?
You gotta do something.
For Christsakes, do something.
Do you have any ideas?
Oh, you think
this is funny, do you?
- More ironic, really.
- Oh, really? Well, please share.
I'm sure we could all do
with a good ironic laugh right now.
Think about it.
You bust your ass in here
eight hours a day, seven days a week.
Right?
You'll probably hump away like that
for the next 40 years.
So whatever way you cut it,
this place was gonna kill you.
Now it's just sooner
rather than later.
You son of a bitch.
I want you to know,
the woman you killed--
her name was Julie
and she was a friend.
- I didn't kill anyone.
- It makes no difference.
She died during your robbery,
so it's your fault, you bastard.
If we get out of here alive, I swear
I'm gonna make you fucking pay.
Enough!
It's coming back.
Why does it keep doing that--
just circling?
Because it's not sure
what we are.
It's curious.
Curious about what?
A shark's only curious
about one thing.
It's trying to decide
if we're food or not.
- What was that?
- Hang on, everybody.
Just hang on.
We have another problem.
Why are you laughing?
'Cause he just realized
when the water hits those cables,
this whole place will light up
like a Christmas tree.
Jessup, where do we shut it down?
The storage room.
All the power mains
are in the storage room.
I'll go.
- What?
- Everyone go to the end of the shelf,
make as much noise as you can.
I'll swim for it.
Josh, no.
I mean, you can't.
Your arm look at your arm.
I mean, the shark will go
straight for you.
You can't, not with that.
I don't think we have
any other options.
Hold on.
I have an idea.
Do you see it anywhere?
Yeah, I see it, but I'm keeping it
a secret from you
because I want you to be surprised.
Oh, well, thank you for your
thoughtfulness, Kyle, really.
It's what I always dreamed of
in a boyfriend.
Oh, I can't handle this much longer.
It may surprise you,
but I am not equipped
to deal with this kind of situation.
Here, Bully,
I need some space.
Kyle, do something.
You have to do something.
Like what?
Ask the fucking thing to go away?
- Oh, shit.
- Help!
- Help us, please! Help us!
Get down. Get down.
Get down.
Help us!
Do something!
- Okay.
- Help us!
All right, just get back in the car.
Just stay as still and quiet as possible.
- What, are you fucking insane?
- Just listen, listen.
Why don't you jump in the water
and do a couple of laps?
All right, just listen to me.
You gotta keep still, okay?
The more you scream,
the more the shark's gonna come.
Hey, hey, just get back in and wait.
I'm gonna get the shark to come to me.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
What?
When I get it over here,
you swim like hell
for my van over there.
You see it?
This is crazy.
Babe, look at me.
Don't move.
Stay here as still as you can.
Can you do that?
You think this will work?
Absolutely.
I wouldn't eat a cheeseburger
with its wrapping on.
But of course...
I'm not a shark.
Here.
Yeah.
Look...
you don't know me...
- but when Tina came to Singapore--
- I don't want to know about it.
Well, you should.
We were never--
The whole time she was there...
she missed you.
It wasn't your fault--
what happened.
That's what she said.
Hey, I found some water.
Good?
You come back, okay?
Just come back.
Ready?
Here you go.
Oh, shit.
Oh, man, he's not gonna make it.
He did it.
- He did it.
- Where is he, Josh?
No!
No.
Fuck it. No!
Hey... are you okay?
Look,
we've got to try to keep it together.
Okay?
I know. I just
When's it gonna end?
And why is this happening?
Why?
When my mom was dying--
she died two years ago--
she was so sick.
I tried.
A couple of months
before she died, I left.
I couldn't take it.
I just took off to America.
And...
I wasn't there
when...
So this is my payback.
Life saying, "Screw you.
How are you gonna
run away from this?"
Here.
There's a secret to it.
You have to do it gently.
Just peel the two
pieces of plastic apart
Iike that.
Thanks.
Was she a friend of yours
the girl that got killed?
Julie?
No, not really.
I mean, I knew her
and everything, but
It was just supposed
to be me, you know?
A quick in and out.
Nobody else, just me.
I guess it's true what they say
"Let the devil take your hand
and God will make you pay."
We're not gonna make it
out of here, are we?
I don't believe that.
No.
We'll make it out of here.
Good.
Oh, shit, it's working.
It's working.
Go now.
Go, go now, now.
Come on, go, go, go.
Fuck! Swim!
- Swim!
- Climb! Just climb!
Sorry, Bully.
- Fuck!
Stay back!
Bully! Bully!
Fuck!
You need to
slide it through...
not fling it.
It's strong, but it can't
take much weight.
Screw this.
I'm out of here.
If you can get through,
you get help and bring them back.
Yeah, yeah, all right, all right.
- Ready?
- Let's go.
Got it?
- Pull him up!
- I can make it. I can make it.
- Pull up now.
- I can make it. I'm okay.
Give me your hand.
Are you gonna talk to me
or what?
No.
- Heather, I didn't.
- Don't.
Don't even try.
Murderer.
I'm not a murderer.
Oh, yes, you are.
You're a dog murderer,
which is worse than a person murderer.
How could you?
Heather, I didn't have a choice.
Bullshit.
You always have a choice.
Murderer.
Whatever.
Argh!
Uh!
Hey. Hey.
Can that pipe hold my weight?
I can't get out this way.
I want to get to that door.
What do you think?
I don't know.
Give it a go.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Can you see it anywhere?
I don't know.
You're the one with the bloody torch.
Shit.
Are you okay?
Whew.
Ooh, Jesus.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
Good stuff.
Keep going.
Is he gonna make it?
Babe, shut up.
Shit.
You're good. You got,
like, six feet. Keep going.
Oh, shit.
Hold on.
Grab on. Grab on.
Shit.
Swim, swim, swim.
Quick, quick.
- Quick.
- Got you, buddy.
Kyle! No!
- Quick, quick.
- Give me your hand.
Give me your hand!
We're not gonna just
sit around and wait for that thing
to pick us off one by one.
And what do you think
you're gonna do?
At the very least, I'm gonna die
on my own terms
and not when that damn fish
decides it's time.
So you think what?
You're gonna catch it?
Why not?
What are you gonna do if you catch it?
Spark up the barbie
and crack open the tartare sauce?
I'm gonna tie it to this shelf
and we're gonna swim like hell
to the entrance.
Get the hell out of here.
All I need isa hook.
You can't save everybody, mate.
You must be getting used
to that by now.
It's not that far.
If we can distract the shark,
I'll swim it,
get the hooks.
I'll do it.
What? Dad, no.
Oh, you can't, not with your leg.
My leg is exactly why I should go.
Dad, no, please.
You keep my daughter safe.
No matter what happens,
you get her out of here, okay?
Jaimie!
Jaimie! Jaimie!
Naomi, make noise,
get the shark to come toward us.
Hurry, quick, make some noise!
Jaimes, are you okay?
Yeah.
Okay, hang on.
Jump!
Good work, kid.
So what's the deal?
Do you know her
or just want to?
I used to.
Used to, huh?
'Cause I can see by that look in your eye,
whatever was there, still is.
That was a long time ago.
Trust me,
after this shit here,
everything we knew
is a long time ago.
You still wear that.
Yeah.
- Tina
- You don't have to.
- We don't have to do this, Josh.
- No, I do.
I wasn't fair to you.
I just..
I always set the buoy.
Rory did it for me that day.
But I should have been
the one out there.
Josh.
And I hated myself.
But...
before I knew
what had happened,
everything just...
slipped away.
And I'm sorry.
I just wanted to say that.
I'm sorry.
The thing is, Josh...
you never had to say sorry to me.
All you had to do
was say it to yourself.
I would have been there.
Hey, you all secure
down there?
Yeah.
Why didn't it take it?
Well, if you ask me,
I think it's pretty obvious.
After the past couple of hours,
it's decided it prefers live bait.
That's not funny.
Do I look like I'm joking?
Get down!
You stay back.
Stay back!
I saved this last bullet for you, Doyle.
- You son of a bitch.
- You.
What about the mask on the body?
Wasn't me, mate.
Now, how about
we get ourselves a shark?
It really is a pretty good idea.
We just need better bait.
And this looks pretty tasty, eh, Doyle?
Kirby, listen to me.
You don't want to do this.
Don't l?
No.
What you did earlier
doesn't matter right now.
So you let her go and
we can work something out.
Shut up, cop.
Don't bullshit me.
I shot someone.
That's not going away.
Now, I'm getting out of here
and I'm catching this fucking shark.
And whatever happens...
happens.
- Get in there!
- Josh, no.
- Anyone thinks about touching her,
you go in too.
Naomi, here.
You're okay. Okay.
So you want to help?
You think it needs live bait?
Well...
Let's give it what it wants.
Oh, my God.
It's worked.
Now let's get out of here.
I don't think anyone's coming for us.
I think if they were,
they'd be here by now.
I don't know.
Maybe they're trying
and they're just dealing
with the same shit we are.
- Bully?
Bully!
Oh, float over.
No, don't. No.
- Come on, Bully.
- Baby, swim.
Grab him quick.
Yay. Bully.
It's a sign.
I know it is.
Yay.
You're a good boy.
Get up.
It's okay, sweetheart.
Come on.
- What are you doing?
- I don't know. Call it a sign.
What is that?
It's Ryan.
Oh, my God, it's Ryan.
I have to go get him.
Jaimie, no. Jaimes.
Go after her, please.
Josh.
I'll be back soon.
He's down there.
I know he is.
Wait here.
Is he there?
Did you see anyone?
All right, give mea hand.
We have to close this door,
so that when we open
the one downstairs,
we don't flood the car park.
- Jaimie!
- Ryan!
- There's a shark. Get out of the water.
- Quick, quick! Go, go!
Go, quick!
Give me your hand!
Come on.
Josh!
Come on!
It's Dad's car.
There's a gun.
- What?
- There's a gun in the back.
Go to the other side.
Get the shark to come to you.
Hurry! Come on!
Hurry, quick!
Josh, quick! Josh!
Come on, quick.
Come on.
No go this side.
Make sure everyone's
out of the water, okay?
- Dad.
- Jaimes?
Jaimie!
Get everyone behind the ramp
and out of the water.
You know what you're doing?
I'm gonna hook this up
and I'm gonna blow us
a way out of here.
Hold on!
Is everyone okay?
Yeah.
- Tina!
- Josh!
Shit.
Get out of the water!
Hit it.
Josh.
What are we gonna do now?
Start over.
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.podnapisi.net