I got nothing, Sir.
No sign of Niobe or Ghost.
Nothin' but blue pills.
Should we jack in and try to contact them?
It won't matter, my gut says they're down.
Then we should start back. No, if that ship can still fly, we need it.
I was afraid you were gonna say that.
Search every pipe, every hole, every crack we know. Sweep as wide as possible...
...as fast as possible.
Captain, these lines are crawling with calamari.
The sooner we find them, the better.
Thought you could use something to eat
Thank you
Any change?
No.
How's he? He's gonna be fine.
At least until he wakes up.
What do you mean?
Captain has some questions for him.
He had better have some good answers.
You see these cuts?
I think they're self-inflicted.
Why? VDTs maybe.
I don't know.
But like I said...
The answer had better be good.
Roland, I'd like to run another search through the Matrix.
For what?
For Neo.
How can he be in the Matrix, Sir? He's not plugged in.
Please, for me.
This is what keeps bothering me. What?
His neural patterns don't read like someone who's in a coma.
The strange thing is, I see these patterns all the time.
Where?
On someone jacked in.
A big bubkis, nada.
He's not in there.
Sir, I got the projections. How long?
Based on the point of entry and the past speed, it looks...
...like the machines will be in Zion in just 20 hours.
Jesus H. Christ.
Alright lets move with a purpose.
AK get upstairs, I want you on holographics.
Mauser, I want forward and aft guns manned at all times.
Make sure we're running on as few pads as possible.
Yes, Sir.
Hey! Hey!
You got a call!
Operator.
It's Seraph.
I bring word from the Oracle.
You must come at once.
Good morning.
Who are you?
My name is Sati. Your name is Neo.
My papa says you're not supposed to be here.
He says you must be lost. Are you lost Neo?
Where am I?
This is the train station.
But this isn't the Matrix?
That's where the train goes, that's where we're going.
But you cannot go with us.
Why not?
He won't let you.
Who won't?
The Trainman, I don't like him...
...but my papa says we have to do what the Trainman says.
Or else he will leave us here for ever and ever.
Morpheus, Trinity.
Thank you for coming.
One thing I've learned in all my years...
...is that nothing ever works out just the way we want it to.
Who are you?
I'm the Oracle.
I wish there was an easier way to get through this but there ain't.
I'm sorry this had to happen.
I'm sorry I couldn't be sitting here like you remember me.
But it wasn't meant to be.
What happened?
I made a choice. And that choice cost me more...
...than I wanted it to.
What choice?
To help you, to guide Neo.
Now, since the real test for any choice...
...is having to make the same choice again...
...knowing full well what it might cost...
...I guess I feel pretty good about that choice...
...'cause here I am, at it again.
Do you know what happened to Neo?
Yes.
He's trapped in a place between this world and the machine world.
The link is controlled by a program called the Trainman.
He used to smuggle programs in and out of the Matrix.
If he finds out where Neo is before you get to him...
...then I'm afraid our choices are going to become difficult.
Why?
Because of who the Trainman works for.
The Merovingian.
He's placed a bounty on your lives. You must be careful at all times.
Seraph knows how to find the Trainman, he'll go with you.
For years he has protected me.
I hope he can do the same for you.
Please, follow me.
Oracle.
I know Morpheus.
I can see you're filled with doubt, clouded by uncertainty.
After everything that has happened...
How can you expect me to believe you?
I don't.
I expect just what I've always expected.
For you to make up your own damn mind.
Believe me or don't.
All I can do is to tell you that your friend is in trouble...
...and he needs your help.
He needs all our help.
Are you from the Matrix?
Yes. No.
I mean I was.
Why did you leave?
I had to. I had to leave my home too.
Sati, come here darling.
Leave the poor man in peace.
Yes papa.
I am sorry, she's still very curious.
I know you. Yes, in the restaurant of the Frenchman.
I'm Rama-Kandra. This is my wife Kamala.
My daughter Sati.
We are most honoured to meet you.
You are programs.
Oh yes! I'm the power plant systems manager for recycling operations.
My wife is an interactive software programmer. She's highly creative.
What are you doing here? You do not belong here.
Kamala! Goodness, I apologize.
My wife can be very direct.
It's ok.
I don't have an answer.
I don't even know where 'here' is.
This place is nowhere.
It is between your world and our world.
Who's the Trainman? He works for the Frenchman.
Why did I know you were going to say that...
The Frenchman does not forget.
And he does not forgive.
You know him? I know only what I need to know.
I know that if you want to take something from our world into your world...
...that does not belong there, you must go to the Frenchman.
Is that what you are doing here?
Rama, please! I do not want to be cruel Kamala.
He may never see another face for the rest of his life.
I'm sorry.
You don't have to answer that question.
No, I don't mind.
The answer is simple.
I love my daughter very much.
I find her to be the most beautiful thing I've ever seen.
But where we're from that is not enough.
Every program that is created must have a purpose.
If it does not, it is deleted.
I went to the Frenchman to save my daughter.
You do not understand? I just have never...
Heard a program speak of love.
It's a human emotion.
No, it's a word.
What matters is the connection the word implies.
I see that you are in love.
Can you tell me what you would give to hold on to that connection?
Anything.
Then perhaps the reason you're here, isn't so different from the reason I'm here.
That's him.
Get away! Get away from me!
We don't want trouble.
Get the hell away from me! We need your help.
I can't help you. No one can help you.
Oh, no.
Damn it.
When is the train due?
It's already late.
It's not like the Trainman to be late.
You think it has something to do with me?
I cannot say. Who knows such thing?
Only the Oracle. You know the Oracle?
Everyone knows the Oracle.
I consulted with her before i met with the Frenchman.
She promised she would look after Sati after we said goodbye.
Goodbye?
You're not staying with her?
It is not possible.
Our arrangement with the Frenchman was for our daughter only.
My wife and I must return to our world.
Why?
That is our karma.
You believe in karma?
Karma is a word, like love.
A way of saying 'what I'm here to do'.
I do not resent my karma.
I'm grateful for it, grateful for my wonderful wife, for my beautiful daughter.
They are gifts. And so I do what I must do to honour them.
Papa, the train! Yes! Find your bag!
Quickly!
Can I carry that for you?
All right.
Hurry it up! I'm late!
Who are you? He is a friend.
Rama! I know you.
So that's what they wanted.
I need to get back.
I'll pay you whatever you want.
One way or another I'm getting on this train.
Oh no, no, no, no, no.
You're gonna stay right here until the Merovingian says different.
If I know him, you're gonna be here for a long, long time.
I don't wanna hurt you.
You don't get it. I built this place.
Down here I make the rules. Down here I make the threats.
Down here, I'm God.
Get on the train or you're gonna stay here with him.
We should return to the Oracle. She will know what to do.
No.
We know what has to be done.
Shit!
You gotta be kidding.
Holy shit. It's wingless.
I get it. You must be ready to die.
I need to speak with him.
Only way you're getting through this door...
...is over my big dead ass.
So be it.
There are no weapons allowed in the club.
At the bottom of this elevator there is a coat-check girl.
And if we're lucky, one man for checking weapons.
And if we're unlucky?
There will be many men.
Can I take your...? Oh my God.
What in the hell?
I don't believe this.
Hey!
The prodigal child returns. L' ange sans ailes. (The angel without wings)
Are you here for the bounty, Seraph?
Tell me, how many bullets are there in those guns?
I don't know, but I don't think you have enough.
We only want to talk. Oh, yes.
I'm sure you do. You have fought through hell to do so.
Yes. I'll tell you what I'll do.
Put down the guns and I will promise you a safe passage out of here.
All three of us. Oh, yes, yes...
Of course.
Quelle bonne surpris, n'est-ce pas? (what a good surprise, isn't it?)
Who could have guessed we would all be seeing each other so soon...
...after our last meeting? A fate too kind.
And since you, my little Judas have brought them here...
...I can only surmise the fortune teller has found herself another shell.
Disappointing.
But not unexpected.
I do hope, however, she has the good manners to learn her lesson.
And to remember there is no action without consequence.
And if you take something from me...
...you will pay the price.
You know why we are here?
Come now, what kind of question is this? Of course I know. It's my business to know.
Some might think this is a strange coincidence, but I do not.
I'm curious, though, as to...
...how it actually happened.
Do you know? No.
No?
I did not think so.
But it is always best to ask.
We want to make a deal.
Always straight to business. Uh, Morpheus? Ok.
I have something you want.
To make a deal, you must have something I want.
Yes?
And it so happens there is something I want.
Something I have wanted ever since I first came here.
It is said they cannot be taken.
they can only be given.
What?
The eyes of the Oracle.
I have told you before, there's no escaping the nature of the universe.
It is that nature that has again brought you to me.
Where some see coincidence, I see consequence.
Where others see chance, I see...
...cost.
Bring me the eyes of the Oracle.
And I will give you back your saviour.
It seems a particularly fair and reasonable deal to me.
Yes? No?
I don't have time for this shit.
You wanna make a deal? How about this?
You give me Neo, or we all die right here, right now.
Interesting deal.
You are really ready to die for this man?
Believe it.
She'll do it. If she has to she'll kill every one of us.
She's in love. It's remarkable how similar...
...the pattern of love is...
...to the pattern of insanity.
Time's up.
What's it gonna be Merv?
Ok, you got yourself in here.
You can get yourself out.
Are you ready for us?
Almost, Sir. They got some pretty ancient hacks here, we're working on it.
Did you find Neo?
Can't you see him? No, Sir.
We were reading something but I couldn't tell what it was.
I can't leave yet.
I have to see her.
Now?
It's my last chance.
That's it, that's the secret.
You've got to use your hands. Why?
Cookies need love, like everything does.
Neo.
I was hoping to have these done before you got here.
Oh, well. Sati, honey...
...I think it's time for a tasting.
Take the bowl to Seraph and find out if they're ready.
Ok.
I'm glad you got out. Me too.
So...
Do you recognize me? A part of you.
Yeah, that's how it works.
Some bits you lose, some bits you keep.
I don't yet recognize my face in the mirror, but...
...I still love candy.
No, thank you.
Remember what you were like when you first walked through my door?
Jittery as a june bug.
And now just look at you.
You sure did surprise me, Neo. And you still do.
You gave me a few surprises too.
I hope I helped.
You helped me to get here, but my question's why.
Where is this going?
Where does it end?
I don't know. You don't know, or you won't tell me?
I told you before...
no one can see beyond a choice they don't understand.
And I mean no one.
What choice?
It doesn't matter.
It's my choice. I have mine to make, the same as you have yours.
Does that include what things to tell me and what not to tell me?
Of course not.
Then why didn't you tell me about the architect?
Why didn't you tell me about Zion, the Ones before me?
Why didn't you tell me the truth?
Because it wasn't time for you to know.
Who decided it wasn't time?
You know who.
KNOW THYSELF
I did.
Then I think it's time for me to know a few more things.
So do I.
Tell me how I separated my mind from my body without jacking in.
Tell me how I stopped four sentinels by thinking it.
Tell me just what the hell is happening to me.
The power of the One extends beyond this world.
It reaches from here all the way back to where it came from.
Where?
The Source, that's what you felt when you touched those sentinels.
But you weren't ready for it.
You should be dead.
But apparently you weren't ready for that either.
The architect told me that if I didn't return to the Source...
...Zion would be destroyed by midnight tonight.
Please...
You and I may not be able to see beyond our own choices...
...but that man can't see past any choice.
Why not? He doesn't understand them. He can't.
To him they're variables in an equation.
One at a time each variable must be solved and countered. That's his purpose.
To balance the equation.
What's your purpose?
To unbalance it.
Why?
What do you want?
I want the same thing you want Neo.
And I'm willing to go as far as you are to get it.
The end of the war.
Is it going to end?
One way or another.
Can Zion be saved?
I'm sorry I don't have the answer to that question, but...
If there's an answer...
...there's only one place you're going to find it.
Where?
You know where.
And if you can't find the answer...
...then I'm afraid there may be no tomorrow for any of us.
What does that mean?
Everything that has a beginning...
...has an end.
I see the end coming.
I see the darkness spreading.
I see death.
And you are all that stands in his way.
Smith. Very soon...
...he's going to have the power to destroy this world.
But I believe he won't stop there, he can't.
He won't stop until there's nothing left at all.
What is he? He is you.
Your opposite. Your negative.
The result of the equation trying to balance itself out.
And if I can't stop him?
One way or another, Neo...
...this war is going to end.
Tonight, the future of both worlds will be in your hands or in his.
How are you feeling?
Are you alright?
I need time.
That figures. Captain Roland.
What's up Maggie? Bane is. He's conscious.
Good. Maybe he's got some answers.
I love that smell.
I sure am gonna miss it.
Oracle. I know, I know.
Sati, honey...
Take a few cookies and go with Seraph. Can I come back? I would like to come back.
I would like that too. Then I'll see you tomorrow.
I hope so honey, I hope so.
I'm scared Seraph.
Come.
He's following us.
Well, well, it's been a long time.
I remember chasing you was like chasing a ghost. I have beaten you before.
Yes, true, but as you can see, things are a little different now.
And you must be the last exile. The Oracle told me about you.
Really?
What did she say about me? That you're a bad man.
Oh, I'm not so bad...
...once you get to know me.
The great and powerful Oracle, we meet at last.
I suppose you've been expecting me. Right?
The all-knowing Oracle is never surprised. How can she be? she knows everything.
But if that's true, then why is she here?
If she knew I was coming, why wouldn't she leave?
Maybe you knew I was going to do that, maybe you didn't.
If you did, that means you baked those cookies and...
...set that plate right there deliberately, purposefully.
Which means that you're sitting there also deliberately, purposefully.
What did you do with Sati?
Cookies need love, like everything does.
You are a bastard.
You would know Mom.
Do what you are here to do.
Yes ma'am.
I really wish I could help, I just...
I don't remember any of it.
What about the cuts on your arms?
Those cuts are more than one day old.
Yeah, definitely.
You're right about that, Sir.
They look like they might be self-inflicted.
But, why would I do something like that to myself?
Unless of course I wasn't myself.
But if I'm not me, then who am I?
Has this man been tested for VDTs? Yes sir, it was negative.
But he's showing a lot of unusual neural activity.
Some cross-synaptic firing, as well as signs of recent trauma...
...with fresh fibrotic scarring throughout the cortex.
I want the truth, I don't care what it takes. Make him remember.
Sir, we found her! The Logos?
Yes sir. 'Bout time we had some goddamn good news.
Are the thermals picking up any signs of life?
No sir. Nothing yet.
What about the ship? Holographic says the hull's intact.
Drop her down, and keep a man in the rear turret.
Yes, Sir.
Get a full diagnostic on that ship as fast as humanly possible.
Careful sir, the squids are sneaky bastards.
Could be a trap.
What was that?
You can put that shit away boys, all she needs is a jump.
Niobe.
Morpheus.
Are you alright? Yes, I'm fine.
We didn't know what happened after...
I'm sorry.
It's ok...
I'm happy to see you too.
Did you get Neo out? Yes.
How did you know about that? The Oracle.
You saw her? Just before the Sentinels found us.
What did she tell you?
The same things she always does.
Exactly what I needed to hear.
In less than 12 hours the machines will breach the dock walls.
Every simulation we've run, we've seen that once the machines are inside the city...
...the odds of our survival decrease dramatically.
Thus our primary objective must be to destroy...
...or disable the diggers inside the dock.
If we can do that, perhaps we can prevent them from ever reaching the city.
If not, the only place we would be able to mount an...
...effective defense would be at the entrance of the Temple.
It's small enough that it would force them into a bottleneck...
...allowing us to concentrate the remainder of our defense.
We understand that you've requested additional volunteers.
That is correct.
Precisely what size of force are you planning...
...to commit to the primary dock objective?
Right now, the entire APU Corps and half the infantry.
Half the infantry? If it were up to me Councillor...
I'd take every man, woman and child, put a gun in...
...their hand and march them straight into that dock.
Perhaps it is best that it is not up to you.
Time will tell, Councillor.
Commander, just one more question.
Has there been word from the Nebuchadnezzar? None.
And at this point there's no reason to expect there ever will be.
Perhaps.
But we can hope.
I'm afraid hope is an indulgence I don't have time for.
Zee, what are you doing?
Making shells.
They're evacuating our level, we have to go.
I'm not going with you. What?
They've called for volunteers to hold the dock.
Kids, you stay here.
I know how you feel, Zee, but you can't do this.
I have to. Why?
Because I love him.
I love him the same as he loves me.
And if I were out there and he were here I know what he'd do.
But you're gonna get yourself killed.
It's crazy Zee.
Maybe it is.
But ask yourself, if it were Dozer, you knew the only...
...chance you had to see him again was to hold the dock.
What would you do?
Make shells.
What the shit is going on over here?
An accident, sir.
I didn't see, sorry.
Who the hell are you? A unit volunteer sir.
What's a pod-born pencil-neck like you doing volunteering for my corps?
I wanna do my part, sir!
We gotta hold the dock.
How old are you, kid?
Eighteen. Should have said sixteen, I might have believed that!
Ok, I'm sixteen. Minimum age for the corps is 18.
Sixteen's too young.
Machines don't care how old I am. They'll kill me just the same.
Ain't that the goddamned truth.
Give me a chance, Sir.
I won't let you down.
You do, and you'll find me and the machines have got something in common.
Ok, charge the igniter.
She lives again.
You want us to patch an uplink to reload the operations software, Sparky?
Yeah, that'd be swell. Could you clean the windshield while you're at it?
Uplinks are in place, I'm bringing her back online.
Looking good, except uh...
Something's wrong with the Matrix feed.
No there's not.
You're looking at what we're looking at.
What the hell is going on in there?
Whatever it is, it can't be good.
The machines have taken Junction 21.
The way I see it, if we drop down from broadcast here...
...at Interstate 153, we might surprise them.
We'll go first, hammer as deep as we can, then blow our EMP.
Hopefully we can punch a hole big enough for you to get through.
It ain't pretty, but the way I see it, it's the only way back.
No it's not.
There's another way.
A support line.
It drops down right here.
A thousand meters short of 21.
If we're lucky we may be able to slip down without them ever knowing.
That's a mechanical line. It's impossible, no one can pilot a mechanical.
I can.
Bullshit.
I've done it. That was a long time ago, Niobe.
I said I can do it.
So what? If you can you'll be the only one that can.
There's no way we can follow you.
Hi.
I know time is always against us. I'm sorry that I took so long.
But I wanted to be sure. Sure of what?
I know what I have to do. What?
There's no easy way to say this, so I'll just say it.
I have to take one of the ships.
What? To go where?
To the machine city.
I know it's difficult to understand.
No, It's not, you're out of your goddamn mind.
I still have to go. You'll never make it. In 100 years...
...no ship has been within a hundred kilometers of it.
You'll never make it. I have to try.
Is this what the Oracle has told you?
No.
This is asinine. If you wanna kill yourself, go do it.
But do it without wasting one of our ships.
You have to believe me, I have to go.
Bullshit!
I am the captain of this ship, I say where it has to go!
And believe me, this ship will go to hell long before I let you take it anywhere.
He can take mine.
You can't do that.
Don't even think of trying to tell me what I can...
...or cannot do with my ship after that little speech.
But for Christ sake, Niobe. I'll pilot this ship, he can take mine.
If we leave inside the hour we should reach Zion as the machines do.
That's as good a plan as any.
It's a waste. A Goddamn waste.
Two ships, two directions.
Sounds like providence, doesn't it Morpheus?
You've never believed in The One.
I still don't. Then why are you doing this?
I believe in him.
Thank you.
What's that for? To help you relax.
Make it easier for you to remember.
What if i don't want to remember?
Why would you want that?
What if I blew that EMP?
What if I did destroy those ships and I am responsible...
...for the deaths of all those men?
If I did that, it wouldn't be very safe for me here.
Would it?
Of course it might not be very safe for you, either.
I'm ready.
Trinity.
There's something I have to say.
There's something you need to understand.
I know I'm supposed to go.
But beyond that... I don't know I...
I know. You don't think you're coming back.
I knew it the moment you said you had to leave.
I could see it in your face.
Just like you knew the moment you looked at me...
...that I was coming with you.
I'm scared Trin. So am I.
It took me ten minutes to buckle up one boot.
But I'll tell you something. Six hours ago...
...I told the Merovingian I was ready...
...to give anything and everything for you.
You know what's changed in the last 6 hours?
No.
Nothing.
Have you finished loading that amunition? Just about, sir.
Lets move it, we're out of time.
You're not leaving them anything?
He said he didn't need it.
I ain't saying goodbye, I'm saying good luck.
Thank you.
I can only hope you know what you're doing.
Me too.
It was an honour, Sir.
No, the honour's still mine.
We're ready sir.
'Bout damn time.
We're already late Captain, so lets hit it and hit it hard.
Bye baby, take good care of them.
Ready?
Engine's still firing.
Must be a fuse, I'll check it out.
I should've known he'd send his bitch first.
Bane!
No one ever got away from me as many times as you did.
Every single time I thought it was the last.
Everytime I was sure we had you, but somehow you'd slip through our fingers.
I really can't express just how aggravating that can be.
What are you talking about?
I think I might enjoy killing you as much as killing him.
Neo, it's Bane, he's psychotic!
You're gonna pay for that.
27 kilometers to go.
Captain, we got an emergency down here. What is it AK?
It's Maggie, sir.
She's dead.
Murdered. I think it was Bane. Goddamn it.
I knew it. I knew he was out of his goddamn mind.
He fired that EMP. God damn it, I should have beaten it out of him.
We've searched the whole ship Captain.
He ain't here.
I know where he is. The Logos.
We gotta go back. Too late.
You don't know that, what if they need our help?
It's too dangerous. Why?
Because if he's killed them, he will control another EMP.
At this point they're on their own.
Just like us.
Mr. Anderson...
I see you're as predictable in this world as you are in the other.
What? He's out of his mind.
It might appear that way to you, but Mr. Anderson...
...and I know that appearances can be deceiving.
Confused, Mr. Anderson?
It'll all become clear in a moment.
Now, thank you for bringing me the gun. You can set it down right there.
Don't do it.
Shoot, shoot now.
Yes, shoot. Fry us. Burn us alive!
Do it! If you don't he'll kill us both.
Look at him. He knows he should do it, but he won't.
He can't. Do it.
Back away from the gun and turn around.
Let her go.
Somehow familiar, isn't it?
We've been here before, you and I, remember?
I do
I think of nothing else
Who are you? Still don't recognize me?
I admit, it's difficult to even think, encased in this rotting piece of meat.
The stink of it filling every breath, a suffocating cloud you can't escape.
Disgusting.
Look at how pathetically fragile it is.
Nothing this weak is meant to survive.
What do you want?
I want what you want.
Yes...
That's it Mr. Anderson.
Look past the flesh, look through the soft gelatin...
...of these dull cow eyes, and see your enemy.
No.
Oh, yes, Mr. Anderson.
It can't be.
There's nowhere I can't go, there's nowhere I won't find you.
It's impossible.
Not impossible.
Inevitable.
Goodbye Mr. Anderson.
This is it, it's gotta be.
Oh no!
I wish you could see yourself Mr. Anderson.
The blind messiah.
You're a symbol for all of your kind, Mr. Anderson.
Helpless.
Pathetic.
Just waiting to be put out of your misery.
I can see you.
It's not over Mr. Anderson, it's not over.
Trinity! Neo.
Oh, no.
Your eyes.
I'll be ok.
It's alright Trin.
But I think you're gonna have to drive.
Seismic's projecting 22 minutes to breach.
They can't know we don't have an EMP. They'll have to attack in waves.
Concentrate our offense on the diggers.
Order the APUs into position.
Yes, sir.
Come on, move.
All right.
This is it.
Now, you all know me,
so I'll just say this as simple as I can.
If it's our time to die, it's our time.
All I ask is: if we have to give these bastards our lives...
...we give them hell before we do!
You scared, Charra?
Shit, yeah.
But I'll make you a deal.
You keep loadin', I keep shootin'.
Deal.
Holy Christ, would you look at that? Quiet.
How far is the opening? 1.4 kilometers
We're still generating too hot a field.
Ghost, kill all auxilliary systems.
Give me full manual, drop down four pads.
It'll bottom out!
Easy baby.
700 meters.
If we can just get close enough.
600 meters.
There.
Shit.
Jig's up, here they come. Give me full power, full systems!
Man the gun turrets! every goddamn one of them.
Go, go! Ghost, you're the best gunner we have, go with them.
Morpheus take his place.
I'm coming baby.
Here they come.
Slow down, this ain't the Logos! Hold on to your lunch, Roland, here we go.
Holy Christ, I didn't know this ship could do that.
Breach! The dock is breached!
Knuckle up!
For Zion!
Shit.
Come on, let's go!
Knuckle up!
Reload!
Reload nine!
Go, go! Move, move!
Watch your left!
Don't let them through!
Zuka!
Oh my God.
Where the hell is my infantry?
I want that goddamn machine taken down!
Dig this.
Oh, shit!
Bogey two at the breach point! Goddamnit.
Shit, she's got a fat ass!
Keep 'em off me. Goddamn, there's a shitstorm of 'em.
Captain, do you see that? They're after the radio, stop 'em.
Damn it.
Yeah.
Grab my belt.
Just give me one clean shot.
Damn it!
Charra!
Commander Lock, I've got incoming!
I've got a dock full of incoming! Sir, yes Sir, but this is different, Sir.
What? I think it's one of ours.
That's impossible. Holographics are trying to confirm, Sir.
Contact them, I want access codes. We're trying Sir, there's no response.
It's a trick. That's not one of ours, it can't be.
That's a mechanical line, no one can pilot mechanical.
Foreward aft, 30 degrees at 80 percent.
30 degrees, 80.
Lower starboard, 60 degrees, 20 percent. 60 degrees.
Shit!
Come on, keep up! I'm trying!
Sir, holographic confirms.
It's the Hammer Sir.
How can that be?
The ship is under attack, sustaining heavy damage.
But at its present velocity it'll reach Gate 3 in 12 minutes.
Sir, their EMP could take out every sentinel up there.
It'd take out more than that.
It'll wipe out our entire defense system.
We blow an EMP inside, we will lose the dock.
Sir, we've already lost the dock.
Open the gate.
Gate 3 is not responding!
It's taken critical damage, Sir!
We've lost control!
We can't open it!
There's the exit. On my mark, give me full power.
90 degrees to lower-left starboard.
Full power.
90 degrees.
Now!
Hold on, baby!
Goddamn woman, you can drive!
We ain't home yet. What about the Gate?
The sentinels are inside the dock.
Are we too late?
How many APUs are operational? Thirteen, Sir.
Get me the one closest to Gate 3.
Reload!
He's pissin' metal.
Go!
Heads up, they're coming around!!
Behind you!
It's jammed!
Forget it, Kid! Get outta here!
Got it!
Captain Mifune!
No.
They're coming.
They're coming. The Hammer.
What?
You have to open that gate.
Cut the counterweights.
You can do it.
Hurry, there's no time.
Captain. I didn't finish the training program.
Neither did I.
Lock that down.
Kill the feeder.
We won't make it. we gotta blow the EMP now.
Come on, someone, please!
Keep the weight forward.
Light as a feather, light as a feather.
Commander, holographics reports Captain Mifune's APU is up and moving to Gate 3.
Don't oversqueeze the trigger.
Captain Mifune's APU just reached Gate 3.
How much time? Two minutes to impact.
Captain Mifune, do you copy?
His radio is down, Sir.
Mifune...
This is Lock.
I don't know if you can hear me, but if you can...
...the Hammer is two minutes away.
You got two minutes, Captain...
...to get that Gate open.
Link!
Get to the main deck! Charge the EMP!
Do it, Kid.
Neo, I believe.
Yes.
Can we make it?
We ain't come this far.
Almost home.
Burn it Link!
You did it.
No, we did it.
You're a hell of a pilot.
Some things in this world never change.
But some things do?
Luckily, some things do.
Link!
Zee?
Link? Zee!
I knew you'd come. I knew it.
I made a promise.
You did wear it.
Are you kidding? I'm never gonna take it off.
Three captains, one ship
I'll assume the other ships were lost under equally pointless circumstances
It's good to see you too, Jason
The council is waiting to hear your explanation
You would forgive me for not attending but I have to try to salvage this debacle
Did I miss something, commander? I thought we'd just saved the dock.
That's the problem with you people.
You can't think for five minutes in front of your face.
The EMP knocked out almost every piece of hardware and every APU.
If I were the machines, I would send every sentinel I had here right now
Saved the dock, Captain? You've just handed it to them on a silver platter
Come on, get it cut!
The bridge is clear
Do you hear that?
Get that cable run
I want the system back online.
Commander, it's the dock. We've got incoming.
Order everyone to fall back.
Seal all the shaft. Now!
Move it!
Oh my God!
All clear
Do it!
Go! Go!
Your move!
So you gave them your ship.
That is correct, Councillor, I did.
Knowing what he planned to do with it?
And the Oracle said nothing of this?
She told me that Neo would need my help and when the time came...
...I would choose to help him or not.
But what hope can a single vessel have against their entire defense system?
None, it's completely impossible.
But he wouldn't listen.
He wouldn't even take any ammunition. He was totally out of his goddamn mind.
No, he wasn't.
Neo is doing what he believes he must do.
I don't know if what he's doing is right.
I don't know if he'll reach the machine city.
And if he does, I don't know what he can do to save us.
But I do know that as long as there's single breath in his body...
...he will not give up.
And neither can we.
Temperature's dropping.
Here we go.
We're over the fields, aren't we?
How do you know that?
I can feel them.
Over there.
There is our path, can you see it?
Three lines. Power lines.
Follow them.
What are they doing?
I don't know.
Lieutenant!
Goddamn it!
What do we do now, Commander?
It's now a matter of time.
Machines will breach the walls of the city.
I recommend that the Council join the rest of the non-military personnel inside the Temple.
How long do we have?
Two hours, maybe less.
My men have begun fortifying the entrance with enough artillery to make our last stand.
Beyond that there isn't anything more I can do.
Commander, do you think that we have any chance of surviving?
If I were you, Councillor, I wouldn't ask me that question.
I would ask him.
Why?
Because he's the one who believes in miracles.
There, those mountains.
That's it.
Do you see what's out there? Yes.
If you tell me we'll make it I'll believe you.
We'll make it.
We have to.
Sentinels!
There's too many.
Gotcha!
Come on, Neo, I need help here!
I can't beat them.
What'll we do? Go up!
Over them. What?
The sky.
It's the only way.
Then up we go.
Beautiful.
Pump the igniter, the ship will start.
Again!
Slowly.
Now!
Trin?
Trinity?
Trinity?!
I'm here. Where?
Here.
We made it.
You said we would.
It's unbelievable Trin.
Light everywhere.
Like the whole thing was built of light.
I wish you could see what I see.
You've already shown me so much.
What is it Trinity? What's wrong?
I can't go with you Neo.
I've gone as far as I can.
What?
Oh, no.
Oh, no, no, no!
It's all right.
It's time.
I've done all that I could do.
Now you have to do the rest.
You have to finish it.
You have to save Zion.
I can't.
Not without you.
Yes you can.
You will.
I believe. I always have.
Trinity.
Trinity. You can't die.
You can't.
Yes, I can.
You brought me back once.
But not this time.
Do you remember...
...on that roof, after you caught me...
...the last thing I said to you?
You said: "I'm sorry".
I wish I hadn't.
That was my last thought.
I wished I had one more chance...
...to say what really mattered.
To say how much I loved you.
How grateful I was for every moment I was with you.
But by the time I knew how to say what I wanted to...
...it was too late.
But you brought me back.
You gave me my wish.
One more chance to say what I really wanted to say.
Kiss me.
Once more.
Get that ammunition where it belongs! You got one chance to get this right.
Get that damn thing mounted.
Hurry. Let's go, let's go!
Neo...
If you're gonna do something, you better do it quick.
I only ask to say what I've come to say.
After that, do what you want, and I won't try to stop you.
Speak!
The program 'Smith' has grown beyond your control.
Soon he will spread through this city as he spread through the Matrix.
You cannot stop him.
But I can.
We don't need you.
We need nothing.
If that's true, then I've made a mistake.
And you should kill me now.
What do you want?
Peace.
What are they doing?
What are you doing!?
Morpheus!
And if you fail?
I won't.
Neo.
He fights for us.
Mr. Anderson, welcome back.
We missed you.
You like what I've done with the place?
It ends tonight.
I know it does. I've seen it.
That's why the rest of me is just going to enjoy the show.
We already know that I'm the one that beats you.
Can you feel it Mr. Anderson?
Closing in on you.
Oh, I can.
I really should thank you for it, after all, it was your life...
...that taught me the purpose of all life.
The purpose of life is to end.
Why Mr. Anderson? Why?
Why?
Why do you do it?
Why? Why get up?
Why keep fighting?
Do you believe you're fighting for something? For more than your survival?
Can you tell me what it is? Do you even know?
Is it freedom or truth?
Perhaps peace? Could it be for love?
Illusions Mr. Anderson, vagaries of perception.
Temporary constructs of a feeble human intellect trying desperately to justify...
...an existance that is without meaning or purpose.
And all of them as artificial as the Matrix itself.
Although, only a human mind could invent something as insipid as love.
You must be able to see it, Mr. Anderson.
You must know it by now!
You can't win, it's pointless to keep fighting!
Why Mr. Anderson?
Why? Why do you persist?
Because I choose to.
This is my world!
My world!
Wait.
I've seen this.
This is it, this is the end.
Yes.
You were laying right there, just like that.
And I... I stand here, right here.
I'm... I'm supposed to say something.
I say...
Everything that has a beginning has an end, Neo.
What?
What did I just say?
No.
No, this isn't right, this can't be right.
Get away from me!
What are you afraid of?
It's a trick!
You were right, Smith.
You were always right.
It was inevitable.
Is it over?
Oh, no, no, no.
No, it's not fair.
It is done.
It doesn't make sense.
He did it.
He saved us.
He did it! He did it!
He did it!
He did it! It's over!
It's over! He did it!
He did it! What is it? What happened?
Sir...
He did it, Sir! Neo! He did it!
Did what? He ended the war!
The machines are gone!!
The war is over, Sir! The war is over!
Zion!
Zion! It's over!
It's over!
The war is over!
I have imagined this moment...
...for so long.
Is this real?
Neo, wherever you are.
Thank you.
Good morning.
Well, now...
...ain't this a surprise?
You played a very dangerous game.
Change always is.
Just how long do you think this peace is going to last?
As long as it can.
What about the others?
What others?
The ones that want out.
Obviously they will be freed.
I have your word?
What do you think I am?
Human?
Oracle!
We were afraid we might not find you. Everything's okay now.
Look! Look! Just look at that!
Beautiful!
Did you do that? For Neo.
That's nice!
I know he'd love it.
Will we ever see him again?
I suspect so.
Someday.
Did you always know?
Oh, no. No I didn't.
But I believed.
I believed.