Here come the wolves.
Uh-oh. Bottleneck.
Mr. Roosevelt
should hear of this.
I'm sorry. Hope you
didn't hurt yourself.
My friend says he's sorry.
Okay.
That just goes
to show you what
a little blonde can do
to hold up
national defense.
Nice, pleasant guy.
Man!
Gee, 100 bucks.
So that's
what they look like.
Where'd he go?
I don't know.
I wonder what his name is.
Wait a minute.
I saw it on the envelope.
Fry. That's it. Fry.
Fry.
How do you know
my name?
What do you care
how I know your name?
I saw it on
one of the envelopes
you dropped.
Here's something
that belongs to you.
The paint shop!
It'll go up
like dynamite!
Here, take this one.
What about me?
Don't I get to play, too?
You get another one.
All right.
So, I see
these two kids, see.
And I yell at them,
"The sprinklers are busted,
"the whole shooting
match will go up."
And they run right in,
the both of them.
And the last thing
I saw when I looked back
was one kid give
the extinguisher
to the other kid,
and then it was just
like all hell comes up.
That's all I see.
Was there
anybody else around?
No. Just the two kids.
The poor kid with
the extinguisher,
and the one who
gave it to him.
Thank you, Rogers.
We appreciate
all you've done.
We needn't keep you
any longer now.
You'd better go
and take care of
those hands.
Who've you got next?
We have a fellow,
Barry Kane, waiting.
Send Barry Kane in!
Barry Kane!
All right.
Just take it easy.
We only want to ask you
a couple of questions,
a matter of
a routine check-up.
Well, I want to do
anything I can to help.
Sure.
Now, suppose you tell us
where you were
when the fire started.
Well, I was one of
the first to rush in.
The sprinkler systems
weren't working.
Who else was with you?
There were just myself,
a fellow named Fry,
and my friend Ken Mason.
Go on.
Fry handed me
an extinguisher,
and I started running
toward the fire.
I gave it to Ken.
And then he...
Okay. Take it easy.
That's all.
Just stick around
for a while.
We may need you.
Send for Fry.
Get hold of
a fellow called Fry.
What'd they do?
Ask you a lot
of questions?
No. Hardly any.
Gee, it's awful tough going,
seeing it happen
in front of you.
Yeah, it is tough.
Ken Mason was your pal,
too, wasn't he?
Yeah.
Was he married?
No. He was living
with his mother.
Must be pretty tough on her.
Sorry, fellows.
I'll see you later.
Hello, Mrs. Mason.
They... They wouldn't
let me see him.
It's awful hard to believe.
It happened so quick.
Why, only this morning...
Please...
Please don't
talk about it now.
Anything I can do?
Could I get you something?
No. No, thank you.
Not now.
Maybe some brandy.
How is the poor,
dear soul?
If you mean Mrs. Mason,
she's feeling bad.
Oh, well,
she has every reason to.
Do you know what?
They wouldn't even
let her see him.
Her only son.
Yes, I know.
I told her
she'd every right to
insist on seeing him.
I told her I would,
and she as good as
told me to get out.
Me that was
only trying to help
the poor, dear soul.
I think you can help,
if you'd tell me where
I could get some brandy.
It doesn't seem to be
in here.
You come with me,
young man.
It just happens that
I have a little
in the house.
Sorry to bother you,
Mrs. Mason,
but we're looking for
a guy named Barry Kane.
Do you know him?
He isn't here
right now, is he?
They told us at the plant
we might be able
to find him here.
Well, what do you
want to see him about?
He's in pretty
bad trouble, lady.
What is it?
I'd like to know.
He was mixed up with
that fire at the factory.
I... I don't understand.
There are a lot of things
we don't understand, either.
But how is Barry
involved in it?
That fire extinguisher.
It seems it wasn't
just an accident.
It turns out that
the extinguisher
Barry Kane handed your son
was filled with gasoline.
You ought to be
able to help us.
Give us a lead
on this guy Kane.
Yeah. That's why we
want to look around.
Well...
Why...
I can't talk about it now.
Yeah. Sorry,
but, you see,
there was a...
I wouldn't give her
too much of that
if I were you,
because it very often
makes people weepy.
I know it affected me
like that...
Yes, Mrs. Moore,
I've got to hurry back.
Thank you very much.
Try some of this, Mrs. Mason.
It'll make you feel better.
There were two
detectives just here.
They were looking for you.
For me?
I guess they want to ask me
some more questions.
I said that I'd do
anything I could to help.
Here. Try, please.
No.
That wasn't it.
They wanted to arrest you.
They said that
the fire extinguisher
that you handed to Kenneth
was filled with gasoline,
that you killed him.
That I killed...
Why, are they crazy?
Why would I want
to do a thing...
Why, Ken was my best friend!
Haven't they talked to Fry?
Haven't they asked him
about the extinguisher?
They said that
there was no such man
employed at the plant as Fry.
Why, I saw him!
I saw him twice!
Ken saw him, too!
He was right there
with us at the fire.
He handed me
the extinguisher. Ken said,
"Don't I get to play, too?"
He was kidding.
I handed it to him.
Fry was right there with us.
I'm sure!
Why, he must have known
there was gasoline in it.
He must have known!
He stood right there
with us and watched, the...
Please go.
Don't you believe me?
Do you think
I had something
to do with this?
I didn't tell
the police anything.
Oh, I don't know!
It's all so confused
and so terrible.
I don't know what
they're talking about!
Why don't they
get this fellow Fry?
You'd better go.
All right, I'll go.
I've got to get Fry.
I've got to find him,
or Ken won't be
the last one to die.
He must be in there.
I saw him go in the back way.
Catchy.
What?
That tune
you're whistling.
Oh, I didn't even know
I was whistling.
That's a sign
you must be pretty happy.
Easy to see there's
nothing on your mind.
Oops. That must
have been Junior.
It felt like him.
Junior?
Yeah, that rock we just got.
I know every one on the road
from Los Angeles to Reno.
Tough job, driving a truck.
Got any other
hot news tonight?
I guess I never realized
how tough it was before.
The tough part,
you can take that.
It's the monotony
that gets you.
I've been thinking
for a long time
I'm gonna get out of
this trucking game.
Why don't you?
One of the neighbors
told my wife
it's stylish to
eat three meals a day.
You married?
Nope.
Go ahead and whistle.
That thing bother you?
What's doing it?
Here, stick
this wad of paper
in there, will you?
It's a pretty good thing
to have around
one of these extinguishers.
I wouldn't be without one.
Now, take the other day.
A big lettuce truck
turns over right down
the road here.
The gasoline catches
and she goes up
like a matchbox.
A fellow riding,
a friend of the driver's,
gets caught in it.
If the driver hadn't
had an extinguisher,
his pal would've
been fried alive
right in front of his eyes.
I didn't see it happen.
I never see anything happen.
I don't even
hear about anything,
except what my wife
tells me what she sees
in the moving pictures.
That's the way
she spends the money,
moving pictures and new hats.
Buys a new hat
so she can put it on
to go to the picture shows,
so she can take it off.
No, sir.
I haven't got anything
to whistle about.
Where're you from, bud?
Los Angeles.
Tough. You work down there?
Yeah. Well, I did.
What doing?
I was working in
an airplane factory.
They say that's
pretty good.
I was wondering
why you weren't
in the army.
Yeah.
I understand that
they all go particular
about the fellows they hire
in those big defense plants.
Well, that's
no more than right.
They got to be careful
they don't get blown up.
Yeah.
I understand if
a fellow would've had
any kind of
police record, no job.
Is that right?
Oh, I don't know.
Hey, buddy,
hold the wheel
a while, will you?
While I animate this thing.
I'm a nicotine addict.
Hey, watch it, bud,
will you?
Stay on this side of
the white line.
Where do you wanna get off
when we get to Springville?
It doesn't matter.
Just drop me in
the middle of town,
anywhere, when we get there.
Listen, the minute
you get to Springville,
you're in
the middle of the town.
And the next minute,
the place is just a memory.
Whole town isn't
a city block long.
You going to one of
those big ranches,
outside, aren't you?
Yeah.
I'd be glad to drop you off
at whatever one you want.
That's it!
Deep Springs Ranch.
Hey! Say, that's
a whale of a big place.
Got a chance of a job there?
Yeah.
I think so.
You ought to like it.
Nice climate.
The police!
Maybe something's happened!
I'd like to have
a little talk
with you out here.
Yeah, sure, sure, Officer.
Stay here a minute, buddy.
I'll be right back.
Hey, bud! Come on.
Everything's fixed.
Good night, Officer.
Can you imagine
a thing like that?
Cop chasing,
the sirens,
the whole works!
And what it's
all about is one of
my taillights went out.
That's the trucking game
for you in a nutshell.
Calling all highway patrolmen.
Be on lookout for
a man named Barry Kane.
Last seen on Highway 99.
He has dark brown hair,
blue eyes,
height about 6'2", no hat,
around 25 years old.
Calling all highway patrolmen.
How do you do?
Is Mr. Frank Fry here?
No, this is
Mr. Tobin's ranch.
Oh. Could I speak
to Mr. Tobin?
Well, I'll see.
Just a minute.
You wait here, please.
There.
We've got the ball.
Now, throw it to me.
A young man
to see you, sir.
Throw it to me.
Where is Daddy's girl?
What did you say, Adele?
Who wants to see me?
A young man, sir.
He came to ask
for a Mr. Fry.
Oh.
Well, have him come
out here, will you?
Yes, sir.
Throw me the ball.
Here comes your granddaddy.
Mr. Tobin will see you.
Follow me, please.
Hi.
Here we are.
The ball.
How do you do?
I'm Charles Tobin.
This is my daughter,
Mrs. Brown.
How do you do?
Well, I'm not gonna ask you
to excuse the informality
of this costume.
We're all informal out here
at Deep Springs Ranch.
That's one of
the rules of the place.
I see.
Do you want me
to take Susie with me
so you won't be disturbed?
No, Susie isn't gonna
disturb us at all.
You just let her
play right here,
and I'll see she
doesn't fall in the pool.
All right.
Well, shall
we sit out here?
Yes, sir.
It seems a shame
to go indoors
on such a beautiful day.
Yes, it does.
You wanted to see me
about something, huh?
Yes, sir. I'm looking
for a man named Fry,
Frank Fry.
I met him up in Los Angeles.
I understand he lives here.
Oh, no, no. Fry, huh?
Frank Fry?
I'm afraid I don't know
anybody by that name.
Wait a minute. Fry.
No, no. I've heard
that name somewhere.
I just don't seem to
be able to place it.
Uh-huh.
There used to be
a fellow with a name
something like that,
worked around here.
No. No. It wasn't Fry.
Well, I'm afraid
you found
the wrong address.
It couldn't be
one of the cowhands,
or maybe somebody
who is working...
No. No. I know
the names of all my men.
Wait a minute.
My next door neighbor...
Well, next door neighbor,
he lives 20 miles from here.
But he may know your friend.
I'll telephone him.
Oh, no, please don't.
No! Not at all.
You look as though
you've had
a hard journey.
It's just too bad
you had to come
all this way for nothing.
Now, if you'll just
wait a minute,
at least we can find out.
Will you see that Susie
doesn't fall into the pool?
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Hey. Come here.
Come over here.
Oh, so you're
a ballplayer, are you?
Wanna throw me the ball?
Let me have it.
Come on. Throw me the ball.
That's right. Throw me
the other one. Come on.
Throw it to me.
Come on. Give me the ball.
That's fine. Fine!
Now, I'll throw it back.
Where are you going?
Uh-oh. Don't do that.
Leave those where they are.
Leave them right there.
You wanna be a good girl?
Put these back
where you found them.
No, no, Susie.
The gentleman says
put them back
where you found them.
The gentleman knows
that you must be
very careful with letters
that don't belong to you.
Probably I'm prejudiced,
but it seems to me
that Susie is
a pretty cute
young lady.
Yeah, she's great.
Where's Frank Fry?
Well, really, you must
do something about
that memory of yours.
You know that
it wasn't a minute ago
that you read
a telegram that
Fry sent me.
And it said that
he was on his way
to Soda City.
Don't you remember that?
Where's Soda City?
Well, I haven't
given it much thought,
but I wouldn't imagine
there'd be an overabundance
of Soda Citys on the map.
I suppose there's some
way of finding out...
...bringing you
last-minute headlines.
Los Angeles. The fire in
the Stewart Aircraft Works,
in which one man was killed,
many injured,
and half a million dollars
worth of damage caused,
has been definitely
set down to sabotage.
Police have traced
the incendiary origin
of the blaze
to Barry Kane,
former aircraft...
Don't want
any more of that.
You'd think you'd be
rather bored with
descriptions of yourself.
Or maybe you'll never
get tired of them.
Well, I am, by this time.
I've been listening
to those radio reports
all morning.
All right, you knew me.
What about it?
Oh, quite a lot
about it, Mr. Kane.
You ought to know that.
You've become too famous
to remain so modest.
Tell me one thing.
Why are you
covering up Frank Fry?
What's a man like you
in this for?
Well, young man,
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I think maybe you do!
Frank Fry is
a saboteur who doesn't mind
killing Americans for money.
You must watch
yourself, Mr. Kane.
I'm telling you this
for your own benefit,
but you have the makings
of an outstanding bore.
You can't get away
with this, Tobin!
Even if I don't stop you,
there'll be others who will.
A man like you can't last
in a country like this.
Very pretty speech.
Youthful, passionate,
idealistic.
You see, I've already
sent for the police.
You can't bluff me.
You're hooked,
and you know it.
Must I remind you that
you are the fugitive
from justice, and not I?
I'm a prominent citizen,
widely respected.
You are an obscure
young workman,
wanted for the committing
of an extremely
unpopular crime.
Now, which of us do you think
the police will believe, hmm?
Oh, you must think me
a very poor host, Mr. Kane.
Now, don't you feel
that a long cold drink
is indicated?
Well, I guess
I've found out everything
you're gonna tell me.
I'll have to go on now
and do the rest by myself.
You mean you wish
to leave us?
Adele, Adele!
Mr. Kane is going!
I'm sorry.
You'll stop, please.
What does that shoot? Water?
Bullets, I'm afraid.
You shouldn't be
so anxious
to leave us, Mr. Kane.
You'll hurt our feelings.
You make it very hard for me
to refuse your invitations.
Susie, come on.
No, no, Susie!
Come here.
Hello, Susie.
You know where
we're going?
We're going for
a piggyback ride.
That's right.
You like piggyback rides?
Dick, Joe! Get after him!
Hurry up! Get him!
Get after him! Hurry up!
Come on. Get going.
Wait a minute.
You can't take me
away like this!
Don't tell us what
we can't do, chum.
Go on, get started.
I tell you,
you've got to
get him!
Just because
he's got a big ranch
and a fancy pool
and a lovely house
doesn't mean
he's a nice guy.
Why don't you find out
the kind of things
he's been doing?
Sure, sure.
We know all about that.
Just come on along.
The baby had the letters,
I tell you.
Oh, of course,
Susie would be only
too glad to cooperate,
but, you see, it'll
be quite a few months
before she'll be
of any assistance.
No, no, Susie.
Those are not for Susie.
Those are for the gentleman.
All right, let's go.
Where're we going?
We're gonna let you
get a little idea
of the county jail.
You won't find it
the best in the West.
But it won't
hurt you to rough it
for a couple of days
till they come up
from Los Angeles for you.
You can't hold me
without a warrant.
Chum, do I have to
keep asking you
not to tell us
what we can't do?
I'm trying to explain!
You give me a break.
There isn't time!
Time's the one thing
you don't need to
worry about.
You'll have it to burn.
You'll have 20 years,
nice and quiet,
if you get the right lawyer.
And if you don't,
you'll have
all the time there is.
What's wrong, Mac?
What's holding us up?
Truck ahead,
blocking the whole road.
Looks like they're
changing a tire.
Got a cigarette?
Sure. All you want.
Hiya, bud!
Hey, what's the matter?
He went behind
those rocks!
Not over here.
There he goes!
There he is!
Hello there.
Hello.
I got caught in this storm.
I'm pretty wet, I'm afraid.
Maybe you'd like to
come inside and get dry.
Did you leave your car
down on the road?
Why don't you bring it up
and put it in the shed?
I'm afraid
it won't do it any good
standing in the rain.
I don't have any car.
You might say
I'm traveling by thumb.
By thumb?
Yeah, I'm a hitchhiker.
Oh, I see.
I've always
thought that,
that was the best way to
learn about this country
and the surest test
of the American heart.
Yes, I guess it is.
Will you go to the fire
and dry your clothes?
Thanks. Thanks.
I think that
they'd dry more quickly
if you hung them up
and put on
something of mine.
Oh, no, thanks!
This is fine.
We could do with
another log on the fire.
Would you?
Why, sure.
You must stay
until this blows over.
It won't detain you long.
These autumn storms
are short.
They yield to none
in wetness,
but they are short.
Yes, I...
I'm sorry,
I should have warned you.
Those logs are
heavier than you'd think.
I drop them constantly.
Yes, they are heavy.
I guess I was too smart
trying to pick it up
with one hand.
Good job it didn't
land on your foot.
That often happens to me.
You're lucky.
Yeah. I'm lucky.
Oh, I was forgetting.
My name is Phillip Martin.
Oh, I'm Barry... Mason.
I'm glad you found
yourself near here,
Mr. Mason,
when the storm came.
It's a pleasant thing
to have a guest
sharing the fire
when the rain
is beating on the roof.
You live here alone,
do you, sir?
Yes. Except
I really don't think of it
in that way.
You see, sounds are
my light and my colors.
My music, for example.
I compose a little.
And there's nobody
to tell me that
the results are
anything but brilliant,
so I live in
a comfortable glow
of self-appreciation.
I'm afraid I prefer
playing the works
of other composers.
Undoubtedly, you'd prefer
listening to them.
I used to play the triangle
in our high school band.
Of course that was
a long time ago.
Oh, that's too bad.
It's unfortunate
when you let yourself
get out of practice
on the triangle.
The piano is a boon to me.
The piano can't know
that you're blind,
so it doesn't embarrass you
by trying to make things
easier for you.
It does you
the compliment
to trust you.
Delius,
the British composer,
was blind too.
That's our only resemblance.
This is his Summer
Night on the River.
A very interesting effect,
obligato on an apple.
Oh, I apologize, Mr. Mason.
I forgot how
hungry you must be
after your long walk.
Just a moment.
I'll get something.
Oh, no. Thanks.
This is fine.
I like apples.
So do I.
We'll save them for dessert.
It was all ready, you see.
All I needed was a reminder
that I was hungry, too.
Are you dry enough?
Just about, sir.
It stopped raining.
Is that a car coming?
Two cars, I think.
Excuse me.
One car is my niece's.
I'd know the sound of
that motor anywhere.
The other is
a stranger to me.
There's a couple
of men in it.
The girl's standing
beside it, pointing
down the road.
They must've
asked her where to go.
This is an easy country
to lose your way in.
That's one of its charms.
The car is moving.
It's starting off
down the road now.
The girl's coming
up the path.
That's my niece.
She's been
staying with me.
She comes from New York
to spend a month
with me every year.
It's one of
my greatest pleasures.
Unhappily for me,
she can't stay longer.
After a month she finds
the quiet deafening.
Oh, Uncle Phillip.
Hello, old boy.
Uncle Phillip,
what do you think happened?
You didn't know
we had a guest.
You turned your back
and see what happens.
My niece, Patricia Martin,
Mr. Mason.
How do you do?
Uncle Phillip,
there was a car full of
detectives down the road.
They wanted to know
the way to town.
They're searching for a man
that got away from them.
It was on all the radios
and everything.
They said he's a really
dangerous criminal. He...
My dear, the police
are always
on the alarmist side.
But they said this man
is really dangerous.
I'm sure they did.
How could they be heroes
if he were harmless?
Pat, dear,
would you mind not having
any further quotations
from the police?
Their remarks are
always so expected.
They kill conversation.
You've probably seen
the face of my niece
before, Mr. Mason.
Why, yes.
I was wondering
where I'd seen...
As a matter of fact,
you've seen her
practically everywhere.
I'm told that
billboards she adorns
would reach
across the continent,
if placed end to end.
But I can't imagine
who's going to place
them end to end,
nor why they
should consider it
the thing to do.
Uncle Phillip
never has really been
enthusiastic over
my career as a model.
Oh, well,
relatives are like that.
My, aren't you two mean,
going ahead and
eating without me.
I'm starving.
Would you pass me
one of those plates,
please, Mr. Mason?
Oh!
What's the matter, Pat?
Have you just
seen his handcuffs?
I heard them
as soon as he came in.
Uncle Phillip,
he must be the man
they're looking for!
Yes, very probably.
But you should have
given him to the police.
Are you frightened, Pat?
Is that what
makes you so cruel?
But you've got to!
He's a dangerous man.
Oh, Pat, come on.
Mr. Mason may be
many things, but he's
certainly not dangerous.
In fact,
I'm not at all convinced
that he's guilty.
Uncle Phillip,
it's your duty as
an American citizen.
It is my duty as
an American citizen
to believe a man
innocent until he's
been proved guilty.
Pat, don't tell me
about my duty. It makes
you sound so stuffy.
Besides, I have
my own ideas about
my duties as a citizen.
They sometimes involve
disregarding the law.
But what are you going
to do? What are you
going to do with him?
I'm going to turn him
over to you, my dear.
And you're going
to drive him down
to Tim, the blacksmith,
and have those
preposterous contraptions
removed from his wrists.
Oh, Uncle Phillip,
how could I do
a thing like that?
Because, you know,
I can see a great deal
farther than you can.
I can see intangible things.
For example, innocence.
Will you go with
my niece, Mr. Mason?
Oh, yes, sir!
If you don't mind?
But what'll I tell
the blacksmith?
Tell him Mr. Mason is
my friend and my guest.
He won't ask
any other questions.
Go ahead, Pat.
Go with her, Barry.
Barry, I know,
is your name.
Your voice explained
to me that Mason isn't.
But as I told you before,
names are of such
little importance.
I don't know how to
thank you, Mr. Martin.
Go ahead, Barry.
Go ahead.
And do the things
I wish I could do.
Good luck, Barry,
and for heaven's sake,
get back in practice
on that triangle!
Is the blacksmith's
shop very far?
Not very, right along here.
And is he...
Is he really all right?
He and my uncle
are great friends.
Oh.
I guess he's all right, then.
You needn't worry.
He's all right.
He's a darling blacksmith.
Only I'm not quite sure
how much experience
he's had with handcuffs.
Do you mind if I see them?
I wonder what
he'll have to do
to get them off.
I can't quite see.
Could you hold them
a little nearer?
Now I feel better.
I'll bet you do.
I'll bet this just
makes you feel great,
doesn't it?
In case you're interested,
the blacksmith's shop
is two miles back.
We're on our way
to the police.
Your uncle's certainly
gonna be proud of you!
The world isn't full of
kind old gentlemen,
like my uncle.
You're gonna find that out.
Even my uncle wouldn't
have been so kind if
he'd known more about you.
All right, go ahead.
What did I do?
I'd be kind of happy to know.
If it had been any
other sort of crime,
if a man had stolen
because he was starving,
even if a man
committed murder
to defend himself,
maybe I wouldn't
tell the police.
But there's only one reason
why a man commits sabotage.
That's worse than murder.
Surprise for you,
Miss Martin,
I agree with
every word you say.
Please don't
talk to me anymore.
That will be my pleasure.
Well! I'll see that
she doesn't!
Never try driving this way.
It hurts.
I'm stopping
the first car I see.
Help!
Come on.
I can't get along
without you.
Let go of me!
Help! Help!
Get the police!
Help!
My, they must be
terribly in love.
Looks as though
this car has been
overheated.
Fan's broken.
I'm cold.
Yeah, I know.
And you're hungry.
Now mostly I'm cold.
Look, if you'd stop
trying to be a hero and
decide to be on my side,
maybe we could do
something about
your being cold.
Build a fire?
No, I wasn't exactly
thinking of that.
Well, I didn't
want to insult you
by not even trying.
What do you want
to turn me in for?
Haven't you got
your picture stuck up
in enough places now?
I just want to do my duty.
That's hard for you
to understand.
Why won't you believe
I'm all right?
'Cause you still
don't make sense.
If you really hadn't
done it, you would've
gone to the police.
I've told you
it's a question of time!
If I go to the police,
it'd take me weeks
to convince them.
If they're as dumb
as you are,
it'll take me months.
Do you think we're
very far from Soda City?
I don't know.
We'll ask at the next town,
if there's a next town.
Well, anyway,
I don't believe
that part about Tobin.
You don't believe it
because he's got
a big ranch and
a beautiful pool and...
No. It's just
hard to believe that
about any American.
Well, you believe it
about me!
Well, you're different.
You look like a saboteur.
You have
a saboteur's disposition.
Don't tell me
you've decided
to be on my side.
No, I'm cold.
Say, aren't you wasting
your very valuable time,
sitting up here
admiring the scenery?
Hey, look at that.
Looks like
we've got company.
What do you suppose
all that's doing way up here?
They aren't moving
very fast, are they?
You know what we can do?
Oh, no, you won't.
Sorry, honey,
I can't take a chance.
You're right. I'd turn you in
at the first opportunity I get.
Let go of me!
Let me go!
Ouch!
Help! Help!
Won't you give me one break?
Won't you wait till
we get to Soda City?
All right. I'm sorry
I've got to
leave you here alone.
But I told you
what I've got to do,
and I'm gonna do it.
There's only one thing I want
to warn you about, snakes.
There're a lot of them
out here.
Of course, there's only
five or six poisonous kinds,
but there are a lot of
the long, squirmy,
slippery, slimy ones.
Barry!
I'm coming up
in the world.
Now I'm better
than the snakes.
Barry, please!
Are you with me?
Yes, yes!
Now, what made you
change your mind?
I can't turn you in
if I'm stuck out there.
Oh, so that's it.
Go back with the reptiles.
Let me go!
Who's there?
You've got no right here!
Stop it and get off!
Now, now, Major.
Ah, stowaways.
In the middle
of this desert sea,
we acquire
two more vagabonds.
Bedouins like ourselves,
eh, Esmeralda?
Why, they're just
a couple of kids.
Our car broke down
a way back,
and we walked for miles.
We saw your bus and
hopped on. We didn't want
to wake you at this hour.
Broke down, eh?
We didn't pass no
wrecks on the highway.
The whole thing
sounds like
a pack of lies.
You see,
we were off
on a side road.
I know. A moonlight night
and a parked car.
That's nice.
Oh, no, really,
we were just...
Esmeralda! Everywhere
you search for sex.
Get your eyes out of the mud
and look up at the stars.
Oh, I beg your pardon.
My name is Bones.
I am also known as
the human skeleton.
How do you do?
And this is Esmeralda,
our bearded lady.
Naturally,
we're very proud to have her
as a member of our group.
You poor kids must be tired.
Come on in and sit down,
have a little rest.
We're trying to
get to a place
called Soda City,
a couple of hundred
miles north, I think.
Well, then, you won't
get there till morning,
so make yourselves
comfortable.
You must meet
our other co-worker,
Tatania, our little
human mountain.
A very great lady, indeed.
How do you do?
What goes on there?
Oh, did we wake you, honey?
That's too bad.
Oh, I was awake.
I wish you'd tell
Mignonette to do
something about
that insomnia of hers.
I've been tossing
and turning all night.
I wish you'd tell
Marigold to shut
her silly old face.
Are you girls not
speaking to each other
again? Dear, dear.
Marigold's mad because
I got her beau away
from her back in
the last town we played.
Kindly tell Mignonette
I heard that last remark,
that I wouldn't
have the gentleman
in question as a gift.
Nothing but a common
novelty-seeker.
Girls, girls!
What will our guests think?
Hey, he's cute!
You hear that?
There she goes again.
Stop your squabbling.
They are tired.
They've been
walking for miles!
Nobody gave you a lift?
I know.
The normal are
normally cold-hearted.
Stop gabbing and
get these tramps off!
A cold heart,
partly reduced in size.
I won't take no insults.
Get them off.
Aw, Major, honey...
Don't "honey" me!
I've got a contract.
It provides for
safe transportation,
and it don't say nothing
about picking up hobos.
That's the police,
all right.
They must be
looking for somebody.
Who could they want?
Me, I guess.
Oh!
The carefree youth,
and he has handcuffs on.
What do they want you for?
For something
somebody else did.
I don't believe
he's done anything wrong!
I'll go to bat
for him anytime.
I've always told Mignonette
she'd get mixed up
with the police
if she wasn't careful.
They're starting to
search at the front.
Well, what are you
waiting for? Hand him
over to the police.
He's perfectly right.
He's a little stinker.
Seems like a terrible
thing to do,
but it'd be terrible, too,
if we got into trouble...
All right, Bones,
call the cops!
Just a minute, Major.
In this situation,
I find a parallel
for the present world predicament.
We stand defeated
at the outset.
You, Esmeralda,
have sympathy,
and yet you're willing
to remain passive
and let the
inevitable happen.
I have a belief,
and yet I'm tempted
to let myself be
over-ridden by force.
The rest of you,
with the exception
of this malignant jerk,
are ignorant of the facts,
and, therefore, confused.
Thank heaven
we're still members
of a democracy.
We'll put the matter
to a vote.
No vote.
I'm against voting!
Fascist!
You know how we stand so far.
The twins, as usual,
are on opposite sides,
and so their votes pair.
Tatania's on
both sides at once
and therefore neutral.
The Major is for
delivering these young
people to the police,
and I, frankly,
am against it.
Esmeralda,
the decision is up to you.
Well, I don't want
any trouble any more
than anybody else,
but while you've been
talking, I've been
looking at something,
something pretty fine, too.
I've been looking at
that little girl there
standing right beside
that poor young man.
Never a word.
Never a question.
Taking everything
he's had to take,
stringing along with him,
whatever happens.
And I've been thinking,
it's the good people
that stick when
anybody's in trouble,
and there aren't
many good people
in the world.
I think that we, all of us,
know that better than most.
And, well, it isn't
something you see
every day of the week,
so I vote...
We don't give them up.
Good girl, Esmeralda.
This is subversive!
I won't stand for it!
Oh, no, you don't, cuddles!
You'll abide by
the will of the majority.
Back into your places
and pretend to be asleep.
That's all
you have to do.
Here, honey, you sit
right down here.
Come on, young man,
we've got to hide you.
Turn all the lights off.
Here. Take off your
coat and put this on.
Come on.
Wake up in there!
Hey, what is this?
Halloween?
Police.
Oh, is that so?
Haven't you got
anything better to do
than waking up
law-abiding citizens
in the middle of the night?
We're looking for
a young man and
his woman companion.
He's got dark hair,
between the age
of 20 and 25.
The dame's supposed
to be good-looking.
Have you seen them?
Now, where would I see
anybody as normal as that?
Who's this? Doesn't look like
one of your troop.
Sure, she's one of us. She's
our little snake charmer.
Right now she's sitting
on a box of snakes
so they don't get lonesome.
Can you imagine that?
And a good-looking gal, too.
Well, I guess you can all go back
to sleep now.
A snake charmer!
Well, well.
You never can tell
about women.
It's all right.
You can come out now.
Wait, justice,
come back!
Sit down here!
We're on our way.
I don't know how
I can thank you, sir.
It's all right, my boy.
It gives you a good feeling
when you can help somebody.
You people have
a right to know
what this is all about.
It's all right, son.
If that little girl
of yours can trust you,
I guess we can.
The baby!
She's had
a tough time.
Poor little girl.
She's worn out.
I'll take care of her.
Come on. Let's go.
Better let the snakes
get some sleep.
They have to
look good tomorrow.
I'm sorry.
What for?
For being such a dope.
I was scared.
You'd have been a dope
if you hadn't been scared.
You're tired,
that's all that's
the matter with you.
Get some sleep.
You'll be fine.
I can go to sleep,
all right. I'm so tired.
I want to tell you
something.
I believe you.
Do you, Pat?
You didn't, you know.
It's a free country.
A girl can change
her mind, can't she?
Sure, she can.
Thank you, Pat.
They made me so ashamed.
They're so nice
and trusting.
They're wonderful people,
all except that
nasty little Major
and the mean twin.
I don't suppose
you can really blame
the fat lady though,
when a woman has lost
her figure that way.
Welcome to Soda City.
The heart of
the bicarbonate belt.
Well, we might as well
do the town.
There's nothing here.
Come on.
I suppose we are
a little late.
I'm sorry, darling.
I knew I shouldn't
have brought you here.
I'm not complaining.
This is great, isn't it?
Solution to all my problems.
I was counting on
this place.
A dump like this,
5,000 miles from nowhere.
Look at this.
It's been in use.
Let's go around
to the window.
Careful!
Don't cut yourself.
Hello? Hello?
Hung up.
What sort of
phone is that?
It's a field telephone.
Well, a room with a view.
What do you suppose
they cut that for?
I don't know.
Say, look.
Tripod.
Looks like it's
the right height. Yeah.
Something else
goes with this.
There!
That's it.
See anything?
Not yet.
Uh-oh.
Let me see!
Why, that's a...
Why, Barry!
Yeah.
We better put this away.
Take that.
Say! The wood.
What about it?
They wouldn't
burn that in a stove.
Why not?
The smoke would show.
That's a car.
You better hide.
No, not here.
Hey. What do you think
you're doing around here?
Hiya. I was wondering
when you'd get here.
Where are you from?
What are you
sniffing around here for?
Excuse me.
Funny, you knowing
about this place.
I don't quite get it.
You might have
thought it over
more carefully.
Your coming here
doesn't help us a bit.
The heat's on this guy
and he shows up here.
Tobin sent me.
The old man
must be off his nut
sending him up here.
Be a little more
careful, Neilson.
Your criticisms
in front of other people.
Yeah. Don't talk that way
about the old guy.
I'll watch out
for myself, Doc.
Me, too.
Don't forget about me.
That's why Tobin
sent me up here.
He said you'd know
how to take care of me.
I guess that makes it
pretty clear, Neilson.
I don't know.
A guy walks in
out of the desert,
and right away
I get orders.
It ain't so clear to me.
I'm a little better
than a stranger, friend,
if you'll remember
my press clippings.
Yes. Mr. Kane has done
pretty well down South.
His accomplishments
can't be disregarded,
at least I hope not.
A man that has served
as well as he has
is entitled at least
to recognition.
I'm entitled to
more than that.
Protection, too.
You guys have got
to take care of me.
I'm sure the firm
will do its best.
They're known
to be quite loyal
to their employees.
Neilson will see to it
that the firm's
record is maintained.
You got it easy,
you guys from back East.
You give orders.
You do that, all right.
The big boys
with the desk jobs.
All you got to do is
reach for a telephone,
sit back in
a big leather chair,
and us guys out here
have got to take the rap.
You know,
I think I'll go back East
and work for a while.
You're not a very
good example of
loyalty to the firm.
Yeah? Well,
I'm getting just
a little bit tired, see.
So am I! I'm getting
tired of all this talk.
Let's get going!
The trip up here
was no pushover.
I had to hoof it
most of the way.
I got no place
to hide you out.
That ain't my line.
That ain't your line, huh?
What about you?
You don't seem
so interested, either!
Or I suppose you're
just the big brains!
Or maybe you take
a chance now and then
just for laughs.
Or maybe it doesn't
work that way.
Maybe I'm
the only guy that
sticks his neck out.
Well, get this,
both of you!
I pulled a big job
and they're after me.
And you guys are
gonna take care of me
and do it right,
or you're gonna have
trouble on your hands.
I've got to get
out of this part
of the country!
The ground's
burning up under my feet!
I've got to get back East!
It's a little more
crowded back there.
A guy doesn't stand out
like he does here.
Hey, take it easy.
Hang on to your nerve.
I've been
hanging on to my nerves!
I've been hanging on
long enough!
I understand
your difficulties.
I'm sorry about
all the talk.
But in this business,
we always
have to make sure.
I think I know him now.
I'm driving back East,
you know.
You'd better come with me.
All right,
let's get going.
Get all the things
together.
After we leave,
I want this place
cleaned up.
You won't be
coming back here.
Why not? You think
they got the place spotted?
I'm making sure.
You'll have to
find another place
and store all this stuff.
Well, it's not
gonna be easy.
It's your job. If you
can't handle it, I'll have
to get someone else.
All right.
I'll handle it.
You'll need some clothes.
Size 42.
What'll we do about these?
Hmm. How did you
manage to break them?
On an automobile fan.
That's very bright of you.
I think we can even
take care of that,
but let's get started now.
Did you hear something?
Where does that lead to?
Just another room.
The way out.
You see,
we figure that Kane
and the other fellows
are probably
heading for New York.
If there's anything
I can do...
We sure appreciate that.
Why, anyone
would have done
the same thing.
That's right,
this war sure
makes a difference.
Everybody wants to
get in and pitch.
Now, if you'll just
give me your address
in New York, Miss Martin,
we can contact you
back there.
Or maybe you could
wire me about
which plane you're taking.
We may want to get
a hold of you fast.
Well, I can do that
when I get back to my uncle.
Okay, Miss Martin,
just keep in touch.
I'm glad
we came this way.
It adds a few miles
to our trip,
but somehow I've become
a little sentimental.
I want to take
a last look at it.
Beautiful, isn't it?
A great monument
to man's unceasing industry
and his stubborn
faith in the future.
You'll be moving along soon.
Are you carrying
any cameras
or firearms at all?
Nothing at all, Officer.
You, sir?
No, sir.
They must get a lot of
power from this dam.
I think it supplies
about 75% for the
Los Angeles district,
naturally including
most of the power for
the defense plants there.
Well, do you think
there's any...
Do you know Tobin
very well?
No, not very well.
I met him just
that once at his ranch.
Did he have
the child with him?
His grandchild? Yes.
He seemed to be
very fond of her.
Yes. That's one of the things
I like about old Tobin,
his love for
that little girl.
Evidence of a good heart.
I have children,
too, you know.
Oh?
Two boys.
Nice little fellows.
Aged two and four.
The four-year-old
is naughty at times.
He's quite a problem.
We get him a new toy
and within half an hour
it's smashed to bits.
And then, sometimes,
after it's all over,
he seems almost sorry.
Sometimes I wish
my younger child
had been a girl.
In fact, my wife
and I often argue
over a little idiosyncrasy
I have.
I don't want
his hair cut short
until he's much older.
Do you think
it'd be bad for him?
Well, I don't know,
it might be.
When I was a child,
I had long golden curls.
People used to stop
on the street to admire me.
Things are different
nowadays.
If you gave the kid
a haircut, it might
save him a lot of grief.
Ah, we're on our way.
Drive to 401
instead of the office.
Okay.
Anything wrong?
Plenty. I've just
called the office.
They've disconnected
the phone.
Same old phone company.
Should have paid the bill.
This is no time
for jokes.
The police.
They're watching
the office.
The disconnected phone,
it's our signal.
You think they're
watching for me?
I don't know.
Who'd know
you were in New York?
Oh, yeah.
I guess you're right.
How about Brooklyn tomorrow?
Do you want me on the job?
When are you going to learn
to keep your mouth shut?
Sorry. I thought
he was in on it.
Shut up!
It's all right.
I'm good at
keeping secrets.
Let's go.
Good evening,
Mr. Freeman.
Hi, Mr. Freeman.
Hello.
Ah, pleased to see you,
Mr. Freeman.
Have a good trip?
Yes. Thank you,
Robert.
Madam is upstairs.
She's waiting
anxiously for you.
Oh, thank you, Robert.
We'll go right up.
This way.
Who's that?
Hey, is this a hotel?
What's the festivity?
It's for a very
worthy cause.
Mrs. Sutton often
gives her house over
to charity affairs.
She's a very
generous woman.
I have an idea
she isn't going
to be really pleased
to see us
on a night like this.
Idiots, all of you.
Stupid, inefficient idiots.
Everything is left to me.
I have to hover
over all of you
like an old hen.
I'm sorry,
Mrs. Sutton.
The guests
downstairs expect me
to put in an appearance.
After all, as you say,
they want something
for their $25!
I will not have
my benevolence abused.
My life, my position,
they're important to me.
I'll do my best,
Mrs. Sutton.
I only wish your best
were a little better.
Oh. Mr. Freeman,
I'm glad you've
come at this time.
I was just telling Edward...
Is this the young man?
Must you bring him
here, as well?
I certainly can't
furnish him with sanctuary.
This house is
full of guests,
important people!
Don't you understand
my position, Mr. Freeman,
with this young man here?
The police are already
watching your office.
Thank goodness
they'll never come here.
But a little more of
your stupid behavior
and even
the respectability of
my house won't shield you.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Sutton.
We can't leave
any loose ends.
All right! All right!
But for heaven's sake,
stop playing the conspirator.
Now tell me
all you know about
the girl or ask him.
Why didn't you tell me
about the young lady
back in Soda City?
Oh. Well, I didn't
think it was important.
She was just a girl,
like anybody else.
She picked me up,
she was pretty.
I guess it was
kind of risky.
Well, there you are.
I'm so sorry to
have exposed you
to any risk.
What's she doing here?
You're surprised
to see me again.
How did you get here?
It doesn't matter
how she got here.
The point is
there was no reason
to bring her here at all!
You see, Mr. Kane,
I just learned
on the telephone
at the gas station
that she was most indiscreet
after she left you
at Soda City.
She went straight
to the local sheriff,
who, fortunately,
happened to be
a particularly
good friend of ours.
Oh, don't waste time
in explanations,
Mr. Freeman.
You've got to get
the girl out of
this house, all of you.
I will not have
my benevolence abused!
So you played smart.
That's great.
That's a big help
to all of us.
No, I wasn't smart at all.
I haven't been smart
for four days.
Even when I went to
the sheriff I hesitated.
I hated to do
anything that might
get you into trouble.
Yeah, I sympathize.
The mistake I made
was not leaving you
back there with the snakes!
You might have at least
learned to rattle.
I was right about you
in the first place.
Good evening, Mr. Kane.
I didn't know
you were a bookworm.
You must let me
choose something
appropriate for you.
Something not too difficult
for you to understand.
Let me see.
Here we are.
This will do admirably.
Remarkable work.
Somehow prophetic.
Why are you here, Charles?
And what's all this
nonsense about books?
I am a refugee.
I have at last joined
that revolting group
of world travelers.
One ultimately
turns into the thing
one despises most.
And whom have I
to thank for it?
You, Mr. Freeman.
The girl was allowed
to escape unobserved.
She left Mr. Kane,
went straight to her uncle.
And that charming old man
went to the police.
As a result,
a whole hoard of officers
came to my house.
Luckily, I was leaving
when they arrived.
And the others,
the very loyal ones,
well, they're paying
for their loyalty.
How appalling!
Your charming house.
I'm so sorry, Charles.
It's rather lucky.
You might have been sorrier.
And you might have been
a little more efficient
in this whole matter,
Mr. Freeman!
What good is it
going to do you
to insult me?
We're in trouble now.
And so the most
important thing
is to make sure of
everyone around us.
Of Mr. Kane?
I'm just not sure.
I want to know that he's all right.
All right?
What an understatement.
He's much more than that!
He's noble and fine and pure.
And so he pays the penalty
that the noble and
the fine and the pure
must pay in this world.
He's misjudged by everyone.
Why, even the police
have a completely
erroneous impression of him.
I can assure you
that contrary to
what is supposed
and to what he may
himself have told you,
that young man is
certainly not one of
his country's enemies.
Charles, you're joking!
I mean exactly what I say.
Mr. Kane is definitely
no part of our
little organization.
Your protg. Well,
you've done splendidly.
You bring him here,
you idiot.
Now what in heaven's name
are we going to do with him?
That's a very
appropriate question.
Not much
we can do with him.
I made the mistake
once of turning him
over to the police.
That's even more
impossible at the moment.
I'm afraid there's
only one thing we can do.
You see, the new law
threatens all of us
with the death penalty.
So, I'm afraid
we'll have to apply
the ancient axiom.
Tooth for a tooth.
Kane for a Tobin.
Please don't discuss things
of that sort here.
It's rather nauseating
and quite out of place.
Oh, Charles, I'm frightened.
We must take all precaution.
Of course. We must also
continue with our work.
It's too risky now.
We're already
abandoning the dam.
We must remain
inactive for a while.
Inactive? You are
utterly mistaken.
Once we do that,
our organization
is finished.
We must carry on
at all costs.
What about tomorrow's work?
Tomorrow's work?
You can't abandon that
after all your preparations.
But, Charles, the risk...
Is great. I know that.
Unfortunately,
we will have to
carry out our orders.
I am leaving for
the Caribbean now.
My position here
is more impossible
than all of yours.
Of course I'm rather
looking forward to
Central America.
Havana will be
very gay this season.
You know, somehow
I've suddenly had
enough of this country.
The war has made it grim.
You're leaving us here
to face everything,
and you'll be on
a boat sailing along.
It all sounds idyllic.
Oh, Charles, Charles,
this whole thing,
it's impossible.
It's panicky.
I'm deeply sorry.
There you are,
darling!
How unbecoming
for a hostess to
hide herself away.
Am I intruding?
I am so sorry,
but I just must
kidnap Henrietta.
She'll be back.
I've had some trouble
with these people.
They're doing the catering
and making rather
a horrid mess of it.
Our boy will appear
any minute with
the caviar! I assure you.
I'll stake
my reputation on it.
Don't be a fool!
Get to the house phone.
How'd you get here?
They met me at the airport.
I thought they were
the police, then
they brought me here.
Wait a minute.
No use trying
the way I came in.
Let's walk right out
through the front door!
Might as well.
Yes, sir.
We'll watch the back exit.
They won't get out.
No good.
See the one on
the other side? I met
him on the way in.
He's one of them.
We'll never
get out that way.
What can they do to us?
Plenty.
They'd grab us.
We wouldn't have a chance.
But these people
would see them do it.
Of course.
And if anyone
had a question,
we're a couple
of gatecrashers.
Barry, this is awful.
It's like a bad dream.
All these people here.
Isn't there anyone
we can trust?
Sure there is.
All of them.
Only which one?
Excuse me.
This may sound
sort of crazy.
In fact,
I don't even
know how to start.
But this whole house
is a hotbed of
spies and saboteurs.
I'm not being silly.
I assure you. Even
our hostess, Mrs. Sutton.
What's the matter
with you, sir?
You're drunk!
You're not even dressed.
What'd he say?
Oh, he thinks
I'm drunk.
When I read in the papers what
those Japs are doing...
Beat it out! Beat it out.
Keep it natural.
Eight to the bar.
Yeah, man.
Stay in that pitch.
Pardon me.
Did you pay $25 to
get in here tonight?
No, not exactly.
My boss gave me
a ticket. Why?
I need your help very badly.
We're in the middle of
the biggest bunch of
fifth columnists
in the country.
Are you kidding?
What's the gag?
No, I'm on the level.
This is it.
Aw, you're kidding.
We got a wag
on the joint.
The guy's trying to rib me.
Aw, sling him
your curve.
Beat it out, son.
Beat it out.
Excuse me, sir.
I'd like to
talk to you
about something
very important.
What is it, Mr. Kane?
You know it's hopeless.
Why don't you join
Mr. Tobin upstairs
for a little supper?
I'll show you the way.
Barry, before
they get to us,
go out and stop the music
and tell them! Tell them all!
Honey, this is
the Sutton mansion.
I'm just a guy from
Glendale, California,
wanted by the police.
They'll grab me
as soon as I open my mouth.
What are you gonna do?
We can't just stand here.
I know where we'll be safe.
Barry, I'm scared.
It's so unreal,
all these people dancing
and having a good time.
Yeah. And when you
try to warn them,
they laugh at you.
They think you're drunk.
That gray-haired man
you spoke to,
he seemed like such
an honest citizen.
Hmm.
Just a friend of the family.
I guess the room's
well sprinkled with them.
They're so smart.
That's what frightens me.
Yeah, they're smart,
that's because
they're ruthless.
It's easy to win
when you forget
about the rules.
A man named Fry
drops a wallet
in California
and we wind up here,
you and me.
That's the only
good part of it,
I'm with you.
I wish it were
somewhere else.
The North Pole,
I wouldn't care.
We might wind up
there yet, too,
chasing Fry over
the old glacier!
Fry. He seems so small now.
I'd forgotten about him.
So had I.
Well, we can't just
go on dancing
like it's Saturday night
at The Palladium.
We can't just wait
till they come and get us.
What do you think
they'll really do?
Oh, right now
they're probably haggling
over the price with
Murder Incorporated.
Oh, Barry, please!
Sorry, Pat. I hate to
be out of it now there's
still so much to do.
If ever there was a time
when staying alive
was important,
you heard what they said.
Something about a job
they are going to do
tomorrow in Brooklyn.
The Navy Yard.
One of us has got
to get out of here.
Maybe if I start something,
you can make a break for it.
Well, what about you?
You can't worry about me.
We got to take a chance.
Oh, Barry, why couldn't I have
met you 100 years ago
on a beach somewhere?
Bathing suits looked awfully funny
100 years ago.
I'll bet you'd look
beautiful, though.
Afraid we're not
behaving very well.
What's the difference?
We weren't invited anyway.
Pat, this moment
belongs to me.
No matter what happens,
they can never
take it away from me.
Oh, pardon me.
Do you mind?
Oh, excuse me.
Would you care to dance?
Why, yes. Certainly.
Oh, you're really
a much better dancer.
Thanks. Who was the man
you were dancing with?
I have no idea.
I never saw him before.
No, I mean the man
that just left you.
I know. That's who
I'm talking about.
I never saw him
before in my life.
Oh, what a pity.
That was lovely.
I hope you will
ask me again.
Oh, thanks.
Thanks a lot.
Well, young man,
you seem to be
enjoying yourself.
Charming party, isn't it?
Where is she?
You mean your young lady?
I thought you were
taking care of her.
Perhaps she has a headache
and lying down somewhere.
Would you like to
come with me
and look for her?
Hold on.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Ladies and gentlemen!
Your attention, please.
I have something
to tell you.
Something you ought to
know about this house
and about your hostess.
I beg your pardon, sir,
but before you go on,
I think you might like
to take a look at
the curtain on the balcony.
I'm not much of a public speaker,
ladies and gentlemen,
and some of you are
probably wondering
how I can tell you anything
about your hostess
that you don't already know.
Her graciousness,
her kindness,
her many charities.
Well, I want to tell you
that you have
a big surprise coming,
ladies and gentlemen.
Tonight, in this house,
for the benefit
of this great cause
for which she's
already done so much,
our hostess, Mrs. Sutton,
is putting up for auction
one of her most
treasured possessions,
one of the famous
Sutton jewels.
Mrs. Sutton, would you
kindly step forward?
Thank you.
Mr. Kane,
the young lady is
asking to see you.
Are you sure?
I wouldn't keep her
waiting if I were you, sir.
Yes.
Will someone please...
Admiral, how about you?
Would you take over
for me, please?
Excuse me, please.
I'm wanted on the phone.
Delighted, sir.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I will entertain
your bids for this
beautiful bracelet,
which has been donated
by our hostess, Mrs. Sutton.
What am I bid?
$1,000.
$1,000 has been bid.
Do I hear any more?
$1,500.
$1,500 has been bid.
Do I hear?
$1,750.
$2,000.
$2,000 has been bid
for this beautiful bracelet.
Where is she?
You seem to have a soft spot
for that young lady.
You can't afford
to make yourself
that vulnerable,
not when you're out trying
to save your country.
Why is it that
you sneer every time
you refer to this country?
You've done pretty well here.
I don't get it.
No, you wouldn't.
You're one of
the ardent believers,
the good American.
Oh, there are
millions like you.
People that plod along
without asking questions.
I hate to use the word
stupid, but it seems to be
the only one that applies.
The great masses,
the moron millions.
Well, there are a few of us
who are unwilling
to just troop along.
A few of us who are
clever enough to see
that there's
much more to be done
than just live small,
complacent lives.
A few of us in America
who desire
a more profitable
type of government.
When you think
about it, Mr. Kane,
the competence of
totalitarian nations
is much higher than ours.
They get things done.
Yeah.
They bomb cities, sink ships,
torture and murder,
so you and your friends
can eat off a gold plate.
It's a great philosophy.
I neither intend to be
bombed nor sunk, Mr. Kane.
That's why I'm leaving now.
And if things
don't go right for you,
if we should win,
then I'll come back.
Perhaps I can get
what I want then, power.
Yes. I want that
as much as you
want your comfort,
or your job, or that girl.
We all have different tastes,
as you can see.
Only I'm willing
to back my tastes
with the necessary force.
You certainly make it
sound smooth and easy.
Well, that's a trick.
I know the results of
that power you believe in.
It killed my friend,
and it's killing
thousands like him.
That's what you're aiming at.
But it doesn't bother you,
I can see that.
Because you really
hate all people.
Let me tell you something.
The last four, five days
I've learned a lot.
I've met guys like you
and I've met others,
people that are helpful
and eager to do
the right thing,
people that get a kick
out of helping each other
fight the bad guys.
Love and hate.
The world's
choosing up sides.
I know who I'm with.
And there are a lot
of people on my side,
millions of us
in every country.
And we're not soft.
We're plenty strong.
And we'll fight
standing up on our
two feet, and we'll win.
Remember that, Mr. Tobin.
We'll win, no matter
what you guys do.
We'll win if it takes
from now until
the cows come home.
Mr. Kane, I think
we've discussed
the rights of man
sufficiently.
I'm feeling a little tired.
You must be, too.
Robert, do you think
you can arrange
for Mr. Kane to sleep
somewhere tonight?
Yes, sir.
Certainly, sir.
That's enough, Robert.
Very good, sir.
Think you can
take care of this?
Yes, sir.
Will that be all, sir?
Yes, thank you.
It doesn't matter
what arrangements we've made,
to what trouble we've gone.
This whole job hangs
on one thing, timing.
If the section of
the slipway goes up
before the actual
moment of launching,
then all our efforts
have been wasted.
If you blow her too late,
well, then you
just scare the crowd.
Timing, timing, timing.
That button must not
be pressed until
the ship starts to move.
What arrangements
have been made
for getting out of there?
As soon as the camera
cables are unhooked,
this truck goes.
We got a fix at the gate
to get through
without failing.
Who's handling the camera
near the slipway?
I am. The wires
to the explosives
were laid last night.
All I have to do
is hook them up
to the camera.
Too bad we have to
lose a good camera.
Well, everything
seems to be taken care of.
I'll be waiting for you
at the newsreel office.
Good luck.
Have they gone?
Yes.
How is she?
Okay. She's having
her breakfast.
Any trouble
keeping her quiet?
No. I made
a deal with her.
You see,
she got tired of having
that adhesive tape
over her eyes and mouth.
Well, I hope we
get rid of her soon.
I promised to
take my kid sister
to the Philharmonic.
Give me the key.
There it is.
I'm sorry we couldn't
keep you at the house
last night,
but Mrs. Sutton has
a limited number of
guest rooms,
and I suppose
Mr. Kane was first in line.
Where am I?
Oh, that's a trade secret.
I only hope it isn't
too high for you here.
Mr. Kane's quarters
are nearer the ground,
but he's being
well looked after,
and, like you, is probably
enjoying a hearty breakfast.
Somebody
get the fire hose!
Whose place is that?
That's Mrs. Sutton's house.
Oh, who's she?
Some rich dame.
Saw something
in the paper about her
doing things for charity.
Right here somewhere.
Here.
What about
tomorrow's work?
Tomorrow's work?
You can't abandon that
after all your preparations.
But, Charles, the risk...
Is great.
I know that.
Unfortunately,
we will have to
carry out our orders.
What's the time?
10:50.
Thanks.
Brooklyn Navy Yard, quick!
How much?
15.
Got change?
Yes.
Courtesy of
the Navy Department,
we are now able to
take you to the
Brooklyn Navy Yard,
where over
a national hook-up
we will endeavor to
bring you a description
of the actual
launching ceremony
of the Navy's capital ship,
the USS Alaska.
And so without further ado,
we switch you now to
the Brooklyn Navy Yard.
Here we are at
It's rather a windy
autumn day,
but still it's a pretty
good day for a launching.
I guess any day
is a good day for
a launching in these times.
Our microphones are located
in several key spots,
so we'll be able
to bring you...
What's holding us up?
Traffic, buddy.
What do you think?
Here. I'll walk.
Okay.
Well, I guess the main speaker
is about to begin.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I am now turning you
over to Bill Donnan,
who is located on
the actual platform.
Go ahead, Bill.
This is Bill Donnan,
ladies and gentlemen.
We're located up here
on the platform,
right below the bow
of the great ship.
It towers over us
like some enormous monster.
This platform
on which we have...
Take me to
the guy in charge!
Okay.
I'll take care of this.
What do you want?
Something's gonna happen
at the launching, sabotage.
Where'd you get
your information?
I can't say now.
There isn't time.
What can I do?
We got to have a little
more than that to go on.
Better come in the office
and talk to the chief.
I tell you there isn't time!
What do you expect me to do?
Take me to the guy
in charge of the launching.
No, you got to go
through the office first.
That's all.
Towley, 1050.
Very crowded at the moment
with all kinds of
Navy officers...
Wait here.
...and Navy personnel.
I can see
in the group to my left
Rear Admiral Pierce
and Mrs. Pierce.
It is Mrs. Pierce
who will perform
the actual
bottle breaking today.
She is shaking hands with
a great many people
down there right now.
Just a second,
ladies and gentlemen.
I see Rear Admiral Pierce
moving toward the microphone.
Yes. I think
he's going to begin
his speech now.
We'll switch you over
to the speaker's microphone.
The launching of a ship in a time of war
is always a solemn occasion.
Today, when our fleet
is fighting
on all the seven seas,
this ceremony
gains magnitude
for it represents,
for the American people,
a victory.
Where'd that guy go?
I don't know.
He just stepped outside.
...by the strong,
diligent of hands
of American workmen.
Let us rejoice,
then, at this moment.
Let us be confident...
...working for
this great country
to show the world
what America can do.
Our American soldiers,
who are freely
giving their lives,
so that we
in this country
can live in decency,
security and peace.
This is Bill Donnan again,
ladies and gentlemen.
You've just heard
Rear Admiral Pierce
speaking from
the Brooklyn Navy Yard.
His speech is being received
with great applause...
Lock the back doors, quick!
I can handle this!
Be ready to pull out
as soon as she goes.
The naval officer is handing her
a bottle of champagne
that is tied
somewhere above it.
The crowd is tense.
It is indeed
a solemn occasion.
I switch you over
to our microphone
near the bow of the ship
so that you may hear
the actual launching.
Now I can see that
Mrs. Pierce is moving
towards the bow of the ship.
I'll switch you over
now to Mrs. Pierce.
In the name of the people
of the United States,
I christen thee Alaska.
What's the trouble?
Don't know.
An explosion somewhere.
George!
Everything okay?
No, give us a hand.
We got a guy.
Better scatter.
Go down the corridor
and through the iron door.
It will take you
to the music hall.
We'll go this way.
You must go,
go at once, before
Henry catches you here.
See here, I thought
you wanted to make
the old boy jealous.
Not anymore.
He's threatened to
kill you on sight.
Oh, I say, you don't think
he'd go that far, do you?
Of course he will.
Oh, will you go
before it's too late,
before he shoots you
to death?
See here, are you
trying to tell me
Old Henry's got a gun,
a real gun?
Oh!
What do you
think this is?
I've caught you at last,
you rat in the grass!
Stop that!
Run, Wilbur, run!
Before he gets your range!
I think I got it now.
Get out before I shoot again!
Run, Wilbur, run!
Quick!
It never touched me!
I'll get you this time.
My husband! He's shot!
I'll kill the rat
if it's the last thing I do!
He was only kidding.
I swear!
And I'm only kidding, too!
Get out of here!
He's gone mad! Mad!
Go on.
Get out! Get out!
Not that way!
He'll kill you!
Stop him! Help!
Murder! Help!
Run, for heaven's sake!
Run for your life!
There he goes!
He's the one you're after.
You're the one
we're after. Come on!
I tell you, he's the one.
He'll get away!
Come on!
Pat, grab a cab
and go after him
and don't lose him.
It's our only chance.
Taxi!
Downtown.
Whereabouts?
Anywhere.
Just keep going downtown.
May I have change
for the telephone,
please?
Yes, ma'am.
There you are.
Operator? Give me
the FBI headquarters, please.
Federal Bureau
of Investigation.
Hold on,
I'll put you through.
Make sure he doesn't
leave by the next boat.
Talk to him, follow him.
Do your best to
keep him there until
our men come along.
A girl says she thinks
she's traced Fry
to Bedloe Island.
She's crazy.
He'd never go there.
Where did you pick
up Schultz last month?
In that museum,
that modern art place.
And Renaldo?
You caught him
looking at the fish
in the aquarium,
didn't you?
Yeah, but the statue's
a dead end.
That's why he's smart.
You better get going.
Let me take him along
in any case,
just to make sure the girl
hasn't made a mistake.
Burke, you're one of
the most obstinate men
I've ever met! Get going.
Come on.
Pardon me.
Could you tell me
which is Brooklyn?
I've seen you before,
haven't I?
Sure.
On that boat
coming over.
What'd you ask me?
About Brooklyn,
I was wondering
where it was.
I've heard so much about it.
Over there.
Where are you from?
New York.
What are you handing me?
Oh, no. You see,
I work in a store downtown.
Now, I never get
a chance to get out.
I just sit around all day,
and I never see anything.
So I said to myself,
the first vacation I get,
I'm going to see
the Statue of Liberty.
This must be a big
moment for you, huh?
Oh, it is.
And it means
so much to us now.
Why, I was just
reading here
in this booklet.
Did you know
this statue was given
to us by the French?
Do you know what
they had written on it?
"Give me your tired,
your poor,
your huddled masses,
"yearning to breathe free,
"the wretched refuse
of your teeming shore.
"Send these, the homeless,
tempest-tossed to me."
And just look at
the French.
Isn't it sad?
Yeah. Very sad.
Oh, it's such
a beautiful statue.
I could just
sit up here all day
thinking about it.
Couldn't you?
Some other day, maybe.
Not right now.
Right now I got to
catch that boat back.
You coming?
Well, there's another boat in 15 minutes.
Couldn't we wait?
All the people have gone,
and we'd be alone,
just you and me.
Sounds cozy.
But I...
I haven't got the time.
Oh, on a nice
autumn day like this,
you couldn't spare
15 minutes for me?
I don't like autumn.
You're not being
very nice to a lonely girl.
You look as though
you might be lonely, too.
Yeah.
I got to catch that boat.
Fifteen minutes
shouldn't make such
a big difference, Mr. Fry.
Who are you?
Come on.
Quit stalling.
Who are you?
I think I told you.
A working girl
on her day off.
Don't kid me!
What are you doing here?
It's rather
a long story, Mr. Fry.
It all started with
an unknown blonde,
an aircraft worker
at a factory
in Glendale, California.
I get it.
Little Miss Liberty,
carrying the torch.
Why'd you follow me?
Why do you think?
Take a look down there.
If you can't figure
it out for yourself,
they're coming for you.
Do you see him
in this bunch?
No.
Barnes, you stay here
and watch this end.
The rest of you fellows,
come with me.
You two,
watch that side.
I'm going up.
Barry!
Pat, where is he?
He started down!
Are you sure?
Yeah.
He's up here! Come on!
Come on, Fry!
I'll get your sleeve.
Don't you go over.
If you slip,
that will be three gone.
Quick! Get a rope.
Can you get a grip
with your feet?
I can't.
Kane, I'm getting a rope!
They're getting a rope.
Hold on, Fry.
I'll clear you.
I swear I will.
Hurry up with the rope!
Tell them quick.
The sleeve. Sleeve!
Kane!