Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
This trip to Lyon should take
no more than three hours
if we don't stop.
Maybe we stop there then and
have a late dinner or something.
(Speaking french) right?
No...
I butchered that
Then we're in Lyon
for two nights or three?
We can just leave that open.
But there's some big old church
that we've got to see, Basilica.
You've reached Crystal Davis,
sorry I missed you
I'll call you back as soon
as I can, bye bye, God bless.
Hey mom, it's me.
Um, just trying you again.
Um, they're guessing
she's not going
to make it through the night,
but um... I will
try you again later, bye.
(Preacher)
I'd like to thank you all
for coming out here today.
This is a time of terrible loss.
We are gathered here
in Jesus's name
to share our love
for our friend Nicole Prevot.
and to share our
compassion for each other
as we go through
this time of grief
and remembrance.
[Vespa engine noise]
Asked why she left the home
of Monet and Rousseau
to come here to Oklahoma
she said,"The people here
don't think they're important
enough to be painted,
that's why I find
them interesting."
Humility...
Fuck...
I don't have
any where else to go.
I know... Look,
I'm going back to work, Okay?
I've had to be in the hospital
for like,
the last four months.
Could I just have
one more month?
Please.
Hello?
[Vespa engine noise]
I'm seriously in like a really
bad thing with my landlord.
So, like you wanna come back?
No, I never left,
I just asked for
a couple extra weeks off.
Oh shit, you're right.
Now I feel like an asshole.
Look, I'm sorry, but,
I mean, we really don't
need anyone right now.
I'm so sorry.
when the colleges start
taking orders again?
Right, but half of these
designs are mine, JD.
Aw shit, I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
[sighs]
[bird chirping]
Oh, there she is.
Hey! Mwah. Come on in.
I just got home myself.
I found this bed skirt
at Big Lots for $9.
It's perfect for hiding
some of the stuff
that doesn't look so pretty.
- Never was there. [Laughs]
- Looks good.
I am so excited that
you're home to stay.
I'm sorry that I never ended up
making it down to the hospital.
I was planning to that
Tuesday when you called,
but then I went off and left
Mr. Moffat's
prescriptions at home.
Oh it's Okay,
I'm sorry that I called you.
And with his dementia see
he's taken to
stuffing cube steaks
down behind the radiator
to where I had to air out
his whole house.
[laughs]
Uh, yeah that night I called
I just got overwhelmed
I thought you had experience,
but it's totally Okay.
It is never easy moving on,
I could clean out
a couple of these drawers,
make them free again.
I mean I really
don't have anything.
Oh and your brother's
coming home in a couple of days.
I guess he couldn't hide her
from us forever, could he?
Couple days, right?
Ohhh,
no hold it up.
I've been needing
a new picture of you.
Here we go,
let me get the flash.
One, two, three, smile!
[laughs]
Oh there's my pretty girl.
Oh, great.
May I?
Oh, I just love your drawings,
look at that gold leaf.
Here.
- Sorry... sorry.
- Oh, hang on,
I got a surprise for you.
Ta da! Funfetti!
Thank you, Mom.
[crying]
Oh,
oh honey, it's just a cake.
It's just a cake.
[crying]
Why don't you, I could,
wash that dress for you.
Why don't you
change into something,
you've got a lot old sweat
clothes here, get comfortable.
[deep breath]
[TV in background]
That fella there
has kept all his
baby teeth in jelly jars
and his kids too,
which well I can see that,
but he has kept
all his jelly jars.
[phone ringing]
Hi there.
- We're coming.
- It's Justin.
Heading to the airport now.
We have early business
in Dallas,
but we should be in
by noon tomorrow.
Well we are just as excited
as can be to meet Carrie.
What does she like to eat?
Oh, anything you make
is going to be great,
don't want you worrying to much.
And I got a turkey breast
and sliced it and froze it,
- Itineraries are?
- In the scheduling folder.
[beep]
[mother still talking]
Mom, listen I got another call,
yup we will see you then.
Can't wait.
We love you!
- We love you Justin.
- Love you.
Oh, hmm, he hung up.
[box rattling]
[doorbell rings]
One, two, three.
- Hey!
- Hi.
- Come in!
- Oh Carrie, look at that face.
- Oh. Hi.
- Hi, nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
[laughing]
- Lauren how are you?
- Good, how are you?
- I missed you.
- I know, I know.
- Thank you.
- Yeah sure.
She takes all kinds of pictures.
You get used to it really fast.
- Welcome, welcome, welcome.
- Thank you for having us.
- Your home is beautiful.
- Oh, thank you, thank you.
- Oh wow.
- Oh, that's Justin's Daddy.
He would be so proud
of all that your building.
He's just told me a little bit,
he looks just like him.
Yes.
- Oh, this is for you.
- Ohhh.
Oh, how beautiful.
It's got my name!
- It's a decanter.
- Oh and what's that for?
It aerates the wine
when you open it.
Oh well, we don't
drink that stuff, dear.
But, thank you.
Hey look Mom,
it can be a pretty vase too.
Oh, yes, well there you go.
Well, that's more my speed.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
One, two, three.
Now, I am going to seal
our leftovers in Ziplocs,
and we'll have them
for a snack tonight
when we get home from the party.
Oh everyone's going
to be so excited to see y'all.
I'm hoping to get some
boating time in too.
Carrie has never fished.
- How's that even possible?
- Right?
Maybe we all go.
If there's time. It's gonna
be an insane couple of weeks
making sure this
deal goes through,
so can't make any promises.
Well, I've got nothing going on,
so if you guys need any help.
- Oh thank you.
- Sorry, one sec.
This is Justin.
So, when are you heading back?
Spending a lot more
time here now, with this...
Yeah well we weren't really sure
how long the branch
set up here would take.
- So, no flights booked back yet.
- Yay!
(Lauren) I'm so happy
it's actually happening
Justin has been
talking about this forever.
Yeah, but my parents
will probably need us
back in Napa soon,
we're part of the
headquarters team,
but Kenny will run
the Vineyard here,
once it's set up, so thankfully
we don't have to stay.
But, we will
be be back and forth
I'm sure, and visiting a lot.
You just do what you need to do,
things were hectic for Averall
and I too at your age,
you've got each other and some
day you'll have more time.
Yeah, we really
work well together,
it helps with the chaos.
Oh, I understand,
such a blessing and you'd
be surprised how many people
never wind up finding that.
Lauren, Justin told me
about Nicole, I'm so sorry.
Oh, thank you.
Yeah, I just can't even imagine.
You know,
to be one of those that
has found what you were saying,
I... it's just not fair.
Well, that's not really
what I was meaning.
But, she was a real good friend.
Thank you.
Lobi Kenobi!
- Just fixing this real quick.
- Fun.
Don't want Carrie thinking,
you know,
going for charming
over hillbilly.
Hoping to win her over
to the dark side.
[Darth Vader imitation]
Oh my gosh.
Let me see those.
Okay, these earrings you added
kind of look like sperm now.
Yeah a little bit.
You wanna play?
Yeah.
- Take five.
- Okay.
All right, all right.
Do you have the guy who
is required to remain 200 feet
away from playgrounds?
- That guy?
- Yup, that's him.
You been... uh
You been Okay?
Yeah I've been totally Okay.
You have?
I really thought the timing
was gonna work out,
and we'd be here.
But, it all happened
so quick at the end.
I'm so sorry.
She was so great.
5pm, yeah, 5pm, right.
Sorry Lobi, can we...
Can we finish later?
We're on a really tight leash
right now and this designer
is taking his sweet time
with the labels.
Labels? Wine labels?
Yes, we will send them over
immediately, thank you.
[sighs]
I mean, I can help
you guys out with that.
If you have something already,
that's totally fine,
but you know that's what I do.
Well...
I'd love to help you guys out
Yeah.
You wanna take a crack at it?
There, we actually have
some bids out already, so...
Right, there are some bids out,
but we haven't
settled on anything yet.
Great, just tell me
what you guys want.
- I mean if it sounds fun, yeah?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Stacy, Stacy, look who's here.
- And look.
- Oh my God, I can't believe it
(Crystal) Wait until you see
Heather, she's about to pop.
Good to see you.
Hi how are you, Heather?
Hey!
Well hello stranger,
how are you?
- How are you?
- Good to see you.
I got both of my kids back,
I got Lauren and Justin.
Who has the "J"?
Think jelly bean.
(Justin)
And this little local start up
that Kenny and I
had in mind years ago,
well it could turn into
something pretty legit.
Once we convince the investors
to take a chance here,
Missouri and Kansas are next.
Lauren and Kenny used to go out.
- Right, I remember.
- Oh, I met him didn't I?
Carrie's been marketing
wine tastings for her family
since she was like a teenager,
tell em babe.
That's right, since I was a kid.
You don't drink
that stuff do ya?
I got dirty.
Now, why'd you do that?
Come here.
Lauren this might be
something good for you to do,
- we could sell it together.
- Yeah maybe so.
No, you all could be a lot
more generous than that
with your pours, I got plenty.
Excuse me,
really good seeing you.
Oh,
this place wasn't really built
with reception in mind, was it?
Nope, probably not.
- Feeling overdressed?
- They said party.
[sighs]
So, I've had vodka all along.
Don't tell anybody
Thank God.
I just wanna make sure
we get a prayer in,
before people start
needing to leave.
I know we've got bed times
for some of our little ones.
Also, I want to say
how excited we are
to welcome back
a few of our own.
Lauren, and Justin, and Carrie,
it's also so great to have you.
Justin, I was wondering if
you'd mind leading us in prayer?
I'd love to, yeah, Okay.
Um, well it's really great
to be back,
miss seeing a lot of your faces
some not so much.
- Oh, he didn't mean that
- I'm kidding, I'm kidding.
So let's go ahead and pray
before I make a fool of myself.
We just want to thank you
so much for this opportunity
to come together
friends and family,
to just celebrate the day,
and life, and...
I pray that you bless all of us
as we head out of here today,
keep us all safe,
in the days and weeks to come.
We love you.
In your holy name we pray. Amen.
- Amen.
- Go Sooners!
And the decanter
was a total bust,
I felt like an idiot.
We don't drink wine.
Well, I wish I had known that.
It didn't even occur to me babe.
I promise, she didn't think...
- it's not a big deal, I promise.
- Well, to me, it... I just,
I want them to like me.
- Never mind.
- They do, I can tell.
It's fine.
But Justin, the labels.
- They're already on their way...
- Shhh, stop, stop.
- The vent. She can hear you.
- Okay.
No, it's fine, you can tell me,
just do it quietly.
You know that the labels
are ready for shipping
and that my Dad
usually uses the same guy
- Why would you tell Lauren?
- You saw her face,
this will help her take her
mind off of all the other stuff
and then we'll just tell her
that your Dad uses a...
You know what, you're right.
It's not a big deal.
Sounds like it is.
Here, take the floor,
state your case, babe.
I just think... maybe
Lauren doesn't need
the distraction, I mean,
maybe you should just
let her feel it instead...
Here you go.
There's a wash cloth here,
you just gotta shove it
in the drain hole
if you need to take a bath.
Oh, thank you.
And I'm leaving
a night light on in the hall
in case you have to pee-pee.
- Thank you.
- Okay-dokey, well good night.
Justin, I fixing up the couch
- Oh, Mom let me do that.
- The couch?
Yeah, yeah, that's just
how it's done here.
Listen, can you set
a backup alarm for eight?
We have to be up
and at Kenny's by...
10, I have two set already.
You're perfect.
Night.
[sighs]
[bangs on barrel]
Hey.
- Hey!
- Sorry.
- Kenny!
- Hi,
- it's been a while.
- I know, how are you?
- Good, good, busy.
- Yeah.
That's great,
is Justin here or Carrie?
Yeah, out in the field
with my Mom.
Great.
I thought I'd see you
at the funeral.
Oh you went to the funeral?
Yeah, I, we
thought you'd be there.
Yeah, I was sick, but,
you went, thank you.
That's really sweet.
I mean you
didn't really have to go,
because you barely knew her,
but thank you!
Yeah, I just wanted to,
you're Okay?
I just, I really need
to go find Justin or Carrie
because they're
helping me with something.
But, thank you so much
for thinking of me
and congratulations on
all of this, this is so great!
Really good seeing you.
Yeah.
Good seeing you too.
This soil it'll grow anything
you've got in California,
- or Italy even.
- Wow.
Hi.
- Hey Darlin'.
- Hi, how are you?
- Good to see you.
- So good seeing you.
- You look good.
- Thank you.
I think I might know
what we need for the labels.
It's, uh, an idea.
But then I could do paintings
based on a whole collection.
You know, it's Heartland,
but it's like specific. Yeah?
I mean, either of you have
some time to come with me?
Um...
- The labels?
- Um hmm.
- If you guys hate the idea.
- Branding, Carrie's territory.
We'll cover you here, Okay?
We got time.
Yeah. She doesn't
want to waste her time.
No, this is not the place
that we should be.
Why not?
You afraid of old people?
This was our grandparents house.
Hi, hi.
We do not need to be doing this.
It's fine, Justin's probably
hoisted me over this fence
like 600 times,
it's totally fine.
- No
- Come on, Puss
I'm sorry did you
just call me a Puss-y.
No I called you a Puss,
it's different...
But you are pussy.
I'm not... a pussy.
I'll help you, turn around.
Jump, jump, jump.
[squeals]
Hi there.
You're a good dog.
What the fuck
are y'all doin' here?
Um,
do you care if my friend
and I take a few pictures
of you and your dogs?
Do you want me
to take my clothes off?
No thank you.
Well, make me look purdy.
Okay.
[dogs barking]
[gunshot]
[laughs]
Them's bird dogs.
[laughing]
For this it might be fine,
but that's just not
how branding works.
Hi, thank you.
Thanks.
Because then you have what,
six different logos
for one product?
Okay, just listen.
On the label there's
a section here,
where everything's the same
and then another section
with different art
for each type of wine.
Okay,
I like the graphic.
But let me just explain
a few key elements
to creating a brand.
You want Heartland.
Oklahoma, yeah?
This guy is Heartland.
Let me just have the floor
for two minutes.
What?
Let me present my side
and then you can counter,
the floor.
The floor.
It's a technique for
conducting business
that I learned in school,
we've adopted it,
I'm big on communicating.
Okay.
It works, gives me a chance
to express my concern,
before Justin
jumps in with a solution.
Just talk, I'll listen.
Name one successful product
that keeps changing
it's label design.
(Male) Wheaties.
Yes. Ha!
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Yes, thank you.
Yeah and so then
Justin and I got together
and they were
super psyched because
of his passion for growing.
My parents have been
in the wine industry
for four generations.
So, perfect.
What if this one
is the fourth composition?
- Yeah, I really love that.
- Yeah?
I do, almost more than
the snow cone stand.
Yeah, I think so too.
Yeah, so then that's what
you've always wanted to do too?
Uh, yeah, yeah, I mean I've
always known I was going to.
I'm an only child, so
pretty much always
known that I was going to
inherit the company
one day and all that.
Well, I mean that's good,
takes the guess work out, right?
Oh yeah, yeah.
You know,
I actually one time briefly,
campaigned to be journalist.
But then my dad and I
compromised
and I just ended up
taking journalism classes
while double majoring in
communications and marketing.
All right.
Let's drink more.
Wow.
I should probably forego
and finish this.
And tell him to get his ass
over here to drink with me.
I will do that for you,
but he's probably sleeping.
He really needs his rest.
Watch this.
Okay, Puss.
If you can stack a tower
higher than this
without making it topple,
then no shots for you.
Oh, please.
Okay? I'll be right back.
Thank you.
[sound of cups toppling]
Here you go.
- No.
- Yup.
- You said one shot.
- I predict more of that.
- Oh my God, cheater!
- Sorry! [Laughing]
- Shot, now.
- Okay.
I hate that.
- No you don't.
- I do.
- Carrie. Carrie, serious.
- Yeah?
Does Justin ever
purposefully wait to poop
until you're in the shower?
[laughing]
What the fuck?
He used to do that to me.
Well, use a lock.
That's gross.
Do you always drink like this?
Stop holding your cups steady,
- shot.
- Oh, no.
Are you always
this fucking blunt?
No, I'm usually more tactical
than this, but you know...
Well, I talk sometimes.
Doesn't mean I have to.
Well it might help.
Oh? Why is that?
Well, like I said I'm
a former communications major,
and I also grew up in
a very therapized community,
so I'm armed...
- Therapized?
- and dangerous.
Therapized?
That's not even a word
- I do not like you.
- Yes you do.
- No I don't.
- Hey no.
- I win. I win, right?
- She does not win.
(Carrie) Excuse me.
[laughing]
Whoo!
This is so much fun.
I cannot even remember
the last time...
I don't even know
what time it is.
Can you... can you drive?
There's a whole lot happening
over here right now.
No, I don't know to drive
one of these things.
- Really?
- Yeah.
[laughing]
[crying]
Hey. Woah, you Okay?
Hey, you Okay?
Uh, Lauren.
Uhh...
Okay. Um...
Let's get you home.
[sound of vomiting]
[coughing/sighing]
[laughing]
Oh my God.
You're a champ Lobi,
right here. Okay.
I got you, I got you,
let go, let go.
Oh man.
You are a mess.
What'd you do?
(Lauren) Not funny.
I hate you.
[birds chirping]
I have been working on this
going on three months now
And I was saving it to be
a wedding present someday if
well... I just have
to show it to you.
- Oh, wow. That's... so...
- Thank you
Now previously,
I had always just
bought a pre-made book
but I figured if I wanted
to make a true family heirloom,
then from scratch
was the way to go.
I bought these cardboard sheets,
and I covered it with fabric.
I just love paisley.
And I made these little ties.
Oh, there he is.
You have the prettiest eyes.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, and here to find
these particular stencils
I had to join up
on a site called Etsy,
- have you heard of that?
- Yeah.
Oh, there's their daddy.
That's Averall.
He passed,
near 15 years ago now.
Grain explosion. Terrible.
Oh, I'm so sorry,
Justin told me.
Some people just can't
be replaced, so why try?
Oh Averall, he could calm
any tizzy just by being there.
Just taking both hands in his
and well, I'm sure
you know how it is.
Bitsy got hold of it.
She was a biter, but it's
one of my favorite pictures
so I just had to keep it in.
Oh, that backpack.
We had to look everywhere
for that exact one.
- Peek-a-boo
- Oh, wow!
- That's so creative.
- Oh, isn't that clever...
I can't take credit for that,
but Justin had a tree-house
down at the lake,
Their daddy put it up for them
when they were little.
You should make him show
it to you while you're here.
Has he shown you around it all?
Hey Carrie,
can I talk to you for a minute?
Yeah.
Okay. I'm so sorry,
I'll be right back.
What's going on?
Fort Worth, gotta go tonight.
Turns out one of the investor's
sure thing isn't so sure.
Shit.
Okay. So...
- we're leaving like now?
- No.
One of us has to stay here
or the tasting obviously.
I don't want to go back
to your dad's people.
I promised new guys.
So you're leaving?
Makes the most sense, yeah?
Yeah, yeah.
When do you get back?
Two days, Monday.
Okay, so I'll handle the tasting.
Take over catering, printing,
you already sent in the deposit
for the speakers right?
Already done.
I really wanted to be here
with Kenny, and you.
This was the part I was
most looking forward to
and now I'm gonna miss it.
You're perfect.
All right, you've got this babe.
- Thank you.
- Breath.
Wait, wait.
Wait, wait!
Just a little
something something.
(Lauren) Where's he going?
(Carrie)Fort Worth.
Oh.
Last night was pretty, uh...
It was fun right?
Even though now
I can't find my keys.
I drove.
- You drove?
- Yeah.
Well that was
clearly a good idea.
- You girls want some ice water?
- Yeah.
It's getting hot.
[faucet turns on]
Oh, you should add visiting
the tree-house to that list.
Write down,
"See Justin's tree-house,"
and have him take you
when he gets back.
Very romantic.
Or could be I think.
So add that in.
This is more of an itinerary
for the important stuff,
so I will, yes. I definitely.
Doing that now.
I just have to show you this.
This is a pillow sham
embroidered by Justin's
great aunt from Denver.
- Oh.
- Isn't that pretty?
(Carrie)
The stitching is so pretty.
Oh, Lauren,
come hang out with us.
Yeah, I want to,
I'm kinda behind on the labels
right now though.
Oh...
And this, this is Justin's
great great grandmother
Johnson's wedding veil.
They saved it
from the 1923 flood.
Oh, wow.
Great great grandmother.
That's on my side.
We go way back.
We kind of need to sort
through the copyright issue
- before Justin gets back.
- Oh now? Oh, Okay.
If it's Okay with you.
Oh, now go ahead,
it's way over my head.
Thank you so much.
[sighs]
I thought she was gonna pull out
her great great great
aunt's wedding band.
Oh my God, give it a day.
Oh, thank you.
You are so welcome.
Can you check the tub
under the bed over there
and see if my mom
has a graphite stick?
Okay..
No I don't see any,
I'm pretty sure
I know what those are.
Shit,
I kind of need some of my stuff.
(Lauren) Hey.
Yeah?
Would you want to do something
crazy with me right now?
[cricket chirping]
No, no, no, no, we could
get into so much trouble.
[window squeaks open]
Taupe?
Yellow?
Neither.
It looks kind of like
our stucco back home.
Sonoma Beige, that's fancy.
At least they
boxed it all up for me,
that was nice.
Was this yours?
Yeah and hers.
- Nicole's?
- Right
[toothbrush falls in box]
[breath out]
Lauren I want to live here...
They're just going
to paint over everything?
Hey.
It would be easier
if it wasn't so dark in here.
[deep breath out]
I mean what's the etiquette?
It's all mostly her stuff.
Where's it all supposed to go?
Well, um, she have other family?
None that count.
Definitely belongs to you then.
Well then let's just take
what we have in here I guess.
It's all just stuff.
Well, your mom
has been through this before
maybe she has some ideas
to help you take more
and really sort through it.
She doesn't really like to talk
about that kind of thing.
- What?
- Nicole.
She's fine about it,
she's totally fine.
She just doesn't really
like it shoved in her face.
How would it be shoving it
in her face to ask for help?
Carrie. Not everyone's
a talker, Okay?
And that can work too. Just...
it can be a lot easier that way.
Okay.
[dog barking]
I understand, I'm just
asking you to take a look...
I think that you'll
really like her designs.
I know, I understand, Okay.
I'm just going
to call you back later. Bye.
Need help?
Honestly we've had a lot of this
covered for two weeks now.
So why are you still stressing?
Why does everyone in your
family think it's Okay
to read over my shoulder?
Boundary issues.
You put the tree-house
on the list?
I don't even know anymore.
I'm done.
[birds chirping]
(Carrie) Yeah, I know, but why
is she so obsessed with it?
I mean,
isn't everybody obsessed?
Aren't your parents obsessed?
I mean, I guess,
but they're not handing me
ancient wedding veils
or anything.
Yeah but I mean that's
what comes next you know,
that's what you do.
When we're ready I guess.
It's exciting to think
about though, right?
I mean, otherwise what are you
building all this for?
Yeah, I think, uh
things are just kind of coming
a little too fast right now,
honestly and, you know,
when I have time to think,
maybe I'll be feeling
a little bit more excited.
Yeah. Watch out.
Here.
- What an asshole.
- I know but
I didn't really mean
to stay that long anyways
I wanted to own my own shop.
I was saving for it too, but
this last year
got pretty expensive.
Do it, put that guy
out of business.
I'd do marketing for you.
Aren't you a little busy?
That's so cute.
Dad built it for us.
But Justin wouldn't
let me up at first.
So, I had
to sit right there, see.
He'd go up and he'd
jump off over and over
and I'd just sit here and watch.
May have thrown a fit or two.
- That is so mean.
- Oh my God, you have no idea.
Then, when dad died,
I hid up here for three days
and Justin found me and he'd
bring me string cheese.
He didn't really know
what to do so he's just sit here
and read to me, Stephen King.
Yeah, dad used
to read him to us.
I eventually felt bad for him
so I came down.
I have no idea how he did it,
taking care
of mom and I like that.
- May I?
- Oh yeah.
[laughs]
Hand me that.
Are you going in?
Yeah, it's fun.
You wanna try?
Uh, no, I think I'm good.
You should try, it's really fun.
[screams]
Come on!
Uh...
- Come on Puss! Come on!
- Hey.
[splashing]
[laughs]
[screams]
[laughing]
It's cold.
We should, get out.
Yeah.
[birds chirping]
[crickets chirping]
Well I'm glad it's going
so well, I had no doubts.
Mom and Lauren
being nice to you?
Oh yes, no shortage of nice.
- Lauren's pretty great.
- She's great right?
I'm kind of worried
about her though,
I feel like she's going through
most of this by herself.
Mom's been there.
Yeah, I'm not really sure
how much help she's been.
Nicole seems to be a topic
they've agreed to gloss over.
Even with Nicole?
No, I'll talk to mom.
Gotta fix that.
Okay.
Everything else Okay?
Yeah, I'm just, I'm tired.
Um, and, honestly
I've been thinking a lot
and um, I was just curious
was there ever an exact moment
that you and Kenny
knew that you
wanted to make wine?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Oh, uh, it was
a sixth grade field trip,
and then started
dreaming up ways we could
turn his parent's farm
into a vineyard,
to throw
stomping parties of our own.
Nice...
Yeah, I guess um...
I've never really
had a moment like that
about anything.
[sighs]
Babe I don't need you to...
Sorry, I mean
that was good advice, thank you.
I was just making
an observation.
Didn't know.
Could help though.
Well, I love you.
I love you too.
Hey, I'm gonna take
the extra bottles inside.
Oh, great, thank you so much.
[laughing]
[whistling]
Gotta show you something,
come on!
[giggling]
So these just came in.
The wine labels.
Oh, wow, those look really good.
Don't they Carrie?
Those look really good.
I'm going
to be right back Kenny,
I forgot something at home.
My dad usually uses the same guy
Well then why
didn't you tell me?
Justin said that this would
help you, you know, uh
I called my dad I did,
I really did.
You're gonna do great Carrie.
No please stay, please!
If Justin wants
to be so helpful,
then where's he been?
Fuck.
Hi. Hi welcome.
- The tasting this way?
- It is. Right this way.
[Vespa engine]
Our company not only wants
to expand, but broaden
adjust our image to appeal to
a more easy-going local market.
Red wine for this, white wine
for that, it's too stuffy.
What we like to say is
Heartland wine
goes with everything.
Our drinkers are approachable,
wine is now relatable,
and a local homegrown bottle,
attainable.
[clapping]
- Where did we eat last night?
- Cattlemans.
Oh I heard Cattleman's
is supposed to be great.
Um, can you all actually
excuse me for just one second.
I'll be right back.
Enjoy yourselves.
I'm so sorry.
Thank you for coming.
You were so great.
Thank you so much,
we're really excited.
- Thank you.
[glasses clink]
[laughing]
Oh God...
Hey!
Y'all want chicken?
Kenny, you want chicken?
No, that's not that song.
Jesus loves
the little children
All the children
of the world
- What a gentleman you are.
- Awww.
- Bye guys.
- Bye!
Kiss her.
[kissing noises]
- Kiss her.
- Kiss her!
Aw, aren't you cute, lover boy.
[kissing noises]
- Where you going lover boy?
- Kissing Kenny.
Kissing Kenny.
[kissing noises]
[screams]
[laughing]
[cell phone vibrates]
[tapping]
Carrie.
- Carrie.
- Yup?
- Hi, uh...
- Oh my God, my head.
Yeah, hey, Justin
just called eh...
No, no, no,
don't say anything. Uh...
I won't tell him
about the one before.
Before?
Shit.
I can't find my phone.
- Are there a dozen there?
- I think there are thirteen.
I still got a couple more
boxes in the trunk.
I never did get
Paulette to sign up.
Oh just keep her in your
back pocket, hon, you'll see.
Once you and Lauren start
making sales, it'll be fine.
[knocking]
Oh.
Oh, hi! Come on in.
So good to see you.
You girls,
you remember Kenny right?
- Hi there.
- Look at you tall boy!
Did you come by to visit Lauren?
No I actually found
this in my truck, Carrie's.
Oh well she's asleep
up in Justin's room,
you can go on up
just slip it under the door.
Lauren's been working
real hard on those drawings
you should take a look.
Okay.
He knows the way.
He's such a cutie!
It's not anywhere.
And he didn't leave a message?
No, oh God, I did not
remember the one before.
- Did anyone see?
- No, no, no. Oh God, oh God.
Okay, nothing even
really happened so,
it doesn't have to get weird.
[knocking]
Hey I'm sure he was just calling
to see how everything went,
all right you can call him
back on my phone if you...
[knocking]
Yeah? Come in.
What are you doing here?
I brought Carrie's phone
and your Vespa back,
but your mom said you wanted
to show me some drawings?
Oh, God no, she's...
no, never mind,
- she's... that's just my mom.
- Everything Okay?
Yeah, uh...
[phone vibrates]
Can we not do this right now?
Yeah, yeah, sure.
(Justin) Call me, call me.
He's in,
thought you'd wanna hear.
Call me.
Wanna tell you about it.
Kenny said your home safe
and that all went well
and the investors loved it,
so, it's a go,
huge day!
Can you call me?
(Carrie) It's not like I
purposefully didn't call you,
and the second I found it
I called you back.
Okay, you don't need
to get so defensive.
It's just really hard to be two
places at once as a team,
- if we can't communicate.
- Trust me, I know.
And it was a really
unfortunate day for an incident.
Justin!
Nothing went wrong,
I dropped my phone
and that is the only thing
that varied minutely from
all the details
that we discussed,
and planned,
and discussed again.
Let's not get upset.
[sighs]
[tornado siren]
Uh...
We can discuss it,
we'll share the floor
when I get back.
Just keep your phone
on you is all, Okay?
I'm keeping my phone on.
Is that a tornado?
Does that mean that
there's a tornado outside?
What's going on?
There's a siren.
All right it'll be Okay,
just find my mom.
Carrie? Carrie, hello?
[beeping]
Justin? Hello?
Hello?
[tornado siren]
You hear them sirens?
The Dogs'll be
peein' on the couch.
I gotta call home.
Mom?
Oh, bless her heart.
[laughing]
Lauren, go grab a mattress
and y'all two take the tub.
It'll be alright darlin'.
I think this
is her first tornado.
[tornado siren]
Oh God...
Wouldn't I be safer
away from the wall?
It seems safer where you are.
The whole room's built
in the center of the house,
we're safe.
Dorothy did not get into a tub.
Well Dorothy wound up in Oz.
- Ow.
- Sorry!
- Okay, here.
- No, no, no, no, no
You don't need this. Here.
We've never actually
had one touch down here.
[loud thunder crack]
Oh my God, oh my God.
- Do you wanna trade places?
- Uh huh.
No, no, no, please stay.
Okay.
Here.
Is that better?
Yeah, that's better.
Sorry, I'm...
just gonna...
[thunder]
You can tell how far away
the storm is by
counting the seconds
after you see lightening
until you hear the thunder
and that's how
many miles away it is.
Of course, we don't
see any lightening.
[thunder]
Sorry.
It's Okay...
I don't mind.
[thunder]
You still scared?
[hail]
[thunder]
[heavy breathing]
[moaning]
[thunder]
[heavy breathing]
[moaning]
[crying]
(Crystal) Lauren!
You girls got flashlights?
It's Okay, we have our phones.
Y'all survive it?
Yeah, we're good.
Hi.
Bless her heart.
Yeah, they're just fine,
just had a little wind is all,
and some hail.
Oh, sweetie, you wanna
speak to Justin?
Tell him,
I'll talk to him later.
- Okay.
- Hi, Justin!
- Hey Justin.
- Hey.
Yeah, everything's just fine.
Yeah, it's all good.
All right, here you go.
It's really good.
- Yeah?
- Isn't it?
And it's jammed packed
with antioxidants.
And Phyto nutrients
in digestible form.
My daughter got married
a year and a half ago,
how'd y'all meet?
Oh we, his internship, he...
at my parents vineyard.
Well we know that.
Yup, you do.
We, that's, yeah my dad...
really liked him
and sort of adopted him.
And... so he was
just around a lot and...
we just, you know,
kind of kept crossing...
- Paths?
- Paths, yup,
and I still remember
the first time I...
Oh when are y'all
just gonna get married?
[laughing]
You know, my son
got married four years back.
Now I got two grand-babies.
[laughing]
I'm so, I'm sorry, I'm so sorry.
This provides
a terrific opportunity
to supplement
a husband's income.
Yeah, just gotta get everyone
to drink the kool-aid.
[laughing]
Now, it isn't kool-aid.
Tell her why.
Oh, well, um...
Dynamic essentials.
Kool-aid doesn't have
dynamic essentials
Whenever somebody compares
Vitamade to an inferior product,
you jump right in and you
explain what makes our distinct.
I was just kidding,
I was just referring to...
No wonder
you're only second tier.
I signed her up 8 months ago.
By then,
I was already peach diamond.
Well, could be that working
with dementia patients
is kind of edging out the
pyramid scheme at the moment.
Maybe they could use some
dynamic essentials too.
[laughing]
(Carrie) I'm so... So sorry.
I don't know
what's gotten into me.
I'm sorry.
[laughing]
I'll be right back.
I'm so happy that you're showing
this sudden respect
for your mom, Lauren.
It's a long time prayer of mine.
You gave her a lot of grief,
but now it's really nice.
Please explain.
No, it's none of my business.
- It seems like it is.
- Lauren, now
I have something for you Sherri.
I have a magic ingredient
that's really
gonna help your sales.
Lauren, go to your
room this instant.
- Go to my room?
- Get out of here now!
I'm sorry, you can stay. Gail,
you can stay, please, Sherri.
Oh, Lauren!
What is wrong with you?
(Lauren) Who gives a shit
what they think?
(Crystal)
I care those are my friends
and let me tell you
something Missy,
there wasn't a meal you ate
after your daddy died
that those women
didn't fix for you.
Fine, but I...
I was defending you.
Why can't you just take my side?
(Crystal) I defend you
all the time. Believe me.
Babe, you survived
your first tornado warning,
- I'm so proud.
- Yeah, I...
It's a serious right of passage,
kind of fun though right?
Babe, can we go ahead and
book our flights back yet?
Who's hungry? Surprise!
Surprise babe!
Congratulations.
Look what I brought
for us to celebrate.
- Oh boy.
- Oh, look who's here.
Mom!
- Oh no, we gotta celebrate.
- Come on, let's eat.
I'm hungry.
That tornado took it out of me.
Book a cabin on lake
Eufala next weekend,
see if Kenny can
bring his boat down
and teach Carrie
how to fly fish.
Mom you think you could get
couple days off of work?
- Well I could sure try.
- Tell them we're celebrating.
Y'all scooch together.
Lauren, get over there.
Get over there next
to Carrie now, right now.
She's practically
your sister after all.
Mom!
I know.
Squeeze in there Lauren,
squeeze in.
One, two three... yeah.
Oh that's darlin', look at that.
Oh, that's so great.
We should probably
head back soon now.
We don't want
to leave my parents
carrying the load
of opening the new branch.
But I wanted to be here
to help Kenny,
at least through bottling.
- We have several weeks...
- Weeks?
We'll discuss it later
and I'll talk to your dad.
How are the labels coming Lobi?
Great! They're great.
I'm gonna go finish those.
Lauren, you didn't
even eat anything.
I'm not hungry!
She's so skinny,
she's gonna blow away.
Mom, no tornado jokes.
[laughing]
[text message alert]
You awake?
Look, I know
I know you're not.
I don't want you
to think that I'm like,
but now you're
in this big hurry to leave
and I don't want to not
ever see you, and, and,
you won't even look at me.
No, it's not because of you,
it's just,
what happened,
- that can't happen.
- No, that, that won't happen.
And Justin cannot ever know.
Justin, no, Justin cannot.
I would never, just,
I am so sorry,
but are you like, so freaked out
that you never want
to see me again?
No.
We're good.
Good, cause
it's meant a lot to me
that, you know,
not like that, just...
and I don't want to have like,
fucked all that up.
Or for you and Justin either.
No, No, Justin and I
are gonna be fine.
That's, that
is all good. Okay?
People freak out, you know?
- Uh, and I fucked up.
- No.
Yes, commitment is...
commitment is really, um...
It happens, you know?
And that does not mean that
Justin and I aren't gonna...
Shit...
Okay.
- Yeah, I really should go.
- Yeah, go.
I should go, but this
is not because of you,
it's just because I...
really don't belong here.
I get it.
[sighs]
[gasps]
Oh, you scared me.
What am I not
supposed to find out?
- What?
- The vent, I, I heard.
You guys seemed super upset,
what did you fuck up?
Just, uh, the labels.
Shit...
I know...
- Hang on, I'll handle it Okay?
- No, no.
No, Justin, Lauren, um,
I just told her
and she's pretty upset.
So, I, I, I handled it.
- No it's gonna be Okay.
- No, Justin, I handled it.
- It's gonna be Okay.
- Justin, I handled it.
[knocking]
Lauren?
God.
[knocking]
Lauren?
I know,
I shouldn't have done that.
Done?
Lied about the labels.
(Lauren) Oh, don't,
it's Okay, don't worry.
No, I should've said something.
I'm really sorry.
No, I really, don't worry.
Really, really, it's...
But Carrie said you were upset
and then you guys had
this intense conversation.
- So, are you?
- Yeah, I mean, yeah,
I'm angry Justin!
Like what was that, honestly?
Justin, was that some kind
of like, pity assignment?
I thought it would give you
something to take your mind off,
I don't know, and then it
turned into a big lie, and...
Yeah, it's fine.
that Carrie had
nothing to do with it.
She tried to tell me and look,
look, her dad uses
- Got it, got it.
- No, her dad uses the same guy
- maybe we can talk to him, yeah?
- Yeah, maybe.
And I'm, I'm sorry
that Carrie had to tell you,
Fine! Just, it's fine,
let's move on.
No, I don't want
you to be upset.
Justin, it was
my fault too, Okay?
I should've... I should've
told you that I knew, so...
But, but, Carrie just told you.
Okay, what's going on?
Carrie. Carrie please. Baby.
[crying]
I'm so sorry.
What happened?
It wasn't a planned thing.
No.
No, no, no.
(Carrie) Please forgive me.
There's no way, there's no way.
Are you kidding?
(Carrie) I'm so sorry.
(Justin) No!
That's my little sister!
Oh, you better believe
it's not going to happen again.
I mean, how did it even get to
this point? I was two days!
- A lot happened.
- Are you kidding me?
I don't get it.
I, I can't. Oh my God.
- Justin!
- No.
- I'm gonna talk to him.
- No, hey let me talk to him.
Lauren, please.
It's between me and Justin...
Lauren, what the fuck
were you thinking?
Stop it. I wasn't!
Too bad Nicole's not around,
I could even the score.
You don't say shit
about her, you hear me?
You were happy to be off
making your big important deals.
You were too busy for us.
Yes, I was busy.
I told you I'd be busy.
I am sorry your
girlfriend's dead.
Doesn't mean you get mine.
Got it, Justin.
You're very important.
I'm just gonna try
to stay out of your way.
No! You do not get
to twist this around.
You think I like
kissing ass all day?
Fuck you!
People make sacrifices!
Justin, you apologize
right this second.
Mom, go back to bed.
No sir, no siree bob,
I'll do nothing of the kind.
You apologize your sister
right this minute.
Okay I'm sorry,
just so sorry, that you
slept with my girlfriend!
(Carrie) Justin!
Okay we are not children,
I think we should talk
about this like adults.
- Please take the floor.
- Okay.
Something happened
and Lauren hasn't
really been in,
(Justin) To fuck her?
Feel sorry for me? No.
That's not what happened
- That is not what happened.
- Lauren is this true?
Two days! How?
I mean it was only
two days, right?
(Justin) Do you need a shrink?
I'm finding you a shrink.
- Justin!
- No, Google's great for this,
I'm worried, Carrie thinks
you need someone.
- Justin!
- We are not children!
- Stop it!
- Let go! Justin!
Ow, God!
- Why are you taking her side?
- I'm not.
Whatever, I'm done.
You can have her.
Please, I want you,
please let's go back to Napa,
Did you do this thing?
Lauren, did you?
Lauren just needed somebody,
to be there for her
- Stop! I don't...
- Oh my God, its such bullshit,
- I'm going Justin.
- Go, you're so fucked.
- Language.
- You're fucked!
- You are!
Stop it, that's enough,
out of both of you.
This is the last straw.
I have, I have been forgiving,
and I tolerated that...
thing with that friend of yours.
Mom, nobody really
likes being tolerated.
Great, now I'm defending you.
(Crystal) This is my home.
You did this thing in my home?
I tried to help you.
I gave you a place to stay,
I tried to get you work,
I made you meals.
Yeah, you're great.
Who would guess
that you're a bigot?
[knocking]
Hey, is it cool if I chill
with you for a little bit?
- Yeah, sure, sure.
- Thank you.
- Everything Okay?
- Oh yeah, yeah, yeah.
I just uh... is it Okay
if I chill here with you?
- Can I get you anything?
- Oh my God, it's late.
- Yeah.
- Were you asleep?
- No, not yet.
- Oh, good.
Um, oh, no, no
I'm good, thank you.
Okay. Just make
yourself at home.
Thank you.
I've never seen
your place before.
- This is, looks really good.
- Thank you.
Is that your Dad's?
Yes, yeah.
[crying]
I've just missed you.
- You Okay?
- Yeah...
What are you?
- It's Okay, Kenny, it's Okay.
- Are you drunk?
What are you doing? Lauren!
Hey, um.
[sighs]
- I'm gonna go.
- No, hey, you don't have to...
- No, I'm fine. I'm fine Kenny.
- No, you're obviously...
You keep acting
like nothing happened.
It's fucked up.
What do you want, me to cry
for the rest of my life?
No, you don't get to tell me
how to handle this. No!
I was there,
I was there for all of it,
I was there to remind her
what her catheter was,
every time she
tried to take it out
and I was there
to rock her when it hurt,
because she would do it anyway!
I was there to shave her legs
in the bathroom sink
when she still cared
what the nurses thought.
And I was there to feed her,
when she didn't care
about anyone else.
At all. Okay?
I am not fucked.
I am not fucked!
[Vespa engine revs]
Lauren!
(Justin) How do we go forward?
Please, please,
don't make the mistake of
it was just a one time thing.
I'll call your dad,
I'll let him know.
You always do this.
You jump to a solution.
Isn't that one of
the off-limit words
in your communications rulebook?
Effective communication
makes for a strong team, Justin.
This is a strong team?
Yes, are you kidding me?
Babe, we convinced
four Napa bred investors
to buy into a vineyard
in Oklahoma.
- I mean, Oklahoma.
- Go us.
- That's not...
- And fuck you,
I'm so glad to hear
my dream of local wine
is so preposterous to you.
Not surprised.
You made it very clear
how much you hate it here.
Why don't you just decide
where all the branches go.
Justin, I don't care where the
branches go, I honestly don't.
Well I do care!
I care about this branch.
I know you do,
and of course I care. I just,
I've been doing
everything in my power
to make this happen for you.
What do you mean for me?
This was our future.
What future are we
talking about right now?
Are we talking about business
or are we talking about us?
Or is there even a difference?
What's the point in drawing
a line Carrie, either side...
- You can't fix this.
- this is the problem
- just listen.
- Oh, is that it? Lauren listens?
That is so pathetic, Carrie.
What are we even doing?
It's fucked.
Well, that's your choice.
Is it?
Because it seems like
it was your choice.
[crying]
[deep breath]
[whimpering]
[crying]
[sighs]
[cuckoo clock chimes]
(Female) Three bedroom,
one bath and the last tenant...
[door opens]
(Carrie) It just doesn't
make sense anymore,
for him to come back with me.
I've had more with you,
than I've had
in two years with Justin.
I just feel like,
if you guys tried
- then maybe.
- I don't want to.
You know that none of this
was ever about
feeling sorry for you, right?
Yeah I do.
I've just been such a mess
and
I'm really glad
that you were here.
Me too.
[car pulls up]
Justin, Justin. I know
you don't want me here,
I'm not going to stay,
I promise you, Okay?
I did these for you.
And you haven't seen them,
I just want you to,
just have them.
It's mostly stuff you showed me,
and places we went
when we were kids.
This one's great.
[paper tearing]
No thanks.
I was gonna be head
of the whole Midwest operation.
The whole thing, you know?
Could've been a big deal.
- Still can be.
- No, no.
- We had a three year plan to...
- You know what I think?
I think this whole thing,
this whole fiasco
sort of saved you
from becoming a...
Oh God, have you been
talking to her?
No, I have been watching you,
on the rare occasions
you're around
stressed as fuck over some shit
that I know you
couldn't care less about.
We worked very hard.
Tell me you're
happier in a board room
talking quarterly bullshit
than you are
right here.
I mean, if you're really
into it though, you know,
tell me to shut up.
[birds chirping]
Come on.
Kenny told me you were here.
I was surprised.
I don't know how to,
[deep breath]
I am so sorry.
I know that's not enough,
I know.
I know it's enough, but I am.
Chapter one.
Once in a kingdom
called Delaine,
there was a king with two sons.
Delaine was a very old kingdom
and it had hundreds of kings,
perhaps even thousands.
When time goes on long enough
not even historians
can remember everything.
Roland the Good
was neither the best
nor the worst king
ever to rule the land.
He tried very hard
not to do anyone great evil
and mostly succeeded.
He also tried very hard
to do great works,
but unfortunately he didn't
succeed so well at that.
The result was
a very mediocre king.
be remembered
long after he was dead.
[boxes sliding]
[knocking]
Lauren.
Did you lose your key?
Um, no.
Good.
I came to get my boxes,
and I wanted to tell you
that I was sorry...
and stuff.
Is Justin here?
He is.
Okay.
That's for you.
Well, thank you.
- Okay bye.
- Take care.
Can I ask you?
When Nicole was dying,
why didn't you just
come to the hospital?
Oh, honey, I told you
- I tried, more than once.
- Yeah,
but I needed you there with me.
Oh, honey she was
your friend, not mine.
My girlfriend.
Oh for pity's sake, Lauren,
do we have to do this?
No.
Bye Mom.
[screen door squeaks]
[gasps]
Oh Averell.
[screen door squeaks]
[tap, tap]
Can I ride along?
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org