我仍然不知道 世界之大 何处为家
I still don't know where we fit in the world.
我以为放弃信仰就能减轻
I thought leaving faith behind would relieve
我一直以来的负罪感
the dissonance I always felt.
并没有
It didn't.
一路走来 才发现我一直试图抓住某些价值
Through it all, I find myself holding onto these values.
我曾经的属灵同伴 Chris也一样
So does Chris, my former mission companion.
出于某些原因 在探索这条道路上
For one reason or another, we've had trouble
我们遇到了麻烦
finding our way.
我已经一年没有见过他了
It's been a year since I've seen him,
明天他就要回来北镇了
and tomorrow, he comes back to the Northwest.
我们已经说好忘记以前的事重新开始
We've agreed to put it all behind us and start fresh,
不受教会家庭和距离或者其它什么事
uninhibited by the Church, our families, distance,
的影响
or anything else.
这是我们应得的
We deserve that.
所有人都是
Everyone does.
* 你是否想坠落 *
* Don't you wanna fall *
* 你是否想翱翔 *
* Don't you wanna fly *
* 你是否想垂吊悬崖边 *
* Don't you wanna be dangled over the edge *
* 体验危险浪漫 *
* Of this aching romance *
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
真不敢相信 你明天就回来了
I cannot believe you're going to be here tomorrow.
我也是
I know.
终于可以把你介绍给我的朋友了
I can introduce you to all my friends finally.
我也可以把你介绍给我朋友
I can introduce you to my friend.
嗨
Hi.
- 嗨 Kaylee  - 海
- Hi, Kaylee.  - Hi.
你好吗
How are you?
很好
Good.
真受不了 你是在太可爱了
You are so cute, I can't even stand it.
已经超过睡觉时间了
It's past her bedtime.
想要道个晚安吗
Do you want to say goodnight?
- 晚安  - 晚安 Kaylee
- Goodnight. - Goodnight, Kaylee.
好了 带上Gillian 去洗漱一下
All right, wanna take Gillian, and go brush all your guys' teeth.
上帝保佑你
God bless you.
也保佑你
Gesundheit.
我马上就要见到你了
I'll be in tuck you in just a sec, okay.
很高兴能见到你
I'm so excited to see you.
我也很高兴能见到你
I know, it'll be good to see you, too.
我想我也该睡了
I better hit the hay as well.
耶 嗯
Yeah, um...
额 既然我们讨论了这事
Uh... so I know that we discussed this,
看得出来你一直想要知道
and I know that you're trying to figure it all out,
我想说的是
but I just want to say that...
我很欢迎她下次
you know, she's more than welcome
能够和你一起来
to come up with you next time you come up,
如果没关系的话
if that's okay.
耶 不是  我会考虑的
Yeah, no, I'll think about that.
很好
Okay, great.
嗯 晚安 再见
Well, goodnight, I'll see you soon.
耶 晚安
Yeah, goodnight.
我爱你 我爱你 Chris
I love you, I love you, Chris.
就是 我爱你
Just... I love you.
我为什么无法像正常人那样说呢
Why can't I just say that like a normal person?
RJ?
Okay 耶 嗨
Okay, yeah, hi.
嗨 不是 我还在 需要我挂电话吗
Hi, no, I'm still here, did you want me to hang up?
- 额 当然 这  - 或者我挂
- Well, sure that'd be... - Or I can.
我不想挂你的电话
Not that I want to hang up on you.
- 我知道  - 好
- No, I know. - Okay.
- 好了 晚安  - 耶 晚安
- Alright, goodnight. - Yep, goodnight.
拜
Bye.
* 骑那大家伙 *
* Ride the big one *
* 你是否想坠落 *
* Don't you wanna fall *
* 你是否想翱翔 *
* Don't you wanna fly *
* 你是否想垂吊悬崖边 *
* Don't you wanna be dangled over the edge *
* 体验危险浪漫 *
* Of this aching romance *
* 我想知晓是否已到尽头 *
* If it's going to end then I wanna know *
* 用尽我的一生 *
* Let me squeeze out every moment *
* 此生若无余剩 *
* But if there's nothing left *
* 可否知晓我缘由 *
* Can you tell me why *
* 你怀抱我时 *
* That it is you're holding onto me *
* 犹如坠入世界的尽头 *
* Like it's the end of the world *
嗨
Hey.
谢谢你来接我
Thanks for coming to get me.
你看起来很帅
You look good.
- 谢谢  - 你是不是瘦了
- Thank you. - I think I lost a little weight.
看起来更帅
It looks good.
谢谢
Thanks.
真高兴你能来
I'm really happy you're here.
从没想过你还愿意和我说话
I didn't think you'd ever speak to me again after the...
我说过原谅你了 我没开玩笑
I said I forgive you, and I meant it.
我想别人肯定很疑惑
I just think people were legitimately confused
为什么两个男人会在我父母的结婚纪念日上接吻
why two men were kissing at my parents' anniversary party.
我只是想要知道答案
I was trying to make a statement.
嗯 看来是拿到答案了
Well, mission accomplished.
你知道我很高兴你能见一下Adina和Sheris
You know I'm excited for you to meet Adina and Sheris.
耶 他们听起来很棒
Yeah, they sound great.
还有我的朋友Ryan
Any my friend Ryan.
他是你跟我讲过的那个
Oh he is the returning missionary
新来的教士
you were telling me about?
很好
Great.
是的 我会出席
Yeah, I'll be there.
好的 代我问好
Okay, give her my love, please.
好的 谢谢
Alright, thank you.
好 拜
Okay, bye.
有时候感觉好像还没离婚
Sometimes it feels like I'm still married.
谢谢
Thanks.
你饿了吗
You hungry?
我吃得下
I could eat.
我在这会让你们难堪吗
Am I that hard to be around?
不会
No.
医疗销售怎么样
So how is life after pharmaceutical sales?
额 到目前为止还没听到
Well, I haven't heard back from any of the schools
任何回应
that I've applied to.
我对这事倒不担心
I've got my heart set on sticking close to home.
你的写作怎么样了
What about you, how's work?
还不错
Work's going well.
只是有段时间没写了
I haven't written anything original in a while.
我忘了跟你说
I forgot to tell you my sister read
我妹妹看过你的一本书
one of your books.
哦 哪一本
Oh, which one?
很黄的那本
The really dirty one.
耶 告诉她我很抱歉
Yeah, tell her I'm sorry.
只是她知道你讲的是我们的事
It's just that she knew you were talking about me,
这有点
and it was like...
我知道 这就是为什么我要道歉
I know that's why I'm apologizing.
Chelsea最近怎么样
How is Chelsea?
她很好 只是Greg的事我没说
She's good, it's Greg that I don't talk to,
但你已经知道了
but you already knew that.
他们知道你现在在这里吗
Do they know that you're here with me right now?
我妈知道
My Mom does.
至于我爸 他
My Dad, he's...
我们来放松一下吧
Let's loosen up.
好的
Okay.
不 我不喝酒
No, I don't drink.
来吧 你又不去哪里
Come on, you have no where else to be.
我多久才见你一次
How often do I get to see you?
好吧 就一杯
Alright, I'll do one.
再来一杯
Another one?
- 你知道你不能把我灌醉  - 我才刚到这
- You know you can't get me drunk. - I just got here.
我没有想把你灌醉 自然而然的
I'm not trying to get you drunk, it's just happening.
我们为什么需要这么久才能变得舒适
Why does it take us so long to get comfortable?
我不知道
I don't know.
感觉在你面前 我还是会紧张
I feel like I still get...nervous around you.
耶 我也会紧张
Yeah, I get nervous, too.
虽然已经过了这么久了
After all this time.
耶 因为我们都有一颗颤抖的心
Yeah, we're just two fluttering hearts.
- 我好想你  - 我也是
- I missed you. - I missed you.
知道吗 我觉得我可以做
You know, I think I can do
任何疯狂的事
this whole Northwest thing.
什么 你正做的不就是吗
What? You are doing it.
哪些
What?
你正和带胡子的男人约会
You're hanging out with gay, bearded men,
还有喝酒
and you're drinking beer.
要不要做点像盐湖城那种疯狂事
And what about the Salt Lake City thing?
什么方面的
What about it?
你敢吗
Could you do it?
我觉得你勉强可以
I think you could barely do it.
额 我想最好还是不要
Well, maybe you won't have to.
好
Okay.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我进去拿点啤酒
I am headed back to your house to get some more beer.
你不是说过不喝酒的嘛
I thought you said you weren't drinking.
帅哥 都是你惹的
You, sir, have opened the flood gates.
我已经没有退路了
I'm past the point of no return.
别走 这事可不能怪我
You can't just say that and then walk away.
太迟了
Too late.
拜托
Come on, ugh.
你会没事的
You'll be okay.
- 我认为它  - 有点干
- I think it's... - It's a little dry.
我们会没事的
We'll be okay.
我很好
I'm good.
- 嘿 你 额   - 自从上次分开
- Hey did you... - sleep with anybody else
你和其它人做过吗
since I saw you last?
离开盐湖城后我和Paul做过一次
I had sex with Paul after Salt Lake.
这个我知道
I knew about that.
我说的是之后
I saw you after that.
有 我只是不知道还能再见到你
Yeah, I just didn't know if I'd ever see you again.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
你有男朋友吗
Was there anybody else?
嗯 或者一夜情什么的
Um, like a night here, and a night there, but nothing real.
耶 我有破坏婚姻的坏习惯
Yeah, I had to break a couple bad habits myself.
还有什么比这更坏
What makes them bad?
只是 换个地方
Just, oing places, and...
认识新朋友
meeting people.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think about that?
我觉得我们不应该一直这样
I think that we shouldn't feel like we're bad people
妄自菲薄
all the time.
做爱很正常 你懂的 我们是需要发泄的
It's okay to have sex, you know, we're supposed to cum.
我们本应该如此的
We're supposed to cum.
我们是动物 这很正常
We are animals, it's okay.
我们很正常
We're okay.
不要 不要随意断定我
You're not, you're not going to judge me?
我没有
No.
我只是希望我们能够打开天窗说亮话
I just wanted to get it all out in the open.
耶 这样很好
Yeah, it's fine.
我们把所有的事情摊开讲清楚
We can get everything out in the open.
还有多少件事没有摊开讲
Every last thing we can get out in the open.
三 二 一
Three, two... one.
嘿
Hey.
早上好
Good morning.
来杯咖啡吗
Do you want some coffee?
我是摩门教的 先生
I am a Mormon, sir.
现在才说你是摩门教的
So now you're a Mormon?
阿门
Amen.
起来 起来
Get up, get up.
起来
Get up.
哦
Oh.
什么
What?
我的口气
My breath.
我不介意 快点
I don't mind, come on.
我介意
I do.
快点 来吧
Come on, go.
我还没有准备好
I wasn't ready for that.
那你为什么叫我做
Then why did you tell me to do it?
开个玩笑
I'm just kidding.
我去做煮早餐
I'll go make us some breakfast.
嘿 你想吃什么类型的煮鸡蛋
Hey, how do you want your eggs cooked?
怎么什么都这么亮
Everything's so bright.
因为现在是白天
It's called day.
谢谢你的早餐
Thank you for breakfast.
不用谢
You're welcome.
你头在哪受伤的 那里
Where does your head hurt, there?
这里  喔
Right here. Oh.
嗯 你应该多喝点水
Well, you gotta drink more water.
继续
Keep going.
好了 我再去给你盛点
Here, I'm going to get you some more.
- 谢谢  - 嗯嗯
- Thank you. - Mm-hmm.
"新来的教会指导表示同性家庭的孩子
"New IDS guidelines say children of same-sex couples...
不能接受洗礼仪式"
will not be baptized in the Church."
我知道你想争论这个
I know you want to discuss this,
但是能不能给我点时间
but if you'll just give me a moment
- 读完这篇报道  - 他们开玩笑的 对吗
- to read the whole article. - They're joking, right?
上面说由于同志家庭的小孩不能被同等对待
It says they're doing this for their own protection,
所以这样做是为了
that children from gay marriages can't be treated
保护他们
like everyone else.
免受更多来自同志父母的罪恶
Punishing children for the sins of their own fathers.
真不敢相信
We don't even believe in that.
你可以随你瞎掰
You can interpret this any way you want,
但是我受够了
but I am done.
我在说什么
I don't think you mean that.
那是Adina
That's Adina.
哈喽 嗨
Hello, hi!
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi!
我是Adina 久仰大名
I'm Adina, I've heard so much about you.
我是Chris
I'm Chris.
耶 我知道
Yeah, I know.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
耶 这是什么
Yeah, what's this?
什么
What?
你的挚爱终于回来了
The love of your life is finally here,
你却给他吃这个
and you make him this?
额 我只有这个
Well, it's all I had.
Sheris去哪了
Where's Sheris?
不清楚
Not sure.
一切都还好吧
Is everything okay?
不怎么好 不过我没事
No, but I'll be fine.
来吧
Come on.
什么
What?
我又不舌吻 来吧
I'm a lip kisser, come on.
哦
Oh?
什么 你和女人结过婚的 这无所谓的
What, you were married to a woman once, you'll be fine.
他的嘴唇好软
He has soft lips.
前后前后
Back and forth?
耶 这有点像
Yeah, you know it's like...
不是 那是上下上下
No, that's up and down.
放一起
Together.
我假定人是站着或蹲着拉屎
I assume that people poop up and down.
停 换一个 关于眼睛的
Okay, moving on, having anuses for eyes.
- 嘿 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey. Hey. - Hey.
- 嘿  Ryan  - Chris
- Hey. Ryan. - Chris.
哦 终于见到你了
Oh, it's great to finally meet you.
- 谢谢  - 很高兴见到你
- Thank you. - Nice to meet you.
嘿
Hey.
- Ryan  - Anya
- Ryan. - Anya.
Steve  很高兴见到你
Steve. Nice to meet you.
- 嘿  - 嘿 哥们
- Hey. - Hey, buddy.
你们没等我就开始了
Oh, you guys started without me?
耶 而且玩得很开心
Yeah, we had some really great ones,
不过我想你无所谓
but you can still deal yourself in though.
只是你得赶上我们
But you gotta catch up.
好了 那七张 选两张
Yeah take seven and pick two.
Chris 你打算待多久
Chris, how long are you in town for?
明天过后就回去
Oh just through tomorrow.
回去工作还是
You have work or?
我有一个六岁的女儿
I have a six-year-old daughter.
- 哦  - 真的
- Oh! - Really?
你做什么工作 Ryan
And what do you do Ryan?
按摩师
Oh, I'm a masseur.
你做按摩师多久了
How long have you been doing that?
嗯 其实我才刚刚结业 才刚开始做
Oh, I actually just graduated, so I'm just starting out.
而且RJ是我唯一的客户
Actually RJ is my only client.
你是唯一的客户
You're only client?
其实我早就想走人了
Yeah, I'm hoping it'll take off.
It's mostly word of mouth, but he's giving me lots
of practice.
We all know how tense he gets, right.
Wow, maybe like a website or business cards.
Yeah, you know, I gotta handle that side as well.
I'm feeling it out, literally.
- Good card. - It's so accurate, too.
- Your turn. - Oh, sure, okay.
Lifetime presents, A Sad Handjob: The Story
of a Homoerotic Volleyball Montage.
I'd watch that.
I can't believe I'm smoking pot with you, Chris.
Your dad's a member of the Quorum.
Yes he is.
- Yeah, that's a tough
one for us right now.
- Yeah, I heard...
- but to be expected.
- So where did you serve
your mission, Ryan?
- I spent my mission
in Mexico City
It was beautiful...
and so was my companion.
For a year straight...
he would always change
in front of me...
totally innocent,
but he knew what he was doing.
And then one night,
we were on a bus
heading back to our district, and
I fell asleep on his shoulder.
While I was sleeping,
he had taken my hand,
and he was holding it
in a patriarchal grip.
I woke up... like this...
and I looked up
into his eyes, and...
I saw a lust and love
and longing...
but I also saw
this deep sadness...
because we both knew
we could never be together...
and it would just be this moment
in the back of a bus.
We got sent home shortly after.
I haven't seen him since.
But seeing you guys
together after so long...
it gives me hope.
I'm going to go.
- Really?
- Yeah...
- It was nice to meet you.
- Yeah, you too.
- Are you okay?
- Not really.
- Hey, hey, hey...
Love you.
- Love you, too.
- Where did you guys meet?
- Um, we met at Affirmations.
It's like a support group
for recovering Mormons.
- Yeah, I know what it is.
- Yeah, his parents kicked
him out of the house.
- Wow.
- I don't know,
I feel bad for him.
He's out here without
no family or friends.
- Wow.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- You coming?
- Oops, sorry.
- It's okay.
- Have you and Ryan ever...?
- No.
- He sure loves you.
- Do you love me?
- Do you want some water?
What are those?
- Oh, I have pressure
points in my back.
- What's wrong with your back?
- Just all those years of
carrying around a heavy suitcase.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Whoa, it got chilly.
Can I ask you something?
- Sure.
- Would you consider going to
a sacrament meeting with me?
- Chris, I just don't
know what the point is.
- I don't think it's
coincidence that you live
only a few blocks
away from the war.
It's not too late to come back.
- Where do you think I've gone?
- Not far, unless all of that
stuff in your living room
is just for show.
- I'm still trying to figure
out what they're trying
to say with this announcement.
By the way...
did you know?
- What?
- About the policy, did
you know before they made
the announcement?
- No... You honestly think
that I knew about that.
- I don't know, I just... I don't
know, I thought that if you did,
maybe there was something
you could've done about it.
- I don't know.
- Like what?
- Talk to your father.
- What possible
good would that do?
- I don't know, he's
like an inside voice.
One of the twelve
apostles has a gay son.
I mean if that's not a prophecy,
then I don't know what is.
Do you ever think about it?
What it would be like?
- What?
- I think about it
all the time...
with you, getting married...
in the Church with
the Sealer above us,
my parents and your parents.
I do... but it's not
going to happen.
Not like that.
You know what the Church does?
They convince me more and
more that maybe Joseph Smith
really did make it all up.
- Don't do that.
- How can you be a part of
something that alienates
parents from their children?
Don't you understand
what this means for you?
- I've stuck with the
Church through all of its
flaws and idiosyncrasies,
just like I've stuck with you
through all of these years.
- What are you talking about?
I'm done with it,
I've had my fill.
- No, you gave up,
that's different.
- And you don't have
the courage to leave.
- I don't want to leave.
- How are you okay with
the way the treat you,
or the way they treat your
family or your daughter?
As a father, how
do you accept that?
- Everything I do is for her.
You can question my beliefs
as a man of the faith,
but don't you ever question
my devotion to my daughter.
- I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
- What am I doing here?
What am I doing?
I just feel obligated
to you, you know.
I just keep coming
back and coming back
because it's all that I know.
- Wow.
- Ricky?
- Hey... are you alright?
Hey.
What's wrong?
Are you alright?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Easy, easy,
Okay.
What's wrong? Hey, look at me...
I'm right here.
Breathe... Are you alright?
- I get these sometimes.
- Hey, hey... Alright,
Alright.
Back to real life.
- This is real life.
I'm sorry we keep
fucking things up.
- You don't have to be sorry.
- Okay.
- Thanks.
- Call Chris.
- Say the list
number of the one you...
Calling the mobile
number for Chris.
- Hello.
- Chris, Chris, I just heard.
I'm so sorry.
Is there anything I can I do?
Would you consider
coming to Salt Lake?
Yeah.
- I can make
all the arrangements.
- No, don't worry about it.
- I'll get there.
- The service is tomorrow.
- Yeah, that's fine.
- Okay,
I'll send you all the details.
I'll see you soon.
- Are you okay?
- It'll just be
good to have you here.
- Yeah, I want to
be there with you.
- I'll see you soon, RJ.
- Okay, I love you.
- Elder Merrill's
gonna pitch a fit when he sees you.
I think I'd like
to be there with you.
- Uh...
- I just-I think I should
do it alone.
- Look, son,
I never told you this, but...
I had a conversation with him.
- Wait, when?
- We talked when you were
in Salt Lake City with Chris.
I was a bit direct.
- How so?
- Doesn't matter now.
Back then I had my reasons.
- Um... okay.
What does Mom think?
- She backs me up on this.
- What about your foot?
- It'll be fine, RJ.
- Okay.
- Alright, son, I'll see you
in the morning in Salt Lake.
- Yeah, I'll see
you in the morning.
- Alright, bye.
- Bye.
- Where are you headed today?
- Uh, Utah.
- Will you be checking
any bags today?
- No thanks.
- There you go, sir,
have a good flight.
- Thank you.
- Hi, thank you.
Hey.
Hi.
Thank you for coming.
Thank you.
Thank you, guys.
- Hi, Kaylee.
- Hi.
- You look really pretty.
- Thank you.
- I like your shoes.
- She gets a little shy.
- It's okay.
- I'm glad you're here.
- Me too.
- Hey, shall I take
her for a little why?
Yeah absolutely, you wanna
go with Grandma, honey?
Yeah.
I'll see you later, sweetie.
You look good.
- You too.
- Thanks.
- I'm sorry.
- It's a very tough situation.
- It's challenging, yeah.
- Yeah.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, he's walking over here.
- It's gonna be fine.
- I'm right here.
- I think they're
starting to recognize me.
- They probably are.
Hey, just don't kiss me.
Sorry, that wasn't funny.
- RJ.
- Elder Merrill, I want you to
know I'm very sorry for your loss.
- I appreciate that.
Chris didn't tell me
that you were coming.
- I invited him, Dad.
- Elder Merrill,
I'm Tom Smith, RJ's father.
- Oh, right.
- I can't begin to know what
you're going through right now.
Saying sorry isn't enough
to express my sympathies.
- Thank you, Brother Smith.
- And you must be Chris, brother Smith.
- Yes.
I've heard so many
great things about you.
Welcome.
What happened?
- Oh, an accident at work.
- Elder Smith,
I thought that was you.
How are you?
- RJ, are you okay, son?
- I'm sorry.
- RJ?
- Excuse me.
Easy, hey, easy.
- I'm so sorry.
- It's okay.
- That was so weird.
- Yeah.
- Our mission president...
and the look that your father
gave me, he hates me.
- Okay. Okay.
- He doesn't hate you.
- I just wanted to
be here for you.
- You are, you're here.
Rest.
Easy, easy, easy.
There we go, there
we go, there we go.
- They're gonna be alright.
- Yeah, why don't you
and RJ stick around,
and we'll get some dinner?
- Oh, Elder Merrill, I couldn't
intrude on your mourning.
- We need to have a talk.
We need to have a
candid conversation,
and I would like you and RJ
to join us for dinner tonight,
alright?
- Absolutely.
- Good, thank you.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
So, I hear you're
going to law school.
- I'm still applying.
- I bet your mother was proud.
- Yeah, she was.
As far as she was concerned,
I was already practicing law.
- My old mission companion
became an attorney.
I saw him and some of my
other companions recently.
We met up for a night, and
life didn't skip a beat,
let me tell you.
We picked up right
where we left off.
We shared our blessings,
and our tragedies,
love and heartbreak.
Some of them... I had no idea
what they were going through
back then.
It's nice to have
people in your life
you can depend on.
- I'm Greg, Chris's brother.
- Thomas Smith, RJ's father.
- It's good to see you again.
- Thank you.
Did you know my mother?
- Okay, Greg, I know that
you don't care much for me,
so maybe we should...
- I would like to sit
here and mourn my mother
without the shadow
of my brother's past
looming over this sacred moment.
- I'm sorry.
- May I have that?
- You're really going to
do this right now, Greg?
- Our father asked me to
be here, and here I am.
Dad.
- Boys, Brother Smith, RJ.
- Elder Merrill.
- Good to see you.
- I didn't know what to get, so I
got a variety of foods, pad Thai.
- I hope Thai is
good for everyone.
We didn't have much left
after the reception, so...
Looks good, nice and hot.
Brother Smith, would
you like to pray for us?
- Elder Merrill, I'd
be honored if a member
of the Quorum would
say a blessing.
- Okay, call me Noah, alright?
- Let's pray.
Our Heavenly Father,
thank you for bringing
Tom and RJ safely to us
today and as our families
come together, please help
us guide our conversation,
help us discover what
is best for everyone,
in the name of
Jesus Christ, Amen.
- Amen.
- Brother Smith and RJ,
thank you both
for being here today, it was
very gracious of you to come.
I have to make clear right
now and bear testimony
to each of you that...
sexual relations
between two of the
same sex is wrong.
By doing so, our children
become apostates,
and should be culled
from the kingdom.
Now the rest of the world may
be taking a different path,
but we remain faithful
to the Gospel.
- You've made some pretty
bold assumptions, Dad.
- I've seen it with
my own eyes, Chris.
I've read his book.
- There's a book?
- It's a detailed account
of their mission together.
And you, how do you feel
about this, having your
adventures out there in
print for everyone to see?
- I wouldn't want them in print.
- Well, no one would read
a book about you, Greg.
- Did you read the whole thing?
- I read as much as I could.
- What about the part when
they helped the veteran
with PTSD make his peace with
heavenly Father and himself.
Did you read that?
- Your son and I fell in love.
We did things that people do
when they love each other.
- Faith isn't a Kinsey scale.
You're either a man of faith,
or you're not.
- Elder Merrill, I can assure you, RJ...
- Dad.
Like it or not,
I'm in your life.
A man of God or not, I feel the
loss of this woman tonight,
and I feel it through him.
And he's a man that I love
and whose family I love.
- My mother would've loved you.
Just like I do.
- So what's this
going to look like?
- What's what
- This.
- What?
You two, with him in Seattle?
- Well, RJ moved
to Portland, Dad.
- Well, that's the same thing.
Kaylee's in Salt Lake City.
- RJ and I aren't
together right now.
- Wait a minute, I thought
that you guys were...
ya know.
- Yeah why not? I just heard
you say that you love him.
Do you mind if I ask
what the problem is?
- The Church... and where
we fit inside of it all.
We don't know.
- I see.
Thanks.
RJ, thank you for
being here for Chris.
- Mm-hmm.
- Thank you for coming.
- Son, give me a hand.
- Thanks.
You know, RJ, I get it...
about Chris. I mean.
Your mother and I
want the best for you, and...
I can't think of anyone
better for you than him.
I want you to know...
I'm proud of you, son.
- For what?
- For...
- being a good human being...
and for having the fortitude
to... follow your heart.
I knew someone in
your situation once.
He wasn't nearly as
courageous as you and Chris.
- Yeah, I think I remember
you talking about him.
Do you know what
happened to him?
Is he okay?
- He is... he's fine.
- Well if you ever
want to talk about him,
I'll listen.
- Thank you, son.
* Looking at the sun *
* You think there's only
one light in the sky *
* You wouldn't be right *
* Wait until the night comes *
* See a trillion suns
spinning up above *
* That's how it is *
* That's how it is when *
- Have a seat.
- Is Sheris here?
- She's asleep.
- Is everything okay?
- Yeah, we're fine.
Now tell me about Salt Lake.
- Well, it was really
sad and really sweet.
And we said goodbye,
and... now I'm here.
- Well that doesn't
make any sense.
You guys have been at this
what, six, seven years.
I love you, no I don't,
I'm Mormon, no I'm not.
My parents will be mad if
we fuck, we shouldn't fuck.
Fucking is against our religion.
If everyone would just
stop giving a fuck about
who everyone else was
fucking then there wouldn't
be a problem.
I don't care who anyone
fucks except for Sharis.
Why should I care about
who that guy fucks,
or that guy fucks, or that
guy fucks, or that guy fucks,
it's all bullshit.
- Yeah, I agree.
- Good, so then what
are you afraid of?
- Nothing.
- You know there's a
community of people out there
who love you and
want you to be happy
and we want you to find love.
- You know, I could do it.
I could-I could compromise if
it meant living a life with him.
- So then why don't you?
- Because you're either gay,
or you're a man of faith...
but apparently
you can't be both.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- You know, you can tell
her to stop talking.
That's what I do.
Waking me up.
Hi.
I heard about Chris's mom.
How are you doing?
- Eh...
- Come here.
- You make me feel like
a baby when you do that.
- Because you are one.
- No, no, no.
- Do one more with me.
- No, I'm good.
- Just one more, come on.
- No, really, I'm good.
- Fine.
- You are falling apart.
- Am I? I think I'm
finally letting loose.
- Well, you've been
letting loose for a while.
- Well, you need to loosen up.
What do we do now?
- Well I pass out because I have
to go be an editor in the morning.
- No, no, no, I mean
your body of work.
Those books on the shelf, they're
filled with your feelings
about this man.
He was your muse.
- I'll find a new one.
- I could be your muse.
I make a great muse.
- Yeah, you are.
- What?
- Nothing.
- Okay, okay,
no, okay, okay, okay.
- He's not here.
- It's not about him.
- You're attracted to me right?
- Of course, you're beautiful.
Hey come on, please don't be...
Don't let this
be awkward between us.
- Too late.
- Look, I have feelings for you.
And they are
complicated feelings.
We just can't have sex.
It'll mess it up.
- We both know what it's
like to love something
that doesn't love
us back, don't we?
- Ryan... come on.
- What?
- Come here, come on.
Come here.
- Do you still
believe in God, RJ?
Do you think that
He's here right now?
Because I'm starting to
see our Heavenly Father...
like I see the Prophet
or the other leaders, as...
flawed men.
I don't want to
see Him like that.
I want to know that He's
here, and that He loves me.
- Do you feel loved right now?
- In this moment, I do.
- Then maybe He is.
- I have to admit...
I didn't want you and Chris
to work out.
- I know that.
- I just didn't want
to lose what we have.
- I am not what you want,
and I think you know that.
- I looked at you guys,
and I thought to myself,
"I want that... I want that.
Or something like that."
- You can have it.
- I want a family some day, RJ.
I want a Temple wedding.
I don't want to be told that
I'm going to be banished
to the outer darkness
for wanting that.
I have been to the dark places,
and I had to pull myself out.
I don't want to go back there.
- You can have all of that,
but not if you're gone.
- What do we do now?
- We call your
mission companion.
- No, no we don't.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Come on is there a way to
get a hold of Elder Petersen?
- Maybe.
- Then let's call him.
- It's probably not even
his number any more.
Besides he wouldn't
pick up, he's probably
out with his friends
or something.
At BYU, it's like 2 am.
- Okay, well maybe not, but
still he wouldn't pick up.
- Well then it doesn't matter.
- He might be angry with me.
- Why?
- He went home for what we did.
He's ashamed.
- He could fall in
love with another boy,
or worse, he could marry
some unsuspecting girl.
- I've been drinking.
- That'll only help.
- I'll call him some other time.
- No, no, tonight, we're
gonna call him tonight.
- Chris never answered your
calls after your mission.
- Yeah, I didn't try hard enough.
- Well, he didn't let you.
- I could've tried harder.
- Don't fuck this up like I did.
- You didn't.
- Come on let me see your phone.
- It's probably dead.
- You're not going
to do it, come on.
- Just let me sort it out.
- His roommates are
probably out right now
soaking with their girlfriends.
- Gross.
- He's alone in his dorm,
and he wants you to call him.
- No, he doesn't.
- You know when you think
about someone you love,
it's usually because they're
thinking about you, too.
- Hello?
- It's Ryan.
I'm in Portland.
That's cool.
How did you know I'd be up?
- Just luck, I guess.
It's nice to hear from you.
- It's so good to
hear your voice.
It's weird you'd called,
I've been thinking about you.
- You have?
- Yeah,
like all the flipping time.
- Are you alone?
Yeah, are you?
- Yeah, I am.
So, how have you been?
- Good.
I miss you.
- I miss you, too.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- I wish I could see your face.
- Well maybe we could
make that happen.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- I remember how you
used to look at me.
- Like you were the only
person in the world?
- Yeah.
- It's because that's all I saw.
I love you.
- I love you, too.
So much.
- I'm coming home,
I think it's time.
- President, may I sit?
- Yes, brother Merrill.
Let me first say that
I am praying for you.
I've been speaking with
our Heavenly Father,
and He loves you.
Debbie was dear to
me and to Francis.
How are Chelsea, and Greg,
Chris and Kaylee?
- Well Chelsea is taking
it pretty hard, as is Greg.
Kaylee, we tell her
that Deedee has gone on
to her eternal family, but
you know, she's a child.
Chris has been a rock.
And he's actually a
big part of the reason
I'm here today.
- Oh?
- He suffered from same-sex
attraction for many years.
I tried, I did everything
I could to help him,
but I've stopped that now.
- It's a very difficult
situation.
- I realized that he
is fine the way he is.
There's no need
for him to change.
- Brother Merrill,
you know that Lucifer will
try every trick to mislead us.
- You continue to
teach me to be open
to the promptings of the
spirit, and I feel my heart
softening towards Chris
and the many faithful
who are like him.
Where's our spirituality?
Where's our response
to the love of God?
This doesn't feel like
love, making people choose...
separating ourselves
from them for eternity.
Have you seen what's
happening in the world?
People are being killed,
beaten, discriminated against
every day, my son among them.
- I understand,
brother Merrill, but I
have heard from the Lord...
is that we have to proceed
as we already have.
- Well, I, too, have talked
to our Heavenly Father.
Oh, have you?
Yes and He told me that
we, the apostles, and...
the Quorum must continue
to discuss this matter.
- Alright, son, you'll
have your meeting.
In the meantime,
Noah, get some rest.
You're going through
much more now
than you may realize.
- Thank you, but I really
need to work right now.
- I understand.
Let us pray.
- Of course.
- Dear Heavenly Father,
we thank you for the friendships
that support us in difficult times...
when we lose family
until we see them
again in eternal life,
it is very hard.
- Okay. Do you remember which
order these go in?
- Yeah.
- Alright, put 'em
in order for me.
Very good, good job.
So can you tell me where
Grandma is, do you remember?
Very good, that's the spirit world.
That's paradise.
That's where she's
waiting for all of us.
- Here?
- Yep, right there.
- Yeah, right there,
and one day, we will all
be together right here.
So it'll be you, and me, and
Mommy's going to be there,
and your Grandma, and we
will all be together forever.
- RJ, too?
- Yeah, of course,
he'll be there.
Of course, he'll be there, baby.
Oh, your Mommy's going to
be here in a few minutes.
Do you want to go
outside and wait for her?
See if we can see her drive up?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- You promise you're not mad
that I'm not going to BYU?
- I'm not mad.
This makes so more sense.
You won't have to
disrupt Kaylee's life.
This place is beautiful.
- Yeah.
It's the right thing.
I was thinking about our
dinner with the Smiths,
and how much I wished your
mom could have been there
for that.
It had a life marker
feel about it.
It's inspired me to
bring some matters up
before the Quorum.
I'm going to broach the
subject of the new policy
and also same-sex
marriage in the Church.
What do you think about that?
- I don't think I ever told
you this, but... while I was
in therapy... they told
me time and again,
you can choose God or
you can choose love.
Well, to me, they're
one in the same.
My own daughter knows
that, a child knows that.
I'm not going to let
anyone tell me who I can
and can't be with... and I'm
not going to let anyone...
define those choices
for me either.
This meeting with the
President, with the Quorum...
thank you, but I hope you're
not doing it just for me.
I hope you're doing
it because you know
it's the right thing to do.
- As a member of the
Quorum, I'm limited.
I'm one voice in that
room, but I'm going to have
your mom with me.
You know... when I saw
you and RJ together,
when he had his panic attack,
and you ran after him...
reassured him, talked
him through it.
That reminded me so
much of your mom and I,
and how we cared for each other.
That's love.
I saw that with you.
It's like a dream...
this life,
it only lasts so long.
I love you, son.
- I love you, too, Dad.
- God, I miss her.
- Me too.
* His love shall light my way *
* Through darkness
and through doubt *
* Imprisoned by uncertainty *
* His love has brought me out *
- Hey.
- Hi.
- How long have you been here?
- Three and a half hours.
- I'm so sorry.
- It's okay.
- You got into law school.
- I did.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you... Oh, okay.
- Have you had time... to think?
You don't have to
be strong for me.
- I never got to say goodbye.
She was so good.
- Hi, you've reached
the voice-mail box of Christopher Merrill.
- Chris, as a member of
the Quorum of the Twelve,
I have to tell you that
I cannot support you,
but as your father,
you have my blessing.
You don't need it,
but you have it.
- Hey, hey, you have time.
You're not going to
miss your flight.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
What's in going to be like
when you start school?
- Well, you know there's
going to be breaks every now
and then, and it's
only three years.
- A lot can happen
in three years.
- Yeah.
- I just feel like
you're going to leave,
and everything's
going to be the same.
- RJ, I know why
you feel that way.
- I prayed this morning.
I prayed for Heavenly
Father to give me strength.
I prayed for strength
to let us go,
so that you could attend to
matters in your own life,
and I could do the same.
I know that the Church
has betrayed us...
and it's excluded us, and
it's been... heart breaking...
but when you're
wrapped up in it,
I can't live without it.
- I know it's been really
crazy the last couple
of weeks, and for my part,
I apologize for that...
but if it's taught me anything,
it's that life is way too short.
For the first time in my
life, I know what I want
and who I want.
I want you.
And Kaylee, and the Church,
I want it all...
because we deserve it.
- I want it all, too.
I want everything.
It belongs to us as much as
it belongs to anyone else...
and nobody can tell us
what our options are...
and I don't want to
fuck around anymore.
- Well, I had this whole
other thing planned.
I called your dad recently...
and the reason I called him was to
ask his permission to marry his son.
Will you marry me?
Yes...
I love you.
- I love you so much.
I will never leave you again.
You need some tissue?
- No, no I'm okay.
- I have a plane to catch.
- You said you would never leave.
- Just this once.
- Okay.
- Our dear Heavenly Father,
we're so very grateful
for this blessed day, to be
here, with these two young men.
We pray that thy
spirit will be with us,
and it will bless them
and strengthen them
as they endure life's
challenges together.
We pray that all will be
enriched by this experience
as we leave today,
and that we will always
remember to treat thy children
with the utmost of love,
kindness, and patience,
and we ask these things
humbly in the name of thy Son,
Jesus Christ, Amen.
- Amen.
- And now the rings.
Brethren, do you take
one another by the hand
and receive each other to
be your lawful and wedded
husband for time
and all eternity,
and this you do in the
presence of God, angels,
and these witnesses of your
own free will and choice?
- Yes.
- By the power vested in me,
I now pronounce you husbands.
- My name is RJ Smith, and I
married Chris, the love of my life...
in December of 2016,
in Portland, Oregon,
our families were both there,
including my stepdaughter
Kaylee.
I soon moved to
Salt Lake with them.
I got a job as an
adjunct professor
at the University of Utah,
and I finished my new book.
I finally found a way to join the
two opposing sides of myself.
My first day in our home,
we knelt down and prayed.
Chris said to me softly,
"This is it."
This is what we have.
"This is what we've
been fighting for."
He said it was all worth it...
and he was right.