(glass breaking)
(slow elegant classical music)
- [Narrator] I still don't
know where we fit in the world.
I thought leaving faith
behind would relieve
the dissonance I always felt.
It didn't.
Through it all, I find myself
holding onto these values.
So does Chris, my former
mission companion.
For one reason or
another, we've had trouble
finding our way.
It's been a year
since I've seen him,
and tomorrow, he comes
back to the Northwest.
We've agreed to put it all
behind us and start fresh,
uninhibited by the Church,
our families, distance,
or anything else.
We deserve that.
Everyone does.
(uplifting piano rock music)
* Don't you wanna fall *
* Don't you wanna fly *
* Don't you wanna be
dangled over the edge *
* Of this aching romance *
(cell phone ringing)
- Hey.
I cannot believe you're
going to be here tomorrow.
- I know.
- I can introduce you to
all my friends finally.
- I can introduce
you to my friend.
- Hi.
- Hi, Kaylee.
- How are you?
- Good.
- You are so cute, I
can't even stand it.
- It's past her bedtime.
Do you want to say goodnight?
- Goodnight.
- Goodnight, Kaylee.
- All right, wanna take Gillian,
and go brush all your guys' teeth.
[sneeze]
God bless you.
- Gesundheit.
- I'll be in tuck you
in just a sec, okay.
(giggling)
- I'm so excited to see you.
- I know, it'll be
good to see you, too.
I better hit the hay as well.
- Yeah, um...
Uh... so I know that
we discussed this,
and I know that you're
trying to figure it all out,
but I just want to say that...
you know,
she's more than welcome
to come up with you
next time you come up,
if that's okay.
- Yeah, no, I'll
think about that.
- Okay, great.
- Well, goodnight,
I'll see you soon.
- Yeah, goodnight.
I love you, I love you, Chris.
Just... I love you.
Why can't I just say that
like a normal person?
- RJ?
- Okay, yeah, hi.
- Hi, no, I'm still here, did
you want me to hang up?
- Well, sure that'd be...
- Or I can.
Not that I want
to hang up on you.
- No, I know.
- Okay.
- Alright, goodnight.
- Yep, goodnight.
- Bye.
(groans)
* Ride the big one *
* Don't you wanna fall *
* Don't you wanna fly *
* Don't you wanna be
dangled over the edge *
* Of this aching romance *
* If it's going to
end then I wanna know *
* Let me squeeze
out every moment *
* But if there's nothing left *
* Can you tell me why *
* That it is you're
holding onto me *
* Like it's the end
of the world *
(traffic rushing by)
Hey.
- Thanks for coming to get me.
- You look good.
- Thank you.
- I think I lost a little weight.
- It looks good.
- Thanks.
(clearing throats)
(blinker ticking)
I'm really happy you're here.
I didn't think you'd ever
speak to me again after the...
- I said I forgive you,
and I meant it.
I just think people were
legitimately confused
why two men were kissing at
my parents' anniversary party.
- I was trying to
make a statement.
- Well, mission accomplished.
- You know I'm excited for
you to meet Adina and Sheris.
- Yeah, they sound great.
- Any my friend Ryan.
- Oh he is the
returning missionary
you were telling me about?
Great.
- Yeah, I'll be there.
Okay, give her my love, please.
Alright, thank you.
Okay, bye.
Sometimes it feels
like I'm still married.
Thanks.
- You hungry?
- I could eat.
(slow, warm piano music)
- Am I that hard to be around?
- No.
- So how is life after
pharmaceutical sales?
- Well, I haven't heard
back from any of the schools
that I've applied to.
I've got my heart set on
sticking close to home.
What about you, how's work?
- Work's going well.
I haven't written anything
original in a while.
- I forgot to tell
you my sister read
one of your books.
- Oh, which one?
- The really dirty one.
- Yeah, tell her I'm sorry.
- It's just that she knew
you were talking about me,
and it was like...
- I know that's why
I'm apologizing.
How is Chelsea?
- She's good, it's Greg
that I don't talk to,
but you already knew that.
- Do they know that you're
here with me right now?
- My Mom does.
My Dad, he's...
- Let's loosen up.
- Okay.
- No, I don't drink.
- Come on, you have
no where else to be.
(glasses clinking)
How often do I get to see you?
- Alright, I'll do one.
(groaning)
- Another one?
- You know you can't get me drunk.
- I just got here.
- I'm not trying to get you
drunk, it's just happening.
(glasses clink)
- Why does it take us so
long to get comfortable?
- I don't know.
I feel like I still get...
nervous around you.
- Yeah, I get nervous, too.
- After all this time.
- Yeah, we're just
two fluttering hearts.
(breathing heavily)
(breathing heavily together)
(moaning)
- I missed you.
- [Chris] You know,
I think I can do
this whole Northwest thing.
- [RJ] What? You are doing it.
- [Chris] What?
- You're hanging out
with gay, bearded men,
and you're drinking beer.
- And what about the
Salt Lake City thing?
- What about it?
- Could you do it?
- I think you
could barely do it.
- Well, maybe you won't have to.
- Okay.
- Where are you going?
- I am headed back to your
house to get some more beer.
- I thought you said
you weren't drinking.
- You, sir, have
opened the flood gates.
I'm past the point of no return.
- You can't just say
that and then walk away.
- Too late.
- Come on, ugh.
(lighter clicks)
(giggling)
You'll be okay.
- I think it's...
- It's a little dry.
We'll be okay.
- I'm good.
- Hey did you...
- sleep with anybody else
since I saw you last?
- I had sex with
Paul after Salt Lake.
- I knew about that.
I saw you after that.
- Yeah, I just didn't know
if I'd ever see you again.
- Don't worry about it.
Was there anybody else?
- Um, like a night here, and a
night there, but nothing real.
- Yeah, I had to break a
couple bad habits myself.
- What makes them bad?
- Just, oing places, and...
meeting people.
What do you think about that?
- I think that we shouldn't
feel like we're bad people
all the time.
It's okay to have sex, you
know, we're supposed to cum.
We're supposed to cum.
We are animals, it's okay.
We're okay.
- You're not, you're
not going to judge me?
- No.
- I just wanted to get
it all out in the open.
- Yeah, it's fine.
We can get everything
out in the open.
Every last thing we can
get out in the open.
Three, two... one.
(kissing and breathing heavily)
(laughing and kissing)
(sleepy harp music)
(yawning)
- Hey.
Good morning.
Do you want some coffee?
- I am a Mormon, sir.
- So now you're a Mormon?
- Amen.
- Get up, get up.
(groaning)
Get up.
- Oh.
- What?
- My breath.
- I don't mind, come on.
- I do.
- Come on, go.
(laughing)
I wasn't ready for that.
- Then why did you
tell me to do it?
- I'm just kidding.
I'll go make us some breakfast.
Hey, how do you want
your eggs cooked?
- Everything's so bright.
- It's called day.
- Thank you for breakfast.
- You're welcome.
- Where does your
head hurt, there?
- Right here. Oh.
(groaning)
- Well, you gotta
drink more water.
Keep going.
Here, I'm going to
get you some more.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
(phone clatters on counter)
- "New IDS guidelines say
children of same-sex couples...
will not be baptized
in the Church."
I know you want to discuss this,
but if you'll just
give me a moment
- to read the whole article.
- They're joking, right?
It says they're doing this
for their own protection,
that children from gay
marriages can't be treated
like everyone else.
Punishing children for
the sins of their own fathers.
We don't even believe in that.
You can interpret
this any way you want,
but I am done.
- I don't think you mean that.
(knocking on the door)
- That's Adina.
- Hello, hi!
- Hi.
- Hi!
I'm Adina, I've heard
so much about you.
- I'm Chris.
- Yeah, I know.
- Nice to meet you.
- Yeah, what's this?
- What?
- The love of your
life is finally here,
and you make him this?
- Well, it's all I had.
- Where's Sheris?
- Not sure.
- Is everything okay?
- No, but I'll be fine.
(laughing)
Come on.
- What?
- I'm a lip kisser, come on.
- Oh?
- What, you were married
to a woman once, you'll be fine.
- He has soft lips.
(murmuring agreement)
(laughing)
- Back and forth?
[Chris] Back and forth?
- Yeah, you know it's like...
- (making swishing sound).
- No, that's up and down.
- Together.
- I assume that people
poop up and down.
- Okay, moving on,
having anuses for eyes.
- Hey. Hey.
- Hey.
- Hey, girl.
- Hi.
- Hey. Ryan.
- Chris.
- Oh, it's great to
finally meet you.
- Thank you.
- Nice to meet you.
- Hey.
- Ryan.
- Anya.
- Steve. Nice to meet you.
- Hey.
- Hey, buddy.
- Oh, you guys
started without me?
- [Steve] Yeah, we had
some really great ones,
but you can still deal
yourself in though.
But you gotta catch up.
- Yeah take seven and pick two.
- Chris, how long
are you in town for?
- Oh just through tomorrow.
- You have work or?
- I have a
six-year-old daughter.
- Oh!
- Really?
- And what do you do Ryan?
- Oh, I'm a masseur.
- How long have you
been doing that?
- Oh, I actually just graduated,
so I'm just starting out.
Actually RJ is my only client.
- You're only client?
- Yeah, I'm hoping
it'll take off.
It's mostly word of mouth,
but he's giving me lots
of practice.
We all know how
tense he gets, right.
- Wow, maybe like a
website or business cards.
- Yeah, you know, I gotta
handle that side as well.
I'm feeling it out, literally.
(laughing)
- Good card.
- It's so accurate, too.
- Your turn.
- Oh, sure, okay.
- Lifetime presents, A
Sad Handjob: The Story
of a Homoerotic
Volleyball Montage.
- I'd watch that.
(laughing and coughing)
- I can't believe I'm
smoking pot with you, Chris.
Your dad's a member
of the Quorum.
- Yes he is.
- Yeah, that's a tough
one for us right now.
- Yeah, I heard...
- but to be expected.
- So where did you serve
your mission, Ryan?
- I spent my mission
in Mexico City
(speaking foreign language)
It was beautiful...
and so was my companion.
For a year straight...
he would always change
in front of me...
totally innocent,
but he knew what he was doing.
And then one night,
we were on a bus
heading back to our district, and
I fell asleep on his shoulder.
While I was sleeping,
he had taken my hand,
and he was holding it
in a patriarchal grip.
I woke up... like this...
and I looked up
into his eyes, and...
I saw a lust and love
and longing...
but I also saw
this deep sadness...
because we both knew
we could never be together...
and it would just be this moment
in the back of a bus.
We got sent home shortly after.
I haven't seen him since.
But seeing you guys
together after so long...
it gives me hope.
I'm going to go.
- Really?
- Yeah...
- It was nice to meet you.
- Yeah, you too.
- Are you okay?
- Not really.
- Hey, hey, hey...
Love you.
- Love you, too.
- Where did you guys meet?
- Um, we met at Affirmations.
It's like a support group
for recovering Mormons.
- Yeah, I know what it is.
- Yeah, his parents kicked
him out of the house.
- Wow.
- I don't know,
I feel bad for him.
He's out here without
no family or friends.
- Wow.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- [RJ] You coming?
- Oops, sorry.
- It's okay.
(yawning and breathing heavily)
- Have you and Ryan ever...?
- No.
- He sure loves you.
- Do you love me?
(breathing heavy)
(breathing grows rhythmic)
(moaning and breathing heavily)
(moaning grows
louder and deeper)
(exhausted breathing)
(water rushing)
(birds chirping)
- Do you want some water?
What are those?
- Oh, I have pressure
points in my back.
- What's wrong with your back?
- Just all those years of
carrying around a heavy suitcase.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Whoa, it got chilly.
(water trickling)
Can I ask you something?
- Sure.
- Would you consider going to
a sacrament meeting with me?
- Chris, I just don't
know what the point is.
- I don't think it's
coincidence that you live
only a few blocks
away from the war.
It's not too late to come back.
- Where do you think I've gone?
- Not far, unless all of that
stuff in your living room
is just for show.
- I'm still trying to figure
out what they're trying
to say with this announcement.
By the way...
did you know?
- What?
- About the policy, did
you know before they made
the announcement?
- No... You honestly think
that I knew about that.
- I don't know, I just... I don't
know, I thought that if you did,
maybe there was something
you could've done about it.
- I don't know.
- Like what?
- Talk to your father.
- What possible
good would that do?
- I don't know, he's
like an inside voice.
One of the twelve
apostles has a gay son.
I mean if that's not a prophecy,
then I don't know what is.
Do you ever think about it?
What it would be like?
- What?
- I think about it
all the time...
with you, getting married...
in the Church with
the Sealer above us,
my parents and your parents.
I do... but it's not
going to happen.
Not like that.
You know what the Church does?
They convince me more and
more that maybe Joseph Smith
really did make it all up.
- Don't do that.
- How can you be a part of
something that alienates
parents from their children?
Don't you understand
what this means for you?
- I've stuck with the
Church through all of its
flaws and idiosyncrasies,
just like I've stuck with you
through all of these years.
- What are you talking about?
I'm done with it,
I've had my fill.
- No, you gave up,
that's different.
- And you don't have
the courage to leave.
- I don't want to leave.
- How are you okay with
the way the treat you,
or the way they treat your
family or your daughter?
As a father, how
do you accept that?
- Everything I do is for her.
You can question my beliefs
as a man of the faith,
but don't you ever question
my devotion to my daughter.
- I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
- What am I doing here?
What am I doing?
I just feel obligated
to you, you know.
I just keep coming
back and coming back
because it's all that I know.
- Wow.
(wind blowing)
- Ricky?
(labored breathing)
- Hey... are you alright?
Hey.
What's wrong?
Are you alright?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Easy, easy,
Okay.
(panting)
What's wrong? Hey, look at me...
I'm right here.
Breathe... Are you alright?
- I get these sometimes.
- Hey, hey... Alright,
Alright.
(somber piano music)
Back to real life.
- This is real life.
I'm sorry we keep
fucking things up.
- You don't have to be sorry.
- Okay.
(slow, melancholy rock music)
(moves into
uplifting rock music)
(music fades)
(paper tearing, crumpling)
- Thanks.
(computer jingles)
(phone ringing)
- Call Chris.
- [automated voice] Say the list
number of the one you...
Calling the mobile
number for Chris.
(cheerful chiming)
(phone ringing)
- [Chris] Hello.
- Chris, Chris, I just heard.
I'm so sorry.
Is there anything I can I do?
[Chris] Would you consider
coming to Salt Lake?
Yeah.
- I can make
all the arrangements.
- No, don't worry about it.
- I'll get there.
- [Chris] The
service is tomorrow.
- Yeah, that's fine.
- [Chris] Okay,
I'll send you all the details.
I'll see you soon.
- Are you okay?
- [Chris] It'll just be
good to have you here.
- Yeah, I want to
be there with you.
- [Chris] I'll see you soon, RJ.
- Okay, I love you.
(phone beeps)
- [Man on the phone] Elder Merrill's
gonna pitch a fit when he sees you.
I think I'd like
to be there with you.
- [RJ] Uh...
- I just-I think I should
do it alone.
- [Tom] Look, son,
I never told you this, but...
I had a conversation with him.
- Wait, when?
- [Tom] We talked when you were
in Salt Lake City with Chris.
I was a bit direct.
- How so?
- [Tom] Doesn't matter now.
Back then I had my reasons.
- Um... okay.
What does Mom think?
- [Tom] She backs me up on this.
- What about your foot?
- [Tom] It'll be fine, RJ.
- Okay.
- Alright, son, I'll see you
in the morning in Salt Lake.
- Yeah, I'll see
you in the morning.
- [Tom] Alright, bye.
- Bye.
- Where are you headed today?
- Uh, Utah.
- Will you be checking
any bags today?
- No thanks.
- There you go, sir,
have a good flight.
- Thank you.
(melancholy music)
- Hi, thank you.
(indistinct conversation)
Hey.
Hi.
Thank you for coming.
Thank you.
Thank you, guys.
(bright harp music)
- Hi, Kaylee.
- Hi.
- You look really pretty.
- Thank you.
- I like your shoes.
- She gets a little shy.
- It's okay.
- I'm glad you're here.
- Me too.
- Hey, shall I take
her for a little why?
Yeah absolutely, you wanna
go with Grandma, honey?
Yeah.
I'll see you later, sweetie.
(clearing throat)
(breathing audibly)
You look good.
- You too.
- Thanks.
- I'm sorry.
- It's a very tough situation.
- It's challenging, yeah.
- Yeah.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, he's walking over here.
- It's gonna be fine.
- I'm right here.
- I think they're
starting to recognize me.
- They probably are.
Hey, just don't kiss me.
Sorry, that wasn't funny.
- RJ.
- Elder Merrill, I want you to
know I'm very sorry for your loss.
- I appreciate that.
Chris didn't tell me
that you were coming.
- I invited him, Dad.
- Elder Merrill,
I'm Tom Smith, RJ's father.
- Oh, right.
- I can't begin to know what
you're going through right now.
Saying sorry isn't enough
to express my sympathies.
- Thank you, Brother Smith.
- And you must be Chris, brother Smith.
- Yes.
I've heard so many
great things about you.
Welcome.
What happened?
- Oh, an accident at work.
- Elder Smith,
I thought that was you.
How are you?
- [Tom] RJ, are you okay, son?
- I'm sorry.
- RJ?
- Excuse me.
(labored breathing)
Easy, hey, easy.
- I'm so sorry.
- It's okay.
- That was so weird.
- Yeah.
- Our mission president...
and the look that your father
gave me, he hates me.
- Okay. Okay.
- He doesn't hate you.
- I just wanted to
be here for you.
- You are, you're here.
Rest.
Easy, easy, easy.
There we go, there
we go, there we go.
- They're gonna be alright.
- Yeah, why don't you
and RJ stick around,
and we'll get some dinner?
- Oh, Elder Merrill, I couldn't
intrude on your mourning.
- We need to have a talk.
We need to have a
candid conversation,
and I would like you and RJ
to join us for dinner tonight,
alright?
- Absolutely.
- Good, thank you.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
So, I hear you're
going to law school.
- I'm still applying.
- I bet your mother was proud.
- Yeah, she was.
As far as she was concerned,
I was already practicing law.
- My old mission companion
became an attorney.
I saw him and some of my
other companions recently.
We met up for a night, and
life didn't skip a beat,
let me tell you.
We picked up right
where we left off.
We shared our blessings,
and our tragedies,
love and heartbreak.
Some of them... I had no idea
what they were going through
back then.
It's nice to have
people in your life
you can depend on.
- I'm Greg, Chris's brother.
- Thomas Smith, RJ's father.
- It's good to see you again.
- Thank you.
Did you know my mother?
- Okay, Greg, I know that
you don't care much for me,
so maybe we should...
- I would like to sit
here and mourn my mother
without the shadow
of my brother's past
looming over this sacred moment.
- I'm sorry.
- May I have that?
- You're really going to
do this right now, Greg?
- Our father asked me to
be here, and here I am.
Dad.
- Boys, Brother Smith, RJ.
- Elder Merrill.
- Good to see you.
- I didn't know what to get, so I
got a variety of foods, pad Thai.
- I hope Thai is
good for everyone.
We didn't have much left
after the reception, so...
Looks good, nice and hot.
Brother Smith, would
you like to pray for us?
- Elder Merrill, I'd
be honored if a member
of the Quorum would
say a blessing.
- Okay, call me Noah, alright?
- Let's pray.
Our Heavenly Father,
thank you for bringing
Tom and RJ safely to us
today and as our families
come together, please help
us guide our conversation,
help us discover what
is best for everyone,
in the name of
Jesus Christ, Amen.
- [Together] Amen.
- Brother Smith and RJ,
thank you both
for being here today, it was
very gracious of you to come.
I have to make clear right
now and bear testimony
to each of you that...
sexual relations
between two of the
same sex is wrong.
By doing so, our children
become apostates,
and should be culled
from the kingdom.
Now the rest of the world may
be taking a different path,
but we remain faithful
to the Gospel.
- You've made some pretty
bold assumptions, Dad.
- I've seen it with
my own eyes, Chris.
I've read his book.
- There's a book?
- It's a detailed account
of their mission together.
And you, how do you feel
about this, having your
adventures out there in
print for everyone to see?
- I wouldn't want them in print.
- Well, no one would read
a book about you, Greg.
- Did you read the whole thing?
- I read as much as I could.
- What about the part when
they helped the veteran
with PTSD make his peace with
heavenly Father and himself.
Did you read that?
- Your son and I fell in love.
We did things that people do
when they love each other.
- Faith isn't a Kinsey scale.
You're either a man of faith,
or you're not.
- Elder Merrill, I can assure you, RJ...
- Dad.
Like it or not,
I'm in your life.
A man of God or not, I feel the
loss of this woman tonight,
and I feel it through him.
And he's a man that I love
and whose family I love.
- My mother would've loved you.
Just like I do.
- So what's this
going to look like?
- What's what
- This.
- What?
You two, with him in Seattle?
- Well, RJ moved
to Portland, Dad.
- Well, that's the same thing.
Kaylee's in Salt Lake City.
- RJ and I aren't
together right now.
- Wait a minute, I thought
that you guys were...
ya know.
- Yeah why not? I just heard
you say that you love him.
Do you mind if I ask
what the problem is?
- The Church... and where
we fit inside of it all.
We don't know.
- I see.
(somber piano music)
- Thanks.
- (speaks indistinctly)
RJ, thank you for
being here for Chris.
- Mm-hmm.
- Thank you for coming.
(speaking indistinctly)
- Son, give me a hand.
- Thanks.
You know, RJ, I get it...
about Chris. I mean.
Your mother and I
want the best for you, and...
I can't think of anyone
better for you than him.
I want you to know...
I'm proud of you, son.
- For what?
- For...
- being a good human being...
and for having the fortitude
to... follow your heart.
I knew someone in
your situation once.
He wasn't nearly as
courageous as you and Chris.
- Yeah, I think I remember
you talking about him.
Do you know what
happened to him?
Is he okay?
- He is... he's fine.
- Well if you ever
want to talk about him,
I'll listen.
- Thank you, son.
(somber piano music)
* Looking at the sun *
* You think there's only
one light in the sky *
* You wouldn't be right *
* Wait until the night comes *
* See a trillion suns
spinning up above *
* That's how it is *
* That's how it is when *
(knocking on door)
(music stops)
- Have a seat.
- Is Sheris here?
- She's asleep.
- Is everything okay?
- Yeah, we're fine.
Now tell me about Salt Lake.
- Well, it was really
sad and really sweet.
And we said goodbye,
and... now I'm here.
- Well that doesn't
make any sense.
You guys have been at this
what, six, seven years.
I love you, no I don't,
I'm Mormon, no I'm not.
My parents will be mad if
we fuck, we shouldn't fuck.
Fucking is against our religion.
If everyone would just
stop giving a fuck about
who everyone else was
fucking then there wouldn't
be a problem.
I don't care who anyone
fucks except for Sharis.
Why should I care about
who that guy fucks,
or that guy fucks, or that
guy fucks, or that guy fucks,
it's all bullshit.
- Yeah, I agree.
- Good, so then what
are you afraid of?
- Nothing.
- You know there's a
community of people out there
who love you and
want you to be happy
and we want you to find love.
- You know, I could do it.
I could-I could compromise if
it meant living a life with him.
- So then why don't you?
- Because you're either gay,
or you're a man of faith...
but apparently
you can't be both.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- You know, you can tell
her to stop talking.
That's what I do.
Waking me up.
Hi.
I heard about Chris's mom.
How are you doing?
- Eh...
- Come here.
(speaks indistinctly)
- You make me feel like
a baby when you do that.
- Because you are one.
(upbeat electronic dance music)
(groaning)
- No, no, no.
- Do one more with me.
- No, I'm good.
- Just one more, come on.
- No, really, I'm good.
- Fine.
- You are falling apart.
- Am I? I think I'm
finally letting loose.
- Well, you've been
letting loose for a while.
- Well, you need to loosen up.
What do we do now?
- Well I pass out because I have
to go be an editor in the morning.
- No, no, no, I mean
your body of work.
Those books on the shelf, they're
filled with your feelings
about this man.
He was your muse.
- I'll find a new one.
- I could be your muse.
I make a great muse.
- Yeah, you are.
- What?
- Nothing.
(heavy breathing)
(grunting)
(belt buckle clinking)
(moaning)
- Okay, okay,
no, okay, okay, okay.
- He's not here.
- It's not about him.
- You're attracted to me right?
- Of course, you're beautiful.
Hey come on, please don't be...
Don't let this
be awkward between us.
- Too late.
- Look, I have feelings for you.
And they are
complicated feelings.
We just can't have sex.
It'll mess it up.
- We both know what it's
like to love something
that doesn't love
us back, don't we?
- Ryan... come on.
- What?
- Come here, come on.
Come here.
- Do you still
believe in God, RJ?
Do you think that
He's here right now?
Because I'm starting to
see our Heavenly Father...
like I see the Prophet
or the other leaders, as...
flawed men.
I don't want to
see Him like that.
I want to know that He's
here, and that He loves me.
- Do you feel loved right now?
- In this moment, I do.
- Then maybe He is.
- I have to admit...
I didn't want you and Chris
to work out.
- I know that.
- I just didn't want
to lose what we have.
- I am not what you want,
and I think you know that.
- I looked at you guys,
and I thought to myself,
"I want that... I want that.
Or something like that."
- You can have it.
- I want a family some day, RJ.
I want a Temple wedding.
I don't want to be told that
I'm going to be banished
to the outer darkness
for wanting that.
I have been to the dark places,
and I had to pull myself out.
I don't want to go back there.
(sobbing quietly)
- You can have all of that,
but not if you're gone.
- What do we do now?
- We call your
mission companion.
- No, no we don't.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Come on is there a way to
get a hold of Elder Petersen?
- Maybe.
- Then let's call him.
- It's probably not even
his number any more.
Besides he wouldn't
pick up, he's probably
out with his friends
or something.
At BYU, it's like 2 am.
- Okay, well maybe not, but
still he wouldn't pick up.
- Well then it doesn't matter.
- He might be angry with me.
- Why?
- He went home for what we did.
He's ashamed.
- He could fall in
love with another boy,
or worse, he could marry
some unsuspecting girl.
- I've been drinking.
- That'll only help.
- I'll call him some other time.
- No, no, tonight, we're
gonna call him tonight.
- Chris never answered your
calls after your mission.
- Yeah, I didn't try hard enough.
- Well, he didn't let you.
- I could've tried harder.
- Don't fuck this up like I did.
- You didn't.
- Come on let me see your phone.
- It's probably dead.
- You're not going
to do it, come on.
- Just let me sort it out.
- His roommates are
probably out right now
soaking with their girlfriends.
- Gross.
- He's alone in his dorm,
and he wants you to call him.
- No, he doesn't.
- You know when you think
about someone you love,
it's usually because they're
thinking about you, too.
(phone ringing)
- [Young Man] Hello?
- It's Ryan.
I'm in Portland.
- [Missionary Companion]
That's cool.
How did you know I'd be up?
- Just luck, I guess.
- [Missionary Companion]
It's nice to hear from you.
- It's so good to
hear your voice.
- [Missionary Companion]
It's weird you'd called,
I've been thinking about you.
- You have?
- [Missionary Companion] Yeah,
like all the flipping time.
- Are you alone?
- [Missionary Companion]
Yeah, are you?
- Yeah, I am.
- [Missionary Companion]
So, how have you been?
- Good.
- [Missionary Companion]
I miss you.
- I miss you, too.
- [Missionary Companion] Really?
- Yeah.
- I wish I could see your face.
- Well maybe we could
make that happen.
- [Missionary Companion] Really?
- Yeah.
- I remember how you
used to look at me.
- Like you were the only
person in the world?
- [Missionary Companion] Yeah.
- It's because that's all I saw.
- [Missionary Companion]
I love you.
- I love you, too.
(crying)
- [Missionary Companion]
So much.
- I'm coming home,
I think it's time.
(mournful soft rock music)
(inspiring instrumental music)
- President, may I sit?
- [President Of The Quorum Of The
Twelve] Yes, brother Merrill.
Let me first say that
I am praying for you.
I've been speaking with
our Heavenly Father,
and He loves you.
Debbie was dear to
me and to Francis.
How are Chelsea, and Greg,
Chris and Kaylee?
- Well Chelsea is taking
it pretty hard, as is Greg.
Kaylee, we tell her
that Deedee has gone on
to her eternal family, but
you know, she's a child.
Chris has been a rock.
And he's actually a
big part of the reason
I'm here today.
- Oh?
- He suffered from same-sex
attraction for many years.
I tried, I did everything
I could to help him,
but I've stopped that now.
- It's a very difficult
situation.
- I realized that he
is fine the way he is.
There's no need
for him to change.
- Brother Merrill,
you know that Lucifer will
try every trick to mislead us.
- You continue to
teach me to be open
to the promptings of the
spirit, and I feel my heart
softening towards Chris
and the many faithful
who are like him.
Where's our spirituality?
Where's our response
to the love of God?
This doesn't feel like
love, making people choose...
separating ourselves
from them for eternity.
Have you seen what's
happening in the world?
People are being killed,
beaten, discriminated against
every day, my son among them.
- I understand,
brother Merrill, but I
have heard from the Lord...
is that we have to proceed
as we already have.
- Well, I, too, have talked
to our Heavenly Father.
Oh, have you?
Yes and He told me that
we, the apostles, and...
the Quorum must continue
to discuss this matter.
- Alright, son, you'll
have your meeting.
In the meantime,
Noah, get some rest.
You're going through
much more now
than you may realize.
- Thank you, but I really
need to work right now.
- I understand.
Let us pray.
- Of course.
- Dear Heavenly Father,
we thank you for the friendships
that support us in difficult times...
when we lose family
until we see them
again in eternal life,
it is very hard.
(crying softly)
- Okay. Do you remember which
order these go in?
- Yeah.
- Alright, put 'em
in order for me.
Very good, good job.
So can you tell me where
Grandma is, do you remember?
Very good, that's the spirit world.
That's paradise.
That's where she's
waiting for all of us.
- Here?
- Yep, right there.
- Yeah, right there,
and one day, we will all
be together right here.
So it'll be you, and me, and
Mommy's going to be there,
and your Grandma, and we
will all be together forever.
- RJ, too?
- Yeah, of course,
he'll be there.
Of course, he'll be there, baby.
Oh, your Mommy's going to
be here in a few minutes.
Do you want to go
outside and wait for her?
See if we can see her drive up?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- You promise you're not mad
that I'm not going to BYU?
- I'm not mad.
This makes so more sense.
You won't have to
disrupt Kaylee's life.
This place is beautiful.
- Yeah.
It's the right thing.
I was thinking about our
dinner with the Smiths,
and how much I wished your
mom could have been there
for that.
It had a life marker
feel about it.
It's inspired me to
bring some matters up
before the Quorum.
I'm going to broach the
subject of the new policy
and also same-sex
marriage in the Church.
What do you think about that?
- I don't think I ever told
you this, but... while I was
in therapy... they told
me time and again,
you can choose God or
you can choose love.
Well, to me, they're
one in the same.
My own daughter knows
that, a child knows that.
I'm not going to let
anyone tell me who I can
and can't be with... and I'm
not going to let anyone...
define those choices
for me either.
This meeting with the
President, with the Quorum...
thank you, but I hope you're
not doing it just for me.
I hope you're doing
it because you know
it's the right thing to do.
- As a member of the
Quorum, I'm limited.
I'm one voice in that
room, but I'm going to have
your mom with me.
You know... when I saw
you and RJ together,
when he had his panic attack,
and you ran after him...
reassured him, talked
him through it.
That reminded me so
much of your mom and I,
and how we cared for each other.
That's love.
I saw that with you.
It's like a dream...
this life,
it only lasts so long.
I love you, son.
- I love you, too, Dad.
- God, I miss her.
- Me too.
* His love shall light my way *
* Through darkness
and through doubt *
* Imprisoned by uncertainty *
* His love has brought me out *
(wind blowing)
(breathing tiredly)
(slow, soft piano music)
(knocking on door frame)
(laughing)
(soft piano music quickens)
- Hey.
- Hi.
- How long have you been here?
- Three and a half hours.
- I'm so sorry.
- It's okay.
- You got into law school.
- I did. (laughing)
(kissing)
- Congratulations.
- Thank you... Oh, okay.
(belt buckle clinking)
(laughing)
- Have you had time... to think?
You don't have to
be strong for me.
(crying quietly)
- I never got to say goodbye.
She was so good.
(sobbing loudly)
(hopeful, uplifting
orchestral music)
(wheels rolling across pavement)
(people conversing
loudly on street)
(laughing and shouting)
- [Voicemail Recording] Hi, you've reached
the voice-mail box of Christopher Merrill.
- Chris, as a member of
the Quorum of the Twelve,
I have to tell you that
I cannot support you,
but as your father,
you have my blessing.
You don't need it,
but you have it.
- Hey, hey, you have time.
You're not going to
miss your flight.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
What's in going to be like
when you start school?
- Well, you know there's
going to be breaks every now
and then, and it's
only three years.
- A lot can happen
in three years.
- Yeah.
- I just feel like
you're going to leave,
and everything's
going to be the same.
- RJ, I know why
you feel that way.
- I prayed this morning.
I prayed for Heavenly
Father to give me strength.
I prayed for strength
to let us go,
so that you could attend to
matters in your own life,
and I could do the same.
I know that the Church
has betrayed us...
and it's excluded us, and
it's been... heart breaking...
but when you're
wrapped up in it,
I can't live without it.
- I know it's been really
crazy the last couple
of weeks, and for my part,
I apologize for that...
but if it's taught me anything,
it's that life is way too short.
For the first time in my
life, I know what I want
and who I want.
I want you.
And Kaylee, and the Church,
I want it all...
because we deserve it.
- I want it all, too.
I want everything.
It belongs to us as much as
it belongs to anyone else...
and nobody can tell us
what our options are...
and I don't want to
fuck around anymore.
- Well, I had this whole
other thing planned.
I called your dad recently...
and the reason I called him was to
ask his permission to marry his son.
Will you marry me?
- Yes...
- (crying quietly)
I love you.
- I love you so much.
I will never leave you again.
You need some tissue?
- No, no I'm okay.
- I have a plane to catch.
- You said you would never leave.
- Just this once.
- Okay.
- Our dear Heavenly Father,
we're so very grateful
for this blessed day, to be
here, with these two young men.
We pray that thy
spirit will be with us,
and it will bless them
and strengthen them
as they endure life's
challenges together.
We pray that all will be
enriched by this experience
as we leave today,
and that we will always
remember to treat thy children
with the utmost of love,
kindness, and patience,
and we ask these things
humbly in the name of thy Son,
Jesus Christ, Amen.
- [Together] Amen.
- And now the rings.
(sweet music plays quietly)
Brethren, do you take
one another by the hand
and receive each other to
be your lawful and wedded
husband for time
and all eternity,
and this you do in the
presence of God, angels,
and these witnesses of your
own free will and choice?
- Yes.
- By the power vested in me,
I now pronounce you husbands.
(crowd applauding loudly)
- [RJ] My name is RJ Smith, and I
married Chris, the love of my life...
in December of 2016,
in Portland, Oregon,
our families were both there,
including my stepdaughter
Kaylee.
I soon moved to
Salt Lake with them.
I got a job as an
adjunct professor
at the University of Utah,
and I finished my new book.
I finally found a way to join the
two opposing sides of myself.
(twinkling piano music)
My first day in our home,
we knelt down and prayed.
Chris said to me softly,
"This is it."
This is what we have.
"This is what we've
been fighting for."
He said it was all worth it...
and he was right.
* *