SUDDEN RAIN
"Winter Cooking: 15 Hot-Pot
Recipes"
Whats for dinner?
I haven't decided yet.
Cook me something good, wont you?
Almost forgot my medicine.
Lets go for a walk, but maybe
it's a bit late.
We can still go to Tamagawa or
Inogashira.
Still behaving like a child at
your age.
That’s not too bad.
How much money do you have?
It's like this every Sunday,
what a drag.
16, 17, 18, 19
If were going, we should start
getting ready after dinner.
Yes. But first we must decide
where to.
How about visiting Mr. Kawakami?
Come on.
No.
Stop this! I heard you.
I see him everyday in the office.
It's not so bad staying home on
a Sunday.
I really don’t know what I'm
doing here.
Whats wrong?
Nothing.
I just don’t understand you.
Well what is it?
You just to whatever I'm doing.
I pick up a newspaper, and you
start knitting.
I sigh, and you sigh.
I yawn, and you yawn.
That's why I suggested going out,
but you're always against it.
We didn't get married to go out.
It's not so bad staying home on
Sundays, to enjoy family life.
That explains why you never say
anything.
Whats there to say?
People make conversation for it's own sake,
not because they have or
don't have things to say.
So you want to talk philosophy!
Okay, people make conversation.
But you hardly start one yourself.
Because you always say I'm
nagging you.
Because you talk when I reading
the paper.
Also when you are sleeping.
I was tired.
Please only cut out the cooking section
after I've done with the newspaper.
I'm afraid I've forget...
and I thought you've finished.
But you don't use the recipes.
They all cost too much.
Green beans are 35 yen a jar.
And a piece of salmon costs 15 yen.
Where are you off to?
Be right back.
Is that so?
I'm not going to Kawakami's.
It doesn't matter if you do.
Are you mad?
Whats going on?
Now I understand.
Understand what?
I’m sorry.
How strange.
Post this letter for me on your way.
So Ayako's gone on her honeymoon.
I suppose she and her husband are taking
a walk in Kyoto right now.
Now is the time.
Men should leave early and come
home late.
But other women like their husbands
to stay out.
Strange. But now I understand.
Lets move this.
Hey, give me a hand.
It's rather heavy.
Welcome.
Take a look at our toasters.
How much is this?
Cheap. Only 1,500 yen.
What about blenders?
We also have a big selection.
They're very good for mixing salad
dressing or bean paste.
A great help to patients and
old people.
And also people with stomach
problems.
Yes, do come in.
I'll give you a discount.
But it must cost over ten thousand yen.
There're less expensive models.
But no, thank you.
Come by another time.
Excuse me.
Is this household at home?
The missus maybe somewhere
in the neighborhood
The one who just went out with
a green basket.
Thank you.
Ayako,
why did you come back alone?
I got your postcard yesterday.
Oh yes?
I was waiting for you.
But you said you’d be gone for
a week.
I got back early.
Let me open the door for you.
I'll just come in through the
kitchen.
You just came back from your honeymoon
come in through the door.
No, that wont be necessary.
It's a mess. Please be careful.
Where did you go?
A dog.
A tramp. You feed him once and
he becomes a regular.
Well of course.
Still better than a human being.
You must be tired.
Sit down, and stop laughing.
What happened?
I'll tell you later. Wheres uncle?
Gone out.
I thought you always go out
on Sunday.
I suggested it.
But the old thing wouldn’t go.
So what happened?
I'll never understand if you just
keep on crying.
So what did he do?
I’m sorry. I didn't want to cry.
I didn’t want to mention it.
But it's really too much.
I’m going home. It's so disgusting.
What is so disgusting?
Everything.
Anybody home?
My name is Imasato. I’m your
new neighbor
How do you do?
Here're some coupons from the
noodle shop. Please accept them.
You’re too kind.
Sorry to have troubled you.
Goodbye.
Let's get back to our conversation.
You had a fight, didn’t you?
It's much worse. I don't think it's working.
It took you three years of marriage
to learn this?
But it's really too much.
What happened before all this?
I said he didn't have any manners.
Is that it?
It's not just manners, other things too.
Disgusting.
Men are all like this.
He yawned in front of my mother
when he visited me at home.
Mother was furious.
But compared to all the other things...
Yawning was nothing.
But that’s something biological,
isn't it?
No, it has to do with love.
The moment he gets on the train, he
puts up his legs and falls asleep.
He didn’t say anything?
Like asking if you're tired?
Never. I don’t know why we
went on a trip.
He sleeps with his mouth wide open,
and wont cover it with a handkerchief.
Maybe the wedding was too tiring.
I was wearing that stupid wig and
heavy belt.
But you’re a woman.
Auntie really. Coming from you.
But...
And he flirted with the waitress
at the hotel.
I was really embarrassed
And the language he used.
"Are you from Tokyo?
You look swell in country clothes."
And the waitress said,
"And you, are you also from Tokyo?"
Tickling and teasing him,
a horrendous sight.
Disgusting. Isn’t it?
Men say different things to
different people.
Is uncle the same?
Pretty much.
No, not uncle.
What he said later was
even more outrageous.
I asked him where Kawa County was.
And he said make a guess. Auntie,
do you know where it is?
I said it's in Mie, and he started
laughing.
Whats so funny about it?
He was making fun of me!
Then he asked me to draw a map,
and point it out to him.
I said I hated being examined like
a high school pupil.
And he brought out pencil and
paper and made me do it.
He was such a pain. So I started
drawing one, from memory.
Could you?
He said it looked like a cucumber,
before I even finished.
He said it looked like a cucumber.
That’s too rude.
Why did I marry such a man?
A brute who knows nothing about tenderness...
I brought some local products for you.
Thank you. Are you hungry?
No, thank you.
We have coupons from the noodle shop.
No, I don’t want any.
They are a present.
It's alright. I'll get some noodles.
The drug store outside has just
installed a pay phone.
I'll be back soon.
Anybody home?
Excuse me.
I ordered noodles, but got udon
by mistake.
That’s alright. Come on, eat.
Your judgments are perhaps
premature. In fact men...
I’ve had enough of your advice.
Who actually decides what men
are like?
It seems that auntie's been tamed.
It's not that I can't stand up
for myself.
It's just that I never thought it
was a big problem.
He asked you to draw a map, but that
doesn’t mean he didn't love you.
There're even harder things to
explain between husband and wife.
Older people and younger people
have different ways.
Be loved or not be loved, and that’s
secondary?
What?
The most important question is...
Is me.
Is whether I feel happy.
Eat, before it turns cold.
You’re too happy; you won't understand.
Since that’s the case, I'll tell you
everything.
I cant stand it any more.
it's going to shock you.
Calm down. Certain things are
better left unsaid.
Once they come out there’s no return.
So think about it.
I only want to know the facts.
You make it really hard for me
to speak my mind.
Better not say it.
But if I don’t,
people will never understand.
Anyway, they’re not problems
that can be solved.
Are they that kind of problems?
Yes.
Welcome.
How're you?
Luckily I didn't send out the postcard.
I did.
Fool.
Men are like this; they are never wrong.
I’m hungry.
Have you had lunch?
No.
Udon or noodles?
A present from our neighbor
She's really nice. Please.
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
The shoes were lined up like this.
A child in the neighborhood saw your
stray dog carrying a shoe in It's mouth.
So I thought I might find it here.
I’m terribly sorry.
I´ll look for it right away.
My husbands favorite shoe,
custom-made.
I am sorry.
Earlier, the childrens toys.
And Celluloid were all damaged.
That dog is not registered, is it?
But that’s not our dog.
Maybe you should put him to sleep.
I'll think of something.
You don’t have children, you can't
understand.
Children can get rabies if they’re
bitten.
Then it’ll be too late.
Id do my best.
If you want to keep a dog, you have
to go through all the procedures.
Don’t make trouble to one.
I am terribly sorry.
Excuse me, uncle.
What nonsense.
Give me a hand when you’ve
finished eating.
Sundays are a pain.
Auntie deals with these things
everyday.
That’s woman’s work.
A man has to find somebody’s
shoe on a Sunday?
Forget it.
That’s outrageous.
But this is our family’s business.
Never mind out business. Lets
hear yours.
Precisely, what is most important?
What is the most tedious, the most
unbearable?
I was going to keep quiet.
But since you don’t understand,
I may as well say it...
Last night,
he met a friend at the hotel.
Someone hes never mentioned before.
They started drinking from late
afternoon.
They got drunk and were making
all these noises.
I didn’t want to disturb other people,
and asked them to be considerate.
And I got scolding.
Then the two of them went out.
I waited and waited, and he only
came back in the morning.
Bring me my medicine. And then?
I was silent for a while. Then I said
I wanted to go back to Tokyo.
He asked me if I was angry.
I said I wanted to go back to Tokyo.
Please let me leave first.
He said then we should leave together.
But he made the point that he was
leaving for my sake.
He seemed so righteous.
But even if he had apologized,
I wouldn’t have accepted it.
And if fact he was justifying himself
making excuses.
So I asked him if he was ashamed.
What did he say?
"I’ve done nothing wrong. You just
go ahead and suspect me".
I wasn’t suspecting him of anything.
But what he did made me feel
insulted.
And he had shamed himself.
Of course I wasn’t that clear at
that time.
I was so broken-hearted, I couldn’t
say a word.
Is that everything?
How do you feel?
A bit rough.
Must be more than just a bit.
Then what did he say?
Not a word until we got into
Tokyo station.
Then just "I’m going home" and
we left each other.
If sister is still alive,
shell surely ask you to come back.
Ayako, men are...
No more advice, please.
Why?
I was going to and he refused.
You cant understand men like this.
If you have an opinion, tell me.
Just don’t be too serious.
You have to look behind the surface
evidence and understand his motives.
But...
Listen to me.,
let me try to explain for him.
He met a friend, and was surely
teased for getting married.
And surely he was embarrassed
And he was afraid of being called
a henpecked husband.
Afraid of what?
Listen to me.
The other guy would say.
He was dying to spend the night
with his wife.
That guy was really annoying.
So he decided to show him how
free and easy he was.
And had dinner and a few drinks
with him.
So that he wouldn’t say I´mm only
interested in my wife.
You...
And he believed that his intelligent
wife would understand.
But that guy was really too much.
He wouldn’t let him go home,
and made fun of him being lonely.
It was only in the morning that
he managed to get away.
As he suspected,
his wife had cried her eyes out.
If he was [illegible], he’d sweet-talk
his wife.
To make her happy.
That’s quite enough.
But in such situations,
all Japanese men could do is traverse.
That’s quite a speech. I've listened
enough.
Ayako, right?
It's just a small misunderstanding.
The important thing is to make up.
It's not as simple as that.
To insult a woman to save his face.
I absolutely cannot tolerate
such behavior.
Marriage means seeing your partner
in a new light.
Which also means discovering
each others shortcomings.
But that’s only my experience.
It's the same with men.
You only find out the truth about
your partner after?.
In other words, disillusionment.
But women are usually more giving.
How so?
They always bend themselves backwards
for men.
On the surface, naturally.
They even make sacrifices.
Like what?
Like giving up ones own interest
for the husband's.
Are we talking about music?
Not only music.
Oh, that.
What? What is that?
How could you bring this up before
other people?
That’s history.
You cant criticize me.
Ayako is here.
Will you behave yourself.
He spent his honeymoon sleeping
in the train.
Who?
He left Ayako alone;
and he slept with his mouth open.
An ugly nose hes got.
And ill-mannered too.
He flirted with the waitress right
in front of Ayako.
His table manners are dreadful.
That’s not the worst.
The worst is he simply wasn’t
interested in anything.
I suggested sightseeing,
and he said he was tired.
I suggested food,
and he complained about the taste.
Maybe he has stomach problems.
And lazy too.
He combs his hair with his fingers.
And bossy too, a show-off.
He asked Ayako to draw a map
of Japan.
Before she finished,
he said it looked like an eggplant.
Auntie, It's cucumber.
Yes. He said cucumber.
Is that so.
What a drag.
How're they going to go on?
Well what do you think? Should
they separate?
What would you do if it was you?
I think I've made a mistake in
talking to you.
I should have made my very own
decision.
But I was afraid you’d disapprove if
I didn't listen to your advice.
So I told you everything.
It's been a very rewarding day.
Ma’am, it raining.
Thank you.
I’m sorry.
Let me do it myself.
Nenkichi, what're you doing?
The luggage is still outside.
Excuse me.
Sorry to trouble you.
Good morning.
The weather forecast has been
remarkably accurate lately.
Don’t bank on it.
It was supposed to rain last night.
Galoshes depress me.
True. They don’t look like shoes.
It’d
closer to the station.
Yes.
What kind of toothpaste do you use?
Before I used Silver.
After marriage I used Diamond.
I’m exactly the opposite.
Your wife changed to Diamond?
I forgot when we changed.
Your wife’s very young.
I really shouldn’t have married
a young wife.
I have to take care of here all the time.
Better someone dependable,
someone I can rely on.
But shes so healthy and so
naturally beautiful.
Stop kidding.
Yours wife’s so gentle. You're a
lucky man.
Stop kidding.
We’ve been married four years.
We’ve just come to know each
other very well.
You don’t say.
For a start she gets up earlier
than her husband.
That, of course.
She never brings an umbrella to the
station when it rains.
And says she knows It's going to
rain when I get home.
You spoil her because shes adorable.
You think so?
Hot waters ready.
Hot water! Excellent!
I'll wash my face.
Good morning.
Feeding the dog?
I just leave it here and hell come.
Whose dog is it? It's damaged again.
I’m sorry.
Yours?
I’m really sorry.
That’s okay.
In any case, hats are out of fashion.
But...
The dog is not guilty.
Whats up? Are you still not ready?
Sorry. Good morning.
Good morning. Please hurry.
Stay in line. You can go on your
own when we get to the park.
Show some spirit.
Going on a hike?
Too Oak Tree Hill. I’m already
exhausted.
Kiiko. How nice!
They have monkeys there.
Really?
Thank you for the present.
Don’t mention it.
Going shopping?
Yes, to the train station.
See you.
That was Mrs. Amayama.
Shes been sick for quite some time.
She looks quite young.
It's the medicine.
it's turned her hair white.
The butcher shop was okay.
But they weren’t that friendly if
you didn't buy a lot.
50 yen is just too much for two persons.
They bragged about their customers
who own Alsatians.
And gave us the third degree because
we only spend 20 or 30 yens.
I’ve decided never to set foot in
that shop again.
It's just too much.
The one behind the train station
is better.
Behind the train
station is better.
Kenkichi can pick some up on
his way home.
Your husband is brilliant.
But he looks so dumb, he drives
me nuts.
I searched everywhere to look
for your shoe...
If it isn't in the house, you'll never
find it.
I’m sorry. This is Imasato,
our new neighbor
The one in the promotion business.
Pleased to meet you.
I myself teach flower arrangement.
My name is [illegible].
This is Mrs. [illegible],
a big shot at the company.
Oh please...
This is a good film.
There’s a discount coupon in the
newspaper, let's see it.
It's very touching.
That’s how I felt.
It could have happened in real life.
You just cant depend on your
children these days.
All the toil and work to bring up
a child, why bother?
The children leave home,
the husband cheats on her, poor woman.
That Mr. Amayama seems to be
having an affair.
Was that her?
It's so terrible when a woman gets sick,
and she has to bear children.
[illegible]
She cant. There're side effects...
I´mm going to get some threads.
I have to pick up some vegetables
for lunch.
I have to go get cotton balls.
Goodbye.
Here you are. You’re really early
today. This morning...
The guy next to us forgets his pass.
Here you are.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
That’s alright.
It's great to be home early.
It's good enough to be home on time.
You’re getting a big bonus,
aren't you?
To fight for our New Year stipend,
we have to wait.
If we go on like this, the company
will fold.
You’re kidding.
I’m serious.
Your wife showed me this shop
this morning.
Really?
I’m going the other way.
Do you like movies?
I used to go to the cinema
every week.
You like foreign movies,
don't you?
It's terrible here. The smell from
the toilet ruins everything.
You’re home. For once you're
early and you have to complain.
You should have told me.
Here're the keys.
I’ve made an appointment with
your husband.
To see a movie on Sunday.
It's all settled.
Open up!
You’re so bad.
You should be glad when other
people are happy.
From now I’m not going to
take you anywhere.
Sorry. I just cant help it.
A question of the lack of simplicity.
If you’re not going, tell them quickly.
I don't even have a clean pair of socks.
I told you they're not dry. Size 22.
Herringbone.
They don't last very long.
I don’t get it.
Hurry. The third shop before the
train station.
They’re so keen on having us.
it's hard to decline now.
Why don’t you go by yourself.
I don’t want to twist your arm,
that'll upset you.
You have to do something about your
personality.
I was never interested in going out.
My sister and I would have a date
to go see Sumo wrestling.
And I would take out the kimono
and still didn’t want to go.
I suddenly have an headache.
I don’t know what to do.
Lets call it off.
If Mr. Namiki doesn’t mind,
why don't you go.
Since your husband is also not going...
What a Sunday. What a drag.
You go by yourself.
It's alright.
I´mm fine one way or another.
Sorry to trouble you. He doesn’t
understand, he just complains.
In that case, I’m going.
Don’t be too late.
I’m so glad.
Such fine weather.
Excuse me.
Missus... I'll bring back some
local products.
Don’t be in a hurry.
They are made of the Chinese Parasol
of Aizu, where they come from.
With real clog tracks. Please take
a look.
There're more than 10 tracks on a clog
and only 120 yen a pair.
A real bargain.
Please take a good look.
Real quality clogs, well worth
the price.
And now only 200 yen for two pairs.
290 yen for three pairs.
The clog shop over there will cost
you more than 300 yen a pair.
I'll take that pair, please.
Thank you.
A hot bath is nice.
The ox spleen from day before
yesterday has gone bad.
Are you upset?
Forget it.
I didn’t get drunk that last time
I was with you.
It's not that bad to go with you
once in a while.
How understanding you are.
I’m sorry for yesterday.
I had a good dream last night.
The happiest dream in my life.
I dream I was a millionaire.
Did you get your traveling
allowance yet?
I spent it all yesterday.
Really?
Two three thousand yen they don’t
last very long. Where're...?
I forgot this morning.
You forgot. That’s swell.
All the ugliness, all the sorrow.
I really forgot.
And today’s rice.
I almost broke my gullet.
It could also be good exercise for
my stomach...
You fool. It's not working because
you don't dream.
Dreams are fun, you know.
But...
In last nights dream, a 16
or 17-year-old.
Walks into a big forest. She is
not frightened,
...only sad. Suddenly, she is overcome
by the thought of suicide.
Listen, when she is about to
kill herself...
Who?
Lets drop it.
I was just in the middle of it.
And then? There got to be people
flying in dreams.
You really don’t have a poets
sensitivity.
I was just going to hang myself...
I’m not going out today.
Where're my socks?
All of a sudden,
a teenage girl touched me.
A really familiar face.
She asked me what I was doing.
I said I was making a swing,
and she gave me her belt.
What a drag.
The two of us were swinging...
Her hair caressed my face...
Finish it tonight. I’m late.
Guess who she is.
Yesterday I...
That young girl...
Whoever she is.
Looks like you.
Really?
How can you be so calm.
Someone picked my wallet yesterday.
Where?
How much money did you have?
Good morning.
Thank you for inviting my wife
to dinner.
The dog. It belong to that family,
doesn’t it?
We lost a short-legged chicken
recently.
Were sure the dog had it.
We keep chickens to educate
our children.
That’s really too much.
Excuse me.
Mimi main store. Yes.
Yes. I understand.
Fujita, come over here.
I've just been refused an advance.
Is that so?
The old man is coming in from the
countryside. Bad news.
A pickpocket got my wife’s wallet.
Really, this woman.
Were having meeting at 11:45.
Everybody please be present and
on time.
What is it?
Can't be any good.
For the purpose of expansion,
the Tsukijirushi Company...
...will deploy one third of it's
staff here.
What does it mean?
Dismissal.
Please listen carefully. As the sales
department is particularly important.
The company is therefore sending
four employees over.
And hoping four employees here will
resign.
On top of a severance pay, the company
will contribute another 100.000 yen.
If no one resigns,
the company will make the decision.
The bonus, however, will be withdrawn.
Please consider the offer carefully.
In other words, it mean laying off.
Just as I expected.
100.000 yen.
Four from the sales department.
Five years. How much severance
pay does it worth?
It's more than 5 years.
I win!
Take!
Running a lucky streak.
Winning back what your wife lost,
aren’t you?
Not yet...
100.000 yen bonus.
100.000 yen!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Lets eat.
Yes.
Is Mr. Namiki not eating?
His stomach is not well.
Really?
I know a very good doctor.
Roast yam!
How're you?
It's 20 yen.
Thank you. It's freezing.
Good morning.
Good morning, Ma’am.
Your husband just called.
He asked you to come to the
roof of the Shiraki building.
Shiraki.
He's waiting for you there.
The roof...
Excuse me.
Thank you for your trouble.
Have your husband gone to work?
It's early.
From here those expensive cars
look insignificant.
Supposedly there’s a big safe
inside the Nihon Bank.
Standing here,
everything look like junk.
Do you come here often?
I often come on the roof.
I rarely...
What a coincidence.
Where do you work?
The sales department of Mimi
cosmetics.
Expensive stuff.
I believe your wife will know.
A good business.
Just getting by, two meals and
a roof.
What about foreign literature?
We also ship to Thailand and India.
Foreign languages also come in
handy.
Are you looking at my shoes?
That’s okay.
No shame in wearing broken shoes.
Of course. But before you wouldn’t
even explain.
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
Did you get everything?
Someone is bringing them to the car.
Your wife’s still not here?
We were planning to eat together...
I was just saying my stomach isn’t
feeling too good...
Something light wont do any harm.
Welcome everybody.
Mr. Kato of High School 1.
Please go to refreshment on the
third floor.
The clock stopped;
and I didn’t sleep very well last night.
Eveything's wrong since I lost
my wallet.
You fool. The company is in trouble.
You'll get your money back from
mah-jong.
It looks really bad.
Whats the problem?
Are you hungry?
I can't eat anything
maybe some red bean soup.
Red bean soup.
Welcome.
What can I get you?
Soup.
Soup. Soup and soda.
Yes.
That was your old friend?
Inherited the family business;
he's got it good.
I could be as good if I went back
to my village.
I hate people who look down
on others.
It's rather embarrassing.
Are you going back to your village?
Just to have a look, then I'll decide.
The old man's no longer young.
Treat your stomach to an x-ray.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Severance pay and bonus,
altogether 200,000 yen.
Spend it on your children's education,
retire to your village.
No more worries about making a living.
But you don't like village life?
It's good for your health.
Sticky rice and crowded trains.
What a life!
Sticky rice?
Bread is also bad for the stomach.
So is mah-jong.
Don't be so careless.
Do you have enough presents?
Mrs. Namiki.
How´re you?
The principal of the kindergarten
said you ordered it.
He insisted on leaving it here.
And he said he´s done everything
he could to bring it back to life.
Really?
Please take over quickly.
How much?
500 yen.
Annual production is 369 eggs.
For an hour he repeated the same
thing over and over again.
I´m truly sorry.
And say I should be careful living
in the neighborhood.
Sorry.
And said both master and mistress
of the house are unfriendly.
That they pretend not to see you
when you meet them on the street.
I go out when I hear the bell of
roast yam at night.
I only had them once.
I only have cheap bean curd...
My husband has stomach problems.
Bean curd!
Yes.
What´s his business.
Really.
The problem with the stomach
is not just food.
It´s a nervous disorder, an urban
ailment.
A friend of mine has removed 2/3
of his stomach.
Another has removed 3/4.
They say they feel better this way.
Why don´t you do the same?
I´m thinking about it.
If I were single I´d have something
to do.
Single won´t do.
My professor has retired and is
devoting himself to writing.
He´s looking for someone to run errands,
no special knowledge required.
The hours are 9 to 4, lunch is provided;
and he pays 9,000 yen a month.
Comparable to a clerical position.
He´s looking for a man.
No, a woman.
Oh, a woman.
I thought your wife might...
Did my wife ask you to look for
a job for her?
It´s not that. I was just thinking...
That won´t be necessary.
Have an operation...
That´s my stomach.
You´re back.
Who is it?
We´ve been waiting
for you.
What is it?
Kawakami has something to discuss
with you.
This is my neighbor Komori.
He´s a painter.
How do you do?
Come over here.
Please go ahead.
A chicken?
The kindergarten chicken.
What?
It was bitten by the stray dog
yesterday, it just died.
The meat will be rough.
The kindergarten chicken.
I forgot to get eggs, and wine too.
Money?
Pardon me.
What did the doctor say?
Remove it, make things simple.
So you´ll delay your trip back to
the village.
I have more pressing business.
About what?
I have a good idea.
Did you get my chicken?
My husband just came back.
I still don´t have money.
You can pay me later.
To promote understanding among
neighbors.
I´m inviting everybody to attend
a meeting.
Please come to the kindergarten
at 7:30 this evening.
It´s not against you.
Better talk about things in the
open than behind people´s back.
We can discuss and make improvements.
It´s all for the good of the neighborhood.
Remember, 7:30.
Please.
A frugal meal.
This chicken has laid too many eggs.
It´s not bad if you really taste it.
Opening a yakitori shop?
Listen to me.
Komori is good with deep fry.
He can do Java or Sumitra deep fry.
I can do the decoration.
A fashionable cafe or a bar is
more profitable.
So?
In other words, the four of us, our
total pension fund comes to 1 million yen.
That I know.
It´ll be a waste not to start a business.
That I understand.
Jintaro has started a business.
What people call a merger is in
fact sharing the debts.
And people come fighting for it.
It´s always like this.
So they moved to the wooden
factories in Wakayama.
A most fitting burial ground.
Mimi´s cleansing lotion is not
too good.
There´re always new products.
What are ours plans?
Yes.
What should we do?
Fashionable and elegant...
Just like Mrs. Namiki.
What?
Different from an ordinary bar.
It should have the feeling of
Mrs. Namiki.
Lively but emotionally fragile.
Exactly.
Stop kidding.
Don´t egg him on.
He´ll think he´s some big shot.
You are the bartender, be more
generous.
No.
He´s not important; if you´re in it.
About sharing profit's,
that we can discuss later.
Both Tada and I have jobs,
so this is only a side-line.
Your stomach is not well.
You should first make you wife
a uniform.
Uniforms are very important.
Western style is better.
Contemporary Japanese is fine.
Mrs. Namiki, are you interested?
Could be very hard for just
one person.
But there must be a home atmosphere...
Everything has to be proper.
Two persons take charge of the cooking,
and we´ll hire an assistant.
Mrs. Namiki will take care of the
customers...
Whose idea is it anyway?
Ours. We really worked on it.
And we found someone willing
to loan us the capital.
We can decide on the amount after
talking to Mrs. Namiki.
What?
Time´s changed. Men are now useless.
That´s not true.
It´s a woman´s world.
You have to use yours looks.
It´s hard to make a living.
You can´t close yourself up.
Is that so?
Shut up!
What is it? It´s all out of good will.
For your health´s sake...
That won´t be necessary.
Sorry to have disturbed you.
I´m going out for a while.
Please enjoy the meal.
Thank you.
Everyone´s waiting for you.
I´m sorry.
What meeting? A war has just started.
My wife said someone was going to
use it to run an election campaign.
Dogs are smarter than people.
But they need training.
Please sit down.
I´ve invited her along.
Sorry I´m late.
Please express your opinions in
this meeting.
So we can make improvements.
We´re just talking about dogs.
There´s a 20 yen fee,
but we´ll collect that later.
Who was talking?
I was. I think dogs must be leashed.
You´re walking down the street in the evening
and a dog jumps at you out of nowhere.
Mrs. Taneda, you don´t put your Alsatian
on leash, do you?
For safety, also for exercise.
But people can get hurt.
My little Mary is also afraid of
dogs in the evening.
He´s really noisy.
He wakes up my children all
the time.
But your children and their friends.
Are always making all this noise
outside my study.
I just can´t write.
Really? I´ll teach them.
So the problem is children?
No, it´s dogs.
Let me bring up an even more
important issue.
On a rainy day, when you turn into the
little streets here from the main road.
It´s really troublesome.
That we have to talk to the
landowner or the government.
Also, please set up a time table
for piano practice.
It´s always the same tune.
Are you talking about my Chieko?
You talk about noise,
and I´ll talk about smell.
I can smell it from my sitting room
when you fertilize your garden.
Can you use odorless fertilizer?
Everybody,
let me get the issues in order.
The issue is dogs.
The chicken always dig out
the seeds.
The principal´s chicken always
dirty my walls.
Really?
Also,
who said my wife wears her clothes
like wearing a hat on a finger?
She was really upset about it,
and instructed me bring this up.
A hat on a finger.
I´ve been criticized for not
greeting others...
That´s just because I was thinking.
Don´t let these things upset you.
We´ve come to no conclusions
whatsoever.
In any case,
dogs and chickens must be unleash.
I have to go first.
Good night.
Is everybody gone?
I threw them out.
What happened?
What is it?
They were talking about such things,
and you didn´t do anything.
What things?
You fool. The yakitori shop.
I think that's rather amusing.
How?
Well isn´t it?
People look down on us.
You have a problem. Why can´t
I work?
Why don´t you let me work?
A working wife makes her husband
lose face?
What nonsense!
I don´t want my wife to support me.
Who´s supporting you?
I only want each of us to make money-
You´re still providing the meals.
We spend what we earn.
Are you serious?
Come here. I have to talk to you.
I haven´t had lunch.
I´m so hungry I could cry.
What a drag.
Do you know what I want to
talk about?
What?
I thought you were ignoring me.
Why are you so angry?
You can do what you please.
I´m going back to the village
to farm.
You´re not used to life in the
country, better stay here.
Good. I see what you mean, you...
It´s too much trouble.
Listen.
You always say you´re going back.
But your younger brother is already
there, farming.
You can´t just go back and eat
even if you´re the eldest son.
Is 100,000 yen really that important?
You´ve become a mouse for a little
money. How dreadful.
Mouse?
If you make 5,000 yen a month
it´ll just take you two years.
10,000 yen a month and it´s even
less than a year.
Even I can do that.
In that case, it´s alright to separate.
Well, do you want to separate?
I see no other way.
I thought I was having a serious
discussion with you.
You´re so feudal,
no wonder Ayako is mad at you.
You think everything will be there
for you in the village.
You ruin your stomach and you´ve
become a coward.
"My husband took this picture.
We are fine."
"Don´t worry about me. Will visit
you later."
"Ayako."
Uncle, balloons.
Okay?... Oh...
Get hold of it.
Damn it.
Harder.
That´s it.
Keep going.
Damn... not yet.
They were fighting last night.
Just look at them!