In the year of Lord. 1442.
The Turkish Sultan enslaved
1,000 Transylvania boys.
To fill the ranks of his army.
These child slaves were
beaten without mercy.
Trained to kill without conscience.
To crave the blood..
of all who would
fight the Turks.
From among these boys...
one grew into a warrior, so fearsome that
entire armies would retreat in terror..
to the mention of his name,
Vlad the Impaler.
Son of the Dragon.
sickened by his monstrous act...
Vlad came to bury his past with the dead.
And returned to Transylvania
to rule in peace.
His subjects called him Prince.
I call him Father.
But the world would come to know him as...
Dracula.
I left it...
where I found it.
What do you think, Vlad?
Bring it to me.
This belongs to a scout.
One of Hamza Bey's men.
What the hell is a lone
Turk doing out here?
Turkish scouts never travel alone.
If there is one, there is more.
And whatever they scout...
they conquer.
This is washed downstream.
It came from up there.
Broken Tooth Mountain.
Soon it will be night.
They'll seek refuge.
Dumitru, I need you to
return to the castle.
Alert the guards and
double the sentury.
What? I'm not leaving you here.
The Turks to cross into my land,
unannounced, is a sign of war.
What are you going to do
if you find them?
I'll do what Princes
do best, negotiate.
Nicolai, Andre, with me.
Anything?
It smell like your feet.
They are inside.
How do you know?
Bats don't come out during the day.
Something's disturbed them.
Come on.
What is it, my Lord?
The floor. It's crushed the
bone.The Turks didn't do this.
What's that?
We leave. Now.
The creature you encountered
was no accident, my Prince.
4 nights ago every brother of our order
awoke from an identical dream.
I would not have thought
it possible, had I not..
..suffered the same vision
myself that night.
every  creature lands siege
to this holy place.
The Romans mystics prophecized
the coming of a great evil.
A vampire.
From the Greek word, Vry.
To drink.
The beast was once a mortal
man,who summoned the demon..
from the depths of hell, to
trade for his dark power.
The demon tricked the man,
granting his wish.
But his price was eternity condemned
the darkness of that cave.
Where he remains until he finds
another to set him free.
Now you know it's true face.
The people of Transylvania are
living in a fear the Turks return.
Promise me you'll guard
this secret, brother.
Papa!
I've missed you.
And I - you.
My big soldier.
What, an embrace, but no kiss?
Are we going to argue?
You always go away if you want to?
I've missed you.
Something troubles you, what is it?
Only the impossible depths of your beauty.
Puts the rest of the world to shame.
Pay no attention to your father, Ingeras.
Flattery is a cheap distraction from truth.
Ah, she knows all my tricks.
You're a terrible liar.
It's one of your most endearing qualities.
You're just in time for bed.
Can we go riding tomorrow, Papa?
Of course we can.
You most certainly cannot!
Why not?
Because tomorrow is the
day of our recent Lord.
Ah, of course.
That's Easter.
What was I thinking...
So, what attacked you?
Wolves?
I suppose.
All I know... is that I've
lost two good men today.
There is something more...
I was the same age as Ingeras, when
I was sent to live with the Turks.
To fight for them.
If I never saw another
it would be too soon.
You're home now.
For almost as many years as you were gone.
I just want peace, that's all.
My fellow Transylvanians,
an Easter toast.
Ten years of peace and prosperity,
ever since our prince came back to us..
My old friend, here's to 20 more..
Hamza bey, welcome.We were
not expecting you so soon.
Sultan mehmed II offers his
salutation for you and your son.
Thank you.
I have his tribute ready.
I am afraid there's something
more than attribute to discussed.
The Turk has no enemies here.
Did you think we would notice
a battalion scouts missing ?
I did not kill them.
It still lives inside you, Lord Impaler.
Locked in a dark cage, hidden away.
But you and I.. we both
know that it,s there.
The sultan's tribute.
Take it and leave.
There is one last thing.
The Sultan requires 1000 boys
to join his Janissary Corps.
NO! Never.
He ended that practice years ago.
If a soldier is plucked as a child.
And is educated, only in this life.
Kill them without question,
and die without complaint.
Any who are 15 years of age or older,
will fight in Hungary.
Those from 10 to 14 will be
made ready for the siege of Vienna.
The sultan expects your abiding.
After all, did not your father give you up
without a fight.
Soft, but they'll do.
Don't, please.
Do you know who I am?
You mean who you were.
You have no army and no choice, prince.
Follow our command, or
suffer the consequences.
It must be done.
Courage, anger love, non of
these can matter to a prince.
All that matter is his duty  to his people.
What does it mean to be a royal hostage?
My father gave me to the
sultan to prove his loyalty.
Were you scared there?
With them?
I wanted to make my father proud.
Do you have to give me to the Sultan?
That was a long time ago.
You have nothing to worry about.
You understand?
Good.
If I defy the order they'll
kill 100 for every one I save.
You told me you and Mehmed
were once like brothers.
Why didn't you ask... Isn't it possible
he might show you some mercy?
Have you ever seen the like of it?
Soon the entire world will be Turk.
Lord Impaler.
My oldest of friends.
I miss that days together.
All I miss from my time
with you is the coffee.
It's true that my father's palace was a
cruel place for a young boy far from home.
But soon you talked like us,
prayed like us, fought like us...
speakig of which, I am owed 1,000 boys.
Why I have not seen them?
Mehmed, my brother.
I will grant you anything El's.
I need soldiers, brother.
Then take me.
I'm worth a 1,000 boys
and you know it.
Kings would tremble if they knew.
Then accept my offer.
When we were boys, how I
long to fight side by side.
But now I sultan what I needed to one
soldier. I will have my 1000 boys.
And one more.
Your son will be raised under my roof.
Just as you were raised under
the roof of my father.
You may retain your throne.
But General Ismail will remain to see
that my orders are fulfilled.
So what is one son?
If you're virile, you make plenty more.
You promised this would never happen.
Merina, listen.
The day you asked for my hand,
do you remember what I said?
You said no.
I knew what happened
with the son of a queen.
You said things would be different.
You said if I loved you I should trust you.
I love you!
-Then trust me!
-It's this or we start a war!
The Great Impaler can't
to satisfy his women.
It's just saying goodbyes.That's all.
I will not let them take our
children. I promise to my family!
I won't let them do that.
I'll go.
I can do it.
You are proud of me. Aren't you?
Of course, I am.
You have chosen wisely.
I have to say, we are
a little disappointed.
Frankly, I expected more
resistance from you.
Run to your mother.
What?
Now.
Mehmed will punish all the transylvania
for what you've done.
It's not a child's place
to save his country.
Get my family to the castle.
Mehmed will be sending others soon enough.
War will come,
You can't protect us.
I'll find a way.
Vlad, where are you going?
Whatever horror in Broken Tooth.
I know it kills Turks.
I assume no one has ever had
the privilege of leave either.
Those are meant to reek of fear.
In you... I sense hope.
Your silver offends me,
from my sight.
What kind of man crawled into his
own grave in search of hope.
A desperate one.
The Turks threaten to destroy my kingdom.
Power like yours. I could stop them.
Save my people. Save my family.
How supremely noble, Lord Impaler.
How is Dracula, son of the devil?
You are mistaken.
It means 'Son of the dragon,
protector of the innocent'.
Do your people how many
innocents you have killed?
Was it... Hundreds?
Yes.
Lie to me again, and I open you
from your belly to your brain.
and feed you your intestines.
Thousands.
And when you put them to the
stake, what did you feel?
Shame, horror, power?
Answer me!
Nothing. I felt nothing.
There is nothing more cruel than that.
Then why spill blood, if not
for the pleasure of it?
Because men do not fear swords.
They fear monsters.
Run from them. By putting one..
..village to the stake I spare ten more.
Sometimes the world no longer needs a hero.
Sometimes what it
needs is a monster.
And you believe you know
what it is you be a monster?
You have no idea.
But I am going to show you.
For centuries these mouldering
walls have been my gallows.
Now I'm bound to this cave,
condemned by one who turned me.
Oh, I've waited an eternity
for a man of your strength.
Your gifts, your will.
A man, worthy of the dark.
and all it's powers.
For if I am your
salvation, you are mine.
Drink, you will have a
taste of my power.
The strength of a 100 men.
The speed of a falling star.
Predominant on the night.
And all it's creatures to see
and hear through their senses.
Even heal gravest wounds.
At what price?
Once you drink your thirst for
human blood will be insatiable.
But if you can resist for tree days.
You'll return to your mortal state.
Having sampled my power.
And perhaps saved your people.
And if I feed?
The price will be worse than if
you'd never stepped in here.
Well, I will be set free, having granted
the darkness a worthy offering.
You will become it's vessel, as I am.
A scourge on this Earth.
Destined to destroy.
Everything you hold dear, your lands, your
people, even your precious wife and son.
I would die before I harm them.
Indeed you will, I'm afraid.
I however would last be free to unleash..
my wrath against the one who betrayed me.
And one day I will call on
you to serve me, my pawn.
Ending the mortal game of revenge.
This is not a game!
Won't better way to endure the eternity?
This little prince is the ultimate game.
Light verses dark.
Hope verses despair.
And all the word's fate hangs in balance.
And it will be my great
pleasure to disappoint you.
Drink.
Let the games begin.
What now?
Now...
You die.
Papa!
Just a small scars.
Fire!
You came back.
I always will.
Where were you?
Searching for the strength I needed.
You're back.
They want our children!
A good Prince would
had given them up!
A good Prince would have
paid that price for peace.
But I give you my word.
We will not be defeated.
They brought war to our land,
and they will pay dearly for it.
Fire!
Negotiation's failed.
Do not ask me what happened
on this field tonight,
Trust only thar I use all
I have to keep us safe.
But we will not be safe if we stay here!
We must leave directly to the Casio
Monestre. It's high in the mountains.
Too remort for Cannon fire.
It's our best chance of survival.
We'll take a half of our people, it's
not that our absence is noticed.
That way, when Mehmed learns
what has happened here.
He'll come hunting for us.
Vlad from Castle Dracula.
Vlad has defeated a 1000 of our men.
Then send a 100,000.
I will lead them.
When I march into Europe, I will
have his head upon my spear.
And his child? At my side.
We can fight the way our
great grandfathers fought.
Use the forests, the mountains
around the Burgo Pass.
Four or five months of that.
Not months. I'm gonna win
this war in three days.
Why not two?
That really impresses.
What is it?
I need some air.
I'm sorry.
Don't think I haven't
noticed you following me.
You're mistaken. I follow them.
They recognize one of their own.
The night is their kingdom,
blood is their sustenance.
And some may say have lived for as long
as there have been prey to devour.
Spare me your reevings.
They say the one who escaped the mountains,
hides behind the
face of a man.
Well if that man is me, you know
your knife will not do you any good.
Of course not.
Why do you think I stayed?
I know there's only so far on this earth
they can run.
And it is not far enough.
Let me serve you.
Stay away from me.
Yes, Master.
We found him in the field.
He asked for you.
A message from Prince Vlad.
He hopes you enjoy the view.
Your scars are gone?
What's happening to you?
I meet what men fear in broken tooth.
Not a ghost, something else.
No! Stop it! May God strike down
whoever did this to you.
I chose this.
This is the strength you sought?
But why?
Because I sent corpses back to
mehmed, instead of our son.
You did this for us?
In two days I'll be restored.
I just have to resist.
Resist what?
Resist what, vlad?
Tell me.
Thirst for blood.
And if you were to give in?
Then I become this for eternity.
You will not do this, won't you?
Yes.
I swear, I will not give in.
So God will forgive you.
Vlad! Mehmed is getting closer.
You might want to move out soon.
I need you to get to the monastery
as quickly as you can.
Mehmed's men will
be close behind.
-No!
-Listen to me.
I will reach you after sundown.
I promise you.
I love you.
My husband agrees with your council.
We will depart now, under
your temporary command.
What? Where is Vlad going to be?
Spying on the Turks.
He insists on doing a reconnaissance.
No. I won't allow it.
It's too late. He's already gone.
All right, everyone.
Prepare to move out!
Tell the Sultan where his
enemies will be buried.
Listen.
We are nearly there.
Cover the rear.
Couldn't these monks put the gate
a little bit closer?!
Stay behind me.
Didn't the Turks teach you anything,
I saw your blade coming from..
Ingeras, run!
Where is your Prince now?
My Lady..
Dimitru
It's ok.
Vlad.
Dimitru listen. Listen!
No.
Come here.
Never leave us again, Papa.
Never.
I will always watch over you.
To the gate!!
Keep moving on!
This way!
You should never've
straight from us!
Whatever you reason.
Quiet.
Get these men off their knees.
Stand up, you hear me stand up.
The turks are coming! Prayers
will not defend these walls!
Do you believe we can do this?
Mehmet's men will be
coming from the north.
Double the guards of the fort.
Go, do it now!
What's in there?
Something I hope to never use it again.
Come now.
The men say that vlad has become a monster.
They fear this will only inflect the
rumors of the prince' dark magic.
Only we allow it.
Men can not fear what
they can not see!
Remember when you
first join my army!
You wanted to pick up
your sword and fight!
When my generals blindfolded you,
You did not believed that you
could march without seeing.
But you could.
Now march with me!
Your sultan will guide you!
Prince vlad, the vampire
is vulnerable to daylight.
And to pure silver.
Yet the holy cross has
no power over you.
That can only mean you have yet to
seal your fate with human blood.
Let me kill you now, my Prince.
Please!
Before your people do. Rumor has
spread of what you have become.
You can still repent.
You do will to run, Lucien.
He's a vampire.
No!
Listen! He is your Prince!
Please give him a chance to explain!
-Stop, please!
-Kill the monster!
Satan lives in his heart!
Vlad...
Try to save his soul.
Take him to my room and shut the door.
Do not let him not look outside.
Mama!
This is your loyalty?
Your gratitude?
Fools. Do you think you're
alive because you can fight?
You are alive because of me!
Because of what I did to save you!
This is not who you are.
Return to your stations.
Believe me, there is
still more to fear!
Lord, if you've not yet forsaken me
that I may resist the darkness.
Allow me to endure this
test one more day.
I beg you.
Please.
Are you sick?
If you are sick, thought
this make you feel better.
Thank you. Come.
You'll make a great
leader some day.
You think of others before yourself.
When the Turks came to take me...
you stopped them.
That's why you got sick, isn't it?
To save me?
Yes.
And I would do it all again.
They're almost here.
Sun will be breaking soon
and with it the last of my powers.
If we've not won this war by then.
I will fight beside you until death.
Your death would end my fight.
We have done the duty of any good parent.
Protected our child.
Protected all the children in the kingdom.
Perhaps our destiny was
not to rule in this life.
Do you remember our wedding vow?
Why thinks separately if
this life and the next.
When one is born from the the last.
Time is always too short
for those who need it.
But those who love,
love forever.
Stand your position!
Fire!
Mehmed!
Where is he?
Where is he!
Fire!
Find your father, go!
Where is he?
You can keep running,
if you like.
Mama!
Let me go! No!
Mirena!
No, please!
Ingeras!
No!
No!!
Please stay with me.
I can not do this without you.
Mirena!
There's still time for you to stop them.
Drink my blood.
No! I can not take your life.
My life is lost already.
But our son is not.
No!
I love you.
Do it now.
Please.
Do you want vengeance?
Drink.
I now know hell is real.
So I know there's a heaven.
Neither this world nor the
next shall keep us apart.
I will honor your sacrifice and I
vow that our son shall be safe.
Of all my lands, this is
the one I love the least.
Look to the east. The sun should
be up by now but it's not.
What is that?
It is the prince the prince.
He's coming.
I used to think there
were too many of you.
Now this not enough.
I understand you
have a weakness.
Pure silver.
Papa!
He's waiting for you
You're slower, brother, and the weaker.
Go on, take it!
Is this the monster
that terrified my men?
You grow more weary by the moment.
Tell me, how long can
you bear it in here?
Long enough to strike your name
from the history books.
Papa!
Look at your father Ingeras.
Look how pathetic he is.
Stop! please!
If I put the stake
through your heart..
It will kill you.
Like any other man.
A fitting death,
for Lord..
Impaler..
Papa!
That is no longer my name.
My name is Dracula.
Son of the Devil.
It's all right,
I'm here.
- You old goat.
- I don't feel old.
How many are left?
None... except for your son.
Of course.
A distraction we can now... dispense.
What have I told you?
Repeated, over and over,
since you were a boy?
All that matters is that
prince's duty to his people.
Don't you realize?
They are all our enemy now.
When he's gone, you'll be free.
You forget who I am?
Leave him.
Come with me, child.
Please.
Reverse!
It has to stop.
Please!
I don't want to leave you.
-You have to go with him.
-No!
Do not leave his side.
No!
I will always love you.
Always.
Go!
No!
Please.
Go.
No!
You take care of him.
Papa!
No!
He's safe now Mirena.
The Turks never conquered
the capitals of Europe.
Prince Vlad Dracula was a hero.
But there are no pictures
or statues of him.
I.. am his legacy.
His sacrifice taught me,
that even after the darkest night.
The sun will rise again.
Drink, master.
If the heart is strong enough,
the soul is reborn.
With each new day.
In life after life.
Age after age.
Forever.
Beautiful.
The flowers, my lady.
My lady?
Where are you from?
Far away from here.
Well, good night.
I think separate of this life and the next.
When one is born of the last.
It's my favorite poem.
It speaks to you of yearning.
Of one soul pleading for another.
I am mina.
Vlad.
Let the games begin.
Subtitles by: Min Ciosa