- Still nothing?
- Nothing.
Food court? You sure they said food court?
I'm sorry, have my translation skills
been letting you down?
We don't know it's your kids.
Yes, we do.
- What is that?
- There's something in there.
- No!
- Jesus Christ.
Keep her talking.
Keep her awake, okay?
Jesus Christ.
Hey, hey, hey. Stay awake, stay awake.
Let's get her on this side, on this side.
- Easy, easy, easy, easy.
- It's, uh...
You know, it's not actually that bad.
There was a...
The goalie on my soccer team,
Beth Wildfire,
this other girl slid into her leg,
and the bone came out of her knee,
- six inches or something, it was insane.
- Robin.
- Yeah?
- You're not helping.
I'm sorry.
Okay. All right, El?
This is gonna hurt like hell, okay?
- Okay.
- Need you to stay real still.
Here, you're gonna want to bite down
on this, okay?
Jesus Christ.
Holy shit. Holy shit.
Do it.
Okay.
Oh, shit.
- Jonathan!
- Stop talking!
- Goddamn it!
- No! Stop it!
Stop! Stop!
I can do it.
God!
The Mind Flayer,
it built this monster in Hawkins,
to stop El, to kill her
and pave a way into our world.
And it almost did.
That was just one tiny piece of it.
How big is this thing?
It's big.
- Thirty feet, at least.
- Yeah.
It sorta destroyed your cabin.
Sorry.
Okay, so, just to be clear, this...
this big fleshy spider thing that hurt El,
it's some kind of gigantic... weapon?
- Yes.
- But instead of, like, screws and metal,
the Mind Flayer made its weapon...
with melted people.
- Yes, exactly.
- Yeah, okay.
I... Yeah, I'm just making sure.
Are we sure this thing is still out there,
still alive?
El beat the shit out of it,
but, yeah, it's still alive.
- But if we close the gate again...
- We cut the brain off from the body.
And kill it.
Theoretically.
Yoo-hoo!
Okay, this is what Alexei called
"the hub."
Now, the hub takes us to the vault room.
Okay, where's the gate?
Right here.
I don't know the scale on this,
but I think it's fairly close
to the vault room,
maybe 50 feet or so.
More like 500.
What, you're just gonna waltz in there
like it's commie Disneyland or something?
I'm sorry, who are you?
Erica Sinclair. Who are you?
Murray...
Bauman.
Listen, Mr. Bunman,
I'm not trying to tell you
how to do things,
but I've been down in that shithole
for 24 hours.
And with all due respect,
you do what this man tells you,
you're all gonna die.
I'm sorry, why is this four-year-old
speaking to me?
Um, I'm ten, you bald bastard!
- Erica!
- Just the facts!
She's right. You're all gonna die,
but you don't have to. Excuse me.
- Sorry, may I?
- Please.
Okay, see this room here?
This is a storage facility.
There's a hatch in here that feeds
into their underground ventilation system.
That will lead you to the base
of the weapon.
It's a bit of a maze down there,
but between me and Erica,
we can show you the way.
You can show us the way?
Don't worry, you can do all the fighting
and the dangerous hero shit,
and we'll just be your...
navigators.
No.
Nope.
Well, that settles it.
He's gonna die. They're gonna die.
Yep, most likely.
You guys survived.
Barely.
We could've really used you guys
down there.
Could've used you up here, too.
Yeah, man. We missed you, dude.
Yeah. Big-time.
I missed you guys, too.
Big-time.
Please don't cry, nerds.
- Erica.
- Keep saying my name, see what happens.
Hey, heads up. You can navigate,
just from someplace safe.
- It's not that simple.
- The signal won't reach.
Not with this. You need something
with a high enough frequency band
to relay with the Russians' radio tower.
But for that to work, you need someone
who has both seen their comms room
and has access to a super-powered
handcrafted radio tower,
one preferably already situated
at the highest point in Hawkins.
Oh, wait.
That's me.
If you want us to navigate, you got us.
But we need a head start.
And a car.
Oh, man, now this...
this is what I'm talkin' about!
- "Toddfather"?
- Oh, screw Todd!
Steve's her daddy now.
Did you just talk about yourself
in the third person?
- Did he just call himself daddy?
- All right, where are we going?
- Weathertop.
- Weather-what?
- Just drive.
- Okay. Jesus!
Bottom lock,
second-to-top lock,
third-to-top lock,
top lock.
Listen to me, I need to end this,
but I will be back before you know it,
okay?
- I don't know, Mom.
- No, listen. You're gonna be safe there.
It's... It's far away from all this.
You just stick close to your brother
and... and do whatever he says.
No matter what. Okay?
I'm not worried about me, Mom,
I'm worried about you.
Oh, honey, I'm gonna be fine.
Okay? I'm gonna be fine.
Okay, Mom.
Okay, Mom. That's enough.
- I'm gonna be fine.
- Okay.
Mom, I can't breathe.
- My battery's low, but...
- You're suffocating me.
It will recharge.
I know it will, kid.
I know.
I can fight.
Better than any of us.
But right now,
I need you safe.
This thing is after you.
It's not after me.
Do you understand?
Hey...
I need you to understand.
Okay?
Hey.
We should probably go.
Mike?
Be careful.
What?
It's a two-man operation. Two!
- Yeah, well, change of plans.
- Change of plans?
- Yeah. Will you explain it to him, please?
- We have two options here, Jim.
We can turn the machine off,
or we can explode it.
- Oh, yeah, says who?
- Says the man who built it!
- Yeah, and we wanna explode it!
- Or else our heroic efforts
will be for naught!
This is a three-man operation, Jim,
not two.
Yeah, three.
El, you're bleeding.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
- Here.
- Okay.
Here.
Lay down.
- What's wrong?
- I don't...
I don't know.
You can't be serious. Come on!
Didn't your mom just buy this car?
Yes. I'm sure it's fine.
- Did you leave the lights on?
- No.
- Do we have gas?
- Yes!
- Come on!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa! Just stop, stop!
Pop the hood.
- What the hell?
- What?
The ignition cable's gone.
Back in the mall!
- Go! Go, go, go!
- Be careful!
Go! Go!
Go, go, go!
So then I yank those cables
like I'm pulling weeds.
- And that'll set off the alarm...
- According to Alexei,
may his soul rest in peace.
Which should give you two an opening
to retrieve the keys from the vault.
And then we just follow the map
to the observation room, turn the key...
- Kaboom, we blow this sucker sky-high.
- Yeah.
And then, once the rift is closed,
we escape back through the vents.
Right under their commie noses.
Then home free.
Uh...
Oh, God, just because it wasn't your plan
doesn't mean it was a bad plan.
I didn't say it was a bad plan.
You made a noise.
- I did not make a noise.
- You did too.
- I really think it's disrespectful...
- What is up with you and noises?
Children! Children!
It is a good plan.
A solid B, which is laudable,
given the situation and time constraints.
Dare I say, if it all goes right...
They'll never even know we were here.
Stop right there!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Documents, important documents...
for the Lieutenant-Comrade!
He called us, last minute.
Pardon our sloppy appearance.
Lieutenant? What Lieutenant?
Lieutenant...
Molotov?
Oh, shit.
Jim...
This is crazy.
- Oh, my God.
- Jim, I... This...
I had it under control.
Yeah, sure you did.
What are you doing?
I'm improvising.
♪ Your love ♪
♪ Liftin' me higher... ♪
Jesus, how far is this place, man?
Relax, we're almost there.
Suzie must be pretty special, huh?
I mean, if you built this thing
and lugged it all the way to the middle
of nowhere just to talk to her?
I mean, nobody's scientifically perfect,
but Suzie's about as close
to being perfect
as any human could possibly be.
She sound made-up to me.
She sound made-up to you?
- Why are you hesitating, Steve?
- I'm... I'm... I'm not! I'm not!
I think she sounds real.
You know, totally, absolutely real.
Left. Turn left.
- There's not a road here.
- Turn left now!
Jesus! Hang on!
♪ Higher and higher ♪
Whoa! Henderson, where are we going?!
Up!
Whoa!
♪ Liftin' me higher... ♪
- Oh, Jesus!
- We're not gonna make it!
Yes, we are. Come on, baby.
Come on, baby!
Come on!
Come on. Come on.
Guess the Toddfather has its limitations.
Scoops Troop, do you copy?
Scoops Troop, I repeat, do you copy?
We're trapped in the mall
and in need of emergency transportation.
Scoops Troop, do you copy?
Billy has found us.
He has disabled our car
and we are trapped in the mall.
Repeat: Billy has disabled our car
- Scoops Troop...
- You're gonna kill him, aren't you?
This is just a precaution, okay?
And not just against Billy.
If he knows we're here,
so does the Mind Flayer.
Scoops Troop, I repeat, we are in need
of emergency transportation.
Do you copy?
Scoops Troop, do you copy?
No chance that thing'll drive, right?
- Steve, do you copy?
- We don't need it to drive.
Dustin!
We just need the ignition cable.
Push!
Shit!
Let me try.
El...
I can do it.
Can I help?
Picking up.
Do I know you?
New arrivals.
Landed last night.
Say goodbye to sunlight.
Who needs sunlight
when we have one another, comrade?
Indeed, comrade!
And a bottle of Stolichnaya.
Why are you talking so much?
He was nice.
- He was nice?
- He was a nice guard.
Yeah, I mean, we should probably
invite him over after all this is done.
Yeah, I can bake him a casserole.
Get a six-pack,
share some laughs.
You know, have a drink.
Ugh.
Anyone wanna trade jobs?
Bald Eagle, do you copy?
Bald Eagle, I repeat,
this is Scoops Troop, do you copy?
Yes, I copy.
Call sign?
Bald Eagle.
Please repeat.
- Bald Eagle. This is Bald Eagle!
- Copy that.
Good to hear your voice, Bald Eagle.
What's your 20?
We reached the vent.
I'll contact you when I need you.
Until then, silence.
Roger that, Bald Eagle.
This is Scoops Troop, going radio silent.
10-10, over.
I hate children.
- Remember, if anyone says anything, just...
- Smile and nod.
Good luck.
Push!
All right, great.
All right, now, all the way. Ready?
Three, two, one... Push!
Told you.
Physics.
How do we get it open?
Uh, there should be a latch.
Check under the wheel.
- You see it?
- I don't know, hold on.
What's she doing?
El.
Are you okay?
- Do you see it?
- I don't know.
It should be right here.
Distributor, distributor...
Mike.
Got it.
Nancy!
Come on!
We just found them like this.
The American.
It's taking too long.
- It's fine.
- No, it's not. It is not.
She could've died back there.
She almost did.
Well, she's safe now.
She's on her way to Murray's.
That thing won't find her,
not before we kill it.
Hey. This isn't the way
this is supposed to work, all right?
You're supposed to say,
"Yes, I told you so.
That's why we needed to go back
to the kids."
Oh, yeah, and then
you say something like...
"Yeah, well, it's really hard to listen
when you make everything sound
like it's the end of the goddamn world."
You know...
I think, despite everything,
I mean, despite the arguing,
I think we make a pretty good team.
Well, we made it this far, didn't we?
Yeah.
We did.
So, uh...
did I get the job or what?
Ah, come on.
Detective Byers.
It has a ring, doesn't it?
It's kinda hard to serve in a town
where you don't live, Detective.
You're still moving outta here.
I mean, that is the plan, right?
Eh, we'll see how it goes.
"How it goes"? How what goes?
You know, if... if we actually do
make it out of here,
we... we deserve to celebrate, right?
Yeah.
I mean...
yes.
Absolutely.
I hear Enzo's is pretty good.
What do you say, Friday, eight o'clock?
Uh, El likes to watch Miami Vice
on Fridays.
It... It starts at 10:00,
so I... I can't be out late on a Friday.
Okay, well, how about 7:00, then?
7:00?
Enzo's, Friday, I meet you there?
No, you pick me up.
Picking you up, 7:00 p.m. Friday.
Yeah, it's a date.
Just for clarification, just because I...
I mean, just... If...
When you say "date,"
just so that we're crystal clear,
- so there's no confusion... Yeah?
- Yeah, Hop?
Stop talking or I'm gonna change my mind.
Yeah, okay. Yeah.
Okay.
Scoops Troop, this is...
Hm.
Bald Eagle.
I've reached another junction.
- This is what?
- The fourth junction.
All right, so if memory serves, this is
right after the My Little Pony thesis.
- We went left, so he has to go right.
- Right.
Fly right, Bald Eagle.
- Fly right.
- Roger that, flying right.
Little shit.
What's the My Little Pony thesis?
Don't get him started.
- Get him started? Just tell me...
- Hey, guys?
Griswold Family, this is Scoops Troop!
Do you copy? Over!
Griswold Family, I repeat,
this is Scoops Troop. Do you...
Griswold Family, do you copy?
Do you copy?!
Griswold Family,
this is Scoops Troop.
Please confirm your safety!
Griswold Family, this is Scoops Troop!
Are you en route to Bald Eagle's nest?
Please confirm your safety!
Someone, please just answer.
Is anyone there?
Just answer!
Anyone, please...
Griswold Family, do you copy?
Do you copy?!
- Where are you going?!
- To get them the hell outta there!
Stay here, contact the others!
- Shit.
- Wait, Robin!
Stay in touch.
Got it.
Bald Eagle, this is Scoops Troop.
What's your 20?
I told you, radio silence!
Yeah, but we have a problem.
What kind of problem?
It's turned away.
If we go up the stairs now, we'll make it.
- No way, not with El's leg.
- We have to try.
There's another way...
to get out.
Through the Gap.
Okay.
Now.
Bald Eagle has landed.
Repeat.
Bald Eagle
has landed.
Okay.
Come on, how much longer?
I don't know, I've never done this before!
Okay.
Okay, okay!
Get ready, lovebirds,
you're almost up to bat.
Oh, shit.
- What are you doing?
- Don't worry.
Go! Go, go, go, go, go, go!
Let's go.
Did Mikhail send for you?
- All right.
- Okay.
- Give me the code.
Six-six-two,
six-oh-eight,
oh-oh-four.
Uh...
again?
Six-six-two,
six-oh-eight,
oh-oh-four.
Murray?
Your goddamn code...
is wrong.
What? Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Well, I... I suppose it could be wrong.
How could it be wrong?
The code is a number,
a famous number.
Planck's constant
I... I thought I knew it.
Planck's constant.
- You know it?
- Not by heart. You?
I'm not a nerd, nerd.
He told me it was
Planck's constant, which I know.
Why would I need him to give me a number
I already know?
What are you doing?
Go, go, go!
- Shit.
- Get the car started. Go!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Come on.
- Come on.
- We gotta go!
Come on!
We gotta go!
Are you okay?
Ask me tomorrow?
Oh, shit!
Get in!
- Go, go, go, go!
- Go, go, go!
Suzie, do you copy?
This is Suzie. I copy.
- Suzie!
- Dusty-bun?
"Dusty-bun"?
Where have you been?
I'm so, so sorry.
I... I've been really busy...
uh, trying to save the world
from Russians and monsters.
Of course you have.
Get the goddamn number already!
Who was that?
It was...
Uh, I don't know, actually.
I think it was just some interference.
So, why don't we, uh, change frequency
to 14.158?
Copy that, shifting frequency. Standby.
- Dusty-bun, you copy?
- I copy, Suzie-poo.
It sounds much better now, thanks.
- Suzie.
- Okay, so, listen,
do you know Planck's constant?
Do you know the Earth orbits the sun?
Okay, so I know it starts
with two sixes, and then a...
W-What is it?
Okay, let me just be clear on this.
I haven't heard from you in a week,
and now you want a mathematical equation
that you should know
so you can... save the world?
Suzie-poo, I promise,
I will make it up to you
as soon as possible.
You can make it up to me now.
- What?
- I want to hear it.
- Not right now.
- Yes, now, Dusty-bun.
Suzie-poo, this is urgent.
Yes, yes, you're saving the world,
I heard you the first time,
but Ged is also saving Earthsea
and he's about to confront the shadow,
so this is Suzie, signing off.
Wait, wait, wait! Okay.
Okay. Okay.
Shit.
♪ Turn around ♪
♪ Look at what you see ♪
♪ In her face ♪
♪ The mirror of your dreams ♪
♪ Make believe I'm everywhere ♪
♪ Given in the light ♪
♪ Written on the pages is ♪
♪ The answer to ♪
♪ A never-ending story ♪
♪ Reach the stars ♪
♪ Fly a fantasy ♪
♪ Dream a dream ♪
♪ And what you see will be ♪
♪ Rhymes that keep their secrets will ♪
♪ Unfold behind the clouds ♪
♪ And there upon a rainbow is ♪
♪ The answer to a never-ending story ♪
♪ Story ♪
Planck's constant is 6.62607004.
You just saved the world.
Gosh, I miss you, Dusty-bun.
And I miss you more, Suzie-poo.
I miss you more,
multiplied by all the stars in our galaxy.
No, I miss you...
Enough.
- Shit!
- Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
It's turning around.
- What?
- It's turning around!
Maybe we wore it out.
I don't think so. Hold on.
Hey! Everybody out.
Everybody out!
Hey.
You ready to end this?
In here. In here.
Okay. Come on, come on, come on...
Billy.
Billy, you don't have to do this.
Billy. Your name's Billy, Billy Hargrove.
You live on 4819 Cherry Lane.
Billy, please, I'm Max, I'm your...
Murray, you all set down there?
All set, but I've got some company
which I'd love you to obliterate.
Will do. Hang tight.
On three.
One...
Two...
The Americans,
I've found them...
Don't be afraid.
It'll be over soon.
Just try and stay... very still.
Flay this, you ugly piece of shit!
Hey, asshole! Over here!
- We're almost out!
- I know!
Dustin! We're out of time!
Hurry! Close it now!
Close it!
Come on!
Mike...
Mike.
Mike. Mike. Mike, get up.
Mike, can you hear me? Mike! Mike!
Hey, come on.
You okay?
Where's El?
- Leave me alone!
- Stop it!
- Mom!
- This is your new sister.
...at least seven feet.
Seven... feet.
You told her...
the wave was seven feet.
Woo!
Yeah!
You ran to her, on the beach.
There were seagulls.
She wore a hat...
With a blue ribbon.
A long dress...
with a blue and red flower.
Yell... Yellow sandals,
covered in sand.
She was pretty.
She was really pretty.
And you...
you were happy.
I'll see you in hell!
Hit me.
We're out!
Damn it!
No!
Close it now!
Close it!
Billy!
- El.
- Mike!
Billy?
Billy.
Billy, Billy, get up, please.
Billy, get up, please, please.
- I'm sorry.
- Billy...
Billy. Billy.
Billy, wake up. Billy, get up.
Please, Billy...
Billy!
Billy...
I'm sorry.
It's okay. It's okay.
Hop.
Jim. Where's Jim?
Let's go! Go! Come on!
You all right?
Hands up!
Don't shoot! American!
We're Americans! Americans!
Hey, come on, let's go!
Go, go!
Thank God!
Welcome to Hawkins, Indiana,
a wonderful place to grow up,
to raise your family,
to walk your dog.
But then...
On July Fourth,
everything changed.
A terrible tragedy struck
this small town.
But this was not this small town's
first brush with tragedy.
Mysterious deaths, government cover-ups,
a bizarre chemical leak.
Is it all linked?
All a vast conspiracy?
The fault of a disgraced,
corrupt mayor?
Or is something more going on
in the heartland?
Can a town itself be cursed?
Some believe a rise in Satanism
is to blame.
To find out,
tune in tonight at 8:00 p.m.
for "Horror in the Heartland"
on Cutting Edge.
You put your mom down as a reference?
Yeah. Why not?
She's, like, super well-respected.
You're such a dingus.
Wha...
Uh, just to be clear,
we weren't fired, you know.
The mall burned down and, like,
killed a bunch of people.
Thanks for sharing.
Didn't know.
Three favorite movies. Go.
Uh... The Apartment,
Hidden Fortress, Children of Paradise.
You, go.
- Favorite movies?
- Did I stutter?
Uh... Animal House, for sure.
Um...
Eyes on me, Harrington.
Yeah. Uh...
Star Wars.
A New Hope?
A new what-now?
Which Star Wars?
The one with the teddy bears. Duh.
No? Uh... Oh, the one that just came out.
The movie that just came out.
The one with the DeLorean
and Alex P. Keaton,
and he's trying to bang his mom.
The time...
Yeah, those are my top three. Classics.
You start Monday.
You start never.
Will you just, um...
Will you give us a minute?
Why?
Steve.
All right, you have to understand, Keith,
I know his taste is a bit pedestrian,
but the dingus has other qualities.
He's a douchebag of the highest order,
Robin.
He was a bit of a prick to us
in high school, I'll grant you that,
but he remains...
a total chick magnet.
Yeah, okay,
and this is relevant to me how?
Uh, Earth to Keith.
The ladies will come in just to see him.
They'll come in in droves.
Droves, Keith.
We sold so much ice cream,
they had to get a second shipment in
from Michigan.
Goddamn Michigan, Keith.
And these ladies...
These ladies are hot.
They're so very hot.
And there are too many of them
for little Steve.
He needs assistance.
He needs your assistance, Keith.
What's in it for you?
You got a thing for him or something?
Goddammit. This is...
Hm.
We're just, um...
We're just friends.
Oh!
Fast Times. Fast Times. Ever heard of it?
Top three for me, Keith.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa! Slow down.
- Sorry. Sorry.
- Still got it?
- Yeah, yeah.
♪ Turn around ♪
♪ Look at what you see ♪
♪ In her face ♪
♪ The mirror of your dreams ♪
♪ Rhymes that keep their secrets ♪
♪ Will unfold behind the clouds ♪
Wait, did we get that verse right?
It's "unfold behind the clouds"?
Yeah, but you're butchering it,
so could you please stop?
So then join in, Dusty-bun.
Yeah, come on, Dusty-bun,
why don't you join us?
You guys are so funny,
you should be on Carson.
- Can't we just hear your rendition?
- No.
Please? Just one verse?
No. No way. It's reserved for Suzie's ears
and Suzie's ears alone.
♪ Turn around ♪
♪ Look at what you see ♪
♪ In their face ♪
♪ The mirror of your dreams ♪
Shut up, you guys.
♪ Rhymes that keep their secrets ♪
Stop! You guys, please, shut up.
Whoa, dude. That's the donation box.
I know.
I'll just use yours when I come back.
I mean, if we still wanna play.
Yeah, but what if you want to join
another party?
Not possible.
Is that...
everything?
I guess so.
Seventeen years of my life...
packed up in one day.
What if I just...
don't let you go?
I think...
the new owners might kick us out.
You could stay in our basement.
Your dad'd love that.
We could hide you in a tent,
like El.
Hey.
It's gonna be okay.
As a wise man once said...
we've got shared trauma.
So what's a little more, right?
What's a little more?
They'll come back.
I know they will.
Thanks.
- You packed your walkie, right?
- Yes.
Because you know that I'm gonna
steal Cerebro from Dustin
and call you so much,
you're gonna have to turn it off, right?
Did you talk to your mom?
About Thanksgiving?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I got the okay. I'll be there.
And then I was thinking maybe
you could come up here for Christmas.
And Will, too.
You can come before or after Christmas,
or whatever Mrs. Byers wants,
but I was thinking Christmas Day
could be super fun,
because we'd all have cool new presents
to play with and, uh...
Sorry, that made me sound like
a seven-year-old.
I like presents, too.
Yeah, cool. Yeah.
I like... I like presents, too.
Cool.
Mike?
Yeah?
Remember that day...
at the cabin, you were talking to Max?
Um...
I don't think I follow.
You talked about your... your feelings,
your heart.
Oh.
Oh, yeah, that.
Man, that was so long ago. Um...
That was really heat of the moment stuff,
and we were arguing and...
I don't really remember...
What did I say, exactly?
Mike...
I love you, too.
Donation box?
Uh, yeah, sure.
What is that?
Uh...
It... It's the speech Hop wrote
for you and Mike.
Speech?
Yeah. You know, the heart-to-heart.
He never talked to you, did he?
Can I read?
"There's something I've been
wanting to talk to you both about.
I know this is a difficult conversation,
but I care about you both very much.
And I know that you care about each other
very much.
And that's why it's important that
we set these boundaries moving forward,
so we can build an environment...
where we all feel...
comfortable...
trusted...
and open...
"to sharing our feelings."
Feelings.
Jesus.
The truth is,
for so long,
I'd forgotten what those even were.
I've been stuck in one place,
in a cave, you might say.
A deep, dark cave.
And then,
I left some Eggos out in the woods,
and you came into my life and...
for the first time in a long time,
I started to feel things again.
I started to feel happy.
But, lately, I guess I've been feeling...
distant from you.
Like you're...
you're pulling away from me or something.
I miss playing board games every night,
making triple-decker Eggo extravaganzas
at sunrise,
watching westerns together
before we doze off.
But I know you're getting older.
Growing.
Changing.
And I guess...
if I'm being really honest,
that's what scares me.
I don't want things to change.
So, I think maybe that's why
I came in here,
to try to maybe... stop that change.
To turn back the clock.
To make things go back
to how they were.
But I know that's naive.
It's just...
not how life works.
It's moving.
Always moving, whether you like it or not.
And, yeah, sometimes it's painful.
Sometimes it's sad.
And sometimes...
it's surprising.
Happy.
So, you know what?
Keep on growing up, kid.
Don't let me stop you.
Make mistakes, learn from 'em,
and when life hurts you,
because it will,
remember the hurt.
The hurt is good.
It means you're out of that cave.
But, please,
if you don't mind,
for the sake of your poor old dad,
keep the door open three inches.
♪ I ♪
♪ I will be king... ♪
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Time to go?
I'll be out in a minute.
Okay.
♪ Oh, we could be heroes ♪
♪ Just for one day ♪
♪ Oh, we can be us ♪
♪ I ♪
♪ I can remember ♪
♪ Standing ♪
♪ Standing by the wall ♪
♪ And the guns ♪
♪ Shot above our heads ♪
♪ Oh, we can be heroes ♪
♪ Just for one day ♪
No. Not the American.
No, I'm begging you...
No! Don't!
No! Please! No! Don't!
No, don't!
Don't do this!
Let me go!
Don't leave me in here.
Let me out,
I'm innocent.
I'm innocent!
I'm begging you, please!