Morning, Stosh.
- Morning.
Chase Research.
- Have
you seen Paul?
- No,
I haven't seen him.
- You with the railroad?
- No, I'm Maindrian Pace,
I'm with Chase Research,
I'm here to investigate
the accident
for the insurance company.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
- Morning, Paul,
what a way to start a day.
- Yeah, morning, Pace.
- Well, I
always get the biggies.
- What
do you got so far?
- Well, not
much, no skid marks.
I'm thinking maybe a
possible brake failure.
- How's the driver?
- Well, he died
en route to the hospital.
Looks like we're gonna
lose the brakeman, too.
- What's
your liability?
- The whole package.
Hope you can find something
mechanically wrong
with that truck.
- You know
me, Paul, if it's there
I'll find it.
- Do your best.
- Stosh, just
get it back to the shop.
Taylor Webb may be buying
another car to switch over.
It's about time you
learned the business.
I'll stay here and make
sure I get all the pieces.
I'll see you later.
- All Auto,
five 15.
B20.
96 oh seven.
Number 19.
Warrens.
268-99.
Number 22.
Taylor Webb Used cars.
- Yeah.
- 333 dollars.
- 1973
Challenger, number 22.
- Hey, Atlee,
how come you never get called
at five o'clock in the morning?
- 'Cause I live right.
- Well, I'll
fix your living habit.
Tomorrow morning you
can get up at five
and start tearing
down that truck
to find out how come
he hit the train.
- Okay, if
Stanley helps me.
I think two years in the
Army gave him brain damage.
- Hey, hey, I'll
learn the business next week.
I don't even know how
these switch-overs work.
- Well Stanley,
it goes like this.
Taylor Webb buys a wrecked car.
We cut it up, and save
the serial numbers,
the engine and trans,
and junk the rest.
Then we go out and
steal one identical,
and put these serial
number from the wrecked car
on the new one.
- Well
don't the police
and the insurance
companies check these guys?
- Oh, the odds
about 5,000 to one.
Do you know how many cars are
in Los Angeles County alone?
Over two million.
- Hey, Stanley,
what's your new
girlfriend's name?
- Jill, why?
- Gonna
name this car after her,
'cause she's a wreck, too.
- Hey, Maindrian, I
need your trunk-locking key.
- Hey,
Stanley, got the mileage?
- Yeah, it's
uh, 6891, five tenths.
- Hey, Atlee,
what kind of tires are those?
- They're
Goodyear E7814.
- Two-stripe
or one-stripe?
- They're two-stripe.
- I'm
going back in the Army.
- I think
that's a good idea.
Take Corlis with,
he's in a bad mood.
- Ah,
cram it, you guys.
- Ah, that's 'cause
his sweetie is in New York.
- Corlis, Why
don't you give me a hand,
get those doors over there.
- Do I have to do
everything while I'm here?
- Why you have to--
- Hey, I'm hungry.
- Come on, let's go.
- Come on.
- Want this
motor over there now?
- Yeah, let's go Atlee,
Atlee, get the truck in here
get this back body section
of these doors loaded.
Now all we gotta do
is go steal her twin.
- Please
lock your car.
Do not leave
articles on the seat.
Do not leave parking
ticket in your car.
Please lock your car.
Do not leave
articles on the seat.
Do not leave parking
ticket in your car.
Please lock your car.
Do not leave
articles on the seat.
Do not leave parking
ticket in your car.
Please lock your car.
Do not leave
articles on the seat.
Do not leave parking
ticket in your car.
- Hey Atlee,
how'd you get mixed
up with Pace, anyway?
- Well, I'll
tell you Stanley,
I used to steal trucks,
and one day this dude comes in,
he say he's Maindrian Pace
for some insurance company,
and he's here to investigate
a truck I bought.
Well, he walks around the
truck, opens his briefcase,
and right away I see
these pictures of my truck
all wrecked up and stuff.
Then he said, "Mr.
Jackson, do you realize
"you can to jail for stealing,
like you can for lying?"
Right then I knew he had
me, but he made me an offer.
And here I is, me, Investigator
Jackson, stealing cars,
I still haven't been caught.
- Atlee, when
you came to work for me,
you became a pro.
The amateurs are in jail,
professionals never get caught.
- What
about Bush Doctor?
He was a pro, over 400
cars and they nailed him.
- Well, he got sloppy.
- You don't get
sloppy in this business.
- Jill just
became a statistic.
One of the 32 percent
of the cars stolen
never to be recovered again.
Holy Christ, I gotta be
in Vilas' in 20 minutes.
- Hey, you
want me to come with you?
- No, they
said to come alone.
And for 400,000 dollars,
I'm going alone.
See you guys later, get
this place cleaned up.
- Mr. Pace,
you came highly recommended
from our associates
in Argentina.
- Thank
you, Mr. Vilas.
- Like you asked,
200,000 dollars up front.
This is a lot of money.
Those cars must be at the docks
for transfer delivery
Saturday, no later than five.
They must be there.
Now, I don't need to
tell you the consequences
if you fail to perform.
- Don't
worry, Mr. Vilas.
- I
don't worry, that's your job.
Saturday, by five.
- Here's a list
and the code names of the
cars we're gonna need.
What was that black
football player
that played for the
Green Bay Packers?
Remember, we handled
loss on his trucks
at the distributing company?
- Oh, yeah, you
mean Willie Davis.
- Yeah, that's him, Davis.
Yeah, he drives
a burgundy Rolls.
Here's his address.
Now I want you to have as
much of this information ready
as you can by the time
we get back on Sunday.
Now, here's how we'll handle it.
What are the uh, the
first two are Stutzes.
Let's see, I code named
'em Donna and Karen.
- Yeah.
- But, you'll have to redo
this so we can read it.
- Yeah.
- But just go down the line
here and code name 'em.
I want all of 'em listed
this way, all the way down.
- Okay, I'll put
'em in order, yeah.
- Get the rest of this
junk cleaned off here.
- Yeah.
- Also, uh, lemme
see what was it,
oh, I want you to get both
undercover cars serviced
and ready to go.
- Okay.
- Okay?
And you'll pick us
up at the airport
or take us to the
airport at 8:30.
- Here they come!
- Hello, this is
the long-distance operator.
Is this the Kosciuszko
Club in Dunkirk, New York?
- Yes, it is.
- I have a
collect person-to-person call
for a Mandrian Pace
from an Atlee Jackson
of Chase Research
in Los Angeles.
Will you accept the charges?
- Uh, hold
on a moment, operator,
I think he's with
the wedding party.
I'll have to find him.
- All
right, I'll hold.
- This
is Maindrian Pace.
- Will you
accept a collect call
from an Atlee Jackson?
- Yes,
I will, operator.
Atlee, how come you're
calling collect?
You in jail or something?
- No, but I
think we all gonna be.
I been going over this list,
And I think you lost your mind.
Do you realize there are
48 cars on this list,
and nine are Rolls
Royce, seven limousines.
They even want Parnelli
Jones' Big Oly Bronco.
Four Ferraris--
- Atlee, Atlee,
what are you trying to say?
- There's
no way we can steal
and switch over this
many cars by Friday.
- We don't
have to switch 'em,
just clean 'em up, take
off the license plates
and deliver them to the docks.
- We're still
gonna need some more help.
- Just getting
ready to tell Eugenius
to hold off his
honeymoon for a week.
- You gonna tell a boss
to wait a week
for his honeymoon?
Good luck.
- Listen, Atlee.
You just get to work on
those insurance files.
I can think of at least
25 cars in those files
right off-hand.
And don't worry about Eugene.
You just be at the
airport to pick us up.
- Okay, why you
wanna talk to me?
- We got a little problem.
We have to deliver over 40
cars to the docks by Saturday.
- What do
you want me to do?
- I want you to
postpone your honeymoon.
- Hey, I'd like to help
you out, it's my wedding!
- You don't seem to understand.
We gotta deliver over 40 cars
to the docks by Saturday.
We've got all our regular work,
plus we got three court
appearances this week.
- That's a sad story.
Why don'tcha call
me up in three weeks
when I get back
from my honeymoon?
- I want you to listen.
- You goddamn--
- Hey, hey.
- Please, Maindrian, not here.
- You might've inherited
most of the shares
when your old man died,
but your brother and sister
have held up your end,
plus theirs, ever since.
Now it's about
time you shape up.
Because the three of
us can vote you out.
Pumpkin, I want him on
that plane tomorrow,
or he's out.
- Maindrian,
I worry about you
and Eugene, you're
always fighting.
- Do me a favor,
let's not talk about him.
Just make sure he's on
that plane tomorrow, okay?
- Hey, I
saw the nicest house,
can we go look at
it when we get back?
- Oh boy.
- Come on,
you know I love you.
Besides that, it was
always Papa's dream
that we get married someday.
- I know.
- I'm
a good cook, too.
- You
just want me to be fat
like all the other Polacks.
- Yeah, then no
one will look at you.
- Hey, we
got a contract to fill.
- How about
after the contract?
- We'll talk
about it then, okay?
- Promise?
- I promise.
- Look
at the house, too?
- Well,
we'll talk about it.
- Okay.
- Mr. Eugene Chase.
- Yeah, right here.
- Hello, Mr. Chase.
- Atlee, Atlee!
Old blue eyes is back.
Hey, you been workin' hard?
- Hi,
Atlee, how ya doin'?
- Just can't trust
nobody, Atlee.
- Hey, thanks for coming by
but actually I'm going.
We got lots of work to do.
- You do?
- Yeah.
Hey, I want you
to go with Jenny.
- Okay.
Bye bye!
- Bye!
- Go with Jenny and help
her get settled down.
- Okay, fine.
- You get everything ready?
- Hold everything,
hold everything.
There's Eleanor.
Get the briefcase.
- Let me do it,
my knack is back.
I can feel it in my bones,
just let me handle it.
- You'll handle it.
Okay.
- Left the key in the car.
- Really?
Stosh?
Okay, Stosh, let's go.
- Thank you.
May the Lord be with you, child.
- What in the world?
- Sorry, lady, I
thought it was my car.
Wrong car!
Pretty damn funny.
You said I'd be picking my
ass up off the sidewalk.
- Don't
worry, Corlis,
I got Eleanor's license number.
Come on, Atlee, let's take
a ride around the airport.
Gotta go to work now.
- Lucky.
- All right, pay up.
- Bet you
can't do it again.
- Double or nothing?
- You're on.
- Game's
over, let's go.
- Easy money.
- I don't wanna sound
like a drill sergeant,
but this is the biggest
contract we've ever handled.
I don't want any mistakes,
so pay attention.
- Doesn't he look good
with his gray hair?
- Ah, he looks like a Polack.
- At least my mother
didn't name me Atlee.
Atlee, you've been with
us for three years,
and you're about
as good as I am.
There's Corlis's wig, we're
gonna do this different.
You're gonna be
working with Corlis.
Stosh, you're coming
off shop detail,
and you're gonna
learn all about it.
Here's a list of the code names.
I want you to look at
'em, study 'em carefully,
and get to know 'em.
That's the only way you're
gonna refer to these cars
from the day on.
Pumpkin, I want you to
get on this list of cars,
check 'em all out, see if the
addresses are all current.
And I want you
using only the phone
that Atlee here has got
tied in to the switchboard
next door.
- Now, Maindrian, remember
we're only going after
cars that are insured.
- Right, if you guys
have any questions
just have Pumpkin
run a 10-28 on them.
If there's a legal indicated,
that means they're
usually insured.
I know it's been a long day
but we got some
easy hits tonight.
I've got the DMV info on Eleanor
and she lives over in Torrance.
- I found the Italia.
I remember seeing this
picture of Lyle Waggoner
in Playgirl magazine.
- You got any more?
- Yeah, we can get Parnelli
Jones' Big Oly Bronco,
it'd be on display
at the racing today.
- Good, you
and Corlis handle it.
- Okay.
- Now one more thing, you guys.
All the personal effects
go into duffel bags
that go to the shredder.
We don't wanna keep any
cameras, typewriters,
all that stuff can be traced.
Now there are some new
additions to the briefcases.
Make sure the walkie-talkies
are always on.
Same for the police
radios in your cars.
That'll keep you on top
of things and outta jail.
Now this is our new
compact key cutter.
Take a look at that, Atlee.
- Oh, yeah, I'll
brief Corlis on this.
- Pumpkin, I want you to get
as many of the code numbers
for the keys as you can.
That'll keep us
from popping locks,
especially the foreign cars.
Any questions?
- Nope.
Good. Let's go to work.
Okay, Atlee, go by and
pick up Corlis, huh?
- Yeah, I'll go get him.
- Okay, meet here.
- Yeah.
- Atlee,
don't take any chances,
check on all your equipment.
- I'm not a Polack.
- Let's go, Stosh.
Damn, tired of this.
Make sure you always have
your walkie-talkie on,
and there's your, your squelch.
- Okay?
-  - Okay.
Okay, let's go.
- Annual Grand
Prix, 23rd running of this
national championship
event for the
United States Auto
Club division.
Tonight we will be pitting
some of the fine driving talent
of the United States
Auto Club organization
against some of our very fine
local Southern
California drivers.
We have a fine
variety of automobiles
in attendance here tonight.
We have Sesco Chevys,
Offenhausers, and
Mighty Mite Vws.
Moving down to trackside
for this evening's
trophy presentation
to our featured winner,
a gentleman whose name is
synonymous in automobile racing
here in the Southern
California area,
championship car owner
of the Indianapolis 500
for the past 26 years, your
host here at Ascot Park,
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. J.C. Agajanian.
- - Harold?
Harold!
- What?
- The dog's in the house again.
- That's all right, he--
- Will you get the dog
out of the house, Harold?
Your dog!
Take him out.
- Take him, take
him out, nag woman.
- He brought mud in last night.
I'm sick of the dog
in the house, Harold.
- Ah, you're crazy.
You're absolutely nuts.
- Tomorrow morning
this thing's gonna be--
- Stay out there with him.
I'm sick of your dog, Harold.
- Ah, crazy women, they're
all nuts, every one.
- Don't slam the door!
- Come on, walk.
Walk.
Hey, hey, hey!
Fella, that's my car!
That's my car!
Son of a bitch!
Steal my car, I'll show ya!
- Hey, you kids,
get the cars outta the street!
- Drive
around the block.
- Yeah,
go up the sidewalk.
- You're
stealing my car!
- Hey, Smith,
too bad he didn't just
steal your old lady
and your stupid dog!
- WJ 90,
I'm in pursuit of a
blue Plymouth two-door
southbound Crenshaw, from 186.
License unknown,
one male occupant.
- 10-four,
all units stand by.
WJ-90 in pursuit of a
blue Plymouth two-door
southbound Crenshaw, from 186.
One male occupant,
license unknown.
- Really
bowled a terrific game.
I hope she gets in our league,
I think that she is really good.
- Oh, I know it.
- Look out!
- WJ-90, suspect
vehicle involved in TA
at Crenshaw and 210th Street.
Suspect's still southbound
on Crenshaw towards the bowl.
- 10-4
all units in the area
to Crenshaw and
two-one-O Street,
a blue Plymouth is southbound,
with a TA at that location.
- WJ-seven, we
have spotted suspect vehicle.
At the bath ramp.
He just turned
south on Van Ness.
- Not me!
They've got my car!
No, no, no, hey, fellas,
I didn't do anything.
The guy took my goddamn car.
- Why don't
you break his arm?
- No, you're
making a mistake.
Oh, guys, they have
my car, running down
Look for my car, yellow
Mustang down there.
- WJ-seven,
request assistance.
To Vanness, possible major 4-15.
Suspect in custody.
- WJ-seven
requests backup
to possible major
4-15 at Midtown.
- WJ-seven,
our ETA three seconds.
- WK-nine,
give town report.
- This is the fella who
was driving the other car.
- Well,
they made it all right,
got out of it pretty good.
See what's you caused now?
- He says his car was stolen
and he was chasing it,
we'll go back and check it out.
- Yeah,
that sounds good.
- Okay.
- I'll take
care of everything here.
- Mr. Smith,
is that your yellow Mustang
with the black trim?
- What the
hell's my car doing here?
Honest, fellas, that
guy, he was in it,
he took it and he
went out that way.
The big, a guy dressed
in black, honest.
I mean I, what the
hell was I doing out,
driving around in my pajamas,
I was out walking my dog.
- AK-seven, taking
19-50 to Harbor Division,
231 on 2A booking.
- Copy,
AK-seven, 10-4.
- Why don't you knock?
Damn.
- I closed the
door, what do you want?
- Where were
you raised, in a barn?
- What do you want?
- What's this I hear about
you giving a car back?
- You called me
in here for that?
- Yeah, Mr. Bigshot.
- That's why.
- So what?
- I didn't connect the two
until I found that card
on the sun visor.
"H.D. Smith" is none other
than Harold Dwight Smith.
Senior Claims Supervisor
and head idiot
for the Kenden
Insurance company.
- What difference
does that make?
- He's denied more claims
and screwed more
people than you have.
And I wanna see him get
his ass outta this one.
- J and I wanna
go on our honeymoon.
- The bulletin board says
you're supposed to be in court
in 20 minutes, or are
you on your period again?
- One of these days, Pace.
- Yes, yes, he passed away
this morning in Santa Barbara.
Of course we would
like very much
for you folks to take
care of things for us.
- All right, Mrs. Weatherton.
That's 3700 Artesia
Boulevard, apartment four,
that's upstairs in the rear.
- That's right.
- Fine, will there be more
than yourself coming in
for the arrangements?
- Yes, there are several
members in the family
and a limousine would be needed.
- There will.
Okay, fine, then we'll send our
limousine right out for you.
- All right, we appreciate it.
- Thank
you very much.
- Thank you.
That's right, it'll
be in the lobby
of the Laguna Riveria
building, 2206 Ocean Boulevard,
in Long Beach.
Yes, at 2 P.M. this afternoon.
There will be a party of six
going to the convention
center in Anaheim.
Hello, yes, I would
like a limousine
to pick up a party of five
at 1:30 this afternoon.
They'll be going to the airport
and the address they need to
be picked up is 8253 Artesia.
All right then,
thank you very much.
Hello, this is Haynes
and Purcell Realtors.
I would like a limousine
to pick up Mrs. Haynes
and her party at the
Tijuana Cafe in Gardena.
And would you please be there
at three o'clock prompt?
Thank you.
- This working
is ruining my sex life.
- Who would
have sex with you anyway?
- Nobody you
know, that's for su...
Will ya look at that?
- Hey, I
think I'm in love.
- I'm talking
about the car, Stanley.
10 to one she left
the keys in it.
You know, Stanley,
I'm gettin' tired
of stealing this Eleanor car.
- Yeah,
but just think,
some Venezuelan general's
son is just waiting for her.
- This
time I've got her.
She's about to go bye-bye.
- No, baby, I promise ya.
We'll be in London by
this time next week.
I love you too,
okay, bye-bye honey.
You blew it this time.
- What's wrong today, Eugene?
- We've been asked
to investigate Taylor Webb
Used Cars, that's what's wrong.
The adjustor that
handled that total loss
on that Challenger you did?
Well, he drove by his car lot,
and saw that darned
thing sitting out there
and recognized the
license number.
Now he wanna ask to find out
how come that basket case
that he bought five days
ago is back out on the road.
- Well, I'll tell
you what to do.
- What's that?
- Why don't you just
investigate Taylor Webb
in your usual manner,
and by the time you get around
to it, it'll be history.
- Maindrian, be serious.
- How can I, in this nuthouse?
Eugene, Pumpkin called
me earlier and told me
that Jill was sick.
I called Taylor Webb,
and he wholesaled it
to Prince Chrysler
Plymouth today.
Don't worry, I'll have the
fairy godmother take care of it.
- Maindrian.
- Don't anybody worry,
by morning it'll be gone.
- KV-L, four seven two.
- One nine four.
- KV-L, this is K9-five.
I'm at Prince Chrysler,
there's a tow truck
hooking up to a car,
I'm gonna check it out.
- One
nine four, 10-4.
- You son of a bitch!
- Chase Research?
- Hello,
Pumpkin, did you call me?
- Yeah, Maindrian, we have
a meeting this afternoon
at two o'clock
with Parnelli Jones
and the insurance company,
about his Big Oly Bronco
that was stolen yesterday.
- Oh, you mean Janet, yeah.
Yeah, I think I
better handle that.
- All right, it's all set then.
- Let's go, Stosh.
I gotta go investigate a theft.
Somebody stole Parnelli
Jones's Big Oly Bronco
and I think it was Atlee.
- I hope it was Atlee.
- Hey, Stosh,
lookit, three o'clock,
the dude with the goatee.
Another Eleanor.
- When
you don't need 'em,
they're all over the place.
- Yeah, she's
sure been a lot of trouble,
right, because she's the
last of the Mustangs.
- Sure
is a pretty color.
- Yeah, sure is.
She lives at the
International Towers,
we'll have to keep her in mind.
Never know when you might
need another Eleanor.
Hello.
- Hello, Pace,
you're right on time.
- You look a little tired.
- Oh I'm nervous and upset.
- What's the matter?
- Well it all
started Sunday night
when J.C. Agajanian's
Rolls Royce was stolen.
And yesterday four more
expensive cars we insured
were stolen.
If they're not recovered
within 30 days,
we stand to lose
150,000 dollars.
- You know I read about that,
J.C.'s car was at
Ascot, wasn't it?
- Yes, but here's the clincher.
Last night,
someone stole Parnelli
Jones's Big Oly Bronco
which we insure for
100,000 dollars.
And, if it's not recovered
within 15 days before the race,
we stand to lose a
quarter of a million.
- I'll bet the odds against
that are one in 10,000.
- One in 22,000.
- I'll bet underwriting
is just delighted.
- Gentlemen.
-  - Yes.
- Mr. Jones can see you now.
- Thank you.
- Parnelli, nice seeing you.
- Yeah, see you later Bob.
-  - See you again.
- Okay, bye Lisa.
- Much luck at Indy.
-  - Lisa.
- Mr. Jones, I'm Frank Acrino
from your insurance company
and I talked to you earlier.
This is Mr. Maindrian
Pace, with Chase Research.
- Pleasure.
I understand if anybody can
find my Bronco, you can.
- Thank you.
What can you tell
us about the theft?
- We definitely think it
was done by professionals.
The police just couldn't
find anything, and--
- Are you sure it was stolen,
I mean, not just misplaced
or left in one of the
trucks or something?
- Well, I'm sure that
it wasn't misplaced.
- Is this a
picture of it here on the wall?
- Yes, as a matter of fact
that was taken last year
down in Mexico.
- Can we see the area where
the Bronco was stolen?
- Sure, right this way.
- Well, they
definitely couldn't drive it
or put it on the street
or anything like that.
- Well it is
one of a kind, and uh,
I'd really like to have it back.
- Well, we'll
do everything we can
to get it back
for you, Parnelli.
Tell me, Frank, does your
company have an insurance policy
on these too?
- Yes x
to the tune of 8
million dollars.
- Oh, it
isn't that bad, Frank,
it's all your imagination.
You shouldn't let little
things like that bother you.
- Right here's where
the Bronco was stolen from.
- Well it's
definitely not there now.
- Excuse me, Parnelli, but
Jim Cook is on the line.
- Okay, I'll just
take it down here.
- Okay.
- Excuse me, gentlemen, but
uh, just get my Bronco back.
- If we can't find it, Frank's
company will just have to
pay your 350,000 dollars.
- Well I'd rather
have my Bronco back.
- We'll do our best.
- I'll drop by the police
department, pick up the report,
and have it in your
office right away.
- Okay, Frank, I got work
to do, I'll see ya later.
- Bye.
- I'm here for
Lyle Waggoner's car.
- What, man?
- I'm here for
Lyle Waggoner's car.
- What?
Oh, wait a minute.
What'd you say?
- I'm here for
Lyle Waggoner's car.
- But the car's not ready, man.
- But I gotta go,
he's in a hurry.
- You're not Lyle
Waggoner, either.
- I know.
-  - He's a lot taller
than you are.
- I know, I'm just
here to pick his car up.
- Oh, I, well--
- I really gotta go.
He's in a hurry.
- The thing is, man, we
haven't had time to wax it.
- This is good enough.
- But that's a bummer,
you're taking it when
we're not finished the job.
- Yeah but
he's in a hurry.
- It's not even ready.
- I gotta
go, I gotta go.
- Hey, where's
Lyle Waggoner's car goin', man?
- Oh, man, it just
uh, you guys are...
- No, I just saw some
guy drive Lyle's car.
Now I'm here to pick it up,
now where the hell did it go?
- Hey, no, wait a minute,
he doesn't have a beard.
- No, I'm not Lyle
Waggoner, man.
I am here to pick his car
up, now where did it go?
- Uh, uh, you got a breath mint?
- Lemme ask you one question.
Got your insurance
policy paid up?
- You got any uppers?
- Okay,
stand by and cover.
- Good
afternoon, upstairs gallery.
- Hello,
this is Eileen Bates
with Studson Owner Cars, does
Mr. Simon still own his Studs?
I'm calling to see if he's
pleased with the performance
of the automobile.
- He certainly is,
he drives it to work every day.
- Very good,
that's what I like to hear.
Thank you very much.
- Glad to help.
- Bye bye.
-  - Goodbye.
- I still say we're lucky.
- Pumpkin sent a letter
to the insurance company,
telling them that Taylor
Webb was not in possession
of the car and we
couldn't locate--
- We only have
Taylor Webb's car--
- Just lay off of me, huh?
- Pace, he's
here, open the gate.
- I don't suppose you'd
open the damn door?
- No way.
- Here, hold this.
- What do you want me to
do with this darned thing?
- Shove it up your doo-bob!
- How do
I look in this one?
- Like a
Polack, where's your wig?
- It itches.
- I'll itch ya,
get this damned thing in
there and get it cleaned up.
- Atlee,
get the trunk.
- Oh, this
is loaded with junk,
better bring the uh
duffel bags over.
- Come on, let's
get this cleaned up today, huh?
Let's go.
- Here you are.
- Thanks.
Hey, look at the
junk in this car.
- Yeah.
- Work,
work, work, work.
Holy shit!
- Hey, let's see that.
Heroin.
- You're kidding.
- No shit.
- Lemme see that.
- Goddamn, we're
rich, we're really rich.
Look at all this.
- What the
hell is going on here?
- How much you
think this stuff is worth?
- Yeah, there must
be a million bucks' worth.
- Think
we could peddle it?
- Oh, you can
always get rid of it.
- Oh, damn.
- Atlee, where'd
you get this piece?
- I picked it up on Vermont
in front of a poker parlor.
- Well take it back.
- What do you
mean, take it back?
- You heard me, take it back.
- I'll
take care of that!
- Who is it?
- Police!
- Whole damn thing's loaded.
- In a second!
Oh, it's you, Hawkins.
- Working nights
now, eh, Vicinski?
- You know how it is.
-  - I know how it is.
Gentlemen!
- Hi, Hawkins.
- Hi Atlee.
- Hi, Sarge.
- Evening, Eugene.
- Hey, how you doing, Hawkins?
- Come on, you
guys, let's get to work.
What's up, Hawkins?
- The shit's really in the fan.
Leiutenant's really
on my ass this time.
Figures, you're too
hard on me, Pace.
- Hey boss.
- Atlee, just get to
work on the Pinto.
- What's this?
- Cadillac.
- What's wrong with it?
- Oh, it's uh, theft recovery.
- Mm, nice.
- Like that, uh?
What are you doing out
this late at night?
- I just finished
taking a report
down at Whittle Sea Motors.
Seems someone
ripped off a Manta.
- What's a Manta?
- It's the
35th expensive car stolen
in three days.
You heard about
that, didn't you?
- Listen, all I hear
is the insurance
company screaming at us
every time they
lose a lousy dime.
- Maindrian!
- Mm, comfort.
- Why
don't you back this up
so Eugene can get in
the office there, yeah.
- Yeah sure.
- Would ya?
- Yeah.
-  - Thanks.
All right!
- That's good.
- Mm, I've been
working too hard.
Look, do me a favor and keep
your ears open for me, will ya?
- Sure, Hawkins.
- You know something, Vicinski?
There's probably been
five more cars stolen
in just the time I've been here.
- Nah, I don't
think so, Hawkins.
Good night.
- Goddamn, are we lucky.
- Look, I say we peddle
the stuff right now!
- We'll talk about
it in the morning.
- No, we're gonna talk about--
- We'll talk about
it in the morning.
- Maindrian, we have
to give Eleanor back.
- What are you talking
about, the contract's filled.
- She's not insured,
here, look for yourself.
- You've gotta be kidding.
"Owner desperate, '73
Ford Mustang stolen
"from 18511 Mariposa in Gardena.
"Not insured.
"Please return. No questions."
Pumpkin, I'm tired.
I'm not Superman.
Look at that.
That contract is filled.
- Maindrian.
- Damn you, Pace!
Where's the El Dorado?
- It's gone, Eugene.
- What'd you do
with it, you son of bitch?
- I burned it.
- You burned a million
dollars worth of heroin?
- I'm gonna give Eleanor back,
but only because of one reason.
I know where there's another
at the International
Towers of Long Beach.
Get 'em cleaned up!
- Maindrian.
- We go out
and we do the impossible,
steal 48 cars, get 'em to the
warehouse with hours to spare,
and only Eleanor gives
us all the trouble.
- Do we really have
to put her back on the street?
- Yeah,
I promised Pumpkin.
Hell, if we're lucky
the one we saw yesterday
may still be at the
International Towers.
- Light your
cigar and calm down,
before you bite the end off.
- Let me
speak to Sergeant Hawkins.
- Hawkins.
- You wanna
catch that car-theft ring
that's been bothering you?
Well, put a stake-out at
the International Towers
in Long Beach.
- Who is this?
- That'll fix you, Mr. Bigshot.
- Man, I got to hit the head.
How long before our
shift relief get here?
- Man, in 15 more minutes
and we're all through.
One Baker 11.
10-28-29.
- Soon as I find out
if Eleanor is here
I'll give you a call
and you can take off.
Okay?
- Okay.
- It's California six three
five Charles King George.
- One Baker 11.
Six three five,
Charles King George.
No warrant, not in file.
- One Baker 11, 10-4.
Nothing on it.
What do you think,
think he's our dude?
- Ah, probably a
salesman, let's wait.
- There's
your salesman.
Sounds like he forgot
about his alarm system.
- Could be he didn't know
the car had one on it.
Pull around to the corner,
we'll run some film on it.
- One Baker 11, 10-28-29.
California, six one
four Henry Sam Ocean.
- Should've read my
horoscope this morning.
- One
Baker 11, 10-4.
Switch to
All units stand by, one
Baker 11 in pursuit,
a '73 Ford Mustang,
license number
six comma six one
four Henry Sam Ocean.
Westbound Ocean Boulevard,
against traffic.
- And it is currently 63
degrees in Long Beach.
Yeah, John, did
you give me a buzz?
- I
think that we have
a large police chase going on,
originating right in
front of our studios.
I see a couple people.
I'm trying to get
some interviews,
I'll be right back in a minute.
- Okay, John, I'll
be monitoring for it.
You keep me posted.
- Now, I just got a report
from one of our mobile units
a moment ago, a big police
chase started right here
at the KFOX studios.
You stay tuned to 1280,
Constant Country KFOX,
for that report.
- All units,
the pursuit has entered
Lincoln Park from Pacific side.
- Get your hands on the
windshield and don't move!
Up! Get 'em up
where I can see 'em!
- Everybody down!
- You
gotta get down, go!
- All units,
one Baker 11 has
the suspect stopped,
Cedar and Ocean, in the park.
- Get out, put your hands
up in the air, don't move!
- All units, the
pursuit has left Lincoln Park,
westbound Ocean Boulevard.
- About how many
cars were involved?
- 20, 30?
- And your husband went over
to see what was going on?
- Yes, he's helping a
lady out of the car now.
- Fine, Carol, if he
comes back, let me know,
we'll try to talk
to him, thank you.
Good afternoon, my
name is Jonathan Frick
with Constant Country KFOX.
- One Baker 11, in pursuit
following belligerent suspect,
vehicle '73 Mustang, westbound,
600 block Ocean Boulevard,
against traffic.
Male, white, 40 to 45,
six feet, 175 pounds,
gray hair, gray sports
coat, black trousers.
TA's have occurred.
- Air unit 31, your 10-20?
- Air 31,
over the Queen Mary,
we have approximately
12 minutes of fuel left.
We'll have to refuel shortly.
- Now, I told you a moment
ago that our mobile unit
had joined in to give us a
report about a police chase
that started right here
at the studios at KFOX.
Well I just got a
call a moment ago,
and Cal, in the Flying Fox,
has just now taxied for take-off
at the Long Beach airport.
And he'll be flying to
the scene of this chase,
and we'll be getting reports
from both Cal and John
in just a moment right here
on Constant Country KFOX.
Now listen to this.
- Did you hear that
accident a while ago?
- Yes, yes we did.
- We
hear crashes all the time.
- You hear crashes all
the time, how come?
We come here every day.
- I was just leaving
the real estate office
and this car came flying
up over that hill there
and slammed into a boat, just--
- It hit a boat?
- Yes.
- Units involved in pursuit,
LAPD units, responding
from harbor area.
- Well, honey,
what do you think of it?
- I like it, let's buy it.
I'll kinda miss the
old one, though.
- Attention, all units in
the San Pedro, Long Beach,
Torrance, and Carson
area, stand by to copy.
Long Beach PD is in pursuit
of a 1973 Ford Mustang,
yellow in color,
California license six
one four Henry Sam Ocean.
One occupant, male, Caucasian,
approximately age 45,
six feet, 185 pounds,
gray hair and mustache,
gray coat, black pants.
Uh, reason for pursuit unknown.
All units stand by.
Attention all units,
special attention Carson units,
Long Beach PD is in pursuit,
northbound Harbor Freeway
from the Benson Thomas Bridge.
The suspect's vehicle is a
1973 Mustang, yellow in color,
license number of six
one four Henry Sam Ocean.
The reason for pursuit unknown.
- Attention
all units standing by,
suspect has just exited
the Harbor Freeway.
- All
units in pursuit,
suspect now southbound
in the construction area.
- And is in
the construction area
south of Sepulveda.
Use caution,
civilians in the area.
Repeat, civilians in the area.
Assist code three.
- All
units in pursuit,
LA Sheriff's Department
is positioning units
parallel to the
freeway and monitoring.
- Air unit
31, your 10-20 and ETA,
Harbor Freeway and Sepulveda?
- Air 31, we're at the airport,
we'll be 15 to 20 minutes.
- Air Unit 31, 10-4.
- Man.
- Wanna
bag, man, here you go?
- Hey man, check that
bitch out, right there!
- Aw, look at that, aw, man!
Check her out over here, man.
Shit! Ooh-wee, goddamn!
- One Baker 11, one
Baker 11, come in.
- I'll get it out.
-  - Okay, let's go.
- Attention,
all units in pursuit,
helicopter unit seven is
now en route to the scene,
ETA in 20 minutes.
- Hold you fire, hold your fire.
You in the car, the
area is surrounded.
There is no way
you can move out.
- Sounds like it's finally over.
- Finally.
- We have
people all over the place.
I want you out of your car,
with your hands on
top of your head.
He's going again!
- All units, the
pursuit is going again.
- What the hell's going on?
- Shit, I don't know.
I'm gonna run that
son of a bitch down.
- Go on, push!
Get in, let's go.
- Man, this damn sure don't
help my hemmorhoid things.
- Well,
let's get him.
- One Baker 11,
what's your traffic?
- One Baker
11, Air Unit 31 ETA,
15 to 20 minutes.
One Baker 11, are you
still with the pursuit?
- Where in the hell's she
think we been, out to coffee?
Attention all units,
pursuit is not terminated,
repeat, not terminated,
and is now westbound
from the construction
area on Sepulveda.
Pursuit is now
northbound Harbor Freeway
from Sepulveda, all units
in the area, assist.
Code Three.
- All units, the
vehicle is now northbound
Harbor Freeway from Sepulveda,
approaching the city of Carson.
- Units
involved in the pursuit,
Highway Patrol
helicopter en route.
- Jesus Christ, he
just hit a damn post!
Turn around, turn around!
We got him now.
Attention all units,
suspect is TA with light pole
on Harbor Freeway northbound
and Carson Street off ramp.
Pursuit is terminated.
That is negative, pursuit
is not terminated,
repeat, not terminated.
- Suspect vehicle
has exited the freeway
and is now southbound Figueroa
from the Carson Street off-ramp.
- Attention all units,
Firestone 16 advising
he's northbound on Figueroa.
He has just spotted the Long
Beach PD pursuit vehicle
southbound Fig at 220.
As a result of that TC,
they need an ambulance
at Figueroa and 220.
- All
units in pursuit,
you are now in the
city of Carson.
- Lady, get outta the street!
- Attention all units,
14 advising the pursuit
is now northbound
on Figueroa from 223,
advise another TC has
occurred at that location.
14, 10-4 on the ambulance.
- Suspect is
now northbound, Figueroa
from 223 Street.
- Fire department radio
We need a rescue at
220 and Figueroa.
Pursuit, use caution
at these intersections:
Figueroa and Carson Boulevard,
Carson and Main Street,
Carson and Avalon,
Main and Victoria.
- An ambulance is
needed at 223 Figueroa.
- What it
is, man, all right.
- Hell yeah.
- Be cool, Billy, shoot,
you got the big highway's
following you now, you
always doing something man.
- Hey, B,
- Yeah, man.
- Hey, Billy, man,
you rollin' a joint man?
- Golly!
- Remember that party
we went to last night?
- Yeah, man.
- Got fine
bitches there man.
- Yeah, all right.
- Come on, get
the party on, man, golly.
- Hey,
man, I am loaded, man.
- Good afternoon,
I'm Darryl Forrest,
here with Mayor Sak Yamamoto
of the city of Carson
for the groundbreaking
ceremonies
of the new sheriff's station
being built here in Carson.
In February of 1968,
the city of Carson was
incorporated and since then
it has grown to be one of
the fastest-growing cities
in the Southern California area,
with a population of over 82,000
and an assessed valuation of
nearly 350 million dollars
and no property taxes.
Mayor, how does the city feel
about the new sheriff's station
being built here in Carson?
- We really all feel
that this is an asset
to the community and it'll
give us better service
to all the outlying
community, from Palos Verdes
all through in this
community, you see.
In fact, this will
be the headquarter
for all the sheriffs
and we feel it'll be a big
asset to the city, sir.
- Where did the funds
come from, to build this?
- Well it came from
uh, the city has--
- Excuse me, Mayor.
There's something going on here
and it's some kind of action.
Let's find out
from this officer,
exactly what's happening.
What's happening here, officer?
The officer is now calling in.
Officer, what's
happening right now?
- Units from another city
are in pursuit in our area.
I was advising the dispatcher
and they're aware of it.
- Yes, there's a pursuit.
Units have been advised.
As of right now, we don't
know exactly what's happening.
- I don't know what happened,
but I just came out of that
store and here comes this car
barreling down the
street, and I just,
I was so scared I ran
back in the store,
and I thought--
- He was going down the
street? And you ran--
- He was coming
down the sidewalk!
- The sidewalk?
-  - Yes.
- He was barreling
down the road, man,
it was unreal, man, he
almost ran the trees down
and killed about 500 people.
It was unreal, man.
Attention all units,
roadblock being set up
at Torrance Mazda Agency,
190 Street and
Hawthorn Boulevard.
Use caution.
- We are the police.
This is a police emergency.
Please, clear the area.
Men, we've only
got a few minutes.
Suspect just crossed Western
Avenue, so we have to hurry.
Get the cars in
the covered area,
and we're gonna set up a
roadblock in the street.
Now let's move.
Man, I think I hear 'em.
Get ready to move, shotgun.
- There's
our roadblock.
He's turnin' around!
Get on the other side,
no, the other side!
- Tell them in the
service department...
Tell them...
Attention all units,
suspect now inside
Moran Cadillac Agency
six three and
Hawthorn Boulevard.
The area is
surrounded, stand by.
- You're surrounded,
you can't escape.
- May I talk to Mr.
Wackeen, Bud Wackeen,
this is Moran Cadillac.
- Mr. Bud Wackeen,
white courtesy telephone.
Mr. Bud Wackeen, white
courtesy telephone.
- This is Wackeen.
- Mr. Wackeen.
I don't know how to
tell you this, but
this whole place is a mess.
I mean, the front
line got wiped out.
Um, the used car lot.
There were some police
chasing some, somebody,
I don't know what it was.
It all happened so fast.
- I'll be right there,
I'll be right there.
- Redondo Fire,
this is Global Rescue Two.
We're at the scene of
a four-car collision
with multiple injuries.
Respond to ladder
truck, Code Three.
We'll need the jaws of life.
Respond.
- All units,
suspect vehicle has left
Moran Cadillac Agency
westbound on 190 Street.
Redondo advises they
have a multiple TA
at Flagler and 190 Street.
Accident is unrelated,
repeat, unrelated,
to Long Beach pursuit.
The area is closed except
for emergency vehicles.
Suspect is headed
in that direction.
Use caution in that area.
Repeat, use caution
in that area.
- Must request tow
trucks and units to assisting
the Redondo rescue.
- Possible
fracture and internal bleeding.
concussion, will be en route.
ETA, 12 minutes.
- Hello, down there,
this is up here,
we've just left Long Beach
where the traffic
isn't moving too well.
It's all jammed up with
wrecked cars, tow trucks,
ambulances, and John
Frick, right John?
- And I ruined my
perfectly good umbrella!
- And you know we haven't
had so much excitement
here in Long Beach since the
arrival of the Queen Mary.
You just heard a
report a moment ago
from Cal in the Flying Fox.
You stay tuned to
the Hal McClean show
for continuing details.
Don't move.
- Sir, what happened
to your car?
- You know those
parking lot attendants.
- Sir, do you want a spray wax?
- No, just wash it.
- Hey, hey.
- Come on, Billy,
this thing's shocks'
going out, man?
- Something's
wrong with it.
- Oh, no, man.
- Is that the pigs?
- No, that ain't the pigs, man.
Satisfaction
- I hear ya 'cause dude
just opened his door
and everybody put in jail.
- Right on, man!
- Hey, y'all,
party tonight, man.
- I'm going
to the party tonight, man.
- Guess
who's giving a party,
you know what's-her-name,
that fine broad?
- Eleanor!
Eleanor giving a party.
- Hell, yeah.
- Excuse me, ma'am,
is this your car?
- Oh, yes it is.
Good, would you mind coming
back to the manager's office?
We have to re-wash it.
- Re-wash the car?
-  - Yes.
We have to re-wash it,
just come back to
the manager's office,
And I'll bring the car
back there for you.
It'll only take a minute.
- Oh, all right.
- Are you Mr. Hal McClane?
- That's me.
- Sergeant Hines, Long
Beach Police Department.
- What can I do for you?
- Officer Parks.
Are you the owner of
a 1973 yellow Mustang?
California licencse
number 614 HSO?
- Sure sounds like
my car all right.
- This bulletin
from the KIIS newsroom.
A high-speed police pursuit
starting in Long Beach,
is now in the--
- Billy, you gonna get
a ticket for this, man.
- You
polluting the air.
- I hear you.
- How we gonna pick up the
broads in this shit, man?
- No, man, we ain't going
nowhere in this shit, man.
- I hear you, B.
- I'm not going nowhere.
- Pass the joint, man.
- You think we'll make
it to the junkyard, man?
- I don't know, man.
- I hope so.
- Oh, wow, oh!
Look at that, this is shit, man.
- What's
wrong with this damn car?
- Goddamn, man.
- If that
crazy white man hadn't.
- Beach area, with
police cars and helicopters
of surrounding cities
joining the pursuit.
- I don't know who
sent you to see me,
but if they sent you, they
must be re-washing the car.
- Police
ask all motorists
to stay out of the area.
Roadblocks are being set
up all over that section
following a daring,
spectacular escape
by both the car and driver.
Having now eluded police
for over 40 minutes.
Stay with KIIS for further det--
- We'll I've been
waiting, where is my car?
- Well what kind of car is it?
- It's a yellow Mustang.
Oh my God!
- La--
- There he is!
- One Adam nine,
we have suspect
matching description.
- Hold on.
Freeze.
- Come here.
Put your hands up.
Spread 'em out.
- What's going on, officer?
- Let's have the license, sir.
- How do I get to
Harbor Freeway?
- Let's have the license.
- One Adam
Nine, we have a suspect
matching the description
of the suspect vehicle
in custody.
At the Rosencranz Car
Wash, 190th and Anson.
Attention all units,
suspect has just
been apprehended
at the Rosencranz car wash,
190 Street and Anson, repeat,
suspect has just
been apprehended.
- Move on.
- At the
Rosencranz Car Wash.
- Thank you, have a nice day.
- 190
Street and Anson.
- Hold it.
- Yes, officer?
- Stay right on 190th,
it'll take you right
to the Harbor Freeway.
- Thank
you very much.
- Let's
stake out the car club.
- Maybe we
could sell some parts
off this thing.
- I wish y'all
could find that damn Mustang.
- No, you
haven't ever lied.
- What's wrong?
- Let's
go to that party.
Let's go to that
party in this tonight.
- Y'all gettin' all
- Something's
wrong, it's on fire.
- Hey man,
let's just, holy shit.
- Oh, my
goodness gracious.
- See you around, Billy.
- Everybody
gon' let me...
- Don't do it.
- Aw, man,
I gotta get home...
- Hell,
yeah, I gotta come down.
- Yeah,
and get that...
- Get
out, get out, get out.
- Look
and see what's wrong.
- Booker!
Booker, see what's wrong!
- Don't
be kicking my car!
- What the
hell's wrong wit' you?