They're all set for us
over at the stable.
早点都为我们准备好了
- You all ready?
- Yes.
你们都吃过了吗
是的
- Would you like some coffee first?
- Yes, good idea.
你先喝点咖啡吗
是的 好主意
I... I just talked to Joseph.
我 我刚刚和约瑟夫谈过了
- Oh, about the marriage?
- Yes.
哦 谈结婚的事情吗
是的
Is he happy about it?
他高兴吗
More like worried.
好像很担心
Like he thinks it was a mistake.
他觉得这桩婚姻是个错误
How do you feel about that, Blake?
你觉得呢 布莱克
Well, they're young.
They're obviously in love.
他们很年轻 也很相爱
It was their decision to make
and they made it.
这是他们该做的决定
而且他们已经决定了
I only hope
我只是希望
that Jeff's mind was clear,
that he knew what he was doing.
杰夫头脑很清楚
知道他正在做的事情
As to Joseph, well, he's a father.
至于约瑟夫 他是父亲
And since when
haven't most fathers
世上哪有父亲不为
been at loggerheads
with their children?
他们的孩子忧虑的
I've just been so happy.
我倒是很高兴
These past few days
have been like a dream.
这几天就像是一场梦
Flying away to be married to the man
who I've been in love with
远走高飞和我所爱的人结婚
since I was 1 0 years old.
那从我10岁起就是我的梦想
Being separated from reality.
不切实际的幻想
That part's over, I guess.
幻想结束了
Why?
为什么
You're still my wife.
你是我的妻子了
Like the man said,
"ln sickness and in health,
多愁善感的人
in Reno and in Denver."'
不管是在里诺 还是在丹佛
Boy, I'm really striking out today.
Still no smile.
今天我一直想让你高兴起来
I'm just wondering
what's waiting for us there. Fallon...
我在想 我们将面对什么情况 法伦
Now, what about Fallon?
法伦怎么了
I wish we'd told her
what we were going to do.
我们应该提前告诉她
Kirby, this marriage of ours is ours.
科比 我们结婚是我们的事情
Between you and me only.
只和你我有关
We owe Fallon nothing.
我们不欠法伦什么
Then why do we have to go back
right away?
那我们现在就回去
Because I do owe Alexis something:
因为我欠亚历克西斯
A showdown.
一场对决
And because I have a son
还因为我有一个儿子
that I don't wanna be separated from
right now.
这会儿我想儿子了
You and Fallon have a son you don't
wanna be separated from right--
你和法伦有一个儿子
你们不想分开
Let's finish packing.
我们现在收拾行李
And no more talk about Mrs. Colby.
Just us.
不谈论科尔比太太 只谈我们
Jeffrey,
杰弗里
I'm Mrs. Colby now.
我现在才是科尔比太太
Mrs. Jeffrey Colby.
杰弗里 科尔比太太
Need any help?
需要帮助吗
No, thanks. According to Jeanette,
I'm doing just great.
不 谢谢 珍妮特说我做得很不错了
Yeah, you are.
是的
Off to the hounds, Mrs. Carrington?
你要出去吗 卡林顿太太
No, I just got back.
不 我是刚刚回来
Steven, your father
was very disturbed this morning.
斯蒂文 你父亲今天很郁闷
About Jeff and Kirby?
是因为杰夫和科尔比吗
That happens to be
none of his business.
这件事和他没有关系
No.
不
About you. The two of you.
是因为你 是因为你们俩
Last night.
昨天晚上
Call it business as usual.
没什么情况
Nothing's changed between us.
That much should be pretty obvious.
我们之间还是老样子
小事一桩
Neither of you is willing to see
the other's point of view.
你们俩都想读懂对方的观点
Oh, no, I saw his point.
哦 不 我读懂他的观点了
The trouble is he doesn't--
He won't see mine.
问题是他还没读懂
也读不懂我的观点
I told him I was going to New York
to see my wife.
我告诉他 我要去纽约
去找我的妻子
He said, "My God, Steven,
you just got home. Your life is here."'
他说 天啊 斯蒂文
你刚刚到家 你的生活在这里
Well, he's wrong.
所以说 他是错的
More wrong than he's ever been
about anything concerning me.
对我来说 他比以往更加错误
Steven, that's his way of saying
he wants you here
斯蒂文 他是想让你呆在家里
because he loves you.
因为他爱你
Krystle, I appreciate
his having searched for me.
克瑞斯特 我感谢他去寻找我
I know that
that was out of some kind of love,
我知道那是对我的爱
a father's instinctive love for a child.
一个父亲对孩子本能的爱
But the truth is,
I didn't want to be found.
可事实上 我不想被找到
Okay, I was. And I came back.
Okay 我被找到了 于是我回来了
But not for him, Krystle.
但不是为了他回来的 克瑞斯特
I came back
because of this little guy right here.
我是为我的儿子回来的
And you're going to see Sammy Jo
你想去找萨米 乔
to see if you can make things work
between the two of you.
想试一试 看看能否挽回你俩的关系
I lay awake last night
praying for that.
昨天晚上躺在床上
我一直在祈祷
Steven, this is hard for me to say...
斯蒂文 我本不想说
...because Sammy Jo is your wife
and my niece and Danny's mother.
因为萨米 乔是你的妻子
我的外甥女 也是丹尼的母亲
She doesn't want Danny.
她不想要丹尼
- She's tough and ambitious.
- Yes.
她既固执 又有抱负
Well, maybe that's for me
to find out.
所以我要去找她
I'm sorry, Krystle.
对不起 克瑞斯特
I just can't even accept your opinion
for something this important.
我不能接受你的观点
这对我至关重要
"Steven, your life is here."'
斯蒂文 你的生活在这里
I don't think it is.
我不这么认为
I know damned well it isn't.
我确信无疑
纽约市
Well, well.
好吧 好吧
Eleven-thirty
and you're finally awake.
11点半了 你终于醒了
After you finally
let me get some sleep.
是你让我睡得那么晚
Oh, Fred, you just said it was 1 1 :30.
And you don't wanna be late, do you?
哦 福瑞德 你说是11点半了
你不想迟到 是吗
To that lunch
with a certain important client.
和一个重要客户一起吃饭
About getting
the prettiest country girl in town
想找到一名最漂亮的姑娘
to be their exclusive
cosmetic model, right?
给他们的化妆品当模特 对吗
You promised.
你答应过我
I know.
我知道
But these things take time.
可梳妆打扮需要时间的
So meanwhile, you--
所以 你
You keep comfortable here,
all right?
你还是呆在这里吧 好吗
Shouldn't be too tough.
不要固执了
You've got yourself
a very comfortable little pad
你已经把你自己安顿在了很舒适的地方了
for a struggling newcomer.
对于一个初来乍到的人来说
I think it's okay.
那么好吧
And I get a break on the rent.
这样我可以休息一会儿了
Goodbye, Fred.
再见 福瑞德
No, Mr. Hess, that will not do.
不 赫斯先生 那样不可以
I hired you to unearth some real
scandal on Congressman McVane,
我雇你是想挖到迈克万议员的丑闻
not some innocuous
gossip-column item
不是什么无关紧要的花边新闻
that Suzy would just chuck
in her waste-paper basket.
那位苏西已经不值一提了
Yes, David, what is it?
是的 大卫 什么事情
Blake Carrington is here to see you,
Mrs. Colby.
布莱克 卡林顿来见你 科尔比太太
Tell him to come--
让他进来
Well, he is in.
他已经进来了
All right, Mr. Callahan,
if you'll just be a little patient,
好吧 卡拉汉先生
如果你能等一下
I'll get back to you as soon as possible.
Yes, goodbye.
我会尽快回复给你
好吧 再见
Well, Blake.
And what can I do for you?
布莱克 我能为你做些什么
Oh, no, don't tell me. Let me guess.
哦 不 你不要讲 我猜猜看
Those board members of yours
who mysteriously disappeared
是你的那些神秘消失的董事
are suddenly surfacing,
忽然之间又都浮出水面了
and you want to set a date
for my meeting about the merger.
你是想确定日期
商量公司合并的事情
I'm here on personal business: Steven.
我来这里是个人的事情
有关斯蒂文的事
Something happened?
发生了什么事
What's happened is you.
是发生了你的事情
Now, when I went off to Singapore
to bring him back home,
我去了新加坡 把他带了回来
you made me swear
that I wouldn't do anything
你曾让我发誓
to poison his mind against you.
不要玷污他的心灵
以其反对你
That was the word you used, "poison,"
wasn't it?
你说的那个词 玷污 是吗
Yes.
是的
Damn it, that's exactly
what you've done to me now.
见鬼 现在你就是干了这样的事
以其对付我
What are you talking about?
你在说些什么
That miserable lie
that you threw at him,
你想他撒了弥天大谎
that I tried to buy his son for Krystle.
诬陷我为克瑞斯特收买了他的儿子
Now he's gone off to New York
to see Sammy Jo.
现在他到纽约去了
去找萨米 乔了
- To do what?
- Guess, just guess.
去干什么
是猜测 只是猜测
He's not gonna try and reconcile
with that tramp, is he?
他不是想和那个流浪女和解吧 对吗
Well, whether he comes back here
with or without her,
不管他能否带回她来
I've got something to ask you
right now.
我现在想和你商量
Not on the basis of decency,
God knows,
不是什么体面的事情
上帝才知道
but because I'm sure
that you really love your son.
可我想你是爱你的儿子的
Can we come to a joint decision?
我们能否共同做一个决定
What kind of a joint decision?
什么样的共同决定
Not to turn our son into a battleground
to settle our own personal interests.
不要将我们的儿子卷入你我之间的争斗当中
Now, I'm determined
to make peace with Steven.
现在我想和斯蒂文言归于好
I'm prepared to do anything
to bury the past,
只要是忘记过去 我可以做任何让步
but I'm gonna need help.
可我需要帮助
Yours.
你的帮助
Well, do we have a deal?
我们能否达成一笔交易
Well, Steven is our son.
斯蒂文是我们的儿子
He's yours and he's mine.
是你的 也是我的
Yes, we have a deal.
是的 我们可以达成一笔交易
Good.
好的
- Morning, Mother.
- Good morning, darling.
早上好 妈妈
早上好 亲爱的
What did father want
at this hour of the morning?
我父亲这么早来此
有什么事情吗
What he wants, Adam,
isn't important.
他想做什么并不重要 亚当
What I want is.
我现在想的是
Now, you promised me once
that you would be a brother,
你要答应我 你要当好兄长的角色
a true brother to Steven.
作为斯蒂文的兄长
Big brother. Yes, I remember.
Now's your chance
to keep that promise.
You usually smile when you have
a grand plan going, Mother.
You're not smiling now.
Listen to me, Adam.
Now, I know that you're not
particularly fond of Steven,
but I want you
to become friends with him.
It's funny, isn't it?
You don't think I like Steven.
But I do.
I never had a kid brother before.
I never had a friend.
Not a real friend.
I just hope to God Steven likes me.
Well, here we are.
I see my father didn't arrange
for a brass band.
Not even a string quartet.
Well, whatever his problem is--
Jeff. Kirby.
Welcome back.
Congratulations.
- Thank you.
I was just on my way to the hotel,
check things out.
How's it going?
Oh, fine. The same.
Well, you two look wonderful.
Can I see your ring?
It's very pretty.
We bought it in a hurry at the
Reno airport, if you can believe that.
Oh, I can.
Slot machines, wedding bands,
all part of the big--
The big what?
Gamble?
Sorry.
It's just that this is so unexpected,
I'm not as witty as I might be.
Well, Jeff,
I know you wanna see Little Blake.
I'll go back upstairs with you. I wanna
give him an extra kiss goodbye.
Kirby, I know you'll
wanna see your father.
I'm sure he's waiting for me.
Hi.
Here.
Look, I didn't mean to behave
the way I did downstairs, I just--
Oh, what was so wrong?
You were just
trying to make a little joke.
I mean, that is you, Fallon, isn't it?
The smart-talking Carrington?
What are you thinking right now?
"Here today, gone tomorrow."'
Come on, let's hear it.
Well, today's just
not my day for quips, okay?
Look, Jeff,
you and I couldn't make it work.
But I'm glad you and Kirby will.
It's wonderful for you and I'm glad.
Do you really mean that?
Yes, and--
And what?
And I was just thinking I should
probably arrange a party for you both.
Or somebody should.
That's a nice thought.
But...
Well, let's talk about it
some other time.
Fallon, I want you to know that it's--
It's going to work
between Kirby and me.
Because it-- Well, because it is.
I also want you to know, though...
Well, there's something
inside me that's--
That's never gonna stop loving you.
Don't say that, Jeff.
You're on to a new life now.
The new wipes out the old.
Let's hope so.
Mrs. Gunnerson told me you were
downstairs checking a wine delivery.
I said I'd wait for you here.
I'm home, Papa.
What am I supposed to say to that?
What I wanted you to say
on the phone: congratulations.
For ruining your life?
How am I ruining my life?
I'm married to a man
I love very, very much.
At the moment.
I always have.
Even when you were having
an affair in Paris with Jean-Paul?
Yes.
Oh, Papa, say it, please?
"Congratulations."'
What I'm going to say is this,
daughter:
You're not of the same world
as the Colbys and the Carringtons.
I find that funny. Very funny.
Because I remember a time
when you were all for me marrying
into the upper classes,
when I was with Jean-Paul,
before I knew he had a wife.
That's not the same thing.
Then what is it you're thinking?
That the people in this house,
who've known me practically
since I was born,
are not gonna let me forget
that I'm a major-domo's daughter?
Or that they've always thought that
they're better than we are, is that it?
Why on Earth would they think that
about the downstairs girl
who finally had her wish
and became the upstairs bride?
Why would your loving husband
ever think about that?
You seem to think that he will.
That someday Jeff and l
are gonna have an argument
and he's gonna bring it up,
he's gonna hit me with it.
Remind me
of my humble beginnings.
Yes, maybe. In fact, probably.
Is that a prediction?
You seem to have all the answers.
Why don't you answer that question
for yourself.
I have a question for you.
From this moment on,
what am I supposed to call you?
Mrs. Colby? Madame?
Your royal highness?
Don't answer that.
As the major-domo
of the household,
I'll come up with
the proper form eventually.
I'm very happy for you, Jeff.
My best wishes
to both you and Kirby.
Thank you, Blake.
Glad to see you looking so well.
- You sound surprised.
- No, no.
Well, it's just that
after all you've been through,
and then this thing happening
so suddenly.
And you're wondering if I got married
without knowing what I was doing.
Right?
Look, Blake, I know you always wanted
it to work out with Fallon and me.
Well, it didn't.
Jeff,
you have always been
like a son to me, you know that.
And I was hoping that you would
always be my son-in-law,
but I guess life just doesn't work out
the way we want it to all the time.
Important thing
is for you to be happy.
Well, Blake, I'm married now.
I'm gonna be happy.
But look, I don't wanna
talk about that right now.
What I do wanna talk about is this:
I wanna sue Alexis.
On what grounds?
On the grounds that I signed over
my son's stock when I wasn't fit.
I was sick,
I didn't know what I was doing.
I can't let you do that, Jeff.
Blake, I can do anything I want.
I won't let you do it.
Now, look, I don't have to remind you
that she's planning on merging
Denver-Carrington with Colbyco.
She's waiting there to bury you.
I know that, and I'm gonna fight that,
but I can't let you go into court.
Well, first of all, it would take years
for that litigation to go through.
Meanwhile,
it's gonna be mother's milk
for every newspaper editor
in the state,
in the country,
to print that when you signed
those papers,
that you were temporarily insane.
And that's the way they'll put it,
believe me.
Well, Blake, if it doesn't bother me,
why should it bother you?
Your reputation could be clouded
for a long time to come.
Maybe even the rest of your life.
And it could conceivably
affect your son.
Blake, it's my fault.
I signed that paper. I'm the one
who put you where you are.
It doesn't matter.
I'm gonna be in there fighting Alexis,
but I'm going to fight her my way.
Now, that board meeting
has not been convened yet.
Neal McVane is in Washington
trying to convince the right people
not to consider that merger,
even if it is presented.
So I'm not out of weapons yet.
And I will not allow you
to put your head on the block
when you don't have to.
End of discussion.
All right.
Well, Jeff, I'd be very happy
if you and Kirby would consider
staying on at the house for a while.
You've got enough pressures
hanging over you right now anyway,
and we could both use
one another's support.
I'll think about it.
Hello, Elizabeth.
- Who is it?
- Steven, it's Adam, may I come in?
Sure.
- Hi.
Oh, I'm glad I caught you.
Now, we didn't have much time
to spend together when you got back.
Yeah, I know,
I'm really sorry about that too.
- Unfortunately--
- Yes, I know.
You're ready to leave town.
Well, before you go,
I just wanna tell you
how much I admire your courage
for what you went through.
May l?
Thank you.
And I regret having grown up
without a brother,
and I hope that we get
to know one another better.
Thanks. I hope so too.
And I appreciate your coming,
it's just that right now
I really have no time.
Of course,
you're off to New York to see that girl.
My wife.
Steven,
I know it's none of my business,
but I've heard a lot about her.
I've known girls like her.
So I'd say leave well enough alone.
Who sent you here
with that bit of fraternal advice, Adam?
My father? My mother?
No, you're wrong.
I came on my own.
And look,
when you get to know me better,
you'll know that I don't make
judgements about people.
Is that what you rushed over
to talk about? My lifestyle?
No, believe me.
But it does have
something to do with it.
Steven, look,
I've been around a lot
more than you.
I mean, sleeping with girls.
How can you know
the baby's even yours?
Because I know he is, Adam.
And if you're asking me
if I ever went to bed with my wife,
and if I ever made love to my wife,
I did.
Now, get lost, Brother.
Adam, I'd like to see you
in the library.
Why?
To talk about Steven.
Krystle, I have things to do.
Whatever it is, it can wait.
What I have to say to you can't.
What kind of a brother are you?
How could you say something
like that to him?
About his sexual preference?
Well, that's national news, isn't it?
Ever since my father's trial.
Tell me something, Krystle.
Did something happen
when my back was turned?
What does that mean?
You suddenly seem
to have become Steven's mother.
No, Adam,
I'm not Steven's mother.
But I am his friend.
And I want you to know
he was my first friend in this house,
back in the days when everyone else
was hostile to me.
And where I come from,
one friend defends another.
Ohio, wasn't it?
Where embraces flourish,
along with
sometimes hot-tempered ladies?
Adam, Steven needs support
from all of us, you know that.
Yes, I do.
And so does mother.
But if she sees fit--
Sees fit to what?
Steven was right.
She did send you.
No.
She may have suggested it,
but then l--
But then what?
Never mind. Forget it.
Adam, tell your mother that no matter
what she had on her mind,
Steven's on his way to New York.
We're going to stay here?
Is that what you're telling me?
That's right. For a while.
We're not going to find a house
of our own?
Jeff, Fallon lives in this house.
- She's your--
- She's my ex-wife
and she has nothing to do with it.
How many times
do I have to say that?
do we have to talk about Fallon?
Then it's your son.
You wanna be near him.
We can find a house close by,
you can see him every day.
You know that.
No, there are other things.
And finding the right house
will take time.
Now, I've gotta go downtown again.
It's all complicated.
Blake's in trouble and I got him there,
and I gotta get him out of it.
Now, everything's going to be fine.
You know that.
I heard the news.
You and Jeff.
And felicitations?
You are so dumb.
You are so dumb, Mrs. Colby.
"Mrs. Colby."' Is that a first?
No, Mr. Carrington,
a bellboy in Reno beat you to it.
Don't walk away from me, Kirby.
And don't try to walk away
from the truth.
You married Jeff Colby for his money
and his name.
And you aren't fooling anybody,
especially not me.
You see,
we are cut
from the same calico cloth.
Now, I know we each have to climb
these gilt-edged walls
in our separate fashions,
but why did you choose him?
When I could've had you?
Oh, we had a night that night.
That night was a mistake. I still get
sick when I remember that night.
- Do you really?
- Now get your hands off of me.
And I forbid you
to ever touch me again.
Forbid?
Spoken like a true mistress
of the manse, Kirby, well done.
And so quickly too.
But you'll be back with me.
Married or not,
you and I aren't finished.
Married?
Jeff married Kirby Anders?
I thought you might've heard by now.
No.
No, I hadn't heard.
Mother, I know
the news is surprising.
I didn't think it would
hit you this hard.
Why is it so important?
Why does it matter so much to you?
Because of what you did to Jeff,
that's why.
Kirby had nothing to do with that.
She is married to the man
that you tried to poison.
Maybe she'll try
and find out what happened.
That girl is as insolent as her father,
but she is intelligent.
She'll start digging.
And maybe
she'll discover something.
There's nothing to discover.
The panels with the paint have been
destroyed. I gave that order myself.
I don't think that's it.
No? Then what do you think it is?
I think there's something else
in this thing with Jeff and Kirby.
Mother,
I think you know something I don't.
Adam, I know many things
that you don't.
I know about wine,
I know about art and music.
And life, of course.
Yes, you can throw that one in.
You also know something I don't.
The question is,
do I get filled in or not?
Adam, you're beginning to bore me.
Sorry.
- Fallon?
- Come in.
Business is bad
and you can't afford
to pay the electric bill.
I'm tied up with my thoughts.
I can't seem to get anywhere.
Your ex-husband came home
with his new bride
and there's a hollow feeling
inside of you.
I'm happy for them.
Maybe.
I am.
But you're confused
and even kind of miserable.
Hey, I went through that when I heard
that Krystle married your father.
You know,
what were my inadequacies?
What happened to the great moments
we had together, right?
No.
Fallon, come on, you're talking to me.
The guy in Haiti, remember?
When all we did was talk?
Serious talk.
What are you,
a tennis pro or a shrink?
If you're a shrink,
maybe I should lie on the couch.
Maybe you can get me an office
with a big leather couch.
And then I'll moonlight.
Not until I pay my electric bill.
I would make a good shrink.
God knows I've known all kinds
of women with all kinds of problems.
There he goes, bragging again.
Yeah, that seems to be
my kind of style.
At least I have something
going for me.
You have a lot going for you, Mark.
You are one of the few people I know
who's really himself.
Like my brother Steven.
And that's rare.
Okay. So you'd make a good shrink.
And you wanna continue analysing
my plight?
No, I've got the cure.
Well, just what
every tired businessman needs.
A lovely lady on the floor next to a fire,
a pitcher full of martinis.
The only thing that doesn't go
with the picture is,
why are you so pensive, darling?
I was just thinking.
About Jeff and Kirby.
And about you.
Oh, how did I get into this?
I know deep in your heart
you've always hoped that Fallon
and Jeff would get together again.
Yes, I did. But obviously,
that is never going to take place.
Now, what exactly is on your mind.
What else are you thinking about?
Well, how everybody in this house
is shocked by Jeff
and Kirby's marriage,
their so-called impulsiveness.
And I know what they're thinking.
"Marry in haste, repent in leisure."'
Darling, that wouldn't have become
a truism if it weren't often true.
I know that.
But we have to give them a chance.
I mean, they are already married.
And one of the things
that might be a problem
is the uncomfortable position
Kirby's in,
reversing her place in this house.
- And--
- And what?
Well, someone should talk
to Joseph.
I mean, her own father
is making her feel
more uncomfortable
than anyone else.
Now,
I could do it, I know--
But coming from me,
it would have double authority.
Yes.
My beautiful wife,
always thinking
about someone else.
I love you for that. I always have.
More than you'll ever know.
All right, of course, I'll talk to Joseph.
Anything you want.
But since you're not quite dressed
for dinner yet,
what would happen
if we decided to skip dinner tonight?
Well,
probably be a scandal downstairs.
Let's risk it.
Who is it?
Steven.
Hello, Steven.
- It is you.
- Sammy Jo.
Aren't you gonna come in?
A taxi from the airport
must've been hard to find.
It's been over an hour
since you phoned.
Yeah.
But I made it.
Looks like you're doing well here
in the Big Apple.
Don't let this place fool you.
I haven't paid next month's rent yet.
It's due in a couple days,
but I'll manage.
Modelling.
Well, your father sends me
a little money.
I guess you know that.
And right, modelling.
They putting out any calls
for a young guy with a new face?
And a cane.
Real distinguished, huh?
How long will you have to use that?
Not long.
Well, I guess this is what you'd call
appropriately awkward conversation
between two people who haven't seen
each other in a while.
Not since that night in Hollywood.
Why are you here, Steven?
I thought we said goodbye
in Hollywood.
I wanna talk to you, Sammy Jo.
There's a great little restaurant
downtown
that I dream about
every once in a while.
The food's that good.
They stay open till 2.
So, what do you say?
You wanna go grab a bite to eat
with me and we can talk there?
All right.
You want me to come back to you,
the three of us together.
- Is that what you're saying?
- Yes.
Well, maybe it wouldn't be so bad.
We could get an apartment.
You know,
overlooking the East River,
and then a summer place
in the Hamptons.
Or even better, Connecticut. Westport.
Oh, that would be more fun.
And we could afford it.
At least your father could.
Sammy Jo, I'm not talking about
taking any money from my father.
I don't need it.
I'll get a job and I'll support us.
And I'm not talking about living here.
I'm talking about Denver.
Going back home.
Home?
Maybe your home, Steven,
but not mine.
I'm here. And I'm staying.
But you just said--
"Maybe it wouldn't be so bad.
Two of us, together again."'
It'd be rotten and you know it.
And you know why.
If you're thinking
what I know you are,
I haven't touched a man.
Not in a long time. A very long time.
But you haven't stopped thinking
about them, have you?
This place,
your favourite restaurant downtown.
Isn't that where you lived
with your boyfriend? Ted Dinard?
Isn't it?
Yes, but--
Isn't this where you used to come
to eat with him?
This great little restaurant
you told me you dreamed about?
Once. Maybe twice.
Oh, I'll bet.
Nothing's changed, Steven.
Not with me and not with you.
At least I know who I am
and what I want out of life.
And I don't want you.
Just like I don't want a baby
who was a mistake.
He's our son.
He's a beautiful boy
and he's our son.
He's the baby you gave birth to.
Yeah. You know why?
Because I was afraid
to have an abortion.
And you don't love him?
I don't know him.
How can you know eight pounds
of a kid? Of any kid?
I can't believe you're saying this.
I can't believe
that when you see him again,
and when you see
that I've changed--
But you haven't changed.
Because you can't change.
What's it gonna be,
the two of us together again?
You laying in bed with me,
sometimes even making love to me.
But not really to me.
To a ghost.
- Sammy Jo, listen to me--
- No, you listen to me.
I didn't do such a bad job of thinking
about Danny's best interests.
At least I put him with people
who can give him what he needs,
including a normal upbringing.
You wanna do your thing
with other guys, go do it.
But if you really give a damn
about your son,
Iet him grow up
with a straight family.
Don't stick him with you for a father.
I'm not hungry. I'll take a taxi back.
Before you go,
I want to ask you one thing.
Did you really try to sell him
to my father like a piece of goods?
Let's just say I thought about it.
I never got anything else from you,
did l?
I think that you like
this plain little old wedding band.
Well, I love it.
I love the man who gave it to me.
Just like I love you,
Iike I couldn't love you more
if you were my own handsome boy.
Which he isn't, Kirby.
I only meant that--
Oh, no apologies necessary.
I know what you meant.
Fallon, I'm happy and Jeff's happy.
We know you're going to be happy.
Do you mind, Kirby? I'd like
to spend some time with my son.
Hi.
What the devil are you doing here,
Sam?
I know. I'm supposed to be off fishing
in the Bahamas
where your ex-wife
couldn't track me down.
Except that she did.
Sure as that seaplane landed next
to my boat and handed me this.
Now, listen.
"Attention: Samuel Dexter.
I intend to hold merger meeting
with you there or not.
If you are absent l, as a holder of
majority interest in Denver-Carrington,
shall present my own list of nominees
for the board,
and have their election confirmed
by the courts.
Alexis Colby."'
No love and kisses.
I'm hamstrung, Blake.
The meeting's called for tomorrow.
But you will not be there,
is that clear?
Because I'm gonna have Andrew Laird
down at court in the morning
arguing that she got this majority
by her typically dirty pool.
No, I'm sorry, Blake.
I can't take that risk.
You can't? Why not?
What if Laird's arguments
are tossed out? I've got no choice.
I own stock
in Denver-Carrington too.
And you're fighting a personal battle,
it seems to me,
and this is a business battle.
Yes, my business.
A company that I built up
from nothing.
A company that made you a rich man,
a very rich man.
I'm sorry, Blake.
Blake, I'm your friend.
I always will be, I hope.
But gratitude isn't the name
of the game in this part of our world.
I'm back and I'll be at that meeting.
Anyway, the fishing was lousy.
Steven.
Oh, darling, I'm so glad you're back.
I'm here because your chauffeur
was waiting for me at the airport.
The guy practically kidnapped me.
Well, I was so anxious to see you.
Come and sit down.
Now, I know that you called
from New York about the baby and--
Well, since you
were coming back alone--
Without Sammy Jo, that's right.
Which I'm sure pleases you.
Darling, what pleases me
is that you obviously,
and finally, saw that girl
for what she really was.
But that's all in the past now.
The reason
that I practically kidnapped you
was to talk about your future with me
at Colbyco.
Mother,
I can't give you an answer yet.
Another part of my future
hasn't been settled,
the most important part:
What I intend to do about my son.
I understand, darling.
But what I really want you to know
is that I'm praying that you'll say yes.
Well, thanks for wanting me.
But right now--
Right now you have
other things on your mind.
I understand.
I've always understood you, darling.
Better than your father,
better than Fallon,
better than all of them.
Promise me
that you'll bear that in mind.
- I promise.
- Good.
Move into your own apartment?
Why?
Easy answer, Dad?
I'm going to make a life for myself
and my son,
and I intend to raise him
as a single parent. Alone.
- I don't understand that.
- Try, Dad. Try.
Krystle.
Yes, Steven?
I know how much you love Danny.
And I'm grateful for all the love
and care you've given him.
But he is my son.
He's my responsibility and I'm the one
who has to take care of him.
You understand that, don't you?
Of course I understand.
Well, I don't.
Here stands my son,
obstinate as always.
My son who's--
Steven, all we want for this child here
is to be surrounded by a real family.
A whole family, and not some--
Some--
Say it.
You can speak plainer than that, Dad.
You don't want Danny
to have a gay for a father.
Well, don't worry.
Because your grandson will be able
to choose for himself
who and what he wants to be
when he grows up.
Yes, with you as an example?
Blake!
No, Krystle, don't.
Don't get him to apologise to me.
Don't get him to say,
"I'm sorry, son, I didn't mean it."'
Because he did.
There are mornings
when I wake up in bed
and I'm perspiring and trembling,
and I ask myself,
is it me or is it my life here,
being back in this house?
Just being back in this house.
Well, I don't think it's me, Dad.
And I'm getting out of here
as soon as I can.
Me and my son.
I'm gonna bring him up
to the nursery, all right?
- All right.
- Now, Steven,
we are not finished
talking about this.
I insist that we talk this out.
- Steven.
- Blake.
- Steven!
- Blake, let him go, please.
Try to see it his way.
His way?
Have you suddenly lost your mind?
If you try to stop him,
you may never see Danny again.
And that would break your heart
and mine.