! (Kylie)
Then shot
.. Even though my vision for this dream a lot
I was not before
Of carrying a gun
I know
This is absolutely wonderful
This shows a deep sense of
To accept responsibility
And tell me you did not go beyond your illusions
In your conscious mind only
In his mind, but also subcontractors
This is my opinion that (Tim) Rashid Salim
Does not represent a danger to himself or others
I think it should be released
He also asked the state representative
Holiday in the birth atheist twenty
Sold, congratulations to you sir
He Highest No. 131
Well, the purpose of the following
Are those wonderful antique mirror
"Recovered from the manor" No Wska
Glass Restorer to mirror decorated royal palaces
For several generations in the Middle Ages
This is the original glass and frame
Mirror in excellent condition
With the exception of a small fraction below
Frame carved from one piece
From "Alsadar" Black
We will start the auction at 10 thousand dollars
Do I get 10?
Here is a
Thank you sir -
If your sister will take you -
According to its mission in anything
For the management of my posts
This would be a wonderful thing
Your period of transitional
We have 12 thousand over the phone
And return to the room
Omtakdh of desire
Not I go with you?
Some moral support
No. No Thanks
This is best done alone
Way to deal with it -
Of course -
Remember what we talked about
I've had to have a support system
Dedicated to help you
Kiley) forced to rely on itself)
It is important to restore communication with your sister
But more importantly, to maintain your recovery
We have 16 thousand -
"We have over 16 thousand" Skype -
Preparing the first, second
Was selling! Please inform the buyer congratulations -
See you tonight - Well -
I pull the door when you hear the sound, my son,
Hello, my little brother
Half the inheritance of thy
Apartments
Well, studies say that the move
To a place not necessarily have to be large
So put a list of small apartments
And until you find what you like
Will love if you stay with us
Kiley), I do not know how to thank you)
Well, I wanted to tell you all this before
But they suddenly
Did not let me see you
Not ... not that they
They did not let you see me
I had some things
I wanted to understand myself
I understand
I am your family, the only thing important
Is that you are here now
! Well?
I've found
What do you mean?
You know .. It was not easy
I had to defeat some bidders
It was stored
"Part of a group of collectors in the" Bremen
It took me a year and a half to be brought into our store
And stayed less than a week
It is on the verge shipped to the buyer of a new
We do not have only a few days
Should be enough
A few days to do what O (Kylie)?
To keep our promise
And murder
"11 years ago"
Well, the situation here couch
And these funds in the kitchen
TEM), do not do this)
You'll get them as soon as
That I arrange my files, dammit
Can I call later?
Jeff!) I am very sorry for not redial)
I've been extremely busy
It even easier when the chief of staff
Kiley) in custody)
She's not here, my friend.
! Feint
I've spent on you -
Please, please, darling -
Do not -
Why? -
Where do we put this?
That room
Well .. -
Be careful -
Well, guys
Olaba abroad
But, my mom -
The alternative is to assist in the transfer of funds -
OK
Yes, we talk soon
Well -
Thanks for as -
OK
I'm going out at once
If you are asked for more furniture
I do not know that I love you
Put this office here
Are you going to tell me
Or you wait until
I see the credit card bill?
Well, I hope your news thing
Smoothly through the three-piece vanity
Supposed to be represented by those artifacts
Do not you see this, my dear?
I understand, your office systems as desired
Thank you
By this sort of affectation, do not you think?
I'm confused, you are wanted artifacts
And I was satisfied with the ordinary furniture
Yes, some of the pieces I wanted to improve the place
Do not turn it into a show room
We've got a new home
New work
So we come with new furniture
This is logical -
But the same wife, right? -
I told you I
Radi Bada
Joking -
I do not like this -
Are you sure you prefer this?
Guest room we have a much better
Yes, I think this is the best
Place me alone
I've promised not to
Forget what really happened
I promised
I've been in the tenth
Well, I'll do it tomorrow night
I really need to thyself;
(Night carefree O (Tim
I feel that Ndbta clear now
More than it was ten years
Let me take a look at this professional
Any scar?
You did not Ttfqdha from the ground up
If you? -
You just put the bandage -
This has not been easy
! Oh my god
There is nothing wrong
It's just a nightmare
Hello -
If you can use the printer
You do not have to participate anymore
Will not allow you to use the network
Well -
I think that there are those who get offended when -
Puts his sales
And find some horrific images
Originating from your Computer.
I noticed you made a transfer request
Mirror restored
Yes, for repair
(I thought (Warren
Said no to repair
We have changed his mind
I for honest, I'm waiting
Your explanation of the images of bodies
I know that things
The strange sometimes
I deal with some of the things the dark
(Now after exit (Tim
I do not expect you to understand that
This part of my life
But hold me for a day or two
Things should be back to normal
I promise
OK
I usually do not get transfer orders
For reform through a third party
Yes, the seller wants this guy
That Ieanha before shipping
But we both know you are the best -
That's right -
'll Take her there myself
Consonant with her at every moment
Must Ojhzha
As long as we Snnqlha
Hello again
Must be hungry
I hope they still hurt
Once ..
Are you okay?
I'm fine if
Comrades Sejehsoha you immediately
(Thank you, (Warren
See you at home
My car at the pier
Hello -
I bought a phone -
Gorgeous -
I need you to sign a transfer order
I do not like how
We left things last night
Would we meet to talk about this?
Of course
Can you come to the house?
Certainly, what title?
No. I mean, our house
Yes, and here is the front
I do not know, about half the time
Is this acceptable?
OK
Damn
"The answer is still" no
My goodness, (automatic) has one
And (physical) has one
I am the only one in my class
That do not have phone
This is terrible
(Thanks for nothing, (Mary
! I Sahra to buy it off you, my daughter,
O love of my life and the fruit
"Well, I wish I were," Pineapple
Hla Tsdiagn service nor Tqdma
Ozafrckma never like Aldkma, this sickening
Dad -
(Well, call him "Dad" and I (Mary -
Who was that lady
In your office today?
Yes, my father
That was the
The lady in the office today?
Any lady?
I do not know
Lady
The place looks very small
Come on, dog
Is Osmita dog "dog"?
Does not have a name
Are you okay?
Of course
.. Did not come here since
Did not receive a look?
I've been home without Chari
I am in the role of care
Took me out when I was eighteen
I was only in college
, Which owns a house
But I think we should try to sell it
... As you know, after
Can you help me with something before you leave?
How predicted the introduction of this thing alone?
The Secretariat did not expect
For as long as I thought it would be both of us
Put it here
What are these?
Anchor? , A button to kill
So ..
I understand if you do not want to stay
Accept this
But, to start
I'll stay for a while
Hello
My name is (Kylie Ann Russell) I am 23 years
(I'm with my brother (Timothy Al Contact
Has called on the name of our father
That in the twenty-first
The time now is 4:50 pm
On October 13
"We are in the" 2705 through Hathurn
I'll start lists precautions taken
Before you place the mirror and disclosed
There are three cameras
Each has its circle electrophysiological own
When something abnormal occurrence
Will be conclusive evidence is biased
There is a land line phone and mobile phone
And now I will ask his brother
In order to be all
Electronic devices under my control
I've just purchased
(Thank you, (Tempo
This alarm is set to ring every 45 minutes
Reminds me to change the tapes cameras
This is set to ring every hour
To remind us that we eat
We have a stock of water
To prevent us from dehydration
As for the house itself
Each room is equipped with a thermal regulator are recording data
Program is designed to measure changes in temperature in hospitals
Any change in temperature greater
Of five degrees would be warning
Reserve the third also in his
But I'll come back to it later
So
The goal of today is to demonstrate experience
"The purpose for which the rear," the mirror
Is the home of the forces of abnormal
Can be measured and predicted
There is synonymous with scientific
The word "haunted" So we will say
To this end, responsible for 45 deaths and at least
In the four centuries of its existence registrar
Would you abandon your for a moment? -
No .. -
Do not move the camera
Sorry
Mirror source unknown
So I can not provide a full history
"But the impact begins in" London
In 1754
Philip families) Earl "Lester" XVII)
Got a mirror and hang it above the fireplace
Last reservist
Hello my dear, how are you -
Hello, are you check my, as she asked me, Are you okay -
Everything is okay I know it's a silly request
But Hla trying to connect at, I've crossed the seventh
Of course
Speak to you after 53 minutes, and I love you
I was waiting for periodic contacts
(From My fiance (Michael Dumont
I told him that I'm afraid to spend time
With my brother's newly released
And told him to inform the authorities immediately
That did not answer the phone -
I'm with you in the room -
It is not personally
(In 1755, has been found (to the families of Philip
Fireplace in the great
Distorted way as to prevent identification of the body
"While Tksmt and distributed his property in southern England '
A family member claimed to see in the mirror
Allegation was treated seriously summoned
An order to inspect the house church
Then was sold in the mirror
Auction in the year 1758
The following information is the owner of industry giant American
Robert Clancy) in the year 1864)
Apparently (Clancy) was weighing 300 lbs.
"While attending high university was called" Pisces
Commented the mirror in the dance floor
"At his home in the" Atlanta
Later that year
Was filmed by a local newspaper
And .. Well, I've lost some weight
His obituary was published after three weeks
Without mentioning the cause of death
Unfortunately been regarded as his property, including the mirror
Been destroyed in the campaign, "Sherman Marsh" war 1865
And then
Lost the mirror
"Until the beginning of the century appeared in the" New England
The following case is (Maria Connor) 1904
I hung the mirror in the bathroom
(Two weeks later found by her niece (Beatrice
Dead in the bathtub
The autopsy report identified the cause of death
I hear this, drought
She died of thirst and is lying
In the bathtub for three days
(The following is the case (Alice Carden
B "Lake Geneva," "Wisconsin" 1943
Neighbors reported hearing screams from the house
We have the police found children drowned
The (Alice) Chamber of children and her legs completely Mahtmtan
Her left hand broken places 4 and 6 of the Odilaha been crushed
Her right hand hammer
Used to break bones
They found them on the verge of breaking her skull
But her right hand was fully intact
Because they are needed by the
To carry the hammer
Hours after she thought
It puts children Pferachehem
Has still not recovered from her injuries
The family had several dogs
Of them, "Australian Shepherd" for children
Let's eat
From talking with exactly
Those tapes?
Each of pry
The
Children in school
Who discovered it
I think I speak
With all of the thought and the DNA killer
And he called killer
(Hear, O (Kylie
We have two children
We have invented the story in order to avoid frightening reality
And that DNA killer, has been well
He was a sick man
.. Tortured and killed or
You can Palmjnona descriptive as you like
But you are not allowed to
So talking about it
Tobin Cap) 1955)
Died in his room
The mirror was hanging above his desk
"In 1965 the" California
Receive hall mirror hanging
"Hotel in the" San Diego
Employee 10 years ago
When you go behind the electrical wiring
Kylie) - 1979 (Marisol Javiz) died) -
In her room because of bleeding from abortion
Found all her teeth
In a small bag and pliers Bmnddtha
In 2002
You know, there is a big difference
Between cause and correlation
I know the difference
Thank you
Well, in 2001
Mom and Dad Ostra new sofa
Occurred for a serious heart attack
Ruby Shawees) hit by a car)
Katana and fled
None of this Thelominh on the couch?
Can I update now?
Sure, but let's get into
(The heart of the matter, O (Kylie
Let's talk about why we are here
Let
(Mirror adorn the home (Alan Contact
Designer Software
(Husband's (Mary
Father (Timothy) and (Kylie), after two weeks
Of existence, located (Mary), the victim of a severe nervous breakdown
Is then tortured and killed
The home of the family
By whom?
At the hands of her husband
According to the police report
Her husband was killed
At the hands of his son
Before the eyes of her daughter
I intend to prove that all the people who reminded them
Are not responsible for their actions
Alan Russell) was not fatal)
I've been the victim of
One of the many victims
A victim of supernatural forces that static mirror
Why not finish it off
And destroy the dreaded this thing?
You really do not remember?
What do I remember?
Please shattered ..
Prefer
OK
I learned a lot about what
.. Happens to people who can not afford
To deal with is terrible
The mind creates many protections
To help them to adapt
When rooted belief
Mind takes random events
And combines them to support the novel
A sleeve issue discussed by
To find 12 or 13 supports your novel?
Why put the chair to the ground?
I'm trying to talk with you
Only one person from
Tried to destroy the mirror before
(Oliver Jeffries)
"In 1971, a professor of the Academy of" Manhattan
Where the suspended mirror hall for lectures
One day, I rush towards the mirror fire extinguisher
Flagrant that it should be destroyed, but he did not draw any blow her
According to his students, he sat quietly for a minute
Before you head out and walking through cars
Clearly, it is able
To defend itself
I Gerdtk of your weapon just
Do you know why did not extinguish
Oh mirror (Kylie)?
In addition to the possibility of evicted
Or charged with destruction of property
It is not for me to destroy them
No one can
Save you from your illusions
You did it yourself
Which brings me to the last reserve
You look to anchor weighs 20 lbs.
In addition to the 20-pound weight rack connected to cable
Is operated automatically by a temporary my kitchen
Without the need for electricity, which is something important
We are after 10 seconds
Temporary work every 30 minutes
.. If we were not here to stoppable
Here we will put the mirror
What prevents this
Is our survival
You see, did not wait too long?
Because we hold the weapon server
Addressed to the head
I expect to be willing
To defend itself
Taala to my office for a moment
I think I was clear
On non-Abzqm my office
We do not do
I do not like it here
Well, what is this?
We did not do it
OK
Otalman, I can Smaekma night
And ye are playing
I have a child it Votfhm
I know that the transition is difficult
But this will not happen again, okay?
If You were Tabthan plants Omkma
Stopped it too
You know uncle indicate dead plants?
Problems in the source water
Tank or bad
I remember we were purify water, filter
Oliver Jeffries), dead plants in the auditorium)
Tobin) keep plants dead in the bedroom)
Park worker could not understand
The reason for the presence of dead plants everywhere
Live plants
Live plants in the living room
Live plants, plants alive
Those are your rules -
Give it some time -
To your knowledge, were not fed on plants only
But there was another variable
My dog?
Sorry, my dog
Drinking water
Come, my friend -
Come on, (Mason) - zap -
Mason), later the stick) -
! I run -
! Later stick
! Come on, go! , Go
The only reason for his bullish
Anxiety is that we are not safe
I told you I saw a person below -
But this does not makes me feel more secure -
Quite the contrary
Well, it will be closed, and Avrgh lead
Until an emergency
! O silly cow
Bam just called me?
I did not say anything
! Oh my god
! (Alan) -
! I'm working -
From talking with?
Are you going to do something about the dog barking?
(There are speeches, my dog ​​(Alan
I have bit me
Are you okay?
I'm just fine
You just lost
In your world here
.. I'm not lost in
Well, 'Listen, I'll go
To play golf with a client
I want both of you stay away
For my office, okay?
Well, Dad
Well, love you both guys
Do you want to come in?
Will enter
Enter the liter is there
Damn
Why do not you get it out? -
My mom said it punishable -
Hello, did not Tglsan so? -
We must do something about this dog -
It would be nice if I say hello
I've been barking all day long
I had to incarceration in your office
Tmonyh
Where is it?
Here's the problem, you remember wrong -
Do not -
I assure you, I remember correctly -
No I'm not well -
Ciberd Australian "and the other"
Animals not found them
Do you remember (Mason) in his last days?
Vomiting and accidents all over the house
My doctor made me emotional
Looking for fever virus
Fatal disease that causes nausea and aggressive
And urination, but Aradi, which could kill plants
Mason) was sick)
Well, I'm taking to the doctor tomorrow
Bad news, I think it will not come back to me
Mom, where (Mason)?
It is punishable
Are you saying that you remember
Thus it occur?
Is this really says?
Why not?
You're wrong
I saw my mother closed the door upon
And sat down in front of the door and did not come out of it
Have you heard about the confused memories
In psychology?
No, but I think you've heard
I read an article about
Our brain stores information
Tracers confused
The general idea is not
.. Accurate record of what happened
This is nonsense -
It is easy to convert it to the memory of the wrong -
I have seen my mother is trapped dog
For many times
My goodness, what have they done to you?
But this was before my father prevents us
From entering office
I feel sorry for you
Well, what is more likely?
You mispronounce remember the anniversary of 11 years?
Or the mirror that eat dogs?
"Look, that" the dog
Give it some time
Little time
Nothing happens
I can hear you talking with a
You know, you're crazy
I'm not crazy
I've heard you talk with someone
Hear did you say
I hear you through the door
! Did not recognize
I'm not crazy
You say that the water is contaminated
And that there is a thief?
! You you lose patience
I'm sorry because we Oikznak
Is Ti_ajeryn with dad
Because of the woman in the office?
You must remember that woman
I've seen you too
I have convinced myself
I saw many things
But what we're seeing really?
Mom screaming at Dad
In the middle of the night
Mom says she heard a voice
But probably my father on the phone
What about women
I have seen out of the window?
When Roitea?
The first time, and we play in the garden
Was safer at home?
Mother was always home
Are you sure about that?
I am not sure
Damn -
! Recessive! , Retrograde
've Been staying affair
It was a failed marriage, see how he ended
No
Our father was a traitor
This has made it safer to lose her senses
Stop -
Go haywire and kill her, and he'll kill us as well -
Really, a failed marriage
This explains how she lost her teeth
Her hair and her senses before you die
And yes, a failed marriage, this explains
People who saw them in the house
It was inclosed, discreet
All signs of an affair
I have looked at all their belongings, and while washing your brain
I did not find any evidence of any relationship
So intelligent that it does not leave impact
! Hist
I have spoken with friends and colleagues
If there was a woman are like a ghost
And yes, I agree with you, I've had inclosed and discreet
All signs of a relationship, Well
I'm not saying it has not been seduced though
Question Why seduced
There have been things
We bicker, you know?
Did you know that the temperature
Increased three degrees?
Three degrees
Two people in a tight space
Lights and Consumer Electronics
And probably phones no longer work
Did not materialize?
Well, let's look
Dial tone
Heat?
Kiley), you can overcome this)
I did it
You want save the family name?
You do not have to do for our parents
But you did it to yourself
I Dmarwk in that place, is not it?
I was very natural when I went
It was necessary to destroy you in order to graduate
! And (Mason), stop the dreaded Nbag
! You know! , You have finished
I want to help you to overcome this
But I will not stand
And let you dog Tazben
What do you do? -
Hear Nbaha -
! Stop, stop this
! No. No, wait
Why?
You do not know what to do -
Oh do not even know (Kylie), you're sick -
Did not happen anything
I said that it will happen
The plants are still alive, still mirror mirror
The only danger is you on the dog
This is not your fault
It also was not my fault
I've had the help of
And you're on your own
Difficult to overcome these difficulties
But it does not call for shame
They inherited in our family
Kiley), I'm sorry)
Listen ..
Let's get out of here
Let's go to another place
And continue talking about our lives
Where are we going?
... (Kylie)
Where?
Let's turn off the Alcamert
Dismantle those Anchor
Then we can go
Anywhere Tredenh
Maybe talk with your fiance
Would want to help
You know that
Kylie)?)
Here is
Here is a
! Yes
! Yes! . Yes
I was reviewing the tape
For the last three minutes
I've had a relationship, I've had a failed marriage "
Look at how he ended
Our father was a traitor
Safer than lose my senses
Go haywire and kill her -
Yes, a failed marriage -
This explains how she lost her teeth
Her hair and her senses before you die
And yes, a failed marriage, this explains
"People who saw them in the house
I do not remember doing this, remember?
Do not remember, and the heat may increase two degrees
Leading to the firing warning
Telephone
He began to move -
Telephone -
Which indicates that the dog
Born enough energy to succeed as bait
Contact your doctor
TEM), if you will take a call)
You did it outside the range of impact
Otherwise you will not know from talking with really
Hello
Hello, yes, everything is fine
I'm sorry about earlier
Speak to you after an hour
Possibility that it is really
Fifty percent
We left that room for a period of
I think that the dog was helpful
More than I thought
It seems that the extent of their impact
About 30 feet
This means that our kitchen
Laundry room, garage
The master bedroom and backyard
TEM)?)
! (Tim)
You can not complete the call
Please try again
(Tim)
How I came back to here?
What do you mean?
I walked here and I sat
I've been abroad -
No, were not -
Do you think you were?
Would you say this in front of the camera?
! Withering, withering
Because you're still here
I know we will win
Do you hear me?
Do you understand me?
When my father would return?
I do not know
Do not you know when he would return?
I do not know where he is
I know where he is going
(Kylie)
Tell me more about
Woman office
I have not seen
I've seen
Mute
When?
Last night
Were not in the office
Was on the stairs
What were you doing?
Did not see
I was scared
But I think it is returned to office
I think they live by
Go ye up to play
Mom?
! Illiterate
! Let him! , Mom
! No
! Do not turn around
! Faster, faster
! Mom, stop
Marie)?)
! Withering, withering
Dear?
You bleed
Go back to the room
But, do you mom ..? -
Omkma okay -
But just to come back inside
And shut the door, well, my dear?
Damn
Hello, there is an emergency for my wife
Please ..., mom -
Leverage the inside -
TEM)?)
! Ostvq of this
I'm here
Are you with me here?
(Tim)
Omkma very sick
You'll need to rest in bed for a period of
Even better, but
We do not want both of you nuisance
We?
So, O hero, O Princess
Both of you to stay away
For that room, you Tfhman?
What illness?
Now
You can both stay here
And play video games
I said that Znntek
We are not allowed to stay here?
Each
Come on, I need help
! (Tim)
Tim!) , Ostvq of this)
Is this to my mother?
Wonderful
Maybe we have to stay together
(I'm hungry, O (Kylie
You go to buy food, Dad
What did you say, my princess?
Food -
It is on my list -
TV does not work
What did you say, my princess?
! We brought a doctor to mom
It is on my list
This stupidity
'll Tell her that the food carried
But ... my father said -
I do not care what he said -
Mom?
They need a doctor
.. Has told me that she is sick, but it's not over -
! You know the problem, the problem is that you do not Overhearing -
I have commanded you not to go to her room
Not disobey my orders, why?
I've disobeyed my orders
So you punish
You and your brother were banned
From out of the house
Now, get out of here
Well, thank you
Good-bye
What the doctor said?
Mark that my father spoke to him
Like the previous doctor?
Exactly like the previous doctor
The same sound
Hello, Dad
I'm sorry to hear this, I hope it gets better -
Thanks Dad -
You know, I'm sorry
They brought you here
It makes use of her mother's illness
For misconduct
When you start driving
This would be nothing
Well, I'm sorry this regard
I hope to recover (Mary) recover quickly
Thank you
You know, my Felttsal Next Week
For Ntskaa together
Well! , Sahatvk
! See you later -
Goodbye -
.. (Tempo)
We will have to be
With the utmost courage
The ultimate IQ
! (Tim)
Kylie)?)
Here we had lost electricity
Something unexpected
This is not real
Dad?
Can you fit the lights?
Deceived nice
(Kylie)
Oh my god
Do you see it?
Hello?
I just check my your affairs
I see how things are going
I'm fine.
Well, I think I Saklmk hour after
Those trick
I did not kill him
I could not
Billy, it's not real
! I did not kill him because the vessel is not real
! (Michael)
What did you do?
No ..
Come on, we are out of here
Hello?
I need the police and ambulance
"Hathurn 2705"
Well, Well
Help on the way
Saotwa and explain all of this
! (Kylie)
! We're fine
(Michael), (Michael), (Michael)
When is the last time seized a temporary anchor? -
Do not -
The court plan
We do not have to do anything
All we have to do to stay here and wait
Not more than half an hour
! Button thy murder
Did you call Balnagdh? -
! Yes -
We have finished
We ended up
Will enable us to stay here
And watch this thing die
It is a trick to make us go back to the inside
Or this trick
To keep us there
! I have asked for help -
Order it again -
Police, what is the emergency? -
"Yes, I've just contacted," Hathurn 2705 -
You have to make your father related
The doctor will come tomorrow
What do we do?
We can not do anything
Just wait -
We see ourselves die -
We will have to be
Very brave
I've looked for a mirror
Then remove the gun
We'll have to destroy
It is not real
Znntna not play a Okhbertkma here
This is not true, okay?
Kylie)?)
Are you gone?
Never were not here
They only hurt us below
We have taken the right decision abroad
They are trying to keep us away
We have to go down
Before working Anchor
You can be sure that he went
He went
I promise
Look ..
We have to go down
They did not go -
I will open the door -
Do not -
.. I will open the door, if it were not gone -
We'll have to run down
What would you do? -
Do not worry in this regard, just run -
Ready?
I will open the door
I run down
You trust me, do not you?
For
OK
I love you
Directly to the bottom
This is not real
It is just a hoax
Ali will catch ya (Tempo)?
(Tempo)
TEM)?)
(Tim)
Mom, please Avoid Me
! Do not! , Does not
(Kylie)
Illiterate
(Come on, (Tim
! I run
! Mortuary
Will not allow us to
I think I Okhbertkma
Here not to play a
This is not you
It is I
I have met Xiatini
I have seen the devil
I need Alec -
That I -
! Pat
Run away
! Do not! , Does not
Dad
! (Kylie)
(Kylie)
Illiterate
TEM), (Tempo)?)
I want you to promise me
That when we are bigger and stronger
We will make it rightly
We should kill this thing
For parents
I promise
(Kylie), (Kylie)
! (Kylie)! , (Kylie)! , (Kylie)
! (Kylie), (Kylie)
Contact is made of? -
Yes, it is the call for help -
Then the result of this
Where Takhdhunni?
No. Were not my fault
It was a mirror -
(Tim) -
! Stop
! I did not
! I did not, it was a mirror
Please, you ratifications
! I did not -
! Mirror! - It was a mirror -
! Please
Do not forget, do not forget our promise
Do not forget
F: Sulong