Come on, Cameron.
- Is it Dad?
- No.
Come on. Let's cook.
What are we eating?
Spaghetti?
Or...
spaghetti?
Come on. Help me make the sauce.
Lindsey, what are you doing?
Answer the phone.
You can't ignore me, alright?
He's my kid too. I have...
Alright, look. I'm sorry, okay? Just...
just let me talk to him.
I didn't mean to hit him, okay?
It was an accident, alright?
I would never intentionally
hurt him like that. You know that.
Okay? And I've apologized.
What the hell do you want from me?
Honey?
- Everything okay in there?
- One second, Mom.
You okay?
Mom?
Mom!
What? What?
No!
Cameron?
Oh. Could be important.
- More important than right now?
- No.
- Can I help you?
- Yeah.
You could have answered your damn phone.
It's time to go, Henry.
- How do you know my name?
- You want me to call security?
No. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Who are you? What's this about?
Look at your watch. What's it say?
- 1:46.
- It's been 1:46 since you came in here.
My watch froze. So what?
I guarantee you every watch and clock
in this place says the exact same thing.
Alright, crazy guy. Security!
Time for you to go.
You know what this is?
It's something important to you.
It's to help you remember who you really are.
My brother gave me this
when I became partner.
That's right. You're a lawyer, Henry.
You work all the time.
You have no social life. You don't go out.
And to be painfully honest, women
don't even look in your general direction.
We're not in a nightclub.
You're not surrounded by beautiful women.
Wake up, buddy.
We're in your head.
It's time for you to go.
That's rude.
Whoa!
You gave them the power, Henry.
You can take it back.
He's just messing with you, babe.
That all you got?
- Looking for Maggie?
- Where is she?
She says she's so very sorry
about your little boy.
- Fuck you!
- Get him out of here.
- Better luck next time.
- Look out the window, Henry.
Something wrong, Henry?
- Come on.
- Oh...
- Don't look at them. Keep moving.
- I'm losing my mind. Losing my mind.
- Shit.
- What? What?
Come on, did you really think I was
gonna make it that easy for you?
- What's your favorite color?
- I don't have a favorite.
What color's your car? Your best suit?
Favorite sweater? Come on!
- What?
- I need to make an escape route,
- something true. Answer the question.
- Green.
- Where the fuck did that come from?
- Come on!
- What the hell is this?
- This is where we break down the illusion.
If you want to wake up from this, jump.
- Henry, open the door!
- Fuck that.
Open the door! Henry, let me in!
But, baby... But your eyes are black.
Baby, he slipped something into your drink.
Henry! Jump, now.
You won't get another chance.
- You can't make me do this.
- I can't make you do anything, Henry.
- You have to believe it will work.
- Open the door! Let me in!
Come on. Open the door! Let me in!
- You go first.
- If that would help, I would.
But you have to make the choice.
Come with me, Henry.
No!
Alright. Rise and shine, boss.
You did it. Another one bites the dust, huh?
Welcome back to reality.
How many fingers am I holding up?
Oliver, get your damn thumb out of my face.
Alright. You'll live.
Maggie wasn't there.
After 15 dives, we've lost her.
I know. But we'll get her.
She can't hide forever.
She's taunting me, Oliver.
It's a game to her.
You.
You were in my dream.
Wasn't a fucking dream.
This is gonna be the end of you.
You know that, right?
- We'll lower the dosage next time.
- Can't lower the dosage.
The problem is you, boss.
Come on. Look what the bouncer
did to your wrist.
Look, you're adapting.
It's becoming too real.
I'm telling you, if you don't watch it,
you're gonna get stuck in there.
You're not going soft on me, are you, Oliver?
I'm just saying... I don't know.
Take a month or two off.
Let your body recover, you know?
Maggie wasn't there.
Why wasn't she there?
Hey, I dug up all the places
our guy visited before the possession.
Aside from his office, he hung out
at Starbucks and low-rent strip clubs.
Okay. Let's check it out.
I'm gonna need surveillance tape
on the nights Henry visited.
I want to see who he's
hanging out with at those strip clubs.
I think I just heard Oliver volunteer.
Oh! You cannot pay me enough money. No.
Besides, I have a date with reality tonight.
Well, that sounds intriguing.
- What's her name?
- Sara.
- Wait a minute.
- What happened to Jenny?
Jenny? Jenny wanted to go skydiving, so...
You broke up with her
because she wanted to go skydiving?
Yeah. You know how I feel about high places.
- Hm.
- Oliver, have I taught you nothing?
Oh, my God. I almost forgot. There's someone
named Camilla that's here to see you.
She said she's from the Andrade Archdiocese.
The Vatican?
- Whoa. She's hot.
- Ugh!
So should I tell her to go away?
Tell her she's got five minutes.
I've been following your work
for quite some time.
I understand you've done
three exorcisms in the last six months.
I prefer to call them evictions. Yes.
- Why are you here?
- My superiors need an incarnate.
What happened to Felix Nazra?
They thought perhaps the student
has surpassed the teacher.
Or they just got sick
of the body counts you leave behind.
This situation needs a scalpel, not a hammer.
Please.
Camilla, right?
You're wasting your time.
It's not gonna happen.
I don't clock in for the Vatican.
- What do you have against the Church?
- How much time you got?
Look, I just don't believe what I do
belongs to any one religion.
- Exorcising demons?
- No, to you, it's a demon.
To others, it's an unclean spirit, it's jinn,
it's orisha. Take your pick, okay?
Really, it's just a parasitic entity
in a non-corporeal transference.
What if I told you a parasitic
entity just took a little boy?
I would say it ain't my problem.
What if I told you it was Maggie?
I thought that would get your attention.
Hmm...
Let me guess.
She's holed up in a half-dead body in a
whorehouse, just ready to be taken down.
You need an incarnate because the ring
of St Vicinius and a piece of holy cloth
- just won't cut it this time.
- I'm sorry.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- Then let me make it crystal-clear.
The last beautiful woman your superiors
sent here dangled the same carrot,
"We're sure it's Maggie."
Well, surprise, it wasn't,
just some lesser succubus who...
turned a suburban housewife
into a heroin-addicted throat-cutter
who nearly killed me and my assistants.
Look, I have no idea
about the last woman they sent.
What I do know is that I have
an archdemon possessing the body
of an innocent 11-year-old boy.
We believe that arch
is that entity you call Maggie.
So if you and your assistants
really want to take her out...
give me a call.
Just don't wait too long. The boy
won't survive more than three days.
- Ember.
- Is it her?
Why don't you come inside?
So this is what Vatican money buys?
Can I offer you anything?
I just need to know, Felix. Is it Maggie?
Uncertain.
The Church has excluded me from this one.
Why? Because they can't stomach
the murder of a child?
Or because they're afraid
they can't cover it up this time?
Ember, remember where you are.
And where's that?
With a friend.
Remember the first thing I taught you
about entering other people's minds?
Humans are easily blinded
by their needs and desires.
It would serve you well to remember that.
We each have our methods.
We each have our motives.
This conversation wouldn't have lasted
this long if you didn't know it was her.
You know it's her, don't you?
Yes.
But if you haven't spoken to the Church...
how do you know?
I want to show you something.
The door's glass is four inches thick.
A rhino couldn't crack it.
There are 12 cameras inside and out,
monitored 24 hours a day.
Fantastic. What is it?
I've found the light agitates it.
Is that a person? You got somebody
fucking locked up in there?
Remember the incarnate
who disappeared last year?
Luka Rejick.
Shit!
This hasn't been Luka Rejick
in a long time, I'm afraid.
- What are you doing with him?
- They know a lot about us.
Isn't it time we learned more about them?
Jesus!
Did you know they've been trying to
infiltrate our ranks for years? He told me.
He also told me about the boy,
about Maggie. That's how I know.
- What am I waiting for?
- Don't you want to know how to beat her?
You know, Ember, sometimes...
in order to avoid a fate worse than death,
you must choose death instead.
And thanks to Luka here,
I was able to develop this.
- What is it?
- C-79.
In this vial is a moment of clarity.
What are you talking about?
It's a serum made in part
from the blood of our friend here.
Should Maggie get the upper hand,
and I hope she doesn't,
this will give you approximately
10 seconds of lucidity
in order to do what needs to be done.
Inject this and you'll wake up
with just enough time
to end your life
before she traps you forever.
You seriously think I'm gonna use this?
Look, Felix... I appreciate
everything you taught me.
But keep your poison.
I'm not planning on dying.
Hello?
Alright, Camilla. Let's talk.
The boy's name is Cameron Sparrow.
His parents just recently divorced.
The mother is originally from Holland.
She has a restraining order
against the father, an alcoholic,
he broke the boy's arm.
Does Cameron have any history
of schizophrenia, delusion?
- Any meds I should know about?
- No. Nothing in his records.
The mother heard him scream in the kitchen.
And when she arrived...
she found this.
The boy broke her neck.
Of course, we sent in the best exorcists
to handle the situation, but...
they failed.
- How does it transfer?
- Physical contact.
Judging from its trail of victims,
it can only possess the weak,
kids, the elderly, sick people.
I haven't told the mother
about your connection with Maggie.
- Is the boy quarantined?
- No one has touched Cameron in a week.
- How's the mother's will?
- She's tired.
She's been through a lot.
We're keeping her away from the boy.
I've already answered
these questions a thousand times.
- Who are you?
- Mrs. Sparrow...
Just Lindsey, no Mrs.
- Lindsey, we brought Dr. Ember to help you.
- Another priest. Great.
No, he's not a priest. He's like a therapist.
I'm not here to treat your son
for mental illness.
- Then why are you here?
- I'm here to evaluate whether or not...
Dr. Ember has employed a cutting-edge
method for helping his patients.
He can go places we can't, get information
that'd otherwise be unavailable to us.
- You're here to perform an exorcism, right?
- Let's get this straight off the bat.
I don't do exorcisms. I don't use
religious methods to treat the symptoms.
I go inside the victim's mind
to treat the disease.
I don't compel these entities
from the outside. I evict them...
- from the inside.
- You evict them?
The entity that is holding your son
has no real power. It's a parasite.
It feeds off your son's energy.
But in order to do that,
it has to hold him in a dream state.
Even if his eyes are open and he's speaking,
your son is asleep,
the entity is controlling him.
In order to keep that control,
it has to convince him his dream is real.
It's holding Cameron by...
convincing him he's in another reality?
Yes.
Through suggestion.
It rifles through his mind
and shows him what he wants most,
but it's all a lie.
I tear down the lies.
Once Cameron sees the truth,
the entity loses its power.
What happens to the entity?
It'll try to jump
into the nearest living host.
If it can't find a host, it dies.
And you've done this before?
Strap her down. Strap her down!
Oh, God.
Okay.
Hello, Father.
- The boy hasn't eaten in days.
- Why don't you take a break?
You look like you need some rest.
He's okay.
It might be best
if you waited in the living room.
- But I want to see him.
- I know. I know. But...
You have to trust us.
He'll be fine. It's gonna be okay.
This is just an evaluation.
If I can't confirm this is Maggie,
I'm outta here.
Hello, Dr. Ember.
You know who I am?
How does it feel?
How does what feel?
To lose the one you love.
Okay.
We've established that you know who I am.
Who are you?
I've been known as Ash.
Others have called me Plague.
After the Great Deluge,
when the angels took the mortal woman,
I was Desire.
Is this fun for you?
Holy water, crucifixes
and idle threats get so...
dull.
What do you want?
You're gonna have to try harder than that.
No. I don't have time for this.
Good!
Ah.
So you do remember.
Hey. Hey, hey.
Hey, where are you going? What about the boy?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Wait.
Is it her?
- I know what happened to your family.
- Don't you ever mention my family.
But if this is an archdemon,
the Church needs to know.
A lot of lives could be in jeopardy.
Then move out of my way
so I can get my team in here.
Then I'd lock that door, if I were you.
I'm coming for you.
The Church is pleased
that you have come to help.
Helping? I'm hunting.
Excuse me, but is this necessary?
Why can I not be in the same room as my son?
When the shit hits the fan, I'm gonna
need everybody in here out of my hair.
- It's safer that way, believe me.
- You should see an image.
Oh, Cameron.
What is all this stuff?
Um... this is what we use to monitor
Dr. Ember during dives.
See, each of us is like a wi-fi hot spot,
and our brains give off
an invisible field of energy.
You see this cloud right here?
Some people call this an aura or a soul,
but really what it is
is just a cluster of unique ions,
and each of us has our own frequency.
So this is Dr. Ember's and this is Cameron's.
You see the black streaks in Cameron's?
That's the parasite.
If a victim is weak, it can hook
right into their frequency.
Oh, God.
So we just use this
to monitor it until we can evict it.
What's all that for?
Uh, this is gonna lower his heart rate
and EEG to a stasis state,
leaving the brain as close to death
as physically possible.
When I hit REM, I'll ride into Cameron's
subconscious, begin dismantling the illusion.
The trick is I only have eight minutes
before my heart gives out,
which isn't a lot of time.
Sometimes we get lucky.
It's as easy as the glitch.
- The glitch?
- The time glitch.
We've discovered that time
is meaningless in the subconscious,
so watches, clocks, anything that tells time,
freezes at the time
of the victim's possession.
It'll be okay.
I'm gonna help your son.
Okay, boss. You're good to go.
Keep this area clear in case he tries
to jump. You know the drill.
Don't let the boy touch you or anyone else.
Don't let me touch you or anyone else.
Oliver, I get anywhere near flatlining,
you yank my ass out with the Narcan.
Yeah. I've got the escape hatch
right here, boss.
Only if you absolutely have to.
Dr. Ember.
Good luck in there.
Thank you.
Dr. Ember. So nice of you to join us.
Starting the clock, boss.
Are you ready, Dr. Ember?
Then let the games begin.
Nice, Cameron. Keep it going.
Fastball next, buddy.
Over the plate. Nice!
Nice catch.
Beautiful.
How is he?
Seven minutes to go. So far, so good.
Cameron.
Cameron. Listen, I know you don't know me.
But I'm here to help you.
I just want to talk.
What's wrong?
You're... you're bleeding.
- What?
- Help! We need help over here.
- Oh, no.
- Cameron.
Cameron, come with me, buddy. Come on.
- Wait. Cameron.
- It's okay. You'll be okay.
Sir, I need to lay you down.
No, no, no, no, no. Lie down. Lie down.
You need to lie down. This is serious.
No, no. Hold on.
Oh, crap!
- He's gonna flatline.
- Uh, there's a man bleeding.
I'm in the south-east section
of Douglas Park.
Get away from me. This isn't happening.
You have to calm down.
I'm not sure what's wrong.
Sir. I think I've found your problem.
I'm sorry, boss.
Your EKGs were off the chart,
okay, so we had to pull you out.
- Well, I'm not gonna say I told you so.
- Yeah, well, you just did. Alright, boss.
Let's get you to the hospital,
get you checked out, okay?
- I'm fine, Oliver.
- You're fine?
What the hell happened in there?
It was only a few minutes, Oliver.
A couple of minutes?
Boss, your heart stopped.
Where are you going?
Dan used to play in the park
with Cameron, before he lost his job.
The entity is playing into Cameron's desire.
His desire? That man has never said
"I love you" once to that boy.
Cameron doesn't want anything
to do with his father, believe me.
Maybe you don't want that, but I'm
telling you, Dan was in the park with him.
She's giving him what he wants.
We need to break down her illusion.
It's the only way to free the boy.
- Where's his father?
- He's probably getting drunk.
- We need to bring him here.
- That man is not coming anywhere near my son.
- Listen...
- He broke Cameron's arm!
This entity is strong. Probably
the strongest I've ever encountered.
To get your son back, I'm gonna
need all the ammunition I can get.
- No. It's not gonna happen. I'm sorry.
- Damn it, listen to me! I am too close.
I have come too far.
So you either work with me
or you lose your son.
Ms. Sparrow, just please tell us
where to find him.
There's a bar on 20th and Scarborough.
That's where he usually goes.
Thank you.
Hey!
I'm in a wheelchair.
I can see you're not a fan
of self-preservation.
- Yeah, not much left to preserve.
- Is that self-pity I hear?
No. That's freedom, baby. Freedom.
Focus on the important shit.
Mmm. Found him.
Mr. Sparrow.
Your son's in trouble.
I need you to come with me.
- What are you, another lawyer?
- Do I look like a lawyer?
Your son is in trouble.
Yeah, well...
I need another beer,
so unless you're buying...
You're so funny.
You want me to break your arm, huh?
I don't know what they told you,
but I never touched him.
I don't give a shit.
I said your son's in trouble...
because of you.
Dr. Ember!
Ember, stop!
- Why didn't you call me?
- You're here, aren't you?
Jesus Christ, Lindsey! How long
were you gonna keep this from me?
- Why would I tell you anything?
- Because he's my son!
If we're done flirting here?
- Cameron needs us.
- Dan. You need to go with Dr. Ember now.
Show me where my son is.
With pleasure.
Call him by his name. Remind him
you're in the room. Tell him you love him.
Talk about details that only you
and he would know about.
Okay? He'll hear you. He'll wake up.
- You sure this is gonna work?
- No. I'm not.
- Then why should I do this?
- I would. If it were my son.
Like I said before,
I don't know what they told you, okay,
but I never touched him, okay, ever.
- I never touched him.
- Save it for Cameron.
Alright, we have your back,
if something goes wrong,
you get a bad feeling, we'll get you out.
Like what? What's gonna happen?
Like green vomit?
Are you talking about the whole
head-turning thing? Come on!
- No matter what, don't touch him.
- Come on.
Dan, I mean it.
No physical contact. Do you understand me?
Yeah, I won't... I won't touch him.
Let's go.
Hey, Cam.
It's me. It's Dad.
It's been a while, buddy. I haven't...
Haven't seen you, like, forever.
You know, I tried calling a few times.
I guess my messages weren't getting through.
I remember you had that sick curve ball.
Just me and you down at the park.
You were good, man.
You should try out for the team.
Cameron.
It's Dad.
Slow and easy.
It's working. Cameron's surfacing.
- Dad?
- Yeah, buddy, it's me. It's Dad.
Cameron, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry I hurt you.
You've gotta believe me. It was an accident.
If I could take it back, I'd take it back.
- What do we got?
- There's a lot of movement.
Yeah, it's bouncing around
all over the place.
What happened to you, Cameron?
How did this happen?
I forgive you.
What? I can't... I can't hear you,
buddy. Say it... say it again.
I forgive you, Dad.
You do?
Yeah. I want it to be like it was.
- Can it be like before?
- Yeah. It can be like before. Promise.
I'm gonna clean up. Okay?
I'll do anything for you.
Can we go to the park again?
We can go to the park.
We can go to a carnival.
You want to go on the rides?
- We can do all that.
- Really?
Really. Just as soon as you're better, okay?
I love you, Dad.
Cam...
- Oh, my God!
- No, stay back! Don't touch him!
- Oh, God!
- God is not here.
Stop! Don't do this. It's me you want.
Please follow me. Our people are downstairs.
Why did you say, "It's me you want"?
There's something you're not telling me.
You're not here to help Cameron.
You're here for some other reason.
- Doesn't matter why I'm here.
- Dan is dead!
What the hell is going on here?
Talk to me or get the hell out!
When I was 26...
I discovered that when I was asleep...
I could go into the minds of the possessed.
When I found out there were others like me...
and how their lives
had been turned upside-down...
I kept my abilities hidden.
I just wanted a normal life.
And that's what I had.
No.
She was possessed?
Her name was Maggie Grant.
She was possessed
by the same entity that's in Cameron.
She sensed my ability.
She killed my wife...
and my 11-year-old boy.
After that...
there's no turning back.
Since then, I've used every ability I have...
to try to find her and kill her.
You're not here to help my son.
No. I'm not.
In all these years,
why hasn't she just killed you?
There are fates worse than death.
I was afraid of this.
She's feeding!
What's happening?
Maggie's feeding.
She's consuming Cameron's energy.
We need to move fast.
Boss! Boss!
The kid's got maybe two hours max.
What's the call?
Don't let anyone near him.
Do whatever it takes to keep him alive.
- Where are you going?
- To get the edge I need to end this.
Keep it running.
Felix!
Hello? Felix?
Felix?
Felix, you here?
Felix!
Felix! Felix.
It's Ember.
- What happened?
- I was harvesting more blood.
He broke through the straitjacket and bolted.
- Where are you hurt?
- It's not my blood. I cut him.
Ember, we gotta get out of here.
I think he's still here.
Alright. Let's move.
Whoops.
Felix...
No.
- Stay back.
- Or what?
- What are you waiting for?
- Ember, if only you...
Felix? Felix.
- Maggie wants you for herself.
- No, Felix.
- She's gonna consume you.
- Felix!
- Pray you die so easily.
- Felix! No!
Where have you been?
- I had to get something. How is he?
- He's stable.
- He hasn't moved since you left.
- Alright, let's go.
Where do you think you're going?
- I'm going back in.
- No, you're not.
I need to talk to you.
Look, I don't know where you went,
but you're not gonna go back in,
I'm calling in my people.
If you were gonna call in your people
to contain this you'd have done it.
What happens when this entity's done
with the kid and decides to jump?
- She's not gonna jump.
- Why not?
Because it's me she wants. I'm sport to her.
Which is why I'm your best shot right now.
I need a physical item of Cameron's.
Something special to him.
Why?
We need to find a truth
that she can't distort...
intimate truth that he won't question.
It's our only chance
of shattering his illusion,
pulling him out.
This ring, you know where it is?
Cameron used to keep this by his bed.
And when we left, I took it away.
I wanted as few traces
of his father as possible.
I can't think of anything...
Cameron treasured more than this...
stupid ring.
You can tell me to shut up
any time you want, but, uh...
I think Cameron loves his father, but...
I mean, that doesn't mean
he doesn't love you.
I mean, Cameron might not know
how to say it, but...
I mean, you're his rock.
You're his entire world.
He needs you now more than ever.
Lindsey...
I need you...
to be strong.
We're getting close.
She shouldn't have killed Dan.
Maggie's getting sloppy
and we will use that against her.
I'm gonna get your son back.
I thought you didn't care.
Yeah, well...
I lied.
Here.
You sure about this?
If I get the boy out and I'm still down,
you get that into my IV.
If it works, it'll buy me just enough time.
Enough time for what?
Enough time to get the job done.
Whatever you say, boss.
- Oliver, you got the Narcan?
- Yeah.
Right here. Ready to go.
Let me see it.
Won't be needing this anymore.
I hope you said your goodbyes.
Because you won't be coming back.
Maybe.
But neither will you.
Sir?
Are you gonna take your ticket or not?
Alright. Here we go.
Cam, look at that. That looks good, man.
Hey, Cameron. How about some cotton candy?
Oh! Jesus, I will never get used to that.
You're telling me.
Cameron!
- Dad, it's the guy from the park.
- No worries.
Cameron, I'm here to help you.
Why don't you back off
before someone gets hurt?
This is not your father, Cameron.
This is not real.
- What are you talking about?
- I know it's confusing.
- You're just gonna have to trust me.
- Dad!
Get away from my son.
You know what, this is gonna
end badly for you, man.
Cameron, don't be afraid.
Do you remember this ring?
You used to sleep with it, remember?
- Dad?
- It's not your dad, Cameron.
It looks like your dad,
saying everything you want to hear.
- But it's not your father.
- Give me the ring, Cameron.
You know what, you're a frickin' psycho.
You stay away from my son.
You know I'd never hurt you, son. Okay?
I love you, Cameron.
Cameron?
Your father could never say he loved you.
You ever heard him say those words?
Don't listen to him, Cam. Okay?
Hey. I said get out of here.
You know your dad better than anyone.
This is not your dad.
Don't listen to him, Cameron.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
What's wrong, Cam?
Dad?
What's wrong, buddy?
Why you looking at me like that?
It's not your dad, Cameron.
- This guy's done something to you, Cam.
- Stay away from me.
I would never hurt you. Ever.
You're not my dad.
Cameron, stop!
He's coming up on four minutes.
Cameron!
- Stay away from me!
- Cameron! Cameron, trust me.
- I'm not gonna hurt you, okay?
- What's happening?
Cameron!
Come on!
Come back, Cameron! Come back!
Come on. We gotta keep moving.
Don't trust him! He's a bad man!
He wants to hurt you.
- Cameron!
- Cameron. Shh! It's okay.
- What's wrong with me?
- There's nothing wrong with you.
- This isn't real.
- It feels real.
That's because you believe it.
Stop believing it
and I promise you it'll go away.
You can make all of this disappear.
I just need you to listen to me
right now. Can you do that?
- O... okay.
- Okay. Do you have a favorite color?
- Blue.
- Oh, that's good. Mine too.
You see that blue door?
It's your world, Cameron.
You can control everything in it.
It's your way out. Hurry.
Your mom's waiting for you.
Go ahead. It's gonna be okay.
Now you're in trouble, Cameron.
Go through the door, Cameron, now!
You won't get another chance.
- He's got less than a minute.
- He's cutting it too close.
Oh, come on, boss.
Go through the door! Go through the door!
I'm done with the boy.
I'm going after the bitch that spawned him.
- There's only one place you're going.
- Yeah. And I'm taking you with me.
You remember this?
You remember? My wife was
wearing this the night you killed her.
I want you to wear it now.
10 seconds.
Cameron!
No!
Cameron! You did it!
- Cameron?
- Mom.
Oh... thank you.
Thank you.
Hey, boss.
- How many fingers am I holding up?
- Get your thumb out of my face.
- You're gonna be just fine, boss.
- Can we take a vacation now?
Dad? Can you hear me?
Is it you, Dad?
Dad? Dad?
Dad!
Mom! Dad's awake.
- Hey.
- Where am I? Anna?
Can you hear us?
- What happened?
- We were in a car accident.
- The car went off the road.
- A woman hit us.
No, no, honey. You swerved around a jogger.
You don't remember.
You had a concussion. The doctor
said that you might be disoriented.
You were in a coma for three days.
- How you doing, buddy?
- Good.
Yeah?
Felt so real.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Honey, this way.
Hey, Dad. So you up for some
one-on-one when we get home?
No basketball for him, honey.
He needs to rest.
Then can we play on the Wii?
I'd like that, Jake.
I love you.
Honey, what's wrong?
Dad, what is it?
What's wrong?
No.
You're not real.
- Seth. Seth, don't say that.
- I love you both.
- You're not real.
- Dad!
- Seth, come back!
Going somewhere?
Maggie.
Oh, shit!
- No!
- Maggie!
Why don't you just kill me?
Because I want you to hurt, Seth.
I want you to know pain.
You're gonna burn, Seth.
Think! Think! Think!
Oh, my God!
Let him go.
I'll stop fighting.
You can have me.
Release him or I'll jump.
- Open the door!
- Open the door, Cameron!
Cameron! Cameron, buddy,
we need you to open the door.
- Cameron, we need you to open this door.
- Cameron!
Can you hear me, buddy? Can you hear me?
Just come open the door.
No, Oliver!
Boss?
It's injected!
Boss...
Boss?
No!
You end now, bitch!
No! No! Don't touch him! Don't touch him!
Let's move!
Here we go. The guy's in shock. Clear!
Here we go. Clear!
Come on, Ember, fight.
Here we go again. Clear.
- I'm sorry.
- No, no, just one more time.
- Ma'am.
- Now!
Clear, all clear. Clear!
Oh, my God. We've got a pulse.
We've got a rhythm!
Alright. Let's get another bag here.
What's our ETA?
We're losing him!
Guy's in shock. Clear!