[wind howling]
[rattling]
["Paper Rosie" playing on jukebox]
You want to have yourself a beer
or something while you're waiting there?
♪ Silver hair ♪
♪ That's lost its gold ♪
♪ Trembling hand
As she passed the rose ♪
[bartender] You hear me, mister?
♪ Red crepe paper ♪
I'll take the bottle.
♪ Help a little old lady ♪
♪ Buy a rose today ♪
♪ I took the rose... ♪
[bartender] Howdy, boys.
What can I do for you?
- Brewskis.
- Brewskis. You got it.
There you go.
♪ ...I could smell the rose ♪
♪ It came alive ♪
♪ And I heard her say ♪
♪ Buy my roses ♪
♪ Pretty roses ♪
♪ They're only made of paper ♪
♪ But they only cost a dime ♪
[laughs]
Hey.
[country music playing on jukebox]
Fifty now, 50 more when you're done.
- How many?
- Just one.
What is he, another cop?
No. Matter of fact,
he's a friend of yours.
You're going to like this job.
He was in my brother's gang.
First, he dropped a dime on him...
then he ratted him to the cop
that blew him away.
Hey.
I'm gonna go on in and take a look.
- Want a Coke?
- Yeah, Diet.
[male officer] We're on the Simmons Road
about 15 miles west off of Route 14.
I need wants and warrants
on motorcycle registrations.
- [dispatcher] Roger. I copy.
- First one, California.
6-David-8-4-Sam-Niner.
Roger. Copy that.
Second plate...
Tom.
How you doing? Nice to see you.
Willie Hickok. Right here.
Cherry Ganz, Officer.
Do I know you guys?
[dispatcher] Repeat, code 6-Charles.
[man] Who you calling, friend?
Nobody. I wasn't calling nobody.
[hammer cocks]
Somehow I don't believe you.
Oh, God! Oh, no!
[gunshot]
[man with briefcase] $100,000.
50,000 now. Ice Man's a generous guy.
I don't like hundreds.
I told you that before.
What kind of shit is this?
Well, this is the guy.
The balance is due when he's dusted.
You understand what I'm talking about?
We want him dead.
Yeah, whatever. No problem.
Police! Freeze!
You, move a step apart.
I don't want anybody to get hurt here,
so move slow.
[man screaming]
[man 2] Watch it!
Shit!
Get back! Get the hell out of here!
[sirens approaching]
[coughing]
[police radio chatter]
[helicopter whirring]
Christ, you really toasted that guy.
God damn it, I didn't toast the guy.
I just shot him, for Christ sake.
Don't say I toasted him, Ben.
Calm down. We'll find the gun.
We've just got to do this together.
Get our stories straight.
Checked the guy's locker.
Seems okay. He works here at the track.
Fifty bucks in his wallet,
a pair of sunglasses,
some keys, probably car or apartment.
- We still haven't found his gun, yet.
- Ah, shit.
Cates took down one of the locals.
A slug hit one of the gas pumps
and burned the bad guy to a crisp.
Now, Jack claims
it was a righteous shooting.
Man, I hate these IAD scumbags.
Blake Wilson, Internal Affairs.
Seems like
I'm always running into you, Jack.
Give us a minute, fellas.
What did you do now, Jack?
I was on a stakeout.
I was getting real close
to nailing these...
- Close? Oh, the Ice Man, right?
- Yeah, God damn it. The Ice Man.
I tell you, I'm getting real close.
I'm gonna nail these guys.
For years you've been trying to pin
every case you can't solve on the Ice Man.
He's the biggest drug dealer
in the Bay Area, right, Jack?
Except we don't have any prints,
we don't have a description.
You're the only cop on the force
who believes this guy exists.
I'll let you in on a little secret.
There is no Ice Man.
So let's get back to the cold facts
of this because this is real.
- Now, what the hell happened here?
- I saw an exchange. Probable cause.
I moved in. He had a piece.
He shot. I shot back.
You got the bad guy's gun?
It's got to be in there
with the ashes and shit.
I didn't touch anything.
Cruise, what do you got?
Nothing much. Just some burnt metal.
Must be off the pump.
- No gun?
- No, no gun.
Look, a cop is a guy,
and a guy sometimes steps on his dick.
You think maybe today
you were pushing a little too hard,
trying to make something work,
and you stepped on your dick?
Work with me here. We're on the same side.
- Did you step on your...
- Now, wait a minute.
God damn it, it didn't go down that way.
He had a piece. He shot. I shot back.
Kehoe, I want the lab boys to go over
every inch of this place.
If there's a gun here, I want it.
A bullet. Something. Anything.
- See you around, Jack.
- Yeah.
- [lock clicks]
- [door opens]
Reggie Hammond.
[ball bouncing]
You must be a real dangerous convict.
You made me miss, cop.
You look good, Reggie.
I ain't seen you in years, man.
I thought you was my friend.
Well, I'm sorry. I've been busy.
Yeah, me, too.
You must be pretty desperate
to come down here, man.
You even got a new haircut.
What's going on?
Well, times change.
- Well, you lost a couple of pounds.
- Quit drinking.
So, what, the warden pick you to come
in here and tell me
my sentence got yanked up
another five years or something?
Oh, relax.
You're still getting out tomorrow.
But when you do,
you and me's got another little job to do.
Man, you and me don't have shit to do.
When I get out of here,
just give me my fucking money
and walk away from me, all right?
'Cause I played that cop shit once
and it don't work.
Have my money when I get out, please.
Now, wait a minute, Reggie.
You don't get it.
You see, if you don't help me out
on this one,
I'm not ever gonna give you
your money back.
- You're fucking with me, right?
- No.
Hey, Jack,
I gave you that money in good faith.
'Cause you told me
I could fucking trust you.
Now, you're gonna tell me after all
this shit, I can't have my money?
[chuckles]
Yeah, now you got the picture, convict.
[laughs]
You screwed up real good
this time, Hammond.
- It was self-defense.
- Nobody's gonna buy that crap!
Hey, wait a minute, man!
I served two years for a crime I did
and I never fucking denied that.
But I've just spent five years in here
for some shit that was bullshit!
I never robbed no damn payroll.
You people got murderers in here
been here less time than me.
You can spend your remaining time
in isolation.
Open up.
[singing off-key] ♪ Roxanne ♪
♪ You don't have to put on the red light ♪
♪ Those days are over ♪
♪ You don't have to sell your body
To the night ♪
♪ Roxanne ♪
[rock music playing]
♪ I climbed to the top of24 stairs ♪
♪ Before I fell down 22 ♪
Tequila.
The bottle.
♪ I fell across a table ♪
♪ I picked it up
And tossed it off the roof... ♪
- [server] You guys want anything?
- Whiskey.
- [server] And?
- Put it in a glass.
Mr. Price, the Man is distressed.
That mess you made in the desert
has him wondering
if your boys are gonna be around
to finish the job.
Not to worry.
Real pros, huh?
Not from where I'm sitting.
Pros don't make messes like you did.
Don't get the heat all jacked up
when you're supposed to be doing a job.
You want to be an outlaw,
but you want to play by rules.
There ain't no rules.
- Oh, you giving me your philosophy?
- That's right, bro.
We're the only real Americans left.
We believe in freedom.
We live the way folks used to,
back before there were big cities,
and lawyers,
and computers with your names in them.
Free.
The rest of you are just a bunch
of fucking slaves.
Yeah? Well, that sounds
real interesting, Mr. Price.
Maybe you should run for office.
All I'm supposed to do
is to tell you to take precautions.
We tried to get you some backup,
but he got barbecued at a race track.
You know what to do with that stuff?
No problem here, friend.
- I used to be a Marine.
- I guess that figures.
You guys have any trouble, you come to me.
You know the number.
Hey. Hey, come here.
[chuckles]
[whispers, indistinct]
I think you got the wrong girl.
I don't do that.
Come on.
My friend and I just came into town.
We're looking for a whore that works here.
- Oh, yeah? What's her name?
- Name's Angel.
Angel don't work here anymore.
She's dancing up in North Beach.
Well, you're here. How about you?
I'm getting tired of this. Let go!
- Otherwise, I'm gonna call the cops.
- Go ahead, sweet cheeks.
- [hammer cocks]
- Call 'em.
[Mr. Price]
Hey, let's hit the road, boys. Come on.
Come on, Cherry.
In the matter of
the officer-involved shooting
at Hunters Point raceway
of the suspect Arthur Brock,
a resident of San Francisco,
the review board has carefully examined
the physical evidence
and the testimony of the witnesses,
and has determined
that the officer in question,
Inspector Jack Cates,
had insufficient probable cause.
Based on a review of
the officer's case history
and an ongoing investigation
by the Internal Affairs Division,
this review board cannot help but rule
that the shooting was a wrongful action.
I never thought
they'd land on you so hard.
I swear...
I'm gonna have to recommend
to the District Attorney
that he prosecute you for manslaughter.
Sure as hell wish they'd found that gun.
Well, I'm sorry, Jack.
I'm just doing my job.
Right.
Wilson's got a personality profile
of an obsessed cop,
whose record shows his history
of stepping over the line, okay?
It's quite likely the DA will choose
to prosecute you on third-degree.
In other words, you're screwed.
Unless I find the Ice Man.
Oh, come on, Jack. Give it up.
That's what got you into this.
Jesus Christ, Ben. You sound like Wilson.
We're talking about the facts here.
You got no leads.
The department's got no leads.
This is manslaughter.
Protect yourself.
[guard]
Hammond, let's go. Big day for you today.
- Just get me the hell out of here, man.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. Come on.
[man] Reggie.
Come here.
Excuse me a minute.
You will keep your promise, right?
Everything is... Don't worry,
everything is cool. It's no problem.
That white cop that came
to see you yesterday?
Now, he ain't no problem, is he?
[Reggie] Oh, no.
No, no, no. He ain't gonna fuck that up.
I promise you everything is cool,
but it might take a little bit longer
than I said it was gonna take.
Don't bullshit me, man.
You get that money and you keep your word.
I kept you alive in this funky rat hole
for five years,
so don't act like
everything is everything.
I can get you out there, Reggie.
I can reach out of here
and pull your fucking heart out!
What was all that going on back there?
- Just talking about an old football bet.
- That's a crock.
Hammond, Reggie A.
I came by to give you $100 in cash
and a free bus ride to San Francisco,
all compliments
of the State of California.
- And that's it?
- That is it.
Thank you for sparing me the other crap.
Hey, man, you ain't got to slam
my shit down like that.
Yo, where's my James Brown tape?
The shit ain't in...
Oh.
Everybody trying to keep
me and James in prison.
Hey, we didn't get to finish
our conversation.
Hey, man, stay the fuck away from me
till you get my money, all right?
I told you yesterday, convict,
you're not getting your money
unless you help me.
Look, man, I trusted you with my money
and my car, and you fucked me.
I thought you were straight.
What the fuck's going on?
I've been chasing a drug dealer
called the Ice Man
for the last four years.
Now, last week, I find out
this Ice Man wants you dead.
Here, take a look at this.
I got this off of some guy
paying someone to make a hit on you.
You recognize this guy? Huh?
Now, in four years, Reggie,
that makes you the best lead I ever had.
Yeah? Well, helping you out
while you got my money
is something I don't want to do!
Let me rot in a fucking prison
for five years and you show up
wanting some help.
That's bullshit.
That's worse than bullshit.
That's dumb, man!
Reggie, this time, I promise you
it's gonna be different.
Now, look, I'm gonna lose my badge.
They're gonna put me in jail.
Oh, you're in trouble with the law
this time?
Good! Good!
As bad as I feel
about you keeping my money,
that shit almost makes me feel better.
Now I'm sure I don't want to go with you!
Now, wait a minute, God damn it.
I don't beg!
What you gonna do, whip my ass?
You gonna shoot me out here
in front of the prison?
That's not a very good way
to treat the best lead you ever had.
Don't worry. I'll come visit you
in about five or six years.
- Hey, man, let's get the hell out of here.
- Hey, we got a schedule.
Hey, fuck that, man. I'm a free man now.
I'm not on the state's time no more.
Write a letter.
Everybody around
this motherfucker's crazy.
Big fucker in the blue Caddy.
That's the pig who wasted my brother.
This is great, man. I get 'em both.
[car honks]
["Drinking Them Beers" playing on jukebox]
♪ Last night ♪
♪ I had a little talk with myself ♪
♪ Just me and me, man to man ♪
♪ I said, self, I think it's time ♪
♪ I laid it on the line ♪
♪ And I tried my best
To make me understand ♪
♪ Drinking them beers ♪
♪ Shedding them tears ♪
♪ Over a love that's gone cold ♪
♪ Was wasting time ♪
♪ Yours and mine ♪
[music stops]
[no audible dialogue]
[gunshots]
[Reggie singing off-key]
♪ You don't know ♪
[imitating James Brown]
♪ What you do to me ♪
♪ Get me down ♪
♪ Hey, in misery ♪
♪ Ah, yes, sir, well ♪
♪ Ah, yes, sir ♪
[screams]
♪ Hit me, all right ♪
[screaming, vocalizing]
♪ Wanna kiss myself
Good God ♪
♪ And I got the feeling
Hey ♪
[vocalizing]
♪ Baby, baby, baby ♪
♪ Baby, baby, baby
Baby, baby, baby ♪
♪ Baby, baby... ♪
[screams]
♪ Want to get on the good foot ♪
♪ Good God ♪
♪ September, when the good checks come ♪
[screams]
♪ Baby, baby, baby
Baby, baby, baby ♪
♪ Baby, baby... ♪
[Cherry] Yeah!
Get down!
[men shouting, indistinct]
Yeah!
Heading west on US Highway 50.
Get some help out here right now!
I need some help, now! [grunts]
Shit!
[truck horn blaring]
[tires screech]
Let's go.
[groaning]
[gunshots]
[sirens approaching]
Come on!
[female doctor] You got
a hairline fracture of your left clavicle.
[Jack] Right.
- Blunt trauma broke the skin.
- Right.
You're lucky.
You always wear a bulletproof vest?
Only when I see my friends.
Look, I want you to change the bandage
on your chest
- every hour, hour and a half.
- All right.
And I have to immobilize this arm,
so wear this sling.
All right. Thanks, Doc.
Wait. Where are you going?
I still have to wait for your lab reports.
I've got police business.
[Reggie] Hey, man, look,
I said I was minding my own business,
then those bikers came along
and started shooting at the bus.
X-rays are fine, Mr. Hammond.
Well, how come my head is still hurting?
Look, buddy,
you had a bus roll over on you.
Nobody said it wasn't gonna hurt.
Look, you might have a slight concussion
or a subdural hematoma.
Either way, you're one lucky man.
We're gonna hold you overnight.
We'll know more in the morning.
No, y'all ain't holding me overnight
no place.
Me and my subdural hematoma
are going home.
I ain't spending my first free day out
in no fucking hospital.
Now, you're gonna be here till you
answer all our questions.
Are you sure you never saw
those bikers before?
Look, man, all you rednecks
look the same to me, all right?
Keep on him, Art. I'll be right back.
Oh, great. I gotta spend my first day out
with Art, the goddamn redneck.
Coming out of the kitchen, with my arms
full of this guy's breakfast, you know.
And I'm worried 'cause I don't want to be
late, you know, 'cause he looks funny.
Not like just he's hungry,
but like he's mad at something.
And then, the next thing I know,
there's these big gunshots,
and the window's breaking, and...
Reggie Hammond. When can I see him?
[officer]
If it was up to me, I'd help you out.
They're gonna keep him overnight.
You know, observation.
Hey, that's one lucky guy.
I'd like to follow him
around the racetrack.
You know what I mean?
You know what that guy
was in the joint for?
No.
That son of a bitch is a child molester.
He's involved in kiddie porn.
Now, I got to get him back
to San Francisco by tonight,
so that he can identify the kingpin
of the organization.
If I don't get him back there by tonight,
the goddamn kingpin walks.
Hey, Reggie.
You want to go for a ride in a Cadillac?
Oh, Jesus Christ. Look, man,
I've been having a fucked-up day,
and the last thing
I wanted to see was you.
Come on, Reggie,
I'm just trying to help you out.
Of course, you could always catch a bus.
You had a lot of luck on the last one.
Look, just do me a favor, Jack,
and just disappear.
Stay away from me, all right?
I'm sorry, Reg.
They released you in my custody.
[typing]
[woman speaking
on hospital PA, indistinct]
Let's get down to business.
You ever seen those bikers before?
Jack, my memory gets a lot better
when I got money in my pocket.
You know the rules, Reggie.
Soon as you tell me
why the Ice Man wants you dead,
I'll think about giving your money back.
Why don't you ask that guy
who you got my picture off of?
[Jack] He's not talking real good anymore.
I killed him.
Very smooth, Jack.
What, they paying you by the pound now?
[Jack] Well, he shot at me first,
only we can't find his gun.
That's why I'm in the shitter.
Hey, Jack, if you're looking for sympathy,
you've come to the wrong person, okay?
I'm supposed to be on my way to Florida
to be in my uncle's used-car business.
Instead, I'm here with you,
I'm broke, I've been shot at,
I was in a bus that flipped over 20 times,
I had glass all in my hair
and all over my suit,
broke my Walkman,
and lost my James Brown tape,
and plus, I've been hit
by a big fucking truck.
So leave me alone, okay, Jack?
[Jack] Well, life's tough, Reggie.
I ran into your friends too today.
They shot me in the chest six times.
- You don't look bad for a dead person.
- I would be if it wasn't for one of these.
Yeah, why'd you wear this, anyway?
Well, I knew I was gonna see you, Reg.
Now, I wouldn't want to get killed
by a stray bullet that was meant for you.
Now, that'd be a hell of a way to go,
wouldn't it be?
That's very sensitive, Jack.
You think maybe I should get one of these?
Well, you can get these anyplace.
You can get 'em at sporting goods.
They run about 750 bucks.
A little more than they gave you
when they let you out, right, Reg?
Jack, I hope you at least
still got my Porsche.
[Jack] Oh, yeah.
It's safe and sound back in the city.
I took real good care of it
like I said I would.
Hey, just 'cause you said you gonna
do something don't mean you gonna.
You said we had a deal and you fucked me.
[Jack] I fucked you? You fucked yourself.
You stole the payroll out of the prison.
They found the money in your cell.
I checked into it.
- Motherfucker, I got framed.
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
Some convict got a guard
to open up the cell,
put the money underneath the pillow
like the tooth fairy.
Yeah, you got framed.
That's what every convict says.
Hey, what about you, man?
You know they never found
that bad guy's gun at the racetrack.
- That's different.
- What's different about that?
- I'm a cop. You're a crook.
- Get the fuck out of here!
Just because I'm a convict,
everything that comes out
of my mouth is a goddamn lie?
- That's right.
- So just screw Reggie Hammond?
- Man, just take me to my goddamn car.
I'm through with you.
- What's wrong? Your arm hurt?
- Yeah. Thanks to your friends.
- Hurt bad?
- Yeah.
Good.
You hear the news?
Yeah, well, we got a problem here, slick.
Hey, man, back up.
I'm not the one
that hired these hillbillies,
so don't come complaining to me, okay?
Yes. Plan B.
We got an ex-Marine on the case.
Only problem is he's a hillbilly, too.
Yeah. Right.
Later.
How much of my money
did you spend, anyway?
Oh, about 25 grand.
You said I could buy a new car.
- Well, where is it?
- This is the new car.
This look like the same piece-of-shit,
sky-blue Cadillac you had before.
Yeah, I bought the same model,
year, color, everything the same.
That's the way I like it.
I get attached to things, Reggie.
- You got the same car. Same clothes.
- Yeah.
You got the same girl, too?
Elaine?
Ah, hell, I don't want to talk
about this shit.
Well, this is good.
Keep it all balled up like a nut.
[Jack]
She married me about five years ago.
Drove me over to city hall
for a quick ceremony.
She figured she'd settle me down.
This is where we lived until we split up.
She moved up to Mill Valley.
I've been trying to sell it.
Twelve grand of yours
went for the down payment.
Man, how could you leave my car
outside all these years?
Why didn't you put it
in the fucking garage?
Look at that dirt all over it.
What if somebody stole it?
Yeah, I had an alarm put on it.
Here, you just push
this blue button right there.
You have no appreciation
whatsoever for what's hype.
That's what it is.
You don't know that that car is fly.
You know how much pussy I got
because of that car?
[alarm chirps]
They blew up my car! They blew up my car!
They blew up my car!
It's a damn shame.
They blew up my goddamn car, and all you
got to say is, "It's a damn shame"?
No car. No money. You're having a bad day.
That's it. I'm through with you, man!
I'm calling some of my fucking homeys.
I'm getting a loan
and I'm stepping the fuck off!
[debris clattering]
Buster! Hey, what's up, man?
How you doing? Reggie Hammond.
Yes, my brother!
Yeah, I'm out, my man.
I'm on the street again.
Yeah. Yeah. Uh-huh.
Just cool it, brother. Yo, listen.
No, no, no, listen.
Yeah, I know. I'm gonna do that.
I know. I'm gonna take care...
That's what I'm calling about.
I need a loan.
Uh-huh. Yeah, I know... I know
I owe you some shit, but I need a loan.
Now, I just got out of jail. Brother,
my brother, everything's gonna be...
Yes, listen.
No, I don't have no collateral.
I just got out of jail, man.
The fuck I need collateral for?
This is Reggie Hammond.
Hey. Hey.
Hey, Buster? Buster?
[Ben] Jack, what the hell's going on?
We got a report you were shot
and your house blew up.
No, not my house. A car.
The fire department's still out there.
Your car blew up?
No, no, it wasn't my car.
It was some other guy's car
parked in front.
Listen, anything come in on those bikers
that hit the prison bus?
- No, not yet. I'll check again.
- All right.
Look, Jack, do me a favor
and go see Wilson.
He told me
if you won't see him right away,
he's gonna send somebody out to get you.
Shit.
Hey, Jack. You okay?
[siren wailing]
[police radio chatter]
Hey, you giving that guy a ticket?
Good. He hates cops.
He does, huh?
Yeah, I rode down here with him.
He told me that cops ain't shit
and that y'all was just pussies
that hide behind your badges.
And he also said
that he gonna park this car,
he don't care if it's a no-parking zone,
and if I see a cop,
tell the cop to kiss his ass.
So kiss his ass.
Your friend's not too smart.
Yeah, I know. He's a big dumb-ass cop
named Jack Cates.
Shit.
Tell Cates to stop parking
in front of the station.
[knocks]
[Wilson] Hello, Jack.
First, the motorcycle track
and then the diner,
and now we found a bomb at your house?
And I'll bet the Ice Man's responsible
for it all, right?
I'm not gonna stand here
and argue with you.
Man to man, I'm here to support you.
However, as Supervisor
of Internal Affairs,
it's my job to tell you
that you're still on suspension,
at least until the court hearing tomorrow.
So, why don't you give me that gun
and your badge and police ID?
Yeah. Right.
[Wilson] I'll bet you think
I enjoy this, don't you?
Jack, do me a favor.
Go home and get some sleep.
I got to go down
and check on a few things.
Make out some reports.
You know, I don't mind
people checking up on cops.
I don't think we're above the law.
But making cops do it,
it's bad for morale.
It's bad for cops.
Civilians ought to do it.
You're a real chickenshit, Wilson.
But maybe it's not your fault.
Maybe it's your job.
[mutters]
All right.
Yo, Marvin! Hey, what's up, man?
Reggie Hammond.
How y... Hammond. Reggie Hammond.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. How you doing, man?
I just got out. Yeah, my brother, yeah.
Listen... What?
You a born-again Christian?
Get the fuck out of here.
No, man, it's just...
No, I just can't picture you,
you know, being no born-again...
I was there
when you beat the bitch up, now.
No, no, don't get me wrong.
I know you can find Jesus.
Everybody can find Jesus.
No, I love Jesus.
I love Jesus. I love Jesus.
I love... Hello?
Hello? Hello? Marvin?
Hey, Willie Biggs! Reggie Hammond.
Hello? Hello?
Black motherfucker.
[printer whirring]
[Ben] Here you go, Jack.
Thirteen complaints involving
biker types in the last four days.
Two traffics and a D&D up in North Beach.
Run these guys through the NCIC.
I'll have Cruise do it.
Don't look much like a biker to me.
Nice talking to you.
You still here?
I didn't think you'd stick around.
If you think I'm happy about being here,
you can guess again, all right?
I'm supposed to be a free man
with money in my pocket
and getting along with my life,
and the last thing I wanted to do
was get tied to your big, dumb,
white ass again.
- [chuckles] Welcome back, Reg.
- Get the fuck off me, man.
I ain't no fucking convict no more.
I'm a free man.
And you? You about an inch away
from where I was yesterday.
So you ain't running jack shit, okay?
Let me tell you something.
I ain't working for you,
I don't like you, and I don't trust you.
All right, now just cut the bullshit.
Just give me something I can use, Reggie.
The Ice Man?
The Ice Man bought your house.
Now, God damn it, I said cut the bullshit.
I can't believe you didn't put this shit
together yet, man.
Me and Ganz robbed somebody
for half a million dollars
a couple years back.
That was the Ice Man,
and he's still pissed off about the shit.
Yeah, it's amazing how money affects
some people, ain't it, Jack?
I see your wheels turning. Yes. Yes.
The man that you've been looking for
all this time
bought your fucked-up car
and put a down payment
on your house for you.
And you've been riding around in the car
that he bought for you, looking for him,
which makes you probably the dumbest
motherfucker in law enforcement.
Get in the car. I'm driving.
You got a fucked-up arm,
and I'm not getting in another wreck.
I, unlike you, have a lot to live for.
[car horn honks]
I always wanted a chauffeur, Reggie.
Hey, man, I recognized one of those bikers
that attacked the bus today.
His name is Cherry Ganz.
He's a fucking lunatic.
- He's Ganz's brother.
- Ganz's brother?
Yes, he makes Ganz look like Gandhi.
Why in the hell would the Ice Man
hire Ganz's brother?
Think about it. I ratted Ganz to you,
and you killed Ganz.
Who'd want to kill us more?
Ganz said his brother used to fuck
this bitch named Angel.
All he used to talk about
was how insane the pussy was.
Said the bitch worked at a place
called Barnstormers or something.
Barnstormers.
Yeah, we got a complaint a couple bikers
rousted a bar called Barnstormers.
Wait. The cops are actually contributing
to this investigation? I'm shocked.
Now, wait. How the hell do you
remember where this girl works
after seven years in prison?
Hey, Jack, after seven years in prison,
you remember every story about pussy
you ever heard. Trust me.
Wait a minute. I gotta get something.
Hey, Jack, this shit is fake.
So what? People don't know the difference
when you flash it fast.
Somebody spooks that fake badge, and you
fuck around and get your ass whipped,
don't come crying to me.
I ain't got nothing to do with it.
You just watch your own ass, Reggie.
[rock music playing]
♪ We were two lovers, one of a kind ♪
♪ We shared a love
That you are lucky to find ♪
♪ We were as close as two could get... ♪
I'll go get some info.
A barmaid called in the complaint.
You go do your cop shit, Jack.
I'm gonna check out these hos.
[Jack] All right.
♪ But now it seems
You want every guy you see ♪
[song continues]
Hey!
You're the one that called in
the complaint on some bikers?
Oh, well, call the 6:00 news.
Cops finally responded.
Only been a day and a half, you know.
You gonna tell me what happened
or bitch a little more?
I'm gonna bitch a little more.
You guys are never here
when somebody needs you.
- Can I have a shot of Stoli?
- On the rocks?
Yeah. Great.
- Hey, how you doing?
- Hi. Buy me a drink?
Oh, baby, I just got out of jail.
I'm dead cracked,
but you can buy my drink.
Fuck off.
- Hi.
- I know you, right?
- Yeah, you do.
- You broke my heart once.
- [laughs] Did I?
[man]
I'm not letting you get away this time.
- I'll be right back. I'll be right back.
- Well, take mine.
I just have to powder my nose.
Just powder my nose. I'll be right back.
[chuckling]
- Hey.
- Hey, how you doing?
I'm pretty good. How are you?
- I'm all right.
- Yeah.
Hey, you ever see those commercials on TV
with, uh, the tourists?
With the guy with the big nose?
- Karl Malden.
- Yes, the big-ass nose man.
You ever see those commercials
where he shows the people
getting their pockets picked
in slow-motion?
- Yeah.
- Shit!
Yeah. Shit is a good word
to say there. Right.
But, listen, I can get
your money back for you,
- but it's gonna cost you.
- How much?
I think half your money would be good.
Half? Give me a break!
I'm giving you a break.
You ain't got nothing now.
The bitch is in the back,
counting your money.
Listen, she's gonna get your credit cards,
run your rate up, and your credit's
gonna be all fucked up.
Look, you don't want to do it, fuck you.
- You got a deal.
- I figured I had a deal.
So the guy with the dark hair
starts asking about this girl
who used to work here,
then he gets rough,
starts grabbing me and stuff.
And the blond one pulls out a gun.
- Cute, huh?
- What about this girl?
Angel? She stopped working here
over a year ago.
She's dancing at the Bird Cage
up in North Beach.
Hey, aren't you supposed
to be writing all this down?
I got a photographic memory.
Now, you got an address
of where she lives?
[splashes]
[chattering]
- This is the ladies' room.
- You're not supposed to be in here.
Well, y'all are leaving,
so mind your business.
Hey.
I thought this would be a good time
for us to get to know each other.
You're very smooth. Very, very smooth.
I've seen a lot of pockets get picked,
but I ain't never seen
nobody as smooth as you.
I was just talking to the guy that you hit
and, um, he's so upset.
I told him that I'd come in here,
and I'd get half his money back for him.
That is, unless, of course,
you offer me a nice little bribe,
then I'll go out there and tell him
you was a bit too fast for me.
I am too fast for you.
[laughs]
[laughing]
Oh, hi. Almost finished.
Was anybody else with them?
No, they came in, just the three of them.
Oh, there was this black guy.
Yeah, skinny.
Yeah, the oldest one
was talking to a black guy.
A black guy, huh? Here.
Was it something like this?
Yeah. Yeah. That's him.
He was okay. He didn't bother me.
Now, look, if they come in again,
I want you to call down to the department.
You ask for Inspector Ben Kehoe.
He'll know what to do.
You're in luck. Here's half your money.
Great. What about my credit cards?
We had no credit card deal.
I said your money.
Your cards are still in the bathroom.
[new song begins]
You gotta give it all you got.
Till you drop.
♪ Sometimes you win
And sometimes you lose ♪
Jack Cates?
Remember me?
No, I don't think so.
You busted me in the back seat
of a Camaro with a girl!
That don't sound like me.
Turns out she was underage,
but I didn't know it!
Well, you know, shit happens!
And I didn't steal that car, either.
My buddy did!
Maybe you'd better pick better buddies!
I gotta go see somebody!
- I got two years!
- Oh, come on, give me a break!
I don't want to get in a bar fight!
People are always getting in bar fights!
It's a damn cliché!
I mean, you hear about it all the time!
You see it in the motion pictures!
People are getting hit in the head
with them damn beer bottles and furniture.
- [bottle smashes]
- [man] Oh!
[patrons screaming]
[chuckling]
[laughs, sighs]
[band plays sting]
[laughing continues]
- [shouting]
- [Jack grunts]
[patrons shriek]
- [music stops]
- [feedback whining]
[Jack grunting, snarling]
[man shouts] Ow!
[both straining, breathing heavily]
I'm taking two years
out on your ass, Cates!
- You got a gun?
- What?
You know, a gun.
In case they stick the place up.
[onlookers shouting, cheering]
- [man] Hey!
- [woman] Stop wrecking the place!
All right! Knock this shit off!
I have been having a very bad day.
I just got out of jail this morning.
Already, I have been shot at,
I was on a bus that flipped over 17 times,
bitch tried to stab me in the bathroom,
and somebody blew up my Porsche.
I am in a bad goddamn mood.
Now, I usually don't jump in
when somebody's getting beat down,
but this man, Jack Cates, is gonna help me
straighten out the rest of my day.
Now, I suggest y'all back up
and let us go about our business.
'Cause you got a gun?
No. Because I have a gun
and I'll pop a cap in your ass.
I don't think you've
got the guts to use it.
[screaming]
Anybody else want to limp?
[music resumes]
Sorry about the kneecap.
I got a little, um, excited.
Pretty smooth, Jack. You know
how to handle an investigation.
It's your fault. You disappeared on me.
Where in the hell were you?
In the bathroom
taking care of some business,
then I got to come out and save your ass.
- I didn't need your help.
- I was not helping you.
I was protecting my money.
I knew this wasn't gonna be easy.
I shouldn't have gone in there
without my goddamn spare gun.
I go in there
and I get in a goddamn fight.
A bar fight! Jesus, Jack!
What the hell are you doing?
Hey!
Yo, man, what was that for?
That was for the basketball.
Now we're even.
We can start fresh.
Man, I got to get the hell out of here,
or I'm gonna do a homicide.
The deal is off.
Fuck this. The deal's off.
Oh, the deal's off. Bullshit.
Come on, let's go. Get in the car.
- Come on.
- Hey, Jack, was you born a shithead,
or did you take lessons to get like this?
Oh, I was just getting even.
Now don't take it so damn personal.
Come on, let's go. Let's get in the car.
Man, I told you before
to stay away from me, right?
Stay the fuck away from me, Jack.
I mean it.
Ah, hey, don't be stupid. Where you going?
Away! Away from you!
That's where I'm going.
Hey! Your tip turned out okay.
Ganz's old lady lives
down in the tenderloin
at the King Mei Hotel!
Bye, Jack.
Fuck you, Jack.
Ah, shit!
[fax machine whirring]
Okay, here's the story
on one of the bikers.
Just came in.
"Ganz, Richard, aka Cherry.
Known member of
Western Brotherhood Motorcycle Gang.
Seven outstanding warrants,
details to follow.
Seventy-two outstanding
traffic violations."
LA bike gangs?
[Ben] Yeah, LAPD faxed up some stuff
a few minutes ago.
Supposed to be a lot more coming in.
[Jack] All right. I'll be right over.
Why is he on the streets?
The man is on suspension!
Jack, coming to the station
ain't such a good idea.
Wilson's looking for you.
Oh, Christ. He heard about the bar.
All right, be out in front in 15minutes
with everything you got.
You got it? Fifteen minutes.
Kehoe, get in.
Give me that. Here, you take the wheel.
- What?
- Steer.
- Jesus Christ, Jack.
- Got it?
Yeah.
"Hickok. Ganz."
This guy is Albert Ganz's brother.
Yeah, I know all about that.
Did you know they're cop killers?
Capped two chips
and a bystander five days ago.
I talked to a special
investigations guy in LA,
said these guys are enforcers
for their gang, the Brotherhood.
Last two years,
they've been linked to over 15 deaths.
Brake! Brake!
- Christ.
- Got anything else?
- No, nothing hard.
- [cars honking]
Jack, just go around the block, will you?
Nah, it's too easy.
[chattering]
- [guard] Kirkland Smith!
- Yeah!
You got a phone call. Reggie Hammond.
- Reggie?
- [Reggie] Hey, Kirk. What's up?
Is it done?
Look, it's a little bit more complicated
than that.
Don't mess with me, Reggie.
Let me tell you something.
You ain't a citizen no more, man.
You can't vote.
Ain't nobody gonna hire your ass.
You an outcast. Nobody wants you.
Now all you got left is your word.
Don't break your fucking word to me.
[dial tone]
[chattering in Mandarin]
[woman speaking Mandarin]
[Reggie] It's a nice place, huh?
- What took you so long?
- I thought you quit for the fifth time.
What is it? You can't stay away?
I'm gonna hang, Jack. I'm gonna hang,
and we're gonna straighten this shit out.
But let me tell you something, man,
if you hit me again, if you grab me,
if you touch me,
if your hand brush up against me lightly,
I'm gonna kill you, Jack. I'm serious.
[Jack] Aw, don't worry, Reggie.
I'm gonna treat you right.
Only reason I let you get away
with some of this shit
is 'cause I know you got shot,
and your mind not be acting right
'cause you're in a lot of pain.
- Which arm? Your right or your left?
- It's my left.
It hurts like hell. The doc says
it's bruised down to the bone.
- To the bone?
- Yeah.
- That's a deep bruise.
- Oh, God!
- Now we even, motherfucker.
What do you mean? God damn it!
I just got even for the basketball,
you son of a bitch!
Yeah, well, give me my money back,
then you can hit me
in my face with the ball.
Now wait a minute, Reg.
Now, let's... We're just gonna go
and talk to this girl. Right?
- Don't snake me, Jack.
- I'm not gonna snake you.
If she's here,
we're just gonna talk to her. All right?
I mean, this is just
straight-ahead cop stuff, isn't it?
Here.
Thank you.
Give me that.
So, when's Cherry coming over?
Don't worry. He'll be by.
He said you were real nice.
He was right.
[speaking Mandarin]
- We never hear of her.
- Heard of her now?
[scoffs, speaks Mandarin]
That fake badge. My kid get one of those.
Your kid got one of these?
[speaking Mandarin]
Angel Lee, upstairs. Fourth floor, 4B.
Okay.
Chances are she hasn't even seen this guy.
I mean, he's in town for a hit.
He's not gonna stop off
and pop his old girlfriend.
Yes, he will, man,
and then share with his friends.
- They're like Eskimos.
- All right, you wait down here.
I'm going up and see the lady.
No. Wrong. I ain't waiting down here.
I ain't got no gun.
What am I gonna do
if these bikers show up? Make a mean face?
You got a pistol.
You stay here and watch this shit,
and if she's up there, I'll shout down.
All right, all right.
Here, you want this badge?
No. I don't think I'm gonna run
into no little kids on the way up.
[chattering in Mandarin]
[men arguing in Mandarin]
Yeah? Who is it?
[Reggie] I have a pizza delivery
for Miss Angel.
I didn't order any pizza.
Uh, it says, um, uh, room 4B,
Miss Angel, pizza delivery.
Hang on a second.
I got to get something on.
She naked!
I didn't order any pizza.
[gunshot]
[Angel shouting]
[speaking Mandarin]
No fucking way!
Fucking pig! I killed you!
You can't be alive! I already killed you!
[shouting in Mandarin]
Call for help! Now!
[scoffs, speaks Mandarin]
What is going on, God damn it?
Where you going?
[door creaks]
[speaking Mandarin]
[gunshots]
What's up? Wait!
[woman shrieks]
You killed my family, pig!
I'm gonna kill you!
Get the fuck out of here.
Fucking pig! Motherfucking pig!
- [Willie] Cherry, we got to get going!
- That motherfucker's still alive!
Why don't you fucking die?
- [gun clicking]
- [Cherry shouts]
Come on.
[Willie] Come on!
They're out back!
[truck horn honking]
[woman shouting in Mandarin]
Down the alley.
[moaning]
Yeah, we got the perimeter secured.
Jack's okay.
I haven't had a chance
to get a statement from him yet, though.
I don't know whose gun he used.
Look, I'll get a statement from him...
I'll get the statement, okay? Fine.
You know, you're in deep shit.
You know that, Jack?
Tell me something I don't know.
I ran this guy through NCIC.
I couldn't come up with a match on him.
[sighs] That figures.
Okay. Right now you're looking at
accessory to murder one.
That gets you five to ten years inside,
and that's with good behavior,
unless you cooperate with us,
and then you might not do any time at all.
Look, I told the other cop.
I got nothing to say
until I talk to a lawyer.
Are you protecting this guy Cherry
because you're in love with him?
I can certainly understand
why a girl could fall in love
with a guy like that.
What's he do?
Blow through town once or twice a year,
let his friends jump up and down on you,
get drunk and beat
the shit out of you, huh?
I can understand
why a girl would love a guy like that.
- I totally understand that.
- Look, I don't know where they're at.
They move around all the time.
- I can never get in touch with him.
- Well, who can?
I don't know. Those guys are nuts.
[Reggie] Don't worry about anything.
This is officer Jack Cates.
Mr. Cates,
Miss Lee here was about
to help us out with the investigation.
I think she was about to tell me
the name of Mr. Cherry's contact man.
The guy's name is Malcolm Price.
He's big, spooky eyes, long hair.
Nobody talks to Cherry
unless they talk to him first.
- Okay. Now, where do we find this guy?
- I don't know.
Hey.
I swear. I only know a name.
Thanks, babe.
Hey, wait a minute!
Hey, Jack. Hey, Jack.
Where in the hell
do you think you're going?
Radio back to Kehoe,
and tell him to run up a shit sheet
on a biker named Malcolm Price.
Good bet he's got a long record.
We're out of here.
[Cruise] I got to get a statement.
Hey, man, your ass is gonna be grass.
I'm telling you now.
At the rate we going, you'll probably
pick up Price at my funeral.
Oh, don't worry about your funeral.
If the Ice Man gets you,
we won't even find your body.
You know what it is, man?
We need to go somewhere and talk to
somebody who knows about stuff like this.
- Okay, where?
- Honestly?
- We should go back to prison.
- Oh, bullshit.
Hey, man, you got any better ideas
on how to find out something
about Malcolm Price?
I got a guy on the inside
who knows everything about everybody.
He can finger anybody, man.
Plus, it wouldn't be a bad idea for you
to go to prison, anyway,
'cause you might be spending
some time there real soon,
and I think it'd be a good job
for you to go get reacquainted
with some of the brothers
whose rights you violated.
Oh, don't give me that!
I just arrest crooks.
I don't make 'em steal.
Jack, you don't get it, do you?
You make it sound like
everybody went down
to a guidance counselor,
took a test, and the results came back,
crook was the only job
they was qualified for.
Oh, that's a real good story, Reggie.
Blame it on society.
Put it on society's shoulders.
Let me tell you something, Jack.
If shit was worth something,
poor people'd be born with no assholes.
[pay phone ringing]
Yeah, it's me.
I heard about it.
Well, hey, man, I warned you about
dealing with these crazy-ass crackers.
What? No, I ain't carrying.
That ain't my thing. You know that.
Look, I'm a businessman, too,
but I just don't want to get too close
to these guys.
You know, man, these cats are taking
all of the fun out of my work.
Right.
Yeah, I remember. I remember.
I said you don't have to remind me
of it, okay?
Don't worry about it.
I'll pull it together.
[keys rattling]
[lock clicks]
Good morning, Kirkland.
You got some visitors.
[man] Hey, man,
will you shut up over there!
All right. Hold on.
Get that picture of the guy.
He's a small-time dealer.
His name is, uh, Burroughs.
Recruited by the Ice Man,
I don't know, a couple of months ago.
Okay, I wanna know, like,
do you know anything about the guy
he's supposed to work for?
This main dude named Malcolm Price?
Yeah, I know him. Western Brotherhood.
You want these guys to do a hit for you,
you got to go through Price.
- You got an address?
- I'm not 411. You look it up.
Sunset Motel on the beltway.
And give the phone back to Reggie.
- What's his problem?
- I don't know.
Say, man, do you mind?
I'm trying to talk to the brother here.
Oh, uh, I'll handle this.
Can you excuse me? Me and my brother
want to talk, you know.
It's Black stuff. Excuse us.
- It's private.
- You mind? You mind?
Yeah. Hang on.
Just... Look, can you go over there,
please? Thank you.
- It's private.
- All right, all right.
Reggie, look.
Now that I've given you something you need
for the second time...
Yes, you have, and I appreciate
your patience, and thank you.
You will
repay your debt to me!
[knocks]
Hey, man, not to worry.
We got lots of backup.
Come on in and have a drink.
- [silenced gunfire]
- [groaning]
Malcolm Price.
Must have been a real good lead, Jack.
Somebody shot him 16 times.
I've been chasing
this goddamn Ice Man for years.
Every time I get close,
it's another goddamn dead end.
- This job will drive you crazy.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Jack, the Ice Man's a cop.
No way.
Hey, come on, Jack.
Put this shit together, man.
Jack, think about it.
You called for Price's address.
The Ice Man shows up there first.
It's a coincidence. Bad luck.
That ain't no damn coincidence.
What about the brother
whose picture you've been showing around?
You get any feedback on that yet?
Well, that don't mean nothing.
You gotta run a mug shot through NCIC.
It takes time to get a make.
- How long that take?
- Hours.
- It's been hours.
- Well, sometimes it's slow.
Come on, man. That's a lame excuse, Jack.
Let me tell you
why the Ice Man wants to kill me.
Has nothing to do
with the money that I took, okay?
That's fly shit to him.
He want to kill me
because I seen him, Jack.
I can identify him.
I'm back on the street.
He thinks I can blow his cover.
The same guy that's trying to kill me
is fucking up your investigation.
Find out which guy is putting up
the most resistance
'cause you're on this case.
That is probably the Ice Man.
Only guy it could be is Wilson...
and that prick's been dogging my ass
for years,
ever since I started looking
for the Ice Man.
All through this thing.
Listen, I got to get you over
to the hearing
- so you can ID this guy. Come on.
- What hearing?
The one where they're going to decide
whether they're gonna put me in jail
and take away my badge for good.
It started two hours ago.
[Wilson] After the incident
in the Mission District,
Inspector Cates dredged up this theory
of a criminal mastermind
running the drug traffic in the Bay Area.
For four years, in my opinion,
he has wasted department resources
and manpower,
risked other officers' lives
to vindicate himself and his theories.
Can you describe
Inspector Cates's professional attitude?
When a police officer
takes it upon himself
to violate department regulations
and suspects' civil rights,
it makes it hard on every good cop
who's out there trying to do his job.
Objection, Your Honor,
these remarks have nothing to do
with the incident at hand.
On the contrary, Your Honor.
I'm trying to show a pattern of behavior
on Inspector Cates's part
that will illuminate
the events at Hunters Point Raceway.
I'll, uh, let the testimony stand.
[judge] In consideration
of the preliminary evidence
presented thus far by the State
and in adherence to the laws,
statutes, and rules
as specified by the State of California,
city of San Francisco...
There he is right there!
[judge] Order! Order!
Please, let's have some order here.
This is an official hearing.
- No, it's some other guy.
- No, no, no! Right there!
I'm looking at him, Jack.
It's somebody else. That's not him.
- No, God damn it, that's gotta be him.
- Who are these men?
That, Your Honor, is Inspector Jack Cates.
That's definitely not the guy.
No, that's got to be
the goddamn Ice Man. People change.
Hey, man, you don't
forget somebody you took
half a million dollars from.
That's not him.
Well, God damn it, it's gotta be him!
That's gotta be the Ice Man!
- [judge] This is too much!
- [gavel raps]
This court rules
that there is sufficient evidence
to proceed with a criminal trial
against Inspector Jack Cates.
Trial date will be set for the
earliest opening on the court calendar.
- This hearing is adjourned.
- [gavel raps]
Ice Man whacked out Price.
You want to talk about it?
The man had no choice.
Your girl ratted him out to the cops.
- [Cherry] Bullshit.
- I don't bullshit. You both know her.
She works as a dancer,
lives at the King Mei Hotel.
You know, you two should be
a little bit more careful
about who you hang out with.
Who pulled the trigger?
What's the fucking difference
who pulled the trigger?
The cops were getting too close.
That's the way the Man does business.
Business, not personal.
You know, you two fucking hillbillies
should learn the difference.
Business. Yeah.
[Burroughs] Ah! What?
That's business, too.
[groans]
[laughing]
You happy now, asshole?
That still doesn't change the job.
- You got to kill Reggie Hammond.
- And how are we gonna do that?
Kirkland Smith, he's the dude
who kept Reggie alive in the joint
when we had papers out on him.
Reggie owes him.
I figured out where he's gonna pay back.
The dude's got a daughter
works in the Goodwill store
in the Haight just off Central.
Well, you know what we're gonna do?
We're going to get Hammond,
and we're going to get the cop,
and the Ice Man,
and we're going to kill them all.
You just stick to Hammond, Joe Bob.
That's the gig.
I keep forgetting the combination.
Hey, Jack, I don't want to see
you clear out your locker, man.
Let's get back out on the streets.
We can get this guy.
You know, Reggie,
I've been a cop for 20 years,
and all I've ever been around is pimps,
murderers, and robbers,
but between you and me,
I've always been straight.
Now, you did your best.
So, here's your 475 thou.
- You kept my money in your locker?
- Yeah.
In a police locker, Jack?
Yeah. Hey, we got no more ties.
You're a free man, Reg.
Now, listen, my advice to you
is take this money and disappear.
You sure, man?
Yeah.
All right.
[door closes]
Thank you. Have a nice day.
[Reggie] Hammond. Reggie Hammond.
This is $75,000, courtesy of your father.
This money comes from Kirkland Smith?
It's got to be dirty.
Hey, wait a second, now.
We both know your father's no angel,
but this money is not stolen.
Your father did a favor for me.
I just got out of jail.
Had some money before I went in.
I owed some money to your father,
and he thought it would benefit you.
A lot of fathers wouldn't even do this.
I think you should accept it.
Bye-bye.
Mr. Hammond.
- How is he?
- He's good. You should go see him.
Maybe.
No. No maybe. You should go see him.
- [whimpers]
- [shushes]
Hey.
Hey, Ben.
Sorry I couldn't help more, Jack.
Uh, it's all right.
You did what you could.
It'll be pretty fucking dull
without you around here.
[Jack chuckles]
Can't believe
you're not coming to work tomorrow.
- Get a beer?
- Maybe later.
- You got a bunch of messages, Frank.
- Thanks, Joe.
[line ringing]
- Yeah.
- [Malcolm] We got Hammond.
Good. Is he dead yet?
There's a change in plans.
Killing one of us wasn't part of the deal.
What kind of shit are you trying to pull?
You want this guy dead. We want 500 Gs.
That's the price for you doing
one of the Brotherhood.
What the hell are you talking about?
500,000, or we let Hammond finger you.
There's a place out of Modesto...
What, are you nuts? No way.
You want more money, pick a new place,
something indoors,
something with lots of people.
Hey, Jack, this just came in.
Some guy named Burroughs
looks just like the guy you were after.
They found him dead
in the Mission a little while ago.
Here's his sheet. It's a mile long.
I circulated this guy's picture
at the precinct last night.
I got nothing.
[Joe]
That's funny. Cruise busted him last July.
Cates, even though
there's no love lost between us,
I just want you to know it hurts me
to see a man throw away his career.
So let's let bygones be...
[people exclaiming]
[chattering]
Hey, I'm looking for the Cage club.
The upstairs part.
Fifth floor. You got to join. Fifty bucks.
[elevator bell dings]
[rock music blaring]
You don't look too happy, Reg.
Sorry, babe. Look me up later,
and I'll buy you a drink, all right?
Where's Hammond?
- Who's the girl?
- Just somebody he was with.
Five hundred Gs, right?
Now, let's check the merchandise.
Take him out behind the building
and blow him away.
Shoot the girl, too. Shoot both of them.
Yo, man, what's this guy doing here?
You said the Ice Man was gonna
bring you your money.
That guy ain't the Ice Man.
You're just trying to save your ass.
That's bullshit, man.
That ain't the Ice Man.
That guy is a cop. You're getting set up.
They got the wrong guy,
don't they, Cruise?
Hello, Jack.
[Cherry] It's Christmas here, Willie.
We can take 'em all, Hammond, the pig,
the Ice Man. The whole ball of wax.
That's him!
That's the Ice Man, right there.
Pretty good, Jack.
You always were a smart cop.
You know, Ben,
I really didn't want to believe it.
Sorry to let you down, Jack.
[Jack] All I want is the Ice Man.
You two take the money.
Get the hell out of here.
Ain't nobody leaving here with my money.
Money? I want the fucking Ice Man!
[shouts]
[patrons screaming]
Get the fuck out of the way!
[gunfire]
[gunfire continues]
[groans]
- [woman screaming]
- Come on, you fuck!
[gunfire continues]
[automatic weapon fire]
Somebody help me!
Shut up!
Get away! No! No!
You fucking bitch!
You fucking bit me, you fucking bitch!
[gunfire]
[Cherry screaming]
[gunshot]
You set me up, Ben!
You never ran that shit through NCIC.
You had Cruise pick up the gun that day
at the track.
I needed leverage on you, Jack.
You were getting close.
[shouting]
[gun clicks]
[laughs]
[hammer cocks]
[gun clicks]
[chuckles]
Fuck you! [shouts]
[pedestrians scream]
Jack, we can work this out.
Just let me out of here.
You're a disgrace, Ben.
Nothing worse than a bad cop.
Hey, Jack,
thank you for a very pleasant day.
Okay? I got no car, I got no money,
and I'm gonna fucking end the day off
with this goddamn dope man's Uzi
by my temple.
Thank you, Jack. Look, this is Jack's day.
Why don't you just let Jack shoot me?
Save your bullet.
Jack, why don't you shoot me?
Shoot me, Jack!
[gun fires]
[siren wails]
Coming through. Coming through.
[Reggie] Oh, Jack.
I can't believe you shot me, man.
This shit hurts, man.
Well, I told you you should have bought
a damn bulletproof vest.
You did good, Reggie. You did real good.
Doc says you's going to be fine.
Guess I'm a pretty good shot, huh?
You're going to have to take it easy
for a while.
I'm sorry
you had to knock your friend, man.
He wasn't my friend. You're my friend.
Besides, I had to save my partner,
didn't I?
I got this off the Ice Man.
It's 500 grand.
I'll meet you at the hospital.
We'll talk about it, okay?
Here. Hold this for me.
["(The Boys Are) Back in Town" playing]
[siren wailing]
♪ Well, there's a reason everybody
Should be shakin' in the house tonight ♪
♪ And you should grab your favorite lady
And promise her you'll do it right ♪
[laughs]
♪ So you can party
To some stomp-down, butt-bumpin' ♪
♪ Rock-and-roll rhythm and blues ♪
♪ 'Cause the boys are back in town ♪
[song continues]