(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING
ON RADIO)
You want to have
yourself a beer or something
while you're
waiting there?
BARTENDER:
You hear me, mister?
I'll take the bottle.
BARTENDER: Howdy, boys.
What can I do for you?
Brewskis.
Brewskis. You got it.
There you go.
(CHUCKLING)
Hey.
Fifty now,
50 more when you're done.
How many?
Just one.
What is he, another cop?
No. Matter of fact,
he's a friend of yours.
You're going to
like this job.
He was in my
brother's gang.
First, he dropped
a dime on him,
then he ratted him to the cop
that blew him away.
Hey.
I'm gonna go on in
and take a look.
Want a Coke?
Yeah, Diet.
We're on the Simmons Road
about 15 miles west off of Route 14.
I need wants and warrants
on motorcycle registrations.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
Roger. I copy.
First one, California.
6-David-8-4-Sam-Niner.
Roger. Copy that.
Second plate...
Tom.
How you doing?
Nice to see you.
Willie Hickok. Right here.
Cherry Ganz, Officer.
Do I know you guys?
Repeat, code 6-Charles.
(GRUNTING)
Who you calling,
friend?
Nobody.
I wasn't calling nobody.
(COCKS GUN)
Somehow
I don't believe you.
Oh, God! Oh, no!
(ANNOUNCER CHATTERING
OVER PA)
$100,000.
$50,000 now.
Ice Man's a generous guy.
I don't like hundreds.
I told you that before.
What kind of shit
is this?
Well, this is the guy.
The balance is due
when he's dusted.
You understand what
I'm talking about?
We want him dead.
Yeah, whatever.
No problem.
Police! Freeze!
You, move a step apart.
Now, I don't want anybody
to get hurt here,
so move slow.
(SCREAMING)
MOTORCYCLE DRIVER: Watch it!
Shit!
Get back!
Get the hell out of here!
(SIRENS APPROACHING)
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(POLICE RADIO CHATTERING)
Christ, you really
toasted that guy.
God damn it,
I didn't toast the guy.
I just shot him,
for Christ sake.
Don't say
I toasted him, Ben.
Calm down.
We'll find the gun.
We've just got to
do this together.
Get our stories
straight.
Checked the guy's
locker.
Seems okay.
He works here at the track.
Fifty bucks in his wallet,
a pair of sunglasses,
some keys,
probably car or apartment.
We still haven't
found his gun, yet.
Shit.
Cates took down
one of the locals.
A slug hit one
of the gas pumps
and burned
the bad guy to a crisp.
Now, Jack claims
it was a righteous shooting.
OFFICER: All right, man.
It's all right.
Man, I hate
these IAD scumbags.
Blake Wilson,
Internal Affairs.
Seems like I'm always
running into you, Jack.
Give us a minute,
fellas.
What did you do
now, Jack?
I was on a stakeout.
I was getting real close
to nailing these...
Close?
Oh, the Ice Man, right?
Yeah, God damn it.
The Ice Man.
I tell you,
I'm getting real close.
I'm gonna nail these guys.
For years you've
been trying to pin
every case
you can't solve on the Ice Man.
He's the biggest drug dealer
in the Bay Area, right, Jack?
Except we don't
have any prints,
we don't have
a description.
You're the only cop
on the force
who believes
this guy exists.
I'll let you in
on a little secret.
There is no Ice Man.
So let's get back
to the cold facts of this
because this is real.
Now, what the hell
happened here?
I saw an exchange.
Probable cause.
I moved in.
He had a piece.
He shot. I shot back.
You got the
bad guy's gun?
It's got to be in there
with the ashes and shit.
I didn't touch anything.
Cruise,
what do you got?
Nothing much.
Just some burnt metal.
Must be off the pump.
No gun?
No, no gun.
Look, a cop is a guy,
and a guy sometimes
steps on his dick.
You think maybe today
you were pushing a little too hard,
trying to make
something work, and you stepped on your dick?
Work with me here.
We're on the same side.
Did you step on your...
Now, wait a minute.
God damn it,
it didn't go down that way.
He had a piece.
He shot. I shot back.
Kehoe, I want
the lab boys to go over every inch of this place.
If there's a gun here,
I want it.
A bullet.
Something. Anything.
See you around,
Jack.
Yeah.
Reggie Hammond.
You must be a real
dangerous convict.
You made me
miss, cop.
You look good, Reggie.
I ain't seen you
in years, man.
I thought you was
my friend.
Well, I'm sorry.
I've been busy.
Yeah, me, too.
You must be pretty desperate
to come down here, man.
You even got a new haircut.
What's going on?
Well, times change.
Well, you lost
a couple of pounds.
Quit drinking.
So, what,
the warden pick you to come in here
and tell me my sentence got
yanked up another five years or something?
Oh, relax. You're still
getting out tomorrow.
But when you do,
you and me's got another little job to do.
Man, you and me
don't have shit to do.
When I get out of here,
just give me my fucking money
and walk away
from me, all right?
'Cause I played
that cop shit once and it don't work.
Have my money when
I get out, please.
Now, wait a minute, Reggie.
You don't get it.
You see,
if you don't help me out on this one,
I'm not ever gonna give you
your money back.
You're fucking
with me, right?
No.
Hey, Jack,
I gave you that money
in good faith.
'Cause you told me
I could fucking trust you.
Now, you're gonna
tell me after all this shit,
I can't have
my money?
Yeah, now you got
the picture, convict.
(LAUGHING)
You screwed up real good
this time, Hammond.
It was self-defense.
Nobody's gonna
buy that crap!
Hey, wait
a minute, man!
I served two years
for a crime I did
and I never
fucking denied that.
But I've just spent
five years in here
for some shit
that was bullshit!
I never robbed
no damn payroll.
You people
got murderers in here been here less time than me.
You can spend
your remaining time in isolation.
Open up.
(SHRIEKING)
♪ Roxanne
♪ You don't have to
put on the red light
♪ Those days are over
♪ You don't have
to sell your body to the night
♪ Roxanne ♪
(BLUES MUSIC
PLAYING ON STEREO)
Tequila.
The bottle.
BARMAID:
You guys want anything?
Whiskey.
And?
Put it in a glass.
Mr. Price,
the Man is distressed.
That mess you
made in the desert has him wondering
if your boys are
gonna be around to finish the job.
Not to worry.
Real pros, huh?
Not from
where I'm sitting.
Pros don't make
messes like you did.
Don't get the heat
all jacked up
when you're supposed
to be doing a job.
You want to be
an outlaw,
but you want to
play by rules.
There ain't no rules.
Oh, you giving me
your philosophy?
That's right, bro.
We're the only
real Americans left.
We believe in freedom.
We live the way
folks used to,
back before
there were big cities, and lawyers,
and computers
with your names in them.
Free.
The rest of you
are just a bunch of fucking slaves.
Yeah? Well, that sounds
real interesting, Mr. Price.
Maybe you should
run for office.
All I'm supposed
to do is to tell you to take precautions.
We tried to get
you some backup,
but he got barbecued
at a race track.
You know what to do
with that stuff?
No problem here,
friend.
I used to be
a Marine.
I guess that figures.
You guys have any trouble,
you come to me.
You know the number.
Hey. Hey, come here.
I think you got
the wrong girl.
I don't do that.
Come on.
My friend and I
just came into town.
We're looking for a whore
that works here.
Oh, yeah?
What's her name?
Name's Angel.
Angel don't work
here anymore.
She's dancing
up in North Beach.
Well, you're here.
How about you?
I'm getting tired
of this.
Let go!
Otherwise, I'm gonna
call the cops.
Go ahead,
sweet cheeks.
(COCKING PISTOL)
Call 'em.
Hey, let's hit
the road, boys. Come on.
Come on, Cherry.
(UNCOCKS GUN)
In the matter of
the officer-involved shooting at Hunters Point raceway
of the suspect Arthur Brock,
a resident of San Francisco,
the review board
has carefully examined the physical evidence
and the testimony
of the witnesses,
and has determined
that the officer in question,
Inspector Jack Cates,
had insufficient
probable cause.
Based on a review of
the officer's case history
and an ongoing investigation
by the Internal Affairs Division,
this review board
cannot help but rule
that the shooting was
a wrongful action.
I never thought
they'd land on you so hard.
I swear...
I'm gonna have to recommend
to the District Attorney
that he prosecute you
for manslaughter.
Sure as hell wish
they'd found that gun.
Well, I'm sorry, Jack.
I'm just doing my job.
(SARCASTICALLY)
Right.
Wilson's got
a personality profile of an obsessed cop,
whose record shows his history
of stepping over the line, okay?
It's quite likely
the DA will choose
to prosecute you
on third degree.
In other words,
you're screwed.
Unless I find
the Ice Man.
Oh, come on, Jack.
Give it up.
That's what got you
into this.
Jesus Christ, Ben.
You sound like Wilson.
We're talking
about the facts here.
You got no leads.
The department's got no leads.
This is manslaughter.
Protect yourself.
(BELL RINGS)
(CELLBLOCK DOOR SLAMMING)
Hammond, let's go.
Big day
for you today.
Just get me the hell
out of here, man.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Come on.
KIRKLAND: Reggie.
Come here.
Excuse me a minute.
You will keep
your promise,
right?
Everything is...
Don't worry, everything is cool.
It's no problem.
That white cop that came
to see you yesterday?
Now, he ain't
no problem, is he?
Oh, no.
No, no, no.
He ain't gonna fuck that up.
I promise you
everything is cool,
but it might take
a little bit longer
than I said it
was gonna take.
Don't bullshit me, man.
You get that money
and you keep your word.
I kept you alive
in this funky rat hole for five years,
so don't act like
everything is everything.
I can get you
out there, Reggie.
I can reach out of here
and pull your fucking heart out!
What was all that
going on back there?
Just talking about
an old football bet.
That's a crock.
Hammond, Reggie A.
WARDEN: I came by
to give you $100 in cash
and a free bus ride
to San Francisco,
all compliments of
the State of California.
And that's it?
That is it.
Thank you for sparing me
the other crap.
Hey, man,
you ain't got to slam my shit down like that.
Yo, where's
my James Brown tape?
The shit ain't in...
Oh.
Everybody trying to keep
me and James in prison.
Hey, we didn't
get to finish our conversation.
Hey, man,
stay the fuck away from me
till you get my money,
all right?
I told you yesterday,
convict,
you're not
getting your money unless you help me.
Look, man, I trusted you
with my money and my car, and you fucked me.
I thought
you were straight.
What the fuck's
going on, man?
I've been
chasing a drug dealer called the Ice Man
for the last four years.
Now, last week, I find out
this Ice Man wants you dead.
Here, take a look
at this.
I got this off of some guy
paying someone to make a hit on you.
You recognize
this guy? Huh?
Now, in four years, Reggie,
that makes you the best lead I ever had.
Yeah?
Well, helping you out while you got my money
is something
I don't want to do!
REGGIE: Let me rot
in a fucking prison for five years
and you show up
wanting some help. That's bullshit.
That's worse
than bullshit.
That's dumb, man!
Reggie,
this time, I promise you it's gonna be different.
Now, look,
I'm gonna lose my badge.
They're gonna
put me in jail.
Oh, you're in
trouble with the law this time?
Good! Good!
As bad as I feel
about you keeping my money,
that shit almost
makes me feel better.
Now I'm sure I don't want
to go with you!
Now, wait a minute,
God damn it.
I don't beg!
What you gonna do,
whip my ass?
You gonna shoot me out here
in front of the prison?
That's not a very good way
to treat the best lead you ever had.
Don't worry.
I'll come visit you
in about five
or six years.
Hey, man, let's get
the hell out of here.
Hey, we got a schedule.
Hey, fuck that, man.
I'm a free man now.
I'm not
on the state's time no more.
Write a letter.
Everybody around
this motherfucker's crazy.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Big fucker
in the blue Caddy.
That's the pig who
wasted my brother.
Oh, this is great, man.
I get 'em both.
(HORN HONKS)
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING
ON STEREO)
♪ Last night
♪ I had a little talk
with myself
♪ Just me and me
and a man
♪ I said, self,
I think it's time
♪ I laid it on the line
♪ And I tried my best
to make me understand
♪ And them tears
♪ Over a love that's gone cold
♪ Was wastin' time,
yours and mine... ♪
REGGIE:
(IMITATING JAMES BROWN) ♪ You don't know
♪ What you do to me
♪ Get me down
♪ In--In misery
♪ Oh, yes, sir
♪ Well
(SHRIEKS)
♪ Hit me
♪ All right
♪ Wanna kiss myself
♪ Good God
♪ And I got the feeling
♪ Hey
(GRUNTS)
(SHRIEKS)
♪ Baby, baby, baby
♪ Baby, baby...
(SHRIEKS)
♪ Want to get on the good foot
♪ Good God
♪ September,
when the good checks come
♪ Baby, baby, baby
♪ Baby, baby... ♪
(MEN CLAMORING)
Get down!
(MEN YELLING)
Heading west on
US Highway 50.
Get some help
out here right now!
I need some help, now!
REGGIE: Shit!
(TRUCK HORM BLARING)
(TRUCK HORN BLARING)
Let's go.
(GLASS TINKLING)
(GASPS)
(SIRENS APPROACHING)
Come on!
(GUNSHOTS)
DOCTOR:
You got a hairline fracture of your left clavicle.
JACK: Right.
Blunt trauma broke the skin.
Right.
You're lucky.
You always wear
a bulletproof vest?
Only when I see
my friends.
Look, I want you to
change the bandage on your chest
every hour,
hour and a half. All right.
And I have to
immobilize this arm,
so wear this sling.
All right. Thanks, Doc.
Wait. Where
are you going?
I still have to wait
for your lab reports.
I've got police business.
REGGIE:
Hey, man, look, I said I was minding my own business,
and then those bikers
came along and started shooting at the bus.
X-rays are fine,
Mr. Hammond.
Yeah, well, how come
my head is still hurting?
Hey, look, buddy,
you had a bus roll over on you.
Nobody said it
wasn't gonna hurt.
Look, you might have
a slight concussion
or a subdural
hematoma.
Either way,
you're one lucky man.
Now, we're gonna
hold you overnight.
We'll know more
in the morning.
No, y'all ain't
holding me overnight no place.
Me and my subdural hematoma
are going home.
I ain't spending
my first free day out in no fucking hospital.
Now,
you're gonna be here till you answer all our questions.
Are you sure you never saw
those bikers before?
Look, man,
all you rednecks look the same to me, all right?
Keep on him, Art.
I'll be right back.
Oh, great. I gotta
spend my first day out with Art,
the goddamn redneck.
Coming out
of the kitchen,
with my arm's
full of this guy's breakfast, you know.
And I'm worried
'cause I don't want to be late, you know,
'cause he looks funny.
Not like just
he's hungry,
but like he's mad
at something.
And then,
the next thing I know, there's these big gunshots,
and the window's
breaking, and...
Reggie Hammond.
When can I see him?
Hey, look,
if it was up to me, I'd help you out.
They're gonna
keep him overnight. You know, observation.
Hey, that's one
lucky guy, you know.
I'd like to follow him
around the racetrack.
You know what I mean?
You know what that guy
was in the joint for?
No.
That son of a bitch
is a child molester.
He's involved
in kiddie porn.
Now, I got to get him back
to San Francisco by tonight,
so that he can
identify the kingpin of the organization.
If I don't get him
back there by tonight,
the goddamn kingpin walks.
Hey, Reggie.
You want to go
for a ride in a Cadillac?
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Look, man, I've been having a fucked-up day,
and the last thing
I wanted to see was you.
Come on, Reggie,
I'm just trying to help you out.
Of course,
you could always catch a bus.
You had
a lot of luck on the last one.
Look, just do me
a favor, Jack,
and just disappear.
Stay away from me,
all right?
I'm sorry, Reg.
They released you
in my custody.
(TYPEWRITER CLACKING)
(WOMAN CHATTERING OVER PA)
All right,
let's get down to business.
You ever seen
those bikers before?
Jack, my memory
gets a lot better
when I got money
in my pocket.
You know
the rules, Reggie.
Soon as you tell me
why the Ice Man wants you dead,
I'll think about
giving your money back.
Hey, why don't you
ask that guy
who you got my
picture off of?
He's not talking
real good anymore. I killed him.
Very smooth, Jack.
What, they paying you
by the pound now?
Well, he shot
at me first,
only we can't
find his gun.
That's why I'm
in the shitter.
Hey, Jack,
if you're looking for sympathy,
you've come to
the wrong person, okay?
I'm supposed to be
on my way to Florida
to be in my uncle's
used-car business.
Instead,
I'm here with you, I'm broke,
I've been shot at,
I was in a bus
that flipped over 20 times,
I had glass all in my hair
and all over my suit,
broke my Walkman,
and lost my James Brown tape,
and plus, I've been hit
by a big fucking truck.
So leave me alone,
okay, Jack?
Well, life's
tough, Reggie.
I ran into your friends,
too, today.
They shot me in
the chest six times.
You don't look bad
for a dead person.
I would be
if it wasn't for one of these.
Yeah, why do you
wear this, anyway?
Well, I knew I was
gonna see you, Reg.
Now, I wouldn't
want to get killed by a stray bullet
that was meant
for you.
Now, that'd be
a hell of a way to go, wouldn't it be?
That's very
sensitive, Jack.
You think
maybe I should get one of these?
Well, you can
get these anyplace.
You can get 'em
at sporting goods.
They run
about 750 bucks.
A little more
than they gave you
when they let you out,
right, Reg?
Jack, I hope you at least
still got my Porsche.
Oh, yeah.
It's safe and sound back in the city.
I took
real good care of it like I said I would.
Hey, man,
look, just 'cause you said
you gonna do something,
don't mean you gonna.
You said we had a deal
and you fucked me.
I fucked you?
You fucked yourself.
You stole the payroll
out at the prison.
They found the money
in your cell.
I checked into it.
Motherfucker,
I got framed. Oh, yeah, yeah.
Some convict got a guard
to open up the cell,
put the money
underneath the pillow like the tooth fairy.
Yeah, you got framed.
That's what
every convict says.
Hey, what about you, man?
You know they never found
that bad guy's gun out at the racetrack.
That's different.
What's different about that?
I'm a cop.
You're a crook.
Get the fuck out of here!
Just because I'm a convict,
everything that comes
out of my mouth is a goddamn lie?
That's right.
So just screw Reggie Hammond?
Man, just take me to my goddamn car.
I'm through with you.
What's wrong?
Your arm hurt?
Yeah. Thanks
to your friends.
Hurt bad?
Yeah.
Good.
You hear the news?
Yeah, well,
we got a problem here, slick.
Hey, man, back up.
I'm not the one
that hired these hillbillies,
so don't come
complaining to me, okay?
Yes. Plan B.
We got
an ex-Marine on the case.
Only problem is
he's a hillbilly, too.
Yeah.
Right.
Later.
How much of my money
did you spend, anyway?
Oh, about 25 grand.
You said I could
buy a new car.
Well, where is it?
This is
the new car.
This look like the same
piece-of-shit, sky-blue Cadillac you had before.
Yeah, I bought
the same model, year, color,
everything the same.
That's the way I like it.
I get attached
to things, Reggie.
You got the same car.
Same clothes. Yeah.
You got the same girl, too?
Elaine?
Hell, I don't want to
talk about this shit.
Well, this is good.
Keep it all balled up like a nut.
JACK: She married me
about five years ago.
Drove me over to city hall
for a quick ceremony.
She figured
she'd settle me down.
This is where we
lived until we split up.
She moved up
to Mill Valley.
I've been trying
to sell it.
Twelve grand of yours
went for the down payment.
Man,
how could you leave my car outside all these years?
Why didn't you put it
in the fucking garage?
Look at that dirt all over it.
What if somebody stole it?
Yeah, I had an alarm
put on it.
Here, you just push
this blue button right there.
You have no appreciation
whatsoever for what's hype.
That's what it is.
You don't know that that car is fly.
You know
how much pussy I got because of that car?
(ALARM CHIRPS)
(HUBCAP CLATTERING)
They blew up my car!
It's a damn shame.
They blew up my goddamn car,
and all you got to say
is, "It's a damn shame"?
No car. No money.
You're having a bad day.
That's it.
I'm through with you, man!
I'm calling some of
my fucking homies.
I'm getting a loan
and I'm stepping the fuck off!
(METAL CLATTERING)
(TRAM BELL RINGING)
Buster! Hey, what's up, man?
How you doing? Reggie Hammond.
Yes, my brother!
Yeah, I'm out, my man.
I'm on the street again.
Yeah. Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Just--Just cool it,
brother. Yo, listen.
No, no, no, listen.
Yeah, I know. I'm gonna do that.
I know.
I'm gonna take care...
That's what I'm
calling about.
I need a loan.
Uh-huh. Yeah,
I know I owe you some shit, but I need a loan.
Now, I just got out of jail.
Brother, my brother,
everything's gonna be...
Yes, listen.
No, I don't have
no collateral.
I just got out of jail, man.
The fuck I need
collateral for? This is Reggie Hammond.
Hey. Hey.
Hey, Buster? Buster?
(PHONES RINGING)
KEHOE: Jack.
JACK: Yeah?
What the hell's going on?
We got a report
you were shot and your house blew up.
No, not my house.
A car.
Well, the fire department's
still out there.
Your car blew up?
No, no, it wasn't my car.
It was some other guy's car
parked in front.
Listen, anything
come in on those bikers that hit the prison bus?
No, not yet.
I'll check again. All right.
Look, Jack, do me a favor
and go see Wilson.
He told me
if you won't see him right away,
he's gonna send
somebody out to get you.
Shit.
Hey, Jack. You okay?
(SIREN WAILING)
(DISPATCHER CHATTERING
OVER POLICE RADIO)
Hey, you giving
that guy a ticket?
Good. He hates cops.
He does, huh?
Yeah, I rode
down here with him.
He told me that
cops ain't shit
and that y'all was
just pussies that hide behind your badges.
And he also said
that he gonna park this car,
he don't care if it's
a no-parking zone,
and if I see a cop,
tell the cop to kiss his ass.
So kiss his ass.
Your friend's
not too smart.
Yeah, I know.
He's a big dumb-ass cop named Jack Cates.
Shit.
Tell Cates to stop parking
in front of the station.
(PHONE RINGING)
WILSON: Hello, Jack.
First, the motorcycle track
and then the diner,
and now we found
a bomb at your house?
And I'll bet
the Ice Man's responsible for it all, right?
I'm not gonna stand here
and argue with you.
Man to man,
I'm here to support you.
However, as Supervisor
of Internal Affairs,
it's my job to tell you
that you're still on suspension,
at least
until the court hearing tomorrow.
So, why don't you give me
that gun and your badge and police ID?
Yeah. Right.
I'll bet you think
I enjoy this, don't you?
Jack, do me a favor.
Go home and get some sleep.
I got to go down
and check on a few things.
Make out some reports.
You know, I don't mind
people checking up on cops.
I don't think
we're above the law.
But making cops do it,
it's bad for morale.
It's bad for cops.
Civilians ought to do it.
You're a real
chickenshit, Wilson.
But maybe it's
not your fault.
Maybe it's your job.
(COMPUTER BEEPS)
All right.
(BEEPING)
Yo, Marvin!
Hey, what's up, man?
Reggie Hammond.
Hammond. Reggie Hammond.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
How you doing, man? I just got out.
Yeah, my brother, yeah.
Listen... What?
You a born-again Christian?
Get the fuck out of here.
No, man, it's just...
No, I just can't picture you,
you know,
being no-born again...
I was there
when you beat the bitch up, now.
No, no, don't get me wrong.
I know you can find Jesus.
Everybody can find Jesus.
No, I love Jesus.
I love Jesus. I love Jesus.
I love... Hello?
Hello? Hello? Marvin?
Hey, Willie Biggs!
Reggie Hammond.
Hello? Hello?
Black motherfucker.
MAN: Here you go, Jack.
Thirteen complaints
involving biker-types in the last four days.
Two traffics
and a D&D up in North Beach.
Run these guys
through the NCIC.
I'll have Cruise
do it.
Don't look much
like a biker to me.
Nice talking to you.
You still here?
I didn't think
you'd stick around.
If you think I'm happy
about being here,
you can guess again,
all right?
I'm supposed to be a free man
with money in my pocket
and getting
along with my life,
and the last thing
I wanted to do
was get tied to
your big, dumb, white ass again.
(CHUCKLING)
Welcome back, Reg.
Get the fuck
off me, man.
I ain't no fucking
convict no more. I'm a free man.
And you?
You about a inch away from where I was yesterday.
So you ain't
running jack shit, okay?
Let me tell you something.
I ain't working for you,
I don't like you,
and I don't trust you.
All right,
now just cut the bullshit.
Just give me something
I can use, Reggie.
The Ice Man?
The Ice Man
bought your house.
Now, God damn it,
I said cut the bullshit.
I can't believe
you didn't put this shit together yet, man.
Me and Ganz
robbed somebody for half a million dollars
a couple years back.
That was the Ice Man,
and he's still
pissed off about the shit.
Yeah, it's amazing how money
affects some people, ain't it, Jack?
I see your wheels
turning.
Yes. Yes. The man that
you've been looking for all this time
bought your fucked-up car
and put a down payment
on your house for you.
And you've been riding around
in the car that he bought for you, looking for him,
which makes you probably
the dumbest motherfucker in law enforcement.
Get in the car.
I'm driving.
You got a fucked-up arm,
and I'm not getting in another wreck.
I, unlike you,
have a lot to live for.
(CAR HORN BLARING)
I always wanted
a chauffeur, Reggie.
Hey, man,
I recognized one of those bikers
that attacked
the bus today.
His name is Cherry Ganz.
He's a fucking lunatic.
He's Ganz's brother.
Ganz's brother?
Yes, he makes Ganz
look like Gandhi.
Why in the hell
would the Ice Man hire Ganz's brother?
Think about it.
I ratted Ganz to you, and you killed Ganz.
Who'd want
to kill us more?
Ganz said his brother
used to fuck this bitch named Angel.
All he used to talk about
was how insane the pussy was.
Said the bitch worked
at a place called Barnstormers or something.
Barnstormers.
Yeah, we got a complaint a couple bikers
rousted a bar
called Barnstormers.
Wait a second.
The cops are actually contributing
to this investigation?
I'm shocked.
Now, wait. How the hell
do you remember where this girl works
after seven years
in prison?
Hey, Jack,
after seven years in prison,
you remember
every story about pussy you ever heard. Trust me.
Wait a minute.
I gotta get something.
Ah!
Hey, Jack,
this shit is fake.
So what?
People don't know the difference
when you flash it fast.
REGGIE: Somebody spooks
that fake badge in there,
and you fuck around
and get your ass whipped,
don't come crying to me.
I ain't got nothing to do with it.
You just watch
your own ass, Reggie.
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ We were two lovers,
one of a kind
♪ We shared a love
that we were lucky to find
♪ We were as close... ♪
I'll go get some info.
A barmaid called in
the complaint.
You go do your
cop shit, Jack.
I'm gonna
check out these hoes.
All right.
Hey!
You're the one that called in
the complaint on some bikers?
Oh, well,
call the 6:00 news.
Cops finally responded.
Only been a day
and a half, you know.
Are you gonna tell
me what happened,
or you gonna bitch
a little more?
I'm gonna bitch
a little more.
You guys are never here
when somebody needs you.
Can I have
a shot of Stoli?
On the rocks?
Yeah. Great.
Hey, how you doing?
Hi. Buy me a drink?
Oh, baby,
I just got out of jail.
I'm dead cracked,
but you can buy my drink.
Fuck off.
Hi.
I know you, right?
Yeah, you do.
You broke my heart once.
(CHUCKLES) Did I?
I'm not letting you
get away this time.
I'll be right back.
I'll be right back. Well, take mine.
I just have to
powder my nose.
Just powder my nose.
I'll be right back.
(CHUCKLING)
Hey.
Hey, how you doing?
I'm pretty good.
How are you?
I'm all right.
Yeah.
Hey, you ever see
those commercials on TV
with the tourists?
With the guy
with the big nose?
Karl Malden.
The big-ass nose man.
Did you ever see
those commercials where he shows the people
getting their pockets
picked in slow-motion?
Yeah.
Shit!
Yeah. Shit is a good word
to say there. Right.
But, listen, I can get
your money back for you,
but it's gonna cost you.
How much?
I think half your money
would be good.
Half? Give me a break!
I'm giving you
a break, man.
You ain't got
nothing now.
The bitch is in the back,
counting your money.
Listen, she's gonna get
your credit cards,
run your rate up,
and your credit's gonna be all fucked up.
Look, you don't want
to do it, fuck you.
You got a deal.
I figured I had a deal.
So the guy with the dark hair
starts asking about this girl
who used to work here,
then he gets rough,
starts grabbing me and stuff.
And the blond one
pulls out a gun.
Cute, huh?
What about this girl?
Angel?
She stopped working here over a year ago.
She's dancing
at the Bird Cage up in North Beach.
Hey, aren't you
supposed to be writing all this down?
I got a photographic memory.
Now, you got an address,
or where she lives?
This is
the ladies' room.
You're not
supposed to be in here.
Well, y'all are leaving,
so mind your business.
Hey.
I thought this would
be a good time
for us to get to
know each other.
You're very smooth.
Very, very smooth.
I've seen a lot of
pockets get picked,
but I ain't never seen
nobody as smooth as you.
I was just talking to
the guy that you hit,
and he's so upset.
I told him that
I'd come in here,
and I'd get
half his money back for him.
That is, unless, of course,
you offer me a nice little bribe,
then I'll go out there
and I'll tell him
that you was
a bit too fast for me.
I am too fast for you.
Hi. Almost finished.
Was anybody else with them?
No, they came in,
just the three of them.
There was this black guy.
Yeah, skinny.
Yeah, the oldest one
was talking to a black guy.
A black guy, huh? Here.
Was it something like this?
Yeah. Yeah. That's him.
He was okay.
He didn't bother me.
Now, look,
if they come in again,
I want you to call down
to the department.
You ask for
Inspector Ben Kehoe.
He'll know what to do.
You're in luck.
Here's half your money.
Great. What about
my credit cards?
We had no credit card deal.
I said your money.
Your cards are
still in the bathroom.
♪ Gotta give it all you got
♪ Till you drop
♪ Now sometimes you win
and sometimes you lose
Jack Cates?
Remember me?
No, I don't think so.
You busted me in the backseat
of a Camaro with a girl!
That don't sound like me.
Turns out
she was underage, but I didn't know it!
Well, you know,
shit happens!
And I didn't steal
that car, either.
My buddy did!
Maybe you'd better
pick better buddies!
I gotta go see somebody!
I got two years!
Oh, come on,
give me a break!
I don't want to
get in a bar fight!
People are always
getting in bar fights!
It's a damn cliche!
You hear about
it all the time!
You see it in
the motion pictures!
People are getting
hit in the head
with them damn beer bottles
and furniture.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
♪ Give it all you got,
all you got
♪ You got to give it
♪ Give it all you got,
give it all
♪ Give it all you got ♪
(SHOUTING)
(GRUNTING)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
I'm taking two years
out on your ass, Cates!
You got a gun?
What?
You know, a gun.
In case they stick the place up.
All right!
Knock this shit off!
I have been having
a very bad day.
I just got out of jail
this morning.
Already, I have been shot at,
I was on a bus
that flipped over 17 times,
bitch tried to stab me
in the bathroom,
and somebody
blew up my Porsche.
I am in a bad goddamn mood.
Now, I usually don't
jump in when somebody's getting beat down,
but this man, Jack Cates,
is gonna help me
straighten out the rest of my day.
Now, I suggest y'all back up
and let us go
about our business.
'Cause you got a gun?
No. Because I have a gun
and I'll pop a cap in your ass.
I don't think
you've got the guts to use it.
(SCREAMING IN PAIN)
Anybody else want to limp?
Sorry about the kneecap.
I got a little, um, excited.
Pretty smooth, Jack.
You know how to handle an investigation.
It's your fault.
You disappeared on me.
Where in the hell
were you?
I was in the bathroom
taking care of some business,
then I got to come out
and save your ass.
I didn't need your help.
I was not helping you. I was protecting my money.
I knew this wasn't
gonna be easy.
I shouldn't have gone in there
without my goddamn spare gun.
I go in there
and I get in a goddamn fight.
A bar fight! Jesus, Jack!
What the hell
are you doing?
Hey!
Yo, man,
what was that for?
That was
for the basketball.
Now we're even.
We can start fresh.
Yo, man, I got to get
the hell out of here, or I'm gonna do a homicide.
The deal is off.
Fuck this. The deal's off.
Oh, the deal's off.
Bullshit.
Come on, let's go.
Get in the car.
Come on.
Hey, Jack,
was you born a shithead,
or did you take
lessons to get like this?
Oh, I was just
getting even.
Now don't take it
so damn personal.
Come on, let's go.
Let's get in the car.
Man, I told you before
to stay away from me, right?
Stay the fuck
away from me, Jack. I mean it.
Hey, don't be stupid.
Where you going?
Away! Away from you!
That's where I'm going.
Hey! Your tip
turned out okay.
Ganz's old lady lives
down in the tenderloin
at the King Mei Hotel!
Bye, Jack.
Fuck you, Jack.
Shit!
(DOT-MATRIX PRINTER BUZZING)
Okay, here's the story
on one of the bikers.
Just came in.
"Ganz, Richard, aka Cherry.
"Known member of
Western Brotherhood Motorcycle Gang.
"Seven outstanding warrants,
details to follow.
"Seventy-two outstanding
traffic violations."
LA bike gangs?
Yeah, LAPD
faxed up some stuff a few minutes ago.
Supposed to be
a whole lot more coming in.
All right.
I'll be right over.
WILSON: Why is he
on the streets?
The man is on suspension!
Jack, coming to the station
ain't such a good idea.
Wilson's looking for you.
Oh, Christ.
He heard about the bar.
All right,
be out in front in 15 minutes with everything you got.
You got it? 15 minutes.
Kehoe, get in.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Give me that.
Here, you take the wheel.
What?
Steer.
Jesus Christ, Jack.
Got it?
Yeah.
"Hickok. Ganz."
This guy is
Albert Ganz's brother.
Yeah, I know
all about that.
Did you know
they're cop killers?
Capped two chips
and a bystander five days ago.
I talked to a
special investigations guy in LA,
said these guys are
enforcers for their gang, the Brotherhood.
Last two years,
they've been linked to over 15 deaths.
Brake! Brake!
Christ.
Got anything else?
No, nothing hard.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(CAR HORN BLARING)
Jack, just go around
the block, will you?
It's too easy.
(MEN CHATTERING)
GUARD: Kirkland Smith!
Yeah!
You got a phone call.
Reggie Hammond.
Reggie?
REGGIE:
Hey, Kirk. What's up?
Is it done?
Look, it's a little bit
more complicated than that.
Don't mess with me,
Reggie.
Let me tell you something.
You ain't a citizen no more, man.
You can't vote.
Ain't nobody
gonna hire your ass.
You an outcast.
Nobody wants you.
Now all you got left
is your word.
Don't break
your fucking word to me.
(DIAL TONE DRONING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING
IN CHINESE)
REGGIE: It's a nice
place, huh?
What took you so long?
I thought you quit
for the fifth time.
What is it?
You can't stay away?
I'm gonna hang, Jack.
I'm gonna hang,
and we're gonna straighten this shit out.
But let me tell
you something, man,
if you hit me again,
if you grab me,
if you touch me,
if your hand brush
up against me lightly,
I'm gonna kill you,
Jack. I'm serious.
Don't worry, Reggie.
I'm gonna
treat you right.
The only reason
I let you get away with some of this shit
is 'cause I know
you got shot,
and your mind not be
acting right 'cause you're in a lot of pain.
Which arm is it?
Your right or your left? Oh, it's my left one.
It hurts like hell.
The doc says
it's bruised down to the bone.
To the bone?
Yeah.
That's a deep bruise.
Oh, God!
Now we even, motherfucker.
What do you mean?
God damn it!
I just got even
for the basketball, you son of a bitch!
Yeah, well, give me
my money back,
then you can hit me
in my face with the ball.
Now wait a minute, Reg.
Now, let's...
We're just gonna go and talk to this girl.
Right?
Don't snake me, Jack.
No, I'm not gonna snake you.
If she's here,
we're just gonna talk to her. All right?
I mean, this is just
straight-ahead cop stuff, isn't it?
Here.
Thank you.
Give me that.
(WHISTLING)
So, when's Cherry
coming over?
Don't worry.
He'll be by.
He said you were
real nice.
He was right.
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
We never hear
of her.
Heard of her now?
(SCOFFING IN CHINESE)
That fake badge.
My kid
get one of those.
Your kid got one of these?
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
Angel Lee, upstair.
Fourth floor, 4-B.
Okay.
Chances are
she hasn't even seen this guy.
I mean,
he's in town for a hit.
He's not gonna stop off
and pop his old girlfriend.
Yes, he will, man,
and then share with his friends.
They're like Eskimos.
All right,
you wait down here.
I'm going up
and see the lady.
No. Wrong.
I ain't waiting down here.
I ain't got no gun.
What am I gonna do
if these bikers show up? Make a mean face?
You got a pistol.
You stay here and watch this shit,
and if she's up there,
I'll shout down.
All right, all right.
Here, you want this badge?
No. I don't think I'm gonna
run into no little kids on the way up.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING FAINTLY
IN CHINESE)
(MAN AND WOMAN
ARGUING IN SPANISH)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING FAINTLY)
(MEN ARGUING)
(METALLIC DINGING)
(KNOCKING)
Yeah? Who is it?
REGGIE: I have a pizza
delivery for Miss Angel.
I didn't order
any pizza.
Uh...
It says, um, uh, room 4-B,
Miss Angel, pizza delivery.
Hang on a second.
I got to get something on.
(WHISPERING)
She naked!
I didn't order any pizza.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(BOTH CHATTERING IN CHINESE)
No fucking way!
Fucking pig!
I killed you!
(SHELL CASINGS CLATTERING)
You can't be alive!
I already killed you!
(YELLING IN CHINESE)
Call for help! Now!
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
ANGEL: What is going on,
God damn it? Where you going?
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
What's up? Wait!
(SCREAMING)
You killed my family, pig!
I'm gonna kill you!
Fucking asshole.
Fucking pig!
Motherfucking pig!
Cherry, get going!
Let's go!
We got to get going!
Motherfucker, die!
(GUN CLICKING EMPTY)
(BELLOWING IN FURY)
Come on.
Come on!
They're out back! Jack!
(TRUCK HORN BLARING)
(WOMAN SHOUTING IN CHINESE)
Down the alley.
(SCREAMING)
(BELLOWING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
Yeah, we got
the perimeter secured. Jack's okay.
I haven't had a chance
to get a statement from him yet, though.
I don't know
whose gun he used.
Look, I'll get
a statement from him...
I'll get the statement,
okay? Fine.
You know,
you're in deep shit. You know that, Jack?
Tell me something
I don't know.
I ran this guy
through NCIC.
I couldn't come up
with a match on him.
(EXHALES)
That figures.
(POLICE RADIO CHATTERING)
Okay.
Right now you're looking
at accessory to murder one.
That gets you five
to 10 years inside,
and that's with
good behavior,
unless you cooperate
with us,
and then you might not do
any time at all.
Look, I told
the other cop.
I got nothing to say
until I talk to a lawyer.
Are you protecting
this guy Cherry
because you're
in love with him?
I can certainly understand
why a girl could fall in love
with a guy like that.
What's he do?
Blow through town once or twice a year,
let his friends
jump up and down on you,
get drunk, and beat
the shit out of you, huh?
I can understand why a girl
would love a guy like that.
I totally understand that.
Look, I don't know
where they're at.
They move around
all the time.
I can never get
in touch with him. All right?
Well, who can?
I don't know.
Those guys are nuts.
Don't worry
about anything.
This is officer
Jack Cates.
Mr. Cates,
Miss Lee here
was about to help us out with the investigation.
I think she was about
to tell me the name
of Mr. Cherry's contact man.
The guy's name
is Malcolm Price.
He's big, spooky eyes,
long hair.
Nobody talks to Cherry
unless they talk to him first.
Okay. Now, where
do we find this guy?
I don't know.
Hey.
I swear.
I only know a name.
Thanks, babe.
Hey, wait a minute!
Hey, Jack. Hey, Jack.
Where in the hell
do you think you're going?
Radio back to Kehoe,
and tell him to
run up a shit sheet
on a biker
named Malcolm Price.
Good bet he's got
a long record.
We're out of here.
I got to get
a statement.
Hey, man, your ass
is gonna be grass. I'm telling you now.
At the rate we going,
you'll probably pick up Price at my funeral.
Don't worry
about your funeral.
If the Ice Man gets you,
we won't even find your body.
You know
what it is, man?
We need to go somewhere
and talk to somebody
who knows about
stuff like this.
Okay, where?
Honestly?
Yeah.
We should go back
to prison. Oh, bullshit.
Hey, man, you got any
other better ideas
on how to find out something
about Malcolm Price?
I got a guy on the inside
who knows everything about everybody.
He can finger
anybody, man.
Plus, it wouldn't be
a bad idea for you to go to prison, anyway,
'cause you might be spending
some time there real soon,
and I think
it'd be a real good job for you to go get reacquainted
with some of the brothers
whose rights you violated.
Oh, don't give me that!
I just arrest crooks.
I don't make 'em steal.
Jack, you don't
get it, do you?
You make it sound
like everybody went down to a guidance counselor,
took a test,
and the results came back,
crook was the only job
they was qualified for.
Oh, that's a real
good story, Reggie.
Blame it on society.
Put it on
society's shoulders.
Let me tell you
something, Jack.
If shit was
worth something,
poor people'd be born
with no assholes.
(RINGING)
Yeah, it's me.
I heard about it.
Well, hey, man, I warned you
about dealing with these crazy-ass crackers.
What? No, I ain't carrying.
That ain't my thing.
You know that.
Look, I'm a businessman, too,
but I just don't want to get
too close to these guys.
You know, man,
these cats are taking all of the fun
out of my work.
Right.
Yeah, I remember.
I remember.
I said you don't have to
remind me of it, okay?
Don't worry about it.
I'll pull it together.
Good morning, Kirkland.
You got some visitors.
INMATE: Hey, man,
will you shut up over there!
All right. Hold on.
Get that picture of the guy.
He's a small-time dealer.
His name is Burroughs.
Recruited by the Ice Man,
I don't know, a couple of months ago.
Okay, I wanna
know, like,
do you know anything
about the guy he's supposed to work for?
This main dude
named Malcolm Price?
Yeah, I know him.
Western Brotherhood.
You want these guys
to do a hit for you,
you got to go
through Price.
You got an address?
I'm not 411.
You look it up.
Sunset Motel on the beltway.
And give the phone
back to Reggie.
What's his problem?
I don't know.
Say, man,
do you mind?
I'm trying to talk to the brother here.
I'll handle this.
Can you excuse me?
Me and my brother want to talk, you know.
It's black stuff.
Excuse us.
It's private.
You mind? You mind?
Yeah. Hang on.
Just... Look,
can you go over there, please? Thank you.
It's private.
All right, all right.
Reggie, look.
Now that I've given you
something you need
for the second time...
Yes, you have,
and I appreciate your patience,
and thank you.
You will
repay your debt to me!
Hey, man, not to worry.
We got lots of backup.
Come on in and have a drink.
(SILENCED GUN FIRING)
(GROANING)
(BODY THUDS)
Malcolm Price.
Must have been
a real good lead, Jack.
Somebody shot him
16 times.
I've been chasing
this goddamn Ice Man for years.
Every time I get close,
it's another goddamn dead end.
This job will
drive you crazy.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Jack, the Ice Man's a cop.
No way.
Hey, come on, Jack.
Put this shit together, man.
Jack, think about it.
You called for
Price's address.
The Ice Man
shows up there first.
It's a coincidence.
Bad luck.
That ain't no
damn coincidence.
What about the brother
whose picture you've been showing around?
You get any
feedback on that, yet?
Well, that don't
mean nothing.
You gotta run a mug
shot through NCIC.
It takes time
to get a make.
How long that take?
Hours.
It's been hours.
Well, sometimes it's slow.
Come on, man.
That's a lame excuse, Jack.
Let me tell you
why the Ice Man wants to kill me.
Has nothing to do
with the money that I took, okay?
That's fly shit to him.
He want to kill me
because I seen him, Jack.
I can identify him.
I'm back on the street.
He thinks I can
blow his cover.
The same guy
that's trying to kill me
is fucking up
your investigation.
Find out which guy is
putting up the most resistance 'cause you're on this case.
That is probably
the Ice Man.
Only guy it could be
is Wilson,
and that prick's
been dogging my ass for years,
ever since
I started looking for the Ice Man.
All through
this thing.
Listen, I got to get you
over to the hearing so you can ID this guy.
Come on.
What hearing?
The one where
they're going to decide
whether they're
gonna put me in jail
and take away my
badge for good.
Started two hours ago.
WILSON: After the incident
in the Mission District,
Inspector Cates
dredged up this theory
of a criminal mastermind
running the drug traffic in the Bay Area.
For four years,
in my opinion,
he has wasted
department resources and manpower,
risked other officers' lives
to vindicate himself and his theories.
Can you describe
Inspector Cates' professional attitude?
When a police officer
takes it upon himself
to violate
department regulations and suspects' civil rights,
it makes it hard
on every good cop
who's out there
trying to do his job.
Objection, Your Honor,
these remarks
have nothing to do with the incident at hand.
On the contrary,
Your Honor.
I'm trying to show
a pattern of behavior on Inspector Cates' part
that will illuminate
the events at Hunters Point Raceway.
I'll let the testimony stand.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
JUDGE: In consideration
of the preliminary evidence
presented thus far
by the State
and in adherence to the laws,
statutes, and rules
as specified by
the State of California,
city of San Francisco...
There he is
right there!
(GAVEL BANGING)
JUDGE: Order! Order!
Please, let's have
some order here. This is an official hearing.
No, it's
some other guy.
No, no, no!
Right there!
I'm looking at him, Jack.
It's somebody else. That's not him.
No, God damn it,
that's gotta be him.
Who are these men?
That, Your Honor,
is Inspector Jack Cates.
That's definitely
not the guy.
No, that's got to be
the goddamn Ice Man. People change.
Hey, man, you don't
forget somebody you took half a million dollars from.
That's not him.
Well, God damn it, it's gotta be him!
That's gotta be
the Ice Man!
JUDGE:
This is too much!
This court rules
that there is sufficient evidence
to proceed with
a criminal trial
against Inspector Jack Cates.
Trial date will be set
for the earliest opening on the court calendar.
This hearing is adjourned.
(GAVEL BANGS)
(DISTANT SIRENS WAILING)
Ice Man
whacked out Price.
You want to talk
about it?
The man had no choice.
Your girl ratted him out
to the cops.
Bullshit.
I don't bullshit.
You both know her.
She works as a dancer,
lives at the King Mei Hotel.
You know, you two should be
a little bit more careful
about who
you hang out with.
Who pulled the trigger?
What's the fucking difference
who pulled the trigger?
The cops were
getting too close.
That's the way
the Man does business.
Business, not personal.
You know,
you two fucking hillbillies should learn the difference.
Business.
Yeah.
(GROANING)
That's business, too.
(LAUGHING)
You happy now, asshole?
That still doesn't
change the job.
You got to kill
Reggie Hammond.
And how are we gonna do that?
Kirkland Smith,
he's the dude
who kept Reggie alive in the joint
when we had
papers out on him.
Reggie owes him.
I figured out where
he's gonna pay back.
The dude's got a daughter
works in the Goodwill store
in the Haight
just off Central.
Well, you know
what we're gonna do?
We're going to get Hammond,
and we're going to get
the cop,
and the Ice Man,
and we're going
to kill them all.
You just stick to Hammond,
Joe Bob.
That's the gig.
(PHONE RINGING)
I keep forgetting
the combination.
Hey, Jack, I don't want
to see you clear out your locker, man.
Let's get back
out on the streets.
We can get this guy.
You know, Reggie,
I've been a cop for 20 years,
and all I've ever
been around is pimps, murderers, and robbers,
but between you and me,
I've always been straight.
Now, you did your best.
So, here's your 475 thou.
You kept my money
in your locker?
Yeah.
In a police locker,
Jack?
Yeah. Hey, we got
no more ties.
You're a free man, Reg.
Now, listen,
my advice to you
is take this money
and disappear.
You sure, man?
Yeah.
All right.
Thank you.
Have a nice day.
(WOMAN CHATTERING)
Hammond. Reggie Hammond.
This is $75,000,
courtesy of your father.
This money comes
from Kirkland Smith?
It's got to be dirty.
Hey, wait a second, now.
We both know
your father's no angel,
but this money
is not stolen.
Your father did
a favor for me. I just got out of jail.
Had some money
before I went in.
I owed some money
to your father,
and he thought
it would benefit you.
A lot of fathers
wouldn't even do this.
I think
you should accept it.
Bye-bye.
Mr. Hammond.
How is he?
He's good.
You should go see him.
Maybe.
No. No maybe.
You should go see him.
(WHIMPERING)
Shh. Shh. Shh.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hey.
Hey, Ben.
Sorry I couldn't
help more, Jack.
It's all right.
You did what you could.
It'll be
pretty fucking dull
without you
around here.
(CHUCKLES)
Can't believe
you're not coming to work tomorrow.
Get a beer?
Maybe later.
You got a bunch
of messages, Frank.
Thanks, Joe.
(RINGING)
Yeah.
CHERRY: We got Hammond.
Good.
Is he dead yet?
There's a change
in plans.
Killing one of us
wasn't part of the deal.
What kind of shit
are you trying to pull?
You want this guy dead.
We want 500 Gs.
That's the price for you doing
one of the Brotherhood.
What the hell are
you talking about?
500,000, or we let
Hammond finger you.
There's a place
out of Modesto...
What, are you nuts?
No way.
You want more money,
pick a new place,
something indoors,
something with lots of people.
Hey, Jack,
this just came in.
Some guy named Burroughs
looks just like the guy you were after.
They found him dead
in the Mission a little while ago.
Here's his sheet.
It's a mile long.
I circulated
this guy's picture at the precinct last night.
I got nothing.
That's funny.
Cruise busted him
last July.
Cates, even though
there's no love lost between us,
I just want you
to know it hurts me
to see a man
throw away his career.
So let's let
bygones be...
(PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
Hey, I'm looking
for the Cage club.
The upstairs part.
Fifth floor.
You got to join. 50 bucks.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(COUNTRY-ROCK MUSIC
PLAYING ON STEREO)
You don't look
too happy, Reg.
Sorry, babe.
Look me up later,
and I'll buy you
a drink, all right?
(MEN WOLF-WHISTLING)
Where's Hammond?
Who's the girl?
Just somebody
he was with.
Five hundred Gs, right?
Now, let's check
the merchandise.
Take him out
behind the building and blow him away.
Shoot the girl, too.
Shoot both of them.
Yo, man,
what's this guy doing here?
Thought you said
the Ice Man was gonna bring you your money.
That guy
ain't the Ice Man.
You're just trying
to save your ass, Reg.
That's bullshit, man.
That ain't the Ice Man.
That guy is a cop.
You're getting set up.
They got
the wrong guy,
don't they, Cruise?
Hello, Jack.
It's Christmas here, Willie.
We can take 'em all.
Hammond, the pig, the Ice Man.
The whole ball of wax.
That's him!
That's the Ice Man,
right there.
Pretty good, Jack.
You always were
a smart cop.
You know, Ben,
I really didn't want to believe it.
Sorry to let you
down, Jack.
All I want
is the Ice Man.
You two take the money.
Get the hell out of here.
Ain't nobody leaving here
with my money.
Money? I want
the fucking Ice Man!
(BELLOWING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
Get the fuck out of the way!
(RAPID GUNSHOTS)
(BELLOWING)
(GROANING)
Come on, you fuck!
Somebody help me!
Shut up!
Get away! No! No!
You fucking bitch!
You fucking bit me,
you fucking bitch!
(SHOUTING)
You set me up, Ben!
You never ran that shit
through NCIC.
You had Cruise
pick up the gun that day at the track.
I needed leverage
on you, Jack.
You were getting close.
(BELLOWING)
(GUN CLICKS EMPTY)
(CLICKS)
(CHUCKLING)
(WHOOPS)
(CLICKS)
(CHUCKLING)
Fuck you!
Jack, we can work this out.
Just let me out of here.
You're a disgrace, Ben.
Nothing worse
than a bad cop.
Hey, Jack,
thank you for a very pleasant day.
Okay?
I got no car, I got no money,
and I'm gonna
fucking end the day off
with this goddamn
dope man's Uzi by my temple.
Thank you, Jack.
Look, this is Jack's day.
Why don't you just
let Jack shoot me? Save your bullet.
Jack, why don't you
shoot me?
Shoot me, Jack!
(SIREN WARBLING)
Coming through.
Oh, Jack.
I can't believe
you shot me, man.
This shit hurts, man.
Well, I told you,
you should have bought a damn bulletproof vest.
You did good, Reggie.
You did real good.
Doc says you's
going to be fine.
Guess I'm
a pretty good shot, huh?
You're going to
have to take it easy for a while.
I'm sorry
you had to knock your friend, man.
He wasn't my friend.
You're my friend.
Besides, I had to save
my partner, didn't I?
I got this
off the Ice Man.
It's 500 grand.
I'll meet you
at the hospital. We'll talk about it,
okay?
JACK: Here.
Hold this for me.
(SIREN WAILING)
(THE BOYS ARE BACK IN TOWN
PLAYING)
♪ Well, there's a reason
everybody should be shakin' in the house tonight
♪ And you should grab
your favorite lady
♪ And promise her
you'll do it right
♪ Tell Fat Jack
to jump back and give you a shot of some booze
♪ So you can party to some
stomp-down, butt-bumpin', rock & roll, rhythm & blues
♪ 'Cause the boys
are back in town
♪ The boys are back in town
♪ I know that everybody
when they hear the music
♪ Will be doin' it
on the floor
♪ Jump up and down,
they turn around
♪ And tell the band
to play some more
♪ So tonight you can
dance and romance
♪ And do anything
you feel like doin'
♪ So don't look surprised
'cause you know what I like
♪ And tonight
we ought to do it
♪ ' Cause the boys are
back in town.
(SIREN WAILING)
♪ The boys are back in town
♪ Oh, yeah
♪ Well, there's a reason
everybody should be shakin' in the house tonight
♪ And you should grab
your favorite lady
♪ And promise her
you'll do it right
♪ Tell Fat Jack
to jump back and give you a shot of some booze
♪ So you can party to some
stomp-down, butt-bumpin', rock & roll, rhythm & blues
♪ 'Cause the boys are
back in town
♪ The boys are back in town
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah
♪ And when the boys are back
♪ There ain't
no foolin' around ♪
Whoo!
♪ We're gonna
one, two, three, four, one, two, three
♪ Well, there's a reason
everybody should be shakin' in the house tonight
♪ And you should grab
your favorite lady
♪ And promise her
you'll do it right
♪ Tell Fat Jack
to jump back and give you a shot of some booze
♪ So you can party to some
stomp-down, butt-bumpin', rock & roll, rhythm & blues
Yeah.
♪ 'Cause you know
the boys are back in town
♪ The boys are back in town
♪ Oh, yeah
♪ I know that everybody
when they hear the music
♪ Will be doin' it
on the floor
♪ Jump up and down
they turn around
♪ And tell the band
to play some more
♪ So tonight you can
dance and romance
♪ And do anything
you feel like doin'
♪ So don't look surprised
'cause you know what I like
♪ And tonight
we ought to do it, oh, yeah
♪ The boys are back in town
♪ In town, oh, yeah
♪ The boys are back in town ♪