(♪ Fanfare)
(♪ Theme music)
(CIock ticks)
(Sighs) Most exciting. Hm.
(CIock chimes)
Goodness, Ian wiII be here in a moment.
I must go and get ready.
Oh? Who's that?
Grandfather!
I toId you about him dozens of times.
- Her new boyfriend.
- Ooh!
Yes, I Iook forward to meeting him.
What's his name?
Ian.
Goodness, that'II be him now!
Susie, be a dear
and answer the door, wiII you?
AII right.
(WhistIes)
- GIad you dropped in.
- OK, so you caught me again.
Grandfather, this is Ian Chesterton.
- I am so very gIad to meet you at Iast.
- Oh, hi.
- Oh, excuse me.
- How extremeIy kind of you.
Most thoughtfuI. Thank you.
They're for Barbara.
They're soft centres. Her favourite kind.
Oh, yes, of course, yes.
WeII, she was here a moment ago.
WeII, er, never mind. Why don't you
sit down whiIe you're waiting for her?
- (SqueIching)
- Oh...
Soft centres.
WeII, never mind.
PIenty more where that came from.
(Laughs)
- (Gasps) No! Wait!
- What is it?
A super-ionised
eIectro-kinetic pre-osciIIator.
And you nearIy sat on it.
Years of research work.
Part of my new invention.
WouId you Iike to see it?
Come on. Come on, I'II show you.
He wouIdn't understand.
Anyone can understand science
if they onIy put their minds to it. You can.
WeII, that's different.
- Oh, weII, Iet's give HaroId a chance.
- Ian.
- I beg your pardon?
- Yes, my name's Ian, Dr Who.
Oh! How do you do?
Yes, yes, weII, come aIong, then.
Come aIong.
Thank you, Susie.
Off we go. (ChuckIes)
After you, erm... Yes, right.
There. My Iatest invention.
- What, a poIice box?
- Of course not!
- This is TARDIS.
- TARDIS?
It stands for Time And ReIative
Dimension In Space.
- Oh.
- Go inside. Go on.
- Yeah?
- Mm.
(Beeping and whirring)
(Dr Who chuckIes)
(Ian Iaughs nervousIy)
(Beeping and whirring)
But it's so big in here and yet
it's so smaII from outside. How come?
In eIectro-kinetic theory, space expands
to accommodate the time necessary
- to encompass its dimensions.
- My IittIe feIIow scientist.
We've been working on TARDIS
for many years.
This is the finaI component.
You are priviIeged, young man,
to be the first visitor
to our time and space machine.
There. I can now set the controIs
for anywhere in time and space
that we wish to go.
When I push that Iever,
this room and everything in it
wiII dissoIve into their respective
component eIectricaI charges.
We're aII made up of them.
These charges
wiII then be transferred in time and space
and reassembIed in their proper order
and their proper pIace.
Er, weII, I think I ought to be, er...
Oh, I thought you'd aII be in here.
- HeIIo, darIing.
- HeIIo.
(Whirring)
Young man,
do you know what you have just done?
You have transferred us in time and space
and I haven't even set the controIs.
Now I don't know where we are.
We couId be anywhere in the universe
and at any time!
Rather exciting, isn't it?
Look, I don't know how you do the magic
with the inside of this room,
but as far as being somewhere eIse
in the universe... (Laughs)
Let's see where we are.
(Beeping)
- Grandfather, where are we?
- Susan, dear, don't go too far yet.
There must have been a forest fire.
The heat must have been indescribabIe.
It's turned the earth into ashes.
Oh, weII, the soiI can't be that bad.
It stiII grows these shrubs and trees.
Look at that.
Ooh!
A petrified jungIe!
How interesting.
This is most interesting.
WeII, if it's aII the same to you, sir,
perhaps we couId be making
our way home now, huh?
What, and miss the chance of Iearning
something about an unknown pIanet?
Coward.
I for one am going to investigate.
- (Dr Who chuckIes)
- Come on, Grandfather.
- Come on, Grandfather!
- I'm coming, darIing.
- Fascinating.
- Grandfather, Iook at this!
(ChuckIes) And what is it then?
By jingo!
That Iooks Iike a... Iooks Iike a tuIip.
It's a IiIium phiIadeIphicum.
Is it now? (ChuckIes)
It's a IiIium phiIadeIphicum, is it? Hm.
(Barbara screams) Ian!
(Screams)
Oh! Oh!
Oh, Ian! Are you aII right?
- Nothing broken, Iad?
- No.
It was another soft centre.
WeII, come and sit over...
Look, over here.
There we are.
We shaII never know what that was,
wiII we, Susie? (ChuckIes)
Grandfather, Iook!
- What have you found this time?
- Look!
Upon my souI! A city!
But how extraordinary!
A huge city!
Can you see any peopIe?
(Dr Who) No. No one at aII.
No Iife, no movement.
Here.
- Can you see anyone?
- No.
- Let's investigate.
- Oh, yes, Iet's!
Something terribIe happened here.
This pIace is dangerous.
I can feeI it.
- I wish we couId Ieave.
- WeII, you don't have to convince me.
Er, Dr Who.
I think we shouId get out of this pIace.
But Iook, Susan's just found a city.
WouIdn't you Iike to expIore it first?
Erm, weII, they're expecting me at home.
They'II be wondering where I am.
I... I think we shouId go back.
Aww.
Oh, weII.
(Branches snap)
(Susan screams)
Hey, hey, hey! It's me, it's me, it's me!
(Beeping and whirring)
Are you sure, Susan, dear?
It's not possibIe for any human form
to exist on this pIanet.
It was a hand! It touched me!
Hm. Then I'd Iike to find out
who or what it was.
Rather you than me.
We don't know where we are,
what period in time.
- We don't know what might be out there.
- (Knocking)
The scanner.
(Buzzing)
(Barbara) Nobody. Not a thing.
WeII, something
must have made that noise
and I don't want to find out what it is.
- Can't you set the controIs for home?
- CertainIy.
- AII set.
- WeII, you got us here.
You might as weII get us back.
- (PuIsating buzzing)
- What's the matter?
There's something wrong somewhere.
I'II try the fauIt Iocator.
(Beeping)
K7. The fluid Iink section.
That's it. The fluid Iink.
This end has been
jarred out of position.
Some of the fluid has run out.
- Have you got a spare?
- Oh, we don't need one.
This just needs refiIIing with mercury.
I have some in my Iabora...tory.
Supposing there isn't any mercury
on this pIanet.
We'II have to try the city. It's about
the onIy pIace we're IikeIy to find any.
Be carefuI!
(Dr Who) Susan!
(Barbara) Susan!
Right. Thank you, Susie.
It Iooks Iike some sort of drug.
I wonder what it is.
So there was someone here.
I shaII make some tests on these
when we get home. Yes.
Now, perhaps you'II put those inside
for me, wiII you, Susan, dear?
And now...
...for the city.
That was a steep cIimb, wasn't it, Susie?
- What's the matter?
- It's aII right, dear.
Grandfather, are you aII right?
Just a IittIe tired.
My Iegs are rather weak.
I don't feeI too weII myseIf.
Must be the aItitude.
Take a good, deep breath, Iad.
That's better. Yes.
Now, in a city Iike this,
there must be Iaboratories.
Now, that's where we couId find
some mercury.
Now, I suggest we aII take different
directions and then aII meet back here.
How's that? Yes? Right.
Now, you come aIong with me, Susie.
You take that one.
Having troubIe, Iad?
I can't get through those doors!
(Barbara screams)
Let's try the other way.
Susan, dear, you sit on there
whiIe we try to keep those doors open.
When I shout, you run just as fast
as you can. Good girI.
Ready? Now, Susan! Run! Fast!
Not too fast, Iad. Not too fast.
Come on, Iad.
- Wait.
- What is it?
- Listen.
- (Beeping)
It's coming from over there.
(Beeping)
(Beeping and whirring)
WeII!
Susan! Susan, dear.
Measuring instruments.
But to measure what, I wonder?
This is some sort of Geiger counter.
And it is past the danger point.
The atmosphere is poIIuted
with a very high IeveI of faIIout.
Then we must find Barbara
and get back to TARDIS.
Even if we do,
we can't Ieave untiI we get some mercury.
Young man, I have to confess,
there is nothing wrong
with the fluid Iink.
I just didn't want to Ieave
untiI we had expIored the city.
- PIease forgive me.
- WeII, Iet's get out of here.
You wiII move ahead of us
and foIIow directions.
This way.
He wiII recover shortIy.
Search him.
That is of no vaIue to you! It...
Come this way.
- Thank goodness, you've come!
- I'm so gIad you're safe!
Ian! Ian, what happened to you?
- Oh, it's nothing.
- He'II be aII right in a minute.
- Yeah.
- (Barbara gasps) Ian!
Don't worry. Don't worry, Barbara.
It is onIy a temporary shock.
Get him up over here. Up.
At Ieast we're aII together.
How do you feeI?
Sort of weak and giddy.
- And Susan?
- I feeI the same.
We found a Geiger counter upstairs.
This pIanet has a high IeveI of radiation,
perhaps the resuIt
of some Iost atomic war.
AII the time we were in the open,
we were exposed to it.
What's gonna happen to us,
Grandfather?
UnIess we can get some treatment,
we have IittIe hope of survivaI.
Our prisoners are showing signs
of radiation sickness.
But they have not yet perished from it.
They must have found something
that makes them immune
whiIe we must remain
in these protective machines
and cannot go out of our city.
If we had it, we couId Ieave the city,
destroy aII others
and have the pIanet for ourseIves.
Let us overhear what our prisoners say.
Perhaps they wiII give us the answer.
'If some form of Iife
does exist outside this city,
'they must have discovered
an anti-radiation drug.'
'WeII?'
'That box of gIass viaIs
we found outside TARDIS. Remember?'
One of you four
must go outside the city.
- Which wiII it be?
- Why?
Many centuries ago,
there were two peopIes on this pIanet.
OurseIves, the DaIeks, and the ThaIs.
After the neutronic war,
our forefathers retired into the city,
protected by this cIothing.
Most of the ThaIs perished in the war.
Those who survived
and remain on this pIanet
are horribIe mutations, monsters.
They have a drug
which cures the sickness of radiation.
If we get the drug,
we wiII give some to you.
Without it, you wiII die.
None of us is weII enough to go.
One of you must.
I'II go.
- Susan!
- It's too dangerous.
Hurry.
(Lightning crackIes)
(Thunder booms)
The young one is approaching the forest.
She wiII be there in a moment now.
If she returns with the drug,
am I to aIIow the prisoners to use some?
No. Their onIy vaIue
is to bring us the drug
to dupIicate for ourseIves.
Let them die.
Oh, dear.
I'm so sorry.
It was aII my fauIt.
Oh, dear, he's getting worse.
What does he mean, it's aII his fauIt?
There was nothing wrong
with the fluid Iink.
And now the DaIeks
have taken it from him.
(Barbara) What are we going to do?
Nothing we can do. Just wait.
Hope nothing happens to Susan.
(Lightning crackIes, thunder booms)
(Lightning crackIes)
(Branches snap)
Who's there?
(Thunder booms)
(Beeping and whirring)
(Door Iatch cIicks)
Who are you? What do you want?
My name is AIydon. I am a ThaI.
I tried to speak to you
in the forest just now.
I'm sorry I frightened you.
I came back to make sure
you knew how to use the drugs I Ieft you.
But I found no one here.
The others are prisoners
of the DaIeks in the city.
- There are peopIe in the city?
- They sent me back for the drugs.
Do they want them for themseIves
or for your friends?
I don't know. I don't trust them.
I shaII give you a second suppIy
which you must hide as best you can.
Thank you. But I don't understand.
They said you were mutations.
There were many mutations
after the finaI war.
Most of them perished.
But this form, two hands, two eyes,
has aIways been best for survivaI.
But they caIIed you monsters.
If they caII us monsters,
what must they be Iike?
(Beeping)
Have you brought anything eIse
from your ship?
No.
(Susan screams)
You are hiding something.
Show it to me.
Give these other drugs to your friends.
- Here's yours, Barbara, dear.
- Thank you.
So, a ThaI gave you this cape, Susan?
Yes. His name's AIydon.
He toId me his peopIe Iive far from here
but this year their crops were ruined
and they came here in search of food.
'He said his peopIe wouId gIadIy
give the DaIeks the formuIa for the drug
'if the DaIeks
wouId give them food in return.'
We do not need their formuIa.
Now that the girI
has brought us the drug,
we can make it ourseIves.
We wiII rid ourseIves
of these protective machines,
move beyond the Iimits of the city
and destroy the ThaIs.
No, there is a better way.
Let us offer them food,
bring them into the city.
- A trap?
- Yes.
WiII they not suspect anything?
Not if the message
is written by their friend,
the young girI.
Ian!
I have brought you
more food and water.
- The smaII one is to come with me.
- What for?
You have the drug.
When are you going to set us free?
Stay!
We are going to heIp the ThaIs,
which is what you want us to do.
How do they know
we wanted to heIp the ThaIs?
Add this:
"The DaIeks
"want onIy to heIp you
"and to be friends."
Now sign your name!
'(Dr Who) I've found it.
'Up there.
'That's how they know
what we're doing.'
AII we wanted was this message.
When the ThaIs come
to coIIect the food,
we wiII destroy them.
What on earth are you two doing?
We'II be abIe to taIk
without them seeing or hearing us.
- (Ian) Is it coming away?
- Yes.
(Ian) Right, puII hard.
I'II hoId you. Agh!
Our prisoners are inteIIigent.
And perhaps dangerous.
Why not exterminate them?
They have been usefuI to us once.
They may be again.
First, Iet us exterminate the ThaIs.
ShaII we repIace the Iens?
No need.
We have Iearned enough
from our prisoners.
And we have them
where they can do no harm.
They're bringing the ThaIs into a trap.
Isn't there anything we can do?
If we couId find a weakness
in the DaIeks, just one...
They are protected,
they can move easiIy
and they have weapons
which can paraIyse or destroy.
- There is nothing we can do.
- Then the ThaIs are doomed.
Suppose the DaIeks refuse to heIp us.
Then we shaII have to start back
for our own country.
- Across the desert? Many of us wiII die.
- But if the DaIeks have food,
- how can they refuse it to us?
- Look.
I found this at the gates of the city.
It is from the young girI.
She says that the DaIek peopIe
wish to make friends with us.
Food wiII be Ieft for us
in their great haII.
- We are to coIIect it tomorrow!
- (Excited chatter)
Stop! How do you know
you can trust the DaIeks?
Their ancestors
waged a great war against us,
destroyed our pIanet,
caused aII this devastation.
But that was Iong ago! Now they wish
to make friends with us, offer us food.
There's no reason
not to beIieve their good intentions.
We wiII go to the city of the DaIeks
in the morning.
(MetaI cIanks)
The doors, the waIIs, the floor
are aII made of metaI.
Perhaps this is the DaIeks' weakness.
(Barbara) What do you mean?
Whenever they move,
there is a famiIiar odour.
(Barbara) I've noticed that.
I was trying to remember where...
A fairground. You get the same smeII
from the dodgem cars.
It's ozone, made by eIectric sparks.
EIectric power.
Not the sort of eIectricity we know,
but some form of static eIectricity.
Those armour suits they wear
are actuaIIy machines that pick up their
power through the metaI of the floor.
Now, if we couId insuIate those machines
from their power source,
- they wouId be hopeIess.
- Yes.
But what can we use as an insuIator?
- My cape!
- Susan!
It's made of
some sort of pIastic materiaI.
It shouId be thick enough.
Sure. It's gonna be easy, isn't it?
"Excuse me, Mr DaIek,
wouId you care to move onto this cape?"
Move back from the door!
You, take the food.
They aIways stay outside in the corridor.
You can't get near them
without being seen.
CouIdn't we smash that Iens in their eye?
Or throw Susan's cape over it?
Then what do you use
to insuIate him from the floor?
Hmm...
(Barbara) I think I've got it!
If he's on time,
he'II be here any second. AII ready, Iad?
Just a IittIe farther away from the door,
Susan, dear.
Too cIose wiII make him suspicious.
AII ready, Barbara?
He's coming.
Take this.
It must Iast you tiII tomorrow.
What is happening?
Why do not the doors cIose?
- (Barbara) DaIek!
- Yes? Agh!
HeIp me! HeIp! HeIp me!
- HeIp me! HeIp!
- Here! Tie these!
HeIp me! HeIp!
Prisoners trying to escape!
HeIp me! Cannot see them!
Cannot see them!
HeIp! Cannot see them!
- HeIp! HeIp me! QuickIy!
- (Barbara) Grandfather!
- (Ian) I've got him!
- They must not get away!
- (Ian gasps)
- HeIp me! HeIp me!
HeIp me! HeIp me!
It worked. WeII done, everybody.
Do you think he's dead?
Now, you and Barbara
go and keep watch on the corridor.
Come aIong, Iad.
Move it over to there.
CarefuI!
They couId stiII be dangerous!
Pick up the cape.
How does this thing open?
Can you manage it?
Put it over there.
- Now what?
- Now you get inside.
- What for?
- Pretend you're a DaIek.
If we meet anyone,
you're taking us to be questioned.
- Yeah, but what if they find out?
- We'II be no worse off than we are now.
Come aIong, get inside, Iad!
Speed is essentiaI!
Hatch coming down.
- (Ian) Now I can't see anything.
- What?
- (Ian) I can't see anything.
- The eye.
(Ian) Hey, this thing's fuII of controIs
in here. ShouId I try a few?
Oh, for heaven's sake, no,
don't touch a thing! We'II move you.
Ready, Barbara? Right, on with it.
Susan, show us the way the DaIeks
took you when you went back to TARDIS.
AII right.
Turn Ieft at the end of the corridor.
This is the way I came.
There's a big door with a DaIek on guard.
Beyond the door is the Iift.
Now it's up to you, Iad. Courage.
- (Ian) Ow.
- Ooh, sorry.
Stop.
(Ian) The prisoners have been caIIed
for questioning.
(DaIek) I have not been informed. Wait.
I won't go! I won't!
HaIt her! HaIt her!
HeIp me get them inside.
ShaII I heIp you take them
to the fourth IeveI?
(Ian) No. CIose the doors.
That was cIever of you, Susie!
I have just passed the prisoners
into shaft seven.
(DaIek over radio) 'Stand by.'
(Ian) Can you get me out of this thing?
It's hot in here.
Yep.
(DaIek over radio) 'There is
no movement order for the prisoners.
'HoId them.'
- (Ian) Hurry up and get me out of here!
- We're trying, Iad!
The door is Iocked.
They must have fused it.
Emergency aIarm!
- (AIarm beII rings)
- (Ian) What was that?
- An aIarm beII! They know we've escaped!
- Try to push it up from the inside!
- (Ian) What do you think I've been doing?
- WeII, try harder, Iad!
They're cutting through the door!
The Iift has stopped
just short of the floor.
We'II never get him in.
Let's try. (Groans)
(Ian) Leave me!
No sense in us aII being captured.
(Barbara) No!
(Ian) Leave me!
(Dr Who) One, two, three
- (Dr Who groans)
- (Barbara) Ian!
How Iong wiII it take
to cut through that door?
- Not very Iong.
- But even if he does get out,
he's stuck down there!
This is the onIy way of escape!
- Grandfather, we can't just Ieave him!
- What can we do?
Look!
Stop it! Stop it!
Bring it down!
- Oh, Ian!
- How did you manage it?
(Lift whirrs)
We must find a way out.
The ThaIs are coming
for their food suppIies.
They're waIking
straight into an ambush.
Our orders
are not to capture them.
They are to be
compIeteIy destroyed.
They must not escape.
They must die.
I understand.
(Susan) Hurry up!
Hey! Give me a hand!
(Ian) Now, one, two, three!
We must warn the ThaIs!
HeIp!
(Machines beep)
Got it!
It's a trap! Go back! Run!
(Dr Who pants)
Thank you for warning us.
I'm sorry... we were not in time
to save your friend.
But I don't understand why.
Why did they want to kiII us?
We came in peace.
You are different from them,
and they are afraid
of anything different.
And what peopIe are afraid of,
they try to destroy.
If we couId reason with them...
They are beyond reason.
They wish onIy to conquer.
- What can we do, then?
- Why, fight them!
We're a peacefuI peopIe.
We see no reason to kiII others.
But even when you know
that they wouId kiII you?
The Iast war destroyed
aImost everything on this pIanet,
Ieft it... Iike this.
- We do not want another.
- That is understandabIe.
I wish there was some way
we couId heIp you.
You must go.
We shaII survive.
Goodbye.
And good Iuck.
Madam.
Yes.
Come aIong, chiIdren.
- Goodbye.
The drug of the ThaIs
has been dupIicated.
Good.
We wiII test it on this work section.
If it is effective,
we wiII discard these machines
and go out and destroy the ThaIs.
(Beeping)
- (Susan) Check.
- Check. Barbara?
Check.
(PuIsating buzzing)
Hm.
- Check.
(PuIsating buzzing)
The fluid Iink!
Oh, no. What are we going to do?
- We must get it back.
- How?
OnIy the ThaIs can heIp us.
We'd Iike to heIp you.
You saved many of our peopIe.
But we do not wish to kiII others.
And I do not want
any of my peopIe to be kiIIed.
Supposing the DaIeks
come out of their city and attack you?
They couId find a way
of getting out of the city.
They have weapons, you have none.
We wiII not fight.
'Out of controI.
'HeIp me. HeIp me.
'Out of controI.'
This is the section
to whom we gave the drug.
It is obvious that we DaIeks
cannot use the drug of the ThaIs.
We wiII not be abIe
to Ieave these machines
or go out of the city.
Then we wiII destroy the ThaIs
without Ieaving the city.
We wiII expIode another neutron bomb
and increase radiation
throughout the pIanet
to a point where
even the drug of the ThaIs
wiII not be abIe
to protect them from it.
- When shaII we expIode the bomb?
- ImmediateIy.
These writings contain a compIete history
of our pIanet and our peopIe.
Fascinating.
AbsoIuteIy fascinating.
But these writings go back
nearIy haIf a miIIion years.
There was a great civiIisation here once.
Destroyed by the war.
But you can rebuiId it, man. Now, sureIy
that is something worth fighting for.
Why do you keep these writings?
They're the history of our peopIe.
A history that wiII end
with this generation
unIess you are prepared
to fight for its survivaI.
One of your peopIe
was kiIIed in the city.
Many others couId have been kiIIed
and wiII be unIess you take action.
We wiII not fight.
(Woman giggIes)
Lad.
Young man.
Do you know
why the DaIeks heId us as prisoners?
They wanted to experiment on us.
Perhaps if we gave them
one of your peopIe instead,
they might return the piece of equipment
they took from me.
- Take her to the DaIeks.
- You can't...
You cannot do this!
- I thought you were our friends!
- You see? You wiII fight for something.
The neutron bomb wiII be ready
for expIosion in one hour.
Good.
In one hour,
we wiII be soIe masters of this pIanet.
(ThaI) The city is surrounded
on three sides by rock waIIs.
The fourth side is protected
by mountains and a deadIy swamp.
DeadIy?
Five of us
went Iooking for food there one day.
OnIy my brother and I came back.
- (Dr Who) What happened to the others?
- We found them. What was Ieft of them.
The swamp is aIive with mutations.
It's a perfect defence for the city.
If we couId get through that way,
we couId take the DaIeks by surprise.
It'II be too dangerous for aII of us.
But we'II send a smaII party that way,
Ied by our brave friend.
The rest wiII come with us
to try to find a way to approach the city.
You wiII go with him
through the swamp.
Hey!
AII right.
What have you to report?
Our Iong-range scanners
detect movement by the ThaIs.
A Iarge party
is approaching the city waIIs.
Bring defence pIan seven into operation.
AIert aII sections.
Another group is moving
towards the rear of the city.
They cannot pass. They wiII die.
- We'II never get through!
- We must try.
- It's fuII of mutations!
- You keep your fears to yourseIf!
I don't want you upsetting the others.
Right, come on!
(Barbara) Oh, can't we rest
just a minute?
AII right, rest.
Oh, I couId do with a wash.
Hey! Hey!
- I saw a great big thing in the water!
- What was it?
I don't know.
I didn't wait to find out.
- Are you aII right?
- Look!
The DaIeks
must get their water from here.
The pipes must go
straight through the mountain,
perhaps into the city of the DaIeks.
If we couId find that way...
I'II fiII the water bags.
We'II need them. I'II catch you up.
Right, come on!
- (Barbara) Oh!
- HeIp! Get me out!
Get me out!
- (Screaming)
- Stay with her.
You, come with me.
What's happened to EIyon?
Where is he?
Let's get out of here.
Come on!
The DaIeks have the entire city
surrounded with eIectronic instruments.
Now, to get past the waIIs of the city,
we must find a way of approaching them
- without being detected.
- But you're a man of science.
SureIy you can think of a way.
Yes, yes,
but it's not aII that easy, young man.
WeII, we're Iucky
they don't go underground.
We can foIIow them
straight over the mountain.
- How are we going to do that?
- We'II cIimb.
CIimb?
I was onIy thinking about Barbara.
Come on!
This is the finaI battIe.
When we expIode the neutron bomb,
there wiII be more radiation
on this pIanet
than even the ThaIs with their drug
(AII) Destroy the ThaIs!
Tonight we wiII compIete the war
which our ancestors shouId have won
many centuries ago.
(AII) Destroy the ThaIs!
(Barbara) Do you think
we're aImost there yet?
(ThaI) I don't know.
AII we can do is foIIow the pipes.
We must be
over the worst of it by now, huh?
Right, come on.
Ganatus.
- I...
- Yes?
- I want to go back.
- We must get to the city!
They couId have scanners here.
I'm going back.
- No, you're not!
- We'II be kiIIed! We won't defeat them!
(Cracking)
What have you been doing?
Now there can be no question
of going back!
Grandfather!
I toId you to watch the cakes!
- Now you've burnt them!
- Oh, yes, the cakes. The cakes!
Madam!
Pardon me, pIease.
May I borrow that just for a moment?
Thank you so much.
Young man, do you have
any more of these mirrors?
- Why, yes.
- Get them, pIease.
- CoIIect as many as you can.
- Why?
They may be our way
of getting into the city.
- Ooh!
- (Barbara screams)
Here.
- What are you going to do?
- Jump it.
We'II use this as a safety Iine.
I'II go first.
Now you.
I think I need a Ionger run.
Don't worry, it's easy.
Catch!
Coming over.
You must jump. It's the onIy way.
Now catch it!
Don't worry, it's perfectIy safe.
Look, I'II catch you.
(Screams)
Oh, no!
Short-wave Iight radiations.
That shouId confuse their detectors.
(Beeping)
They are attacking our instruments.
Move. We can take them by surprise.
Stay where you are.
Do not move.
Do not move. Do not move.
You are our prisoners.
No, Antodus! No!
Hey! Get me out of here!
- He's aII right!
- Oh, what a reIief!
But why must you destroy the ThaIs?
Why can't you Iive together in peace
and share your knowIedge?
We wiII be the ruIers here.
We wiII share nothing.
We wiII expIode the neutronic bomb.
Begin the countdown.
No!
'1 00.
'99.
'98.'
The Doctor and his granddaughter
have been taken prisoner by the DaIeks.
- Now it is up to us!
- What can we do?
We can fight!
'68.'
The ThaIs are moving
towards the city once more.
But it does not matter now.
In a few minutes,
they wiII aII be dead.
Wait! I have something to teII you.
You do not know
how we came to this pIanet.
I have a machine which is capabIe of
crossing the barriers of time and space.
I wiII teII you its secrets
if you do not expIode the bomb.
We do not beIieve you are capabIe
of creating such a machine.
- It's true!
- You took a vitaI part of it from me.
Examine it. You wiII see that it must
beIong to some compIicated machine.
- I have it here.
- '52.'
Where is the machine?
In the petrified forest outside the city.
Good. We wiII examine it
and use it to conquer other pIanets.
But you couId not operate it without me.
We wiII find a way.
'43.
'42.
'41 .'
How do we get in?
'37.
'36.
'35.'
ThaIs in city. ThaIs here.
Emergency.
(AIarm beII rings)
Stay where you are.
You are trapped.
You cannot get away.
Stay where you are!
Come down! Come down at once!
Prisoners escaping.
Reporting to upper IeveI controI.
'Four ThaIs are moving
to controI room IeveI.
'Intercept them.'
'29.'
Attention.
Four ThaIs moving
to upper controI room IeveI.
- '27.'
- Destroy them.
Stay where you are.
You cannot get away.
You are trapped.
- AIydon!
- There were no DaIeks at the waIIs.
- We came into the city easiIy.
- Then there must be a reason.
'24.
'23.'
(CIattering)
Ian, no!
Come on!
Barbara! Look behind you!
(Dr Who) Lad!
Stop the countdown!
The bomb wiII destroy the pIanet!
DaIeks!
- Susie, are you aII right?
- What happened?
(Whirring)
- Barbara.
- They're aII dead.
Yes.
That's my Iucky number.
AII set for home.
Let's say goodbye to our friends.
Come aIong.
Quite a reception.
You saved our peopIe
from the ruIe of the DaIeks.
We do not have much
with which to thank you,
but we wouId Iike you to take these
to remember us.
- How very kind of you.
- Thank you.
Thank you so much.
We wiII treasure them.
Thank you.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
- (Barbara) Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye!
- (Ian) Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
- (Barbara) Goodbye.
- (Susie) Goodbye!
- Goodbye.
You'II Iook pretty funny
wearing that in London.
Hey!
Thank you, Barbara.
Oh! And now we wiII return
to our own time and pIace.
- Thank goodness for that.
- Just push the Iever, Iad.
(Whirring)
Ah. Now if you'II open the door,
you wiII find
we're back in our own IittIe garden.
AIways nice to get home, isn't it?
(♪ MiIitary drums beat)
Hey! You ought to see what...
Look out! They're coming!
(Screeching and beeping)
WeII, do something!
(♪ Theme music)