Brother...
Mother...
It was they who led me to your door.
A man's heart has heard two ways through life.
The way of nature.
And the way of grace.
You have to choose which one you'll follow.
Grace doesn't try to please itself.
It accepts being slighted, forgotten, disliked.
It accepts insults and injuries.
Nature only wants to please itself.
Bless our lord this food...
Get others to please it too.
...loving and faithful service...
It likes to lord it over them.
...Bless these boys...
To have its own way.
It finds reasons to be unhappy.
When all the world is shining around it.
And love is smiling through all things.
They taught us, that no one who loves the way of grace,
ever comes to a bad end.
I will be true to you,
whatever comes.
My son.
I just want to die. To be with him.
He's in God's hands now.
He was in God's hands the whole time.
Wasn't he?
My home.
My God.
I shall fear no evil.
Fear no evil, for you are with me.
What did you gain?
Be not far from me, for trouble is near.
Go on now, we're alright.
We're alright.
Thank you.
Shouldn't have your memories of him.
You have to be strong now, and...
I know, the pain will, it will pass in time.
You know, it might seem,
hard, my saying that, but it's true.
I don't want it to.
Life goes on.
People pass along.
Nothing stays the same.
You still got the other two.
The Lord gives and the Lord takes away.
That's the way he is.
He sends flies to wounds...that he should heal.
I never got a chance to tell him how sorry I was.
I even...
punched himself in the face for no reason.
You sit next to me at the piano
and I criticized where he'd turned the pages.
I might even feel ashamed.
Why shame?
Poor boy. Poor boy.
How did you come to me?
In what shape?
What disguise?
I see the child I was.
I see my brother.
True.
Kind.
He died when he was 19.
Just check, this one against this.
She wants to get back together.
But, the chapter's closed, the story's been told.
What are you gonna do?
Experiment.
When you're young, it's all about your career.
I just feel like I'm...bumping into walls.
The world's gone to the dogs,
people are greedy and keep getting worse.
I try to get into their hands.
Hey dad, I'm sorry I said what I said, I'm...
Yeah, I think about him every day.
I just shouldn't have said what I did, I'm sorry.
What are you thinking? I know, I know what you did...
And only two of those were turned down by client...
How did I lose you?
Wandered.
Forgot you.
Find me.
How did she bear it?
Mother.
Was I false to you?
Lord...
Why?
Where were you?
Did you know?
Who are we to you?
Answer me.
We cry to you.
My soul.
My son.
Hear us.
Light up my life.
I search for you.
My home.
My child.
You spoke to me through her.
You spoke with me from the sky.
The trees.
Before I knew I loved you,
believed in you.
When did you first touch my heart?
...and manfully to fight under
his banner against sin, the world, and the devil.
We're having Mr. McMander over for dinner.
This is a double bidder right on in.
What's this?
- Two alligators. - Two alligators.
- Kangaroo. - Kangaroo.
Jump. Jump. Jump. Jump.
Sweetheart.
Please.
I know.
No! No!
It's mine!
You found me!
You'll be grown before that tree is tall.
Blue far.
You.
Are you afraid?
Come here.
Come here. Alright, now come back here son,
stay out of there. That's Spencer's yard, okay?
You see this line?
Let's not cross it, you understand?
Do you understand?
Do you see this line? Look it here. Look here.
Okay, now come back here son. Come on back.
Let's stay out of there.
"Now, my dears," said old Mrs. Rabbit one morning,
"You may go into the fields or down the lane."
"Don't go into Mr. Mcgregor's garden."
"Your father had an accident there."
That's where God lives.
Goodnight, we'll see you in 5 years.
Want to eat a grasshopper?
I found it! I found this old bone!
Oh, is that a rock?
No.
Bless this food to our use.
As to your loving and faithful service.
Make us remindful of those who are in need.
Amen.
Can you pass the butter, please?
Can you pass the butter please sir.
Sir.
- What did you do today? - We went to school.
After that.
What about the yard?
Did you put the runners in like I asked?
Yes.
Yes, sir.
Well, it didn't look like it.
Yes.
Mr. Reese liked Jack's book report.
Nobody's asked sweetheart.
You know this.
Crowns!
- Son. - Sir.
Reach me my lighter.
Haven't you forgotten something?
Do you love your father?
Yes, sir.
...and they went off to look for Kaa the Rock Python.
They found him stretched out
on a warm ledge in the afternoon sun,
admiring his beautiful new coat.
Who do you love most?
I love you all three the same.
Tell us a story from before we can remember.
He went for a ride in a plane once.
It was a graduation present.
Mother...
Am I any good?
Brave.
Can it happen to anyone?
Nobody talks about it.
Help me not to sass my dad.
Help me not to get dogs in fights.
Help me be thankful for everything I've got.
Where do you live?
Help me not to tell lies.
Are you watching me?
I want to know what you are.
I want to see what you see.
Come here.
You're going to stand there and
you're going to close this door quietly, 50 times.
Count it out.
You can't just take off the top.
You got to get them by the roots.
Your mother's naive.
It takes fierce will to get ahead in this world.
If you're good, people take advantage of you.
Every one of these top executives,
you know how they got where they are?
Floated right down the middle of the river.
Don't let anyone tell you there's anything you can't do.
Don't do like I did, promise me that.
Dreamed of being a great musician.
I let myself get sidetracked.
If you're looking for something to happen, that was it.
Life, lived it.
Job imagined he might build his nest on high.
That the integrity of his behavior
would protect him against misfortune.
And his friends thought mistakenly
that the Lord could only have punished
him because secretly he had done something wrong.
But no.
Misfortune befalls the good as well.
We can't protect ourselves against it.
We can't protect our children.
We can't say to ourselves, even if I'm not happy,
I'm going to make sure they are.
We run before the wind,
we think that it will carry us forever.
It will not.
We vanish as a cloud,
we whither as the autumn grass.
And like a tree, are rooted up.
Is there some fraud in the scheme of the universe?
Is there nothing which is deathless?
Nothing, which does not pass away?
We cannot stay where we are.
We must journey forth.
We must find that which is greater than fortune or fate.
Nothing can bring us peace, but that.
Is the body of the wise man or the just, exempt from any pain?
From any disquietude, from the deformity
that might blight its beauty from the weakness,
that might destroy its health.
Do you trust in God?
Job too, was close to the Lord.
Are your friends and children, your security?
There is no hiding place
in all the world where trouble may not find you.
No one knows when sorrow might visit his house,
any more than Job did.
At the very moment everything was taken away from Job.
He knew it was the Lord who had taken it away
Return from the passing shows of time
he thought that which is eternal.
As he alone see God's hand,
who sees that he gives.
Or does not also the one see God's hand,
who sees that he takes away.
Or does he alone see God,
who sees God turn his face towards him?
Does not also he see God,
who sees God turn his back.
He's a friend of mine.
The one who's after real estate in town.
Frank Johnson.
Started out as a barber.
He built something, big.
Now you'd think he was the fourth person of the Holy Trinity.
They never talk about their money.
Wrong people go hungry.
Die.
Wrong people get loved.
The world lives by a trigger.
You want to succeed? You can't be too good.
Hey there young fella, try my cornbread.
Do y'all want some butter, do you?
How about a pound of bread?
You'll like this right? Okay? Come on.
Act like you're in trouble,
you don't want to fight, you don't want any trouble.
The minute you see him blink, crack him!
Okay?
Okay, come on, three quarters.
Cover, you're going to cover, right?
Okay, here. Come on, nice, harder, nice.
That's a good right, let's see your left.
This is the most important thing.
Okay? You come in this way, keep your guard up.
Hit me, come on, hit me. Come on, Jack? Hit me.
Hit me, come on, come on!
Okay, here it is, hit me!
Come on, son, come on!
What are you doing?
Wipe yourself off.
Left! Don't leave your tongue out, you're going to lose it!
Left. Left. Right. Right.
Left, harder.
Harder. Harder!
Hit me, hit me. Come on, son, hit.
Give me something, show me what you got.
Come on, go on.
One meal.
Leave the table.
You too?
- You going to continue to defy me? - No, sir.
You're interrupting me, I wasn't done yet.
Am I finished?
- Am I? - No.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Makes up stories.
Fortunate words.
He says don't put your elbows on the table.
He does.
Insults people.
Doesn't care.
I remember when you were born.
They wouldn't let me come home.
Navy said an officer must be present for the laying of the cue.
I had to launch.
The next word is volcano.
Next word is socket.
Please pass your answers to each other.
We're going to grade each others' papers now.
No interruptions, please.
Come on, get your pencil out.
Sweetheart! Oh God, sweetheart!
Honey!
Was it bad?
Will you die too?
You're not that old yet, mom.
Where were you?
You had a boy die.
Would anything happen?
I can't see! I can't see!
Why should I be good?
If you aren't.
Thank you.
We're close.
Why's this bare here?
The grass won't grow under the tree.
- It does at Kimbles. - They have a gardener.
They have money.
Of course he inherited it.
I don't want to hear one more word out of you,
not until this is finished.
You're cropping that too close.
You're going to have to keep that water.
Toskanini.
Once recorded a piece 65 times.
You know what he said when he finished?
It could be better.
Think about it.
27 patents, your father has.
It means ownership, ownership of ideas.
You gotta sew them up.
- Get them by the nuts. - If you pardon my French.
Be rich.
You make yourself what you are.
You have control of your own destiny.
Can't say I can't.
You see I'm having trouble.
I'm not done yet.
Can't say I can't.
Why's he hurt us?
Our father?
- Come on, Vince! Come on. - Get it, get it!
Give your father a kiss.
Lies.
- I can't. - Will you do something for me?
Do you promise you'll do it?
Without having to ask what it is?
Just have the confidence in what your father asks of you is right?
Yes, sir.
In the next half hour, will you
not speak unless you have something important to say?
What did you do today, my fine feathered friend?
Sit on the front of your chair.
It's better for your posture. I read that in the paper.
Did you actually buy this from Mr. Ledbetter?
Don't explain, just nod, yes or no?
Be quiet.
What did you say?
Please.
Leave him alone.
Leave him alone!
Come here! Come here!
Get up there!
You turn my own kids against me.
You undermine everything I do.
How do you like it?
Stop it!
Stop.
- Where's Dad? - He's gone on a trip.
Get her! Get her!
Help each other.
Do not slam that screen door!
Love everyone.
Every leaf.
Every ray of light.
Our gift.
Shut up!
- Watch out! - Watch out!
- Go. - Go!
I say let's bust them.
Found a frog!
Lets go set it off in a sky rocket!
He's getting away!
Get back! Get back!
Did he go to the moon?
- Where is he? - Here he is.
It was an experiment!
Why?
Never do it again.
Promise?
You want to tell dad?
They're just trying to scare you.
Keep your ear there.
Things she got to learn.
I gotta know stuff too.
They say you can't try stuff? They do!
What do you need be afraid of?
You're afraid. I see it.
Right here! Right here!
I can't talk to you.
Don't look at me.
Au revoir, story.
Au revoir, dawn.
Put it in there.
I trust you.
- You tired? - No. I never get tired.
- You did this morning. - No, I was just pretending.
- You call me a liar? - No.
- I don't want to fight. - Afraid to?
No, I just don't want to.
- If I was to say you're scared, would you call me a liar? - No.
You're scared, aren't you?
Quit it.
Come here!
No!
I don't want to do anything you tell me to.
I want to do what I want.
What do you know? You let him run all over you.
How do I get back?
Where they are?
This one is heavy, you're going to need two hands.
- Careful now, you know what's that? - Chinese?
That's Chinese, that's very good, yes, it is.
Your father went all around the world. All the way to China.
That's Pan Am Airlines,
that's what your father flew on.
The entire bathroom was stainless steel.
Even the wash basin.
I feel confident the deal is going through.
Nothing, forget it. I'll tell Molly to go to hell.
That's from Germany.
See that?
Put that down, son.
Can Taylor come over?
Was your family not good enough for you?
It's not going to take as long as last time?
Al dente.
It's a subjective point, you know the difference?
Subjective means it comes from your mind.
It can't be proven by other people.
It's good to see you again. Let's go, boys.
There are things you can't do.
But there are things I can't do either.
You're not to call me dad, you will call me father.
- But... - Do not interrupt!
- But you did... - Don't interrupt!
It's your house.
You can kick me out whenever you want to.
You'd like to kill me.
Dad.
Why was he born?
Please, God, kill him.
Let him die.
Get him out of here.
She only loves me!
Defend O'Lord this thy child with thy heavenly grace.
That he may continue thine forever.
And daily increase in thy Holy Spirit more and more
until he come unto thy everlasting kingdom, Amen.
See something...
Put your finger over it.
There.
Come on.
What I want to do I can't do.
I do what I hate.
You can hit me if you want.
I'm sorry.
You're my brother.
What was it you showed me?
I didn't know how to name you sin.
But I'll say it was you.
Always you were calling me.
I wanted to be loved because I was great.
A big man.
I am nothing.
Look, the glory around us.
Trees and birds.
I lived in shame.
I dishonored it all and didn't notice the glory.
A foolish man.
They're closing the plant.
They gave me a choice.
No job.
Or transfer to a job nobody wants.
Father.
I never missed a day of work.
Mother.
Tithe every Sunday.
Always you wrestle inside me.
Always you will.
You know, Jack, all I ever wanted for you was...
Make you strong and, grow up and be your own boss.
Maybe I've been tough on you.
I'm not proud of that.
I'm as bad as you are.
I'm more like you than her.
It was about all I've done in life, otherwise I've drawn zilch.
You're all I have, you're all I want to have.
My sweet boy.
Are you just going to stand there like a bump on a log?
The only way to be happy is to love.
Unless you love,
your life will flash by.
Do good to them.
Wonder.
Hope.
Brother.
Keep us.
Guide us.
To the end of time.
Follow me.
I give him to you.
I give you my son.