Downloaded from
YTS.MX
("The Dead Are After Me")
Official YIFY movies site:
YTS.MX
♪ Hear the footsteps,
noises in the night ♪
♪ Something's burning,
fire burning bright ♪
♪ Keeps getting closer,
chills me to my soul ♪
♪ They're come to get
me, hear the devil call ♪
♪ The dead are after me ♪
♪ I said the dead are after me ♪
♪ Well I saw something
that I shouldn't see ♪
♪ And now the zombies
are coming after me ♪
♪ I can't escape them,
the dead are everywhere ♪
♪ The evil's rising, does anybody care ♪
♪ The dead are after me ♪
♪ I said the dead are after me ♪
♪ There's a mad man in control yeah ♪
♪ Doin' evil in the night ♪
♪ Well we get nowhere to run to ♪
♪ Got to stand our ground and fight ♪
♪ We are the raiders of the living dead ♪
♪ Now the hunted are
hunting them instead ♪
♪ Got to destroy them,
master and the slave ♪
♪ We got to drive them
back into the grave ♪
♪ The dead are after me ♪
♪ I said the dead are after me ♪
(lively music)
(lively music continues)
- [Radio] Check report.
Armed suspect, hijacked Mill Run tanker,
heading west on Route 25.
(sirens blaring)
(lively music)
- Spotted tanker, calling car four.
(sirens blaring)
(lively music)
(horn blowing)
(sirens blaring)
(lively music)
- [Officer] Get those
SWAT men down here fast.
Yeah, with the electric stun gun.
- [Radio] Time check, 5:07.
- Yeah, this is Randall.
Here it is.
The man's some kind of a terrorist.
He's holding the people at the
Mill Run nuclear power plant
hostage until state prison
releases a group of convicts
on his list.
Whole thing's been hushed up till now,
but the police are starting
to cordon off the area.
And I think he may have some
kind of explosive device.
Yeah, I'm aware of what
happens if he blows it.
And you're close enough
to hear about it, too.
I'll call you back when
I get some more details.
(tense music)
(excited music)
(suspenseful music)
(gunshot fires)
(twine zips)
(man screaming)
(electricity buzzing)
(suspenseful music)
(gunshot fires)
(suspenseful music continues)
(punch thuds)
- Oh!
(excited synth music)
(excited music continues)
(electricity buzzing)
(man screaming)
- School okay today?
- Sure, fine.
- I don't know how you
can do your homework
with all this rock music
and still get good grades.
- Yeah, it helps me
relax. It helps me work.
- Oh, I got a letter
from your folks today.
Your dad's special project
will be finished in five weeks.
Then you're to go home.
You know, I like having
you here, Jonathan,
but at my age, I also like
a little peace and quiet.
- Oh sure, fine. Just ask.
- I took my LaserDisc player
back to the video store today
and they wanted to
charge me $175 to fix it.
I told them to forget it.
You know, that's almost
as much as I paid for it.
- Well, why don't you
let me take a look at it?
- Well, I've got nothing to lose.
(tense music)
(machine beeping)
(rock music)
- Hey, Felix.
(Felix squeaks)
Hmm, let's see what this is.
Here we go.
This is good, Felix.
You'll like this.
Warning, high voltage.
Removal of cover exposes
hazardous voltages.
I gotta use that.
(rock music)
(Felix squeaking)
(Felix munching on snacks)
(rock music continues)
(wire snapping)
(lively music)
(loud electrical beep)
Oh, damn, Felix!
- Something wrong?
- Yeah, it's Felix. I think I killed him!
- Why'd you do that?
Was it an experiment?
- Yeah, sort of.
But it wasn't supposed to happen that way.
- You're a dangerous man to know.
Just what are you cooking up in your lab?
- A new death ray.
I wanna rule this block.
- All right, but stop at the corner.
My parents still think they're
running our house, okay?
- Look, Michelle, this really isn't funny.
I killed Felix with the laser beam
from my granddad's video player.
Look, would you stop laughing?
We gotta get rid of Felix
before my grandfather
comes home from his office.
He's not gonna think this is funny.
- All right.
Maybe you've discovered something.
Think you can use that
laser ray for anything?
- You may be right.
If I leave the amplifier alone
and just take the laser beam
and the circuits out, hmm.
Do you know any good assistants?
(rock music)
- I'm beat.
Got your fast film and high speed lenses?
- Yeah.
- Good.
This place is dark and it's
gonna be a bitch to shoot.
- What exactly are we covering tonight?
- I don't know, but I think it's something
that's really gonna make the story.
- Really make the story?
And you don't know.
How do you write those bylines?
- [Randall] Talent. Pure talent.
- And modest too.
- Hey, look, all I know
is what I've been told.
The last guy who went
poking around out there
didn't come back.
- [Shelly] And do the
cops know about this?
- No.
- Well, isn't it your duty to tell them?
My job is to get the story, that's all.
- [Randall] Just where are we?
We've been driving over two hours.
- Coulter's farm.
- Coulter's farm?
Are you kidding?
That's where they found
those mass graves last year.
- No, I'm not kidding.
If you're scared, stay here in
the car and lock yourself in.
I'll let you know if
there's anything to shoot.
- Unless they shoot you first.
(door slams shut)
(lock clicks)
(mysterious music)
(mysterious music continues)
(heartbeat thumping)
(glass shattering)
(mysterious harp music)
(heartbeat thumping)
(suspenseful music)
(suspenseful music continues)
(dramatic music)
(dramatic music continues)
(tapping on window)
(car engine sputtering)
(suspenseful music)
(heartbeat thumping)
(suspenseful music continues)
(Shelly gasps)
(rain pattering)
(wind howling)
(car honking)
(car thudding)
(birds chirping)
- [Randall] What's your name anyway?
- Shelly.
Shelly Godwin.
- Mine's Randall.
- Randall what?
- Morgan Randall.
- Oh.
- Hey, let me in there.
- No, no, that's okay.
- Oh no, come on, let me do it.
- If you insist.
- By the way, thank you.
- Oh, that's all right.
- No, no, I mean it.
I really appreciate what you did for me.
- You look like a guy who has
a pretty interesting story
if a person wanted to cry.
- Don't.
You gonna be going to work pretty soon?
- Yeah.
- Can you give me to ride into town?
- Sure.
(synth rock music)
- Nice.
Nice, but I was looking for something
a little more inconspicuous.
- What for?
What do you mean what for?
What the hell are you,
one of these big gun control people?
- The hell I am.
- It's getting so a man can't
even buy a gun these days
without the damn do-gooders
and bleeding hearts
jumping all over him?
- That's true, but I
gotta look out for myself.
- I know, I know you do.
But a man's got a right to
protect himself, don't he?
He's got a right to protect his home?
- Not anymore, he doesn't.
Not with all these
liberals all over the place
infiltrating the government.
- It ain't safe to walk
the streets at night,
now it ain't safe to stay home.
- It's disgusting, that's
what it is. It's disgusting.
Now, if a man had something like this.
- You know, this is more like it.
- [Staff] You do a lot of hunting, do you?
- I've been involved in a lot of hunting.
You got shells for this thing?
- All you want.
- Good.
I'll take it.
- Have you known Ms.
Godwin long, Mr. Randall?
- Not very long, no.
- She seems like a very nice young woman.
- Yeah. Yeah, she is.
- I have a few rooms available.
Why don't we take a look?
- Okay.
- Here we are.
- Oh, this is nice.
Yeah, this is a very nice little town.
- Yeah, I've lived here all my life.
Sometimes seems it hasn't
changed in all that time.
Very peaceful here, Mr. Randall,
if you appreciate that sort of thing.
- Yeah, I certainly do.
This room is fine, Mrs. Levitt.
- That'll be $45 a week.
$60 if you want dinner.
(phone ringing)
- Hello.
Oh, hi. How you doing?
Oh, that's good, glad to hear it.
Yeah. Yeah, that is a nice place.
Look, I think that we better get
something straight right away.
I'm really glad that I helped
you out and I'm really glad
that you're feeling better
and you seem like a really nice guy,
but I just don't wanna get involved
with anybody right now, okay?
Yeah, I know this time, it's
only a date, but I just...
Well, I'd rather not, okay?
Well...
Well, my loss I guess.
No, no, I'm not mad you called.
(laughs) You wanted to see what?
Oh, you're crazy.
Yeah, when I was a kid.
You know, but...
That sounds like it would be fun.
Yeah...
Well look, why don't I meet you there?
Give me about an hour.
Okay?
Good.
(playful music)
(playful music continues)
- A tarantula!
(performers screaming)
(screams)
(slap landing)
- What's the matter with you?
(gunshots blasting)
- [Actor] I killed it!
- [Actor] Stand back,
it's liable to bite you.
Tarantula?
Shot fight holes in a divot.
(handslap)
Get at it, go on.
- Do you really know what
you're doing, Jonathan?
I don't mind donating my
video player to science,
but I'd hate to see you get hurt with it.
- No, I won't get hurt.
This is really great!
You see the voltage is
multiplied here and produces
the laser beam in this
part of the circuit.
It's this fabulous optical unit,
which can be adjusted to focus the beam
for the proper target distance.
In this case, the video
disk is the target.
- Well, I'm happy you're
so enthused about it.
Look, I'll be leaving for
my office in a few minutes,
so I'll see you later.
And please, don't burn the house down.
- (chuckles) I promise.
(mysterious music)
- Hey, babe, what do you
got in the box there?
How you doing?
Hey, I am talking to you.
- Slow down.
- We wanna talk.
- Come here, how you doing?
- Hey, I'm talking to you.
Hey, what's in the box?
(electronic beeping)
(men screaming)
(car speeds off)
(light rock music)
- What's the matter?
- I was almost attacked.
- Where? How?
- Right downstairs.
I...
Did you save me?
- Oh, is that what happened?
I went to do some target
practice on the garbage cans
and I missed.
I heard somebody scream.
- You shot one of them.
- How badly?
- I don't know. Maybe you
just burned them a little.
- You had me worried.
One murder was enough.
- Are you sure you know what you're doing
with this experiment?
- Everything's okay.
All I had to do was put
a new optical system in.
Now I can focus over long distances.
Did you bring your
family's video player over?
- Yeah, but I feel like a thief.
- They won't miss it.
- Alright.
- Look, after what's happened tonight,
you can see there's a
good use for this device.
(suspenseful music)
(heartbeat thumping)
(door crashes down)
(gunshot firing)
(suspenseful music continues)
(horn blowing)
(bells ringing)
(suspenseful music)
- [Doctor] Are you all right?
Do you need help?
- No, I just need some rest.
- I'm a doctor. Come with me.
Take a seat.
Are you from this area?
- No, Fairfield.
- Oh, quite away from home, eh?
My name is Dr. Carstairs.
What's your name?
- Morgan Randall.
- Guess you had a pretty good night out
on the town last night, eh?
- No, but I could use a drink now.
You got any?
- Sure.
Just what the doctor ordered.
Coffee.
- Cream or sugar?
- Nothing, thanks.
- Well, I take both.
Don't like it too strong.
You know, I sometimes come
back to my office at night
to do some paperwork when it's quiet,
but nothing too important tonight.
Wanna talk about anything?
I've got plenty of time.
- Look, I'm grateful for your help, but...
- Are you in any kind of trouble?
Want me to call the police?
- No.
No.
- Then, can I be of any help?
- It's a crazy world we live in.
There's a lot of strange
people around out there.
I started in on this story
about three months ago.
(mysterious music)
- Detective Kruger.
- Shelly, thanks for coming.
- Yeah.
What's happened?
- Mrs. Levitt said you
knew a man staying here
by the name of Morgan Randall.
- Yeah, that's right,
but we only met this morning.
- Do you know anything about him at all?
- Not too much.
It's kinda strange.
He was hitching a ride into town and a car
almost ran him over, so I
stopped to help him out.
He was in pretty bad shape, but
it wasn't from the accident.
So I cleaned him up a
little bit, and that's that.
Except for a movie this evening.
- That's it?
- Yeah, just about.
What's this all about?
- Come on upstairs. I
want you to see something.
(suspenseful music)
- Shelly.
- Dr. Kapek.
- Tell her.
- Oh.
I don't offer any explanation for it.
All I can do is tell you what I see.
This man has been dead
for a good two years.
- I don't understand.
- Welcome to the club.
- I feel much better
after the coffee, cleanup,
and just having somebody to talk to.
- What you have to say is fantastic,
but I can see why you
can't go to the police
with that kind of tale.
- Exactly.
- I'll get you something to eat
and you'll stay with us tonight.
I'm not so sure that your
story is as crazy as it sounds.
You may have seen something,
but not the zombies you imagine.
- Oh no, not another one.
- Another what?
- Unexpected guest.
My grandfather's a people collector.
I don't know where he digs them up.
- Jonathan, come in here.
I want you to meet someone.
- Okay, grandpa.
Come on. Keep me company.
- Jonathan, this is Mr. Randall.
He's a newspaper reporter
and he's stranded here,
so I figured we could help him out.
Mr. Randall, this is my grandson, Jonathan
and his friend Michelle.
- Could you excuse us, Grandpa?
We have some work to finish.
- Oh, not tonight, you don't.
As soon as we're finished eating,
we're gonna drive Michelle home
and we're all gonna get some rest.
After a good night's sleep, Mr. Randall,
I think it might be wise for
you to leave town tomorrow.
- Go home, Shelly.
If there was anything you could
do, it would be different.
- Hmm.
- You're not worried
about this guy, are you?
- Oh, I don't know.
He just seemed hounded by something.
He didn't say anything,
but you could feel it.
I just can't help but wonder
what kind of bizarre situation
this guy's got himself into.
- Well, he's gonna be hounded
by us for a while now.
- Interesting point of law though.
The victim's been dead for over two years.
- The law covers it.
(phone ringing)
Yeah.
Well, that's something.
Get on it.
Right.
- [Shelly] What?
- They found the car this guy was renting.
Abandoned on the road to Hollis.
- Hmm.
- (snickers) Okay, Shelly.
You're officially off the force now.
Go home.
Go to bed.
- Let me know what happens, okay?
(phone ringing)
Hello?
Morgan, are you all right?
Where are you?
- Never mind about that now.
I just called to let you know I was okay.
- Look, the police are
out looking for you.
Where are you?
- I'm not sure.
I took the main road west outta town.
- I wanna talk to you.
- It'll have to wait.
Just take care of yourself, okay?
- The hell it'll wait.
(receiver clicks)
(lively music)
(lively music continues)
- What's the idea?
- [Actor] Give me that hose!
- [Actor] Hey you.
(inaudible chatter)
Whoa.
- Shut that that off!
- Wait a minute, I'll
have to tie a knot in it.
(gentle music)
- Well, here we are.
I really appreciate you coming
out here to track me down,
but you're asking for trouble.
- Well, I may be asking for
it, but you've already got it.
There was a dead body outside your room,
and now the police are looking for you.
What's going on?
- The police aren't the only
ones that are looking for me.
That visitor didn't get there by accident.
- Is somebody else chasing you?
Why?
- I don't know.
- Who are you, really?
- I'm a news writer from Fairfield.
I was working on this story
when I got involved with these things.
I know it sounds crazy,
but I think somebody's found
a way to bring dead bodies
back to life.
Why? I don't know.
- You expect me to believe that?
- Believe it.
I've seen it.
- You're really serious, aren't you?
Well, what are you gonna do about it?
- Try and keep a low
profile for the time being.
- That makes sense.
Do you have any proof?
- That's it. Nothing.
Wait a minute.
I found this the night it all started.
I've had it in my pocket ever since.
Any ideas?
- R.C.I?
It looks like a piece of
a uniform or work clothes.
Maybe from some kind of
a factory or institution.
Yeah, I don't know what it means.
- Any idea who would know?
- Maybe one of the teachers
at the high school,
or the college?
(mutters) No.
The Historical Society
keeps all its records
at the Wilson Street Library. Try there.
No, you'd get spotted.
- It'd be worth a chance.
- Okay, let's go.
- No, you go home and keep
your nose out of all this.
- Fat chance, I'm already involved.
- You better hope not.
Go home.
I'll call ya.
(light switch clicking)
(suspenseful music)
(heartbeat thumping)
(suspenseful music continues)
(phone ringing)
(bell ringing)
(students chattering)
- My grandfather and
Randall talked some more.
- So?
- Well, this Randall's no loony,
and my grandfather takes
him very seriously.
- About what?
- About being attacked by zombies.
- Zombies?
You're not making this up?
- Nuh-uh.
I saw a special on TV about them once.
They have them in Haiti, the undead.
Here, we have them in the movies.
There, they have them for real.
- Wow, and you actually
think that we have them too?
- Could be.
- What can we do about it?
Nobody will believe this.
- I don't know, but we've gotta
try and help this Randall.
- Well, expert, you saw the show.
Where are zombies kept?
- Well during the day,
they're in their graves,
but at night, they come
out, when nobody's around.
You know they work in the fields.
- So you think they may be
buried somewhere near here now?
- It might be.
(doorbell buzzing)
(mysterious music)
- [Michelle] We don't even
know what we're looking for.
- [Jonathan] Evidence.
Something suspicious.
See? Over there, that grave's freshly dug.
- So what? Somebody was just buried.
- That may be evidence.
Let's come back tonight and we'll see
if it's just a normal grave.
You afraid?
- [Michelle] Not if you
finish your laser gun first.
- [Jonathan] Okay, come back and help me.
I just have some adjustments to make
and then connect the battery pack.
(suspenseful music)
- Oh, anything I can do to help you?
- I'm looking for some
information on local history.
- Oh, you must be another one of those
colonial history buffs.
- I'm sorry,
but I haven't come here to
study the colonial period.
- Okay.
We have a card file and you can look up
whatever it is you are interested in.
You're not from around here?
- [Randall] No, I'm from out of town.
- Oh, you're studying at the college?
- No, I'm working on a news article.
- Oh, you're not one
of those who come here
to dredge up our past.
- No ma'am.
I haven't come here to write
anything uncomplimentary.
I'd just like to know what
the initials R.C.I mean?
- What do you wanna know about that for?
The whole thing's forgotten by now.
- Well, if it's all forgotten,
there's no harm in you talking about it.
- I grew up here.
I used to see the R.C.I trucks
going out there all the time.
- And exactly where was there?
- Well, the prison, of course.
- Can you tell me something about it?
- Yes.
They called it the Rockmore
Correctional Institute.
Some of the young couples
would go up to the top
of Lookout Hill and watch.
All the lights on the island grow dim
while a man was being put to
death in the electric chair.
I watched once, made me sick.
- I guess it would.
- A lot of people were against the prison
and what it stood for.
And then there were the bells.
- The bells?
- Early in the morning,
the jailers would ring
those horrible bells
to wake the prisoners
for some awful reason.
There are some people who insist
they still hear them ring.
And the prison's been closed for 40 years.
- What's become of the property?
- Oh, nobody goes near
Rockmore Island anymore.
It's not safe.
Town Council wanted to build
a children's park there.
But too many parents objected,
especially after the scandal
that closed Rockmore.
- Scandal?
- Yeah, the head doctor at
the prison used to perform
some terrible experiments
on the prisoners.
Even on those who had been executed.
The families could never claim the bodies.
That's what started the investigation.
- And what happened to the doctor?
- After a while, they just
stopped looking for him.
- Well, thank you very much, ma'am.
You've been very helpful.
- Helpful?
Well, just don't come again.
Once is enough.
(lively pensive music)
(mysterious music)
- [Michelle] if anyone catches us here,
and you've got this gun...
- [Jonathan] Stop worrying.
We've got more important
things to think about.
- [Michelle] I don't think anyone's here.
Let's go home and forget about it.
This Randall was probably
drunk and your grandfather
was only being nice to him.
- [Jonathan] Yeah, that's possible,
but what if his story's true?
Who else is going to do anything about it?
- Look over there in the distance.
See that light?
Listen.
(mysterious music continues)
(bell rings gently)
- It's maybe Evans.
- Be quiet.
(insects chirping)
(loud heartbeat)
(suspenseful music)
- Randall's not crazy.
Look at that!
(loud heartbeat)
(dramatic music)
- Here he comes, let's go!
- Wait, let's try the gun.
- Come on, what are you waiting for?
- It doesn't work.
- Let's go!
(loud heartbeat)
(suspenseful music)
- Of all the unmitigated stupid things.
The two of you could have been arrested
at the cemetery or worse, much worse.
These are dangerous people.
We'd better contact the authorities now
before anything else happens.
- I guess you're right, but
we were just trying to help.
- Help?
You've been spending too much
time with your experiments.
You've gotta forget these fantasies
and get out in the real world.
- Real world?
Is that what you call it
with all these creeps running around?
- Well, I guess you've got me there,
but this whole situation
is pretty unnerving.
- Doctor, I don't know
if Jonathan told you,
but his laser ray really works.
- Did something else happen?
(phone ringing)
Hello?
It's Mr. Randall.
- It's the old abandoned
prison on Rockmore Island.
We're gonna have to do something.
- Well, I think we'd
better call in the police.
You can't try to do anything by yourself.
You could be walking to your death.
- But they may have Shelly
out there somewhere.
Whether you come with me or
not, I'm going out there.
- I may be nuts,
but we can't let him go out
to Rockmore island alone.
I'll tell you what,
I've got my old target bow and
I'd like to get a better look
at your laser guns.
(lively music)
(phone ringing)
- Accident Security West.
Oh, hello, Doc.
But just ask, you know I
owe you more than one favor.
Uh-huh.
Rockmore?
His name's Randall?
Uh-huh.
- I wouldn't ask for your
help, unless it was important.
Come armed, and be careful.
(rock music)
(rock music continues)
(mysterious music)
(mysterious music continues)
(zombie moaning)
(heartbeat thumping)
(man screaming)
(dramatic music)
(bell ringing)
(heartbeat thumping)
(mysterious music)
(mysterious music continues)
(bell continues ringing)
(heartbeat thumping)
(mysterious music continues)
- If you encounter any of these creatures,
always know that you can outrun them.
Now, I'm going off in this direction.
If you get into any trouble, just yell.
- Okay. Be careful.
- Oh, I will.
- Come on, Michelle.
And make every shot count.
I don't know how much power
these battery packs have.
- It's Dr. Kapek, the coroner.
He's behind all this. I can't believe it.
- Believe more than that.
We got in here, but getting
out is something else.
- Precisely right. Getting
Shelly, why did you have to
stick your nose into this?
It's none of your business.
- What do you mean it's
none of my business?
People are being killed.
Doesn't that bother you, doctor?
- A little bit,
but I've been attending
the dead for so many years.
Let's just say I'm reclaiming lives.
- And just who's your
little pal here, huh?
- Oh, he's just a young man I helped.
He's become very dependent on
my particular medical skills.
- Oh, what a cozy arrangement.
- He supplies them, you revive them.
- Oh, something like that.
- So you went from
prison doctor to coroner
in one easy step?
- Not so easy.
There are always those curious ones
who have to play investigative reporter.
Professor Canaan from the college,
young Lieutenant Michaels from
our own Police Department.
And dear old Mr. Barrett,
but they never had a chance
to talk about their discovery.
You see, they're all out here now.
(triumphant music)
(heartbeat thumping)
(suspenseful music)
- Look, there they are.
And that strange guy's got a gun.
Maybe I could save
them. Here goes nothing.
- Well, we're up here. What now?
- We gotta find a way off this roof, fast!
(suspenseful music)
(heartbeat thumping)
(electrical beeping)
- Shoot. Shoot him!
(arrow whirs)
(lively music)
(electronic beeping)
(arrow whirs)
(suspenseful music)
(heartbeat thumping)
(suspenseful music continues)
- Quick, let me try one of those.
(electronic beeping)
Shelly!
- You just don't give up, do you, doctor?
- Come with me, dear.
(rock music)
My colleague here has a
lot of explaining to do.
I hope what you have to
say is as interesting
as the lectures you used
to give at the hospital.
("The Dead Are After Me")
♪ Hear the footsteps,
noises in the night ♪
♪ Something's burning,
fire burning bright ♪
♪ Keeps getting closer,
chills me to my soul ♪
♪ They've come to get
me, hear the devil call ♪
♪ The dead are after me ♪
♪ I said the dead are after me ♪
♪ Well I saw something
that I shouldn't see ♪
♪ And now the zombies
are coming after me ♪
♪ I can't escape them,
the dead are everywhere ♪
♪ The evil's rising, does anybody care ♪
♪ The dead are after me ♪
♪ I said the dead are after me ♪
♪ There's a mad man in control yeah ♪
♪ Doin' evil in the night ♪
♪ Well we got nowhere to run to ♪
♪ Got to stand our ground and fight ♪
♪ We are the raiders of the living dead ♪
♪ Now the hunted are
hunting them instead ♪
♪ Got to destroy them,
master and the slave ♪
♪ We got to drive them
back into the grave ♪
♪ The dead are after me ♪
♪ I said the dead are after me ♪