There's some things
I never told you about Maria.
Save the details till
after the honeymoon, homeboy.
She has some problems.
Daddy, I think there's a snap undone.
Would you take a look?
I don't think so, honey.
Are you sure?
I'm not feeling very well.
Of course you don't. You're getting
married. Get used to it.
- Here we go.
- She's a bit compulsive.
Maybe I should say
compulsive and neurotic.
Yeah, I know. She's Maria.
She sleeps with a flyswatter.
Hell, if I looked like Maria,
I'd sleep with a bazooka.
So you guys got some issues.
It's called modern romance.
If you need it, there's an ice chest
under your mother's seat.
I'm okay. I feel better now.
Careful of your dress, dear.
She, uh-- She cleans the house
twice a day on her day off.
Yeah, well, at least she works.
We get to go to all those
great magazine parties.
Hey, remember Claudia from
the Elle party? Oh, man.
She's always locking
the bathroom door.
She gets suicidal
from time to time.
All women get suicidal
God, I love her.
So how long haveyou
known all ofthis?
Theyjust sort of creep up
on you, you know? One by one.
- And beforeyou know it--
- I say, don't panic.
It's probablyjust a phase.
Yeah.
Here she is.
- You guys are awfully late.
- We're supposed to be late.
- Mom, you got my train?
- I got it, dear.
- Come on, Dottie.
- I still think that dress is too tight.
I require and chargeyou both as you
will answer on the Day ofJudgment...
when the secrets ofall hearts
will be disclosed...
that if either ofyou know
any impediment...
whyyou may not be lawfully
joined together in matrimony...
do now confess it.
Howmuch doyou love me?
Oh, a thousand.
Only a thousand?
That's not very much.
I can even count to a thousand.
One, two, three, four--
Okay, a hundred thousand
million billion.
That's better.
We're gonna be late for Alfred.
Yeah, but I love the reason.
Besides, myJuliet...
wilt thou leave me
so unsatisfied?
How much satisfaction
can'st thou get in 1 1 minutes?
I'll be nicer in therapy.
How about the issues
wewere discussing last time?
Things are still the same.
He's not nice to myfriends
or my parents.
He's cheap. He flirts,
and he has a terrible temper.
But I'm a loving,
tolerant woman, so--
Oh, that feels so good.
She keeps bugging me to build
another room on to the house.
- We don't have any money, so--
- It would, of course...
put his car out in the driveway
for a couple of months.
Okay, okay.
Yes. Yeah.
Oh, right there.
Right there. Yes.
Maria, why is this new addition
to the house so important toyou?
Because I wanna have a baby.
Go deeper.
With all this talk about a baby,
how's the sex?
You go first.
- You want me to?
- Sure. Why not?
Okay.
I have a confession to make.
I fake my orgasms.
Oh! Oh! Oh!
- You what?
- I didn't wanna tell you.
I didn't want to hurtyou.
You're telling me
you've never had an orgasm?
Not with you.
Joseph, it's important
you appreciate the risk...
Maria's taking in
communicating this toyou.
Doyou think
I'm a lousy lover?
Hmm?
I loveyou, you know.
Whoa!
Tell the balcony crew
those doors are in.
Yo, Nick, you must have
fucked up big.
We is humbled byyouse
royal presence, Sir Suits.
Relax, Carlos.
Yo, Nick, I go out on a limb to get
you this job, like I always do--
I wouldn't workwithoutyou,
Joseph, mywhite patron saint.
Well, thankyou, Nick,
but the problem is...
we're about four months behind
after two months on the job.
You geniuses made the schedule.
I just took the job.
Hey, Nick, what's this?
Oh, yeah, go ahead, Tanner.
Take a look.
- Yeah?
- It's a little discovery ofCarlos's.
- Every hour on the hour.
- Holy shit! Oh, man!
This is unbelievable.
You gotta check this out.
- This is unbelievable.
- Must be the redhead.
Oh, man. Mm-hmm!
Ooh!
You guys are perverts.
Areyou kiddin'? This guy's
a national treasure. One ofa kind.
- Holy shit!
- What doyou mean?
This guy has anywhere from four to
six women a day, one after the other.
And word has it he pleases
every one of'em.
-Joseph, take a look.
- No, I can see just fine.
Oh, my God!
Here comes another one.
I don't believe it. Theyjust
passed each other and said hi.
They said hi to each other.
- Oh,Jesus.
- Tanner.
- Yeah?
- Let's check out the site.
All right,Joseph, I am. I am.
- It's gotta be an implant.
- An implant?
Yeah, an implant, you know.
A lot of guys got 'em.
It comes with a pump.
You just pump it up,
and itjust stays there...
you know,
wheneveryou need it.
- Sounds like a good idea.
- Yeah, I gotta talk to that guy.
That redhead was to die for.
Oh, man, I wanna die.
- Tanner?
- Yeah?
Does Vicky have orgasms?
- What?
- You know, does she--
Does she come when you're
doin' it, or does she fake it?
What? No!
Of course she has orgasms.
I mean, man, she goes crazy.
How doyou know?
I mean, she could be fakin' it.
You can tell. I mean,
they quiver all over.
Believe me, they quiver all over
even when they're fakin' it.
Shut the fuck up, would ya?
Come on, Freddie,
you little bugger.
Would you help me
with my tie, sweetheart?
Out, baby. Get out.
Maria, we're gonna be late.
Freddie listened to me.
He just flew out the window.
How doyou know it's a he?
Because it bugs me, darling,
so it must be a he.
How do I look?
Do I have lipstick on my tooth?
Honey, every time
we come seeyour parents...
you obsess
over the wayyou look.
Is my dress, okay? Do I need
to pull it down or anything?
You look fine.
Did you hear me?
Joseph, your tie is a mess.
Well, hello.
And how are the newlyweds?
- Hi, Dottie.
- We've been married seven months.
Yes, dear. Come on in.
Your father's
in the living room.
-Joseph, what are we--
- Surprise!
I'd say she's excited.
What would you say, hmm?
On a scale of one to ten,
about a four.
Oh, my God!
- Martini time.
- Yeah.
How areyou?
Oh, my gosh! Look atyou!
Why is it when we go to parties...
I always have to trackyou down
with a homing device?
Ifyou loved me, you'd get in
that British fantasy ofyours...
and drive me to Vegas.
Okay, let's play
"Ifyou love me," shall we?
- Go on. You start.
- Okay.
Ifyou loved me, you'd take me
to Paris on our second honeymoon.
Ifyou loved me, you wouldn't miss
your appointments with Alfred.
You'd buy us a house
in Briarwood...
with a big pool
and a little froufrou dog.
And you would stop
rearranging my closets.
A baby girl...
and an air-conditioned garage...
for my 1 97 4 Ferrari
Daytona convertible.
- I love you, Maria.
- Shut up. It's still my turn.
It can always be
your turn, sweetheart.
- Oh, baby, is that so?
- Mm-hmm.
It's your turn now.
Honey, that's enough.
Oh, we'll both know
when it's enough, darling.
Joseph, even though
I can't have an orgasm...
I still enjoy
making love toyou.
Sometimes I wonder
ifhe loves me.
I feel he always avoids me.
He never returns my calls.
His secretary, Connie,
is always apologizing for him.
That's not true.
- You're distorting things again.
-Just let me finish, okay?
Connie is embarrassed
every time I call...
because he won't
pick up the phone.
She practically admits
you're avoiding me.
She calls seven
or eight times a day.
- Seven or eight?
- Yes, you do! And you embarrass me...
in front of my secretary
and my associates.
Connie doesn't know
how to handle her because...
halfthe timeyou call,
you're hysterical.
I just need to connect with you
during the day, okay?
Just once or twice.
Is that too much to ask?
Just listen to her,Joseph.
Just listen to what she's saying.
You gotta be kidding me.
Why areyou so afraid
ofbeing close?
Why in the hell areyou
always focusing on me?
I'm just tryin' to do
myjob, for Christ's sakes...
and all we ever do in here is
talk about her problems with me.
What I do, what I don't do,
who I am orwho I'm not...
that she has an issue with.
I just-- I can't handle it
when he gets so angry.
Joseph,
what is ityou want?
I want a good marriage...
a supportive wife.
And I wanna work
all these things out...
so that we can have the baby
that she wants so much.
Joseph, Maria's doing so much
better the past few months.
She's standing up for herself.
It's wonderful.
I know.
But she's still very fragile
with you at this point.
This kind of confrontation
can't work.
You're right. I know.
It's just that I feel like I have
to stay on top ofthe situation...
or it'll fall apart.
She'll fall apart.
Hello? Tanner!
No. No, I'll meetyou
at the site.
You got a sick patient here,
Alfred. I suggestwe talk in private.
Come here, Alfred.
I have a few questions foryou.
Joseph, what's going on here now?
You're scaring me.
That's good,
'causeyou know what?
I'm not totally in control
of myself right now.
Sit down, Alfred.
What does the name
"Baltazar" mean toyou?
You're gonna tell me everything...
and you're gonna start
with this doctor.
Doyou know him?
Did you refer her to him?
No, no.
I don't know him.
All I know is, he's a sex therapist
that practices on the edge ofthe law.
They tried to shut him down,
but nobodywill testify against him.
Can you tell me
why she does this?
Forget the bullshit psycho-babble.
I need to understand!
All I can tell you,Joseph, is that
Maria exhibits most ofthe symptoms...
ofwhat is called
a borderline personality.
By that I mean
she has no real identity.
She has to look outside ofherself
for assurance, comfort, love.
She can find
no sustenance within.
- Shouldn't I have been told this?
- Oh, come on,Joseph.
You've witnessed this foryears.
I mean, her heightened personality...
her need for control
at any cost...
the fly obsession,
the phone calls.
Joseph, you lived it.
You're the expert.
Most borderlines
are incurable,Joseph.
Theyneed to be
totallyreparented.
One of our construction sites
is on Hinton Street.
I know about Baltazar.
It's not what you think.
Oh, really?
What is it then?
Do you come with Baltazar?
Is that whyyou go?
- To learn how to come?
- It's not about that.
Then what is it about?
You know what? You're a lie!
Ourwhole marriage is a lie.
- Fuckyou.
- You wanna tell me why?
I don't feel very close
toyou right now.
You don't feel very close
to me right now?
You're paying some guy
to fuckyou...
and you don't feel
very close to me right now?
- I'm your husband, for Christ's sakes--
- I don't care whoyou are.
The door is open.
Come in. Sit down.
- Listen--
- Ah, you must beJoseph.
I've been expecting you.
Maria's husband.
She's a very special woman.
Look, I don't know whoyou are
orwhatyou thinkyou do...
but I need you to do me a kind favor
and stay away from mywife.
- She's not a well woman.
- I agree.
That's why she came to see me.
Someone would have to be very
disturbed to come here seeking health.
You don't understand,
my friend.
You understand this, Dr. Fuck!
You stay away
from mywife, okay?
I know what goes on in here,
'cause I was here.
And it wasn't love or therapy.
It wasn't even sex!
It was sadistic abuse.
I hope I've made myself clear.
It's over. Now.
Cup oftea?
I'm a therapist,Joseph.
There's a reason
for everything I do.
Acting out her abuse fantasy
is what enables Maria...
to get past the guilt
and anxiety ofbeing intimate.
Ifwe don't express these fantasies,
they run our lives insidiously.
When she stops asking for abuse,
her need for it will be gone.
This is insane.
It's insane.
I'm sitting here having tea with
the doctorwho's fucking mywife...
and trying to convince me
that it's good for her.
Don'tyou get it, man?
She needs medical help.
Maria's been in traditional therapy
for seven years. Three therapists.
Which therapy doyou think
will work at this point?
Doyou know what
a borderline personality is?
They told you there was no cure,
and theywere right.
There is no
psychoanalytic cure.
The mind...
cannot change the mind.
Real change
is not a mental process.
Let me guess.
You think sex--
your sex, in particular--
will heal Maria, is that it?
Yes and no. I hold
no dominion over my teachings.
I only know theywork.
But, yes, conscious sex
that achieves bliss...
is the greatest healer there is.
So the way to heal the woman
is to fuck her?
No. Conscious sex, physically
and emotionally integrated...
is one way to heal
a human being.
Ecstasy heals the unconscious.
A woman can heal
a man as well.
Well, I hopeyou
don't mind, Doctor...
but I'm gonna try some
other approaches at this point.
I knowyou love Maria,Joseph.
I'm not here
to take that away from you.
Just don't make me
take this any further.
I am not the enemy.
I don't know whatyou are.
Oh, hi, sweetheart.
I'm almost done with the kitchen.
- What areyou doin'?
- What does it look like I'm doing?
The entire house
is infested with bugs.
First I spraywith the Raid
to kill any eggs, and then I seal.
Maria, we discussed the fact that
flies do not lay eggs in the house.
Ants,Joseph. Ants!
The wastebasket was full
ofthem this morning.
Maria, we've gotta talk.
Okay.Just let me
finish the kitchen first.
And ifyou wanna help, you can
start cleaning the bathroom.
Just go through
your drawers, okay?
Hi.
What time is it?
It's 5:45 a.m. You busy?
No. No. Of course not.
Well, I guess
we'll have some breakfast.
Maria's gettin' worse.
I'm sure she's very frightened.
Therapy isn't working.
I wantyou to teach me
whatyou do.
You want to learn from me?
I wanna learn
how to heal mywife.
That's not possible.
You fascinate me.
Firstyou want to destroy me.
Nowyou want
to become my acolyte.
Doyou play
a musical instrument?
No.
Doyou thinkyou have the ability
to put asideyour rage and listen?
Look, the rage is gone, okay?
The only thing that's important
to me now is helping Maria.
Ifl agree to helpyou...
you must understand
it means precisely that.
I'm helping you.
Maria has her own path.
I understand.
- I'm not sureyou do.
- And you have to promise me...
thatyou'll never see Maria again.
Ah! Is that whatyou're
really doing here,Joseph?
- Preventing me seeing yourwife?
- Dowe have a deal or not?
I doubt the rage is gone.
But we can put it to good use.
And I agree with you.
As I teach you
the ways oflove...
it would not be
my place to see Maria.
I saw you at the symphony
the other night.
- I followed you there.
- I'm the substitute.
I'd like to play more, but I don't
have the time to devote myself.
So, we have a deal.
You can choose to leave at any time,
and I may askyou to leave.
But the work and our relationship
must remain strictly confidential.
Doyou really
love Maria that much?
Too bad foryou.
Okay, describe to me how
you make love to a woman.
And tell me, in detail,
when and how you make love.
Well...
one of us starts
kissing the other one...
usually at night
before we go to bed.
- Then I kiss her breasts for a while.
- How?
How?
I kiss.
I suck...
twirl my tongue.
How does it feel?
Aroused.
Like I want her.
Then... kiss her tummy
for a while.
Turn her over sometimes
and kiss her bottom.
- I like to do that.
- How does she feel?
I don't know.
Then I usually kiss her
down there for a while.
Down there?
You mean, hervagina?
Yeah?
- Go on.
- And--
Sometimes, I use my fingers.
I-- So I can hold herwhile we--
You know.
Then I get inside her...
and we make love...
Iike normal, I guess.
Anything else?
Sometimes she cries.
Does Maria
ever have an orgasm?
No, I guess not.
- Not with me anyway.
- Not with anyone,Joseph.
Maria is frigid.
- Doyou make love toyourself?
- Hmm?
- Doyou masturbate?
- No. No. Not--
Rarelywhen I'm in a relationship.
Well, we'll have to change that.
How can you make love
to someone else...
ifyou can't make love
toyourself?
So,Joseph, what areyou
doing to help Maria?
Well, I do what I can, you know.
I try to make her go to therapy--
Only do what I say.
I don't wantyou to make love
to her until I say otherwise.
I wantyou to hold her
and talk to her in bed...
about intimate things...
the most intimate feelings
you're having.
When you sleep, spoon her.
Rightside to the bed.
We call this
the nurturingposition.
Come on in,Joseph.
Go into the room on your left...
and take off all your clothes
except your shorts.
Naw, forget it.
Come and stand over here.
I want you to look in the mirror
and tell me what you see.
Tell me aboutyour body.
You're jokin', right?
Okay then.
Is this as far as we go?
I guess I'm a bit too thin.
My legs are
definitely too skinny.
I don't know.
It's fine. Why?
Well, you stand as if
you don't likeyour body.
I likeyour body.
It's lean...
strong.
Capable hands,
well-defined feet.
Of course, you could
change it ifyou wanted...
but it's better to change
howyou feel about it.
Anyone that doesn't
totally accept their body...
can never experience ecstasy...
can never enable another
to experience it.
What do you think
about your penis?
Well, to be honest, I like it.
It's... Iarge and powerful.
Good. I wantyou
to feel that way.
I'm sure it's true.
Later on, I can
give you some exercises...
to further increase its size.
Good foryou.
Good for Maria.
Now, every night
before you go to sleep...
I wantyou to practice
what I call...
"the bliss carezza."
Barelytouching Maria...
tenderlystroke her body
frrom head to toe with your hand.
We are sensitizing her body...
awakening her ecstatic responses.
Then, her hand on you.
Imagine lifre energy...
flowing through her hands.
Feel the electricity.
I promisedJoseph
I wouldn 't come here.
I don't want to hurt hi m...
or us.
I t's just--
Sometimes, I get scared.
Would you like to dance?
I always wanted to be
a ballroom dancer...
you know, the kind
that dons a tux every night and...
dances the world.
Did you enjoy the dance?
Yes.
As did I.
Very much.
And ifyou enjoy the dance, Maria--
Then the dance is enough.
I promise.
Have a cigar.
They're very mild.
- Oh, no. No, thankyou.
- Have one anyway.
Most men fear
women's power,Joseph.
A sexually conscious woman
is as powerful as any being on the planet.
We are entering a new era.
It will be the resurgence
ofthe divine feminine spirit.
We must honor that spirit...
in ourselves...
and in others.
You have to suck on it
once in a while.
Otherwise, it goes out.
The goal ofsex
is not orgasm,Joseph...
but ecstasy.
Maria's satisfaction
will giveyou ecstasy.
Nothing else.
There are nine levels--
movements, I call them--
to a woman's orgasm.
Now, most lovers
only achieve level four--
the ultimate release--
but it's just the threshold.
Between movements five and nine...
is where true healing occurs.
To reach these movements...
you must practice with diligence
the exercises I giveyou.
One oftheir purposes...
is to make orgasm
and ejaculation a voluntary act.
I thought
theywere the same thing.
Most people do.
In truth, both orgasm and ejaculation
are governed...
by different
neurological mechanisms.
You must learn to separate
and control each at will.
What doyou mean?
The onlyway to really satisfy
a woman and yourself...
is to have control--
complete control
overyour ejaculation.
Then you are no longer
led around byyour penis.
This has far-reaching implications
in all areas oflife...
don'tyou think?
Well, sir, areyou saying that
I'm never supposed to come?
When you choose.
That way, you don't
dissipateyour life force.
Don'tyou feel tired
afteryou've made love?
I will teach you
how to "injaculate..."
soyou can have many orgasms
without losing your power.
Yes, I will teach you and Maria...
a greater pleasure
than you imagine possible.
Go on. Let's see howyou do.
I can go a lot further.
I just got
some lungs in mywater.
Okay, using your left hand,
closeyour left nostril...
and breathe in through your right nostril
to a count of seven.
Then close both nostrils...
and hold for a count of 1 4.
Open the left nostril...
and breathe out
through a count of seven.
Close the right nostril...
and hold for a count of 1 4.
Keeping the left nostril open...
breathe in to a count of seven.
Close both nostrils--
Two, three, four, five.
Whywould anybody
wanna do this?
Okay,Joseph,
I'm ready to come down.
Joseph, come on.
No sex without condoms.
No booze, no drugs.
Nowyou tell me
I can't even come?
I know.
It's depressing, isn't it?
Boy!
- Hey.
I just have to run an errand.
I'll be right back.
- Okay.
- Doneyour exercises?
Well, I tried, but--
I don't know.
I just can't do it.
I can't just think of myself.
I need to fantasize.
Go to the white room,Joseph.
Try again.
Concentrate
on your own sexual power.
Don't throw it away on fantasy.
You don't want me
to take you through them, do you?
Maria remains a mystery..
It's hard frorme to determine the roots
ofrhersexual dysfrunction...
or the extent
ofrher childhood trauma.
There have, to date,
been no repressed-memory. flashes...
or nightmares...
yet she lives in a constant state
ofrsuppressed paranoia.
Maria is oddlyprotective
ofrJoseph.
He seems to be a good person--
captured by Maria's
intense passion...
which often springs frorth
to surprise me at any moment...
captured by her beauty
and seductive charms...
and, most likely, captured
by his own need...
to suck love frrom those who are
too wounded to give it frreely.
I know this man.
Fi nal ly.
Hera:
Trials ofrthe Goddess Obscura.
Fi rst publ ished i n 1 908.
I t's been out of pri nt
si nce 1 93 2.
You have yet
to let me down, Eva.
I find the combination
of charm and intelligence...
a rare union these days.
Maria will take time.
She is in the darkness
befrore selfr-realization.
She needs to freel frree...
to express herselfrin ways
she cannot with her husband.
She needs to be released
frrom the burdens...
ofrher shame and selfr-hatred.
I wi I l try.
How are the exercises goi ng?
Fi ne.
Everything's going fine.
I want you to do them
three times a day.
Draw the energy
up to the heart chakra...
and then progress to the third eye,
as we discussed.
I work all day.
Then I suggest you close your door.
Can you explain it to me?
Well,Joseph, you know,
the construction supervisor...
is talking about chakras,
reads books about Hinduism.
MyJoseph
is talking about chakras.
I think thatJoseph's discovery
that his relationshipwith you...
is notwhat he thought itwas
has had a profound effect on him.
It's like... he has this inner life
that I--
What?
Nothing.
I just had a bizarre thought.
Anyway...
Iast night, we just...
sat in bed and talked...
sort of.
Tell me.
I can't. I can't.
Okay.
He sat me down
in front of a mirror...
and he asked me
to masturbate for him.
He wanted me to show him
step-by-step...
how I like to be touched.
He wanted to know
how to please me.
How did that feel?
I wouldn't do it at first.
I was too embarrassed.
Then he did it.
I learned so much about him
bywatching him...
how he touched himself.
Then I did it.
Doyou feel you got closer
to an orgasm?
Oh, God, no!
I was far too self-conscious.
But this is good.
Before we end, though, Maria,
I would like to encourageyou...
to return to therapy
with a greater commitment.
I don't know.
I worry too much
when I seeyou.
- I try to control my thoughts.
- We are what we think, Maria.
Life is learning to come to terms
with our thoughts.
The terms of my thoughts
are unreasonable, Alfred.
It's just as well
I leave them alone.
Start by using
your ring finger.
Slip it in gently
and curl it...
soyour fingertip is touching
the ceiling oftheyoni.
Go as deep as you can.
Then slideyourfinger down
until you feel it.
- Howwill I know?
- Most likely, she'll tell you.
She'll feel it ifyou don't.
When you find the sacred spot...
never break eye contact
with Maria.
Does it hurt?
- It's just sensitive.
- Is it too much?
It feels raw...
almost like it's burning.
The first few times
the sacred spot is touched...
it can be frightening.
She may experience pain.
I'm scared,Joseph.
It's okay.
Just keep stroking.
The sensation will change.
Staywith me, okay?
- I loveyou.
- I loveyou too.
Staywith her for only
30 seconds or so...
and then slowlywithdraw...
but hold hervery closely.
You are assuming the role ofhealer
in this act,Joseph.
All Maria's abuse
and psychic hurts...
reside in this sacred spot.
Itwill take time
to release them.
A bit late,
aren'tyou,Joseph?
I feel it, you know,
whatyou've been talking about.
I've been doing the exercises,
and I feel it.
Describe this feeling.
It's like this, you know, this sadness
that I've been carrying around...
has just, you know--
It's lifted.
And I feel--
I just feel the love.
I feel in love with myself.
So, what's on for today?
Nothing's on for today,Joseph.
I have a very busy evening--
a performance and a date.
You have a date?
Indeed.
And so do you.
It's time foryou and Maria
to make love.
Now remember...
make love from the heart...
nowhere else.
Keepyour eyes open...
move extremely slowly...
and, most importantly...
with love and adoration.
What about
the nine levels of orgasm?
Later. Don't concern yourself
with orgasm.
For Maria, it will take much time.
Foryou, it's forbidden.
I feel the love.
I love myself.
- I love myself.
- Congratulations, buddy.
I love myselfthree times a day.
I feel the love.
Okay. I'll talk to you later.
Bye.
- Hello.
- What's so funny?
How did you know
I was laughing?
I just know.
I've been learning more...
and more aboutyou
every day.
So I see.
- When areyou coming home?
- Soon.
When I do...
do you wanna make love?
I thought
you wanted to wait.
I mean,
areyou sureyou're ready?
Under one condition.
What's that?
We do it myway.
Hon, maybe we should just, you know,
hold each other first.
Shut up.
Why areyou doing this?
'Cause I loveyour toes...
and it excites me.
Don't move.
- Hon!
- Huh?
It hurts.
I loveyou
so deep inside me,Joseph.
Oh, God, I feel you so--
so deep inside.
Not so fast.
- I'm not supposed to come.
- Huh?
- I'm not supposed to--
- What?
- I can't hearyou.
- Don't make me come.
- Why?
Too bad, motherfucker.
Did you like it?
I guess she surprised us, huh?
Yeah.
I felt--
Scared?
A woman's anger
can be very scary.
Most don't feel they have
the right to express it.
Maybe we should encourage Maria
to vent hers more often.
- In bed?
- Why not?
Repressed anger...
chokes us, closes us down.
Are you sure it was
Maria's anger that scared you?
What do you mean?
How did it feel
to be fucked?
Out of control.
How did you feel?
Fear.
I was over on Hinton Street
the other day.
Does he make you feel safe?
Does he love you no matterwhat?
So do I.
Follow closely.
Let me into your subconscious.
Touch her like a harmonic--
gently, yin...
but sure, definitive.
It's nice, huh?
Look at me.
Nowmovements frive to nine.
Support herneck
withyourhand...
preciselyat the frourth and frifth
cervical vertebrae.
Begin your toning
and breathe into her neck...
through your hand.
Energy frollows consciousness.
Are you okay?
Hon? Hon!
Honey?
Yes, I 'm J oseph.
- Do you mind if my friends--
- Anyone you want.
Okay. When Maria
first arrived...
her throat
was almost swollen shut.
We injected the throat
with a strong anti-inflammatory.
We also administered her a sedative
so she would rest.
Now, toyour knowledge...
has anything like this
ever happened before?
Is she allergic to anything?
- Any medication she might have taken?
- Not that I know of.
What wereyou doing
when this occurred?
We were making love...
and she started crying...
and then she started choking.
She's been under a lot
of abnormal stress lately.
She had a severe breakdown.
She had a body memory.
Maria has endured some form
of repeated child abuse.
She shows almost all
the external symptoms...
but it's locked
in her subconscious.
Now she can begin
the road to recovery.
That's possible.
Her memory could've triggered
a spontaneous regression to some incident.
Oral sex is one ofthe most common
forms ofinfant abuse.
It's more about acceptance
than forgiveness for me.
I got a letter a year later.
Now she denies
that anything ever happened.
That's all.
My name is Maria...
and I'm a survivor
of child sexual abuse and incest.
- Hey.
- Hi.
It's Maria's mother on the phone.
Hello, Dottie?
I support her, and I am doing
as best as I can...
as her husband
in this situation...
but does it really matter
what I think?
I realize thatyou think she's ill.
She is getting help.
Because I've seen her suffer.
Well, I'm sorry, too, Dottie.
- Honey, it's the fifth time todayyou've taken--
- Leave me alone.
We have to talk
about this, Maria.
I just needed a shower.
The other night, when you got up
to go to the bathroom...
I knew it was you...
but what I saw was him
standing there...
naked...
ready to come to my bed.
We need to separate,Joseph.
I know I'm going crazy.
You have to let me inside.
You have to let me
try to helpyou.
I don't feel comfortable
around you.
- The things thatyou do frighten me.
-Just tell me what I can do.
When you touch me,
I feel numb.
I'm gonna sleep in the guest bedroom
until you find another place to stay.
Living room, bar, kitchen--
ifyou wanna call it that.
Closets.
Clean towels, fresh linens
every other day.
Any questions?
Notyour most confident stride,
Joseph.
Maria asked you to leave.
Listen, ifyou know everything
that's gonna happen in my life...
for the next twoyears,
why don't you let me know...
so I can plan myvacations and know
when to put my house on the market.
Tell me what happened.
It's what Maria's going through.
What has to do with you...
has to do with you.
What's that supposed to mean?
You married a scarred and
emotionally dysfunctional woman.
Has it ever occurred toyou
to askyourselfwhy?
Whyyou put up with so much
in return for so little?
Because I'm in love
with her, okay?
And because I believed in you.
I believed that we could help her!
Our relationship has never
been about Maria. Never.
You don't love Maria,Joseph.
You want to mold her.
You want to make her
something forJoseph.
And you've only ever
proven to me...
thatyou'd do anything
to make that happen.
What doyou know
about love? Huh?
Love is being there when
they hateyour fucking guts!
Love is being there
when they bleed.
Haveyou ever been with a woman
for more than one hour? Ever?
Wendy takes small steps every day
to make herself attractive.
She eats. Then she eliminates
through the esophagus, mind you.
That's when she's not taking
the latest laxative on the market.
A beautiful woman, Leslie.
God made her 5'5"
and a voluptuous 1 28 pounds.
But sometime, probably
when she was a teenager...
she got the idea that
she wasn't so beautiful.
Maybe it was because her friends,
Debbie and Connie...
were getting all the boys.
But she started a program
of repetitive surgery...
to suck all the fat
from her body.
She started with her hips,
her thighs, her tummy.
Next month, unless
we do something to help her...
she'll continue with
her arms and her ankles.
They always do.
Candy's had four implants.
She just can't get it quite right.
Evelyn injects her face
with cow fat six times a year.
Jane: Two hours
on the StairMaster...
an hour on a treadmill, daily.
They dress to flaunt this,
to hide that.
They cover their faces
with poisons.
You're right. They do bleed,Joseph.
And doyou know why?
Because they're desperate
to sell what men buy.
Desperate to be what
they're not, to be loved.
Like Maria.
Have you ever thought
that maybe your focus on Maria...
is a distraction from
your own fear of abandonment?
Your own emptiness?
Your own life?
You want to be a healer?
Heal yourself.
This'll be painless.
I promise.
- You're a deceptive asshole.
- All you gotta do is meet her.
She just got divorced.
She was married for twoyears.
You guys got a lot in common.
Now she's
a little bit flat upstairs...
but Nancy tells me
she has a bodacious ass...
and is not afraid to use it.
Tanner, do me a favor, okay?
Never talk to me about a woman
like that again.
What is wrong with you?
Joseph, areyou with me?
Hmm? Yeah. Sorry.
Okay. Arthurwants you to take
a meeting with the Kensor group.
Will you do it?
No. You know what?
Cancel my 2:30 meeting
with Cruise, too, would you?
- Whereyou going?
- Goin' out for a while.
Hello?
Yes, Doctor.
No. No, I'll be there.
3:00 Tuesday?
Yes, ma'am.
Yes, I understand.
Theydon't want to be alone
in theirhealing anymore.
Theywantyou to understand,
to be aware...
and to hear them.
Beyond that, there are
no expectations.
Are there any questions?
Okay. Who would like
to go first?
I would.
My name is Maria...
and my husband is Joseph.
From the time I was a baby...
until I was about
ten years old...
I loved my father
more than anything else.
Nobody could say anything bad
about him to me.
The world loved him too.
I have recently remembered
a lot ofthings.
I remembered that
my father's favorite thing...
was to kiss myvagina
when I was a baby.
I remember I'd wake up in the middle
ofthe night sucking his penis.
I didn't even know
what it was.
My motherwent away on a trip
when I was fiveyears old.
This was the first time
he put his penis in me.
I bled for days.
He told me that's what
daddies and little girls do--
that it was our secret.
He made me believe that every father
did that with their daughter.
So I believed him...
and I became that.
And I enjoyed it too.
It seemed to stop
when I was about 1 1 or 1 2.
I don't know why...
but I still loved him.
I had no choice.
I became the woman that
my fatherwanted me to be.
I dressed how
he told me to dress.
I presented myself
as a happy, bubbly girl.
Still do.
It's the way
that I block the feelings.
that I block the pain.
I know I've been away
a long time.
I had to confront my self-hatred...
and I am terrified ofyou...
but it's because
you make me feel so good...
Iike my father did.
My father, who was supposed to
keep me safe from harm, was the harm.
Can you understand?
Do you?
Look at the courage she has.
So many people go
the otherway, live as victims.
They use their abuse as an excuse
to close down, to give in to life.
How do you let it go?
You look it straight
in the eye...
and risk letting someone loveyou.
Maria did that today.
She's gonna be a different woman
when she gets through this.
Yes.
You know, it's not good foryou
to have so many orgasms.
You need to learn
to preserve youryang...
and prolong your sexual activity.
Good foryou.
Good foryourwife.
- Okay. Thanks.
- Sure.
I know.
I feel the same. Yeah.
That sounds good. Okay.
Right. Yeah.
- Hi.
Do you want
to have a seat?
Sure.
Doyou want to play
"Ifyou love me"?
Okay.
Ifyou love me...
you'll understand
that I needed time...
to separateyou from my abuse.
I still wake up every morning
with my memories--
my nightmares--
but I'm facing them.
I can't help feeling ugly...
and ashamed.
Ifyou love me...
Iet me come home.
- Hi.
I'm Eva.
Areyou here
for a violin lesson?
No-- Yes. Yes, yes, I am.
I think I've got the wrong time,
so I'd probably betterjust--
Eva, this is Joseph.
We met.
Bye, lover.
I'll seeyou Friday...
unless you want
to drop by the library.
Good night,Joseph.
- Client?
- No.
That's the healing room.
This is my bedroom.
A violin lesson, huh?
Yes-- No.
I haven't exactly told her
what I do. I--
I need a bit more time.
Isn't she glorious?
And you don't have to heal her?
Doyou--
Doyou ever smell her fragrance
when she's nowhere around?
And doyou--
Doyou know what she's thinking
before she even begins to tell you?
Doyou dread all the moments
in between?
Too bad foryou.