Subtitle created by: ;;;===€h☼¥)
"The Hunger Games: Mockingjay - Part 2 (2015)"
(Run time 02:05:14)
Okay.
I know, I know.
I'm sorry,
I know it's a little tender.
Okay.
Let's try your voice now.
My name is Katniss Everdeen,
I'm from District 12.
My...
Okay, take your time.
You got a lot of swelling
in your vocal chords.
My...
name...
is...
Katniss
Everdeen.
I want...
I want to talk to him.
He needs time.
But...
We're trying something new today.
He's been calmer with
the doctors, but...
They are strangers to him,
so...
We're gonna test his responses
on someone he remembers from home.
Someone he trust.
Send her in.
Hey.
Prim.
- How're you doing?
- She's too close.
- It's okay.
- How did you get here?
We're in District 13 now.
It's a real place.
The stories are true.
You were rescued.
My family hasn't come to see me.
There was an attack on 12.
Yes.
My family.
They didn't survive.
Because of Katniss.
- It's because of Katniss.
- It wasn't because of her.
- She tell you to say that.
- She didn't tell me anything.
She's a liar, Prim.
It's the truth.
Yeah.
What you're saying isn't real.
She sent you here
to talk to me.
- She knows you're here now.
It's okay.
She knows.
You can't trust her!
She's a monster!
She's a mutt!
The Capitol bring her
to destroy us!
Get her out of there.
Do you understand me!
You have to kill her, Prim!
You have...
to kill her!
- Katniss.
- She's a mutt!
- This is just the condition responds.
- Kill her!
- It's not him.
- She's a monster!
- She's a mutt!
- No, it's not him.
She's a mutt!
Please, come in.
Will you excuse us?
- For just a moment.
- Of course.
Have a seat.
I'm glad you're feeling better.
Snow has to pay
for what he's done.
I want to help the rebels
in any way I can.
It's hard to see Peeta this way.
That's not Peeta.
Send me to the Capitol.
I'll do anything.
I can't.
I can't send you there.
We can't get into the Capitol
until we control District 2.
Then send me to 2.
You want me to
fire up our troops.
Call out to the loyalists,
You've seen what I can do.
Yes, I have.
I saw Peeta
before we left.
What'd you think?
Something selfish.
That you don't have to be
jealous of him anymore?
No.
I don't stand a chance
if he doesn't get better.
You'll never let him go.
What's going on in your head?
I don't know.
It's like kissing
someone who's drunk.
It doesn't count.
3 minutes before touch down.
Prepare for landing.
Wrap it up.
Last chance.
Go.
This is another version food
trapping resource.
This one is designed to blind,
the smoke clings to the eyes.
That's an application for
Hummingbird trap.
They're scared of people,
so they flee in this direction
to what they think is a safe haven.
Two tier explosion.
We'll have people enough time to
rush in and help the wounded.
A second bomb.
Right.
Second one goes off here.
I guess there are
no rules anymore
about what a person can do
to another person.
I don't think some of us use any
rule book when we hijacked Peeta.
Welcome to District 2.
I'm Corporal Homes.
If you'll follow me, please.
Don't worry.
That's how the loyals
say good morning.
President Coin, we're indebted
to you for the reinforcements
and the Mockingjay.
But I'm not sure that anyone outside of 2
knows what we've been up against.
This is the Nut.
The Capitol's headquarters
for our offensive operations.
It's manned by both military and
civilian personnel from District 2.
As you can see, the fortress
lies so far beneath the bedrock,
it's untouchable.
Yesterday, we attempted to take
the northeastern gate.
Then we encountered from higher up
and we're forced to pull back.
We took heavy loses.
Could we create a decoy?
Send troops towards one of the gate
and just send an attack on another.
Well, who's troops do you
propose as a decoy, Commander.
We have the Mockingjay.
Don't underestimate her.
We could use her to erode support.
She maybe be able to sway
some of the loyalists.
You've been underground
a long time, Madam Coin.
This isn't like the rest of Panem
Support for the Capitol runs deep here.
Then there's no sacrifice is too great.
We need to control the arsenal
inside that fortress.
Even with every District and it's alliance,
we are outgunned.
I won't commit my people to a
ground assault,  just to pillage weapons.
Commander Paylor.
Your people,
have suffered more than just as
anyone else in the hands of the Capitol.
Which is why I won't
condone a mass suicide.
If we don't take District 2,
we won't get in to the Capitol.
We'll be enough to disable the fortress,
instead of taking it.
What do you have in mind?
We think of it like a wolf den.
You're not going to fight your way in,
so you got two choices.
You trap the wolves inside
or you flush them out.
We can't attack straight on.
Couldn't we use a hovercraft
to strike around it?
We use the mountains,
we have weak spots and peaks.
We could design the bomb to target
some sequence season seismic data.
Trigger avalanches.
Block all exits,
cut off their supplies.
You make it impossible for them
to launch their hovercraft.
Bury them alive.
We forfeit any chance
to control the weapons.
Yes, but we'd place
a weaken in Capitol.
There're civilians in there.
They should be given
a chance to surrender.
Use one of the supply
tunnels for the evacuees
That's a luxury we weren't given
when they fire-bombed 12.
There's got to be a better way.
I suggest we try the avalanche
but leave the train tunnel alone.
Civilians can escape into the square
where our armies will be
waiting for their surrender.
We should have every
available medic standing by.
And if they won't surrender?
Then we will need a compelling voice
to persuade them.
What's the difference, Katniss.
Crushing the enemy alive or blown them
out of the sky with one of Beetee's arrows,
it's the same thing.
We were under attack
in District 8.
And that hovercraft
wasn't filled with civilians.
It doesn't matter.
Even those civilians are just mopping floors,
they're helping the enemy.
If they have to die,
I can live with that.
No one who supports
the Capitol is innocent.
With that kind of thinking
you can kill whoever you want.
You can send kids off to the
Hunger games to keep the Districts in line.
It's war, Katniss.
Sometimes killing isn't personal.
Figure if anyone who knew that
it was you.
I, of all people
know that it's always personal.
Don't worry, Katniss.
There will be survivors.
Let's focus on what
it is you got to say.
- Now, Plutarch wrote a speech...
- I'm not saying that.
Okay, I didn't think so.
Just...
Just remember you're talking to everybody.
And not just the rebels,
but the Capitol and the survivors into
want them to lay down their arms.
So, you might want to experiment with
a little sensitivity and warmth.
Make it quick, you're exposed.
This is Katniss Everdeen,
speaking to all of the loyalist
from the heart of District 2.
Survivors.
Inbound!
Ready!
Guns up!
Arms are ready!
We got to get you back.
Here they come!
Everybody, stand back!
Everybody, go!
- On the ground!
- Get them off the train!
Put your weapons down.
Get on the ground!
Put your weapons down, now!
Weapons down.
You, put it down.
- Put it...Put your weapons down!
- Drop it
Drop your weapon!
You, drop it!
Drop the gun!
Drop it!
- Hold your fire.
- Stop!
Stop!
- Hold your fire!
- Stop!
Hold your fire!
- He needs help!
- Hold your fire!
Drop it.
Give me one reason
I shouldn't shoot you.
Drop the gun!
I can't.
I guess that's the problem, isn't it?
We blew up your mine.
You burned my district to the ground.
We each have every reason
to want to kill each other.
So, if you want to kill me, do it.
Make someone happy.
I'm tired
of killing slaves for him.
I'm not a slave.
I am.
That's why I killed Cato...
and he killed Thresh...
and Thresh killed Clove.
It just goes around and around,
and who wins?
Always Snow.
I'm done being
a piece in his Game.
District 12, District 2
we have no fight.
Except the one the Capitol gave us.
Why are you fighting the rebels?
Your neighbors?
Your family?
These people are not your enemy!
We all have all one enemy.
And that's Snow.
He corrupts everyone and everything.
He turns the best of us
against each other.
Stop killing for him!
Tonight, turn your weapons
to the Capitol.
Turn you weapons
to Snow.
Tonight, turn your weapons
to the Capitol.
Turn you weapons
to Snow.
Hold you fire!
A toast.
Antonius.
With our best troops
crushed in the mountains
and the rebels marching
on us as we speak.
What do we celebrate?
The death of the Mockingjay, Sir.
If Peeta didn't kill her,
her own arrogance did.
Of course.
That's the same facile thinking
that led you to divert our
best peacekeepers into District 2.
You have the habit of burying people
before they are dead.
If the Mockingjay were gone,
the rebels would already
be using her as a martyr.
No, Minister Antonius.
I'm afraid that is not what
we were toasting at all.
Sir.
The rebels can be held off out...
The rebels will reach the
outskirts of the Capitol
in a matter of days.
We'll evacuate the outer blocks...
to let them in.
I want all anti-aircraft defenses ready,
so we're secured from the skies.
Lure them into the city
and then our gamemakers will make
them pay for every inch with blood.
I want every camera watching.
We will turn their advance
into a celebration of suffering.
Let each moment be captured
for all posterity.
So...
What do we toast tonight,
Minister Antonius?
We toast to the glorious era
coming to it's bitter end.
Well, there she is.
The Mockingjay.
Oh, that speech you gave.
Oh, man, the feel. I mean
I still have goose bumps.
You don't mind, do you?
They cut off my supply of morphine.
This head doctor that comes in and
sees me everyday, she tried to...
help me adjust to reality
like some...
Some guy from this rabbit warren
actually knows anything about my reality.
At least 20 times in a session
he tells me that I'm totally safe.
Safe from the Capitol.
Safe from Snow.
What about you, Mockingjay?
You feeling totally safe?
Till I got shot.
Oh, please.
The bullet didn't even touched you.
Something they thought about.
Of course your costume would be bulletproof.
So, what are your injuries?
Bruised ribs.
Bruised lung.
I'm surprised they haven't
found you a new lung.
Well, I got 2,
do you want one of mine?
I mean, it's everybody's job
to keep you alive.
Is that why you hate me?
Partly.
You're also a little hard to swallow.
The whole tacky romance drama and
the defender-of-the-helpless act.
Even though it's not an act.
Which makes you even
more unbearable.
Feel free to take
any of this personally.
You should have been the Mockingjay,
nobody has to tell you what to say.
But nobody likes me.
They're afraid of you.
Maybe here, but...
In the Capitol, you're the
only thing they're scared of.
It's just stuff my family brought.
This from Peeta?
Yeah.
He messed us up
pretty good, didn't they?
We showed him footage of your
speech in 2 (District 2).
He had real memories of you.
That still doesn't mean
I am going in there.
He's strapped down.
He can't hurt you.
No, This is different.
Haymitch, I really
don't want to.
Well, it doesn't matter what you want. It's for Peeta.
What's the harm in trying.
I watched you die.
- You look terrible.
- You looked better.
You're not remotely nice
to say that to me now.
I was never the nice one,
you were.
When I saw you die,
I remembered something.
About the bread.
I remember,
you in the rain.
And I burned it on purpose,
to give it to you.
I remember,
my mother hitting me.
I was supposed to
give it to the pig.
That was the first
I've eaten in days.
How did I take a beating
like that for you?
Because you are kind...
and generous.
- And people said you loved me.
- Did people say you loved me?
They said that's why
Snow tortured you.
To hurt me.
Snow says everything that
comes out of your mouth is a lie.
All I know is that I would have
saved myself a lot of suffering.
If I had just given
that bread to the pig.
I think the only thing left to say
is thank you.
I need to be in the Capitol.
No, you've done your job.
You've been very successful as the Mockingjay,
you've unified the Districts.
And now we want you to rest
and to heal.
The last of rebels saw me,
I was lying on the ground.
Katniss, we won't let this
momentum go to waste.
We will shoot more propos,
right here in 13.
Showing them that you're alive.
I should be with the troops.
It will be like being on the front line.
As far as the soldiers know,
you survived a bullet to the heart.
I think they will understand
why you're not with them.
When we win this war,
we'll fly you in for the surrender.
We'll need you for the ceremony.
You are very valuable to us.
I'll do whatever
you need me to do.
From this day forward,
in sickness and in health,
for richer or poorer,
I promise to love and
cherish you each day.
I, Finnick Odair.
Take you, Annie Cresta as
my wife from this day forward,
together or apart,
we will always be united.
One life.
One purpose.
One destiny.
You may kiss the bride.
You saw Peeta, didn't you?
Would you tell him hi for me?
We're old friends, you know.
We had a joint in the
cells in the Capitol,
we're very familiar with
each other's screams.
I'm going to kill Snow.
Nothing good is safe
while he's alive.
And I can't make
another speech about it.
No more cameras.
No more  propos.
No more games.
He needs to see my eyes
when I kill him.
Now you're talking.
Find a way to the Capitol when
everyone is looking the other way.
I heard the medics talking, they're
shipping supplies to the front line
from Hanger 2
around midnight, tonight.
Medicine, painkillers I was gonna go steal
some for myself,
but I guess I couldn't.
just stay here
and cover for you.
Anybody can kill anybody, Katniss,
even the president.
You just have to be
willing to sacrifice yourself.
Go on.
Don't you want Snow
to see you dance?
Hey, it's her.
It's Katniss Everdeen.
Hey.
- I thought you were in the hospital.
- I was.
Come on.
What is she doing?
Well, it's so frustrating
when she goes rogue.
This isn't just about a lesson,
it's insubordination.
Bring her on the
first hovercraft back.
Don't be ridiculous,
she can't come back now.
She's mythic.
At the front line,
surviving a gun shot wound...
I couldn't stage it better myself.
No.
She's going to stay
where she is.
And whatever she's doing,
we conceived it.
It was our plan all along.
Of course it was.
Mr. Heavensbee.
You are the gamemaker.
I want everyone to know
whatever game she's playing.
She's playing for us.
I'm commander Paylor of District 8.
I'm a soldier like
all of you, so...
Here's what I know.
For the first time in our lifetimes,
we're standing together with 13 districts.
From what I see here,
we've already made history.
But history doesn't stop to celebrate.
And we're facing an enemy that will
not change and will never surrender.
President Snow has pulled back peacekeepers
to fortify the center of the city.
He's evacuating residents
from the outer blocks.
The civilians will be
confused and desperate.
You are under orders
not to target them.
We are deploying medical brigades
to help anyone in need.
We'll show the Capitol people
who we are.
To slow our advance, President Snow
is building a minefield of traps.
And lethal devices called "Pods".
The sadistic inventions of gamemakers
meant to make sport of our deaths.
If our armies make it pass
peacekeepers and other defenses,
we'll converge in the center
of the city at Snow's mansion
Where we won't just
unlock his gates,
but unshackle all of Panem.
- Yeah!
If we die...
Let it be for a cause
and not a spectacle.
If we succeed, let it be for all
of Panem and let it be forever.
Yes, you already made history.
But the future...
Our future starts tomorrow at dawn.
When we march together
into the Capitol.
Squad 451?
Looks like you got
your meals covered.
- I'm trying to be prepared.
- Don't lie to me.
We've been hunting
together all our lives.
I know when you're going
to go off on your own.
You're gonna leave me behind too?
As your fellow soldier,
I suggest that
you stay with your unit.
I couldn't stop you
if you wanted to come.
Hawthorne.
Everdeen.
Come meet your new unit.
I'm Lieutenant Jackson.
And I want to introduce
you to your squad.
This is the second lieutenant Mitchell.
The best sharp shooter in Panem.
These are the Leeg sisters,
First Combat Division.
And this is Corporal Holmes.
Finnick?
- Are you with us?
- Looks like it.
That's a short honeymoon.
Yeah.
Well...
I guess we got to have one
in the Capitol.
- After we take it.
- Gather around.
Squadron 451.
You’re my unit.
Lieutenant Jackson is my second in command.
Each one of you is elite
in some form of combat.
But we are a non-combat unit,
so, we'll be following a days behind
the front line troops.
You are to be the onscreen
faces of the invasion.
The Star squad.
It's been decided that you are most
effective when seen by the masses.
So, we're not going to fight?
You do whatever you
are ordered to do, soldiers.
It's not your job
to ask questions.
Yes, sir.
Our instructions are to shoot
propaganda footage
on the battle scars
troop to the Capitol.
You are handpicked to
intimidate their forces.
And inspire surrenders.
Even though we'll be working on abandon
streets miles behind the front line,
I guarantee you, whatever they put us,
it would not be safe.
This is a war zone.
It is likely that we'll encounter both
active Pods and peacekeepers.
You're considered high value
targets to the Capitol.
In the event of capture,
you'll be given a nightlock pill.
A poison that acts immediately.
Lieutenant Jackson do the honors.
I've already briefed
you on the Pods.
I remind you,
they are on every block.
Our unit has been given a HOLO.
A database that contain the
detailed map of the Capitol
and the list of every known Pod.
These Pods,
can trigger anything from bombs,
to traps, to mutts.
We cannot move without this device.
There's no guarantee that
our database is complete.
There can be new Pods
that we are not aware of.
Because we don't want the gamemakers
to know we have this Intel.
There's a self-destruct on it
You flip this switch.
You say, "nightlock" 3 times it blows itself
in anything within a 10 foot radius.
Stay within our unit.
Even with the HOLO, it's likely
that new Pods have been set.
Whatever they contain,
they are meant to kill you.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome to the 76th Hunger Games.
I've never seen this place so empty.
Just keep your eyes open.
We got a Pod..
Stay cover.
Shoot through those 2 buildings.
Pollux.
Right here.
Castor.
Good.
When you're ready, Katniss.
Hold it.
Pod is tighter.
Okay.
All clear.
I don't think we can
get across this minefield.
Not without that HOLO.
We're not getting to get it
off him while he's awake
Make sure we're on the
same watch tonight.
Is that peacekeepers?
451 to Base. We got a truck
coming in from the south, over.
Copy that, over.
Stand down everyone, it's Bradly.
My name is Peeta Mellark. I'm with District 12.
Okay, stop.
Hold up.
Everyone relax.
What are we doing?
Jackson, cuff him.
Soldier, this is just a precaution, until we
can get everything straighten out, yeah.
Yeah.
My name is Peeta Mellark, from District 12.
They want us to
add him to the propo.
To show he's on our side now.
We'll move forward a few blocks
tomorrow and shoot a new footage.
He's not in control of himself.
I say we schedule an around
the clock watch on him.
The Leegs till 1700.
Homes and Mitchell till 1900.
Give me a watch.
If it ever came down to it,
you think you can shoot him?
I wouldn't be shooting Peeta.
I'd be killing a Capitol mutt.
I'm not sure that kind of comment
recommends you for the job either, soldier.
Put her in the rotation.
He's gonna try to kill me.
Especially with all this going on.
It's going to set him off.
We'll keep him contained.
Why would Coin do this?
Here's all I know.
It was Peeta that she wanted
rescued from the arena.
She never liked you.
She doesn't like anybody
or anything she can't control.
So, she would put my life in danger?
She denied, but...
What?
One way or another this war
is gonna to come to an end.
They promised a free election.
Maybe she's starting
to see you as a threat.
Nobody would
think I'd be a leader.
But you'll throw support to someone,
would it be her?
If your immediate answer isn't yes,
then you're dangerous.
She doesn't need you as a rallying cry any more
these propos can be done without you.
Only one thing you could do now
to add more fire to this rebellion.
Die.
That's not gonna happen
under my watch, Katniss.
I'm planning for you
to have a long life.
Why?
You don't owe me anything.
Because you've earned it.
We've been here before, you know?
What?
That look.
I've seen that look.
You're trying to decide
whether or not you should kill me.
I never wanted to kill you.
That's not what I'm doing.
I saw it with my own eyes.
In the first games.
In the first games, I thought you were
trying to help the Careers to kill me.
After that, I always saw you...
as an ally.
Friend.
Lover
Victor.
Fiancé.
Enemy
Target.
Mutt.
And now ally?
Yeah. I'll add it to the list of words
I use to try to figure you out.
I'm sorry.
I just can't tell what's real
and what's made up anymore.
Then ask.
That's what Annie does.
Ask who?
Us.
We're your new unit now.
Your favorite color is green.
Is that's real?
Yeah.
It's real.
Yours is orange.
Not... bright orange.
Soft like the sunset.
Thank you.
You're a painter.
You're a baker.
You always sleep
with the windows open.
You never take sugar in your tea.
You always double-knot your shoelaces.
You were right.
I can't do this.
I guess we're not leaving anymore.
We're not going anywhere
without that HOLO.
Listen up.
The mag's empty.
It's only for the propo.
Let's move.
We're heading 5 blocks north.
To the Citizens in the Capitol.
Our war is not with you.
You will be a vital part of the
democracy that follows our victory.
Be a vital part of the democracy
that follows our victory.
- You got it.
- Okay.
Boggs.
This is a good spot.
Through there, in the courtyard.
Okay, let us clear it.
Got a Pod.
Split.
Take cover
Stay back.
All clear.
Gale, Holmes, with me.
Leegs, take the wings.
Everdeen, no!
- Boggs!
- Hold your position.
Boggs!
It's okay.
The HOLO.
Unfit for command.
Transfer primary security clearance.
- Say your name.
- Katniss Everdeen.
- What did you just do?
- Katniss.
Don't trust them.
Kill Peeta if you have to.
Do what you came to do.
Boggs?
Come on.
He's gone.
Go! Go! Go!
Now! Now!
- This way.
- Keep moving!
Katniss, go soldier!
Get to higher ground.
Now!
Finnick!
Peeta!
- Let's go!
- Oh God!
Come on.
....
Don't stop, let's go!
Come on! Come on!
We got to move!
Get inside.
Everybody inside!
Go!
Upstairs! Go!
- Hurry up!
- Move!
- Go! Go!
Keep moving.
Keep moving to the top.
Go!
Hey. Hey.
I got you. Shh...
It's slowing down.
Gamemakers are still putting
on quite a show.
- 451 to Base, over.
- Hey, we better move.
If peacekeepers didn't know
where we were, they do now.
Those surveillance cameras caught us.
451 to Base, come in.
This is a bad spot.
We need to move, now.
451 to Base, over.
I can't get a signal.
But I can get us back to Base.
Everdeen, give me the HOLO
Everdeen, what'd I just say?
The HOLO, come on, let's go.
Boggs gave it to me.
- What are you talking about?
- He did.
He transferred security clearance to her.
I saw him.
And why would he do that?
I'm on special orders from Coin.
To do what?
To assassinate President Snow.
I don't believe that
for one second.
As your new unit commander,
I order you to transfer
security clearance to me. Now.
I can't do that.
Let's not lose our heads here.
I'm not asking it again, Everdeen.
Give me that HOLO.
She's telling the truth.
Plutarch wants it televised.
He thinks if we can film
the Mockingjay assassinating Snow,
it will make the Capitol surrender
before the casualties get too high.
While we're arguing, there's a hundred
peacekeepers on their way here.
Boggs promised me that when the
time came you would help me.
Alright, soldier.
The HOLO is yours.
I don't think we're going to leave
any footprints. We should move, now.
Most cameras outside should be
covered up by the oil.
She can't move forward like this.
Her leg's too bad.
We have to evacuate her.
I'm sorry.
I'll stay with her.
As soon as we make contact,
we will send somebody back.
I promise you.
Alright, everybody, move out.
- Let's get him up.
- Go.
Can you walk?
Come on this way.
Get these curtains closed.
It's the Leegs.
Good afternoon,
I'm Caesar Flickerman.
Hear about continuing coverage
of the defense of the Capitol.
Today, as our peacekeepers
valiantly hold off the rebels,
our story takes a surprising twist.
Katniss Everdeen.
Our once favourite daughter,
has infiltrated the city
with some of the Victors.
Who's names are all too familiar.
Finnick Odair
and Peeta Mellark.
Clearly, some alliances don't last forever.
Take a look at what happened
just a moment ago.
When our peacekeepers
cornered Katniss Everdeen
and her band of foolish rebels.
Whatever arrogance brought this
treacherous girl back to us.
You're about to witness a great
victory, not only to the Capitol,
but for Panem.
So, there you have it.
Katniss Everdeen, the girl on fire.
A girl who inspired so much violence.
Seems to have met
a violent end herself.
Stay tuned for more information.
Caesar Flickerman, thank you.
So, now that we're dead,
what are we gonna to do?
Isn't it obvious?
The next move is to kill me.
I murdered one of
our squad members.
Katniss is right.
I'm a mutt.
It's only a matter of time
before I snapped again.
I'm not in control.
I need a nightlock pill.
So, I can die when I need to.
When it gets to that point
I'll kill you myself.
I don't think I ever really
understood the Capitol until now.
You eat like this you could believe anything.
So, Katniss Everdeen.
A poor unstable girl with nothing but
a small talent with a bow and arrow,
is dead.
Not a thinker.
Not a leader.
Simply a face
plucked for the masses.
Was she valuable?
She was extremely valuable to your rebellion.
Because you have no vision,
no true leader among you.
You call themselves an alliance,
but we saw what that means.
Your soldiers are at
each other's throats.
Good night. Panem
For those of you
who don't know me,
please allow me to introduce myself.
I am President Alma Coin,
leader of the rebellion.
I've interrupted a broadcast
from your president
in which he attempted to defame
a brave young woman.
A face, picked from the masses,
he called her.
- Plucked.
- As if a leader...
A true leader,
could be anything else.
I had the privilege of knowing
a small town girl from
the scene in District 12,
who survived the Hunger Games
and the Quarter Quell.
And rose up and turned a nation
of slaves into an army.
Dead or alive. Katniss Everdeen
will remain the face of this revolution.
She will not have
died for nothing.
I had no idea
I meant so much to her.
Her vision and ours
will be realised.
A free Panem.
With self-determination for all.
And in her memory, we will all
find strength to rid Panem
of it's oppressors. Thank you,
and be safe.
- Snow is in his mansion.
- Where is that?
That's us.
That's the city circle.
It's at least
70, 75 blocks north.
- 75 blocks?
- Uh huh.
Nobody knows we're alive.
This is our chance.
These buildings, do these
look over Snow's garden?
- I...
- They do.
If he goes outside at all,
I can get a clear shot.
We are getting ahead
of ourselves here.
Whether they're looking for us
or not, we're pinned down.
Hit that button,
scan for Pods.
Just about every 10 steps.
Yeah, that doesn't even
show the new ones.
So, we can't go anywhere
in the streets.
And the red tops suggest as that.
There might be another way.
My brother knows these
tunnels really well.
He works sanitation down here.
Or after they made him an Avox.
Hey.
You're going to be okay?
Look at me.
We're going to get through this,
I promise.
It take us 5 years to
buy his way out of here.
He didn't see the sun once.
We're too expose here.
Sir.
Shall I call you a doctor?
- What did you say?
- Shall I call for your a doctor?
I hope you waking me for
something more urgent than
an old man's health.
They survived.
I don't know how.
We picked them up
on a surveillance cam.
Let me see.
I-I need to see for myself.
It's her.
It is her.
Her arena has moved underground.
Looks clear.
Everybody, okay?
Yeah.
Alright, everybody.
Let's stop here for a bit
and get some rest, yeah?
I'll take first watch.
Hey, Peeta,
you'll stuck in there.
Alright, settle in, everybody.
Katniss, your watch.
You know, the capital, they used
tracker jacker venom on me.
That's what the doctors on 13 said.
You were stung once too.
Real or not real?
Real.
When they used the venom on me,
they would show me pictures of my life.
But some weren't real.
They changed them.
At first, they all-they all
blurred together, but now...
now I can sort them out a little.
Like the... little ones that they changed,
they have this...
this choir,
it's like they're
They are shiny,
they've been glossed over.
You should get some rest.
You're still trying to protect me,
real or not real?
Real.
That's what you and I do.
Keep each other alive.
Katniss.
What is that?
We got to go.
We got to get out of here now.
Mutts.
They release mutts.
Pollux, what's is the fastest way out?
Come on, go.
Go!
- Move! Move! Move! Move!
- Come on! Come on! Come on!
Pollux, lead us out of here!
Come on.
Castor!
Fall back!
Move.
Katniss. come on!
Move!
Katniss.
Go!
Go, go, go...!
Go, go, go!
Katniss!
- Aww!
- Finnick!
Finnick!
GAWWWWW !!!
- KATNISS !!
- Nightlock.
- AAWWWW!!!
Nightlock.
AWWWW !!!
Come on. Come on!
Let's go!
Keep moving! Keep moving!
Go!
Keep going.
Keep going!
Peeta, come on.
Peeta!
- Peeta, we have to get going!
- I'm a mutt!
We have to get going.
Yes, you can.
Leave me. I'm a mutt!
Look at me!
Look at me.
Stay with me.
Always.
Come on.
I know where we are.
I know a place.
Up those stairs.
Keep going.
Someone's coming.
Shut the door.
No, Katniss, she isn't in the way.
It's okay.
Tigris, you remember me?
I'm with Plutarch's Underground.
We need your help.
Clear!
I know you.
You're a stylist in the Games.
Until Snow decided
I wasn't pretty enough anymore.
I'm here to kill him.
Gales gonna need stitches.
I made it up.
All of it.
There is no
special mission from Coin.
It's only my plan.
Everyone that's dead,
is dead because of me. I...
I lied
We know.
We all knew.
- Soldiers from 13...
- They need to...
Do you really believe that Jackson
thought you had orders from Coin?
She trusted Boggs, so he
clearly wanted you to go on.
I never meant for this to happen.
I failed them.
I killed-I killed them.
I killed Finnick.
I'm sorry, Pollux.
I'm so sorry.
Glimmer.
Marvel.
Mags.
Clove.
Wiress.
Rue.
What do all those deaths mean?
They mean that our lives
were never ours.
There was no real life,
because we didn't have any choice.
Our lives, belong to Snow
and our deaths do too.
But if you kill him, Katniss.
If you end all of this...
All those deaths,
they mean something.
Cinna.
Boggs.
Castor.
Jackson.
Finnick.
They chose this.
They chose you.
You should keep this clean,
otherwise it will get infected.
You should cuff me.
It's not safe with me yet.
I have moments when I'm here...
My memories are getting better,
but...
Other times, it's like I'm sleepwalking.
You should cuff me.
Thanks, for the water.
I can't sleep.
Yeah, I haven't slept
in days either.
I should have volunteered to
take your place in the first Games.
Well, you couldn't have.
And she-she'd never have forgiven you.
She needs you to be there and take care
of her family and you did.
She can't lose you.
She really loves you.
The way she kissed you
in the Quarter Quell.
She never kissed me like that.
You know it's part of the show, Gale.
No, you won her over.
You gave up everything for her.
It's not going to be
an issue much longer.
I doubt all 3 of us are gonna
make it out of this.
And if we do, then...
It's her problem who to choose, right?
Yeah.
Well, I do know that Katniss will pick
whoever she can't survive without.
Mortar shells.
It's not ours.
Peacekeepers must be shelling
the rebels outside the city.
That's not outside the city.
Sun's coming up.
There's some small arms fire.
Could be Paylor maybe Lyme.
The rebels are close.
This is it.
To all Capitol citizens more than
half a mile outside the city circle.
I'm announcing a mandatory evacuation.
Come to the mansion.
I'm promising you shelter and sanctuary.
All refugees, come to my home
There, you will be provided with food,
medicine, safety for your children.
And you will have my solemn oath
to protect you until my dying breath.
You should hurry up
with that last part.
Our enemies are not like us.
They do not share our values.
They have never known
our comfort and our sophistication.
And they despise us for it.
Make no mistake.
They are not coming
to liberate us.
They are coming to
destroy our way of life.
They are coming to bury us.
Is he still in the mansion?
Peeta?
Yeah.
I recognize the room.
Where's that?
About 5 blocks away.
We are right here,
off the avenues.
- The mansion is here
- What about the Pods?
Well, they'd probably deactivate the
Pods around here for the resident safety.
That could work.
I can get close enough.
Every peacekeeper is
going to be waiting.
Next to our faces
on every billboard.
Snow's offering shelter
to all the refugees.
Head straight north.
There's going to be
thousands of refugees,
just get into that stream
and don't look up.
We got one shot.
Let's make it count.
Good luck, Katniss.
Thank you.
Pollux.
Tigris, thank you for
everything you've done.
Katniss, let me come with you, okay?
- I can be a good distraction, they didn't know my face
- No.
No, I'm not losing you again.
You'll be safer with us.
What if peacemakers are searching
the houses, and if he's captured...
Then, give me a nightlock pill, okay.
I'm not going back.
Stay alive.
If I see you again, it's going
to be a different world.
Are you ready, Katniss?
Let's go.
By order of President Snow,
all residents must proceed
to the presidential estate.
Please continue to move forward
in a calm and orderly fashion.
Additional food, medicine and clothing
will be provided upon arrival.
By order of President Snow,
all residents must proceed
to the presidential estate.
Please continue to move forward
in a calm and orderly fashion.
Additional food, medicine and clothing
will be provided upon arrival.
By order of President Snow,
all residents must proceed
to the presidential estate.
Please continue to move forward
in a calm and orderly fashion.
Additional food, medicine and clothing
will be provided upon arrival.
It's the Rebels!
Don't move!
Rebels!
Mama!
Come on!
Come on.
Shoot me!
Stay calm.
Bring your children forward.
The gates will open momentarily.
The children will be received first.
Stay calm.
Bring your children forward.
The gates will open momentarily.
The children will be received first.
Stay calm.
Bring your children forward.
The gates will open momentarily.
The children will be received first.
It's the Capitol.
Medic!
- Medic!
- Make a hole!
Medics coming in.
Bring a stretcher!
Prim.
Primrose.
Prim!
Hey.
I need you to lie back.
You're okay.
Everything's going to be okay.
The fight was over after that Capitol dropped
those bombs at the feet of the palace.
The rebels walked right in.
Don't, Katniss.
The only one's working.
Everybody felt it.
Peacekeepers. Palace Guards.
They had kids in there too.
It was...
It was over after that.
Mom.
I remember the first
time I brought you here.
And here we are.
I've brought all your things.
Well, I'll leave you to get settled.
Sorry, ma'am.
I can't let you pass.
Let her in.
On my authority.
She has a right to
anything behind that door.
That's a nice one.
The colors are lovely, of course,
but nothing says perfection like white.
I was hoping you'd
find your way here.
There are so many things
we should discuss.
But I have a feeling your
visit will be brief. So,
first things first.
I wanted to tell you
how very sorry I am about your sister.
So wasteful, so unnecessary.
Anyone could see the game
was over by that point.
In fact, I was just about to issue an official
surrender when they released those parachutes.
You released those parachutes.
You really think I gave the order?
We both know
I'm not above killing children,
but I'm not wasteful.
I take life for
specific reasons.
And there was no reason for me to
destroy a pen full of Capitol children.
None at all.
I must concede it was a
masterful move on Coin's part.
The idea that I was bombing our own
helpless children to hold back the Rebels.
It turned the last of
my guards against me.
There was no resistance left inside
the Capitol or the mansion.
Did you know it aired live?
There's a...
particular savvy in that, isn't there?
I'm sure he wasn't gunning
for your sister, but...
These things happen in war.
My failure was being so slow
to grasp Coin's plan.
She let the Capitol and the
districts destroy one another,
and she step in to take power
over Thirteen arsenal.
But make no mistake.
She intends to take
my place now.
But, I've been watching you.
And you watching me.
I'm afraid we have both
been played for fools.
I don't believe you
Oh, my dear Miss Everdeen.
I thought we had agreed
never to lie to each other.
President Coin ask for you.
You never came to see me.
- I wanted to.
- Was it ours?
The bomb?
The delayed explosion.
The trap.
To draw more people in.
Was that you?
I don't know.
All I know is,
I'm suppose to take
care of your family.
And I'm sorry I couldn't.
You can't protect
anyone in an Arena.
Goodbye, Gale.
What's this?
The remaining Victors.
Won't you join us?
I've invited you all here for
several reasons, but first...
I have an announcement.
I am taking the burden
and the honor of declaring
myself interim President of Panem.
Interim?
Exactly how long
is that interim?
We have no way
of knowing for certain.
But, it's clear that people
are far too emotional
right now to make a
rational decision.
We'll plan an election
when the time is right.
But I've called you here
for a far more important vote.
A symbolic vote.
This afternoon we will execute Snow.
Hundreds of his accomplices
also await their deaths.
Capitol officials, peacekeepers,
torturers, gamemakers.
But the danger is,
once we begin
the rebels will not stop
calling for retribution.
Thirst for blood is a
difficult urge to satisfy.
So...
I offer an alternative plan.
A majority of four may approve it.
No one may abstain.
The proposal is this.
In lieu of these
barbaric executions,
we hold a symbolic Hunger Games.
You want to have another Hunger Games
with the Capitol's children?
- You're joking?
- Not in the slightest.
Is this Plutarch's idea?
It was mine.
It balances the need for revenge
with the least loss of human life.
- You may cast your votes.
- No.
No, obviously not.
This is crazy.
No, I think it's more than fair.
Snow's got a granddaughter.
I say, yes.
So do I.
Let them have a taste of it.
You guys, this way of thinking is
what started these uprisings.
I vote no, with Peeta.
So would Finnick,
if he were here.
Well, he's not,
because Snow killed him.
No.
We need to stop viewing
each other as enemies.
It's down to Katniss and Haymitch.
I get to kill Snow.
I expected no less of you.
Then I vote yes...
for Prim.
Haymitch.
I'm with the Mockingjay.
That carries the vote.
Excellent.
I'll announce the games tonight,
after the execution.
Bound to be
quite the show.
Oh, you look lovely, as ever.
Just beautiful.
Finishing touches.
Welcome to the new Panem.
Today, on the avenue of the tributes.
All of Panem,
a free Panem
will watch more
than a mere spectacle.
We are gathered to witness
a historic moment of justice.
Today, the greatest friend of the revolution,
will fire the shot
to end all wars.
May her arrow signify
the end of tyranny
and the beginning
of a new era.
Mockingjay, may your aim be
as true as your heart is pure.
Eh-ha-ha...
Ha ha ha...
No.
- Kill him!
Kill him!
I'll say this for you, Katniss.
You don't disappoint.
Well, Plutarch gave
me a letter for you.
I don't want it.
You never make it easy, do you?
Okay.
I'll read it for you.
Katniss, maybe the country was
shocked tonight by your arrow,
but once again
I was not.
You're exactly who
I believe you were.
I wish I could give you a proper good bye
but with both Coin and Snow dead,
the fate of the country will be decided
tonight and I can't be seen at your side.
Tonight, the 12 district leaders
will call for a free election.
There's no doubt that Paylor will carry,
she's become the voice of reason.
I'm sorry so much
burden fell on you.
I know you'll never escape it.
But if I had to put
you through it again
for this outcome.
I would.
The war is over.
We're in that sweet period
where everyone agrees
not to repeat the recent horrors.
Of course, we are
fickle stupid beings
with poor memories and a
great gift for self-destruction.
Although who knows?
Maybe this time we'll learn.
I've secured you a ride
out of the capital.
It's better for you
to be out of sight.
And when the time is right,
Commander Paylor will pardon you.
The country will find it's peace.
And I hope you can find yours.
Plutarch.
What now?
Home.
We go home.
I couldn't let you go
without a proper goodbye.
It's your job to take care
of yourself now, Katniss.
Promise me you'll find it.
Find what?
The life of a Victor.
- Goodbye Effie.
- Goodbye, my girl.
Effie don't be a stranger.
- Take care of her.
- I will.
She's gone.
Get out.
Get out!
Prim is gone!
She's dead and
she's not coming back!
Get out!
Peeta.
Hey.
You came home.
Yeah.
I found these...
off by the edge of the forest.
It's Primrose.
I'm so sorry, Katniss.
You'll be happy to hear
that Katniss' mother
has been training new medical
units in the Capitol.
Gale has been promoted
to a Captain in District 2
to help keep order and security.
And I'm loving every moment
with my son.
He reminds me everyday
of his father.
We've all suffer so much.
But we owe it to their memories
and to our children to do
our best with these lives.
I hope you're both
finding some peace.
Annie.
I solemnly swear
to the best of my ability
to preserve, protect and uphold
the rights of every citizen at Panem.
There's Plutarch,
brand know it all.
And they say,
no one ever wins the games.
You love me.
Real or not real?
Real.
Did you have a nightmare?
I have nightmares too.
Someday, I'll explain it to you.
Why they came.
Why they won't ever go away.
But I'll tell you
how I survived it.
I'll make a list in my head,
for all the good things
I've seen someone do.
Every little thing I can remember.
It's like a game.
I do it over and over.
Get's a little tedious
after all these years, but...
There are much worse games to play.
Subtitle created by: ;;;===€h☼¥)