- Hello, hello, hello.
- Hey.
RUPAUL: Previously
on "RuPaul's Drag Race UK"...
We're gonna play the Snatch Game.
[cheers and laughter]
Queen Elizabeth I, would you
consider yourself thirsty?
Parched.
[laughter]
- Lil Nas X.
- Bend Over.
RUPAUL:
Okay. All right.
Well...
Black Peppa.
The laughter really didn't happen.
Le Fil, your Marie Kondo
wasn't absurd enough.
I say touch.
Every time you touch something,
it spark joy.
Yeah.
Hello, Cheddar Gorgeous.
You're very smart.
- What a triumph.
- [mouthing words]
Condragulations,
you're the winner
of this week's challenge.
[applause]
Black Peppa, shantay, you stay.
Le Fil, sashay away.
[dramatic music]
[trills]
The shade is cru-el.
- [groans]
- Oh, Le Fil.
BLACK PEPPA:
We're back in the workroom,
and I've just sent Le Fil home.
[sighs]
Well, I love Le Fil so much,
but I had to make sure
that I fought, because
I'm not going anywhere.
"Keep whipping that hair.
Smash those gender roles.
Love, Le Fil-osophical."
That performance was incredible.
I mean, everything's
going out of who knows what.
I didn't know what
was going on for half of it.
Ooh, I've seen a lot of very
peculiar performances in my time,
but Le Fil maybe takes the biscuit.
There was mud and grass flying.
It's like there was
a hurricane at Glastonbury.
I may not be a funny bitch,
but you know what?
I can lip-synch Le Fil
out of the competition.
- Ooh, girl, fighting.
- You know what?
'Cause you're a fierce bitch
and that's why you deserve to be here.
We love you, Le Fil.
ALL: We love you, Le Fil.
- Le Fil-osophical.
- Sweetie darling.
Fil came here and really showed the world
what he's made of.
Although I'm sad to see him go,
I'm super proud of him.
Well, girls, here we are.
Top...
- Here we are.
ALL: The top six.
- Whoo!
Cheddar, congratulations on winning.
- Congratulations, well done.
- Thank you.
Are you taking the comedy badge away
from Danny now, like...
- [gasps]
I don't think I could ever wrestle
the class clown title from Danny,
and I wouldn't want to.
I'd sit on you, bitch,
and take the badge off you.
[laughs]
How did you feel this week?
'Cause I feel like you took
a little bit of a knock.
Yeah, I put a lot of pressure on me self.
Do you know what?
It was all right.
It weren't me best work,
but in 20 years' time,
they might be playing that clip
and be mistaking it for the real Cilla.
Oh, oh, 1.000%.
I mean, you know...
[laughter]
DANNY: Hey, I don't see this
as taking a knock.
I've still got three badges,
and there's still opportunity to get more.
So there's a chance.
But you know what?
I'm looking around now,
and I'm like, this is strong.
We all have different strengths.
- Yeah.
- And each of us...
Yours is lip-synching.
Danny.
Obviously.
What's mine?
I haven't won a badge.
- Yours is coasting.
- Survival.
[laughter]
Jonbers clearly has a lot to offer.
He's an amazing performer.
Survival is a very
important skill in this world.
But I haven't been able to pick out yet,
what is the essence of Jonbers?
Who is Jonbers?
Well, I'm being positive.
I'm on top for Snatch Game.
[all cheering]
Let's de-drag, girls.
I'm in so much pain.
- Yes.
- [screams]
[indistinct chatter]
- Oh, God.
- Top six, girls.
Top seven, top six.
Caw-caw.
I can see a few side eyes here now.
- [moans]
- Oh, my God, that is orgasmic.
These queens are watching me now,
and rightly so.
The fibers are fused.
[laughter]
I am genuinely really sorry
for these girls.
[pops lips] One by
one, I will send them out.
Make sure you do your prayers
and your Kumbaya,
because I'm not going anywhere.
JONBERS: Oh, my God.
DANNY: I need some more
badges on my boobies.
These girls need to get out.
- You look like Miss Piggy.
- [gasps]
[laughs]
[snorts]
RUPAUL: The winner crowned
the UK's next "Drag Race" superstar
will receive an all-expenses-paid
trip to Hollywood
to create their own digital series
with the producers
of "RuPaul's Drag Race."
Tonight with Michelle Visage,
Graham Norton,
and extra-special guest judge.
Boy George.
[singing]
SINGER: RuPaul's Drag Race.
RUPAUL: May the best woman,
best woman win
[tires squealing]
[upbeat music]
- Ooh.
- Come on.
BOTH: Whoo!
PIXIE:
It's a brand-new week,
and it's yet another chance
for all of us girls
to prove that we belong here
in this competition.
[singing] Ba-da, ba-da, ba-da
I'm gonna smash it.
I say it every week.
Do I always?
Maybe not, but you know what?
I'm confident that this week
is gonna be my week.
[softly] Fingers crossed]
Looking around, is this how
everybody imagined the top six to be?
Well, I certainly
didn't imagine being here,
but no one's surprised to hear that.
Dakota, self-doubt?
But honestly, like,
to be here right now, like,
I'm so immensely proud of myself.
Now that Snatch Game is over,
none of us know what to expect.
I think, hopefully, it's something
maybe a bit more tailored to my skill set.
Genuinely, that feeling of,
like, positivity,
it's not forced anymore;
It's, like, actually real.
Do you know what? I'm
so glad to hear that, though,
because at least now
you can end on a high.
Shut up, you bitch.
[laughter]
Pixie Polite
ain't so polite anymore, girls.
- A shady lady.
- She's getting rude.
I couldn't have seen a better top six,
and I'm really happy that it's us.
- Yes.
- I know. Yay!
[alarm blaring]
[all scream]
RUPAUL: Her majesty
done already done had hers.
[all yelling]
My queens, the time has come
to repay those
who have so unselfishly
given of their time and care.
So if you can't be with the ones you love,
drag the ones you're with.
[engine revs]
- [groans]
- Family.
- It's makeovers.
- It's family resemblance, so..
It's makeovers.
Family resemblance, girls.
DANNY: Are you worried?
It's just doing somebody else's makeup.
I've just got mine good.
[laughter]
Hello, hello, hello.
ALL: Hi!
- Yes.
- Whoo!
Now, ladykins, in a few weeks,
one of you will be crowned
the UK's next "Drag Race" superstar.
[gasps]
But no one makes it
to the top on their own.
It takes a village, people.
[laughs]
- Yes.
- True. A team of 50.
All of us owe a debt of
gratitude to our amazing crew
that works tirelessly behind
the scenes day in and day out.
Am I right, Mr. Cameraman?
[laughs]
This week, I want to honor
one group in particular.
I'm talking about the Queen Team.
[gasps]
ALL: Yes!
- Oh, my God.
- Yes. Yes. Yes.
- [laughs]
- That's exciting.
A group of selfless ladies
that make sure you're fed,
make sure your corsets are tightened,
and hold your hand every
high-heeled step of this competition.
- Oh, my God.
- Yes. I'm so excited.
BLACK PEPPA:
For those who don't know,
the Queen Team is literally
our backbone in this competition.
They do everything to make sure
that we are taken really well care of,
keeping us together from losing our shit.
Please welcome to the workroom
Fleur...
[cheers and applause]
Gemma...
Lucie...
[cheers and applause]
DAKOTA:
Come on, Lucie.
Mystique.
[cheers and applause]
- Oh, my God.
- Hi.
Oh, she's wearing a tie for the occasion.
Yeah.
[laughter]
I am.
A special occasion.
Olivia...
[cheers and applause]
Wendy.
[cheers and laughter]
Wendy! Oh!
[laughter]
Oh, my God.
PIXIE: They have been
so kind to us and so caring,
they have become our mothers
and our sisters and our family
while we've been here.
Hello, ladies.
ALL: Hi, Ru.
My queens, for this week's Maxi Challenge,
you'll be giving these fabulous
hardworking ladies
a head-to-toe drag makeover.
[laughs]
Now, this is your chance
to hold their hands for a change
as you share the miracle of drag.
[laughs wickedly]
What's the evil laugh for, Danny?
#DragRaceUK.
Now, since the ladies of the Queen Team
work with all of you,
I'm going to pair you alphabetically.
[all gasp]
I'm like, ga-dunk, ga-dunk, ga-dunk.
I don't know the alphabet.
[laughs]
That means, Black Peppa,
you'll be with Fleur.
Ah!
[laughter]
Cheddar Gorgeous, you'll be with Gemma.
- Gemma.
- Ah.
Dakota Schiffer, you'll be with Lucie.
[cheers and applause]
Danny Beard, you will be with Mystique.
Yes, Mystique.
Jonbers Blonde, you will be with Olivia.
[gasps] Yes!
Yay!
[laughs]
My baby.
And that means, Pixie Polite,
you are with Wendy.
[cheers and applause]
I'm with Wendy.
CHEDDAR: They are the people
who work so hard
and their labor very rarely gets seen,
so it's gonna be really nice
just to make them feel great.
Queens, you can use your own drag
plus any of the wigs,
shoes, and jewelry provided.
Remember, as always,
the judges will be looking for
a strong drag family resemblance.
Now, racers, start your engines,
and may the best drag queen win.
[cheers and applause]
[indistinct chatter]
[screams]
- Baby, are you excited?
- I'm so excited.
I can't believe that this
week's Maxi Challenge
is not only family resemblance,
but we get to make over
the amazing Queen Team.
Before we look into looks...
- Yeah.
Have you been in drag before?
I've never been in drag before, never.
- You like a heel?
- Yeah.
'Cause I know got, like,
your own style backstage.
Well, you know, I swing both ways.
- [clicking tongue]
- So... yeah.
Which is perfect to be family Beards.
'Cause I think you're, like, for me,
the most exuberant and extrovert queen,
and I'm the most introvert...
- Yeah.
- Queen Team member.
Yeah, but don't think
that's gonna hold you back here.
MYSTIQUE: No.
Because this is about
a family resemblance.
- Yeah.
- I know, inside of Mystique,
there is an animal,
and I am gonna find it,
and I am gonna grab it,
and I'm gonna pull it onto the main stage.
[cat meows]
Are you ready to become a Schiffer, Lucie?
Oh, babes, I was born ready.
I can't wait.
You especially, like,
just kept me grounded
when I have been in, like...
There's been lots wobbles.
- Oh.
- And you've just been so good to me.
Babe, honestly.
I just can't wait to put you...
To Schiffer-ize you.
It's gonna be so good.
- I can't wait.
So you do love a day beat.
You've got a gorgeous day beat.
- I love makeup.
- Yes.
And I do like to put a bit on day-to day.
- But I've never done drag before.
Always wanted to but never ever.
Yes, especially, like, my makeup,
it's not the most, like, exaggerated,
but I've painted lots of people before
with different facial structures.
- Okay.
- And even just looking
at your face now, you are
going to look so gorgeous.
I am so excited.
Both of us being
hyper-feminine individuals,
it sort of feels like it was meant to be.
The idea I'm having is very,
like, 1960s Balenciaga.
Stop.
The classic Dakota Schiffer experience.
My twin, Harry, might be
a little bit surprised
when I come back with a triplet,
but I'm looking forward
to having a new family member.
- Schiffer-ize me. I can't wait.
- Schiffer-ize.
[laughs]
I'm just so happy that we can
finally take good care of you,
which we will.
- Please.
And I cannot wait to turn
this whole thing around.
[laughs]
I am paired with the lovely Fleur.
We share such a special bond.
Baby, this is a pairing, okay?
- I'm super excited.
- Okay.
But I'll be real with you, Peppa.
- Yeah.
- One of the fears I have
is that from when I came out,
I ditched the heels,
I put on some lovely black boots...
- Yeah.
And I haven't looked back since.
Okay.
So when it comes to walking in heels,
that's not my forte.
- Okay.
So even when I was trying to be straight,
honestly, like, even then...
- You didn't like heels.
I didn't like heels.
Heel no.
Okay.
Well, we will work on that.
I am concerned about Fleur
not wearing heels.
My brand is all about the high heels
and the walk,
but don't worry, baby.
You're in good hands.
I'm gonna make sure I Peppa spray you up.
You're gonna be fine walking with me.
You know, I think you're incredible.
Honestly.
- [laughs]
- How are you?
- I'm good.
I'm actually, like, really excited.
- Yeah?
- I'm not nervous.
- Yeah.
- I think it's just, like, anticipation.
You are also, I think, known out
of all the Queen Team members
as the one who...
- Oh, God.
Is gonna be bringing in
the laughs, the jokes,
the fun, the vibrancy...
- Oh, stop.
The energy.
Oh, no. Not me.
I'm shy.
- Right? I know. Exactly.
- Stop. Oh, my God.
Doing makeovers in drag
is something I've been doing for years.
[laughs]
CHEDDAR: The trick is
gonna be making our energies
complement one another.
I'm really excited to see
Gemma embody that
more kind of slow, you know, alien deity.
Do you have any ideas for drag names yet,
before we look at costumes?
I think we go for the cheese
and the description.
You are 100% energy all the time.
- Yeah.
- What's a better word for energy?
Annoying.
[laughter]
What about Brie?
- Stop. I love Brie.
- Brie.
Brie Gorgeous
because you gotta Brie gorgeous.
We did think about Mini Cheddar,
but apparently that's taken.
I am so excited that I got you
and so excited to drag you up.
Yes! This is gonna be great.
- Thank you.
It's very weird to be sat here.
Usually I'm very much
behind the walls of this room.
- I know, so...
- What the hell?
Now, you're always running
around after us in trainers.
Have you ever wore heels?
- Very occasionally.
- Once in a blue moon.
Once a year for Royal Ascot,
and that's it.
For Royal Ascot?
[laughter]
Is there anything particular
that's worrying you?
The runway... that moment
of going down the runway
is freaking me out.
Well, look, it freaks me out
every time, too,
but there's always a good energy in it.
My look is based on clowns,
so this is all fun.
There's nothing serious here.
My only concern in this is Olivia.
I want her to enjoy it
how I enjoy the runway.
You look after me so much
in this competition,
I'm gonna look after you, so you do not...
- Thank you very, very much.
- Have to be worried at all.
There's no one else
I'd rather make my drag mother
in this moment than you.
- Oh.
Like, I literally
was so elated to have, like...
I'm getting emotional about it.
I just love you.
[speaking indistinctly]
Wendy is like the mother hen
of the queens and the Queen Team.
She is clucking about,
making sure we're all happy and well fed.
The amount of times she's tried
to force-feed me sandwiches
while I'm trying to tighten my corset...
it's not the time, Wendy.
It's just like the stars have aligned.
I think we're a match made in heaven.
- Yeah, and I've just...
- I mean, you've got arthritis.
I have dodgy knees.
- [laughs]
I have every faith in you, Wens.
But I'm looking forward
to the whole glam look of it.
- Mm-hmm.
- Makeup, can't wait.
- Okay.
- Eyelashes, can't wait.
Just everything.
- Yeah.
- I'm just really, really...
- We'll get some big lashes on you...
- Yeah.
- A lovely little...
- Lace front.
Wendy.
- Oh.
We need to choose you a drag name.
- I've got one idea.
- Okay, what's your idea?
You know I've got a big bottom, so...
- Yes, I do.
- My drag name is
Hugh, H-U-G-H,
Jarsse, J-A-R-S-S-E.
[laughs]
- Do you know what?
- Hugh Jarsse.
If you're gonna be a drag king...
- Yeah, okay.
- I feel like yes.
After this, you can go and
live your life as Hugh Jarsse.
[laughter]
We are cackling
like witches in the corner.
Wendy has such an infectious energy,
and I can't wait to walk
down that runway with her.
Well, let's talk about face wigs.
Oh, face wigs.
- Now...
- Looks like a merkin.
Yeah, a merkin for a different
set of lips, sweetie.
- [laughs]
- My plan of action:
Get Mystique comfortable
and feeling gorgeous.
Today is about building up her confidence.
So if you have the lilac beard,
I have the mint hair.
If you have the mint hair,
I have the lilac beard.
- Got you. I got you.
- You get me?
We are gonna look like sisters
from different misters.
Yeah.
I will try it out, but if I look at myself
in the mirror and I think...
[groans]
Then I'll let you know.
- Yeah.
And don't forget, you are
a part of the Beard family.
Yeah.
So we need some hair on there.
You know?
- Yeah. Eyebrows.
Beards.
[laughs]
- I know. I know.
Please wear the beard.
Please wear the freaking beard.
[singing] Da, da-da, da-da.
Here we go, Mama Wendy's in the house.
Yes, Mama Wendy, work.
You look like Dakota after, like,
a heavy night and lots of cigarettes.
[laughter]
- This is just beautiful.
- Yes.
That fabric... back in the '90s,
my mom definitely had
some sort of, like...
Yes.
Accent in her bedroom that was this color.
It doesn't really come alive
until the person's wearing it
because a shift silhouette,
we've seen it miss and we've seen it hit.
- Right. Okay.
- But I think...
- This time, it's gonna hit.
- It's gonna absolutely hit.
Don't you worry.
We're gonna sell the...
We're gonna sell the bleep out of it.
- So-and-sos out of that.
- [laughs]
- I look like if Rod Stewart...
Is really down on his luck.
- I think you look lovely.
- This is absolutely mental.
- Surprise, surprise, surprise.
- Ah!
[all cheering]
It's Raven, hunty.
[screams] Raven is in the workroom.
Ru wanted me to stop in
and check on your progress.
Is it okay?
ALL: Yes.
- Please.
She is perfection,
and this is definitely a moment
I'm gonna cherish.
Is this your first time
getting into drag, Fleur?
I once did, like, a drag king
thing at, like, a talent show
with my girlfriend,
but it was just, like...
It was a little bit of fun, not
actual drag, so this is huge.
So this is your first time
getting into, like, glam drag.
Yeah, yeah, big-time.
You have done your makeup
many, many, many times.
Have you ever painted anyone else?
- Never.
- Never?
I've never painted anyone else.
It's gonna be a club-kid route,
and that's something
that I'm really good at
'cause I love being
really artistic and stuff.
When you go out there, the light kind of
diffuses everything, and you want
to just have things pop a little more.
You do a beautiful crease,
but try cutting it a little more.
I can tell you have a confidence.
[laughs]
I can tell you are not nervous about this,
but you have never painted anyone before,
so I'm excited to see.
- Thank you.
- Bye.
Hi, Pixie Polite and Wendy.
- Hello, Raven.
- Hello.
You're the legend out of the Queen Team.
I'm not a legend.
I'm just the oldie.
[laughter]
And so you've been here
since the beginning.
Yes, season one.
You started season one, episode one.
- Yup.
- Now, out of all that time,
what's the weirdest thing
you've ever had to do for a drag queen?
Backstage, just before a runway,
I've had to bend right down
and go underneath,
do a popper up underneath,
and stick everything back in.
Yes.
- You had to po...
Not everything.
Just one.
[laughs]
- One bollock.
- Oh, you...
[laughter]
- Sorry.
- Wendy.
- Well...
- Yeah.
- Luckily it wasn't two.
- [laughs]
Now, you are gonna be doing purple?
We're playing on a sort of
fairy, pixie theme.
And we're just gonna be... you're
gonna be my mummer, aren't you?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Do you do heels?
I do wear them out.
I wore some to a funeral last week.
That's not really out.
[laughter]
But okay.
All right, then I'll let
you guys get to it.
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you so much.
- Howdy.
- Hello.
Hi. So you won
the Snatch Game.
I did. Crazy.
Now, what do you think that
makes the other queens feel?
Probably a mix of fear and admiration.
And I'm fine with that.
- Good.
Now, Gemma.
- Yeah.
- Ever done drag?
- Well, every day.
- Every day is drag for you.
- You know...
So you are a girl
that likes to wear makeup.
You like to wear heels?
Well, yeah.
I mean, back in the day.
More than makeup, I feel like you have
the attitude of a drag queen,
which is far more important.
Now, Cheddar has a very eclectic
and avant-garde type of drag.
For me, a little more freeing
than just being pretty.
I totally agree with that.
I think, as prickly girls,
I think we're told so often to be pretty.
I'm gonna just throw myself
in the deep end
and hope for the best.
And you are gonna let Cheddar
do what Cheddar does best.
Totally. Cheese me up.
I can't wait.
- Thank you.
- Thanks, gorgeous.
See you later.
- Thanks.
Good luck.
Have fun.
Hi, Jonbers and Olivia.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Great. How are you?
I'm really well, love.
Thanks for asking.
[with Irish accent]
Ooh, well, you're quite welcome.
[laughter]
[normally] Now, what are you
gonna give Olivia?
Olivia is very like me
in that we don't take ourselves
too seriously,
so the concept that I've went
with is, like, mime clowns,
a black-and-white theme.
I'm doing it in a very chic way.
Yeah, I mean, that's what drag queens are.
- Exactly.
- We're clowns.
- We are clowns.
Exactly.
We are the clowns of the gay community.
Have you ever painted anyone else before?
Just, like, on a night out
with her girlfriends.
I'm not worried,
but any tips would be helpful.
What I would say is, you know, you have
a very little about of space
between your nose and your lip.
- Yeah.
- I would bring the contour up a little,
and then your brow, just
make it arch a little bit more.
Arch them. Yeah.
Now, have you ever done drag before?
- Absolutely not.
- No.
- Have you tucked ever?
I don't think I've ever needed to.
[laughter]
So are you willing to go all in?
I really am.
I'm... yeah.
I'm up for anything.
You are gonna look absolute
charisma, uniqueness, nerve, and talent.
- Yes.
All right, now, get the fuck out of here.
[laughter]
Now, Lucie, you've been here
since day one.
That's right.
Series one to four.
Honestly, it doesn't feel like a job.
It feels like a dream to be here,
especially as a queer person
in this space,
you know, that's watched
the show and that loves it.
Like, it really is amazing.
- Well, you just got a raise.
- [laughs]
- Thank you.
- Now, Dakota,
you are not... you are a natural girl.
Are you gonna get in there
with Lucie's makeup
or just do a pretty natural beat?
The judges have commented
on the subtlety of my drag.
So we're gonna do
a quite high-contrast eye
because I know the judges
want to see transformation.
This is just a chance to maybe
go in a little bit more, saying,
"Yeah, I know I'm pretty,
but look what else I can do."
Yes.
Use all the crayons in the crayon box.
I know Raven's aesthetic
is more exaggerated than mine,
so I'll happily take
those suggestions on board.
- Good luck.
- Thank you so much, Raven.
All right, come on over,
Danny and Mystique.
Mystique, you showed up with a drag name.
- Yeah.
- [laughs]
This looks a lot shorter than normal.
I keep it trim for drag,
but with the magic of custom lace...
Ah.
A custom lace beard.
Is Mystique gonna be a bearded queen?
I'm gonna try them on
and see how I feel with them.
So what are your reservations
when it comes to that?
As you can see, I'm not
the most feminine of women.
I'm often mistaken for a male person.
It is one of those things
that I'm still a bit icky with.
The thing that I think
people still don't understand
about drag is that it has
always been about
fuck societal norms on gender.
I'm decorating myself.
Mystique's spoken honestly and candidly,
and I really appreciate it.
I don't want to push her
into feeling uncomfortable.
I cannot wait to see what you turn out.
DANNY: I hope that she can,
by the end of tomorrow,
feel sexy and have a bit of facial hair
and know that she is a superstar.
I want to be, like, out, in, out.
Shake it all about.
The secret to wearing heels...
Yeah.
Is that they're not supposed
to be comfortable.
Yeah, okay.
I feel that.
But no one needs to know
that they're not comfortable.
Okay.
So Fleur has not worn heels
for a long, long, long time.
And this is her moment to feel that power.
Five, six, seven, and...
Look at you.
- How am I doing?
- Whoa, girl.
- That actually feels okay.
You're doing good.
Ah!
That actually feels all right.
Fleur, you're in my house now, baby.
Five, six, seven, and...
Yeah, but with a bit more grace.
- Okay, more grace.
- Yeah.
Gosh.
CHEDDAR: Good?
GEMMA: Yeah, that's great.
I'm a bit worried you might be liking this
a little bit too much, Gemma.
Come on. Take a queue in
my little shoe shop, my angel.
What shoe size are you, my darling?
- I'm, like, a seven and eight.
- You're a seven, eight?
- Seven, eight. Yeah.
- Okay. Okay.
My nature in life is to be
quite a positive and nurturing person.
I want to get this look on her
as fast as possible...
I should've shaved my toes.
[laughs]
Shave... shaved your toes.
And just really encouraging Olivia.
OLIVIA: Oh, my God.
JONBERS: Come on.
OLIVIA: Is that right?
No, yeah, that's definitely right, Olivia.
Come on.
[laughter]
Are these gonna fit you?
I think you might be an eight, angel.
Seven. Six and a half.
Are you too big for these shoes?
- Well, okay, basically...
- And I got a smaller fit than you.
No, no, so I say that I'm a seven
when I'm probably a nine.
[laughs]
Those feet are boats.
- I feel like...
- Am I putting Bigfoot into drag?
She has lied about her shoe size.
She is a drag queen through and through.
[laughs]
- Stop.
- No!
I learn quite quickly
when people explain things.
Oh, my God.
- It's literally just walk.
Walk. Glide.
Pretend like you're gliding.
Oh, no.
- Oh, Mystique.
- Oh, my God.
- There she is.
- [laughs]
- Making her into a mummer.
Oh, my God.
She's been to Turkey, bitch.
Why is it weirdly bulgy here?
Pixie, love.
Please.
My sister has got the queen
of the Queen Team, Wendy,
and honestly, right now, she looks like
she's just rolled through
B&amp;M with Velcro
strapped to her body and come out
with whatever's on the other side.
I'm like, there's camp love,
and there's...
[sighs]
Gay vomit.
When did you come out?
I didn't come out until I was about 21.
I was just so terrified.
You know when you lose an eyelash?
- Yeah.
- You make a wish.
I'd literally wish, like, to be straight.
I just wanted to... to fit in.
How is it with your parents?
My mother has always been,
like, my biggest cheerleader,
so I think I was just
really scared of losing her
as that person in my life.
- Yeah.
But she now, like, celebrates
my queerness so much.
She comes to every single
football match I play in.
Oh, yeah.
She started watching "Drag Race,"
and I feel like through watching this,
she's just learned so much
about queerness, full stop.
That is so amazing
that your mom supports you.
Yeah.
I just remember feeling like
I just could never, ever tell anyone.
I remember seeing my dad.
He would watch, like, in the
news, things that would happen
to queer people, and he would be like,
"Batty man, them.
How could you, you know,
love a guy?"
And I'd be in my room just,
like, trembling like shit.
Like, I'm literally one
of those people, you know?
Growing up in Saint Martin,
it literally is paradise.
I am so fortunate to be from somewhere
where people go on vacation.
But it's a very religious place,
so being gay is obviously a no-no.
I had to go to church
almost every day of the week.
You know, you're brought
in a Christian background
knowing that homosexuality is wrong.
You just feel like
everything that you are,
you know, life is against.
- Yeah.
It's very, very difficult
to be out of the closet
in the island where I'm from.
Because Saint Martin is so small,
there's nothing you can do
that kind of goes under the radar.
You find yourself having
to hide and pretend.
You have no support.
You have no one on your side.
I just couldn't tell anyone, and
I felt like I couldn't trust anyone.
I'm so sorry.
I know it sounds ridiculous,
but this is a time
when I was like, you know,
"I'm gonna be rebellious."
I started sneaking out the house,
going to the underground gay scene.
There was, like, one gay club
where I'm from.
So someone in the club was spying on me
and sent my mom a video.
- That's horrible.
I remember my dad
would ask me on the spot,
"Are you gay?
Like, I need an answer now.
"Are you gay or not?
"Because people are telling
me this, and I need to know.
I don't want no gay son
in my house."
Imagine being on the spot,
like, if I had to tell him,
I'd probably get kicked out the house.
- Yeah.
- I'd be homeless.
Someone who's gay in the Caribbean,
it's just like, you don't win.
We... we're constantly in fear.
It's really scary, like,
being in a household like that,
where it's so religious that
you don't even feel worthy of living.
I was so, like, suicidal already.
Like...
[crying]
I remember going to church,
and I was like,
"Can I just be straight?"
People think,
"Oh, you choose to be gay."
Why the hell would I want to put myself
through all that turmoil, you know?
[sniffles]
[sighs]
It really put things
into perspective for me
that you know what?
If I'm gonna stay here and feel like this,
this is not gonna go anywhere,
and I need to leave.
And thankfully for me,
I was blessed with a brain.
After years
of all the bullying and all of that,
I decided it was time to leave.
Luckily I was a nerd
and got a scholarship
to come to Coventry University,
and I studied biomedical science.
Graduated with my master's,
and I got a first-class degree.
It was like a shift... a shift
happened in me.
I started dressing differently.
I started acting more openly.
When someone would ask me,
"Are you gay?"
I'd be like, "Yeah."
- My God.
How did that feel the first time?
I felt so liberated.
It was such a good feeling.
I'm not, like, this shame label
that people wanted me
to feel like when I was back home.
I realize I have so many
of my years to catch up on.
I look at a queer person here
who's younger than I am,
and they're fully realized.
And I'm like,
"Why am I not like them?"
You know, it's because
I've been holding back
all of who I was all this time.
I have no regrets coming to the UK.
And I didn't feel the love from my family,
and I had to find that love within myself.
And I think that's why
I have such a good drive.
I'm just so proud of myself.
Seeing where I came from to being here,
like...
[chuckles]
You're so strong, and the fact
that you're here right now
being you and showing everyone
who Peppa is...
- Yeah.
- Just is incredible.
BLACK PEPPA: The relationship
I have with my family now,
although it's not the best,
recently my mom did reach out.
It will be a long process,
but I know that there is hope,
and I can see the relationship
igniting slowly again.
For me, it's an honor to be able
to have family resemblance,
like, with you, honestly.
BLACK PEPPA:
I might cinch you to death,
but, you know, forgive me for now.
[laughter]
[gasps] [laughter]
- Whoo!
- Let's go!
Yeah.
[laughs]
- Yes.
- Family.
It's elimination day,
and today we're making over
the "RuPaul's Drag Race UK" Queen Team.
WENDY: Are you putting
a wig cap on me?
PIXIE: We'll put a wig
cap on you today, yeah.
Oh!
JONBERS: It's weird
having 12 people back here.
I've got six more
drag queens to deal with.
Too many... [singing]
Too many drag queens.
Too many drag queens [chuckles]
Welcome to the salon.
What are we thinking?
Highlights? Lowlights?
[laughs] Highlights, I think.
Someone been treating you bad?
At the moment,
where it stands this morning,
Mystique is not very comfortable
wearing the facial hair.
Got the lilac and the mint.
- Oh, nice. Yeah.
So they pick right up through the...
Perfect.
And then we go round the edges like I do,
so we can see it's a mask.
- Yeah.
So all your gorgeous skin tone
is still gonna be on show
so we still know who you are.
Do you know what I mean?
- Yeah.
Because that's important.
I'm hoping once I've beat her face
to within an inch of its life,
she is gonna feel a billion dollars.
And when she feels a billion dollars,
she'll say,
"Eh, throw the beard on."
FLEUR: We're doing
a similar face, I think.
Are we?
BLACK PEPPA: Yeah.
Yeah, I'm doing, like, a clown white face.
Oh, so you're doing
a Danny Beard look tonight.
That's interesting.
BLACK PEPPA: It's not
a Danny Beard look, though.
You didn't invent it.
Sorry to break it to you.
So first it was clash of the blobbies.
Now it's clash of the clown makeup.
Am I pressed?
Absolutely not,
'cause my face gonna be
completely different from theirs.
They're called similarities
'cause they're similar.
They're not the same, so...
So are you gonna
glue down my eyebrows now?
We are, yeah.
I'm feeling very confident.
I know that I can...
[clicks tongue]
Stamp my face straight onto Wendy's mug.
I can't wait to be a fairy princess.
I know.
I'm not one who goes subtle
with the makeup,
so I don't think she's really
ready for what she's in for.
Have you got a good idea
of what you're doing?
Me?
WENDY: Yeah.
- Yes, dear.
- No, I mean, color-wise,
not, like, do you know how to do drag?
Yes.
No, we're gonna...
JONBERS:
"Do you know how to do drag?"
[laughter]
I didn't mean that.
Just make sure we get
all the details right.
Oh, I just love it so much.
Gemma has some of the most
wonderful real estate for makeup
I've ever worked on.
It's great.
I get to just really focus
on making the look really over the top
and really extravagant
and really gorgeous.
GEMMA: [stifles laugh]
CHEDDAR:
Stop laughing,
or else, it'll be printed
on your face forever.
How are you feeling today?
How are you...
I'm good.
I'm feeling a lot less nervous
than I was yesterday morning.
Yeah. I mean, it's a big...
Do you know what I mean?
- Yeah.
You're normally on the
other side of the camera...
- Exactly.
- So, like...
I think it's normal to be a bit nervous,
but I feel a lot more at ease.
DAKOTA:
I was so excited
to be paired with you, Luce.
We've, like, talked so much about, like,
our fashion and makeup references.
And, like, I knew that, like,
it was gonna be a perfect match.
LUCIE: Aw, babe, I feel
the same about you, honestly.
[laughs]
I've always felt hyperfeminine...
DAKOTA: Yeah.
- Just in the way that I am
and the way that I present myself.
One of the funny things
when I first came out
was that my mom
was really shocked because
I'd always been really girly.
DAKOTA: Yeah.
So she sort of said to me,
"But, you know,
there were no signs."
DAKOTA: Yeah.
- "I didn't get a clue."
Exhibit... yeah, no clue.
I mean, passing privilege
is a different conversation
in trans identities,
but in sexuality-wise,
if you don't fit those stereotypes,
then of course your parents
are in for a shock,
because all they've seen
is certain portrayals
of sexual identities on television.
Absolutely.
As someone that I think
really only does drag
because, you know, it was
an outlet for that femininity
that I wasn't allowed
to express as a child,
it's so interesting
hearing Lucie's perspective.
But I think, you know,
now as I've got older
and I'm sort of navigating my own
kind of lesbian identity...
- Yes.
Like, I really feel proud
to be quite femme-presenting.
- Yes.
- And I think that, you know,
there's so much more
representation now on telly.
You know, we haven't seen so many
different queer identities,
I think, on "Drag Race" before
in one room, and it is just
a pleasure to be part of that.
I'm happy I get to share this with you.
I'm just so, so excited
to wear that massive wig.
[laughs]
- Gemma.
- Yeah?
This is the quietest I think
I've heard you, love.
Are you feeling all right?
- Oh, I know.
Honestly, Cheddar's just
enjoying the process
and I'm just enjoying Cheddar
enjoying the process.
WENDY: We're enjoying
the peace, aren't we?
[laughter]
Everyone's really happy today
in the workroom.
I think they've all forgotten
that it's actually elimination day.
You wear falsies, don't you?
Oh, yeah.
I'm from Essex, darling.
[laughs]
Everybody's so good
in the contest right now.
It's anyone's guess
who might be sent home.
There's no chaff here, just chuff.
[RuPaul's "Cover Girl"]
RUPAUL: [laughs]
[singing]
Cover girl.
Put the bass in your walk.
Head to toe.
Let your whole body talk
[applause]
And what.
Welcome to the main stage
of "RuPaul's Drag Race UK."
Due to circumstances
beyond anyone's control,
RuPaul is unable to join us tonight,
but Mama Ru is watching
via a live video link.
So now, with Ru's blessing,
the show must go on.
Let's say hello to national
treasure Graham Norton.
Graham, have you ever done drag?
Done drag?
I mean, I've had sex with a
drag queen. Does that count?
Yeah, it does.
Then yes, I have.
Thought so.
Did it burn?
[cymbal crashes]
- [laughs]
And joining us on the panel
is "Drag Race" royalty, Raven.
Hi, Raven.
Hi, beautiful.
Now, have you ever done drag?
No, I prefer a more natural look.
[laughter]
- Me too.
And welcome the one, the only Boy George.
We are so excited that you are here.
I'm excited to be here.
"Drag Race" without me is ridiculous.
This week, we challenged our queens
to transform
the behind-the-scenes Queen Team
into Glamazons.
Racers, start your engines,
and may the best drag queen win.
RUPAUL: [singing]
Can you feel the love.
Category is drag family realness.
Up first, Jonbers Blonde and Nanu Noir.
Ooh.
[groans]
Black and white and mimed all over.
JONBERS: Olivia and I are giving
vaudevillian sisters from the '30s
in the silent movie era,
gorgina Hollywood starlets.
[laughter]
- Mime your business.
[laughs]
JONBERS:
Olivia's really enjoying this.
It's the most fun that I've
ever had in this runway.
We're clown mimes for God's sake.
[laughs]
MICHELLE: My kind of gal.
Girl, necklace.
Wink, wink.
[laughter]
JONBERS:
I'm so proud of Olivia.
The judges are loving it.
I'm serving Graham a pint of Guinness.
He's having a ball.
MICHELLE:
Zebra, I don't even know her.
Up next, Pixie Polite and Trixie Truelove.
GRAHAM: It's bring
your fairy to work day.
[laughs]
PIXIE: We are serving
fairy garden realness.
We flutter down the runway
like mother, like daughter,
shaking our tits and being camp as hell.
GRAHAM: I love it.
I'll take one in every size.
[laughter]
PIXIE: Trixie Truelove
is really doing me proud.
She is embodying the trademark
Pixie Polite silliness.
Bouquet, hon.
[laughter]
PIXIE:
We look really good together.
You know, she walked past me earlier,
and I thought I was looking in a mirror...
Maybe a mirror in a few years' time
but a mirror nonetheless.
MICHELLE:
Look at her Tinker-balls.
- Very good.
- [laughs]
PIXIE: She's always wanted
to be a fairy princess,
and today she is a fairy queen.
MICHELLE:
See you in the Toll House.
RUPAUL: [singing]
To a brighter day, a little bit.
MICHELLE: Danny Beard
and Mizzy Moustache.
Wait a minute.
I thought I was the only beard in here.
[laughter]
DANNY: For this week's
drag family resemblance runway,
we are serving pastel hairy princesses.
MICHELLE: Ann Jillian called.
She wants her hair back.
BOY GEORGE: That
hair color's beyond, though.
MICHELLE: Oh, it's gorg.
- Starved.
MICHELLE: Yeah.
- [laughs]
DANNY:
We look like bookends.
We look like family.
We have gone for feathers
and little, mini handbags
which say slappers on a night out.
Somebody's been fisting ostriches again.
GRAHAM: [laughs]
That's why they put
their head in the sand.
MICHELLE: [laughs]
DANNY:
Mystique's coming alive,
giving it beats.
Oh, she is looking and feeling gorgeous.
Mission accomplished.
MICHELLE: Not by the hair
of her chinny, chin, chin.
Cheddar Gorgeous and Brie Gorgeous.
GRAHAM:
Look at the cheese selection.
CHEDDAR: We are
an elemental mirror image
conveying a similar
yet slightly askew energy.
This mold, old thing?
No, old thing.
Not mold, old thing.
CHEDDAR:
We look phenomenal.
Whether they're wearing makeup or not,
this wonderful woman is
an energy and a force to be reckoned with.
Why don't you come up
and lactose me sometime?
GRAHAM: [laughs]
CHEDDAR: Brie is pulling out
all of the stops.
She's working that runway
and showing up her mother...
just as her mother requested.
RAVEN: Ham and cheese.
- Where's the wine?
MICHELLE:
There's no wine, Graham.
Up next, Black Peppa and Chilli Peppa.
These two are joined at the tip
but just the tip.
[laughs]
BLACK PEPPA: We are
serving you conjoined twins.
Just like an umbilical cord,
we are attached by our hair.
[pop]
MICHELLE: Oops.
GRAHAM: It's a girl.
- [laughs]
Gender reveal.
BLACK PEPPA: I am giving you
an amazing club-kid beat
with a beautiful moustache.
And you know what?
We look incredible.
Umbilical coordination.
These are members
of the plait Earth society.
[laughs]
BLACK PEPPA: Fleur is doing
incredible on the runway.
She is giving.
This bitch is walking in the heels
like she been walking in heels
every single day.
MICHELLE: Yeah.
GRAHAM: Oh, there you go.
That got in easy.
BLACK PEPPA:
I'm so happy.
I couldn't be more proud of her.
GRAHAM: Twinning is winning.
MICHELLE: Dakota Schiffer
and Brigitte Schiffer.
Well, aren't you peachy keen?
DAKOTA: We are serving
mother-daughter apricot realness
in our gorgeous peach duchess satin gowns.
And Lucie's giving you the more youthful
because she literally looks six
in what I put her in.
What a lovely bunch of apricots.
[laughs]
DAKOTA: I know that Lucie
feels beautiful.
I feel very proud
that I'm bringing home a triplet
to the Schiffer dynasty.
[laughs]
MICHELLE: The Schiffers
are doing it for whom?
Themselves.
GRAHAM: They're doing it
for peach other.
MICHELLE: [laughs]
Welcome, ladies.
Don't you all look stunning?
Now it's time for the judges' critiques.
Up first, Jonbers Blonde and Nanu Noir.
Now, this is Olivia before,
and look at her now.
Wow.
GRAHAM: I like this.
You did something elegant and simple.
You were obviously really having fun.
The problem I slightly have
is family resemblance.
There's more of a sense
of kind of gal pals,
possibly widow on the
formal night on a cruise...
[laughter]
Hoping to sit on the captain.
Black-and-white combination is
one of my absolute favorite things.
What I really loved was the presentation.
It was so well choreographed.
You both broke through the wall
at the same time.
And I think that, Jonbers,
your makeup looks amazing.
- Thank you.
- I love it.
- I love you two.
It's very, like, classic, like
an old black-and-white movie.
But I love the fact
that you have a bigger train.
You're like, "I'm having
the bigger train."
[laughter]
I'm gonna echo Raven here
and say you have come so far
with your makeup skills.
You look beautiful.
Your sister, her makeup is good.
It's struggling a little bit,
but I thought you did a really good job.
And it looks like
you blocked her eyebrows.
I did, yeah.
Yeah, you're a proper drag queen today.
Yeah, I wanted to give Olivia
the full experience,
so she's tucked too.
[laughter]
Good job.
Nanu, so you work here.
What was it like being on the
stage versus from the sideline?
- Yeah, terrifying.
- [laughs]
I was so nervous.
I was absolutely petrified.
But Jonbers calmed me from the get-go,
and I loved every second of it.
- Thank you, ladies.
- Thank you.
Up next, Pixie Polite and Trixie Truelove.
Now, this is Wendy before,
and look at her now.
[laughter]
- Trixie, I truly love you.
- [laughs]
You're just adorable.
I get the family resemblance.
You're just my favorite fairy,
and there's been a lot of them.
[laughs]
Yeah, and I thought the humor
really came across,
and that made me really happy
and made me smile.
It's gorgeous.
I totally enjoyed watching you both.
You looked like you were having fun.
The only thing is padding.
Her hips, they do not lie.
[laughter]
I would say maybe two more pairs of tights
just to kind of cover them up.
- Okay.
Pixie, I thought that your relationship
was abundantly clear.
And I think the makeup on you
is so pretty,
and I think you did your sister
just a little dirty there.
Pixie, what was it like for you
working with Trixie?
These lovely ladies really
have become, like, very close to us
just because of how much
they look after us.
And the outfits
were obviously fairy inspired,
but they were also inspired
by a particular flower that used
to grow in my nana's ga... sorry, hmm.
Hmm. Come on.
That used to grow in my nana's garden.
And when I was growing up... sorry.
I don't know why I'm so emotional.
She's no longer with us,
but she was a very huge part of my life
for me as a young gay person.
And going over to her house
and being in her garden,
surrounded by all her gorgeous flowers,
it felt like I was escaping
to my own little fairy world
where I could sort of...
Be who I needed to be.
Sorry.
There's a lot of kids out there watching
who could relate to that story,
to have the ability that you had a Nana...
- Yeah.
- That let you be
and encouraged you to be who you are.
And I was really glad to be
able to share it with Wendy...
MICHELLE: Aw.
Who's been my little mummy
while I've been here.
Trixie, what was
this experience like for you?
Well, I never thought I'd get to 60
and end up being on a stage doing this.
I think I look older with drag
than I do without.
[laughter]
PIXIE: Oh, we know.
We've got you in a bit of a purple rinse.
I know. The purple rinse,
I think, is what's doing it.
Mm.
Until you actually have it done yourself,
you don't realize
how much work goes into it.
It was amazing.
- Thank you.
Up next, Danny Beard and Mizzy Moustache.
Now, this is Mystique before,
and look at her now!
[laughter]
Wow.
This is so beautiful...
The color palette, the style of it.
Lovely family resemblance.
Congratulations.
There was a time when, you know, the idea
of having a beard
would've just been unthinkable,
but I love your look.
It's so drag remix.
It's breaking all the rules.
I love it.
I love the whole, like, '60s vibe.
The makeup looks great,
that Danny Beard hard-carved cheek.
It's great.
I love all of it.
Thank you.
Quintessentially Danny Beard.
All the details are tended to here,
but it's also fashion,
and that's what it's about at this point.
So I thought it was really, really fun.
Do you feel beautiful, my love?
I do.
I feel amazing.
I was apprehensive about
the beard and the moustache.
Said, "Wait till you've done
all the makeup."
Of course, it all made sense.
He wanted me to have
a good experience as well.
- And did you?
- Yeah.
Well done, babe.
I'm just so proud that she feels great,
'cause I know she was worried
that I was gonna make her look silly.
Yeah.
And I wanted her to have a good time.
I wanted her to come out here
and feel the power that drag gives you.
'Cause although I am gobby,
I wasn't always like that.
And I found that power through drag,
so she's got the power.
[singing] I got the power.
- Yes.
- Thank you guys.
MICHELLE: Love that.
- So lovely.
Thank you so much.
Up next, Cheddar Gorgeous
and Brie Gorgeous.
This is Gemma before,
and wow, look at her now.
[bell dings]
- Cheddar and Brie,
when you came round the corner,
it was just fabulous.
You had that story line
of kind of, you know,
you'd unleashed this terror on the world.
You have stage presence,
and you clearly like it.
[laughter]
So I think...
overall, great job.
- Are you cinched?
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah.
- Very.
My organs are out of place, yeah.
- As they should be.
- Yeah.
I say leave them
in the workroom next time.
[laughter]
Don't even bring them with you.
It's beautiful.
- [mouthing words]
It's so Blitz Club 1979.
Your look is on fire.
Very Michele Clapton.
She went on to design
for "Game of Thrones,"
and she would worship this look.
Royalty from the planet Gorgeous.
The autumn colors.
I almost get a sky in Brie's,
and I get, like, the sunset in yours.
It just all makes sense,
and it's just rich.
Brie, what did you learn from Cheddar?
Watching Cheddar just work
has just been incredible.
It was so special to be able
to put these amazing women
up onstage.
- Aw.
'Cause you are wonderful.
All of you are wonderful.
You're all right too.
[laughter]
I've created a monster, haven't I?
There we go.
- Thank you, ladies.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Good job.
Up next, Black Peppa and Chilli Peppa.
This is Fleur before,
and look at Fleur now.
I love this concept.
I think it's really clever and fun.
But just from the next down,
I sort of wished
there'd been just another detail,
just something else going on.
Graham's right in the sense
that there's this amazing top,
and then it's almost like the
bottom half, you've forgotten about.
More is always a good option.
I think that the makeup job you did,
Black Peppa, is beautiful.
Black Peppa, Chilli Peppa,
it's your girl White Salt.
Hey, girl.
[laughter]
I love the armor-ness of this dress.
It's got details on it.
The problem is, they're hard to see.
It just needed to pop against
all the other things, that's all.
Black Peppa, what was your
favorite part of this challenge?
Working with Fleur.
I was just like,
couldn't have been a better
match made in heaven.
And then the links of the hair.
I don't really get along with my family,
and when I connect... disconnected it...
[sighs]
It was me coming to UK,
but no matter how far I am,
they will always be with me.
MICHELLE: So you disconnected,
and you reconnected
with your new chosen family.
The family that I've made here,
I am so thankful for them.
MICHELLE: Feel the love, baby.
You are loved, and you are welcome.
Up next, Dakota Schiffer
and Brigitte Schiffer.
This is Lucie before,
and this is her now.
You did the brief.
It's a makeover, and there's
a family resemblance there.
I'm not sure
about the checkered flag thing
and quite how that fits into it.
- Dakota, I'm gonna say bravo.
- Thank you.
And looking at Brigitte's makeup,
I see that very graphic
1960s total vibe on her face.
I love it.
Reminds me
of "Ready, Steady, Go!"
You know, bride of Elvis.
So beautiful.
- Thank you.
- I love the peach.
I think my issue is, Dakota,
I'm gonna push you again.
You are beautiful.
[mouthing words]
MICHELLE: You are talented,
but you could also do more
than you're giving me.
Yeah. Okay.
MICHELLE: I know you can.
Because I feel like every time,
it's the same silhouette.
You're dreamy.
- [laughs]
I just want more.
Could you blame me?
Yeah.
[laughs]
No, I can't blame you, Michelle.
MICHELLE: Exactly.
Brigitte.
- Hi.
How was this process for you, my darling?
I was really nervous beforehand,
but my nerves kind of melted away
as soon as I was paired
with Dakota, really,
'cause she's incred.
Thank you.
So just go.
Thank you, queens.
I think we've heard enough.
And to our incredible Queen Team,
for your extraordinary efforts
this week and every week,
we are awarding each of you
a coveted Ru Peter badge.
- Yay!
CHOIR: [singing] Rule, Britannia
[bell dings]
MICHELLE: Wear it with pride.
While you untuck in the workroom,
the judges and I will deliberate.
You may leave the stage.
PIXIE: Thank you all.
MYSTIQUE: Thank you.
[mouths word]
- Whoo!
- Oh, my God.
Drink.
It's like the early days
when this room was full.
We are back and untucked,
and I feel amazing.
- I can't move.
- Welcome to our world.
Welcome to our world.
- [laughs]
There's very few things that
I feel really comfortable doing,
but making somebody over?
I'm good with it.
I love it.
I think everyone deserves
a round of applause.
- Yeah.
- Yes. Cheers, everyone.
- Cheers.
- To the Queen Team.
What a debut.
I don't know what the hell's
going on tonight.
It's so mixed.
Mine, they said they didn't get
family resemblance,
but what I don't understand is,
there's other people up there
that have the same color, like,
same color palette but in different ways.
It's kind of what I've done.
I had the same sort of makeup
sort of every time.
I'm really inspired by old Hollywood.
Looks a bit more like
Paul Hollywood, though, love.
[laughter]
Says "Fraggle Rock" over here.
Ooh.
[laughter]
Well, the thing I'd say about that is,
I don't know what this outfit
or look says about you.
I can see from lot of the
others, like, what their drag is.
There is no specific one look for me
because I change my look
every single time I do drag.
We all change our looks all the time...
No, I know, but I didn't want...
But I feel like a lot of us have something
in our look that is still very us.
I agree with the judges.
I didn't understand...
Why they were dressed like mimes,
and I didn't see
that they were related at all.
Like you, I do different looks
all of the time,
and each runway I've done,
like, something different,
but there are things that I know
that people find as being my signature.
Cheddar, if you think that gold leaf
is what makes your drag,
that's lovely to think that, darling.
But don't come for my drag.
I'm not here to be judged by other queens.
I'm here to be judged by the judges.
This, you can tell this is a Cheddar look.
You can tell this is a Danny look.
No offense.
[laughter]
[slurps]
I think that was kind of, like,
the opposite of my critique.
I think I was so concerned
in the first week
that they hadn't got my aesthetic
that every single week,
I kind of up until now
have been like,
"'Valley of the Dolls, ' '60s.
Like, please get it."
And now they're like,
"We get it.
Jesus, Dakota, like"...
[laughter]
LUCIE: I love being
Schiffer-ized.
- [laughs]
- Honestly, every single thing
about your aesthetic, I appreciate.
But you've actually made me live
my blonde, freckled fantasy...
- Yes.
Which I've always wanted to do,
so thank you.
DAKOTA:
There's definitely a chance
I could be in the bottom,
and it would be so crushing
to go home now, but I'm just
so proud of the work we did,
and I'm just so proud of Lucie.
- Pixie, babe, how are you feeling?
- I feel okay.
I mean, if I'm in the bottom,
it is what it is.
- Yeah.
- I'm happy.
I've given Wendy her fairy fantasy
that she's always wanted.
Oh, Wendy's face. Honey.
It's so funny.
Wendy was like,
"I love fairies."
And Pixie said, "Yeah, I'm gonna drag you
through the mud, girl."
She did Wendy so bad.
[laughs]
I think I could very possibly
be lip-synching still, like...
- It could be any of us, so...
- You know.
Well, I don't think it's you,
Cheddar, and I don't think it's Danny.
You've got the best.
You know, if it comes to it,
you know, we'll spread a little bit
of pixie dust on that stage
and one of you is going home.
This has been my most favorite week
since I've been here.
- Yeah, I've loved it.
- Absolutely.
- Oh, yeah.
It means the world, honestly.
You've just been our family
since we've been here.
- Well done, everyone.
- Here's to everyone.
- To the Queen Team!
Can I take the wig off?
[laughter]
All right, now,
just between us girlfriends,
what do you think,
starting with Jonbers Blonde?
It was perfectly pleasant,
but it didn't make the impact
that a lot of the other couples
made tonight.
They didn't push it enough.
They were sisters
from other misters, whatever.
But she gave them both very chic looks.
I don't think it was that bad.
I like that they had fun,
they had choreography,
they had a thing on the stage,
but family resemblance,
it has to be obvious.
The black and white was
not enough to tie it together.
Up next, Pixie Polite.
I like Pixie.
They were adorable together.
The outfits were a bit panto.
Beautiful, lovely,
but rough around the edges.
I mean, those pads,
they were like lumpy mashed potatoes.
I do think she looked beautiful tonight.
However, Trixie looked like pow, pow, pow.
She took her out.
The best thing ever is hearing someone say
their makeup makes them look older.
[laughter]
- I know.
You don't ever want to hear
one of our guests say
they feel like they look older in drag.
Thanks.
[laughter]
MICHELLE: Okay, up next,
Danny Beard.
I thought it was really
elevated, fashion, stylish.
There was a great family resemblance.
I love Danny Beard's take on drag
because it is this hyper-feminized shape,
and there's a beard.
I mean, imagine the first time
you ever get to be in drag,
you've got to wear a beard.
- [laughs]
BOY GEORGE:
Yeah, I loved it,
laughing in the face of kind of
traditional kind of drag.
Oh, my goodness.
I loved everything about this look...
The different color beards, hair, purses.
I thought it was a strong night
for Danny Beard.
Up next, Cheddar Gorgeous.
This was out of this world.
I mean, literally.
They were like a kind of
constellation or something.
It was really beautiful.
The metallic-ness of the makeup
with the leafing... just those
little, subtle details
that are something that I love.
I thought it was just beautiful.
Like, it was... they were oozing
on the stage together,
and they just looked symbiotic.
It was a home run.
Up next, Black Peppa.
I have to admit,
I was slightly disappointed.
And I guess we've come to expect
such wonderful outfits
from Black Peppa that in this challenge,
for it to suddenly to be, essentially,
a little black dress
seemed kind of underwhelming.
I love what she did from the neck up.
We all know about those
evenings when you've spent so long
on the face, you know,
you forgot what you're wearing.
It did kind of look like
she ripped the head off
of one Barbie
and then stuck it on another...
[laughter]
And was like,
"Okay, we're going
onto the main stage."
I think that hair and
that story was so powerful
but also agree with Graham.
At this point in the competition,
not quite enough.
Up next, Dakota Schiffer.
Checkered tights and gloves with peach.
I love mixing things up
and making it go kind of,
"Oh, wow, I would've never
thought of that."
But I literally would have never
thought of this.
[laughter]
Dakota likes to do a very beautiful makeup
that is suitable for going
to a nice dinner.
[laughs]
I still feel like she could
take it a little further.
Not the best night for Dakota,
but I thought a wonderful night
for Brigitte.
I love that Lucie got to do this.
I love that she felt so fabulous
and looked so fabulous.
I think what upsets me
is that we saw this look.
She just did "Funny Girl."
I'm not trying to change
the way she does drag.
Give us something different,
because predictability
is not a good word here on the main stage
of "RuPaul's Drag Race,"
and that's where we are
with Dakota right now.
All right, silence.
I have not made my decision.
I need to call RuPaul.
Welcome back, ladies.
Oh, no.
But nobody can go, honestly.
Pixie Polite,
your garden fairies were beautiful,
but some of the details
got a little muddy.
I'm sorry, my dear,
but you are up for elimination.
- [gasps]
- Wow.
- No. Wendy.
- My God.
Danny Beard,
you and your sister were groovy, baby.
Cheddar Gorgeous,
you and your sister
were out of this world.
Cheddar Gorgeous, condragulations,
you are the winner
of this week's challenge.
[all cheering]
- Oh, Gemma.
Babe.
You've earned a coveted Ru Peter badge.
[mouthing words]
CHOIR: [singing] Rule, Britannia.
I would offer to give it
to the Queen Team,
but you already gave them one,
so I guess I'll just keep it.
Danny Beard, you are safe.
Thank you, judges.
Ladies, you may step
to the back of the stage.
Black Peppa...
you're safe.
You may join the other girls.
Thank you so much.
Oh, my God.
[sighs]
Jonbers Blonde,
your fashion game was spot-on,
but your family resemblance
was a little off.
Dakota Schiffer,
you and your sister were fabu...
But your makeup and hair
were a little dj vu.
Dakota Schiffer,
I'm sorry, my dear,
but you are up for elimination.
DAKOTA: This is the third
lip sync I've been in,
but, you know, I am still fighting,
and I really don't want to go home.
Oh, hey.
Luce, don't cry.
Jonbers, you're safe.
Thank you so much.
You may join the other girls.
Two queens stand before me.
Prior to tonight,
you were asked to prepare
a lip sync performance
of "Miss Me Blind" by Culture Club.
[clicks tongue]
Ladies, this is
your last chance to impress us
and save yourself from elimination.
The time has come...
[thunder booming]
For you to lip-synch
for your life.
PIXIE:
I love Dakota like a daughter,
but sometimes you've
just got to leave that baby
on the step of the church.
Good luck.
And, Boy George...
Don't fuck it up.
CULTURE CLUB: [singing]
Miss me
I know you'll miss me
I know you'll miss me blind
I know you'll miss me blind.
Bet you got a good gun.
Bet you know how.
To have some fun and then.
You turn it around on me because
I'm better than the rest of the men
I say you'll miss me.
And you always do
Now, would I lie to you.
Now, there's no need to demand.
Grab my golden hand
I'll teach you and you'll never be sure.
If the way that you need.
Is too much like greed.
Decide if you are rich or you're poor.
Because the love that I have to give.
Must be better than that kind.
It can make you rich.
It can make you poor.
But I know that you'll miss me blind
I know you'll miss me
I know you'll miss me.
- Come on, Dakota.
CULTURE CLUB: [singing]
I know you'll miss me blind
I know you'll miss me
[cheers and applause]
- Amazing.
- No one go home.
Let's talk to Ru.
Ladies, Ru has made her decision.
[dramatic music]
Pixie Polite,
shantay, you stay.
PIXIE: [crying]
- You may join the other girls.
- Thank you.
PIXIE:
You're a superstar, okay?
Dakota Schiffer, you fabulous woman, you.
You put the super in supermodel.
Now, sashay away.
Thank you for the most
incredible experience
and letting me finally
have confidence in myself.
[sniffles]
Thank you.
MICHELLE: Aw.
DAKOTA: [crying]
You're amazing.
[crying]
JONBERS: [crying]
The doll has to leave the valley.
[laughter]
[cheers and applause]
Wait. I've got an idea.
[laughs]
To go out on this moment, like,
it's impossible to be sad.
[groans]
I'm so proud of myself.
I've done things I've never thought
I'd be able to do here.
I was the first trans woman
on "Drag Race UK."
To be that representation
has just been an honor
to represent my community.
- Dakota.
- Thank you so much.
Oh, thank you.
- I've had the best time.
- Oh, I'm so proud of you.
Thank you.
You are such an incredible queen,
such an incredible woman.
The world is not ready
for Dakota Schiffer.
[laughs] But I have a new sister.
Absolutely.
I will really miss you, babe.
- Thank you.
You're amazing.
MICHELLE:
Condragulations, queens.
In the words of Mama Ru,
if you can't love yourself,
how the hell are you
gonna love somebody else?
Can I get an amen up in hurr?
ALL: Amen.
Yes. Now, let the music play.
RUPAUL: [singing]
To, to, to, to the moon.
To the moon.
- Gonna take me away.
To, to, to, to the moon.
To the moon, to the moon.
Hello, hello, hello.
Next time on "RuPaul's Drag Race UK"...
[laughs]
- She's back.
You'll be acting in a murder mystery
with a modern twist.
The Squirrel Games.
- Action.
Oh, I'm gonna shove this
where the sun don't shine, my dear.
Oh!
I've got a bit of Tess Daly,
a bit of Cilla.
- Are you a high-vis amoeba?
- [laughs]
Are you a neon scourer?
Not coming for you, though.
It felt a very pointed comment.
They're all a bunch of snakes.