Jesus! He's got my purse!
Stop him!
Hey, you! Come back here!
Yo.
Come on.
You got it all?
Everything.
Damn.
We're rich.
You hear that? We're rich, man.
Ma?
I'm with a friend.
You certainly are.
I gotta take care of some business.
I gotta see my stockbroker.
Okay. Let's go. Come on.
Out with Paco.
You're going to bed right now!
That's where you're going.
No.
Yo, listen to her, all right?
I'll take you out tomorrow, okay?
All right.
Honey, can you turn it down a little?
Paco, your old man.
Look, I don't want a job. I want a business.
We deliver Saturday night, 9:00.
Parking lot around the corner
from the Marshall theater.
All you guys gotta do is...
Paco!
Put it down!
What the fuck is wrong with you, man?
Why you fucking with me?
Let me tell you something.
You pull any shit like this Saturday night,
I swear to God...
Look, man, I'm not playing with you.
You hear me?
Get the fuck out of here!
Barn!
Hey, J.C.
Carl.
I've never seen so much shit in my life.
They got a fucking drugstore.
How're you doing, J.C.?
What do you see in this guy, huh?
Fuck off, Moreno.
Your old lady's got a bad mouth.
If she was my old lady...
- She's not, asshole.
- Oh, wow.
You mean she didn't tell you
about me and her, huh?
Don't listen to that stupid...
Adios, douche bag.
Hey, wake up.
- I gotta get up. I gotta go.
- No.
Your old man will be back soon. I gotta go.
Mick.
Remember Tony Contreras?
- Who?
- The guy with the bike.
He got killed ripping off some house
in Park Ridge last week.
That guy?
That's the way it goes.
I had this dream that you went away.
SO did I.
With you.
I went over to your house looking for you.
Your mother opened the door.
She didn't say anything, so I went inside.
And there you were,
lying in this coffin in a red suit.
I don't have a red suit.
You have the strangest dreams.
What were you and Brennan talking about?
Carl? Nothing.
Nothing!
Someday
you're gonna get busted for real.
So what? They don't do shit.
You know what they do?
They take you down there
and they give you lunch.
Then, they're gonna call my old lady.
They're not gonna find her.
Send me home for her supper,
which isn't as good as their lunch.
It's a joke.
I don't want you to die.
Nothing's gonna happen to me.
I love you.
Don't dream.
Are you sure they won't know who we are?
Not if you do what I say.
You keep your fucking mouth shut,
they won't know shit.
Jesus.
Don't be such a pussy.
We're gonna be in and out of there so fast...
You're not gonna have to use that.
Like that.
What are you doing in here?
You promised me I can go out with you.
Yeah. Not tonight.
We got something to do, it's very important.
I don't want you in the way.
I'll take you to a movie.
Tomorrow, we'll go out, we'll hang out.
All right? Right now, you go home.
But you promised.
Man, don't play with me.
I'm not playing with you. Stop it.
Go home. Get out of here.
Just make sure them guns are ready,
all right?
Believe me, they're going to be ready.
Check this out, man.
Bad motherfucker.
There's Moreno's kid brother.
Relax, Carl. It's gonna be all right.
Okay.
There they are.
Let's go.
Rough neighborhood.
Slow down, slow down.
I'm slowing down.
There's the boys. Right there.
Party time now.
Okay, over here. Carl, over here.
Okay, okay.
Okay.
- Shit. What's with the dude?
- Hey, man. He got a gun.
- Get his ass, man. Get him.
- Go.
Mick, look out!
Hold up, man.
We got to move.
Let's go!
Let's go! Let's go!
Carl! Carl!
We heard shots.
Fuck!
Don't move, in there!
Michael O'Brien,
you have committed the crimes of an adult.
Your previous record of arrests is extensive
and indicates a sociopathic personality.
However; you are protected by the law.
Your status as a juvenile prevents me
from imposing the punishment you deserve.
And until our criminal codes
are revised to incorporate
a more realistic definition
of juvenile offenders,
society will continue to suffer
It is the judgment of this court
that you be committed to
Rainford Juvenile Correctional Facility
until such a time
as your rehabilitation is complete.
Terrell, O'Brien, let's go.
Welcome to Rainford, gentlemen.
My name is Gene Daniels.
I'm one of your supervisors.
Call me Mr. Daniels. I like that.
Don't call me anything else.
You've been assigned to Dorm C.
That's our special circumstances dormitory
for critical offenders.
Your fellow inmates are murderers,
armed robbers, rapists,
and mental defectives.
Just like yourselves,
they've graduated top of the class.
You will be treated with respect
if you treat others with respect.
I suggest you stay cool
and follow all the rules.
Your crime is not that you got caught,
but the crime itself.
Remember that.
Hopefully, you will realize
that what you did was wrong.
Hopefully, you will never do
anything like that again.
This is a juvenile facility.
That means you are not
in charge of the zoo, we are.
If you think you're hip, you're not.
If you were, you wouldn't be here.
Have I made myself understood?
"Yes, Mr. Daniels."
- Yes, Mr. Daniels.
That's better.
Let's go, gentlemen.
Wagner.
YMCA time!
Hey, check them out!
- Over here!
- Hey, beautiful.
Little one's cute.
O'Brien. Hey.
All right. This is Supervisor Wagner.
"Sir" will also do.
O'Brien. Terrell.
Gentlemen, enjoy your rehabilitation.
Hey, the man is over here.
You boys read?
Read this.
Gang activity, 1,000 points.
Sexual harassment, 1 ,200.
Fighting, 700. Drugs and/or alcohol, 1,500.
Running for the fence, 2,000. Smoking, 400.
Okay, Terrell, you take room number 35
up on top,
and, O'Brien,
you take room number 14 on the bottom.
Come on, let's go!
Hey, check it out. It's Batman and Robin.
I want the little dude.
So, how do you like it so far?
You got a name?
Can you talk?
Smoke?
My name is Horowitz.
You don't feel like talking
right now, that's okay.
I understand.
But you understand I really don't
want a fucking mute in my cell.
'Cause I like a little conversation
sometimes, okay?
Last guy that was in here with me
killed himself
by drinking a half a gallon of disinfectant,
he liked the place so much.
My name is O'Brien.
Shit. A fucking mick.
No!
No.
So, what's the toke?
An accident.
Yeah, me, too.
I firebombed the bowling alley,
killed three people.
I was goofing around with some girls.
Their boyfriends didn't like it too much,
beat the shit out of me.
Came back the next night, totaled the place.
Only thing was,
I wasted the wrong three people.
Well, time to get counted.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Get in line, asshole.
- Just get in line. Get in line.
- That's Lofgren.
They can him "Viking."
I Call him "Shit-for-brains."
Shut your fucking mouth, Horowitz.
Come on, get in line. Let's go, let's go.
Come on, wake up, wake up.
- Get in line, get in line.
- Get in line, man.
Get in line, get in line. Come on.
Get in line, man.
You, too, man. Move! Get in line!
Come on, move it, move it.
Let's get in line. You, too.
That's Tweety.
Nice name.
They're smacks.
They keep the rest of the animals in line
and give out the work assignments.
They're gonna put you on shithouse patrol.
All accounted for, Mr. Daniels.
All right, that's five minutes to first bell.
Five minutes.
What happened to your face?
Hey, fuckhead!
What's it to you?
I asked you a question.
I cut myself shaving.
I got news for you, fuckhead.
In here, me and him,
we're it.
You're on shithouse patrol
until we say different. You got it?
Clean it up.
Smokes?
Winstone, Pall Malls, Salems.
Salems.
Ten bucks.
I don't have it.
Take it or leave it.
Perretti, you want your radio fixed?
Give him the smokes.
Horowitz, you suck!
Only your mother, Perretti.
Grass? You need some grass, I got it.
Don't buy it. It's shit.
Horowitz, you better have it ready by Friday.
Or your ass is grass.
Don't worry about it.
The chink killed his father.
The whop snatched a 14-year-old girl
and raped her for two days straight
in a basement.
They run the action for the Viking
and Tweety on a 60-40 split.
Real cuties.
Ain't he sweet.
All right, guys, loosen up a little bit.
How you doing?
Not too good.
They're gonna get me, Mick. I know it.
I'll be right back.
I wrote Mick today.
Started at least 10 times.
You know, "How are you?
What's it like there?"
That kind of thing.
Everything sounded so dumb.
Honey, listen to me.
He's a bad kid.
He's been in and out of trouble for years.
Now, he's finally gone and killed someone.
No.
It was an accident.
I see you're responsible
for the death of an eight-year-old boy.
It was an accident.
An accident.
How about these other charges?
"Driving a stolen vehicle,
assault with a deadly weapon,
"attempted robbery."
I suppose they were accidents, too.
Possession of a handgun
and assaulting a teacher at 12.
Four counts of vandalism,
three counts of breaking and entering at 13.
Assaulting a 70-year-old woman
during a purse snatching at 14.
You're a real class act.
You want me to go on?
How you never did any time here before
is a miracle.
And now you're telling me
what just happened was an accident?
Hey, boy,
let me tell you something.
That was no accident.
You would've killed somebody
sooner or later.
Only it happened sooner, you see?
So, don't bullshit yourself.
Don't bullshit me.
How do you feel about what went down?
About the so-called accident?
I'd like an answer.
I don't have one.
Well, when you do have an answer,
let me know.
Because I'm interested.
Anytime you wanna talk about this,
or anything else,
I'm here.
Thank you, Eddie.
Gerard!
- Holden!
- Right here.
Jones! Is there anybody here
by the name of Jones?
Perretti!
Johnson!
- O'Brien!
- Yeah.
Fucking miracle
someone you know can write.
Jones!
Turn around.
Come on, man. Come on.
Hey, Paco, that's him.
That's the one.
That's the guy.
Hey, what was that?
Someone wasted Willy, man!
Get the license plate, man.
Get the license plate!
Somebody call an ambulance.
Man, that's a lot of blood.
Man, he's bleeding bad, man.
He's bleeding bad!
Jimmy, come here!
Oh, man! Guess he's dead.
What do you want?
Just get the fuck out of here!
Leave me alone!
Come on! Please, man!
How was it?
- Fucking asshole!
- Tweety! Tweety, he's got a knife!
Get out of the way! Get out of the way!
- He's dead.
- He's dead?
Let's get out of here.
Let's go, come on. Come on, let's go.
One way or the other,
I'm going to get to the bottom of this.
You're on cooking detail all day.
I'm gonna check with Axelrod.
If you're lying to me,
I'm gonna deep-fry your ass.
Tell me exactly what happened
when you ran out on the tier. Exactly.
I just turned and
I saw a bunch of people out on the rail.
Who were the people next to you?
So, you're telling me that
you don't remember if you saw anything?
Buy you... You were there, right?
Get out of here. Just get out of here.
Now, turn the chair around and sit down
and talk to me.
Now, where were you?
I was in my room sleeping, like I told you.
No, you weren't.
- And that's all you can tell me?
- That's all.
All right.
You're up.
I know, Lofgren, I know.
You're incurably innocent.
Yeah.
Okay.
O'Brien, if you saw anything
that might help clear this up,
it might knock some time off your sentence.
I can't help you, sir.
- That's it?
- Yeah, sir.
There are these three girls standing outside
the bowling alley, right?
I figure I'd give it a shot.
I walk over, I start talking to them.
Take off.
What'd you say to him?
Not much.
When I ask you a question, you answer.
You dig, motherfucker?
- Go fuck yourself.
- I'm gonna fuck you up.
Hey, you got a problem?
Gentlemen, there's seconds
for those of you who want it.
Now, let's try to be dignified.
Mr. Wagner, here's the mop.
- What are you doing?
- It's okay. Get out of here.
- Look, man, if there's gonna be trouble...
- it's okay.
Hey, sou m bag.
Oh, shit.
Fight, fight, fight, fight!
Come on!
Let's go!
Hi, J.C.
Hey.
- You feel it?
- What?
You're it.
What are you talking about?
You're the new barn boss, O'Brien.
Says who?
Hey, it is what it is.
Fuck that.
What are you afraid of?
I ain't afraid of anything.
I just don't want to be it.
Hey, after what you did to
Viking and Tweety, man, you're it.
Hey, schmuck.
- What?
- Think of it as a present.
Some present.
Barn boss gets 40 % of the cigarette action.
You forgot.
Barn boss gets to give out
the work assignments and take his own.
Barn boss gets time off his sentence
if he stays cool
and keeps the Neanderthals in line.
You didn't know that, did you?
Think you can handle it?
And as your lieutenant,
I get some privileges, too.
Banzai!
Every week,
two cartons for me
and two for Horowitz.
Free.
There's something else.
You know how it used to be a 60-40 split?
Well, it Still is.
Only now, it's 60-40.
Get out of here.
Hey, man.
You're something else, O'Brien.
- Mick.
- You're it, man.
- Excuse me. Make way for the man.
- You're it now.
Go ahead, O'Brien.
What is that shit?
"Poise and control."
Oh, God.
- Shut up.
- Shoot.
- You don't know nothing.
Be cool.
Perretti, read the sentence to the class.
"The domi...
"The dom... Dominant..."
- The dumb what?
- "The dominant..."
- The dumb ass.
- "Primordial..."
- "The dominant..."
- Yeah, thank you. Thank you. Lofgren.
- Oh.
- "Dominant..."
- "Primer... Primer..."
- What?
- "Primer..."
- All right. O'Brien.
You try.
- Come on, Mick.
- "The dominant prim..."
- You don't know...
- "Primer..."
Johnson. Read it.
Hey, look, this is nothing to laugh at.
Now, maybe if some of you could read,
you wouldn't be in here.
You ever think about that?
Look, you think of yourself as a moron,
you can't feel that good about yourself,
now, can you?
I just got back the results of that
literacy test you took, that reading test.
You should be in the third grade.
All right. Yay.
Well, I got my own reading test for you.
I want you to read the comic book
I'm gonna give you
and write a report on it.
- Shit.
- Oh, man.
All right. I want you to write about
the characters and the storyline.
All right? Keep it simple.
What "line"?
Spelling, punctuation, they count.
Let's get started.
It's gotta be done this period.
Sir, I don't think Lofgren can handle this.
- It's a little too advanced for him.
- Shut up.
All right.
I'm not telling you again.
He has a mouth.
Well, let's go. Get to work.
More, Jew boy.
That's a good little kike.
Hurry up.
What?
What? Armstrong? Armstrong? Armstrong?
Can I have your spoon?
Mighty Mouse.
Horowitz!
Get off me! Move!
Get off me! Get out of the way!
Don't put... Don't put me inside there, man!
You can't put me in there! I hate solitary.
Man, don't put me in there alone!
I hate being alone!
Let me go. Let me go, you fucking asshole.
Let me go, man.
Don't put me in solitary. Fuck you.
Don't put me in solitary, man. Let me go.
Let me go. Don't put me in there, man.
That's it.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Don't do it! Get away from the door, man!
Can't someone... Hey, let me out.
You watch it, all right?
You can make all the noise you want now.
Let me out of here, you fucking asshole.
You can't keep me in here! Let me out!
Let's go.
Man, are you crazy?
Paco.
Let's go.
Hey, man, she saw your face.
I know.
Paco.
Do it.
Hey. Get over here.
Hold it right there, buddy.
We need your cooperation, J.C.
I know what you're going through.
Believe me.
But if you don't press charges,
this guy's gonna walk out of here.
Don't let that animal get away with this.
I wanna talk with Mick.
I don't get this shit.
Maybe you got some kind of
reading disability.
- Like what?
- Like you can't read.
O'Brien.
Bye.
She'll be all right.
What's going on inside you right now?
What do you feel?
I just feel like crying.
That's okay.
CW-
I've seen people cry before.
You're number one, number two,
number three, number four, number five.
Remember your numbers. Lieutenant.
Okay, number one. Turn around. Face me.
What's your name?
- Theodore Aparecia.
- Where do you live?
- 1872, South Racine.
- How old are you?
- Seventeen.
- Turn around. Face the wall.
Number two, turn around and face me.
- What's your name?
- Richard DeLeon.
- Where do you live?
- 2166, South Morgan.
- How old are you?
- Eighteen.
Okay. Turn around and face the wall.
Number three, turn around and face me.
- What's your name?
- Paco Moreno.
That's him.
Never mind, miss. Hold on.
What's your address?
- That's him.
- 2395, Grand Avenue.
- How old are you?
- That's the one that raped me.
Okay, turn around and face the wall.
I'm sorry about J.C.
I really mean that.
I gotta see her.
They're not gonna let you
out of here, O'Brien.
Well, I'm not asking.
You want some company?
That's one. Stay, stay, stay.
- Throw it, dawg.
- Throw it, throw it.
We go straight through, right here.
We'll make it.
How do we get through this?
Leave it to Beaver.
I'm out of here next week.
Let's hope I don't see you again,
'cause if I do...
- I'll break your face all over again.
- We can start right now, chump.
What's the problem?
- No problem.
Hey, Tweety.
Yeah. Tweety!
- Hey.
- What it is.
Get him in here.
- You're right.
- Come over here, brother.
Yo, what's up, man?
Yeah. Come on. Let's go.
Hey! Come on, let's go.
Keep moving. Let's go.
- What's the matter? You hurt?
- I twisted my ankle.
You're not hurt, Horowitz, come on.
Move on. Keep going.
- All right, all right, let's go.
- Hey, watch deep right.
- Throw the ball.
- Get out of the way, man.
Go, go, go, go!
- You ready?
- Yeah.
Back of the line.
- Don't dance.
- All right, give it back, baby.
Oh, man. Hey, wait. Now, get over here!
Call signal six.
Hey, get this shit off me!
Oh, fuck!
Wagner! Come on, man.
I hear them over here.
Go.
Go!
Oh, shit.
I can't get this off me.
Stupid shit!
Fuck you, pig.
- Hey! Hey, hey!
- Wagner, man!
Wagner! Wagner!
Wait! Leave the kid alone, man!
What's wrong with you?
O'Brien is gone, man. You let him get away!
Mick.
No.
One minute, one minute.
O'Brien.
Let's go, man.
Come on, come on, come on.
Open up, 407!
Open up, 222!
Open up, 217!
This is it, man. The bigs.
Major league.
Nice, huh?
Fuck up again,
this is where you're gonna end up.
Like I said, life's a choice, right?
It's up to you.
Open up, 344!
Under ordinary circumstances, O'Brien,
I'd add six months to your time.
But just this once,
I'm gonna give you another chance.
Consider yourself lucky. Frank!
Just remember, you're supposed to be
some kind of an example here.
Don't make a fool out of me, O'Brien.
You look terrible.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Did you see J.C.?
Yeah.
John, take this. Get that.
Yo, O'Brien!
I gotta talk to you.
Okay, here it comes.
Paco Moreno is here.
He's being processed right now
and he'll be coming into C-block.
I don't have to tell you,
we're not exactly thrilled about this,
but we had a logjam in admissions,
and that's the way it is.
Now, I suggest you stay cool.
Because if you fuck up,
the only person you'll be fucking up is you.
You've got six months to go before review.
Do your time clean and you walk.
Any trouble,
and you could grow old in here, Jack.
- Understand?
- Yes, sir.
I can't hear you.
Yes, Sir.
Your bad!
This facility runs on a point system.
Points are time.
You get points for doing good
and points for screwing up.
Doing good is no trouble.
Coping a positive attitude.
While screwing up is fighting,
running for the fence,
and coping a shit attitude,
just like you're doing right now,
for instance.
Moreno, we know all about you and O'Brien.
Really?
And I just don't want any shit from you.
I want that dorm to stay nice and quiet.
What makes you think
I'm gonna give you any trouble?
Hey, man, the only reason you're here
is because there's no room for you
any place else.
Well, then why don't you get me a room
at the Holiday Inn?
Why don't you wise up?
Do you know what goes on inside here?
Time stands still.
Outside, everybody else goes on
with their lives.
Working, making money, getting laid,
all that good shit.
But in here, time just stops dead.
Look at your bad self, man.
I was into that gang shit for half my life.
It's dumb-fucking-nowhere shit!
Hey, in here, everybody's the same.
And I mean everybody.
So, until we get you transferred,
I expect you to make good time.
That's right, that's right.
We gonna have your ass shipped down state
as soon as there's an opening
in another facility.
That could take a week, or a month,
or maybe even a year.
But until you go,
you're gonna be real cool.
You got it?
Well, well.
O'Brien,
how's it going?
I hear you're king shit in this place.
Congratulations. If there's anything
I can do to help,
please, let me know.
I'm sorry about your little brother,
Moreno. Okay?
You really break my heart. You know that?
I'm sorry about your old lady.
I'm sorry I didn't get to finish the job.
Stay off my ass, Moreno.
'Cause I got six months before my review,
and I wanna make good time. You got that?
Yeah, well, let me tell you something,
maricón. You're already dead.
Only you don't know it
because you're just as fucking stupid
as you ever was.
Yeah. I killed your little brother, Moreno.
But you just remember, he's dead
because you weren't looking out for him.
All you guys up there, pay attention!
Burns, Richards, Ocampo, K.P.!
Hey, we've got a theater, man!
Johnson, Roberts,
Perretti, Lee, Horowitz, agriculture!
All right, quiet down!
Moreno,
shithouse.
You like it, pretty?
Lassandro, Tolson,
Gonzalez, Jones, Lopez, commons.
Lopez, get a mop and start with this.
Man!
Thompson...
Hey! You gonna keep that all day?
- Who's it gonna be?
- The new guy.
Five bucks.
Make that
two times.
- He's gonna smash that white dude.
- Yeah.
I hear O'Brien messed up your face.
You know, it's too bad.
And he killed your brother.
Yeah, that's right.
But he didn't kill me.
He's not getting out of here alive.
You forget it, Moreno. He's mine.
Yeah?
Yeah.
This is nice. It's real nice.
But it looks like me and you got a problem.
You know,
they're betting on who's gonna kill who.
Moreno's the odds-on favorite.
Perretti and the chink
are running the action.
Who you betting on?
You.
So, what are you gonna do about this cunt?
Nothing.
I wanna get the fuck out of this place.
Yeah, but he's gonna kill you.
That's what he says.
- Gentlemen.
- Yo!
You've all been graded
on those latest reports.
And I'm happy to tell you,
finally, you all passed.
I knew I was good.
And there's a real artist in this class.
Somebody with special talent.
I didn't even know about it myself
until this report.
But first, for the record, let me give you
my definition of what art is.
Now, art is the creation
of something beautiful from nothing.
- You know?
- That's me.
And Lofgren has added a very special page
to his footnote
to his report. Stand up, man.
I think this is beautiful.
I wanna share with the group.
- Faggot.
- Didn't know you had it in you.
Cool it! Cool it, I said!
Hey, Horowitz, stand up, man.
You read this to the class.
"Youth killed in robbery attempt.
"A youth died Saturday
from gunshot wounds
"received in an attempted holdup
of a liquor store.
"Police said Warren Jerome of Chicago
was shot twice in the abdomen
"by the proprietor of the High Jay
liquor store on Kimball Avenue,
"after brandishing a pistol
and demanding money.
"Jerome died undergoing surgery
at Our Lady Queen of Martyrs Hospital."
So what?
So what? Who the fuck is Warren Jerome?
Who the fuck cares?
Really. Who the fuck cares?
Shut up!
Yeah, Viking, tell them
who Warren Jerome was.
That was Tweety, you assholes.
Hey, what are the odds on me now, Perretti?
Three-to-two, against you.
Nothing personal.
Hey! Clean it up!
Fuck you, O'Brien.
Yeah, fuck you. You clean it up.
- Hey!
- No violence!
Hey! You wanna play? You wanna play?
Clean it up!
Give your partner a hand, man.
Horowitz started this shit.
Come on, who started this shit?
I got $5 on Moreno.
Horowitz, you forgot something, man.
Yeah, yeah, Lofgren,
you show us your weenie later.
- How's it going?
- It's going.
Any word yet on the Paco Moreno transfer?
I haven't heard yet.
NO, huh?
'Cause this thing's
ready to blow any minute.
I can feel it.
I'll see what I can do.
In the meantime,
you just have to keep an eye on 'em.
You know what I do to squealers?
I let them have it in the belly,
so they can roll around for a long time,
thinking it oven
- Tell Lipschitz.
- All right.
Lipschitz.
Hey, Lipschitz.
Name's Horowitz, asshole.
Horowitz Asshole?
I heard it was Lipschitz.
Yeah. And if your lip shits,
what's your asshole gonna do?
That's really brilliant.
Just keep it up, assholes.
Oh, yeah? And what are
you gonna do about it, huh?
- Hey, that's enough, Moreno.
- Oh, yeah, is it?
Yeah, it is.
Yeah. Well, eat shit and die, O'Brien!
- Hey, man.
- Hey, hey, hey.
Let's get a smoke.
You better smoke, you little...
It's bad for your health.
Hey, don't fall!
It's time you put that piece of garbage away.
He's gonna do it to you.
You can't do it, can you?
Then I'm gonna get those fuckers.
Five minutes, lights out!
Yeah.
Lights out!
Here comes the rain, man.
Listen.
After you do O'Brien,
what do you say, 50-50 split
and two cartons a week, huh?
I'll think about it.
Hold this.
Okay, now don't move.
All right, let go.
Shit. Man, I almost had it.
What are you doing?
What the fuck's eating you?
Hey, what's up?
Yeah, we gotta shake 'em down.
Take Moreno, I'll take O'Brien.
O'Brien, looks like your time.
It's a bust.
Hurry up, Horowitz.
Here he comes.
O'Brien, Horowitz, let's go now!
Out, out, out, out!
Legs, spread them.
Spread them.
Stay over there.
Tell them you know your rights.
Boys?
I'm going to get you, Horowitz.
I'm not happy about this, Lofgren.
Yes, Sir.
In fact, I'm very pissed off.
I'm very pissed off!
This is an extremely serious offense,
and we are going to take disciplinary action.
The only thing in your favor
is you admitted possession of this weapon.
I'm gonna give you a choice.
Four weeks in solitary confinement
or four months added to your time.
I'll take... I'll take the four months, sir.
Hey, hey. Flush the toilet.
Not bad.
It's even better than the knife.
Really? Forget it.
I told you, that cocksucker's mine.
I'm gonna take him out.
Now, wait a minute.
I lost my brother.
All you lost was some skin.
Hey, Robert.
You guys know where this came from?
- No.
- Sure?
Yes.
Very nice radio.
Yeah, it's mine now.
Somebody get somebody.
Somebody get somebody, man.
Please, please. Come on, guys.
We identified the material
you used to make that charge.
Nitrogen from fertilizer. Very clever.
You're lucky Lofgren didn't die.
One question, Barry.
Did O'Brien know anything about this?
No. I did it all myself.
All right.
You'll serve the remainder of
your time in this program
in solitary confinement, starting now.
Hey, no way, man.
- I'm not going to solitary.
- Barry.
- Fuck you! I'm not going.
- Watch your mouth.
- Fuck you, man!
- Put it down, Barry.
Churchill! Churchill!
Get in here. Barry, stop it!
- Come on, man!
- Barry, give up.
Fuck you! Kill me first, you understand?
Barry, for God's sake, use your head.
- Get him!
- You'll have to kill me first!
- Come on! Come on!
- Get him! Get him!
- Come on, fuckers!
- Barry...
- Get him down.
- Fuck you...
Get him up! Barry!
Barry, you're just adding to your time.
Fuck all you cunts!
Oh, Ray, I was just looking for you.
The Moreno transfer just came through.
We're sending him off to Winfield tomorrow.
- Thank God.
- Amen.
Perretti.
Moreno.
Your transfer just got here.
You're going to Winfield tomorrow.
How're you doing?
Hey, O'Brien.
I just heard your buddy Paco is leaving.
How about that?
What are you talking about?
Moreno's being transferred
first thing tomorrow morning.
You got lucky.
Five minutes, lights out!
Let's go!
- Hey, Briggs.
- Hurry up, hurry up.
Put out that cigarette
and get your ass in bed.
Yeah, yeah.
Gentlemen, here comes the night.
I think my appendix broke. Help me.
- What happened?
- My...
- Your what?
- My appendix.
Let me. ..
Hey. Hey!
Hold it, you guys.
- What's happening, man?
- What's going on?
Hey!
Hey, it's going down, man. It's going down.
Hey, you guys!
- Hold it!
- Moreno!
Come on, you fucking guys.
Hold on!
- Paco!
- Don't be crazy. Come on, man!
Moreno! O'Brien! No!
Come on, man!
Come on, man, you can take him.
Come on!
Get him, get him!
Let's go.
Come on, O'Brien!
Yeah, that's it!
Come on!
Kill! Kill! Kill! Kill! Kill! Kill!
In the rooms. Let's go. In the rooms.
Lights off!
Hey, close that door.
Let's close up there.