Translated By:
||killer_sub||
I did something good today.
You don't always?
You wanna know about my job?
Strike.
Good kill.
Ladies and Gentlemen...
The remotely piloted aircraft
is not the future of war.
It is the here and now.
What'd you log? Three thousand hours in F-16s?
But we've progressed.
Let's go to Afghanistan.
Fly and fry.
Make no mistake about it.
This ain't Playstation.
We are killing people.
Light 'em up.
Yes!
You ever get to like, fly in a war or...?
Blew away six Taliban in Pakistan today.
Now I'm going home to barbecue.
He's quiet.
Does he ever get angry?
Almost never.
What happens when he gets angry?
He gets more quiet.
I am a pilot.
And I'm not flying.
I don't know what it is that I am doing?
But it's not flying.
Weapons away. Eight seconds.
Dammit what's that?
Abort?
You okay?
I feel like a coward.
Takin' potshots from half a world away
in an air-conditioned cubicle.
What is it that you miss?!
Combat?!
I don't want you getting gun-shy on me. We all pulled the trigger.
We both know I pulled the trigger.
I just want things to go back to the way they were.
I'M OKAY!!!!!!
We are cleared up.
Light 'em up.
Don't ask me if it's a just war.
It's just war.