You're fired.
Previously on this is us...
What?
I think it's time
we go at it alone for a while.
You know? See what happens.
This doesn't say "pause"
on my script.
Well, it doesn't say "suck"
either, yet here we are.
Kevin:
I'm not cut out for theater.
You do that a lot--
doubt yourself.
You're so busy making sure that
Kate's not eating too much...
Kev, calm down.
...and Randall's
not too adopted!
I'm sorry. I should have been
there, and I'm gonna be there.
Rebecca: Do you think
that my son could play with
yours sometime after school?
Yeah.
Every time I met a new
black person, I would
put a mark in this notebook,
and every time
i met a black man,
I wondered if that man
could possibly be my father.
♪ Bum, bum, bah-dum,
bum, bum, bum, bah, bah ♪
♪ dah, dah, bah, bum ♪
♪ bum-bum, bum-bum ♪
♪ bah-bah, bum-bum,
ah, ah, ah ♪
♪ ah, bah-bah-bah, bah-bum. ♪
(cheering)
No, baby, you got to
finish your bananas first.
You want some banana?
Kev, you want a little banana,
too?
Go in and see your daddy right
now, okay? You have some more.
Jack, I think we're
completely out of milk.
Yeah.
He won't drink his juice.
Yeah, I'll, um...
He just wants milk.
I'll bring some home.
Do you want some
more apples? Come on.
Come on. Here, do
you want to get out
of your chair?
Yeah.
All right. Come on.
Babe, a desk job?
Jack:
Bec, we need the money.
Rebecca:
You don't even own a tie.
(Typewriters clicking)
♪ ♪
(phones ringing)
Miguel:
So...
Did you hear?
Uh... yeah.
Surprise birthday cake
for Sandra in the break room.
You know, it's never,
it's never a surprise.
Als... okay, also,
I got promoted.
Project manager.
That's great, man. Hey.
Thanks.
And I'm bringing you with me.
Oh. Um...
Thanks, but no.
But thanks.
No?
Keep this quiet,
but I'm, uh, gonna go out
on my own.
I want to start
my own thing.
I know it's risky, but once
i get things up and running,
I can spend more time
with my kids.
All right, how 'bout this:
Why don't you, um,
take till the end of the week,
think about it.
I'm okay.
Don't need to think.
End of the week, okay? Huh?
(Stilted piano playing)
Jack:
Hi!
Daddy's home!
Hey!
Dad! Dad!
Hi.
Dad!
Kev.
Hi. Hey, buddy.
Kev...
I need to ask you a question...
One second.
Dad!
Hey, look-look at the
progress you made, bud.
Watch this.
I'm gonna help you out
after dinner, okay? Hi.
Hi, baby. Mwah.
Dad!
Yeah.
We're getting ice cream!
Kevin/randall: Ice cream!
Jack: Ice cream?
I promised them.
Ice cream? Ice cream?!
(Laughs)
None for me if you want
to be able to pick me up again.
Please, you are tiny.
Rebecca: Right. Mm.
But ice cream must mean
that the kids'
report cards came back
and they were good?
No.
Actually, mostly b's
and c's. I caved.
I don't know. Parenting
makes my cerebellum hurt.
(Chuckles)
Sorry, your what?
It's the part of my brain
that makes my emotions.
I have been doing way too much
third grade science homework.
Mm.
But why don't you,
uh, look at that.
Why does Randall's teacher
want to see us?
I don't know.
Jack:
Hmm. Okay.
(Piano playing gentle melody)
William: ♪ you are
too beautiful ♪
♪ my dear, to be true ♪
♪ for one lucky fool ♪
♪ to be with ♪
♪ you are too beautiful ♪
♪ and I am a fool ♪
♪ for beauty. ♪
oh.
Hope you don't mind. Pianos get
forlorn if you don't play 'em.
No, of course I don't mind.
Where'd you learn
how to play like that?
My dad taught me.
And his dad taught him.
Dad, can you teach
us to play?
Uh, I wish I could.
Grandma and aunt Kate got all
the music talent in the family.
Me? I was always all knuckles.
Yeah, well,
your dad's
got other skills.
Me, I managed to squeak out
a couple of dollars
on one of these back in the day.
Mostly trumpet, mm.
Any gigs I could get.
Tess: Will you speak
at my career day?
Can grandpa speak
I don't think so, baby.
You're only allowed one speaker,
and I'm already signed up.
I pick grandpa.
He had a cool job.
What are you saying, that
daddy doesn't have a cool job?
But you guys love visiting
me at the office, right?
I like spinning
in your chair.
You kind of have
a boring job, dad.
Trading commodity futures based
on long-term weather patterns
is not boring, okay?
(Snores, snorts)
Sorry, sort of fell asleep soon
as I heard the word "commodity."
Ooh, Uncle Kevin,
can you speak at my career day?
Daddy's doing career day!
End of discussion.
And it's gonna be lit.
That's not how
you use "lit," right?
No.
(Chuckles)
Sorry, I don't understand.
So you are saying
that Randall is gifted?
But his grades are average.
Are you sure
you tested him right?
Jack, we know
how smart he is.
Okay, so what's up
with his grades?
M-maybe is
the-the teacher prejudiced?
Jack.
No.
When a child tests well
but his grades
don't seem to reflect it,
oftentimes,
he isn't being challenged
at his school.
And you maybe want to
consider other options.
They have
wonderful programs
for exceptional children
like Randall.
Not gonna happen.
Jack, please stop making me
say "Jack."
Randall is one of the only
black kids at this school,
but at least here he has
his brother and sister.
I know.
What about them?
I mean, can they go, too?
Mr. Pearson, all due respect,
Kevin and Kate wouldn't do well
in that school.
You see, that's
where you're wrong.
All of our children
are exceptional.
Can I touch you?
I just want to touch you
one more time.
Just... one part of your body.
Your hair.
I want to wake up...
I'm sorry, I...
I'm...
I'm not... I'm sorry, can
we... can we just start over?
Yeah, yeah. Uh, Kevin,
can I ask you something?
Yeah.
Why...
Just try to help me
understand this.
Wh-why, every time we
come to this scene,
this-this pinnacle of grief,
which should rip--
I mean, literally rip--
tears from the audience,
why you summon up
all the emotion
of a Google maps voice.
Right. Uh...
I don't know. May...
You know, maybe
it's in the words.
Sloane: How would you know?
You've never said them.
Uh, no,
I think...
I think I'm saying 'em.
No. I mean, yeah,
like, s-some.
Kind of. But you're-you're
mostly paraphrasing.
I'm sorry.
Yeah. Y-yeah.
You see,
it's really simple.
Olivia is Jessica,
your wife.
Okay.
You are David.
You loved her,
but now she is dead.
So you are grieving
the loss of her.
There's no longer
any such thing as gravity.
(Sighs)
Have you ever lost anyone?
Yes.
Because I don't believe you.
Well, you know, Ron,
it's not my job
to make sure
you believe me.
(Stammers)
Oh, yes, yes, it is! It is!
It is exactly your job!
Do your job.
What is she writing?
What are you
writing?
That's her suicide note.
Olivia: All right,
all right, enough,
okay?
He'll get there.
Ron:
(Sighs) Okay.
All right.
10:00 A.M. Tuesday, everybody.
Thank you.
It's a process.
Just... let it go for now.
Yeah.
What are you
doing tomorrow?
Oh. Uh, well, tomorrow
i was just gonna spend
the entire day feeling
like a failure, but, uh...
Come to a party with me.
A party? What kind of party
we talking?
I'll text you the address.
Yeah, okay. All right.
(Door opens)
(Birds chirping)
(Sighs) There's no way in hell.
This job better be worth it.
See ya, world.
It's been real.
Oh, Jesus.
(Water running)
You sure you're
all right?
Oh. Yeah, I'm good.
I'm good. Yeah. Yeah.
I'm good.
Uh, Mrs. rosenthal...
Marin.
Oh. Marin. (Chuckles)
I realize that my previous
employment with my brother
might not be
directly applicable.
However,
i am abnormally organized.
And I'm basically
the not crazy version
of Jack Nicholson
in as good as it gets.
Oh, I love that movie. Oh.
Right?
Both: "You make me want
to be a better man."
(Laughing)
Oh! Sorry.
I'm sorry,
you were saying...
No. I-i have
grant writing experience,
and I'm used to dealing with
Hollywood types, which I know
are large contributors
to your foundation.
And I know you're on the board
of stay in touch
and the butterfly ball.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, my God, that's amazing.
Um, Doug Kincaid,
your boss before
your brother, was it?
He speaks about you
in such glowing terms.
Why did you quit his firm?
Because I fell
in love with him,
and it was not
a healthy situation.
I like you, Kate.
You're qualified,
you're smart,
and I need someone
right now by my side.
Now, it's not
assistant work.
It's part event coordinator,
part development associate.
I would be absolutely thrilled.
But there is some personal
stuff you may have to do,
an errand here or there,
maybe drive my
daughter to and from?
Yeah. Okay.
Not much, so don't
worry about that.
No, of course.
Yeah.
So, do you want the gig?
Wait, really?
I'm so excited!
Oh!
Well, I'm so excited!
(Laughs)
Oh, I wanted you
from the moment
the toilet paper was
stuck to your head.
Seriously, though,
whatever you need,
I'm your girl.
(Typing on phone)
Oh, hey,
this is my daughter.
Jemma, this is Kate.
So, I see you picked
the fat one.
(Continues typing)
Oh.
♪ ♪
weather derivatives
are tradable commodities
that protect business owners
from future changes
in the weather.
It's like licking
a piece of pizza
so that nobody
will eat it later.
Now I'm thinking about pizza.
Okay.
No, wait,
I'm sorry-- no, no, no, wait,
I was gonna get it this time.
Look, how am i
supposed to inspire
an auditorium full of strangers,
and my own wife and kids
don't even understand
what I do?
That's not true.
Really?
What do I do?
You trade weather.
You trade commodities
based on weather patterns.
And what does that mean?
Oh, damn, Randall, I don't know.
(Clicks tongue)
You swap lightning bolts
for thunder clouds?
(Sighs)
Look, I know what
your day is like.
I know that you like
one of your partners
and you hate the other one.
I know that you're gonna
redesign your office furniture
and that you might fire
your assistant
because she says
"like" too much.
It's nonstop.
Can I talk to you in depth
about weather patterns?
No, I cannot.
But I don't think you'd
want me to if I could, so...
Hey, what's-what's this
really about?
Maybe I was meant
to be a musician.
I'm sorry, what now?
Or an artist or a writer.
Just think about it, Beth.
There's this whole
genetic side of me
that nobody even knew existed.
I mean, William was a poet,
an artist, a musician.
You know, maybe I've had
an artistic side in me all along
and nobody knew to empower it.
You know, maybe
i wasn't meant to be
a straight and narrow math geek
destined to wear a
shirt and tie every day
like my parents thought.
Maybe I was meant to live
a musician's life.
On the road and playing clubs,
you know?
All right, well, in this musical
fantasy version of yourself,
what instrument would you...
Sax.
Mm.
Like Wesley in mo' better blues.
Definitely sax.
Oh, yeah.
That's sexy, yeah.
You're making fun of me.
No.
No, you're making fun of me.
No, I am not. I'm-I'm not.
Your biological father
just came back into your life,
and it's bringing up
all kinds of stuff.
It's-it's normal.
Look,
why don't you try out
this-this crazy artist side
of yourself and, you know,
get this presentation popping.
Let's see how it flies with
some eight-year-olds, right?
Before you, like,
shift careers
and start playing
open mic saxophone nights.
You know, maybe I will.
Okay, yeah.
I see you are making
fun of me, but I will.
No, yeah.
Why don't you stop smiling?
I can't.
Stop smiling.
I'm sorry.
This early midlife crisis
is so you, I can't stand it.
(Grunts)
(Shrieks)
You want something
to smile about?
(Laughing): No, please.
Do you, do you really?
♪ ♪
♪ I build it up ♪
♪ I build it u-up... ♪
hi, can I speak
to Michael please?
Hey, Tanner, it's Kate.
Yeah, Kevin's sister.
How are you?
Oh, good. Are you by any chance
available on the third
for a charity event?
Hey, I have a
question for you:
How do you feel
about homelessness?
I know, it's a
bummer, right?
So, we're looking to cater
about 400 people.
Your restaurant's definitely
gonna want to be a part of this.
Oh, my-- I know. Um...
Awesome, okay, great.
Thanks, z. Bye.
You're killer.
(Chuckles)
I need you to take me
to Ashley's.
Oh, well, what if
Kate gave you a ride?
Do you mind?
(Ringtone plays)
No.
Hi.
(Whispers):
Sorry.
I'll be in the car, intern.
Hey.
Should we go in?
Yeah.
Listen, what kind of party
is this anyway?
'Cause everyone
seems pretty sad.
Of course they're sad.
It's a memorial service.
Come on, in we go,
before all the good cheese
is gone.
(School bell rings)
What are we doing here?
Rebecca:
We are here
because your wife--
do you remember her?
I think so, yeah.
The one that you love
more than life itself?
Definitely rings a bell.
Got it.
She wants to take a
look at this place.
Jack:
Okay, I'm looking.
Geez, this place is whiter
than Randall's already
pretty white other school.
I mean, look at these kids.
They look like little
Nazi robots.
That one's got a briefcase.
I... no kid should be
carrying a briefcase.
I think it's cute.
Yeah, it's cute now; Next thing
you know, he's gonna be
trapped in a cubicle
for the rest of his life.
I tell you, it starts
with a briefcase,
then you put on a tie,
you sit at a desk.
Next thing you know,
you are so conditioned
to the florescent lights
that when you step outside,
the sun actually
burns your eyes.
Wow.
Yeah.
Wow. Really?
This isn't about me.
Well, it certainly
isn't about Randall.
Hey.
Look, I...
I wasn't gonna say anything
until I'd had a few
details worked out, but...
I think I'm gonna
go out on my own.
Start my own company.
Big three homes. I just...
Doesn't feel like
a very good time right now.
(Chuckles)
I think it's great.
I think you
should do it.
(Sighs)
It's not that easy, bec.
I mean...
What does this place even cost?
We'll figure it out.
We'll figure it out-- we'll
send Randall to another school,
we'll get him a tutor,
we'll do whatever we have to do.
All right.
I just don't want
you to be unhappy.
I mean it.
Okay.
All right.
We'll come back.
(Engine starts)
This is nice.
Rebecca:
It's very nice.
(Typing on phone)
Jemma, your mom told me
that you would be giving me
Ashley's address.
(Phone chiming)
Jemma, will you answer me?
Jemma, I'm gonna
need the address.
Why?
'Cause you need to get
back to work?
Yes.
And if I didn't value the work,
I wouldn't be tolerating
this attitude.
Just so we're clear.
(Scoffs) What'd she tell you,
you'd be an associate?
And you thought my mom was gonna
give you actual
responsibilities,
because a few c-list celebrities
take your calls?
Clearly she only hired you
because she thinks
the fat girl
can get through to me.
Guess she figured,
bigger the better.
You know, I actually
feel bad for you.
(Tires screech)
What the hell?
Yeah, well, don't feel
bad for me, okay?
'Cause I have a ride home.
I'm sorry?
Get out.
What?
Get out of the damn car, jemma,
before I toss you out of it!
Oh, and you know what?
You can walk to Ashley's.
And fat girl to fat girl,
if you keep up the pace,
you can burn 417 calories
an hour walking.
I love American cheese. Mm.
English cheese is so
blue, it's angry.
Yeah.
American cheese is like a...
A bed you can just fall into.
So, whose good-bye party
is this anyway?
Frank pendergrass-- tree branch
fell on him three days ago
when he was jogging
through central park.
Bang. Dead.
Well, that sucks.
Mm-hmm.
You knew him how?
Oh, I didn't. No, the
obituary gave the address
of the service so, I thought...
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
hold on a second.
What are you trying to say?
Hello.
I'm Frank's wife, grace.
(Quietly):
Hi.
(American accent):
Hi. Uh, I'm Jessica.
This is my husband, David.
Oh.
Were you students
of my husband?
We actually met in his class.
Oh.
Right?
Students.
Mm.
Olivia: Yeah, we were sitting
in the front row,
and we kept looking
at each other,
and then finally Frank stopped
the class and said,
"you two are distracting me.
Go outside, have sex,
and come back when you're ready
to learn something."
(Chuckles)
Well, that sounds like Frank.
Yeah.
(Quietly):
Frank.
Thank you both
so much for coming.
Kevin: Thank you for coming.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
Thank you.
(Normal voice):
Well done.
No, no, no, hold on.
No, no, no. You brought...
(Whispers):
You brought me
to a stranger's funeral?
Memorial service.
Whatever. Why, huh?
What, because I'm struggling
with the grief scene?
You said I would get there.
Yeah, well, I didn't say
you'd get there on your own.
This is insane.
But thank you very much
for the lesson.
I appreciate it.
Now I'm gonna go have a drink.
Enjoy your cheese.
Hey, baby, what happened
to jungle book?
It's over.
Well, mommy snuck in
a quick shower-- shh.
Got to get them in
while you can, little bug.
You're so pretty.
(Chuckles)
Thank you, baby.
Well, if I'm pretty, you're
pretty, 'cause we look alike.
Oh, can you get
mommy's yellow blouse,
the one with the buttons?
Just in the closet? Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
(Sighs):
Ooh.
Thank you, bug.
Mwah.
Okay, I'm going to
pick up Randall.
Good-bye, beautiful.
Bye, see you later.
All right, baby,
I'm almost done getting ready.
Tonight, little man,
you, me and a b-52?
Okay!
Okay, don't finish it;
I got to help with something.
Sounds good.
(Sighs, mumbles)
I'm sorry. I was,
i was, uh...
People keep bringing me things,
like I forgot how to cook.
Mm, there's no room in here
and I don't know where to put
all of Frank's food.
(Sighs)
You have a lot
of pickles.
(Chuckles)
I hate pickles.
Mm-hmm.
But he loves them.
Yeah, he eats them in bed.
"Ate."
He is now past tense.
He used to be "is."
Now he is "was."
Hey, I like pickles.
Good.
Here.
Okay.
How do you feel
about holiday ties?
And sport coats.
Because I asked Jeremy,
but he said he didn't
want anything of his dad's.
Yeah.
How old is Jeremy?
Fifteen.
That's tough.
15 is tough.
Uh, my dad and I...
Used to build models
together, when I was a kid.
Yeah?
Yeah, we'd build, um,
planes and boats.
I used to pick the
most complex ones--
b-52s, aircraft carriers--
'cause they took the
longest, you know?
See, I was one
of three kids,
so you really had to strategize
to get your alone time with dad.
(Chuckles)
You know, and eventually,
we had a whole fleet of them;
We had just rows and rows,
shelves of them.
You know, and then
when he died...
...when...
When he, when he died, I, um...
...i... I threw all
the models away.
I threw every one
of them away.
I don't know why...
Why I did that, you know?
You were how old?
Uh, it was a
long time ago.
I have, um...
I have this.
(Sniffles)
This necklace, this
is his and, um,
it's the only thing
i have left of him.
And at first, you know,
i didn't want to wear it,
I wouldn't wear it, I wouldn't
even look at it, but now it's...
It's all I have and i-i
can't take it off now, so...
(Sniffles)
It's okay.
(Crying)
(Sniffles)
Oh, my God,
this is so dumb.
What am I doing?
I'm... (Sniffles)
Supposed to be comforting you,
not snotting all over you.
(Laughs)
Grace:
Who are you again?
Hey.
Hi.
Randall,
your daddy's here.
Randall: We're almost done.
Best two out of three.
Okay.
Hey, thanks for...
Thanks for having him.
Oh, I will take him
as much as he'll have it.
Show my own boys
what manners look like.
(Chuckles)
Okay.
Um...
Hey, did Rebecca tell
you about his school?
No. What happened?
I guess he scored off
the charts on some tests,
and now they want to uproot him
during the school year,
send him to some
private academy.
You know, take him away
from the other two.
Why? Is it, is it
a boarding school?
No.
No, it's, uh...
It's uniforms and...
A lot of little white kids
marching around like
it's Nazi Germany.
Oh, I see.
That's why you're
running this by me.
What?
You're looking for me
to give you
the black person
seal of approval
for any messed-up
parenting decision you make.
How is it messed up? I just--
I don't want my son
to feel more different.
Okay, so you just want to hold
him back because he's black?
No. Absolutely not. I...
Jack,
Randall is special.
Yeah.
So, if you're looking for
somebody to make you feel better
about denying him
a special opportunity,
you may just have to find
yourself another black person.
See you, guys.
Ready, Freddy.
Bye, Ms. yvette.
Did you win?
Yep.
♪ ♪
and I'll never forget
the look on her face
when I placed her child
back into her arms.
Never.
So, yeah, that's what I do.
Day in and day out, I...
Save children,
just like you guys, from fires.
Thank you.
(Crowd cheering)
Let's give it up for
Kendal's mom, Mandy! Yeah.
All right, okay,
uh, up next is
Tessa's dad, Randall,
who is a weatherman.
(Crowd murmuring)
Oh, sorry, sorry.
Uh, strike that.
He's a... weather trader.
I don't know what that is,
but I think he's gonna tell us.
Here's Randall.
(Applause)
(Clears throat)
Hey, y'all.
Uh, yeah.
I'm a weather trader,
which I know can be
a little bit hard to explain,
and so, um...
I wrote you guys a song
about it.
I thought daddy couldn't
play the piano?
Daddy cannot.
(Piano playing hesitantly)
♪ if you-- ♪
wait, mm, hold on one second.
Sorry about that.
Oh, sweet Jesus.
Randall:
♪ if you-- ♪
mm. One second, please.
♪ If you've got a farm ♪
♪ you should know
the future cost of corn ♪
♪ so buy yourself
a contract to ♪
♪ protect your crops ♪
♪ rain, storm or snow ♪
♪ might affect your ♪
♪ summer crops, so ♪
♪ invest your money wisely ♪
♪ you'll be safe... ♪
come on everybody.
♪ If you've got a farm ♪
(Crowd murmuring along)
♪ You should know
the future cost of corn... ♪
look away. Just look away.
♪ so buy yourself a contract ♪
♪ to protect your crops. ♪
ah, there you are.
I was with grace.
Who?
Grace. Frank's wife.
Why?
Because she's sad.
Her husband died.
Why are you mad at me?
Because we shouldn't be here.
This is not a play.
You know, she's a real person.
I'm a real person.
Yeah, I can see that--
maybe for the first time.
What happened to you?
What happened is my dad died.
That's what.
And I hated him for it.
And I couldn't eat for a month,
and I used to
wake myself up crying,
so I could cry myself
back to sleep again.
That's what happened.
Why do you push
all of that away?
You can't just kill the feelings
like they're some creature
that you're afraid of.
That pain is
a part of you.
I can see it now.
I can feel it.
(Moans softly)
Sorry, pickle mouth.
I don't care.
Is jemma okay?
What? She's fine.
She said she had
a really nice day with you.
Which I didn't believe
for a second,
because you didn't come back,
so I pressed.
I am really sorry
that I left her.
I can understand
if you want to press charges
for child abandonment.
God, don't even
worry about it.
I've left her at
three malls myself,
and I've wanted to shove
her out of the car
on the freeway
at least once.
I don't know what to do
with her anymore.
I can't reach her.
Before yesterday,
she's spoken seven words
to me in two weeks.
And you heard them:
"I see you hired
the fat one."
(Sighs)
Is that why you hired me?
No! God, no.
Not entirely.
Yeah, I thought so.
I am not proud of it.
I am sorry and it's really
not the only reason.
I-i liked your resume
before I met you.
But, yeah.
I thought that maybe
you'd be able to...
Understand her.
Her issues.
Oh, my God, it
sounds horrible
when I say it out loud.
God, please don't quit.
(Chuckles softly)
No more personal stuff.
You saw my work;
You know I can do it.
No more driving jemma around.
Yu can afford
an assistant for that.
Done.
And I want to chair
the butterfly ball.
It's yours.
And I want an office.
Okay.
And I want an intern.
Okay, too far.
(Sighs)
I'll see you
at 9:00 tomorrow.
Thank you.
(Sighs)
Hey, is jemma still here?
She's outside.
(Softly):
Okay.
Hello? Hello?
Pearson corporation.
Would you like to
discuss the big deal?
Well, I'm too busy.
You'll have to call back.
You love coming
to work with dad, huh?
I wanted you here because
i need your help with something.
Come here.
What's that?
That is a house
the company's working on.
Cool.
Yeah.
You see, uh...
You see, I don't know
how many feet of two-by-four
I'm gonna need
for this wall
right here.
You see how each...
How each inch is...
Is three feet?
22h feet.
Wow.
That's pretty cool, buddy.
Didn't know you were
so good with numbers.
Wait, wait, wait.
Come here.
What about this wall
right here?
How many... how many
do I need for that?
I don't know that one.
You knew how do it
a second ago, now you don't?
I don't know it, dad.
I think you do.
I don't.
Randall, that's enough.
Come here.
I don't want to.
Look. This wall, right here.
How much do I need?
I don't know.
Tell me the answer.
How many feet?
Tell me right now.
I don't know.
Damn, it, Randall,
tell me the answer!
(Whispers):
34.
What's that?
That's right.
Why are you pretending
not to know this stuff, huh?
Getting b's in math?
Not letting people see
how smart you are?
I don't want to be
different from them.
Different from who?
Who, the kids at school?
If... if I get an a,
I'll get ice cream,
and Kate and Kevin won't.
And then they'll hate me.
Can I be honest with you?
Man to man?
You know, your mom and me,
we always try
to treat you kids
the same.
Always have.
Hasn't always worked,
because, well,
you're not all the same.
You're adopted, and we don't
talk about that enough.
'Cause to me,
you are every part my son.
Maybe I.. I don't want you
to feel like you stand out.
But I need you
to know something.
I want you to stand out.
I want all of you
to be as different
as you can possibly be.
In all the best ways.
I love you as much as
a human heart can, kiddo.
You are an exceptional
young man.
So don't let your dad's
poor choice make you feel afraid
to be different.
Okay?
Okay.
(Whispers):
Sounds better when you
put your fingers on it.
Hmm.
You know how,
in the movies,
when somebody's bad
at something,
but they don't want to be,
and so they set
their mind to it.
And then we see this montage
of them practicing
and practicing.
And then comes the big moment,
and they're amazing,
and everybody cheers.
I've seen a few movies
like that, yeah.
I think I skipped the montage.
(Both chuckle)
When you first told me
what you did for a living,
man, I didn't
understand a word.
Hand to God, I mean,
you might as well have
been speaking German.
But I was watching
your face.
In my better days,
i have met and played with
some of the greatest
musicians in the world.
And when they talked
about music,
their face looked
like your face
when you told me about
whatever the hell it is you do.
But if it'll help, I can
show you a thing or two
on the piano.
That would be great.
Oh, not tonight, just...
Oh, right.
It's late is the thing.
Yeah. No.
I got ya.
Good night.
Night.
(Phone chiming)
You don't have to
say bye to me.
I didn't quit.
I know what
you're going through.
Stop trying to have
a moment with me.
So, my mom was skinny
and gorgeous.
Well, is gorgeous.
She still gets
hit on by everyone.
She once was asked
if she was a model
when she had the flu.
Pretty hard growing up
with a mom like that.
I spent all my time
comparing myself to her,
and then I took it out on her.
And now we barely talk,
and it sucks.
Hey, your mom's
not perfect.
She has her stuff,
and you have yours, but...
You got to cut her a break.
Or you're gonna regret it.
I promise.
Kate, will you please
help me out?
No, I hate this dress!
I know. I don't care
that you hate it, though.
It's what's clean
and what fits,
and it's what you're wearing.
I hate you!
Put it on, please;
We're running late.
Hey, Jack?
Jack: Yeah?
Randall?
You guys are ready?
Yeah.
We have to leave
in five minutes.
I know. I got him.
You sure about this?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Hey, listen to
your mother.
See, you look great.
Come get your lunch,
young lady.
Thank you.
♪ ♪
got it.
See it?
Yeah.
Yeah. Takes a little time,
but (Chuckles)
You'll get the hang of it.
Here, look at me.
Looking sharp.
You ready for
your first day?
Are Kate and Kevin
gonna ride with us?
We're gonna
drop them off,
then we're gonna
drop you off,
and then we'll all
be back together
after school, okay?
Okay.
Hey, wait. Come here.
(Whispers):
We'll tuck this low.
Nice and comfortable.
Say bye to your mom.
(Sighs)
Hot, plump ones
coming through.
Mm-hmm. Whoo!
Oh, um, mom,
I have a soccer practice
after school today.
Yeah, I remember.
William:
Come on.
I have something to say.
Uh... my dad put on
a tie every day
because he had to.
I put one on every day
because I want to.
It's important
you know that.
Maybe I don't run into
burning buildings for a living,
but to me, my work is
challenging and exciting.
I will not apologize
for the fact
that it's hard to explain
to people.
Okay, daddy.
Uh, also, William,
thank you for offering
to teach me piano,
but I don't think
at this point
in our relationship
it would be healthy
to introduce
that dynamic.
And so,
starting next Tuesday, I'm gonna
be taking piano lessons
from Mrs. Perkins down the road.
There's gonna be
a recital in the spring,
and I hope that you will all
come and support me in this.
What was that?
That was a midlife crisis, baby.
But just a little one,
so go on, eat your waffle.
(Laughs)
"Just a little one."
That's good.
He-he's gonna take piano?
Psst, hey!
Brought you a cappuccino.
(Sighs)
Soy, yeah?
You're too kind.
Yeah.
Also wanted to say
that, uh...
You know, I wanted to say
that I forgive you.
For the lesson. Um...
What can I say?
It worked.
Mm, I'd say it did.
Yeah.
But, um, that's not
the only lesson.
No? Okay.
What happened
between you and me...
...is never gonna happen again.
Oh. I-i thought...
I know you did,
but this is who we are
and all we are.
You're my husband,
and I'm your dead wife.
And you will never
sleep with her again.
Now, how does that
make you feel?
Sad.
Great.
Use that.
(Whispers):
Okay.
♪ ♪
(sighs)
Hey.
♪ ♪
so what was that
about teleportation?
Yeah, the teleportation
and the freeze breath
or, like, hot breath.
Hey, have fun.
Bye, dad.
Love you.
What's up?
♪ ♪
captioning sponsored by
20th century fox television
captioned by
media access group at wgbh
access.Wgbh.Org