Wait for me
Relax, we're just playing mahjong
Ah Fatt
Give me a serving of Three Great Scholars
Got it, no problem
- I'm on it - Be quick about it
White Dragon, Red Dragon, Green Dragon
Isn't that the Three Great Scholars?
Sassy, get to work
Pretty sure she's not here
Nancy, I've got your West Wind tile
- Let me send you to your doom - Pong
Watch it, or you'll meet your doom
- Green Dragon - Pong
You want to win? Dream on
Pong
Crap
Pong again and again
Don't bite off more than you can chew
Ah Lian you haven't ordered,
what do you want to eat?
I'm hungry two fishballs would be nice
I'm dizzy from al the
Pong that is going around
I need a Panadol
- Just that one capsule - One capsule
White Dragon
I'll Pong
Don't mess it up, can't you see
she's on to a Four Large Blessings hand
Don't make me lose my grocery money as well
Will it kill you to just let me win once?
Sure, the weakest hand shall prevail
Show me what you've got, dare you
North Wind
You scared me
Tiger, you want a Panadol, right?
I have one
Don't take everything you're offered
Even if you picked it up
yourself, double check
Kong
Jinx..
Kong again
Kong…pay up please
Here you go again
Three draws and you couldn't even get t,
you'll lose for sure
It ain't over until it's over
Come on, Nancy
Move aside
Jinx..
Three Circles
Self-Draw win
Four Small Blessings and three Kongs
How much do you think is the total winnings?
I'm a newbie at mahjong,
but this seems like a big win
Haven't you heard of "the weakest hand
shall prevail?
You watch out, the ghosts
might follow you home
If I knew I'd lose
I'd have gone home to watch
my wives play mahjong
Come on, we're neighbours, don't say that
A little gambling never hurt anyone
We're just having fun
Come on, pay up
- There goes my money - You little rascal
I asked you to pack yong tau fool
and here you are playing games
Stand right there, don't run
I won't f you stop chasing
Talking back now, eh?
Self-Draw win
The candy is mine
You' even settle for a Chicken Hand?
It'll bring bigger wins
Didn't you say you only
play but don't gamble?
That's why on y won some candy
And I'm the one who bought the candy
What's the matter? You want some?
No, today you're going to learn
how to lose gracefully
Alright, lets learn about sharing first today
What's the matter? Don t you want some candy?
Mr Yang
Well well well , look who we have here
Wayne Yang
Haven't I told you
not to gamble here after school?
Which part of that did you not understand?
We weren't gambling
Yeah, don't twist the facts,
we were just sharing candies
Did you see us gambling with your own eyes?
Although no money was involved
But playing mahjong is gambling
And that's wrong
Playing mahjong doesn't necessarily
mean we're gambling
I was teaching them mathematics and history
No, you were clearly gambling
Don't deny it
Deny? Don't you know?
This isn't just mahjong,
it's the essence of our culture
Go!
Mahjong is a card game created in China
Well-known and well-loved in the whole world
There are many different
theories on its origins
Due to the fact that it's
been around for so long
Some say that in 500 B.C
When Confucius was travelling all over China
He created the game mahjong
to spread his teachings
Using the three tiles of Red Dragon,
Green Dragon, and White Dragon
to represent the Three Virtues
love sincerity and filial piety
Commonly known as loyalty,
filial piety and righteousness
That's all good
But why do the tiles need to be so big?
You…
Such a big tile…
Carving such a big tile.
Right
That's correct
Later on, duel to different requirements
mahjong kept evolving
And finally settled with the 108-tile version
Representing the 108 warriors
of the Water Margin Legend
With the addition of various flower tiles
The whole set has 144 tiles
This is a flower
It's the bird
Centipede
It's a live, and it wants to bite me
Every player has 13 tiles
To represent the 13 weeks n a single season
There are 52 weeks in the four seasons,
totalling 364 days
The winning tile
represents the final day of a year
To make it 365 days, one complete year
Master, is there an ace tile to every suit?
Of course Little Monkey
Mah… mahjong
Pay… pay up
Playing mahjong is commonly
referred to by the Chinese
As playing eight rounds or "dry swimming"
A square table is used for playing mahjong
Which represents North, South, East, West
As well as Spring, Summer, Autumn Winter
- Four Bamboos - I'll take it
One tile discarded and three players win
Mahjong has been passed down for generations
Becoming a form of
entertainment in people's lives
Even the aunties enjoy a game of mahjong
Mahjong became a form of entertainment
and also a sport
It can foster relationships
Prevent Alzheimer's
Hurry up…
Finally I'm here
Come on
Eleven
Two Bamboos
Four Bamboos
I'll take it
One tile discarded and three players win
- Where are you going? - Toilet
- No way - You're wriggling out of this?
We've waited for a year for you
to walk to this table
You might take another two years
to walk to the loo
Pay up before you go
Now it's becoming ever more convenient
to play mahjong
It's even available online
We can play mahjong anytime
anywhere
See they are so well versed n history
You call this history?
Don't be a bad example to the kids
Everyone learns their history
from the TV these days
Nobody takes it seriously
At east their history improved
Since picking up mahjong
they've scored full marks in history
What's the matter?
Not willing to admit defeat?
Let's have a bet then
Sure…bring it on
Alright, same rules
If I win
you can't stop them from
coming to pay with me
And, you have to stop bothering me for a week
- And what if I win… - Okay
Dinner, movies, whatever you want
Everyone has 9 tiles, from One Character
to Nine Character
The first to complete the
suit n order shall win
Let's go
I'm done
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 correct
3 7 9 8 4 1 5 6 2 wrong
Sassy sister won
Mr. Yang lost
Sir
What a pity
Don't worry sir, you'll get used to losing
It's not your first time
losing to Sister Sassy anyway
Come let's continue playing
Let's carry on, Sir has to
go back to teaching
What's the matter? Are you okay?
I'm fine It's just that,
you eat with such elegance
As your father, I feel contented
That's great
- What do you think if.. . - Aright
- Actually… - I get it
- She.. - I said cut it
You want me to be like her
Talk softer, be more gentle,
like a lady right?
What's so bad about me now?
You are perfect as you are
- But if you could… - Dad
There are no ifs and buts in this world
I just want you to have a boyfriend
In case, one day, I'm not here anymore
Not here? Where are you going?
Back to meet my maker
Why would you meet your
maker all of a sudden?
Not all of a sudden
History tells us, people die
No, anyone can die except you
You can't leave me alone
Okay, I won t die then
That's more like it
But even if I don't d e
you'll still need to date
I think that Wayne Yang is not bad
You got to be kidding, Dad
Him? Not bad?
He's old-fashioned and dumb
He stutters and he can't even play mahjong
Every time I play with him, he loses
What's so good about him?
All those can be helped
Old-fashioned means he's honest
A slow talker is better than a smooth tailker
As for playing mahjong, it's easy to learn
What are you doing?
Hey
Are you guys serious?
Yep, it's here
Who's making a din here?
We're looking for Pak Chong Fatt where is he?
What Pak Chong Fatt? Hong Chong Fatt?
There's only Chow Yun Fatt
- Bugger off - Wong Tin Ba
Who's that guy?
He's the World Mahjong Champion
for 10 consecutive years
The modern day King of Mahjong, Wong Tin Ba
He's got style
What's wrong with the plastic bags today?
Those dace a so aren't fresh enough
Sassy, where did you get those plastic bags?
Where did you get those dace?
Hey there handsome,
how many seats do you need?
It's been a while, Pak Chong Fatt
What?
Pak Chong Fatt
Born on the 9th of October 1970
Libra 'O' blood type
His pass on is to help those in need
Cut the crap
Tell me what's their relationship
He was taught by the same
master as Wong Tin Ba
Rumour has it that,
after they turned on each other
Pak Chong Fatt vanished
from the world of mahjong
Brother Fatt is Pak Chong Fatt?
Are you sure you got the right person?
What do you think?
I never thought you could find me here
How's it going, my little brother?
It's been so long
Is this for your birthday party
or your daughter's wedding?
It's to challange you to a duel
The next mahjong championship is coming up
I must have a duel with you this time
It's been a while since I've played,
you should cut down too
I'll ask you again,
are you up for a duel or not?
- No thanks - Come on
- Nah - Come on
Nope
For god's sake quit dilly-dallying
Happiness can't be forced
Sometimes you need to
take a gamble for your happiness
You have no choice, because I have chosen you
I must gamble with you this time
Roasted drumstick
Such a pity, to become a
mute at such a young age
Alright, let's have a drumstick
- Girl - I'm not your daughter
I'm not your daughter,
and you're not my father
How did you find out?
Are you for real? I was just joking
How could it turn out that way?
I thought you were mute,
turns out you're a retard
You are as short as I am
Could you possibly be the daughter
of our neighbour, Tall Wai?
No matter what, from now on
You eat yours, I eat mine,
we stay out of each other's way
Why? We're a family
Have you ever considered me family?
- You seem pissed - You bet I am
My father was the King of
Mahjong Pak Chong Fatt
And I only know it now You
see me as your family?
You've kept a lot of things from me as well
Like what, tell me
When you sat for your exam
you watched my romance
"action" videos instead of studying
and I didn't say anything
Alright, stop it
It's not that I don't want to tell you,
but you never asked
Why would I talk about these things
out of the blue
Okay, let me ask you now
Why sell yong tau foo when you can be
the King of Mahjong?
Let's grab a drumstick first before we start
Stop pretending or I'll chase you out
Once upon a time
Speak Mandarin, sit down
I thought for such an important event,
English would be more apt
English? Your English sounds like Tam
Don't try too hard
We'll have to start from 20 years ago
Hurry up
Twenty five years ago
Zhang Shun You, the Wong Tin
Ba of today, and I
Learnt mahjong together from our
Master Ru from a very young age
Five
Mine
Yours
Skip
Next
Reveal
The Thirteen Wonders
Your hand is
decided the moment the tiles are stacked
If you're not the dealer
Try to put your tiles over here
Look, they're all Bamboos
Told you…
Master always said, you win by not gambling
Winning or losing is just an illusion,
lose your money but never your life
Only the good-hearted wins
He also said,I often win because
I don't harp on winning or losing
Is it really that important,
winning or losing when playing mahjong?
You win this round,
you could well lose the next
What's the big deal
Green Dragon, Four Large Blessings
You need a single Eight Bamboo,
you have a full suit of Bamboos
You lack a tile of Green Dragon
How should I play this Green Dragon tile?
Ah Fatt, Ah You
I think it's time
So ear y? Didn't we just have our lunch?
All you think about is eating
I meant it's time you two have a duel
The winner will succeed
me as the King of Mahjong
What happens to the loser then?
He will become the junior fellow apprentice
of the King of Mahjong
Might as we be the sidekick
I didn't say anything
Alright, best of three rounds
Begin now
Five Circles
Game
- The Three Great Scholars - Wow, you're good
Wow, the Three Great Scholars
Thanks for the recognition
Alright. Self-Draw West Wind
Chicken Hand
Damn you
Why would you even win on a Chicken Hand
You like chicken that much
Do you even know how to play mahjong
Green Dragon
Game
The Thirteen Wonders
Master I've won two of the three rounds
I'm your successor, now teach me
the legendary mahjong kungfu
I'll announce who's the winner
Of course
The winner is
Ah Fatt
Why him?
That's the Thirteen Wonders right there
I didn't say the one who wins will succeed me
You're right
I knew it
No matter how I fare,
you'll always see me as the loser
- Ah You listen to me - Say no more
I've listened to you long enough
You talk all day long
I've had enough of it
From today onwards,
I'm not listening to you anymore
I'm not your discipel anymore
God brother
So that was how Wong Tin Ba left our master
And went on to challenge everyone everywhere
From India to Egypt
From Egypt to Japlan
From Japlan to the China
Challenging the Kings of
Mahjong of every region
Ninety Thousand (Nine Character)
Red Middle (Red Dragon)
Children
Two Circles
Big Four Happiness (Four
Large Blessings), game
Sensei
Get rid of the tiles that you don't need,
no point keeping them
Self-Draw
Why are you discarding your
self-drawn winning tile…
Mahjong?
Hold on
The Three Great Scholars
- After you - See you
Finally, Wong Tin Ba got what he wished for
He defeated all the best
mahjong players in the world
And even won the title of King of Mahjong
for 10 consecutive years
But one thing could never wrap my head around
You gave up the Green
Dragon tile for Wong Tin Ba
So by right he should've won
Why did your master
announce you as the window?
Later on, Master explained to me
I've lost
why did you say I won, master?
Do you think I'm a renovation contractor?
I can see
He won in the game of mahjong
But lost duel to his character
My successor must have a good character
Winning without character s meaningless
It's been days since I heard from you
where have you been?
Everywhere
Any place where I won't see a poker face
a black face and two stupid faces
I've been there
You two look very free
Why don't you go accomplany the boss
Spend some time with your dad
Don't keep avoiding him
I'll just be another black face
Doesn't make a difference
You find that funny?
Don't you?
Yes
It's really hilarious
Why did you hit me?
Hit me? You…
How dare you lay your finger
on the great Wong Tin Ba
Game, 108 Warriors of…
What are you doing?
There are mosquitos
I have such a big house
This mosquito is actually my brother
He talks to me, through h s buzzing
Now that you killed it
who's going to talk to me?
You don't talk to me
And I don't want to talk to these two
You three jump into the water
Where did Deedee Zhang go again?
Right?
There you are
Baby who's that?
Who are you?
He should know who I am
Pure Honour Hand, Four Large Blessings,
Full Blossoms
- That's 88 folds, everybody - What a big win
It's nothing
What are you doing?
Where did the extra tiles come from
Hey are you trying to cheat here?
Cheating?
Are you kidding me?
It's written here No cheating
Do you think I'm blind?
Do you think I'm stupid?
Stop mucking about,
do you know what you're talking about?
They say bringing mahjong tiles
around this year brings good luck
And you thought I'm cheating…
What took him so long
Do you know what time it is now?
Must've come from here
What's with the crowd?
Did Michele Yeoh turn up?
All the neighbours want
you to be their master
I'm number 15 in line
You people are crazy
When did I say I'm accepting disciples?
You're Pak Chong Fatt
The first ever King of Mahjong,
of course we'd like to learn from you
If you're here for the
Tofu, I'm more than happy
But if you're here to learn
mahjong, please leave
Master I've been having a bad hand in mahjong
Any tips?
That's your fate
Don't ask me how would I know?
Why are two of you
holding me down instead of standing in line?
I listen clearer
and learn more this way
My reason is simple, just want to touch you
Do it on me first
You're such a pain
Come on, teach me a few tricks
Which one of you is Pak Chong Fatt?
am, what's the matter?
- Who? - Sure y not me
It's him
You two idiots
It's me
Miss, may I know what you're doing here?
I suppose you don't remember
the King of Gai Hu?
The one whom I defeated
in the inaugural championship?
That's right, he s my father
So you're his daughter
Come and give Uncle Fatt a hug
Come on
That year
He made it to the final s against all odds
But you beat him hands down
Since then he became like that
Never to smile again
Alright, since you're here
I'll let you have vengeance
You two, go distract her
Actually, we…
Today
Let us have a due
- Hey, you - You're up
I already said I've forgotten
how to play mahjong
If you don't play, you'll get it from us
Come on, if not now then when
If you don't play,
we'll annoy the he out of you
- I'll pester you - Won't leave you alone
Come on, play with her
Alright then
Let's do this
- Four Circles - Pong
East Wind
One Circle
Pong One Circle, here's a Four Circles tile
Lucky you getting the final tile
South Wind
Want to make a Pure Hand of Circle,
watch me spoil it
Eight Circles
Pong
Nine Circles
Pong, here's a Seven Circles
Pong Seven Circles
9 Pieces Penalty, it's on you
if he were to win
I'm sorry Hidden Six Circles Kong
Self-Draw win on Replacement Tile
I must win to make my father smile again
Five Circles
Get a Self-Draw win, come on
Kong
Eight Circles
Two Character
I'll take that Two Character
I'll discard a One Character
Game
What?
You're waiting for a single tile
of One Character. Snatch her game
That's none of your business
Are you playing or am I playing?
They came so far for revenge, w nning on
a Ch cken Hand doesn't make sense
Chicken Hand, are you for real?
That's a bit too lame, don't you think?
It's called a Chicken Hand
of course it's lame
I've waited 20 years for this
I finally got my revenge
To be able to pay with a mahjong expert
like Pak Chong Fatt
Look, your father is smiling again
You shouldn't have waited
for so long for that
f you had understood this 20 years ago
You wouldn't have been upset for so long
Playing mahjong is just
a form of entertainment
When it's done, get on with it
That's a load of bull
Remember how I've taught you?
What should be done after you've lost?
What do you want?
Good manners
Thank you
Don't even think of kissing me, I'll hit you
Ramona
It really is you
Sir, have you seen my husband?
What's the matter with you?
Don't you recognise me?
I'm your husband, Ah Fatt
It can't be
My husband is very handsome
He's tall and macho
And he's very good at mahjong
Look
Take a good look at yourself
Not the chest, the tattoo
It's the same, look
This type of tattoo is so common
My husband is so handsome, so macho
But you're short and stout,
and you look so shifty
And you stink
How could you be my husband?
There are so many people here
can you cut me some slack?
But you're not my husband
I really am your husband
You're not
- I am - You're not
You leave me with no choice
But to share this with everyone
Your body anatomy s very weird
If I touch you here, you'll scream
If I touch you here, you'll get excited
If I touch your head you'll be obedient
Am I right?
Shut up
How come you know so much about me?
Because I'm your husband
- Ah Fatt? - Yes
Come on
Where is this place?
This is not a common place,
it s Brother Fatt's house
- Isn't that my house? - Yes
Nan Yang
Didn't I come from a rich household?
Come have a seat
I'll get you a drink
Sassy, we have a guest
Look who's here
Who's so important?
Take a look yourself
Hey is this your wife?
His wife? She left a long time ago
Why is your wife so bad?
That's not all, she's materialistic, greedy
- Ridiculous, shameless… - Sassy
How can you insult your mother
when she's right in front of you?
At east turn around
She's really your mother
- My mother? - My daughter
That is correct
Your mother's daughter is you…
right, that makes her your mother!
Why did you bring her home?
Don't tell me we need to
seek your permission first
This is my home, not yours
Hey you said this s my home
isn't it Ah Fatt's home?
Your home has been broken
since you left us when I was 2 years old
Stop arguing
Yes
I know this is a bit too sudden for you
It's the same for me
Did you know, when I saw her alone today
Looking for her husband on the streets
Isn't she looking for me?
But she couldn't recognise me,
even though I'm so handsome
The only thing she recognises is money anyway
Don't be fooled by her
I'm not that stupid
I brought her to the doctor, the doctor said…
Apparently a year after she left us
She lost her memory after an accident
Lost her memory?
Is this some sort of lame soap opera plot
Soap operas are indeed lame
But she really is your mother
It' hasn't been easy for her,
being alone all these years
You'll understand these matters of the heart
when you grow up
You can see for yourself
Who in the right mind eats mahjong tiles?
What? I'm hungry
You're not supposed to eat mahjong tiles
I'll cook for you if you are hungry
Let's go outside
Loss of memory?
Mom
Let me teach you how to play mahjong today
Mahjong? Is it fun?
It's okay if you don't know
Within a few days and a few losses
You'll get the hang of it
Come on
I've got no money
If I lose, I only have
my daughter to offer you
Let us restart the game,
since she just sat down
- Sure - Let's go
Eight Circles
Nine Character
Can I win now?
You don't have enough folds
Just follow whatever the others are doing
Discard that Nine Character tile
Three Character
Can I win now?
How is it possible that you still can't win
Self-Draw, game
The Thirteen Wonders
You scared the daylight out of me
I can't see through this mess
Eight-and-a-half Pairs Pure Hand
Is that a big win?
I win
Pay up
Five Bamboos
Self-Draw
Nine Gates Hand
Pay up, please
Are you sure you are crazy?
It really doesn't seem like it
Thank you
When are we going to play again?
Come earlier tomorrow,
and you can play with yourself
Who's going to play with you again
First time and we've already lost so much
Do you know how many people
I'll have to massage to learn this much
I lost my grocery money again
Girl, they are such sore losers
Ignore them, we're rich
What are you doing?
Sewing on some buttons
I saw the buttons on your father's clothes
they don't match
Every single one of them
If you really cared for him,
you wouldn't have left
I was wrong
thought could live a good life
having married the King of Mahjong
But he suddenly quit
I got angry, so I left in a fit of anger
I never thought it'd be so hard to turn back
I know you both are still mad at me
I've got nothing to say
If you really don't want to see me
I can leave any time
I'm really leaving
Take care of your father, I'm leaving
You come and go as you please
you think this is a hotel?
I've taken care of your
husband all these years
It's your turn now
One more thing
Don't be fooled by his carefree out look
He's never forgotten you
Take good care of him
It's so hot
I want to be a responsible husband
What kungfu is he practising?
Could it be the legendary mahjong kungfu?
Ah, so you've invited yourself
Drinking alcohol in broad day light
Sassy doesn't care about me anymore
What makes you say that?
She's been Ignoring me…
I think It's time to let her go
She only cares for her mom right now
What about my life? I'm hopeless
So that's what you think
You're too pessimistic
I know my daughter
Her anger is fleeting
It doesn't matter if she's angry with me
The point Is I don't have
a place in her heart
I'm not important to her
If that's the case
Then why would she have wagers with you?
Because she wants to defeat me
She wants me to back off
That silly girl
Every time she plays mahjong with you
she looks at you in a different way
Doesn't that prove that she likes you?
Remember, to be a good man…
One must not be greedy
And one must not be impatient
Even you have the lousiest hand
Don't be afraid
Sometimes, to lose is to win
Get it?
To lose is to win
I get it
Thank you
I understand now
Sassy, here I come
Most handsome guys in this world are dumb
Sister Sassy is having a
duel with Mr. Yang again
Ready,go
So fast? Let's reveal it and see
Sir, don't you know 1, 2, 3?
What are you doing?
Are you trying to be funny?
Sorry
Give me one last chance
One last chance, let's do this again
Every time she plays mahjong with you
she looks at you in a different way
Wow Sister Sassy wins again
But Mr. Yang completed his hand first
So what?
I'm pretty sure it's a mess again
Reveal
Wow Mr. Yang
You're good, you've won
Very good, you've defeated me.
Don't look for me anymore
Sassy
What do you want?
You've said before
If I want to date you,
I'll have to defeat you first
So can I ask you out on a date now
Suits you
But I'm telling you,
I have no feelings for you
Then why is It that whenever
I play mahjong with you
you always gaze at me so gently?
Rubbish
Brother Fatt told me
As long as you're the apple of my eye
and vice versa
Winning or losing isn't important at all
I…
Let's get together
Apparently when you fall for someone
You'll feel happy even when he defeats you
That's life But hey, what's wrong with that
From the moment you fell for him,
you've already lost
Brother Fatt
You're such an expert in love
So why did you break up with mom in the past?
Because of love
We went separate ways
Your mom and I grew up together
She was the girl that everyone coveted
Self-draw win, The Thirteen Wonders
Smart and pretty
Good at mahjong too
She was known as The
Queen of Thirteen Wonders
Look at her smile
Makes my heart skip a beat
We got married later on
I won the World Mahjong
Championship that year
And became the King of Mahjong
- Are you sure? - Is that necessary?
I really can't take it anymore
Ramona and I were soulmates
Since our dating days,
we enjoyed playing mahjong together
Such a lovely couple
Hubby
She was the only person who could
defeat me at the mahjong table
This Green Dragon tile is annoying me,
watch me discard it
Four Large Blessings, pay up
You knew she wanted the Green Dragon,
yet you discarded it
Men
Hubby, quick, pay up
What's going on
- She's giving birth - What's going on
Give me that
Ramona gave birth soon after
That was the happiest time of our lives
Six Circles
Sassy
Two Circles
But good times never last
Before the 2nd World Mahjong Championships
was very stressed
I was terrified of
losing my status as the world champion
At that moment
I realised playing mahjong
no longer means the same anymore
I started having second thoughts
Hubby
I've cooked some ginseng chicken
To help you become the King of Mahjong
for the 2nd time
I'm a little reluctant to go
Why?
I feel like…
Playing mahjong for the sake of competition
seems to be deviating
from its original intent
As long as you win every time
What other purpose do you need?
That's not what master taught me
I'm warning you
because I saw a bright future in you
I'm investing my youth in you
I won't allow you to give up
Ramona don't go
What's going to happen to me and Sassy
if you leave?
My husband the King of Mahjong,
is now a useless man
Why should I stay?
What will it take to make you stay?
Play a round with me
If you win, you can give
the competition a miss
If I win
you have to clinch the
World Mahjong Championship
You can't force me like this
You're the one forcing me to do this
I could've become the Queen of Mahjong
I gave up everything to marry you,
the King of Mahjong
Now you're telling me to give up my dream
Let's play a round then
White Dragon
Kong
Four Character
Red Dragon
Kong
Eight Circles
Green Dragon
Kong
Seven Bamboos
I used to let her win all the time
But this time
Ramona
Chicken Hand
I'm not that important to you after all
Little did she know that
I let her go on purpose
Although I didn't want to complete anymore
But she was still so young.
She should pursue her dreams
I didn't want to hold her back
Your wife was heartless, didn't it hurt you?
That's how youngsters are, they want glamour
Who doesn't want to be the Queen of Mahjong
Do you still love your
wife then, Brother Fatt?
Of course
Every second of my life
So handsome, let's put that on Facebook
Boss
Handsome should be one word, not two
I did it on purpose
If not, you wouldn't have come in
Boss
People are slamming you on Facebook
What are they saying?
They say handsome "should be one word"
Take that picture down immediately
Then upload other stuff to distract them
Avoid bad publicity before
the World Mahjong Championships
Okay
How do I spell surprise?
Just write it in Chinese
Good idea. Surprise
Boss, you're so wise what's the surprise?
The first ever King of Mahjong versus
the winner for 10 consecutive years
Surprising enough?
Oh Boss, so you're the
first ever King of Mahjong
Only now do I know that Pak Chong Fatt
had won't for 10 consecutive years
I've fed and clothed you two
Yet you don't even know who's who
Look at those trophies behind
use them to store my sauces
can't you see
What plans do you have?
Everything is going according to plan
I smell yong tau foo,
this should be the house
I'll take it
The Thirteen Wonders
Crazy
Can't you walk properly?
Boss, you already came in this dressing
with a bell in hand
Sure y I have to pretend to be possessed
to complement you?
Don't talk crap
You've been here for so long
why haven't you reported to me?
Have you found out
what kungfu Pak Chong
Fatt has been practising?
Yes, I found out that he doesn't
even touch mahjong
That's great
I finally have reason to sell you to Ethiopia
Just great
They suffer from famine and poverty
they won't be able to “use” me
They can't use you, but they can eat you
Your skin is slightly wrinkled
but your flesh is still quite tender
- Please, don't - Should worth a dime or two
I did find out a secret of his
What secret? Out with it
He practises a kind of kungfu everyday?
What kungfu?
Pa ms joined with eyes focused
Tongue and limbs stretched out
- Rein in the temples and diaphragm
Take in the energy of the universe
to nourish the brain
So, this is Master's Legendary Mahjong Kungfu
Who's peeping?
I get it now
If Pak Chong Fatt can master it, so can I
Let's see who's the real King of Mahjong
Your mission now is to persuade him
to join the championships
Only then will your mission be complete
Let's see how you resist my cajolement
Hubby
Let's eat first
I have something… to tell you
What do you want?
I want to say…
We're back
Dad, mom
Fill the bowl
Have they gotten married?
Last I checked, they weren't married yet
I really have something to tell you
Why not put that back to where it should be?
So much food today?
Is there some offering to the gods?
No, since your mum came back
we haven't had a sumptuous meal
Thanks to you, mom
Come let's dig in
Let's dig in
What did you want to say just now?
Nothing
I feel like we're a family
What's wrong with you?
We really are a family okay
By the way, when did you marry my daughter,
may I ask?
Last night
You marry my daughter in my room?
So handsome
Hubby
Am I interrupting your kungfu practice?
Are you sure this is related to…mahjong?
Here it comes
I can feel it
Since you left, I…
- You haven't done "it" for 20 years? - Yes
I've practised the Legendary Mahjong Kungfu
for quite some time now
You guys are practising mahjong with me today
I was afraid after not using it for so long,
it will…
That's why I…
Are you waiting for the Six and
Nine Character tiles?
You need a single Three Character tile
You want the Six and Nine
Circles tiles, right?
How do you know?
You won't feel much in the beginning
But after 49 practice sessions
Your carnal desire
will explode from within
How does it feel like?
It feels like someone opened the zoo gates
and all the elephants charging out
Boss, don't…
Boss, I'm warning you I'm very experienced
Once you start, I won't stop
What are you doing?
- Hey - You old and cheap woman
Why don't you dig a hole and bury yourself
Don't let me see you again
Sorry, boss
I was about to call you
The kungfu that Ah Fatt has been practising
isn't for mahjong
- It's for his little brother, right? - Yes
You might as well tell me after my "little
brother" is injured from overexertion?
If you can't make Pak Chong Fatt
join the championships
I'll sell you to Ethiopia
As for the gambling debts you owe me
I'll cut your fingers off one by one
That's all
Wong Tin Ba I shall remind you again
Don't say I'm long-winded
Your 10-year good fortune is coming to an end
If you want good fortune for another 10 years
You must defeat Pak Chong Fatt
at the championships this year
You're not just long-winded,
you're ridiculously long-winded
Can you turn on the heater now?
Don't tell me these vicious-looking people
are here for my yong tau foo so early?
- Hubby - Dear
It wasn't easy finding mum back with us
and now she's taken away from us again
This won't do, I must look for my mum
If it's a kidnap
why haven't we received any calls yet?
- Help - Ramona?
You recognise your wife's voice, right?
- What do you want? - So cruel
Very simple, If I see you
as one of the players in the
World Mahjong Championship
you'll see her
If I don't see you then
you won't see her for the rest of your life
- Help - Ramona?
- So? - Yeah, what now?
Brother Fatt is finally going back
to the mahjong table
Let's welcome back Brother Fatt
I'm very proud to be able to practise
and play with you
I don't know why I'm very anxious suddenly
Why? Ah Fatt, we're here to practise with you
According to the module I've designed
The first session should be…
Drawing tiles
Everybody draw your own tiles please
Draw the Thirteen Wonders
in the shortest time possible
You can't look at the tiles while drawing
- Is this the correct way? - You're good
Next, let's practise how to tabulate points
Tell me the points the
moment I reveal my hand
These are the initial tiles of a dealer
That's Four Small Blessings, totals 13 points
No, it's a so a Mixed Pure Hand,
you've got to add 3 points
So the total should be 16 points
- That's a lot of "fun" - No
If it's a dealers initial hand
it's a Heavenly Hand
A Heavenly, Mixed Pure Hand
with Four Small Blessings is 29 points
What about this one?
Four Large Blessings 13 points
Mixed Pure Hand 3 points
Triplets Hand 3 points
including the flowers is a total of 20 points
Excellent
How many points are there in this one?
Hold on, give us some time
This hand s neither here nor there
Obviously it's a Chicken Hand
Genius
- You're a gambling genius - My idol
Don't be so cliche,
we're learning from one another
I don't think you need to
practise the basics anymore
Why don't we go straight into competition
Sure
I'm so nervous
Hold it
I've never been this nervous playing mahjong
in the past decades
I'm a little apprehensive about playing
against my master today
- Dad - Brother Fatt
What's the matter with you?
- Dad - How are you feeling?
- Lie down - Thanks
It's no big deal
But I think I can t go to the competition
Why?
You were killing it in the beginning
What happened?
I wanted to win
This is what happens when
you're too eager to win
That's why I
pulled out of the second world championships
I don't play to win
With this mentality
how am I to defeat Wong Tin Ba?
Let's begin the day
Where are you going so early?
Sassy
Ah Fatt
Letter for you from Sassy
I'm eloping with Wayne Yang
Don't worry, it's just for a few days
We'll be home once we've had enough fun
So this is Sassy's final move
Ah Fatt, you've raised a daughter
with such fine character
Ah Fatt
I knew you'd come back to find me
I know Ah You all too well
Since the day I announced your victory
I knew he'd never let it go so easily
But I'm traveling the word now
You need to settle your own problems
A word of advice before I leave
You don't have much weaknesses
Except you think too much
If you weren't like that
Ramona probably wouldn't have left
Your life would've been complete
Do you remember?
I told you, the true spirit
of playing mahjong
The tiles don't determine winning or losing
The player does
The tiles are lifeless, but the player isn't
Playing mahjong is like learning
how to be a good person
If you get too caught up in winning or losing
even if you have the best hand,
it'll a I be in vain
- One Cirle - Game
The Three Great Scholars,
Triplets, Mixed Pure Hand
Green Dragon
- You're so smart - Game
You're not affected by the outcome anymore
How can you ever be defeated?
It's only after 20 years
that I began to understand this saying
Am I slow?
Luckily It's still in time
You really want to do this yourself?
I have my dad's genes,
sure y I won't come in last
And the most important thing is
I can take the opportunity to look for my mom
Ms Deedee Zhang
Welcome to the King of Mahjong Championships
- It's her? - You know each other?
I've seen her before
We meet again, isn't that fate?
So that's your type
What type? What do you mean by that?
Why would you know someone like that?
That night inbed
you said you would love me forever
Since It's none of your business
are you still trying to be a hero?
I'll whoop your ass Miss Third Party
Miss, don't be too sad
Sad?
I'm more than thrilled to see them fall apart
That's how she ruined a couple the other day
Just because she couldn't stand them
I'm the type that he likes
and he's been devoted to me all these years
What? Are you jealous?
Why are you talking to
these people in public?
Deedee Zhang
Who are you? And who are they?
Aren't you afraid of
diminishing your own status?
Why? Where did your arrogance go?
Initially there was just Wong Tin Ba
Now there's another Deedee Zhang
how are we going to win?
Are you nuts
Why are you putting
your own team down?
Dad, what are you doing?
I want to come and play mahjong here
Why are you dressed like that here?
I'm a man how can I
let my daughter battle this alone
Brother Fatt, you really are my idol
Of course
I thought you had no confidence?
Initially I didn't
Now do, or how else do we save your mum?
Dad
It's good that you're conf dent
But, the way you're dressed…
- I think it looks good - No way
The first ever King of
Mahjong must look the part
We still have time
- Let's go - Where to?
Not only do I want to win this competition
I want the two of you to make the finals
no matter what it takes
I want Pak Chong Fatt to be disgraced
in the mahjong world
I want him to hit rock bottom
Yes
Do you understand?
I've waited for this for 20 years
I'll finally have my vengeance
Hello everyone
Welcome to the 12th King of Mahjong
World Championship
- I'm your emcee, Mushroom - I'm Sea Cucumber
Not only do we have the
best of the best players this year
we also have a huge
surprise for everyone today
We have invited an
incredibly unexpected special guest
The first ever King of Mahjong
Pak Chong Fatt
Mr Pak Chong Fatt,
you're the first ever King of Mahjong
Is Wong Tin Ba the reason
you came out of retirement?
Is it because no one's been able to
defeat him in the past 10 years?
And you think you can?
Are you confident of beating him?
To be honest, in terms of playing mahjong
Can you not throw it anymore?
It looks cool, master
I know, but it hurts
Thank you
Mahjong is a form of entertainment
If you pay to win, it loses its meaning
Ah Fatt, we're here to support you and Sassy
- Give it your best shot - You can do it
Thank you
Where's Ah Lian?
She's busy doing plastic surgery
Do you think I need plastic surgery as well?
Absolutely
Let's play mahjong first
Will the inaugural King
of Mahjong pit against
the King of Mahjong of 10 consecutive years?
Today's competition is more exciting
than ever before
Relax, just relax
Okay
This is so hot, what should I do?
Just a little while more
I can't take it anymore
Give it your best shot, Ah Fatt
We're right behind you
Thanks
I didn't want to wear this coat,
it was my daughter's idea
- Understood - Good
And now, ladies and gentlemen
The champion for 10 years
in a row, Wong Tin Ba
And his daughter, Deedee Zhang
As well as his disciple, Icy
Mr. Wong Tin Ba
are you confident of reigning the throne?
Are you conf dent of
defeating Pak Chong Fatt?
Don't go, we still have questions for you
Do you think you look
good in that garbage bag?
Hello
That's him, don't take him seriously
As always
In the preliminary round,
the first contestants to score 20 points
will have their bulbs lit up
each bulb represents 2 points
They will then proceed to the next round
This process shall be repeated
until we reach the semi-finals
If no one manages to get all their bulbs lit
The highest scorer will
proceed to the next round
Three winners from the semi-finals
Will get to challenge our
10-year champion for the title
Let's kick off this year s
King of Mahjong World Championship
Heavenly Hand
Are you kidding me?
First to qualify for the
semi-finals is Ms Icy
Game, Earthly Hand
Second contestant to advance to the
semi-finals, the daughter of Wong Tin Ba
Deedee Zhang
Congratulations
Will the father and daughter
be challenging each other for the title?
Let's keep our eyes peeled
Four Large Blessings, Concealed,
Mixed Pure Hand, All Terminal
Three Hidden Treasure
Pak Chong Fatt's daughter
also made it into the semi-finals
- Congratulations Ms Sassy Bai - Sassy won
Come have a seat, Sassy
You were great
It's already the final round
Do you think Brother Fatt
will get full lights
That doesn't matter
What's important is to win
North Wind
Pong
Discarding a character
tile to lure my North Wind
Trying to draw a snake out of its hole
I can see through that
North Wind
Win
What a fine round
What a move by Pak Chong Fatt
Making the semi-finals with the highest score
He won by a hair's breadth
Ah Fatt, you were awesome
You's re so good
It wasn't a landslide win,
but you have such good skills
And what a character, I am deeply humbled
It's just a game
Pak Chong Fatt
You purposely discarded a tile
for the player with the lowest score
Good
A hypocrite, but I like
After the preliminary qualifying matches
The semi-finals will commence now
- East Wind - I'll take that
Chicken Hand
- Five Bamboos - That's right
Take the in-betweens
- Chicken Hand again
- East Wind - I'll take that
East Wind two points
Can he win like that?
It's a race between the hare and the turtle
This move is called stuffing yourself up
A few small wins make for a big win
- One Bamboo - I'll take that
Chicken Hand
Mahjong, Self-Draw three points, sorry
As expected
See I was right
- the turtle won - Mr Pak
Chong Fatt is the first
- to make it to the finals - Congratulations
Next, we shall witness
the battle of the century
You can do it
Look
She's got so many flower tiles
If she wins this round, it's a lot of points
If she makes it into the finals
She will be working against
Brother Fatt for Wong Tin Ba
I'll Jinx that.. jinx…
Self-Draw win, Pure Honour Hand,
Three Great Scholars
We jinxed the wrong one
How many points is that?
A lot, for sure
Our second finalist s Ms Icy
Congratulations
Who will be the final player
in the finals?
So nerve-wracking
But if you look at Sassy Bails and
Deedee Zhang's table
this is an inverse duel between their fathers
Brother Fatt
Ah Fatt
Go
Oh, what a klutz, Deedee Zhang
She accidentally revealed a tile
and is now disadvantaged
Luckily it's just a Formed Meld
Two Circles, Open Kong
Robbing the Kong, win
That's a Trick Hand
You were waiting for the Two Circles,
Five Circles and Eight Circles tiles
You passed up that Eight Circles just now,
and you didn't draw
How can you take the Two Circles now?
Right, according to the rules
she can't take this tile
But she's already revealed her hand,
so it's considered a Trick Hand
- Yes - We are at the last round
and it's a tie between
Deedee Zhang and Sassy Ba
Deedee's Trick Hand causes her
loss to Sassy by a hair's breadth
Sassy
That's right, she won, that's my daughter
Don't you remember what I've taught you?
Do you have polio?
You can't even hold on
to an Eight Circles tile
This is a mistake only an idiot will make
It's my mistake, but I didn't mean it
It's not whether you meant it or not
It's about how I'm going to
face the public from now on
You're my daughter, Deedee Zhang
I don't want you to be
number one in anything else
I only want you to be number one in mahjong
Since I'm such an embarassment
to you, I'll leave
You're leaving…
Who's gonna take photo
with me later when I win?
You'd ruin my perfect father image
If she really leaves
Cancel all her credit cards for me
The most exciting match
and the best of the best
is unfolding right before us
The finals of this year's
King of Mahjong Championship starts now
What's the matter?
- Are you nervous? - A little
Are you worried that you
won't draw a good hand?
Sometimes I can't get good ingredients
from the market
but I still have to cook
You can do it if you put your heart into it
Chicken Hand is also considered a win
Don't be afraid of losing just do it
Brother
Don't call me that
From now on, you'll have to call me
the King of Mahjong for 11 consecutive years
Did you eat a lot of
garlic? Your mouth stinks
He does have a better chance
Cut the crap
- I'll finish you off in
one round - Of course
Let's see what you guys have in hand
Red Dragon
Pong
Let's move in for the kill then
Red Dragon
- Green Dragon - Pong
I'll just follow your lead, Green Dragon
Why did you do that?
I told you before, learn how to
be a good person before learning mahjong
People might think you're talking about them
This is your elder show some respect
That's right, you need to respect your elders
Stop chiding your daughter
She's just following the bad example you set
It's genetics
You already have both Green and Red Dragons
Are you going to get the White Dragon too
That would be such a coincidence
Pong
Why are you so careless?
That's a Three Great
Scholars you just gave away
And you asked me to show him respect?
How would I know he has all three dragons?
And you know how much I hate those tiles
Nine Bamboos
Nothing from you?
Watch me then
East Wind
Pong East Wind
I have to be smart about this
I have to let dad Pong
- One Circle - Pong
South Wind
Pong South Wind
- Two Circles - Pong
West Wind
Pong West Wind
You'll have to cover all losses if you
were to gift her a Four Large Blessings
Three Circles
Even the blind could tell
you can't discard a North Wind tile now
Icy, prepare to Pong
How would you know?
I'm the King of Mahjong
I'll shout it out for you
Pong Two Character
She only needs another tile to win
I can't discard the North Wind
- Three Bamboos - I'll take that
How? It should be hers, not yours
Don't you know the rules?
Take it, even though it's nothing much
Four Small Blessings
Sassy
Winning (eat) with a Four
Small Blessings hand
She's devouring herself
Are you playing or is she playing?
If you're playing for real ,
she should be on her own
If you were to team up and bully her
Why don't you two share a hand
Boss can't defeat them with a single bow
That's a first in 10 years
Pak Chong Fatt is really something
What the…
I'm letting you win this round
since you're not so bright
Let's break for 15 minutes and resume later
Don't take heart, thats how he is
There will be a 15-minute
interval see you later
See you later
I realised that you're rather fidgety today
You'll raise your chest when you
hold big tiles, that's not good
Be more mindful of it
Daughter of Wong Tin Ba
Come with me, I have something to show you
Your father said
What kind of wife did Ah You marry
for him to have a such a tanned
and skinny daughter
Pak Chong Fatt is here for the championship
I have completed my
mission, where's my money?
I want it now
So little?
I've settled your gambling debts
Food and accommodation at
my house cost money, too
- What a cheapskate - Beat it
You couldn't discard the North Wind tile,
that's right
You couldn't discard any Bamboo
tiles as well, yet you did
So everything was a lie
It's not too late to realise that
You came back to find us
because he paid you to do it
That's right
I've succeeded in getting him back
into competition
after all these years
Of course I'm happy
Are you?
Of course who wouldn't
be with all this money?
What's the matter? Are you questioning me?
Dad
Mom's leaving, won't you make her stay?
Can I?
Remember to take care of yourself
Don't open your eyes so big when you're lying
Don't act cool when you're cheating
that will give you away
Aren't you mad at me?
Really?
I just want you to be happy
You knew she was lying all along?
Why didn't you say so?
Because you would leave again if I did
Wait
Alright that's enough
Look, Brother Fatt is not only God of Mahjong
he's also Casablanca
We're not young anymore
We're here for the competition, cut the drama
will you?
Mind your own business
Come on, we're not young anymore
My beloved daughter
Mom has wronged you
The first time I lay my eyes on you
I knew you were the best thing
to have ever happened to me
Can you forgive me?
- Can we proceed with
the game now? - Let's go
People think they need to be number one
What they really need is to be loved
Why isn't my father like that?
Sorry, excuse me
- We're here - Ah Fatt
isn't that a good thing?
You're enjoying this, aren't you?
Dad, mom, people are watching
I can't bear to be apart from you
Dad, mom, let's play mahjong
- Yes - We have to be apart again
I'll make this quick
You'd better,I can't bear for us to be apart
Be good
Take care of him
So handsome
Pak Chong Fatt, are you a man?
You're okay with your wife
treating you this way?
What do you know about love
Is there something wrong with your father?
Let's play
And look at your wife
She just took my money
And now she's on your side cheering you on
So unprofessional
No wonder you're married to each other
Shuffle the tiles
Seven Character
Five Circles
- In-between - Pong
Three Bamboos
I'll take that
Eight Circles
- In-between - I'll take that
Flowerless, Concealed, Sequence Hand
win with a single Eight Circles, three points
This is mere luck
You won't be lucky everyday
Whatever
- Nine Character - Pong
Six Character
- Two Circles - I'll take that
- Three Bamboos - Pong
- One Bamboo - Something to take again
Are you nuts?
All these years you've
been the King of Mahjong
Your daughter has been unhappy
Are you happy?
One has polio, one s pea-brained
Just play
- Eight Character - Pong
win
I am destined to win today
No matter whose side you're on
Do you still remember when we were young
Master told us a story
about the wind and the sun?
He's been such a dumbass since young
Six Bamboos
Eight Bamboos
Five Circles
Three Character
Dad, he has all the suits
I'm sure he's building The Thirteen Wonders
It won't be that easy
Why would Wong Tin Ba
build The Thirteen Wonders
The focus should be on the Green Dragon now
Seven Bamboos
Two Character
Everything is going so well
Pong
Don't rush it
Everyone can tell I'm waiting
for the Green Dragon tile
Yet you discarded it?
Are you out of your mind?
Because all you care
about s winning or losing
Green Dragon
I should thank you
Because of your ploy, I found my wife
And my daughter reunited with her mum
Brother
This Green Dragon is just a mahjong tile
I'll give it to you if you like
So we are really poles apart
It feels as though Pak Chong Fatt
is not a mere human being
He's like.
He is…
Right, that's him
Wukong, you want the Green Dragon tile?
I have it
It always gets in my way,
shall I give it to you?
Wukong
You're good at playing mahjong
But you have no integrity
You've won
Why don't you game?
Green Dragon
Game
The Thirteen Wonders
Do you think we had more fun playing mahjong
when we were kids
Or now?
Playing mahjong
To me, playing mahjong is
about having a good time
Winning or losing is not important
I understand now, master
Understood
I'm hungry, let's go
- I want a roasted drumstick - Sure
The winner of the 12th World
King of Mahjong Championship is
None other than our boss, Wong Tin Ba
Who else could it be, other than our boss?
Come say it with me
Wong Tin Ba! Wong Tin Ba!
Cut the crap, let's go and have a feast
Yeah, let's go
Hubby
What do you want now?
I feel very guilty, are you mad at me?
Let's not talk about this anymore
The most important thing is
for our family to stay together
That's right, you're the best
Pak Chong Fatt
What do you want?
I want to have a word with your father
If they don't sound right to you,
give me two slaps
What do you want?
I have been very worried that
I won't win again after my luck runs out
But I understand today that
As long as I have you as a brother
It's hard for me to lose
I'm not the only one you have around you
Alright, bye
Hey
Are you two going to leave just like that?
I know I was wrong to curse you with polio
But you're my daughter and I'm your dad
we're family
Let's make up, shall we
I can even give up my
tit e of King of Mahjong
Sorry
I'm sorry
You can be so gentlemanly, Dad
How can you leave just like that
Don't forget you've killed Little Mosquito
I would be left alone if you leave
Our house would become so
cold like a big fridge
You want me to freeze to death?
Stay and continue to help me
Okay?
Thank you boss
- Green Dragon, hurry up - Sassy
Nine Circles
- Be careful - Hurry up
- Two Circles - Pong
You're so stupid
There's no fool in mahjong
what matters most is to be happy, right?
- Don't scold him - One Circle
Why do the kitchens of these
rich people feel so hot?
Oh, that's because you are clinging onto me.
Food must be served on time during CNY
Didn't you say you like it
when I pretend to be a koala bear?
Brother
This is the kitchen, not the bedroom
I asked you to cook rice,
not fry rice (make love)
It's been 20 over years, I can't help myself
Speaking of which
The Legendary Kungfu that Master taught you
what was it for?
How did he know?
I think those vegetables have been overcooked
Boss
You've got mail
Brother
- Seems like it's from master - Yes
Ah Fatt, Ah You, this is your master
Excuse me, please come back
Ah Fatt, Ah You, how have you two been
- Master - First of all, congratulations
I heard you're still the King of Mahjong
I'm so proud of you, and happy for you
But nothing beats knowing you two
are on good terms again
That is great news indeed
Master is doing really great over here
I have blondes as my disciples
Business is booming
and they all call me professor
Professor
America is a democratic country
They're all very open-minded
Your master practises the
Legendary Kungfu, right
Have you been practising the great condor?
I'm not going back anymore,
it's so much better here
Remember the "great condor", Ah Fatt
Ah "Fatt"?
Not this "Fatt", I meant that "Fatt"
Alright that's all, bye
Shut it down, bye
Your turn
- Let's snap some pictures - Stand here
This is for big brother
Come on, look this way
- Sorry, master - It's okay
Remember not to tell anyone
I'm practising the Legendary Kungfu
I won't
You're practising the Legendary Kungfu
for mahjong, right?
It is the Legendary Kungfu a right,
but not for mahjong
They're for the "condor"
Condor?
Mahjong players spend a lot of time seated
which is very bad for the prostate
I get it now
Come here
Brother
You said after listening
to master's recording
You regained your confidence to play mahjong
Did master leave any message for me?
Yes or no?
If I press this button,
everything will be history
How does that make me different from a dog?
Quit horsing around Ah Fatt
You think no one knows
You listened to someone else's message
Mind your own business
Ah You won't be coming back to find me
Scared, aren't you
Screw you
How is playing mahjong a gambling addiction
It's a good form of entertainment
That's right
These people betrayed
the original intent of mahjong
They should be cursed for eternity
Punished for their atrocities
Give them 2 slaps everytime you see them
4 slaps when you see them the next time
6 slaps when you see them the third time
See…
Therefore
We have to pay mahjong
with the right attitude
Play it as a healthy form of entertainment
Play it to express your love
towards a cultural treasure
Gong Xi Fa Cai and Happy Lunar New Year
May you all be surrounded by happiness
May all your wishes come true
And you'll have everything
that your heart desires
Gong Xi Gong X
Happy Lunar New Year to everyone
Let's get rich!