I have a message
from the Shield of Light.
Remember the old ways.
Remember what you are.
Remember your traditions.
Only clan ways can save you.
The Prophecy has chosen you.
The man with you is blessed.
Police! Stop!
Please protect me.
Please protect me and the Wand.
Can you tell me your name?
My name is Tikka.
We have to leave before she comes.
Before who comes?
Jakoby?
Jakoby, who are these people?
Keep the Wand safe!
Protect the Wand.
We have to turn back.
Stop the car. Inferni!
-Inferni! Inferni!
She won't let it go!
Leilah. The traitor escaped.
She has your Wand.
Please, sir.
Tell me what happened.
-Tell me.
Cops started shooting at each other,
and a black cop killed them all.
He left with an Orc cop and an Elf girl.
-An Elf?
They're coming for the Wand.
Inferni! She wants her Wand.
Traitor.
An unblooded Orc.
Grew up with humans. Never had a hand
raised for him in respect.
Playing the nice guy.
Where is the Wand?
Roundtooth.
False Orc.
Unblooded coward.
Where is the Wand?
What-- What Wand?
Kill them!
Why are you waiting?
Father... I know him.
He helped me escape from the police.
This is a Prophecy, for he has risen.
I sit before you, Lord of Darkness.
Serving your will is my honor.
I will return you to this world.
Come home.
Please, come home.
I can't go back.
Dream with me again.
What you love is broken, rotten.
So just shut up and kill me.