Mott the Hoople
and the game of Life
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Andy Kaufman
and the wrestling match
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Monopoly, Twenty-one
Checkers and Chess
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Mr. Fred Blassie
in a breakfast mess
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Now, Andy, did you hear
about this one
Tell me, are you locked
in the punch
Hey, Andy
are you goofing on Elvis
Hey, baby
Are we losing touch
If you believed
They put a man on the moon
Man on the moon
If you believe
There 's nothing
up his sleeve
- Then nothing is cool
- Nothing
If you believed
They put a man on the moon
Man on the moon
If you believe
There 's nothing
up his sleeve
- Then nothing is cool
- Nothing
If you believed
They put a man on the moon
Man on the moon
If you believe
There 's nothing
up his sleeve
- Then nothing is cool
- Nothing
I watch the stars
fall silent
From your eyes
All the sights
that I have seen
I can't believe
that I believed
I wish that you could see
There's a new planet
in the solar system
There is nothing
up my sleeve
I'm pushin' an elephant
up the stairs
I'm tossin' up punch lines
that were never there
Over my shoulder
a piano falls
Crashing to the ground
I'm breaking through
I'm bending spoons
I'm keepin' flowers
in full bloom
I'm looking for answers
from the great beyond
I want the hummingbirds
The dancing bears
Sweetest dreams of you
And look into the stars
And look into
the moon
I'm pushing an elephant
up the stairs
I'm tossing up punch lines
that were never there
Over my shoulder
a piano falls
Crashing to the ground
I'm breaking through
I'm bending spoons
I'm keeping flowers
in full bloom
I'm looking for answers
from the great beyond
I'm breaking through
I'm bending spoons
I'm keeping flowers
in full bloom
I'm looking for answers
from the great
Answers from the great
Answers
I'm breaking through
I'm bending spoons
I'm keeping flowers
in full bloom
I'm looking for answers
from the great beyond
I'm breaking through
I'm bending spoons
I'm keeping flowers
in full bloom
I'm looking for answers
from the great
Answers from the great
Answers
Well, it 's time
To say
Good-bye
It's been good
Having you
So near
Although
I've got to leave
It 's the end
I'll always be stayin'
Right here
So, all my friends
good-bye
It's just about that time
Wish that I could do
Just one more song
For you
Good-bye, everybody!
Thank you! Good night!
Good night!
Okay! Great!