Downloaded from
GlowGaze.Com
Hormones play.
Normally I say not fast,
but it is women's issues.
Why "protected?"
With fences and stuff?
She has already secured the load ...
... We're not even expecting
and you get the load no longer open.
Not at all?
Only a crack. Terrible.
-Well, sooner or later ...
Much later, yes. She has only
the top drawers addressed.
The child can only be there for as
ie 30 is, as we have a child.
It is, of course, that they are
The kid wants to protect.
You think as a woman.
-Please, that you said something.
It is a bad omen. 'S Warranty
So we just do not get child.
And grab a beer now takes centuries.
Guys!
Stockholm is nothing.
Really?
'T It looked good anyway?
What went wrong?
I have not seen anything yet,
but that rumor.
No stable scenario. Everyone knows
Sweden that you can not trust.
That leaves Japan and so us.
Not for the first time.
And Japan is almost always successful.
-Then we better do our best.
Since 1998 we have
no more mistakes made.
We know what we do, Lin.
It is somewhere in black and white.
Don't blow it, guys.
Wed not you join us in pooltje
this year? Great effort, though.
I'm just saying
that "t is important.
In '98 went to the Department of Chemistry
the fog, right?
Where do you work again? Wait ...
it reminds me so well remembered.
That is' n long weekend
if everyone is tense.
Come Monday you? I'm all
cupboards and drawers repaired again.
Are you listening?
That jerk ... why does
his picture is not on your dartboard?
So simple is not it.
Your hair ... it's blonde.
-Beautiful, huh?
That you 't really have done ...
Is not it nice?
Give me right now,
otherwise I get very insecure.
It 's wonderful. Curt Wild is fixed.
Curt will be grateful to me.
And you know me ...
That picture ... if we burn.
Not yet ...
Really, it's not his fault.
What is not?
That he fucks a student
or that he 's e-mail part?
I knew what would happen, though.
You know what this weekend
going to happen?
This.
And if Holden indeed handsome,
who knows what else happens.
That 's the last thing I am after.
If that 's, I have no sense.
I force you to nothing,
but this is not so bad.
And we
no room for?
And if I'm bored now?
-Helping them?
Soviet economic structures?
Aftermath of the ...
We go for 't and a lot more beer.
No textbooks!
-You must be faster.
Sorry ... but by row.
Beautiful!
-Is that Holden?
We're coming.
He's new here.
The most convenient
player 's team. And nice.
And very handy with his hands.
I know a certain girl, but
you're much fairer than she is.
But now I'm still wondering ...
What do you need this?
How do you get that?
Good. I do not take books.
How did you get this?
Who taught you that?
You yourself, remember?
I got it just you cheated!
Professor Bennett says just
literally everything in this book.
This must read.
Gurovsky. Much more interesting.
And Bennet does not know this ...
So ... will he heavy
impressed by you.
And you have no pants on.
Is that all?
-I can 't hope.
It's a weekend,
no evacuation.
Believe me, with everything that is,
will you be happy.
I will not complain.
My God ...
Marty!
What ails you now?
The locals drive
really careless here.
I just wanted to lose.
Want this weekend in jail? We want
'S cottage, see my cousin.
This really can not.
The police never a man to
with 'n hash pipe in his car. And why?
Such a man they fear.
They know that he sees more ...
And ... that he will harass them
with ancient facts.
Have you suddenly gray hair?
-That thing is not in there.
Such a huge bong in the RV
your father? Are you stoned or something?
Hey, man.
Dana, good thing!
Did you eat at you?
Everybody ready?
I'm ready!
Go ahead!
Everyone is gone.
Right on time.
I hope we can ride well.
It is not even on the GPS.
So small it is.
That was the intention?
To be away from it all?
No mobile reception,
no flash cameras.
Finally somewhere where they
my position can not fathom.
The point is this ...
Does the company set, Marty?
-No, she binds.
Everything is filled with concrete.
And everything is recorded,
recorded or blogged, right?
Chips in cobblestones,
so they do not get lost.
The society had to be loosened.
But we are just too busy or fearful.
I really missed your rantings.
Someday you 't agree with me.
Legitimacy, please.
Mr. Sitterson.
Mr. Hadley.
-Thank you.
What is your name?
Truman-Daniel, sir.
This is the army not. But Sitterson
is like 'madam' named.
Or "honeybun.
-It is also possible. We understand everything here?
I am fully informed.
That does not necessarily
that you are prepared.
I leave my post is not, Mr. Hadley.
-Good.
'S system is online.
Enter the target.
Let us see ...
I do not want them
accept credit cards.
I think they do accept
no money. They come to barter.
Holden?
-I think no ...
Has anyone invited?
There is still "CLOSED"?
We wanted to refuel.
Does that pump?
If you know how to get him to operate.
We also wanted to ask for directions.
-We are looking ... what's it?
Tillerman Road.
Is it this way?
Tillerman Road goes uphill.
And dead ends at the hut of Buckner.
My cousin has it 's house purchased.
There is a mountain tunnel, and a lake.
That hut Buckner.
Which is quite often for sale.
You have known the owners?
-Yes, but not the first.
I have seen many come and go.
I've lived here since the war.
Which war?
-You know very well!
Had that sometimes something that Civil War
to make North against South?
Brother vs. brother? That war?
Will you take me the piss, boy?
-You were rude to my girlfriend.
That whore?
Pardon?
-We have enough petrol.
Enough to get there.
How you come back,
is your problem.
Good luck with your business.
Soon also stop 'n train here.
Maybe you even get asphalt.
Asshole ...
Guys, look.
This should 't be.
My God, it's ... wonderful.
A spider and I sleep in the car.
I'm serious.
Help me out here.
Fantastic.
- 'T Do something.
Shoot your such a raccoon for supper?
-Then I make a pet of his fur.
Everyone dress; about 1 0
minute we go to the lake.
I did not know we sporty
were doing.
Do not think so ...
That can not ...
This is really happening.
Wait!
You're kidding ...
-Scary ...
There were other times, people had
make their own interrogation rooms.
From whom did your cousin bought this?
-Let's check the other rooms also.
For Marty sees us like to rant.
I will not even hear.
-Do not be silly, Curt.
Shall we swap rooms?
Not that I'm ... I hang 't painting
come back, but would you rather trade?
Sure, yes.
Thank you so politely.
That 's the least I can do,
Now Curt and Jules us to connect.
Very subtly they are not.
-I'm flattered and I love 't stop.
I'm looking for ... oh no,
I'm glad you're not a creep.
Do not jump to conclusions,
because I doubted pretty.
Severe doubt, torn
between two opinions.
So you suffer severe pain?
-Pretty.
Jules is studying medicine.
Talk to her.
Do not think so ...
I like my room.
Everyone in position.
The cameras run.
There is a change of the room.
Polk is now in 2, McCrea in 4.
Confirm that you are here?
'T scenario has changed.
Miss Lin?
We have the results within.
Loudens blood levels are good.
We recommend Rhohyptase to 50mg,
her libido.
We do.
-Through the grille, or orally?
Ask that again, but slower.
-Boar.
Guess how her responses slow?
-No idea.
The color rinse.
-The dumb blonde. Very ingenious.
Through the blood and hair.
Very gradually.
The Chemistry Department is doing a fine job.
-Seeing is believing.
Central?
-Go ahead.
The man 's petrol station on line 2.
-Could you take a message?
Well, he insists rather on.
-Absolutely not.
I am frankly crazy 'm
-Well, connect on.
Mordecai, how you doin?
What's up with you again?
The lambs are inside.
Ready for slaughter.
You do good work.
GlowGaze.Com
View by appointment; good work
so far. We still talk to you, okay?
They see the coming horrors not
arrive. They are all deaf.
They are God's fools.
So does it work it is.
Remove them and clean the world
their ignorance and sin.
Leave them bathed in the crimson ...
I stand on the speaker?
Absolutely not. On the speaker?
I would never do.
Welwaar, I can hear the echo.
God, you're right.
Wait, I'm getting you off.
That is rude.
I do not know who's listening.
You're off.
-Thank you.
Listen to me, boy.
Not everything is according to 't gone booklet.
The fool did the spell almost
failure by his impudence.
The ancients see everything.
And they will not ...
I am still on the speaker, right?
My God ... Mordecai.
Well I do 't again.
Mordy?
And what is gonna happen?
That's cold!
How cold? Is it worth the trouble?
Come on, Jules. You must risk
courage to take.
I'll stay here but
in the sun.
What is that?
-What?
In the lake there.
Oh, stop it.
-I mean it ... over there.
That seems to be my friend!
There is something else 's more!
'N Attractive man!
-I kill you!
No, we are an endangered
species!
Last chance. We begin as so
put your money into. "Can t just.
Who's not Going?
'S Watching: We have Engineering,
Design and Electronics.
Those are beautiful lose their money.
Do you say, Aqua Man.
Why?
-Nothing ...
Well then, I wonder
or that there is between.
According to the Department of Zoology is.
-They can not know.
Who are you betting?
They have been forgiven.
Who then?
-Maintenance Department.
They choose the same every year.
Pity. If they were creative, did
they do not care. Would you trade?
I do not know. What do you think?
-I want this particular call.
Wed're not coming?
-Not me, thank you.
This seems rather cruel, right?
Ah, they blow off some steam.
This job is no piece of cake,
also how they behave.
Does the director ... what is
going down?
So what? As long as everything goes well above
and those kids do what they said.
Then the outcome is fixed.
How can you gamble when you
controlled the outcome?
We bring them to the basement.
Furthermore, 't to them.
They make the choice of free will.
Otherwise the system.
As our informant: he bears some
'N sign around his neck with "You Are Dead'.
Why is he there?
By the system.
They can ignore him, and they can
choose what happens in the basement.
We manipulate a lot, but if they
still make the wrong choice ...
Then they are not punished.
What is' t, Truman? You in?
Never mind.
We go for it!
The stakes are closed.
Then the party begin!
'T party begin!
My turn.
Truth or Dare?
- Make it 'Dare'
I dare you to kiss with tongue ...
-Tell me Dana.
That ... moose there.
Marty, have you ever
'N moose seen?
Whatever that beast is.
-That's a wolf.
I'm popping high,
Leave me alone.
I challenge you to tongue kiss
with the wolf.
No problem.
Who?
I?
I am new to the neighborhood.
How did you know?
How sweet of you to say.
I 've just recently painted.
You do not have to blow down.
I leave you so called within.
Thank you.
And now ...
... Dana.
- 'Truth'.
What does that mean?
I skip a step on.
You're called 'dare' to say.
Then she challenges you from doing something nasty,
and then scratch your back again.
Really?
Okay, Jules ... 'Dare'
What was that?
The cellar door.
That must have been the wind.
And where it refers to?
What would be down there?
Why study it not?
Dana?
I challenge you.
How long should I stay here?
Until tomorrow morning.
Dana?
Are you okay?
I was shocked.
You called 'help'. So you lose.
Take off your shirt.
What? I'm not making the rules.
My God ...
Do you see that shit ...
Guys?
I do not know 't so smart
here below in order to be.
Guys?
Cousin who loves you, strange
hobbies after.
I do not think this is his.
Maybe those same people
such as those of the mirror.
Some things seem to be very old.
-Superb ...
Maybe we should
but go back up.
I challenge you
to go up.
Guys?
Listen.
'4 April ... Father was angry with me
and said that I missed the true faith. "
'Could I prove my devotion but, as
Judah and Matthew in which people do. "
What is that?
'S Diary of Anna Patience
Buckner, 1903.
"Mama cried almost all night long."
"I prayed, but she held until when dad
hair cut open and stuffed her in the coal. "
"Judah told him that Matthew
Black Chamber spent. So he's dead. "
"I want the glory of the pain
understand, like Matthew ... "
'... But by in' t meat to be cut receives
he has an erection, and I can not. "
Do you want to stop?
-Continue.
Why?
-I want to know.
"I will not yet found in the old
books, to protect our family. "
"My schrijfarm is maimed and half
eaten, so hopefully this is readable.
"So there is a believer
and this read aloud ... "
"... So we will be resurrected
and the great pain will return. "
Here is something in Latin.
Okay, here I draw the line.
That you should not read Latin.
Read it ...
What was that?
- ... Out loud.
"Dolor ..."
Do not be so childish.
It's only a diary.
-It means nothing.
"Dolor vivo super caro ..."
"... Dolor Sublimis caro."
"Dolor ignio annivos ..."
We have a winner!
The Buckner family!
The Buck Fasteners grab the prize.
Then our congratulations
to the Maintenance Department.
The pot must share
Ronald, the trainee.
That is unfair.
I also had zombies.
You had indeed zombies, yes. But
This is' Zombie Redneck Family Martel.
A sort itself. The same difference
as between a lion and a sea lion.
Better luck next year.
They seem like a nightmare to come.
No. They are the nightmare itself.
Everything in our cells are remnants
of the ancient world ...
Thanks ... you know who.
Monsters ... magic ... gods.
You get used to.
Would it have to?
Sorry, man.
-He had the shell in his hands.
Who knows what about a couple
minutes was done?
I will never
'N merman see.
Be happy. Those things are
deterrent.
And clean up their mess
is a nightmare.
Okay, so the Buck Fasteners.
They are perhaps a bunch
sadistic, retarded zombies ...
But they are ... our sadistic,
retarded zombies.
With a guaranteed January 00%. score.
-That is true. Should we call Japan?
That she spent the rest of 't take weekend off?
-What did you think? Japanese who do not work?
I want once they see their bill go.
-If that could ...
But everyone except the Japanese
fails. There is too much from here.
Class, you know.
-Like you would not want this.
Can we're talking about something else?
Do you feel lonely, Marty?
Marty and I went together
as a freshman.
We once kissed.
I have never bought that ring.
But we are still ...
... Close.
I have about a theory.
Then we can pack.
Tommy Chong has a theory.
Go ahead, honey.
Tell 't that nerd but, if he' s not
too busy with Dana to deflower.
Jules, would not you rather lie down?
That is exactly the intention. Come on!
Comma-Deer me that.
That way, baby.
Do you really believe there is nothing strange
is going on?
'N Conspiracy?
As everyone behaves.
Why does Jules suddenly so stupid?
And since when Curt behaves
himself as the alpha male?
He studied sociology.
'N Academician,
and he calls his friend a nerd?
Curt's just drunk.
I have seen Curt drunk.
Jules also.
Well, perhaps it 's something else.
You do not see what you do not want to see.
Puppeteers.
Puppeteers?
What? Did you say Pop-Tart pastries?
Marty, I love you,
but you're really high.
We are not who we are.
I ga 's comic book reading.
Thank you.
"The pain transcends the flesh ..."
"The flesh will return '
or a meeting. "
What is that?
- 'T Latin that you read in the basement.
Do you speak Latin?
Not good. Not since
high school.
Funny how everything comes back.
It is also 'n strange evening.
Sorry about tonight. Everyone ...
I lose points if I say
that I was good entertainment?
It's okay to say.
Why are you leaving?
Not spill over me!
-Is there now beer on your shirt?
Then you 'm off.
Not here.
Come on, honey.
We're alone.
I'm talking cold.
For example, he is again. Way!
We need to work.
I loathe you low needs.
Get out.
We have temperature control?
Am I doing.
Spread pheromones fog.
It's so dark.
Can we go inside?
Why are we here anyway?
It is romantic.
Let your boobs but me see.
Let the merchandise 's see.
Do we really watch?
-We are not alone.
The customer must be satisfied.
Do you understand what's at stake is?
And touch.
Jules!
Curt!
This sacrifice we in humility
and anxiety.
GlowGaze.Com
For the blessed peace
of your eternal slumber.
As it always was.
Nemo, wake up.
Everything is upside down.
I ga 'n walk ...
I swear I hear someone talking.
I know it almost certainly.
I ga 'n walk ...
Enough!
Say what?
What do you want?
You think I'm n puppet, huh?
That I dance n do for you!
I am the master of my own brain,
so keep it.
I ga 'n walk.
I do not want?
I've never seen?
I do not mean 'never'?
We do nothing you do not want.
He has an erection ...
I thought there would be stars.
We are left in the lurch.
Run!
Dirty bitch!
What is this?
-Are you hurt?
Is all that blood from you?
You are safe!
Where's Jules?
She is dead.
We must leave.
Dana, do not open ...
I'm not leaving here without Jules.
-That girl is dead there!
Dana, come on!
What is that thing?
There are many more.
-Anyone else?
I saw one young girl. All
of those zombies like him ...
An arm ... but she missed.
Oh, my God ... Patience.
The diary?
We must close the deal here.
-He's right.
From room to room. We barricade
every window and every door.
We take no risks. What is also
happens, we should stick together.
Calm. Look how the master
this approach.
This is not right.
-What is it?
This is not good.
We have split.
Then we can work more efficiently.
Good idea.
Really?
Guys, get your room.
Connect them but.
Now what the hell ...
What the what?
This is not good.
-Move!
Department of Chemistry. I have 500cc
Thorazine needed in room 3.
Wait a minute.
Judah Bruckner shoot us all to help.
What ... the hell ...
My God,
I'm in 's reality TV show.
My parents will me
like a drug user to see.
Help me!
'T is permanently exciting down there.
-Greatest Show on Earth.
Come on!
Use the bed!
Holden?
It's empty.
-Go ahead.
Curt?
-Close the door of the castle.
Go to the basement!
This is the Black Chamber.
Enjoyed it.
From 's diary.
Here are the people slain.
And he will kill us.
Absolutely not.
He will not murder.
We just have 'n door search.
Check the walls, right?
Curt?
A ...
Do you like pain?
How does that feel?
Fucking zombies. Previously it was still just
A girl in 'n volcano throwing.
How old do you think I am?
Come!
Where is Marty?
-They have 'm
The evil is defeated.
Now living Kiko's spirit continues
in the happy frog.
Fuck you!
Val all but dead!
See this?
-Perfect score, eh?
That had the Japs have to finish.
How difficult is it to 9-year olds to kill?
-Nobody slain. Total failure.
If you want something good,
should you do it American style do.
Heard from below?
Japan-leave them cold. They trust us.
Do your work, Lin. While they
celebrate, we store increases.
And that weed then? He hears crackling high
, but he had us almost through.
We had to be even more strengthened.
The camper is on the way to the tunnel.
That jerk is dead. And we also
if we do not control.
Shit ...
-Why?
I have work to do.
You are our last hope.
If the ancients awakening ...
There is no blockade.
That cunt tunnel is open!
Checking for demolition.
- We can not reach it.
Try to go around.
-I am busy.
Open the door.
Move! Make room!
What is happening?
-No idea. There had to be current.
That tunnel had to be inflated.
- 'T Command has never come through.
There!
Hadley, what happens?
Why is the tunnel
not inflated?
That can not fuck!
This may not be true ...
That's it.
We climb stuff? Ropes?
-At home, yes.
Return never succeed.
What do we do now? Jumping?
What?
Curt, do you sure?
-I have bigger jumps.
With a good run, you may have
1 ½ meter margin on the other side.
But at full speed.
Curt?
You stay in the camper.
I should get help.
And if I fall, I hop to help.
But I come back here.
I'll be back with police
and helicopters ...
And ... big guns, and those things
will pay.
For Jules.
Do you not.
Never.
Curt!
He hit something. But what then?
Puppeteers ...
Marty was right.
Ga in the camper.
Dana!
Marty was right.
You go back.
-I go through it.
There's gotta be another way. 'N Way Out.
-Probably not.
There must be something happening;
it is undoubtedly wrong.
Then let the road but
behind us.
We go into the forest and go
than on foot.
You got it not.
Lettuce's not quite through, huh?
You're all I have left.
'T Not much.
I want you continues to be governed.
Whatever happens ...
Damn, that nothing was wrong.
-That was a photo finish, yes.
I do not understand.
Do you have something to celebrate?
They do, I'm drinking.
But she's still alive. Then it is ritual
still not complete?
The death of the virgin
optional ...
... What matters,
is that they must suffer.
And she did.
So strange, I almost hope that she gets up.
She has so much perseverance.
And you think they all hurt ...
.. Tequila is my mistress!
Come inside.
You are welcome.
Tequila brings light ...
in the darkness!
GlowGaze.Com
I wish I could what you can.
It is truly masterful.
Alas, it was nice tonight.
What? This was a classic.
When that truck went into the lake ...
I screamed. That flowing in
water, zombies ...
But it was even cooler was
with a merman.
We get 'n overtime bonus?
-An acquired accounting questions.
I know 't answer al
-I am an intern.
I get no overtime anyway.
Funny that you love loves ballet,
because I happen to 2 tickets ...
Idiots ... I got some
a heart attack of that tunnel.
That was not our fault. We have
never been commissioned.
I am to you but rods.
Come here.
That was not our fault.
Technical fault. lets with
'S power failure there.
Why 'up there? "
Put that fucking music.
Can not, everything went
according to 't book.
The virgin is the only one ...
No, I do not doubt you.
Who?
Marty?
Dana, come on.
Marty, wait.
Are we in the grave?
Dana, come on!
What is this?
The guy I had
into pieces.
Zaal What have you been up to?
Furthermore, no one, huh?
What I thought
You had it much earlier on.
Not at all.
But I just know
certain things.
Like, uh ...
That's a lift.
Someone has zombies
sent to us.
There are no buttons, but
cables. So we can down.
Do we want that?
Where should we go?
Step inside.
Come on!
Fucking zombie arm ...
We have chosen ...
What?
Damn!
In the basement.
When we sat with that stuff
fooling around, they forced us to choose.
To choose how we would die.
We saw them go through the tomb entrance.
The Internal Security can ...
Forget the protocol!
Are you crazy?
That sucker! Not the girl. When he
remains, all is lost. He first.
They seem to show a stock pot to have
missed. That shit made'm stuck immune.
Does that help us now? If his death
confirmed, make your hair off.
There!
Cell 3606.
Gotcha.
Get them on down.
Step off the elevator!
Why do you want to kill us?
Step-out! Only the girl.
Just me?
-Come on!
Nicely done, zombie arm.
You're supposed to be here.
This was very different to walk.
And last be faster.
I can your pain and confusion
hard to imagine, but realize this:
What happens to you ...,
part of something bigger.
Parents than anything you can imagine.
You've seen horrors.
'S Army of nightmarish creatures.
But they are nothing compared to what
preceded it. What lurks underground.
It is our job the Ancients
satisfaction.
And you serve as a sacrifice,
in their honor.
Forgive us.
And now let this be handled expeditiously.
Go inside.
Nightmarish creatures, eh?
Let the party begin.
Cease fire!
Oh, shit ...
Forward!
Commander Truman for High Command:
We need backup. Code Black!
Where are you located?
Sector 12, no function. Sector 8,
inoperative. And Division 3!
Why does not the defense?
Where's the gas?
Slightly, the compound in the shaft
bitten.
What then?
-Something horrible!
The north exit
is blocked.
Then go!
Our time is running out!
-I try 's system to unlock!
Hadley!
No, huh ...
You're 't.
No, please ...
Kill him.
Dana, come on.
Skips' t be easier.
Look's good.
Five pieces.
Who or what are they?
That's us.
I 't even have to see.
This is part 'n ritual.
- 'N Ritual sacrifice?
Enjoyed it.
You tie someone 's stone,
up 'n good knife and a bunch of robes.
Is that so complicated?
-No, it is simple.
But we can not just death.
They want to see us be punished.
Punished for what?
For your youth.
In every culture is different. And the
has changed over the years ...
But the youth was always ...
in the game.
There must be at least five.
The whore ...
... Depraved.
And dies first.
The athlete.
The student.
The fool.
All will suffer and die under the
basis of the sample that they are calling ...
Then ... one remains alive
or death, as fate decides.
The virgin.
I?
Virgin?
We make do with what
we have.
But if it fails?
Then they rise.
-Who?
What's under us?
The ancients. The gods who once
prevailed over the earth.
As long as they accept our sacrifices,
they remain below.
But the other rituals failed.
The sun rises about 8 minutes. As
you still live, the world perishes.
Maybe it should be.
If you must kill people to survive,
is it perhaps about time for a change?
We have not it
about change.
But the painful death
of every human soul.
Including you.
You can die with them ...
For them ... or you can die.
That sounds both so tempting.
The whole world, Marty.
-She is in your hands, Dana.
There is no other option.
You must be strong.
Dana ...
... You feel strong?
I'm sorry.
Me too.
Marty ...
Marty!
Do you ...
I think Curt has ...
not even have a cousin.
How are you?
I'm dying.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry that I you
almost shot.
I had it fixed not dared.
I understand it completely.
Sorry that weerwolfje attacked
and therefore, the world will end.
You were right.
Oh, the humanity ...
'T is time for someone else
even have a chance.
Giant, evil gods.
I had seen them so happy.
-I know.
That would be a fun weekend
have been.
For more new Movies visit
GlowGaze.Com