[Phonograph Needle
Scratching Record]
##
[Pencil Scratching On Paper]
[Man] Al right, you chipmunks.
Ready to sing your song?
- [Chipmunk] I'I say we are!
- [Chipmunk #2] Yeah. Let's sing it now.
- [Man] Okay, Simon?
- [Simon] Okay.
- Okay, Theodore?
- [Theodore] Okay.
Okay, Alvin?
Alvin?
- [Screaming] Alvin!
- [Alvin] Okay!
[Chipmunks]
#Christmas, Christmas time is near#
#Time for toys
and time for cheer#
#We've been good
but we can't last #
#Hurry, Christmas
Hurry fast #
#Want a plane
that loops the loop #
#Me, I want a hula hoop #
#We can hardly
stand the wait #
#Please, Christmas
Don't be late ##
[ Bel Ringing]
[Woman]
You wanna be Atticus Finch.
- Oh, that makes me feel so good!
- I like him.
- Why?
- Well, he's honest.
- Yes.
- He-He stands up for the right thing.
- And-And he's a good father.
- He is.
- All by himself. All by himself.
- Did what all by himself?
- Raised his kids.
He didn't raise them by himself!
Excuse me, who was the woman...
- that came to their house every day?
- Calpurnia.
- Calpurnia. He remembered!
- And what about Boo?
What about Boo?
I think that Boo Radley...
is one of the most interesting
characters in To Kil A Mockingbird.
- Excuse me. I'm a teacher.
- Huh?
Xmas is not a word
in the English language.
It's either "Merry Christmas"
or "Happy Holidays."
Oh. Thank you.
Sure.
- Mom. Tell me more about Livia.
- She killed everybody off...
so her son Tiberius could inherit
the throne... just like Nixon.
[Exhales]
[Mom] Shakespeare... Like those plays
we went to see at the Old Globe.
- [Clattering]
- Anita?
Hey, Mom.
- Want somethin' to eat?
- Oh, no, thanks. I already ate.
- Are you sure? I made soy cutlets.
- I'm fine. I already ate.
Wait.
You've been kissing.
- No, I haven't. No, I haven't.
- Yes, you have. Yes, you have.
- I can tell.
- You can't tell.
Not only can I tell,
I know who it is. It's Darryl.
What you got under your coat?
It's unfair that we can't
listen to our music.
It's because it is about drugs
and promiscuous sex.
Simon and Garfunkel is poetry.
Yes, it is the poetry
of drugs and promiscuous sex.
Honey, they're on pot.
First, it was butter. Then it was sugar
and white flour...
bacon, eggs, bologna...
rock 'n'rol, motorcycles... then, it was
celebrating Christmas in September...
when you knew
it wouldn't be commercialized.
- What else are you gonna ban?
- Honey, you want to rebel
against knowledge.
I'm trying to give you the Cliff Notes
on how to live life in this world.
We're like
nobody else I know!
I am a college professor.
Why can't I teach my own kids?
- Use me!
- Darryl says that you use
knowledge to keep me down.
He says I'm a "yes"person and you are
trying to raise us in a "no"environment.
Well, clearly "no" is a word
Darryl doesn't hear much.
I can't live here! I hate you!
Even Wiliam hates you.
- I don't hate her.
- You do hate her.
You don't even know the truth.
- Sweetheart, don't be a drama queen.
- Feck you!
- Hey!
- This is a house of lies!
- [Door Slamming]
- [Softly] There it is.
- Your sister used the "f" word.
- I think she said "feck."
- What's the difference?
- The letter "U."
## [Piano]
## [Drums]
#Oogum, oogum, boogum, boogum #
#Boogum now baby
You're casting your spel on me #
#And I say, oogum, oogum
boogum, boogum, boogum now #
#Baby, you're casting
your spel on me #
#You've got me doin'
funny things like a clown #
#Just look at me #
- ## [Fades]
- Are you realy in our grade?
- Yeah.
- Hey, guys, check it out.
William doesn't have any pubes.
- How old are you, man?
- He's not a man.
- He's a little baby kid.
- Bet he doesn't even get zits yet.
Everyone has hair.
What's wrong with you?
- [ Boy #1] Pipsqueak!
- What's your age, man?
- [ Boy #3] How old are you?
- You're pathetic!
Where are your pubes?
I had 'em.
I shaved 'em off.
[Giggling]
- [Laughing]
- He's a funny guy!
See ya, pubes.
- Hey, noodle.
- Hi, guys.
Put on your seat belt.
- [Grunting] We got our annuals today.
- [Seat Belt Clicking]
- Received your annual.
- Right, received.
I look so much younger
than everyone else.
Enjoy it while you can.
Mom, it's time.
- Can this wait till we get home?
- Mom, pul over.
Tell him the truth.
Tell him how old he is.
[ Brakes Squeal Engine Stops]
- He knows how old he is.
- The other kids make fun of him
because of how young he looks.
Nobody includes him. They cal him
"The Narc"behind his back.
- They do?
- What's a narc?
- A narcotics officer.
- Well, what's wrong with that?
- [Sighs]
- Come on, you guys. It's no big deal
I'm twelve.
She skipped me a grade.
Big deal
I'm a year younger.
They're 13, I'm 12.
- Aren't I?
- I also put you in first grade
when you were five...
- and I never told you.
- So I'm how old?
Don't you realize that
this is gonna scar him forever?
Don't be Cleopatra. We have to be both
his mother and his dad.
- [Anita] You put
too much pressure on him,
- How old...
and when he rebels
in some strange and odd way...
- don't blame me.
- Am I?
I skipped you
an extra grade.
You're 11!
- Eleven?
- So you skipped fifth grade!
There's too much padding in the grades.
I taught elementary school.
Eleven?
You also skipped
kindergarten...
because I taught it
to you when you were four.
Oh.
This explains... so much.
You've robbed him
of an adolescence.
[Scoffs]
Adolescence is a marketing tool.
Honey, I know you were
expecting puberty...
but you're just gonna have to
shine it on for a little while.
Who needs a crowd?
Who put such a high premium
on being typical?
You're unique.
You're two years ahead of everybody.
Take those extra years
and do what you want.
Go to Europe for a year.
Take a look around.
See what you like.
Follow your dream.
You'I stil be the youngest lawyer
in the country.
Your dad was so proud of you.
He knew you were a predominantly
accelerated child.
What about me?
You are rebellious
and ungrateful of my love.
Well, somebody's
gotta be normal around here.
[Clicks Tongue]
Eleven.
[Anita] This song explains why
I'm leaving home to become a stewardess.
We can't talk?
We have to listen to rock music?
- [Record Needle Scratching]
- [Softly] I love you.
## [Simon and Garfunkel
Humming]
## [Continues]
#Let us be lovers #
#We'I marry our fortunes
together#
#I've got some real estate
here in my bag #
Hey, man, take good care
of her in San Francisco, man.
- [Scoffs]
- # And walked off #
#To look for America #
One day... you'll be cool.
Look under your bed.
It'll set you free.
#Michigan seems
like a dream to me now #
- Watch the plant.
- [Crushing Plant]
#It took me four days
to hitchhike from Saginaw #
- You're 1 8. I can't stop you.
- # I've gone #
- # To look for America #
- Bye.
#Laughing on the bus #
- # Playing games with the faces #
- She'll be back.
[Anita]
Ya-hoo!
Maybe not soon.
#I said, be careful
his bow tie #
#Is realy a camera #
#Toss me a cigarette, I think
there's one in my raincoat #
#We smoked the last one
an hour ago #
#So I looked at the scenery #
#She read her magazine #
#And the moon rose
over an open field ##
## [The Who, "Tommy"]
## [Guitars Continue]
## [Continues]
[Laughing]
- [Horn Honking]
- [Laughing]
[Man] Here's a theory, uh,
for you to disregard...
[Chuckles]
Completely.
Music, you know...
true music, not just rock 'n'rol...
it chooses you.
It lives in your car, or alone,
listening in your headphones...
you know, with the vast, scenic bridges
and angelic choirs in your brain.
It's a place apart from the vast,
benign lap of America.
Did you know that "The Letter"
by The Box Tops...
was a minute
and 58 seconds long?
Means nothing. Nil.
But it takes them less than two minutes
to accomplish...
whatJethro Tull takes hours
to not accomplish!
You see this?
This is fatuous, pseudo blubber!
You know, I mean,
which is fine, but...
to foist it off as art...
Or The Doors?
Jim Morrison?
- He's a drunken buffoon posing as a poet.
- I like The Doors.
Aw, give me
the Guess Who. Come on.
They got the courage to be drunken
buffoons, which makes them poetic!
It's quite an honor to have
the world's greatest rock critic...
- Yes? No.
- And editor of Creem magazine...
back home in San Diego
for a few days:
- Lester Bangs.
- Live "American Woman"?
Have you ever... The most brilliant piece
of gobbledygook ever.
Give me some
"White Light/White Heat."
Iggy Pop! Amen.
[Chuckles]
- I'll put this on. This isn't
on your playlist either.
- Lester, don't you think...
- it's a little bit early for that?
- Not for me.
Okay, that was Lester Bangs, this is
Alice Wisdom, and here is Iggy Pop.
## [Electric Guitar]
So you're the kid who's been sending me
those articles from the school newspaper.
Yeah. Yeah.
I've been doin' some stuff
for a local underground paper also.
What are you, like,
the star of your school?
- They hate me.
- You'll meet them all again...
on their long journey
to the middle.
Your writing is damn good. It's just
a shame you missed out on rock 'n' roll.
- It's over. It's over!
- Over?
You got here just in time
for the death rattle.
Last gasp.
Last grope.
- At least I'm here for that.
- Yeah, what do you type on?
Smith Corona
Galaxis Deluxe.
- And you like Lou Reed?
- The early stuff.
In his new stuff,
he's trying to be Bowie.
He should just be himself.
Yeah, but if Bowie's
doin' Lou...
and if Lou's doin' Bowie,
Lou is still doin' Lou.
If you like Lou.
- You take drugs?
- No.
Smart kid.
I used to do speed.
You know, and sometimes
a little cough syrup?
I'd stay up all night,
just writin' and writin'.
I mean, like 25 pages
of dribble...
You know, about
The Faces, or Coltrane.
- You know, just to fuckin' write.
- Mm-hmm.
All right. Uh, it's
been nice to meet ya.
- Mm-hmm.
- Keep sending me your stuff.
I can't stand here all day
talking to my many fans.
Yeah. I understand.
- Okay.
- Good-bye.
Yeah. Bye.
- Bye.
You need a ride?
No, man,
I took the bus.
You know, because once you go to L.A.,
you're gonna have friends like crazy.
But they're gonna be fake friends.
They're gonna try to corrupt you.
You got an honest face, and they're
gonna tell you everything.
But you cannot make friends
with the rock stars.
- Is it okay if l...
- If you're gonna be a true journalist...
you know,
a rock journalist...
[Mutters, Sighs]
First, you never get paid much.
But you wil get free records
from the record company.
There's just...
[Chuckles]
Fuckin' nothin' about you
that is controversial, man.
[Chuckles] God, it's gonna get ugly,
man. They're gonna buy you drinks.
You're gonna meet girls, they're gonna
fly you places for free, offer you drugs...
I know, it sounds great,
but these people are not your friends.
These are people who want you
to write sanctimonious stories...
about the genius of rock stars...
and they wil ruin
rock 'n'rol and strangle...
everything we love
about it, you know?
'Cause they're trying
to buy respectability...
for a form that is gloriously
and righteously dumb.
Now, you're smart enough
to know that.
And the day it ceases to be dumb
is the day it ceases to be real, right?
- Right.
- And then it just becomes
an industry of... cool
I'm tellin' you, you're coming along at
a very dangerous time for rock 'n' roll.
I mean, the war is over.
They won.
And 99% of what passes
for rock 'n' roll these days...
silence
is more compelling.
That's why I think you should just
turn around and go back, you know...
and be a lawyer
or something.
But I can tell from your face
that you won't.
I can give you 35 bucks.
Give me 1,000 words
on Black Sabbath.
- An assignment?
- Yeah. Yeah.
[Chuckles]
[Sighs]
Hey.
You have to make your reputation
on being honest...
and, uh...
you know, unmerciful.
Honest...
unmerciful.
If you get into a jam,
you can call me.
I stay up late.
## [Rock Guitar]
[Mom] Look at this.
An entire generation of Cinderelas...
and there's no slipper coming.
You just remember,
you wanted to be Abraham Lincoln.
You wanted to be Atticus Finch in
To Kil A Mockingbird.
You want to get high?
Lookin' to get high?
- [Groans]
- Al I have to do is listen.
- That's what Lester Bangs said.
- As long as I know this is a hobby.
I'll pick you up right here
at 11:00 sharp.
If you get lost,
use the family whistle.
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
[Crowd Laughing, Screaming]
## [Whistles]
- Don't take drugs!
- [Crowd Mocking] "Don't take drugs!"
Don't take drugs!
[Girl
Yes, Mother!
[Buzzing]
Hi. I'm William Miller.
I'm here from Creem magazine,
to interview Black Sabbath.
Not on the list.
[Girls Laughing, Chattering]
[Buzzing]
- Sir, I'm a journalist. Here's a copy...
- You're not on the list.
Go to the top of the ramp
with the other girls.
[Giggling]
[Girl
We won't bite.
What happens after I go
to the top of the ramp?
[Chattering]
- Who are you with?
- Me? I'm with myself.
No, who are you with.
What band?
Oh. I'm here to interview Black Sabbath.
I'm a journalist.
- I'm not... Not a... You know.
- You're not a what?
You're not a what?
- Not a... groupie.
- [Girls] Oh! Groupie?
We are not groupies.
This is Penny Lane, man.
Show some respect.
Groupies sleep with rock stars 'cause
they wanna be near someone famous.
We're here because of the music.
We are Band Aids.
- She ran school for Band Aids.
- We don't have intercourse
with these guys.
We support the music.
We inspire the music.
We're here...
because of the music.
Marc Bolan broke her heart, man.
It's famous.
It's a long story.
I'm retired now.
Visiting friends.
You know, she was the one
who changed everything.
She was the one who said...
"No more sex. No more exploiting
our bodies and our hearts."
- Right. Right. Right.
- Just blow jobs, and that's it.
- [Penny Lane Laughs]
- [Another Girl It's al happening!
- It's all happening!
- [Together] Mm!
- Penny!
- [Squealing]
- It's all happening!
Okay, this is
our journalist friend.
Journalist friend,
meet Polexia Aphrodisia.
Estrela Starr.
And you are...
- William Miller.
- [Car Horn Honking]
Here comes Sabbath!
Ozzy! Tony, it's us! It's us!
- [Horn Honking]
- It's me, Polexia!
## [Rock On Car Radio]
- [Garage Door Slamming]
- I think I saw Sapphire in there.
## [Rock]
Does anybody
remember laughter?
Sapphire!
[Squeals]
Come on!
[Sapphire]
Passes, girls. Come and get 'em.
- Oh, no. Not this one.
- Who brought Opie?
- Oh, he's with us.
- Top of the ramp!
- Don't go anywhere, Opie.
- I'll take care of this...
if I can.
- [Whooping]
- [Door Slams]
[Vehicle Approaching]
[Brakes Hissing]
Come on, boys.
Pick it up, will ya?
This is outrageous.
We're an hour and a half late!
[Man #2]
I'm comin', I'm comin'.
[Door Buzzer Buzzing]
- [ Banging On Door]
- [Man] Freddy!
Open up! It's Stilwater!
We're on the show!
[ Buzzing Continues]
Hi.
I'm a journalist.
I write for Creem magazine.
- Oh, the enemy. A rock writer.
- [ Buzzing Continues]
Right. Well, I'd like to interview you,
or somebody from your band.
Look, I'm sorry,
but could you please fuck off?
We play for the fans,
not the critics.
- [Man #1] Freddy!
- [ Banging, Buzzing Continue]
Russell, Jeff, Ed, Larry.
I really love your band.
I think the song "Fever Dog"...
is a big step forward
for you guys.
And you guys producing it
yourselves instead of GlynJohns...
that was
the right thing to do.
And, Russell...
Russell, the guitar sound...
is "incindiary."
L- l-Incendiary.
Way to go.
- [Jeff] Hey, man.
- [Russel] Don't stop there.
- Where are you goin'? Come back.
- I'm incendiary too, man.
I didn't mean fuck off.
- Freddy!
- Hey.
- How ya doin', buddy?
- How ya doin', Freddy? He's with us.
- Come on this way, bro.
- [Freddy] He's not on your list!
Here's a list of people
who do belong, all right?
#Take a straight
and stronger course #
- # To the corner of your life #
- [Russel] Red Dog! Hey, Red Dog.
Hey-hey! We're playin' here
tomorrow night, man.
- Yeah?
- How ya doin', brother?
- [Red Dog] Good to see you, man.
- You too.
That's the Allman Brothers Band's
number one roadie.
- [Russel] How are the guys?
- Havin' a ball, man.
Havin' a ball.
You know, when we have a party, we have
an Allman Brothers Band party, man.
Everybody's boogyin'.
Everybody's gettin' off. Like family, man.
Hey, we got these now.
- Check that out.
- [Oohing, Ahhing]
Yeah, you can taste the colors
with your mind, brother.
[Laughing]
Y'all gonna be in Maryland, right?
- Yeah.
- All right, all right.
Hey, Dickey and Gregg
send you love, brother.
Cool.
- Take it easy. See ya, man.
- Same to you, brother.
[Jeff] Some people have a hard time
explaining rock 'n'rol...
realy explain
rock 'n'rol.
Maybe Pete Townshend,
but that's okay!
Rock 'n' roll is a lifestyle...
and a way of thinking, and it's not
about money and popularity...
alhough some money
would be nice.
But it's a voice that says,
"Here I am...
and fuck you
if you can't understand me."
And one of these people
is gonna save the world.
And that means that rock 'n'rol
can save the world...
al of us together.
And the chicks are great. But what
it all comes down to is that thing.
The indefinable thing when people
catch something from your music.
What I'm talking about is...
wait, what am I talking about?
- The buzz.
- The buzz. And the chicks, the whatever...
is an offshoot
of the buzz.
Like you saying you liked "Fever Dog."
That is the fucking buzz!
#Mirage like soft blue
like lanterns below #
#To light the way gladly #
#Whether whistling
heaven's clouds disappear#
- Found you a pass.
- # Where the wind withers memory #
Thanks. I got in
with Stillwater.
Oh. Stillwater.
#Unbending never-ending
tablets of time #
#Record al the yearning #
Now, you're mysterious.
#Unfearing al - appearing
message divine ##
- How old are you?
- Eighteen.
Me too.
How old are we, really?
Seventeen.
- Me too!
- Actually, I'm 1 6.
Me too. Isn't it funny?
The truth just sounds different.
I'm 15.
What's your real name?
I'll never tell.
- The Enemy! Yes.
- Russell! Hey. Hey.
This... is Penny Lane.
Penny Lane,
Russel Hammond.
- Pleasure.
- "Penny Lane." Like the song.
Have we met?
[Joni Mitchel]
#Songs of joy and peace #
#Oh, I wish I had a river#
#I could skate away on #
#It don't snow here
Stays pretty green #
#I'm gonna make
a lot of money #
#Then I'm gonna quit
this crazy scene #
Oh. Come here, man.
I wanna tell you something.
#I could skate away on ##
It's not what you put into it.
It's what you leave out.
Listen to Marvin Gaye.
A song like
"What's Happening, Brother?"
There's a single "whoo"
at the end of the second verse.
You know that "whoo,"
that single "whoo"?
I know that "whoo."
Yeah. Whoo.
Yeah! That's what
you remember, man.
It's the little things,
the silly things.
The mistakes. There's only one of'em,
and it makes the song.
It's what you leave out.
Yeah, that's rock 'n' roll.
And you're supposed to be the enemy.
What are you, 1 8?
- Yes.
- There you go.
Still young enough to be honest.
All right. Come on.
Bring the lights down.
[Cheering, Applauding]
[Stilwater Chanting,
Singing, Indistinct]
- # Won't you get on my back
for a piggyback ride #
- Hey, get The Enemy in here.
# Get on my back
for a piggyback ride #
for a piggyback ride ##
- Whoa! San Diego!
- You ready, baby?
[Chuckling, Chattering]
- [Crowd Roaring]
- [Russel] Hel, yeah!
- [Announcer On P.A.]
Good evening, San Diego!
- Stand right over there.
Would you please welcome,
from Troy, Michigan...
Stillwater!
## [Drums]
Ow-w-w!
[Girl
Russel! I love you!
# Fever Dog #
# Scratching at my back door #
#I hear you howl
# Oh, I don't listen no more #
#Got a feeling I could taste
every hair of the fever#
- [No Audible Dialogue]
- # Dog #
#Come around again
Wel, that would be the end #
# Of the fever #
# Dog #
## [Guitar Solo]
# Scratchin' at my back door ##
- [Music Ends]
- [Cheering]
[Jeff]
Thank you!
Hey! You, uh...
You wanna come to L. A?
We'll be at
the Riot House all week.
- Riot House?
- Yeah.
The Continental Hyatt House.
It's on Sunset Strip.
Oh, yeah. Right.
Sunset Strip. Yeah.
[Sighs]
Well, tell your friend...
Miss, uh, Penny Lane,
to call me.
Tell her it ain't
California without her.
We want her around,
like last summer.
Say it just like that.
- Mm-hmm.
- Got it. Got it.
I'm under Harry Houdini.
[Chuckles]
I get it.
- Come on. Let's blow this burg!
- The Enemy!
- Come up to L.A. We'll talk some more.
- Bye!
- [Polexia] Bye, Opie.
- Later, Jeff, Polexia. See ya, Dick.
- [Dick] See ya down the line!
- Scully, Ed. See ya, Mick.
Greg.
Yeah, later, guys.
Bye, Opie.
- [Crowd Screaming]
- Bye.
Hey, Red Dog. Red Dog,
I'll see ya later, man.
"The Wheel."
"Frosty."
[Chuckles] Ainsworth. Ainsworth.
I'll see you around, man.
- Penny! Penny!
- Hey! Hey! Be cool.
Penny, you just missed Russell.
He said he's at the Riot House all week
and for you to call him.
[Chuckles]
He's under the name Harry Houdini.
- You know about the Riot House, right?
- I think I've heard of it.
Right, well, he had
a message. He said...
"Tell her it's not California without you.
We want you around, like last summer."
No! No! He said, "Tell her it ain't
California without you, we want..."
- I get the gist.
- Right. Right.
So, uh, how well do
you guys know each other?
Oh, ho-ho.
[Penny] Call me if you need a rescue.
We live in the same city.
[Chuckles]
I think I live in a different world.
- ## [Whistling]
- [Chuckling]
Speaking of the world...
I've made a decision.
- I'm gonna live in Morocco for one year.
- ## [Whistling Continues]
I need a new crowd.
Do you wanna come?
Yes. Yeah. Yeah.
- You sure?
- Ask me again.
Do you wanna come?
Yes. Yes.
- You've gotta call me.
- Okay.
## [Whistling Continues]
It's all happening.
- ## [Whistling]
- You all right?
Yeah. Yeah. Great.
[Typewriter Clacking]
[Jeff On Tape]
And it's not about money and popularity...
And the chicks
are great. Right?
[Tapping On Window]
- Hey, Darryl.
- Hey.
So, your sister's
a stewardess now.
Yeah, yeah.
She and Mom are stil sorta...
Well, I'd say...
I'd say not speaking...
but I don't know
that they ever did.
The things your sister and I
used to do inside these four walls.
That's okay. That's okay.
I don't want to know.
- It is my room now.
- We flew the friendly skies.
Okay, okay, okay.
You seem cooler.
I am... I am thinking
about going to Morocco.
Let me know if you need
a little help with your mom.
- Little may not be enough.
- Yeah, she still freaks me out.
- Yeah. Listen, um, l...
- She's famous.
Go ahead and do
whatever you were doing.
I'm just gonna
hang in here for a moment.
Okay.
[Typewriter Clacking]
I worry about drunk drivers.
Mom, I'm 15. Right?
Yes, you're 15.
And here's that money
I owe you.
Your father's favorite joke.
I don't do it as well.
No, I thought
that was pretty good.
Keep the small bills
on the outside.
- And call me if anyone gets drunk.
- I will call you...
- if anyone anywhere gets drunk.
- Good.
- And don't take drugs.
- Ha-ha, very funny. [Laughs]
See?
Sense of humor.
Funny joke.
Have fun at the dance.
- I'm glad you're making friends.
- Mom, stay.
- Okay. [Chuckles]
- Love you.
Bye.
I always tel the girls,
never take it seriously.
If you never take it seriously,
you never get hurt.
If you never get hurt,
you always have fun.
And if you ever get lonely...
you just go
to the record store...
and visit your friends.
- So, you and Russell...
- No!
Russell has a girlfriend,
and I can't even say her name.
[Rod Stewart]
#Spent some time feelin'inferior#
- [Shrieks]
- [Laughs]
- [Horn Honking]
- [Penny Yelling, Indistinct]
#Standing in front
of my mirror#
It's all happening.
I'm about to use you as protection.
These guys are with Alice Cooper.
I'm gonna pretend like I don't know them.
Penny. Hey.
Does Alice know you're here?
Oh, I'm just showing my very dear, very
wonderful friend William Miller around.
He's a very important writer.
He knows Lester Bangs.
And I'm responsible for his moral
conduct while he's abroad.
Penny Lane!
God's gift to rock 'n' roll.
I'm retired,
and don't argue with me!
- "Retired"? Again?
- Penny!
Oh, it's Reg.
That's Humble Pie's road manager.
- Hi!
- Penny, come to Portland with us, love.
- [Penny] Have we met?
- Have we met?
I've made a decision.
I'm going traveling to India...
and then I'm going
to learn to play the violin.
And then I'm going to college
for one year.
There's nothing they could teach you
in colege, darling.
- [Laughing]
- Right on.
Call Alice.
He's staying under the name Bob Hope.
I heard you were
with Russel Hammond.
[Penny]
Please. I throw the little ones back.
I lost my head.
Martin Bell's
a fucking asshole!
And I'm in love
with Jeff Bebe.
- Polexia!
- Opie?
- Are you okay?
- [Wiliam] Harry Houdini, please.
Houdini...
Harry Houdini!
- It was Sable.
- Sable, Sable.
- We had this really
great night, and he said...
- Houdini.
And I'm in love with Jeff!
I saw them on the 7 th floor.
Mr. Jimmy Page,
Mr. John PaulJones...
Mr. Robert Plant...
Mr. Robert Plant signed...
signed my T-shirt
five minutes ago.
He... Please don't smear it. Oh, gee, no,
please don't... Please don't smear it.
But five minutes ago,
he touched this pen.
- [Penny] Vic is a Zeppelin fan.
- Right, I picked that up.
He tours with them, but not,
you know, with them.
Yeah, uh, they're on
the 12th floor now, but...
- ## [Guitar]
- [Penny] There's no bigger
Zeppelin fan than Vic.
[Together]
# Please stay, I wanna hear you play #
Very dear, very close
friend of Lester Bangs...
William... Miller...
Hey, you're that comedian.
Leonard.
Blow me!
Come on, William.
Okay, time to put on
the lamp shade.
Ladies and gentlemen!
At this time, please extinguish
all smoking materials...
for the captain has turned on
the No Smoking sign.
Your seats and tray tables should be
locked and in their ful upright position.
Ee-yew!
[Speaking Poor French]
- The hell with it!
- [Crowd Cheering]
- [Penny] Play on.
- Miss Penny Lane.
Oh, thank you, thank you.
#... sooner or later#
# Because the revolution's here #
Act One, in which she pretends
she doesn't care...
about him.
Act Two, in which he pretends
he doesn't care about her...
but he goes right for her.
#We have got
to get it together#
Act Three, in which
it al plays out...
the way she planned it.
- She'I eat him alive.
- # We have got to get it together now #
- We've got to stop them.
- Stop them?
You were her excuse
for coming here.
- I need ice.
- # Lock up your streets and houses #
- # Because there's somethin'#
- Hi, man.
#In the air#
#We've got to get together
sooner or later#
[Polexia] I worry
about people using her.
'Cause she brings out the good side in
everybody else, but what do they do for her?
#Because the revolution's here #
Life kills me.
Do you have any pot?
- # And you know it's right ##
- No. Not on me.
- Do you smoke?
- No.
But, uh, l-I grow it.
Yeah. Grow it.
Funny... Um, funny...
if you were only taller and English
and rich and a guitar player...
and older.
I'd... I'd be somebody else.
Yeah. Good point.
The Enemy.
I'm always around
if you wanna talk some more.
- Okay.
- All right.
Bless me, Father,
for I may sin tonight.
- How does it end?
- What?
The story about the girl who dumps
the guy who has the ex-ex-wife?
Cals her a hundred...
Okay, five times...
and doesn't even leave
a pass in San Diego.
I mean, wake up.
I'm retired.
I never believed you, anyway.
You're too good-looking and
too talented to be trusted.
- Everybody knows that.
- You're retired like Frank Sinatra's retired.
Miss Penny Lane, let me tel you
what rock 'n'rol wil miss...
the day that you truly retire.
The way that you turn
a hotel room into a home.
The way that you pick up strays
wherever you go.
The way that you...
you know the words to every song.
Every song,
especialy the bad ones.
It's mostly the bad ones.
- That green coat in the middle of summer.
- [Ice Clinks In Glass]
The real name
that you won't reveal.
[Ice Clinks In Glass]
I could keep goin',
but my glass is full.
Damn.
- [Moans]
- [Exhales]
[Exhales]
Comin' to Arizona?
Never.
We leave Thursday morning,
9 a.m., and pack light this time.
- Jesus.
- [Laughing]
[Penny Laughing]
[Phone Ringing]
- Helo?
- [Man] Wiliam Miler?
- This is he.
- William, this is Ben Fong-Torres.
I'm the music editor
at Roling Stone magazine.
We got a couple copies of your stories
from the San Diego Door.
- Is this the same Wiliam Miler?
- [In Deep Voice] Yes, it is.
"Voice of God, howling dogs,
the spirit of rock 'n' roll."
- This is good, solid stuff, man.
- Well, thanks...
[Continues, In Deep Voice]
Uh, thanks. Thanks.
Listen, I think you should be
writing for us. Any ideas?
- Uh, how about Stillwater?
- Stillwater?
"Hard-working band makes good."
New album out, their third.
Starting to do something.
Crazy.
Let's do 3,000 words.
Join the band on the road.
We'll set up billing.
Don't let the band pay for anything.
We can only pay,
let me see, 3,000 words...
Seven hundred dollars.
All right, a grand. What's your
background? Are you a journalism major?
- Yeah.
- What college?
- [Line Clicks]
- Honey, I need you to do that thing
that fixes the garbage disposal.
Well, I certainly know how
my lady gets when you don't snap to it.
- Crazy. Crazy.
- Crazy.
- [Lester] Stilwater?
Beware, beware of
Rolling Stone magazine...
'cause they will
change your story...
they'll rewrite it, you know,
turn it into swill...
B-But besides that,
what would be wrong with it?
[Chuckles]
You got starry eyes, my friend.
Uh, look. Uh...
Do the story.
Who cares, you know?
It'll be good for ya.
Remember this: Don't do it
to make friends with people...
who are trying
to use you to, uh...
further the big business desire...
to glorify worthless
rock stars like Stillwater!
Don't let those
swil merchants rewrite you.
[Chuckles]
"Swill merchants."
- That's good.
- Yeah, swill merchants.
Now, what are you listening to?
- Stillwater.
- Stillwater? Fucking kid's doin' drugs.
[Mom] No. No. No. No. No.
No. No. No. No.
No more than four days, and give me a
phone number where you are every minute.
Cal me twice a day, and you do not
miss more than one test!
And no drugs.
Oh, this is a big mistake.
## [Alman Brothers,
"One Way Out"]
[Laughing, Chattering]
[Man]
Look at Tony the Tiger.
- [Shrieks]
- Come on, Doris, you darling
bus. You can make it.
#Ain't but one way out, baby #
#Lord, I just can't
go out the door#
- This is what I was talkin' about.
- Russell.
Excuse me. Um, I was wondering
if maybe we could...
find some time to talk
when we get to Phoenix.
I want to interview everybody separately,
and I thought we'd start with...
- just you and me.
- Absolutely.
Because I've got a thing
in a couple of days.
- What?
- Oh, it's a thing, uh...
where you go there to graduate.
School.
[Russel] I never graduated,
and look what happened.
You're here interviewing me.
No, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no.
Don't put that
in Roling Stone.
- Man, our bios say that we all graduated.
- [Laughing]
- Him with honors.
We'll figure out
something better later, okay?
Just enjoy the ride.
- Keep playing that song.
- All right, man.
I may need to stay
in your room tonight.
Russell's in a bad mood. He's very
Bob Dylan and Don't Look Back today.
- He's trying to write.
- Yeah. Sure.
- Yeah? You okay?
- Sure.
Yeah.
Could you put
a "Do not disturb" on my phone?
Here's your key.
Here's your room key.
Larry, put this on,
and that bag's in 10.
Hey, come by in a few minutes.
We'll do that interview.
- Al right?
- Sure. Sure.
Is this Mr. Miller?
- Yeah.
- You have a message from Elaine.
Your mother.
She's a handful.
- [Sapphire] I'm going crazy.
I have nowhere to stay.
- I know.
She freaked me out.
Tell her to stop.
[Sapphire]
Let them do what they do.
Penny?
Finaly, you are here.
[Sapphire]
They threw me out of my room.
- I got in a fight with Ozzy...
- I'm worried, man.
[Russel]
No, you can trust him. He's a fan.
But it's Rolling Stone.
He looks harmless...
but he does represent the magazine
that trashed "Layla," broke up Cream...
ripped every album
Led Zeppelin ever made.
Don't forget the rules, man.
This little shit is The Enemy.
He writes what he sees.
If I don't get into a room
and take a Valium...
Although, it would be cool
to be on the cover.
[Singing Along With Record]
# Offer myself to the world ##
You are going to get me
in so much trouble!
Oh, my God.
Simon Kirke from Bad Company
is by the pool
[Girls Shrieking, Giggling]
## [Rock, Faint]
[Penny Laughing]
Housekeeping.
[Russel]
Go away!
Should I come by later?
Yes. I'm in
too truthful a mood.
- Maybe that's a good thing.
- Go away!
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- [Russel] Go away!
- Don't worry. Come to
the radio interview tonight.
- 'Kay? Okay.
- Go away!
- Bye.
- So rude!
## [Guitar Solo]
## [Continues]
#Dark moon, yeah #
#Takes a fool's moon morning #
#Wel, outside my window #
#Outside my pain #
#I seen my little girl
#My sweet love thing, yeah #
The guitar and songwriting
of Russell Hammond.
The vocal stylings ofJeff"Behbay"...
"Baybay"...Jeff"Baybay"...
- "Behbay."
- Uh, Bebe.
Bebe.
"Fever Dog."
The band is Stillwater.
Watch with your mind as they materialize.
#Like my daddy once told me ##
Look at the dogs wearing the funny hats,
juggling just for you...
freaks and family.
It's Quince with Stillwater,
here, live.
It's The Night Circus.
Every minute
a baby is born somewhere.
Life. Death.
Hermetically sealed bags
of human emotion.
Bags of love.
Bags of kindness?
- [Snickering]
- How'd you all get together?
Well, not to get into a "me" thing,
but I did start the band...
some time, actually, ago, and I placed
an ad in a magazine called Peaches...
and Russell Hammond answered.
- Peaches.
- I think it was a gift
from God, actualy.
Nobody plays
like Russell Hammond.
- Aw, shit, man. Thank you.
- Shh. Shh.
Might want to hit that
delay button there, Quincy.
Quince?
- [Snores]
- [Laughing]
Now we're talkin', right?
Right? Why the fuck do you have to wait
till an interview in Arizona...
to say something nice
about me?
Why don't you say it
to my fucking face sometimes?
'Cause I tell you every time
I think you nail something.
Everybody pays you
compliments.
It's not my fucking job...
to kiss your fucking ass.
Seriously, then whose
fucking job is it...
because my ass is dying
for a kiss, man...
and I know yours is too.
Uh, it's, uh, my fucking job,
and I think you're all geniuses...
and I'd like to say
to the folks out there...
- I'd like to leave you
with this thought: Smegma.
- [Jeff] Nice.
- Felas?
- Feces.
- [Laughing]
- The name of the song...
is "Love Thing."
Your mind is starting
to take effect.
They've all come
to watch you swallow fire.
You scream...
soundlessly
on The Night Circus.
[Recording Stops]
I thought that went well.
- [Russell] Yeah.
- [Jeff] Yeah, absolutely.
[Phone Ringing]
- [Sighs] Pronto?
- May I speak with William, please?
He's still down in the bar with the band.
They just got back from the radio station.
Is this Maryann,
with the pot?
Hello?
No. This is not
Maryann with the pot.
This is Elaine.
His mother.
Could you give William
a message for me, please?
Tell him to call home immediately,
and also tell him...
I know what's going on.
All right. Okay. But I'm just gonna
say this, and I'm gonna stand by it:
You should be
really proud of him.
[Scoffing] 'Cause I know men,
and I'll bet you do too.
He respects women,
and he likes women.
And let's just pause
and appreciate a man like that.
I mean, you've created him out of
thin air, you know, you raised him right.
He's havin' a great time.
He's doin' a good job.
And, don't worry, he's still a virgin,
and we're all lookin' out for him.
You know? That's more than
I've ever even said to my own parents.
[Laughs]
So there you go.
[Chuckling Softly]
- This is the maid speaking, by the way.
- [Line Clicks]
- [Woman] Can you please hold it down?
- [Laughing, Jeering]
- Russell! So, what is it
you love about music?
- [Laughs]
Shut that thing off for a second,
and I'll tell you the truth, all right?
[Click]
Look, uh... Fuck. I trust you,
so I'm just gonna lay this right on ya.
- Just make us look cool.
- [Chuckles]
I will quote you
warmly and accurately.
Well, that's what
I'm worried about.
You see, some of us...
we got girlfriends
back home, you know?
Some of us have wives.
And some of the people
that you meet on the road...
are realy amazing people.
Like you.
Yeah. But some of the stuff
that happens, it's good for...
a few people to know about,
as opposed to, say...
[Sighs]
A million people.
- Do you understand what I'm tryin' to say?
- Yeah. Oh, y...
'Cause, see, you're dangerous.
You see everything.
Most people,
they're just waiting to talk.
But you listen.
See, I grew up with these guys,
but I can't play al that I can play.
I'm past 'em,
as musicians, but...
the more popular we get,
the bigger their houses get...
the more responsibilities,
the pressure, you know...
the harder it gets
for me to walk out on 'em.
Then you forget...
forget what it's like
to be a fan.
You hear it in bands all the time. Doesn't
sound like music anymore, you know?
Sounds like...
lifestyle maintenance
or something.
"Lifestyle maintenance."
That's...
I used to be able to hear...
the sounds of the world...
everything.
To me,
it sounded like music.
And now I don't hear it,
you know, anymore.
- Do you understand what I'm trying to say?
- Yeah.
- Help me! [Shrieking]
[Laughs]
What am I doin'?
I'm telling secrets to the one guy
you don't tell secrets to.
No. No, w-we'll, uh...
We'll do the interview
tomorrow.
- Okay.
So, tonight, it's...
- uh, friends.
- [Chuckles] Right.
We trust ya.
Larry Fellows, how would you describe
your role in Stillwater?
What is the chemical
you add to the chemistry?
I'm the bass player.
Right.
And when you take that away,
what would be missing?
Stylistically, what chemical?
The bass?
Okay.
- ## [Intro to "Love Thing"]
- [Crowd Roaring]
# Dark moon, yeah #
#Takes a fool's moon morning #
- [Buzzing]
- # Outside my window #
- [Buzzing Stops]
- # Outside my pain #
- [Crashes]
- [Music Stops]
[Feedback Humming]
[Feedback Squealing]
- [Jeff] What's going on?
- [Dick] Russell just got electrocuted!
[Booing]
Okay! Everybody, be cool!
Come on, come on.
Let's get on the bus. Let's go, let's go.
This is bullshit, man. Who's takin' care
of us? Who's responsible for the gear?
I'm gonna deal with it.
Get on the bus. Please, everyone.
- Come on. Let's go, let's go!
- Hey, cowboy.
- Hey, hey. You the manager of this band?
- Yes! That and more!
Yeah, well, you didn't finish
your full set, man.
Listen, pal
your shoddy stage setup...
- almost killed my guitarist!
- Yeah, well, you trashed
my fuckin' dressing room...
- and you didn't do your 25 minutes.
- You don't fuck with...
- my band's safety, ever!
- Well, fuck you, man.
I'm gonna report you...
to every promoter
in this country!
- I'm gonna talk to Frank Barcelona tonight!
- You don't know Frank Barcelona!
- You're a bunch of amateurs!
- Fuck off!
- You want it? You want it?
- Come on! Come on!
What do you got?
[Shouting, Indistinct]
Hey, watch the shirt, fuck!
Now I'm gonna kick your ass.
Take it easy.
Take it easy, man.
I hope you got a good lawyer.
You better make a live album, 'cause
this is your last fuckin' tour! What? What?
- [Shouting]
- What is that? What are you, Bruce Lee?
- Come on.
- Take it easy!
- [Laughing]
[Promoter]
Lock the gates! Motherfucker!
- Go through the fucking gate.
- This is your last fucking tour, man!
Lock the gates
on these fuckheads!
- Where's my goddamn cart?
- [Sapphire] Wiliam?
William?
William. William!
I forgot to tell you.
Your mom called.
She says you gotta
call home immediately.
And she says to tell you,
"I know what's going on."
So, I'll see you guys
in Topeka, okay?
[Grunts]
- [ Bus Passengers Laughing, Shouting]
- Amateurs!
You don't know who you're dealing with
here! Lock the gates!
[Laughing, Hooting]
- You wanna buy a gate?
- [All] Yeah!
[Cheering Continues]
[Manager]
You just bought a gate!
#I don't know how
I'm gonna tel you #
#I can't play
with you no more #
Hey, give that
to me, Wiliam.
Give me that!
[Gasps, Sighs, Chuckles]
- Russell, wake up.
- [Snapping Fingers]
Wake the fuck up, man.
It's a girls 'running team.
Goddamn!
Let it go, Fellows.
Let it go, buddy.
[Larry]
Dick, when do we get in to Topeka, man?
[Dick] Larry, you're a sick individual
Leave it alone.
Wake up, man. Look at al these fucking
tasty-looking high school girls.
[Dick] We can't stop the bus every time
you see a girl in shorts.
Hey. When we go to Morocco,
I think we should wear...
completely different clothes
and be completely different people.
What will our names be?
[Camera Clicks, Whirs]
What do you think of Russell?
I like him.
But that's between us.
Because I am a professional.
You should give 'em a break.
There are real problems in the band.
- Off the record.
- What problems?
Okay, I got it. Your name should be
Spencer, and mine will beJane.
- I can't keep up with you.
- Oh, no one can.
You're comin' to Cleveland, right?
Cleveland, Ohio?
Oh, no.
No, no, no,
no, no, no, no.
I have to get my interview
with Russell before Greenville.
And you've got
to help me, okay?
Here's the thing about Russel.
He's my last project.
I only do this for a very few people...
and I think
we should do it together.
Because al the guys are good,
but he could be great.
What's your real name?
Whoo!
[Dick]
Al right, let's go!
[Chattering]
Oh, it's okay.
I'm easy to forget.
Just leave me behind!
I'm only
the fucking lead singer!
Hey!
So, Ed Valencourt...
what do you love
about music?
Okay. Okay.
[Elaine] You told me you would tel me
where you were every minute.
- You told me you would
call me twice a day.
- I know!
- You told me you wouldn't miss
even one test.
- I'll be home for graduation.
- Mom...
- Where are you?
Right now, Topeka.
Then Greenville, then home.
What about graduation?
We had an agreement, William.
I'm sorry I didn't
call you yesterday.
I guess I just miss you,
and I don't understand why...
I've driven my two kids
so far away from me.
By all practical rules,
don't I get you for another three years?
- Was I not fun?
- Yes.
William!
This is Beth from Denver.
She's one of the legendary,
original Band Aids.
- She's clairvoyant!
- Oh, I can't read your mind or anything.
I mean, I pick up things
here and there.
Estrella says hi.
She says I can stay in your room.
- Sure.
- [Beth] Great!
I've got some hydroponic pot!
- Wow, your aura is really fantastic!
- [Elaine] Hey, hey!
- It's this beautiful purple color.
- [Elaine] I love you.
I missed the last thing
you said.
- Mom?
- [Beth] Your aura is purple!
- I love you.
- What?
- Purple, it's purple.
- [William] Mom, what?
- Your aura is purple.
- I miss you and I love you!
I love you.
[Chuckling]
[Chattering]
[Exhales]
All right.
Fire away. I'm ready.
Do you have to be depressed
to write a sad song?
Do you have to be in love
to write a love song?
Is the song better
if it really happened to you?
Like "Love Thing." Where did you
write that, and who is it about?
When did you get
so professional?
Gentlemen, your first
T-shirts have arrived.
[ Band Members]
Yeah! Yea-a-ah!
- Yes!
- [Whooping, Cheering]
Oh, man.
[Sighing]
It's the record company's
mistake, and they will pay.
T-shirts are gone.
Band happy, all right?
Can we just skip the vibe and go straight
to us laughing about this?
- Yeah, okay.
- Because I can see by your
face you want to get into it.
How can you tell?
I'm just one of the out-of-focus guys.
[Clicks Tongue]
Here.
Take it.
Let's take a good look at it, al right?
See, you love this T-shirt.
It lets you say
everything you want to say.
- Well, it speaks pretty loudly to me.
- It's a T-shirt.
Do you give a shit
about a T-shirt?
I'm just hungry, man. Let's just go out
and find some barbecue or somethin'.
- I'm always gonna tell you the truth.
- Are you doing coke again?
Oh, yeah!
All the time!
This is big stuff, man.
From the very beginning,
we said I'm the front man...
and you're
the guitarist with mystique.
That's the dynamic
we agreed on.
Page, Plant.
Mick, Keith.
Blackmore, Gillan.
But somehow it's al
turning around.
We have got to control
what's happening!
- There's a responsibility here.
- [Russel] Excuse me...
but didn't we all get into this
to avoid responsibility?
I can't say any more
with the writer here.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no. You can
trust him. Say what you want.
He won't write it.
Look, I work as hard,
or harder, than anybody on that stage.
You know what I do?
I connect.
I get people off!
I look for the one guy
who isn't getting off...
and I make him get off.
Actually, that you can print!
And yet, why do I
always end up feeling...
like I'm a joke to you?
Look, you want to pretend
this isn't gonna be a very big band?
Wel, it is!
You cal yourself a leader of this band...
but your direction
alowed this T-shirt...
when you allowed Dick
to manage us.
'Cause he's your friend!
Don't you see, man?
The T-shirt is everything.
All right, is it my turn now?
Because I think we should, for once...
- say what we really mean.
- Oh, this is the part where you quit!
- Right. I'm so predictable.
- Deal with it.
- And let me just say what
nobody else wants to say...
- [Screaming] What?
Your looks have
become a problem.
- [Dick] Al right, okay. Enough!
- [Scoffs]
[Dick] Break it up. Everyone out
of the room for five minutes.
[Angry Muttering]
[Shouts] Hey!
Yeah. William. Sorry.
Come on, man. Come on.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Let's go find
something real.
From here on out, I'm only interested
in what is real... real people, real feelings.
That's it. That's all I'm interested in
from here on out.
You're real.
Thanks.
You know, you know all about us,
and I don't know shit about you.
Tell me,
what's your family like?
My dad died
of a heart attack...
and my sister believes that my mom is so
intense that she had to escape our family.
They can't seem to find a way
to get through it.
I mean, they don't even
speak to each other anymore.
Plus, she gave me al her albums,
and now she's a stewardess.
[Chuckles] It's good to talk about them,
really good.
But here I am, telling secrets to the one
guy you're not supposed to tell secrets to.
Aha.
[Hooting]
You're Russell from Stillwater.
- [Warbling]
- Yeah, on my better days
I'm Russell from Stillwater.
You wanna go to a party
at my friend Aaron's house?
I know you're a big
rock star and all...
but do you want to hang with some good
people looking to have a good time?
We're just real
Topeka people, man.
No.
#I think I'd like
to go back home #
#And take it easy #
#There's a woman that
I'd like to get to know #
You too.
Thank you.
Oh, my God. Holy shit.
I grew up with that lamp shade, man.
I love this kitchen.
I fucking love this kitchen!
[Cheering]
#Everybody knows
this is nowhere ##
That's William over there.
Hey, William!
You, Aaron,
are what it's al about.
You're real.
Your room is real.
Your friends are real
Real, man.
Real, you know?
Real.
You-You're more important
than al the sily machinery.
The silly machinery.
And you know it.
In 11 years it's gonna be 1984, man.
Think about that.
- Wanna see me feed a mouse to my snake?
- Yes.
- Can I have that bitchin' belt?
- Take it.
- Thanks, man.
- Thank you, brother.
[Hooting]
Russell, we should probably
get back with the others.
- Oh, it's over, daddy.
- Hey.
There's acid in the beer
that's in the red cups.
Uh, that's mine.
Topeka.
Check it out!
Please don't give him
any more acid. Thank you.
Dick. Dick, I got him.
He's okay.
He is on acid, though.
I can't really tell.
How do you know
when it's kicked in?
I am a golden god!
- [Cheering]
- Yes, you are!
I am a golden god!
Hey, Russel, don't jump!
And you can tell
Roling Stone magazine...
that my last words...
were...
- I'm on drugs.
- [Cheering]
Russel, I think we should
work on those last words.
Okay. Oh, I got it.
I got it. I got it.
This is better.
Last words...
I dig music.
- Yeah.
- [Groaning]
I'm on drugs!
Look, just come on down,
and we'll go back to the hotel.
- Okay.
- Jump!
[Cheering, Shouting, Whistling]
[Cheering, Shouting Stop]
- Uh, he's not comin'up.
- Something's wrong.
[Young Woman]
I'I save you, Russel!
[Dick] They've been crying for you
like a bunch of whimpering pussies.
Oh, the band's over.
This is my family now.
Yeah, that's right, man.
- Definitely. It's over.
- [Young Woman] He's staying with us.
Let's just ride
on down to Greenville...
we'll listen to some great music,
we'll finish the tour...
and we'll leave those
ungrateful fools behind.
Then we'll come back here
where you'll live.
- Yeah, and he can stay in our basement.
- Yeah.
- I see what you're doing, and I like it.
- Okay, good.
- Come on.
- I got it, man.
- [Groaning] Yeah.
- I got it.
That felt kind of good, though.
Excuse me, kids.
Look at him.
He's taking notes with his eyes.
How do we know
you're not a cop? Huh?
- The Enemy! Stop fuckin' looking at me!
- Easy!
He's your guardian angel
al right?
Don't worry.
He only means half of what he says.
Which half?
Dick,just help me get my interview.
I have to go home, Dick.
Dick, I have to go home.
Look, you saved the tour, and that's
good enough for now. All right?
- Come on, big fella. Let's go.
- I hurt the flower.
Did you, man?
Did you hurt the flower? That's nice.
Come on. On the bus.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the evening is over.
We hope you al enjoyed yourselves,
and we'l see you al again in 1 97 4.
- Good evening!
- Yeah! Whoo!
# Blue jean baby #
#L.A. lady #
#Seamstress for the band #
#Balerina #
#You must have seen her#
#Dancing in the sand #
#And now she's in me #
#Always with me #
#Tiny dancer in my hand #
#Jesus freaks #
#Out in the street #
# Handing tickets out for God #
#Turning back #
# She just laughs #
#The boulevard
is not that bad #
#Piano man #
# He makes his stand #
# In the auditorium #
# Looking on #
# She sings her song #
#The words she knows
The tune she hums #
# Hold me closer, tiny dancer #
I have to go home.
#Count the headlights
on the highway #
You are home.
#Lay me down
in sheets of linen #
#You had a busy day today #
# Hold me closer, tiny dancer ##
In Carl jung's opinion, we al
have a sixth sense.Intuition.
When you meet someone and you suddenly
feel like you can't live without them.
This could be the memory of a past love
from the colective unconscious.
- Or it could just be hormones.
- [ Scattered Laughter]
I'm sorry I can't concentrate.
Rock stars have
kidnapped my son.
[Jeff ] On the whole , I'd say
most of the fuckups in the world ...
come from the brain
and not the instincts.
My whole thing is
to try and make my--
My whole thing is to try
and make my brain go away...
but I can't, except onstage.
The brain, I think, should be
a softening influence on the instincts...
but the instincts should drive...
trying to reconcile
the brain with urges...
that come out
of millions of years ago.
The way the brain
interprets these instincts...
is a heavy trip.
[ Dick ] Valencourt, are you getting
on the fucking bus, or what?
Come on, come on.
Let's get on the fucking bus.
[Jeff ]
Usualy, I'm brain...
and Russel is instincts.
[ Whooping, Shouting ]
[Jeff ] But on the days
when we're both instinct...
that's when we've made the music
people know best.
Because it's the best.
Show me any guy who ever said
he didn't want to be popular...
and I'l show you
a scared guy.
I've studied
the entire history of music.
Most of the time,
the best stuff is the popular stuff.
It's much safer to say
popularity sucks...
because that alows you
to forgive yourselfif you suck.
And I don't forgive myself.
Do you?
Lester, Rolling Stone is caling me.
I don't have my key interview.
- I don't know what to say.
Days are just going by.
- All right. Yeah, yeah.
You're flipping out.
It's good. All right.
Uh, this is how you
blow their minds.
- He's gonna ask you--
This is Ben Fong-Torres, right?
- Yeah, yeah.
He's gonna ask you how the story's going,
and this is what you do.
Tell him...
you know,
it's a think piece...
- [ Chuckling ]
- ''A think piece.''
about a mid-level band...
struggling with
their own limitations...
in the, you know,
harsh face of stardom.
- [ Chuckling ]
- ''Harsh face.''
He'll wet himself.
[ Polexia ]
Al dressed up, and no place to go.
Greenville.
I'm bored.
[ Sapphire ] It says the food here is
''hearty and adventurous. ''
[ Sapphire ]
Who hid the quaaludes from me?
I have to pee.
[ Beth ]
Wow, they're cute.
- Let's deflower the kid.
- Hmm.
Whoa. Hold on.
Hold on. Wait.
Uh, I should leave.
I think things are
going backwards for me.
Backwards?
I don't know. I just--
I thought maybe we could hang out.
You know, do some stuff back home,
like regular stuff.
Get to know each other
a little bit better...
and then I'd see you pee.
I mean, that's just
the way I usually do it.
You're one of us.
If you come to Cleveland,
Bowie's gonna be at Swingo's,
the greatest hotel in America...
and I'l introduce you to him
and his security guard, Dennis.
Don't you have
any regular friends?
Famous people are
just more interesting.
Well, I would be worried
that they were using me.
[ Sighs ]
Boy. If this was the real world--
Not that anybody's
using you. No. Hold on.
I'm not famous, but--
- Your time has come!
- Did Russell call?
- Deflower.
- Opie must die!
- Oh, no. Stop. We're talking.
- Pants him, girls.
- [ Giggling ]
- Opie must die.
No. No.
- Okay.
- No.
[ Laughing, Squealing ]
Up, up.
Guys, come on.
I have to write.
No.
[ Sapphire ]
Come on, Penny.Join us.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Sapphire ]
Take a vacation from yourself.
- Leave this up to professionals .
- [ Beth ] Don't worry, Wiliam.
I've seen the future, and this al
works out reasonably wel.
- [ Phone Ringing ]
- [ Wiliam ] Reasonably ?
[ Continues Ringing ]
Hello.
Hello. This is Ben Fong-Torres
calling from Roling Stone.
- Hi, Ben Fong-Torres from Roling Stone.
- Hello, hello.
- You have such a sexy voice.
- Hello, Ben.
William Miller,
this is your editor at Roling Stone.
- How's the story?
- Uh, I'm getting good stuff out here.
- Yeah, it sounds like it.
- Man, I need some--
[ Phone Clangs ]
Now, listen.
Get it together, man.
We're both professionals here.
I don't need to tell you this.
You're not out there to join the party.
We already have one Hunter Thompson.
You're out there to interview
and to report. You got me?
Now this isn't Creem magazine.
This is Roling Stone.
We need this story in four days.
Now, I want to know how it's shaping up.
Uh.
It's a think piece
about a mid-level band...
struggling with their own limitations
in the harsh face of stardom.
That's great.
I like what we're saying.
Let me try and get you
a thousand more words.
Now, it's in consideration
for the cover, but don't tel the band.
The cover of Roling Stone
magazine. Crazy.
- Crazy.
- [ Line Clicks ]
- Some coffee.
- Me too.
Greenville is so boring.
You know, any other city in the world ,
and you'd stil be a virgin.
- Oh, God. Oh, God.
- What?
I've never written anything more
than a few pages in my whole life.
Don't worry, baby. You will.
I gotta find Russell.
Will you take the laundry?
''Take the laundry''?
What am I to you? Huh?
Tell me. Tell me right now.
What am I to you?
Excuse me, sir.
Would you mind signing for this?
Good morning.
- Please go the fuck away!
- [ Penny ] Shh. Shh.
[ Giggling ]
Hey, man, we'l, uh,
do the interview in Cleveland.
No. No, no, no.
I can't go to Cleveland.
Come on, man.
We'll have more time there.
Don't be tense.
- Come to Cleveland.
- Come to Cleveland. Come to Cleveland.
- Come--
- I can't go to Cleveland.
Hey, can we help it
if we like having you around?
- Come to Cleveland.
- I don't wanna go to Cleveland!
Okay? I want to go home.
[ Russel ]
That's good, man. I like it when you yel.
But I'm not gonna let you miss out
on the rock mecca of the Midwest.
- [ Penny Whispers ] Rock mecca.
- Hey, you're with us.
Rock 'n' roll?
- [ Penny ] Rock...
- And roll.
- It's all--
- I know. I know.
It's all happening.
#I'm waiting for the man #
- How ya doin'?
- Hi.
Oh, my God!
It's Stillwater!
Hi, welcome to Swingo's Celebrity Inn.
You must be Stillwater.
''Memory of a Free Festival,''
''Wild-Eyed Boy of Freecloud.''
I mean, those are vintage Bowie,
you know?
I mean, the new stuff,
Ziggy Stardust is good, but it's--
It's mass media, you know?
It's hamburgers for the apocalypse.
[ Shouting ]
It's Bowie! Bowie!
Bowie!
[ Trilling ]
Ai-yi-yi!
#Here he comes
He's al dressed in black #
#P.R. shoes
and a big straw hat ##
Okay. All right.
That's doubles.
jeff and Russel are
the figureheads of the band...
but I think the true Stillwater fan,
your absolute Stillwater fan...
knows that the purity, the essence,
the core of Stillwater's music...
comes from
''Silent'' Ed Vallencourt.
[ Wiliam ] Hi, Mom. I'm gonna
fly back Monday morning.
No, no, no, no.
I'll only miss one test.
I'll be back for graduation.
[ Russell ] Tell her
you're a slave to the groove.
Um, lis--
No. Russell.
No. Russell, Russell, Russell.
Hey, Mom, it's Russell Hammond.
I play guitar in Stillwater.
Hey, how does it feel to be the mother of
the greatest rock journalist we've met?
[ Penny Hoots ]
Hello?
Look, you've got a great kid.
There's nothing to worry about.
We're taking good care of him.
- You should come to the show
sometime.Join the circus.
- Listen to me, mister.
Your charm doesn't work
on me. I'm onto you.
Of course you like him.
Well, yeah.
He worships you people. And that's fine
by you as long as he helps make you rich.
- Rich? I don't think so.
- Listen to me.
He's a smart, good-hearted,
1 5-year-old kid with infinite potential.
This is not some apron-wearing
mother you're speaking to.
I know all about
your Valhalla of decadence,
and I shouldn't have let him go.
He's not ready for your
world of compromised values
and diminished brain cells...
that you throw away
like confetti.
- Am I speaking to you clearly?
- Y-Yes, ma'am.
If you break his spirit,
harm him in any way, keep him
from his chosen profession--
which is law, something
you may not value, but I do--
you will meet the voice
at the other end of this telephone,
and it will not be pretty.
Do we understand each other?
Uh, yes, ma'am.
I didn't ask for this role,
but I'll play it.
Now go do your best.
''Be bold and mighty forces
will come to your aid.''
Goethe said that.
It's not too late for you to become
a person of substance, Russell.
Please get my son home safely.
You know, I'm glad we spoke.
[ Line Clicks ]
# Song and bong
it sounds like lots of fun #
#Won't you get on my back
for a piggyback ride #
# Get on my back
for a piggyback ride ##
- All right, boys.
- All right.
Your mom kind of freaked me out.
She means well.
[ Dick On P.A.]
From Troy, Michigan...
would you please
welcome to Cleveland...
Stillwater!
[ Applause, Cheering ]
#Oh, Father, Father#
#Tell me your story #
#Tell me what to do #
#Oh, Doctor, Doctor#
[ Woman ]
Russel.
# Is there a cure #
# For the young man's
broken blues #
#And he said #
# Love #
# Everybody knows ##
## [ Different Song,
Lyrics Indistinct ]
#Yeah, you had to be there #
# Girl, you had to be there ##
[ Cheering ]
So, Russell, when you play
a great show like tonight--
Okay, I need everyone's
attention, please.
Girls, I need five minutes
with the band alone.
Well, it seems
the rumors are true.
The record company has sent
a big-time manager here to try
and talk you into replacing me.
His name is Dennis Hope.
I know you've all heard of him.
He's got all the big bands.
He's outside right now, and
he wants five minutes with you.
And I think we've gotta do this.
- Well, send him in.
- Yeah, bring him in.
We'l send him out on a rail
Hey, we'll just finish
the interview in Maryland.
You can fly home from Maryland.
- Hi.
Hey, we've already got a manager, man.
He's been with us from the beginning.
Respectfully.
We all have our roots.
I believe in bands holding on
to their roots. But those roots
need to be augmented.
I'm gonna tell you the truth.
I may enrage some
and enthrall others.
I don't really give a fuck.
Your manager here
needs a manager.
Example . If you hadn't run out
on your contract in Phoenix...
we could have sued
over Russell's hand.
But you left, negating the contract,
forfeiting the deposit.
You effectively traveled a long way
to pay that promoter to electrocute you.
Your damages have put you
way in the hole for this tour.
Right now you owe the record company
more than you've got.
But your record's seling.
There's money to be made.
So I brought a plane in. We add more shows
to make up the difference, respectfully.
- We travel by bus.
- Doris is the soul of this band.
That bus has been our home since
we were theJeff Bebe Band. No way.
I'd travel on a pogo stick if I thought
we could make more money.
You could play more dates
with a plane.
Wel, it's not about money. It's about
playing music and turning people on.
Clearly . Respectfuly.
But on the distasteful subject
of money...
just know that you're all
making it right now.
And it's all out there.
I'm just talking about
bringing it back here.
Why should we pay you for something
we can do ourselves?
Do you know how to keep
from getting charged for the ice...
below the floorboards
at Chicago Stadium?
Do you know how
to do a headlining tour?
Do you know Claire Rothman
at the L.A. Forum?
Do you know Bobby Cowan,
Danny Marcus, Lisa Robinson?
Do you know Frank Barcelona?
This is Cleveland!
Where's Kid Leo?
Where is he?
Do you know how to get a record
not pressed, but played?
I didn't invent the rainy day, man.
I just own the best umbrella.
And as much as you may believe that
this is gonna last forever, it does not.
Your biggest fan right now--
your biggest fan--
soon they're gonna want to go to
college, gonna want to buy some clothes...
spend that money
some other way.
And you know what?
They'll tape your record
from a friend's copy.
You gotta take what you can...
when you can, while you can,
and you gotta do it now.
That's what the big boys do.
If you think MickJagger
will still be out there...
trying to be a rock star at age 50...
you're sadly, sadly mistaken.
Yes, well, uh,
thank you, Dennis.
We'll, uh, we'll think
about what you said.
Oh, no, you-- you... don't understand.
I'l think about it.
I'm not auditioning.
I came here to decide
whether I want to represent you.
So I'll stand outside
for a moment and...
think about
whether I want to stay.
It was a good show.
I miss him already.
[ Lester ] You're coming along
at a very dangerous time for rock 'n'rol.
The war is over. They won.
And they wil ruin rock 'n'rol...
and strangle everything
we love about it.
#I listen to the wind
to the wind of my soul
#Where I'l end up
Wel, I think only God realy knows #
#I've sat upon the setting sun #
#But never, never, never, never#
#I never wanted water once #
#No, never, never, never#
#I listen to my words
but they fal far below #
#I let my music take me
where my heart wants to go ##
## [ Rock ]
- Put them up.
- Al right, money--
- I don't know what that was.
- It was a donkey dick, man!
- [ Russel ] Money down.
- No matter where you come from,
a donkey dick is funny.
- Hey. Is Russell Hammond here?
- Can I help you?
- [ Russel ] Hey, The Enemy.
- [ Dick ] Come on in, son.
Hey, welcome to the road manager
poker party.
The game has been going on
for two years. Come on. Find a spot.
This is Mick, he's with The Who.
Raymond, he's with The Eagles.
- Reg, he's with Humble Pie.
I think you know Red Dog.
- Hi, brother.
We've been developing
this system of poker over the years...
so you can play it
in any condition, which helps.
- We only let Russell in
because he brought the hash.
-[ Dick ] Easy, easy.
- The press is here.
- Don't mention me or The Eagles.
Wel, I'm done.
Uh, I'm out.
- I'm in.
- All right, all right.
Side proposition to the winner--
for 50 bucks
and a case of Heineken...
I'll throw into the pot
three lovely ladies...
including Miss Penny Lane
of the famous Band Aids...
who have to leave the tour
before New York.
- Russ, is that okay with you?
- Russ is getting soft on us.
- Is that okay?
- Okay.
It's a deal. Show 'em.
Three lovely ladies in the custody
of Humble Pie. Be good to them, Reg.
All right, so we owe you $50
and a case of Heineken. All right.
Joint? And you know how I know
this is good stuff?
- How's that?
- This is from Crosby.
- Is that Crosby weed?
- Who's in?
- I'm in.
Look, nobody's feelings
are getting hurt here.
She already knows that Leslie's
coming to New York tomorrow.
Everybody understands.
This is the circus.
Everybody's trying not to go home.
Nobody's saying good-bye.
Quit looking at me like that.
[ Man ]
#Larry Felows, get down #
[ Shouting ]
#Ohhh #
# Happy, happy birthday
Happy, happy birthday #
to you ##
- [ Whooping ]
-# Happy, happy, happy, happy birthday #
- I'm making a wish.
-# Happy, happy, happy happy birthday ##
[ Man Shouting, Indistinct ]
[ Cheering, Whooping ]
''So... Penny, our friend,
has gained another year...
''but long ago
she threw it in gear.
''She rocked the South,
the East, the West.
''Could we get off
this endless tour...
where we're Black Sabbath's
fucking special guest?''
[Jeff ]
Yeah!
''She says she's retired...
''but we've heard that before.
''She chose us.
In Penny Lane we trust.
''She is a fan of this band...
- much more so than us.''
- Yeah!
[ Shouting, Whooping ]
-# Cut the cake #
- Let's go!
- Who wants it?
#Yeah, I said
now cut the cake #
-# Cut the cake #
- # Cut, cut, cut, cut #
#Cut the cake #
#Cut the cake ##
Thank you, baby. Aww.
[ Laughing ]
[ Penny ]
Who wants the ''P''in Penny?
- Happy birthday.
- Oh, thank you.
- I'm sorry the plane isn't bigger.
- Oh.
[ Man ]
I'l take a piece.
Who didn't get cake?
Any extra plates? Anybody?
[ Penny ]
You think you can fool me.
I can read you.
I know what you're thinking.
What's that?
You're worried
about me and Russell.
Yeah, I gotta work on that.
You're so sweet.
God, if there was
more of you in him--
Don't tell me this stuff.
I want to like him.
Did you miss a test
or something?
[ Chuckles ]
You have no idea.
I know I'm not on the plane. And I'm not
going on some other band's bus.
I could go with the road crew,
but that would be pathetic...
and the girls are all
going with Humble Pie.
So if you could
find out from Russell--
- Penny.
- Forget it. I'm flying to New York myself.
I've got a bunch of partial tickets.
I know his ex-wife/
current girlfriend thing--
- I'm not sure that's a good idea.
- What are you saying?
Did Russell say something?
No. No, I don't know anything.
Well, I know
he wants me there.
Wake up!
Don't go to New York!
- Why are you yelling at me?
- I thought we were going to Morocco.
There is no Morocco.
There's never been a Morocco.
There's not even a Penny Lane.
I don't even know
your real name.
If I ever met a man
in the real world...
who looked at me
the way you just looked at me--
When and where does this
''real world'' occur?
I mean, I'm realy
confused here.
Al these rules and al these sayings
and nicknames--
Honey, you're too sweet
for rock 'n' roll.
Sweet?
Where do you get off?
Where do you get ''sweet''?
I am dark and mysterious
and pissed off!.
And I could be very dangerous
to all of you.
I am not sweet.
And you should
know that about me.
I am The Enemy!
Look, you should
be happy for me.
You don't know
what he says to me in private.
Maybe it is love, as much
as it can be for somebody--
Who sold you to Humble Pie
for 50 bucks and a case of beer?
I was there.
Oh, God.
I'm sorry.
What kind of beer?
[ Dennis ] Welcome to New York.
It's okay to be nervous.
You should be nervous. Al you
can do is be yourself and leave
a pint of blood on that stage.
Hey, William. We showed you America.
Did everything but get you laid.
#Walking in the park
just the other day, baby #
-# What do you think I saw #
- [ Slaps Wiliam's Leg ]
[Jeff ]
Oh. [ Laughs ]
No. Yeah?
#Lots of people
sitting on the grass #
#With flowers
in their hair said #
#Hey, boy
do you want to score #
#And you know how it is #
#I realy don't know ##
[ People Clamoring ]
[ Chattering ]
- Maybe I can get an autograph?
- Who should I make it out to?
- She's here.
- Make it out to Lenny.
- Russell, can I have your autograph?
- Yeah.
Leslie!
- How ya doin'?
-Jeffrey.
[ Dick ] Room's fuly stocked.
Air conditioning's on.
- By the way, you look stunning.
- Thanks. See you later.
All right, bags in five.
Cars leave for the party at 6:00.
Oh, God.
There are lighter souvenirs,
you know.
Well, I kept thinking
I was gonna go home the next day.
Yeah. So did I,
1 5 years ago.
[ Dick ] Oi!
That's the wrong bag,you idiot!
- William?
- Vic.
It's, uh--
It's all happening.
They're here.
Zeppelin are here.
They are here.
They're at The Plaza.
Sapphire and, uh, and Miss Penny Lane
are, uh, are there too.
They're all staying
under the name Emily Rugburn.
- Wait. Penny Lane is here?
- Emily Rugburn.
Wiliam Miler?
Sir,you have an urgent cal.
- Hello.
This is Jann Wenner,
publisher of Roling Stone.
Congratulations,
it's gonna be a cover.
Annie Leibovitz will
shoot them next week in L.A...
but we are gonna need you
back in San Francisco tomorrow.
You can finish the story
here, okay? Talk to Ben.
You can tell the band.
Alison, our fact checker,
needs you to transmit whatever
you have of the story tonight.
There's a mojo at the Daily News
they'll let us use.
- A mojo?
- A mojo. It's a very modern machine...
that transmits pages
over the telephone.
It only takes 1 8 minutes a page.
[ Man ] As soon as a couple leave,
I can fit you right in.
Right now it's--
Excuse me. You got an I.D.?
- No, thanks. I'm fine.
- No, no, no, no.
- Hey, man. He's cool he's cool
- Hey, Dennis, how ya doin'?
- Everything's great.
- Good. Your guys are all inside.
- Opie.
- Hey.
I'm going to England with Deep Purple,
and we leave in an hour.
Don't forget me, okay?
It's all happening,
but I must ''vamoosh.''
Hey, The Enemy.
Hey, we got a table.
Come on. They're all looking for you.
Guys.
Guys!
You're gonna be
on the cover of Roling Stone.
Are you serious?
The cover of Roling Stone.
And we made it together.
And they don't just put
somebody with one little hit...
on the cover of Roling Stone
fucking magazine, man.
Damn it, I'm gonna enjoy this.
When I first bought the magazine,
the Beatles were on the cover.
The Beatles.
Four of them, four of us.
#We take al kind of pils
that give us al kind of thrils #
# But the thrill
we never known #
- Yee-ha!
-# Was the thril that'l get you #
#When you get your picture
on the cover of Rolling Stone #
-# Rolling Stone #
- #Wanna see my picture on the cover #
-# Roling Stone #
- # Gonna buy five copies for my mother #
-# Rolling Stone #
-# Wanna see my smiling face #
# On the cover
of the Roling Stone #
- [ All Cheering ]
- [Jeff] Thank you.
Who is that girl?
She's creeping me out.
She's not with any
of you guys, is she?
[ All Together]
Yeah, she's with me.
#Until you've seen
this trash can dream come true #
#You stand at the edge
while people run--#
So, uh, who's
gonna shoot it?
#I thank the Lord there's
people out there like you #
#I thank the Lord
there's people out there like you #
#While Mona Lisas
and Mad Hatters #
#Sons of bankers
sons of lawyers #
#Turn around and say
good morning to the night #
#For unless they see the sky #
#But they can't
and that is why #
#They know not if it's
dark outside or light #
#I thought I knew #
#But now I know
that rose trees never grow #
#In New York City #
#And I thank the Lord #
#For the people I have found #
#I thank the Lord
for the people I have found #
#While Mona Lisas
and Mad Hatters #
#Sons of bankers
sons of lawyers #
#Turn around and say
good morning to the night #
#For unless
they see the sky #
#But they can't
and that is why ##
I am no good at good-byes.
And you are the last...
of my old-time friends.
Polexia-- Polexia went
to England with Deep Purple.
Can you believe that?
Even Sapphire
went someplace else.
And all she left
was her quaaludes.
- [ Groans ]
- Oh, wonderful
Where's Beth?
Where's my friends?
Where are al my friends?
Front desk?
Could you please send a doctor?
- [ Thuds ]
- Room 537.
- Penny, get up.
- I'm up.
Uh, my wife's had an accident
with some quaaludes.
- So tired.
- You gotta get up, Penny.
- Penny, get up. Get up.
- So-- You know that.
You know that I'm retired.
I've always been.
I'm retired and I'm tired.
- [ Applause ]
- [ Woman ]Jane Abbot.
[ Man ]
Miss Jane Abbot.
Miss Judy Stanton.
Congratulations.
- Raymond Sanchez.
- Mr. Raymond Sanchez.
- #As time goes on ##
- [ Wiliam ] Seats and tray tables.
- Seat backs and tray tables locked.
- And our pending graduate...
Wiliam Miler, not present.
- [ Scattered Applause ]
- Al right. Yeah,yeah.
#And now #
-# Now that you're near#
- Why doesn't he love me?
#Promise your love #
#That I've waited to share #
[ Graduation Speaker ]
And to the class of 1 973 we say...
don't forget to remember
yourselves as you are today--
ful of hope and the dream
that everything is possible .
And remember this 20 years from now,
when we al own...
home computers
and we all travel...
in shiny electrical cars that
move swiftly, high above our city...
that the key to the future...
is keeping today alive
forever!
- [ Cheering ]
- Forever! Forever!
[ Wiliam ]
Penny, no. Wake up!
- Wake up!
- I'm up.
Well, now that
I have your attention...
uh, I know you've
heard this before...
and I've never
said this to anybody.
Well, nobody who didn't legally
have to say it back to me...
but, uh--
Oh, God. Why am I so nervous?
You'll never remember this.
I love you.
And I'm about
to boldly go where...
many men have gone before.
- What've we got here? What's her name?
- Emily .
Okay, sweetheart. Sit up, sit up, sit up.
Good girl good girl
- What did you take, sweetheart?
What did you take?
- I'll get her legs.
- What did you take?
- I don't know.
Yes, you do.
Tell us what you took.
Emily, we're gonna have
to pump your stomach, okay?
- Emily , wake up.
- I got the tubes. There we go. Water.
All right. Now, you're gonna have
to swallow this tube.
- Open, open, open.
- [ Gagging ]
- Don't fight us. We're trying to help you.
- Emily, Emily.
- Relax.
- Come on. Swalow, swalow.
I know, I know. Swallow this now.
No, don't bite on it. Swallow.
Emily, Emily.
Come on. Swallow.
- Very good. That's it. There we go. Al done.
- Got it.
Very good.
Now we gotta-- come on--
feed some liquid into your stomach.
#My cherie amour#
#Lovely as a summer day #
#Distant as the Milky Way #
#My cherie amour#
#Pretty little one
that I adore #
#You're the only girl
my heart beats for##
[ Wiliam ] You've never done half
the things you said you did.
It was in the middle
of''Midnight Rambler,''
and Keith Richards
saw me...
came to the front of the stage,
and he pulled me out.
And they
took me backstage...
and gave me a Coke
with ice and a lemon.
And I never went home.
I've done twice the things
I said I did.
What about your mom?
She always said, ''Marry up.
Marry someone grand.''
And that's why
she named me Lady.
She named you ''Lady''?
Lady Goodman.
That's great.
Now you know all my secrets.
You've got me.
See you back
in the real world.
Thank you, William Miller.
Hey, Lady!
[ Woman ]
Ladies and gentlemen...
welcome to Eastern Airlines'
nonstop service to San Diego.
In preparation
for our departure today...
we'd like to ask please that
you extinguish al flammable items...
and do return al seats and tray tables
to their ful --
...make sure that your seat bels
are securely fastened...
and do make note
of the emergency exits--
Hey, why didn't you come back last night?
Bob Dylan showed up.
He was sitting at our table
for an hour or something, right, Dick?
Just rapping, Bob Dylan at our fucking
table. I was looking for you.
- I was gonna introduce you.
- What happened to you last night?
It's a long story.
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Chuckling ]
# Peggy Sue, Peggy Sue #
# Pretty, pretty, pretty
pretty Peggy Sue ##
[ Man On P.A.]
Hi, this is Craig,your pilot.
- It appears we've caught the
edge of that electrical storm.
- Oh, my God.
- Electrical storm?
- Buckle up tight.
We're gonna get you out of this.
- Rock 'n' roll.
- [Jeff ] We shouldn't be here.
- [ Thunderclap ]
- Whoa, baby!
[ Russel Whooping ]
Doris, we miss you!
Listen, we're gonna
try and land in Tupelo.
- We found a field to land in.
- A field?
It's gonna be kind of a rough set down,
but we should be fine.
just hang in there,
and we'l get you out of this.
[ Thunderclap ]
- Everyone says,
''It's so glamorous out here.''
- He just told us we're gonna die.
- [ Buzzers Blaring ]
- I'm trying to maintain,
but the fucking thing won't--
- [ Thunderclap ]
- Oh, my God.
[ Engines Straining ]
If something should happen...
maybe I never said this enough:
I love all of you.
[ Engines Whining ]
[ Thunderclap ]
I once hit a man in Dearborn, Michigan.
A hit-and-run.
I hit him
and just kept on going.
I don't know if he's alive
or dead, but I'm sorry.
- Not a day goes by
that I don't see his face.
- [ Leslie ] Oh, my God!
Look, I love you al too. You're like family
to me. Especialy since Marna left me.
And if I took an extra dollar or two here
and there, it's because I knew I earned it.
Yeah. I slept with Marna, Dick.
I did too.
I waited until you broke up with her,
Dick, but me too.
I also slept with Leslie
when you were fighting.
You slept with Jeff?
Yeah, but it didn't count. It was the
summer we decided to be free of all rules.
- And you say you love me!
- I don't love you, man. I never did.
None of us love you.
- You act above us,you always have.
- [ Larry ] Finaly, the truth.
You just held it over us like you might
leave, like we're lucky to be with you.
And we had to live with it, man.
I had to live with you,
and now I might die with you...
- and it's not fucking fair!
- Please, enough!
And I'm still
in love with you, Leslie.
Oh, I don't want to hear any more!
Shut up,Jeffrey!
-Jeffrey?
- It's all happening.
Whatever happens, Bebe,
you're dead!
Don't be self-righteous,
Russell, not now, man.
You were sleeping with Penny,
that fucking groupie!
Last summer up until yesterday.
Why don't you tel Leslie that?
- Shut up!
- I quit!
- [ Russel ] I'm gonna kil you!
- [ Dennis ] I quit!
''That groupie''?
She was a Band Aid.
All she did was love your band.
And you al used her, al of you.
You used her and threw her away.
She almost died last night
while you were with Bob Dylan!
You guys are always talking
about the fans, the fans, the fans.
She was your biggest fan
and you threw her away.
And if you can't see that,
that's your biggest problem.
And I love her!
I love her!
[ Thunderclap ]
- [ Engines Whining ]
- Fuck it!
I'm-- I'm gay!
Thank God above,
we're alive!
We're alive!
We're gonna make it!
Sweet relief!
Halelujah, dear God!
Write what you want.
Just leave your package
on the desk.
Oh, I'm not a messenger.
I'm one of your writers.
William H. Miller.
[ Whispering ]
He's just a kid!
Go right on in.
You're William Miller?
- Yep.
- Oh, baby.
Didn't anything happen,
I mean, after $600 in room service bills?
Didn't you get anything
on tape with Russell Hammond?
Where are you in this piece?
What did you want to write?
This reads like what
they wanted you to write.
You obviously saw more
than you wrote about.
I think we should push up
Flippo's Who cover.
Good, 'cause it's gonna take me
three days to get through this research.
It's al handwritten
on little bits of paper!
- It's a puff-piece.
- Plus, they refer
to al the women as chicks.
- I have a problem with that.
- You want them to like you. It happens.
Ben, you told me
to send what I had.
It's not finished.
Give me tonight to work on it.
[ Lester ] Oh, man.
So you made friends with them?
See, friendship
is the booze they feed you.
They want you to get drunk
on feeling like you belong.
Well, it was fun.
Because they
make you feel cool.
- And, hey, I met you. You are not cool.
- I know.
Even when I thought I was,
I knew I wasn't.
Because we are uncool.
Women will always be
a problem for guys like us.
Most of the great art in the world
is about that very problem.
Good-looking people,
they got no spine.
Their art never lasts.
And they get the girls,
but we're smarter.
Yeah, I can
really see that now.
Because great art is about
the guilt and longing...
and love disguised as sex
and sex disguised as love.
Hey, let's face it,
you got a big head start.
I'm glad you were home.
I'm always home.
I'm uncool.
- Me too.
- You're doing great, man.
The only true currency
in this bankrupt world...
is what you share with someone else
when you're uncool.
Listen, my advice to you...
and I know you think
these guys are your friends...
if you want to be a true
friend to them, be honest...
and unmerciful.
''I'm flying high over Tupelo, Mississippi,
with America's hottest band...
- and we're all about to die.''
- Hmm.
- Dark, lively .
- Yeah, and it gets better.
Did this all really happen?
Give it to me.
I'l cal and check the quotes.
Holy shit! I just got off the phone
with Rolling Stone.
[ Larry ]
They called me too. What's he using?
All, he's using it all.
This, according to the ''fact checker.''
- So what?
- ''So what''?
We come off like amateurs--
some average band trying
to come to grips with success...
jealous and fighting
and breaking up.
We're buffoons!
''Rock 'n' roll can save the world''?
''The chicks are great''?
I sound like a dick!
- [ Muttering ] You are a dick.
- I never said that!
Maybe we don't see ourselves
the way we really are.
Is it that hard
to make us look cool?
This kid has you on acid screaming,
''I'm a golden god,'' from a fan's rooftop.
They used him to fuck us.
They'll probably just put you on the cover.
Wait. I never said,
''I'm a golden god.''
Or did I?
We never took him seriously.
Now it's serious.
I liked him as a person.
He was never a person.
He was a journalist!
You! You had
the right idea all along!
- How about the plane flight?
- [ Dick ] It's al there.
Don't worry.
It's unspecific who says what.
No names are mentioned
in the more embarrassing sequences.
- It's just completely obvious
who's who, and we're fucked!
- [ Russel ] I--
I told him he could write
what he wanted.
Hey, they haven't talked
to Russell yet.
You can always deny
the key stuff to the fact checker.
- One phone call. Then they can't print it.
- Is that true?
This is war, my friend.
If you'd have met me earlier,
he would have never been around.
He'l live.
Let's identify the goals here.
T-shirts, foreign markets, renegotiating
your contract, merchandising.
Happiness.
Realizing your dreams.
Money. Cool
Meeting the Beatles.
Let's put all of it in the pot.
It all depends on mystique.
Not giving too much away.
I'm going to L.A. tonight.
Cal me if you need me.
But before I go, let me
give you a lesson in mystique.
You can only have one.
Which one do you want?
Which one
are you gonna choose?
As long as you can't see
what's in this hand...
you'll always want it more.
It's phenomenal Wiliam.
It's sophisticated. It's inteligent.
We only had to cut out
a couple of'graphs.
Jeff Bebe's mother sent over
a shoe box of childhood photos.
It's gonna look fantastic.
The band just denied 90 percent
of the story. It's a fabrication.
You weren't honest.
And worse, you wasted our time.
D-Did you talk
to Russell Hammond?
Russell Hammond
is the one who denied it.
- Now, wait a second.
- Denied it.
We're going with The Who.
The manuscript's in my office.
He's just some fan.
What do you expect?
Ben. Wait.
William?
You guys, this is my brother.
- Nice to finally meet you.
- You have a good day.
You guys, I'll deadhead back later.
I think I'm needed.
I'll see ya.
You look awful.
But it's great.
You're living your life.
You're free of Mom.
Hey, I'll take off work.
Let's have an adventure together,
you and me, finally.
Anywhere you wanna go.
Anywhere in the world.
This is not my idea
of a good time.
-Just get me to my bed.
- I'll deal with her.
[ Laughing ]
I forgive you.
[ Chuckles ]
I didn't apologize.
[ Laughing ]
Oh.
- Sapphire.
- Hey, boy.
- I hate good-byes.
- Me too.
Al right,
so I didn't like you much.
Do we have to
like each other?
I sorta thought so.
I think it would have worked against us.
I really do.
You know what they say. All the great
partnerships hated each other.
We didn't hate each other
that much, did we?
No, maybe not.
I could work on it, though.
[ Chuckles ]
I just can't
picture you with Leslie.
I'm the you they get
when they can't get you.
- Sorry.
- Got it. It's cool.
- I'll get it, man. I'll see you later on.
- All right, see ya.
All right.
Is Penny okay?
Oh, the quaaludes incident?
Well, it wasn't pretty.
She could have died.
I always told her not to let
too many guys fall in love with her.
I guess I was wrong.
One of them ended up saving her life.
- William?
- What do you care?
I mean, we all know
what you did to him.
Everybody knows...
even Penny Lane.
[ Sapphire ]
Something tels me 20 years from now...
we'll remember her...
and not much else.
Hey, Russell.
[ Chuckling ]
Can you believe
these new girls ?
None of them use birth control.
And they eat all the steak.
I mean, they don't even
know what it is to be a fan.
You know, to truly love some silly
little piece of music or some band...
so much that it hurts.
[ Line Ringing ]
Hello, Penny?
It's Russell. Don't hang up.
I can't really talk right now.
I'm in a room full of people.
Actually, I'm alone.
And I won't call again.
I promise.
But I need to see you
face-to-face...
because I'm never as good
as when you're there...
and I can see myself
the way you look at me.
And I'm sorry. Maybe if we could just
get together, find some time to talk.
Let's say all the things
we never said.
Give me your address.
I'm coming to you...
this time.
Got a pen?
[ Muttering ]
Hello, Penny. Hello, Penny.
Hello, hello, Penny.
[ Doorbel Rings ]
I'm-- I'm Russell Hammond.
So this is the famous
Russell Hammond.
Come in.
Uh, is she home?
Who? Anita?
- Where am I?
- Hello?
Hi.
You know, when we spoke,
I felt that we connected.
Psst.
Oh, man.
My son is very important
to me too.
And I do think
you owe him an apology.
I appreciate you showing up.
No, no. I agree, ma'am.
There's hope for you yet, Russell.
Well.
Uh, hi.
So, this is...
where The Enemy sleeps.
You know, I think we both
wanted to be with her.
I guess she wanted us
to be together.
You should give her a call.
You both live in the same city.
- You really think I should?
- Yeah.
That girl really cares about you.
Man, I never even
knew her real name.
Oh, I caled your magazine...
and told them the truth.
I don't know what
they're gonna do with it...
but I told them every word
you wrote was true.
We are gonna do this
one more time.
- [ Switch Clicks ]
- So, Russell...
what do you love about music?
To begin with...
everything.
#Tangerine, tangerine #
- Tickets, tickets, tickets.
- How much?
#I was her love #
#She was my queen #
#And now a thousand
years between #
Morocco. A seat
by the window, please.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
#Tangerine, tangerine #
#Living reflection
from a dream #
#I was her love #
#She was my queen #
#And now a thousand
years between ##
#Unfolding enveloping
missiles of soul
#Recal senses sadly #
#Mirage like soft blue
like lanterns below #
#To light the way gladly #
#Whether whistling heaven's
clouds disappear#
#Where the wind
withers memory #
#Whether whiteness
whisks soft shadows away #
-# White hot glistening shadowy flows #
-# Feel flows #
-# Black hot glistening shadowy goes #
#Unbending never-ending
tablets of time #
#Record al the yearning #
#Unfearing al -appearing
message divine #
#Eases the burning #
#Whether wiling witness
waits at my mind #
#Whether hope dampens memory #
#Whether wondrous wil
stands tal at my side #
-# White hot glistening shadowy flows #
-# Feel flows #
-# Black hot glistening shadowy flows #
-# Feel goes #
## [ Instrumental
#Encasing al -embracing
wreath of repose #
#Engulfs al the senses #
#Imposing unclosing
thoughts that compose #
#Retire the fences #
#Whether wholy heartened
life fades away #
#Whether hearts
heal the memory #
#Whether wholy heartened
life fades away #
#Whether wondrous wil
stands tal at my side #
#Whether whiteness
whisks soft shadows away #
-# White hot glistening shadowy flows #
-# Feel goes #
-# Black hot glistening shadowy goes #
-# Feel flows #
-# White hot glistening shadowy flows #
-# Feel glows #
-# Black hot glistening shadowy flows #
-# Feelings to grow #
#White hot glistening
shadowy flows #
shadowy flows ##
[ Phonograph Needle
Lifting Off Record ]
[ Record Changer Stops ]