Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
www.NapiProjekt.pl - nowa jakoœæ napisów.
Napisy zosta³y specjalnie dopasowane do Twojej wersji filmu.
My name is Jerrod Hartfelder.
I turn a video production company.
Here in California.
We focus primarily in-
on reality shows.
If you ever seen the show, "Tornado
Trackers, "is one of ours.
A club came to us by mail.
It was an episode of a reality show
new called "Grave Encounters".
It was run by a young
producer named Lance Preston.
The idea was that your group
paranormal investigators,
investigate spirits
places and things like that.
And this was long before
any other
program of the same nature
that there are now around.
It seemed that he was not in his time.
My name is Lance Preston.
When I was small and
my parents moved us to
a house, which later
found to be haunted.
The things it found
stayed with me forever.
Since then, I'm obsessed
in trying to capture evidence
and show that these things are real.
Come with me and
my team
paranormal investigators
professional
while we risk
to enter the premises
Most Haunted
known to man.
We'll be all night, and
with cameras to record everything.
If you're ready, it is
time to attend the
Grave Encounters
(Meeting Cemetery)
Everything seemed to be going well.
The cuts were to be fantastic.
We were very excited.
We had the same thing.
And then of course, they
did the episode 6.
Want to say something else?
Yes! I want to be very
clear about this.
What is about to
see is not a movie.
Ok?
There are 66 hours of film
continuous, unedited,
that was written for
Lance's show.
It was not manipulated in any way.
It's just continuous film, only
edited because of length.
(Do not copy the movie)
Action!
Hello! Hello! Test Site, you!
Lance Preston!
Catch and background
all the time.
I'll just move a little, wait.
Ready? Yes I'm ready!
It's still recording.
I want to get you well.
A palace back. Is it good?
Good Afternoon! Welcome to a new
Grave Encounters episode.
I'm your host
as always, Lance Preston.
And tonight I am very
happy to take you to visit
One of the most terrifying
I have ever seen.
Behind me is the Hospital
Psychiatric Collingwood.
This is one of six buildings
an area of ??80 hectares.
Wait, wait, is
to pass a car.
Matt continues from there,
I will not say that again.
Between 1895 and 1960
It was home to more than 80,000 men
sick and mentally disturbed.
After its closure in 1963
several ghosts have been seen.
Objects that move alone.
And sometimes you hear
the laughter of patients
condemned to live here.
Tonight, my team and I
we will be locked for 8 hours.
Locked inside,
during the hours
that phenomena are
more frequent.
Using the tools most
advanced to hunt ghosts
we look, how
were known,
ghosts of the Hospital
Psychiatric Collingwood.
Cut. Nice!
It was?
Morgan! Morgan Turner! Yes Ola Ola
Sorry! Thanks for coming.
I know the roads and everything.
Do not worry.
I'm really happy to do this.
This will even appear on television?
Yes, hopefully.
Do not look for me
I'm just recording.
Do not worry, it records everything.
Morgan is here with me
Turner, local historian.
Morgan is here today
to tell us about the
dark past of the hospital.
Morgan? Can you tell us when
the hospital was built?
The story is very similar to
other institutes of the same time.
Built in 1893
To relieve overcrowding
the County's hospital in Denver.
At the time, mental illness
was not well perceived.
Treatments were only
Many pioneers.
Psychiatric Hospitals like this
were seen as a trash
for family members
embarrassing, rather
a place where
could even heal.
Right.
The conditions were minimal,
People slept on the floor, the
times, without blankets or clothing.
It was not at all, a place
fun place to be stuck.
Can you tell us about
Arthur Freinken?
Your story should be the most
interesting about this hospital.
Yes, right.
I assumed I would ask that.
Freinken was a neurosurgeon
Harvard graduate.
It was placed here from 1937 to 1948.
He was very
known due to their
experimental methods
to operate the brain.
He started the
frontal lobe surgery.
Performed about 140 surgeries
to the frontal lobe, the cable.
August 15, 1948.
Six patients had fled
their rooms,
and stabbed Freinken
in your office.
His body was found by
a nurse the next day.
Unfortunately, this death was
completely irrelevant due to
death of the famous baseball player,
David Bruce, the same day.
Wow! This story is 'the nuts'!
Morgan, give us your opinion more
honest, believe in ghosts?
I do not know. But this would be if there
a good place to go looking for them.
The traffic was even
crap today.
We did not take long, were
about 6 hours away is not it?
"Death awaits you." Oh my God!
Looks like we'll find out.
This is so silly!
This may take
rather, they're
old current.
We should not use them.
Take it easy bro.
Slow motion, background music.
And it is scary.
Well, that's it. Here we go ...
Go take ...
Oh my God!
This is the entrance
Main building.
Nice! Yes!
If you are family members, make
check-in at the reception, right there.
This is scary as shit!
It's crazy!
Are you picking up? Records everything!
I shoot everything!
Do not smoke.
Obviously you can not. Do not try.
It has a fire alarm.
I'm here with Kenny Sandivol.
Current caretaker, for eight years.
Kenny! Would you say that this
place is haunted?
Well, I've never done this before.
Should I speak to you or the camera?
Only ... ignore the camera.
I do not know if I believe in spirits
or ghosts or anything.
But since I'm here
seen very strange things.
Especially at night,
can hear the
sounds of the pipe and
of the construction.
It is very difficult to say, but
I'm not alone.
Come see!
Let? Ok
It is as if these corridors
be infinite.
Ah, yes.
Hard to believe that this was the home
of thousands of mentally ill.
Exact thousands.
The day is so dark here.
Are you afraid? Yes.
There are plenty of
interest, which I will show you.
Guys! If you think that now is
wait until dark tonight.
None of these work lights,
is just too dark.
You see this window here? Yes.
Closing it before nightfall,
and sometimes I
here in the morning, and is
fully open.
What!
I can not figure out what it is.
It is as if something or someone was
trying to get out or so.
It is definitely a point
interest in the paranormal.
Here you? Perfect.
How is it supposed to help
people in those cubicles?
Oh my God!
This is officially fucked!
Is this real? Yes, totally real.
One patient was here
caught a good few years.
And this is what left us.
He spent his time
write on the walls.
Then it was the same
a quarter of patients?
Yes, this was even the fourth
one of the patients. Really?
I do not know if he died here, but
been here a very long time.
Very scary.
What the fuck!? Kenny!
This is awesome!
Fire, the acoustics are
same shit here.
What is this?
Supposedly a young
patient committed suicide here.
What? Right here?!
One patient committed suicide right here?
Yes, cut his wrists in this bath.
Oh my God, it's so sad.
Some say they hear the sound of
flow of water coming out.
Never heard such a thing.
Where are we going now?
Let the service tunnels.
Can not wait to see them.
Pssst! Are you okay?
Kenny! This is exactly
what I was looking for!
These tunnels all the buildings together.
They have almost a mile long.
This is a maze down here.
You can easily lose yourself here.
Once I got here, and the
air was very cold.
I was so quiet. I felt like
if someone were watching me.
A very strange feeling.
What? What? It's just my shadow.
This is Garry Krefeld.
Krefeld company.
He worked here some time ago.
Is that true?
In 1983, the state was
try to make some changes here
but in the end it was all the fucking.
Damn sorry.
You want to say again? Yes is better.
Anyway,
I and my staff
came here about
two weeks.
And experienced any type
of supernatural phenomenon?
The boys thought
heard weird noises.
And disappeared
some tools.
I thought they were thieves but
never seen any, so ...
And there was an accident, right? Yes ..
One of the boys went upstairs.
Right there.
He swears that something
pushed the stairs.
He gave a very hard fall.
He hurt himself on his knees, and gave up.
Does not sound like a
residual haunting.
Sounds more like a
intelligent haunting.
A residual haunting is
known as an echo of the past.
That repeats itself endlessly.
An intelligent haunting
is actually a spirit.
Interact with intent.
There have been reports
people who say they
been pushed, scratched
or even fired.
It's rare but it happens.
So, you used
spend much time here?
Yes, the kids in high school
came here a lot.
You know. Exit and such.
And then saw something?
Yes.
We were even here.
Here. The date or something.
I looked up and I swear to God.
I swear I saw someone there.
One was wearing white robes ...
as a hospital gown ... yes.
And had his head shaved.
Appearance of full spectrum!
Why not ask
quickly to the gardener?
Sorry! Sorry sir!
We are recording a program
TV, and we were
she liked to think of giving
a quick interview.
I am here with the gardener
local, Javier Horteguez.
Javier, have you ever noticed something
stranger around the building?
No. Not really. What do you mean?
Well, he heard strange sounds or
witnessed anything paranormal?
I started working here.
He started working. Okay.
TC can take a break?
And if you do for the camera?
Pretend you saw something?
I have to go back to work! Ok
It will be fast! Wait, just
wait a bit. You do not have more?
They are $ 20.
I am here with the gardener
local, Javier Horteguez.
Javier, saw something in the past
10 years you worked here?
Yes, I saw a ghost. Right there.
It was very scary.
A spirit outside the building.
Unbelievable.
This is a point of interest
supernatural different
any that
have recorded before.
Three, two, one ...
Due to the huge size of the
We place a medium flame.
Houston we Gris
help in the investigation.
Houston! Are you feeling anything?
Wow! There is an energy
unbelievable here!
It's like thousands of voices
talking at the same time.
This sound is deafening!
There is something more.
It's like a dark spirit.
It may possibly be a demon.
We have to be extremely
careful tonight.
We do not want to play with this thing.
No way.
It's here.
Are you feeling anything?
Yes.
I'm feeling a
great sadness here.
A deep sadness.
I see a patient.
A female patient.
A girl. There is water, red ...
red water.
Blood. Blood. He died here.
He cut his wrists in the bathtub.
The guard said that a girl
had died here.
Houston! This is incredible.
The spirit is still with us.
Cut.
Yes!
There was too much? No.
Lance! How do you feel about
to your episode six? Very well.
It is a good place.
Do you think this is because
we'll see a ghost?
Yes, thousands of them.
I'm sure.
Wow! You try to sound like
less antiseptic.
It would be great.
But if we can not, I
to make sure we get
a good scares.
Wait, wait! TC!
Want to record something to the setting of the sun?
Son of a bitch!
House of the window, tip!
Ok, this is scary as shit.
I'll leave.
Ok, here we are with our wise
Grave Encounters technician, Matt.
Matt! Why not show us the
What are you doing here?
Installed ten cameras
in static
main points
paranormal activity.
Is recorded on tape.
But it also saved on the hard drive.
All who come here is on
to my computer wirelessly.
So always know
what is happening.
Well done Matt!
Why not show to us
what each one
this equipment?
This is an EMF meter.
It is a device that
measures levels of
electricity in the air.
So the main idea
is that when the meter
EMF fields detects human
remains stable.
While the fields
caused by activity
paranormal will produce
peaks in reading.
Infrared sensors.
The idea is the same as the EMF, but this
shows changes in temperature.
It is believed that the spirits
cause a loss of temperature.
Known in the community
paranormal, such as cold spots.
One, two, three ...
This is a recorder
analog audio. Right.
It is used to capture EVPs.
Oh wait ...
Explains to the audience
What is an EVP.
Electronic Voice Phenomenon
(Electronic Voice Phenomenon).
Capture sounds that the ear
humans can not detect.
So when you play,
if we hear something,
means that something is
trying to communicate with us.
This is my favorite.
The Geiger counter.
Turns the sound here, and
you're ready to go.
Look at this! It is spectacular.
I assure you, if there is anything
paranormal here, we'll catch it.
Well folks, we are ready
to be locked.
My friend Kenny, the
janitor of the building,
will have the honor of
locked inside.
Kenny, thank you!
See you at 6 am.
Six hours exactly. Good luck!
I am a demon. A demon child.
I can not wait to see you in the morning.
Yes, we have to spend the
night with these two freaks.
What are you doing?
I'm talking to Kenny.
He locked the door?
It's good for the show.
Do not worry about it.
What do we do if we need
more material?
Well done! This is what will happen.
This is the best place
ever investigated.
And the most dangerous.
I want to draw attention
to the fact that
have been built
almost like a prison.
All the windows have bars.
Could never
leave, even
we wanted.
We are locked here
Kenny in until the
janitor of the building in
come get the morning.
We will be working
in total darkness.
Capturing all three
night vision cameras.
More static cameras
Matt set up in the
main points
paranormal activity.
Okay folks! When you are
ready, it's about time we had a
Grave Encounters!
Okay, we're
now go through the
dark corridors of
old institution.
Abandoned for over 50 years.
We are looking for souls
were trapped in life.
And probably trapped
after life.
I feel a cold, it's cold here.
This was the corridor
where you could see
the appearance of the person
with the shaved head,
to hang down the hall.
Sasha, we use the PVS.
Is there someone here with us?
You were a patient here?
You used to live here in the hospital?
Down again.
"Is there someone here with us?"
"You were a patient here?"
"You used to live here in the hospital?"
Nothing.
Wait! I felt like ...
Spirit, thou hast no
to be afraid of us.
If you're here, show yourself!
I think it is getting cold as
move along, is to join us.
Whether we will be here.
If there is a spirit here
us, give us a sign.
Open the window!
Even just a little bit.
Now I use this camera to
try to capture paranormal anomalies.
Normally, there are
seen by the human eye.
It is known as
spirit photography.
One more.
We expect that
photos are revealed.
If there is a ghost behind
me, just let us know later.
It was you who wrote these walls?
Or just wanted to try to communicate?
Why not try
communicate with me now?
If the patient who killed himself in this room,
in the same bath, is here now,
that show.
I'm really scared here.
The chambers 2 and 4 have
temperature gauges.
Personally, I am the only one
have to be here alone?
Houston, feel anything?
I feel a very negative energy here.
Not just one but many.
If there are spirits here
below, please show yourselves!
Do you hear a sound.
As I said, it seems that
these pipes are endless.
And it smells bad here.
Heard what? I also heard.
Ok, we hear something. What was that?
I do not know, come here. Here, follow me.
Where does it sound? Behind this door.
Ali
Want to open it?
You can slide the camera?
Oh, not really. Damn!
Shit.
Shut up. They are rats.
No way! Really?
It's nothing more.
You're an idiot! There was a joke!
This is almost as scary
as the "Saw Dawn"!
Can this be plasmo-waste.
Discovered for the first time
Team Record Encounters?
I think we should give more
a look at the top.
Saves me a few shots in the hallways,
does that chilling effect.
As we did Playview Mansion.
Yes yes, and then cut.
Scary, scary, scary.
"CHECKERS OF THE DEAD. KING ME."
What the fuck?!
"GLORY HOLE"
Kitchen of the dead.
Said to cause me to lunch, bitch!
What the fuck is that?
This is scarier.
How did we miss this?
Lance is gonna love me!
Shit.
Wait, wait, wait ...
Yes, my dear?
She is crying, give him the phone.
Hello sweet!
What your mother told me
was that you fear
the monsters are
under your bed.
We've had this conversation?
The monsters are not real.
Even if they were not
came to our house.
You know that Daddy will take care of you.
Says the mother who gave permission
to sleep with her today.
Daddy will not be
at home until tomorrow.
We will go to a pizzeria.
The father will be home soon.
Bye bye.
Because I got myself into this?
Shit, it's cold.
What the fuck was that!
Guys, stop this shit!
I'm not playing!
It is not the best time
to do this shit!
What the fuck?!
Where are people?
Maybe it was the wind or so.
Solid. Not a tornado
would be able to move it.
How do you think
it weighs?
TC, how do you move?
Whatever it was,
scared me like anything.
You can not explain?
I have told you. I was shooting,
then turned and the door closed.
I thought you were the first.
Were you shooting?
I had already told you.
You were so busy ...
Grave? Let's see.
Oh my God!
That's scary.
I accept your apology,
I accept your apology.
I do not think you saw that!
The footage we just saw the
moments ago, was captured by
TC cameramen.
This door behind
me close by itself.
There was no wind, no open windows
that could have caused this,
Let's now
establish contact.
Is there anyone here with us?
Please make a noise.
Batam in anything.
Feel free
to close the door
as did also
the bit with the TC.
Feel free to hit with
her with the strength you want.
Force Shut it!
Now, please give us a sign!
Spirit, I invoke thee
to appear.
If there is someone here,
give us a sign ...
Shit. Shit.
Do you really think
we had something here.
Shit! What was it?
Oh my God!
That was very
scary people!
He came here!
Shit, I see nothing.
Did you hear?
What? Oh shit ...
Shit ...
What the fuck?!
Hello!
This is fucked up people.
What is this personal? Matt?
Matt, is there anyone there?
Is there someone at some of the
floors above us?
No. What is happening?
Does anyone know what we're here
shoot and walk with us to enjoy.
Why do not we get out?
Because this is where the sound came.
Jesus Christ.
Hello!
Is there anyone here?
Somebody's kidding us.
If someone is here to enjoy
us, no joke!
I'll call the police!
We have the right to be here!
We have permission, and you do not!
Lower your voice. I'm trying to talk!
Calm down guys. This is something real.
I will use the EVP.
What's your name?
What do you want?
You are in the room with us?
Where are you?
Come on, Sasha. Add to give.
"What's your name?"
"What do you want?"
"Are you in the room with us?"
"Where are you?"
What's that sound? What is this?
What the fuck was that?
No way! I recorded it.
Sasha!
Please, please, I
want to go back to the entrance!
I played some shit!
Was some shit
breathe with me!
We gotta go, gotta go now!
Wait, wait a second.
Wait for what?
We shot this program to what?
Five episodes?
And we've never seen anything like it before.
I do not care!
I just want to get out of here!
Houston, going down there
and turns right ok?
I'd rather be down there.
No, no.
I need another face in the camera.
I'm really scared, I think
I can not do this ...
Be a fucking work ok?
Retains the character.
We found something here.
I do not do that.
Ok, I'll be back. I'll go with Houston.
No no. You come with me, come on.
What are you doing?
Are you kidding? Did you see that?
We could find thousands of things!
Make millions ($$)!
Even the moments
this same corridor
undeniable proven track record
of paranormal activity.
Sasha was terrified because
a ghost touched her hair.
Let's try to make contact.
Spirit, which hangs in the hallway
to beg
show us a sign.
Show yourself!
Please!
If you're still here
us, give us a sign.
It plays a sound or
in my hair.
Do you see anything?
No. Wait. Give me the light ... no, nothing.
Not you dare ask me ...
We are a team.
I think it disappeared.
Honestly, that is
all very funny ...
with these games that
we are preaching ...
Well, I do not know.
Come on, do something.
Have done before, do it again.
Are you fucking scared?
Jesus Christ. Forget it.
Lance! Disappeared ...
is enjoying with us ...
Shut up! Stop saying shit scenes.
Relax.
We could go home now?
Lance, some people try
answers all of life.
Ok
TC, what time is it?
04:40
Let's go home.
Folks, we have footage that arrive.
Why do not we take everything and get out?
Let's go home.
You have everything saved? Yes.
I think it's right, up ahead.
Are you sure?
Yes, that's all. That's all.
Is this the way, right?
Shit, it's a dead end.
Personal.
Shit.
Not here.
Come on, come on!
Come on TC admits ...
What are applications?
We're not lost.
We're not lost,
we came here ...
Matt! Matt! We lost shovel.
I need some information ...
Why the hell is he not responding?
I'm not going there. TC! Why?
Because let's go back here.
If we go in one direction,
'll get there ok?
What? North?
I went around, and there
the corner is where
was the bathtub.
He knows where we are.
've Been here since
TC were here.
Explain to me when
saw this tub.
Not the same bathtub!
I know it is not.
TC, get up, go.
He said six hours was not it?
You'll sleep here? Kenny is at 6 right?
I can not wait.
I can not wait, can not wait.
I will not walk in darkness.
I can not wait.
Where are they?
Shit.
Where have you been?
Do not hear me calling you?
* All the talk at the same time! *
We lost ourselves.
We do not hear the walkie-talkies?
I do not hear the radio call?
No, not heard. You hear? No.
Because we locked Lance?
Lance!
Because they had to lock
the fucking door?
Holy shit!
What are you seeing? What is it?
Her hair. Oh shit.
Fuck.
I'll download it
to the computer.
No, Matt, we do not have time.
Take in the chambers
Still, all come together.
Guys, let's stand up
and begin to fix everything.
Let's get ready to
when Kenny arrived.
Someone help me?
Please? No no.
I need everyone
down here, sorry.
I know.
You have a radio? Yes, I have a radio.
Working? I hope so.
Do you hear that? Yes, that's great,
Be right back, okay? Ok man.
Do not go without me.
Okay, it's time to get out of here.
Fuck!
What the fuck!
Lance, are you there?
Personally, I found something here.
Hello!
Lance!
Guys, stop playing!
The morning is now approaching.
We have not seen anything paranormal
this last hour.
Grave Encounters,
I am Lance Preston.
Again. No, we do not have ...
Again.
Grave Encounters,
I am Lance Preston.
That's all I have.
I can not do this anymore.
No matter, tomorrow with the light
the morning will be much better.
That sounds good.
Where is Matt, anyway?
Why is it taking so long?
Matt?
Matt? Are you there?
Matt? Lance!
The radio was not working before.
Personally, I know this
will sound stupid ...
I'm the last person who wants
back to walk these halls
It's dark, it can
have fallen and have been hurt.
She's right, he may be hurt.
Folks, we have to go look for the.
Very well.
This is ridiculous. Let's look it up.
TC takes the camera.
Sasha takes the camera. Why?
If we do this is
good that shot it.
Thanks for your help.
Hey! By the way, not
is easy to get here
alone, I tell you right now.
Jesus Christ.
Matt!
Matt! Matt! Matt!
What the fuck?
Shit!
Why is this shit
scattered all around?
Fuck.
Okay, okay, okay.
Why he left
the equipment here?
Should not have done.
He should be tidying up.
He must be here somewhere.
TC going there, Sasha
and I will go here.
Why we do this?
It is a terrible idea.
He has to be here, not
would leave things around ...
Sasha comes to me.
TC goes by that side.
This looks like my room after
arguing with my girl!
Matt, where are you man?
I want to go home, that's enough!
Have we scared you are!
I am looking for cigarettes.
Come on, Matt!
Not funny man.
It will take the horns.
Matt! Come on, buddy!
Look what my wife will kill me!
It's late! Come on man.
You better be dead
than to die.
Matt. I'm not kidding! Where are you?
What the fuck?!
Lance! Sasha!
Shit! What happened, what happened?
What, what? No, no.
You okay man?
Raise me. What?
Raise me.
I swear, someone ...
I was pushed ok?
Someone pushed me fucking!
I was on the stairs, the
Matt's looking, I looked
down, and something pushed me
was breaking the neck.
Oh my God.
I looked back and there was nothing there.
These are things to enjoy with us.
It has been like this all night
Call him! Call Kenny!
What are you waiting for?
Okay, okay!
League now. I'll call ok? Take it easy.
Jesus Christ.
Are you okay? No, I'm fine!
Holy shit!
I have no network, your attempt.
Good!
Good shit!
What the hell are you doing TC?
What do you think I'm doing?
Come help me.
You can not break the door! Then see!
We can not damage the building,
we are responsible for this.
Wait! The man can not see shit!
Then shovel?
This will go out of your paycheck!
You think I care? No!
Shit man!
I'm sick of this shit,
want to go home
I lie down and sleep.
This program is your only man.
Put the fucking camera on the floor
and help me.
Help me.
Ok
Need my help? No.
We're fine.
Shit, the three ok?
One, two, three ...
Fuck!
Are you pushing? Yes I am.
One, two, three ...
What the fuck?!
No, this is the fucking entry!
This entry is the shit!
We got here right?
Yes, this is the entrance.
This is not right.
This is impossible.
It was here that we got right?
It was here that brought things.
This makes no sense.
Makes no sense.
It was here we come.
It's just a hallway ...
I do not know ...
He should have gone to get around, should
on the other side of the building.
Lance!
Are the same ports.
I'm getting tired of this staff.
Yes!
Houston, hold it.
Hold that, please.
Be careful with your leg
careful with your leg!
Shut up, you stay where you only the
look and not do anything!
Okay, okay!
What's wrong with you?
One, two, three ...
Fuck!
What is there to say?
What's up Cock?
Perhaps this is the way
for the emergency exit.
Houston shut the fuck up shit!
Shut the fuck up shit!
This, you see?
Move over.
This work is man!
Go la ... You did?
Give me a minute ok?
Oh fuck!
We are here fucking locked!
Let's get a tool.
We try to take the bars.
I have a toolbox.
But it's in the bag, out there!
There was you who wanted to lock in?
Fucking amazing idea!
Obviously all
windows have bars.
No, no! The window up there!
There was no bar do you?
We go there.
Come have my faith!
What time is it Sasha?
8:44
You gotta be fucking kidding me!
I spotted you fucking? Got it?!
8:44 pa are!
I have an audition tomorrow!
Nobody cares to you
or with your fucking
nor with the career
hearing your shit!
Guys, let me
think for a minute!
It makes no sense, it's all fucked!
I checked the time of
Sunrise last night.
What are you trying to say shit?
Should begin to be
clear from the 7:45.
But it's still night.
Still is the night ...
makes no sense!
There's no joke man.
Shut up!
It makes no sense.
Get them out of this building! Please!
Somebody help us!
Ok ok. Ok let's be rational?
A building is old right?
It is an old building can
to be an anomaly
power that made the mess
our clocks fastest ...
So if this does not
this would be hours yet.
This would explain why
it is still dark,
and why Kenny
has not yet appeared.
Electric anomaly!
That idea sucks!
Why come to the
your ideas of rationalism?
This is not an audition for any of the
your science fiction movies!
There is nothing rational here.
It is as rational as
anything else here.
I checked my phone e. ..
And mark 13:12 hours.
Is 13:12 pm
I do not think is right.
But I think that occurred to me ...
I do not know. They are all
are so tired
to take a nap.
Are taking a break.
Let's wait until Kenny appears.
I do not know how he
we will find.
Makes no sense.
I have not slept for about 20 hours.
I'll stop now for a bit e. ..
I take a nap.
What the fuck?!
Houston, what is your problem man?
It was not me!
What are you doing, man?
What happened?
Oh my God!
Someone or something just
from our lights.
We are in total darkness.
All we
remains are the lanterns and
the lights of the cameras.
What a waste.
I checked my phone.
St. 8 pm.
We slept for 7 hours.
The TC was going to eat a sandwich e. ??..
They have to see it.
Lance! It smells bad
shut that shit!
What are you doing? Close it there!
All our food is so but
we still have plenty of water so ...
I do not know, we should be fine.
Why not try to go through the tunnels?
Kenny said that the tunnels
unite all the buildings.
Maybe we can find a
Output in other buildings.
You see the Great Wall of China?
I'm not going to the tunnels ...
If the lights go out we're fucked.
Remember when you asked me
to record the sunset?
I saw a fire exit.
If we ascend to the roof,
maybe we can go down the
climbing and general merchandise here.
So how?
We will stay here or ...
I do not care what we
only do we get out of here man!
I do not want to be here.
Guys, want to do all this?
On the roof! Okay, okay!
Let's get the equipment
whole, and let's go.
Give me a little personal light.
Sorry.
Let's here?
Lance? Where? No, no, no!
TC said you knew where it was.
I said nothing!
Do not put the blame on me.
I do not know where it was said.
I said I had stairs.
What does that
matter now?
That's why we came.
I saw the outside.
Ok! Fuck!
I can not do it guys!
What the fuck was that?!
Hello! Someone up here?
TC! Is there?
I do not ask questions.
Stairs or not?
Let's get together.
Listen, keep the light
connected in front of me.
Move it, move it go!
Get out of my fucking face!
Out of my way!
Wait guys! Slowly.
What's wrong with you man?
Yes! Yes! (Access to roof)
No way!
Shut up and secure it. I see!
It's solid ass!
What do you think?
It seems that there is a long time?
Makes no sense.
Fuck!
The fucking camera away from me!
What do you think? I do not know, I do not know.
Just left of the stairs.
Was completely sealed at the top!
I will document this
all, when we leave
here, people will
want to see it.
See it!
Here we climbed the stairs, right?
This puts us on the 4th floor.
We came here, we
be here at least, right?
Are you sure? I do not know ...
TC, this ... Lance! Lance!
What, what?
We are here? Can not ...
Nor is there stairs!
It means nothing.
This means that
we are on the 1st floor.
Remember that we
we came here right?
TC, can you film it?
Yes, I'm shooting.
This is so fucked!
Fuck! What, what?
What the fuck? Did you hear that?
Did you hear? What the fuck was that?
What is this? Matt? Matt?
Fuck! Matt! On this side!
Matt, are you?
Staff will return! Matt!
Not here. Not here!
That just move?!
Let's fuck out of here!
We had all day to try
find a ladder.
I do not know.
We could not find any.
This building is a maze of shit!
That's what the TC says. It is as if this
will always
change around us.
We have not yet
find Matt.
I do not know if he is okay.
We should not be seeing so much shit!
We are all tired, hungry.
We are trying to sleep again.
This time we are sleeping in shifts.
So it can always be one to watch.
TC, you're writing? Yes.
We rise now.
You should see this!
Off the fucking camera!
Come Sasha!
We have to document everything.
People have to see it.
Caution! Caution!
Sasha, we will take it,
you have to understand ...
It is impossible for anyone
have come here and
have done it without us
We give for nothing.
Cut! Cut shovel there.
Matt!
I swear I heard.
Hello!
See? I told you that was
fucking heard! Alive.
Matt! Are you okay?
Can you hear me?
I'm frozen!
Tell us where you are alone.
We'll pick you up!
Shit!
No longer there!
We have to find it.
How do we find the
if not managed
find your way
to the front door?
We should not be far off.
These walkie-talkies are a shit.
How do you know what is it?
Matt! Are you here?
Sorry, sorry, sorry! Fuck!
Matt! We hear you!
Where are you? Fuck!
Sasha tries in all
frequencies.
This is weak, has no
that much reach.
How far is that
what was said?
I did not say, was not
specifications.
Estimate? 200-300-400?
200 meters to get a clear sound.
Maybe 300 meters ...
We will continue to walk.
Before starting to cause noise.
Stay together, come on.
It's a dead end!
A dead end.
Where are you fucking?
Listen people this is
completely useless right?
If it were to find it ...
the scope ...
Fuck!
What the fuck was that?!
It was Matt!
What are you doing, man?
Lance! Lance!
Oh fuck!
Do something man.
Lance! Lance!
Who are you? What are you doing here?
Turn off the light! Turn off the light!
Have you seen the fucking her face?!
Shut your fucking mouth!
Have you seen the fucking her face!?
Why is this happening?
Oh my God!
Shit! Shit!
We are lost!
Houston lost the fucking!
Matt!
Guys!
Sasha!
TC!
Lance!
Is anybody there?!
Help me! Guys!
We are here today.
The Houston disappeared.
Matt wanted to find the
radio but he does not respond.
What the fuck was that?
Just go to weird shit
around us. Fuck!
I do not know how long it will last.
We are not alone.
My name is on the bracelet!
How is my name
is in the band?!
Fuck!
First scratches on
my back and now ...
What the fuck!
When we wake,
we had one of these ...
have to do this.
Fuck you!
You wanted to get out of there was not?
I did not want!
Vieste is not it? I did not want!
That's it! What an idiot!
What does this mean?
It means we're fucked.
Get it? It is what it means.
This is crazy.
This is crazy shit!
Do not look! Jesus Christ!
What the fuck?!
Is there something! What the fuck?
Enough already!
It is as if we walked in circles.
Still can not find
or Matt Houston.
Stop it! What do you mean, stop what?
Are you kidding?
Fuck more to your program!
I am not part of it ... I just ...
I'm just documenting ok?
People will want to see this!
Matt disappeared and the Houston right?
We have to focus on out of here
and find them.
And you're still doing that shit!
Okay folks, let's stop a bit.
I just ...
Fuck it, let's bazaar!
You can not run faster?
Let's fuck!
Oh my God! Come on!
No, no, no, no! Arise!
Are you crazy?! Arise!
Arise!
I can not, I can not! You know!
Arise, Arise!
I know, I know.
Go recovers. Do what you have to do!
We must continue on!
Damn! What, what?
I found something! Come here!
That are waiting for fucking? Come on!
Look!
Matt? Is he right? I do not know man!
Matt, get up!
So you close
shit the room!
Man, to the jokes!
Matt are you okay?
Oh fuck!
The patient has some kind
phobia in childhood.
Matt! Oh my God!
Arise! Let's go!
Come on, get up!
Let us take you back!
Come on! Here, here!
Come on!
Put him in bed, leave it there.
You see anything? No, we're fine.
Where were you?
Where did you get those clothes?
Damn, talk with us!
Look at his wrist.
Matt? Matt?
How did these wounds?
Matt! What they'll do?
What did you see?
I'm sick of this!
We have to leave.
Yes of course we can leave.
We can go.
When we are better.
What? What do you mean
"When we are better"?
What the fuck does that mean?
I was not ready.
The process is slow. But the patient
was responding to treatment.
He's crazy.
Must be stoned or so.
Not to say
make sense.
TC! Shut up! Do not tell me to shut up.
Do not be sad it's okay.
It will help you too.
Oh my God!
TC! Go check the door!
I've done it.
Go on!
Come on man.
Make sure that nothing is here!
We found Matt.
It's completely fucked.
The TC is still here with us.
What?
It's okay.
What are you doing?
I do not feel well.
There is something wrong with me.
Yes, you're a bit hot.
You must have a fever.
It takes a lot of water. Thank you.
Get some sleep. I can not sleep.
And I think we'll ever get.
What the hell was this?
Jesus!
Come on!
Come on ... go!
Quick, here!
You see anything? What is it?
There is blood in the bathtub!
What? Come on!
We go where man? Come on!
What the fuck?!
Matt? Matt?
What do these fucking?
TC! Stay away from the bathtub.
Come on Matt!
TC! What is it
Cock is doing?
Fuck, I do not know!
Oh my God! Oh my God!
Help me! Help me!
Turn the tub!
Gone!
Fucking disappeared!
Suddenly gone! Without a trace!
Shit! No, no!
It is a lift!
Open it! Open it!
It's just the echo of the elevator.
If we reach
tunnels, perhaps
can get out by
other building.
Go there!
Fuck! Fuck!
Hear! Watch out Matt,
I'll get some tools.
Stay here.
What the fuck is that?
Jesus! It is a language? Fuck!
What's up? What's up?
Bring the light, points to there.
Here is a ladder. Head down.
How do we take Matt?
I'll go first and you come
then with Matt ok?
Get away! It is back there.
Lance! Lance!
Where is the button?
Oh here it is!
Is gone?
I do not know, disappeared.
Ok ok. Let's go.
Where is he? Matt!
Jesus! He jumped! He jumped!
Come on!
Relax. You're done!
It's okay. It's okay.
The tunnels are here!
Finally we arrived.
I can not. I can not go.
Come on, Sasha!
Kenny said that connected
all buildings.
You have to do this to me.
I can not do this alone!
Ok? Ok
It is close to me and let's here.
Should not be too far away.
Okay, off you go.
No, no! We've already been here!
We should not be here! What the fuck?!
I can not go!
Wait a minute!
I want my mother!
It's day ...
What day is today?
I do not know what day it is.
We spent the whole day
walking in one direction.
We did not get anywhere.
It pains me much to leg.
Sasha could.
It will not be able to continue.
Who's there?
Who are you?
Sasha?
Sasha, where are you?
Where are you?
Fuck!
What do you want?
I'm running out
battery bit by bit.
Now, I can only connect
lights when needed.
But I do not need more light!
Just me walking straight ahead.
He could continue to walk for hours.
It's like a game.
How far can you go?
If someone is watching this ...
Fuck you!
Fuck you, fuck!
This was for you.
Do not you hear anything? Do not you hear anything?
Do not you hear anything?
I'm alive!
I woke up e. ..
I do not know how long
I was sleeping but ...
There is a door!
Look!
This is not happening.
I must be crazy!
Jesus!
It is not possible!
No! I'm not crazy!
I'm not loco! No! No! No!
I'm so much better now!
Finally, I can go home!
Grave Encounters. I'm Lance Preston.
Cut!
Subtitling and Translation: MrJonny and
Rafaela
Resync DVDRip:
Shakota
www.NapiProjekt.pl - nowa jakoœæ napisów.
Napisy zosta³y specjalnie dopasowane do Twojej wersji filmu.