Mohamed_sayed1993@yahoo.com
*Araby4All*
Oh..
Oh.
Mom, l'm home five seconds,
you're already cooking.
Come here, l got something
to show you.
-Well, wait a minute.
-Outside.
Wait a minute.
l haven't finished
cooking your dinner.
Yeah, it's a surprise.
lt's all right.
Come on.
Shut your eyes.
Good. Shut 'em.
-Okay, you ready?
-Mm-hmm.
-You sure?
All right.
Whoa. Turning.
Oh, it's cold.
lt's not cold.
Even the chickens are cold.
Okay, steps.
We have steps.
-Ready? One...
-One...
-...two...
-...and three.
-...three!
Okay, look.
-No, that's not it.
-Well...
Shut 'em. Shut 'em.
Come on.
Now, Frank...
h-how far are we gonna go? Ooh.
Come on, come on. Come on...
You're all right.
Sweetie, the dinner's
just gonna...
The dinner's fine.
Okay.
Almost, almost...
now...
now!
Oh, it's ...
-ls that beautiful?
-Oh, it's ...
-Huh?
-lt's lovely.
l know. l won it
in a poker game in ltaly.
-Huh?
-Well...
well, drive it carefully, honey.
l will.
-Enjoy it...
-l will.
but be careful.
God, Ma, you're such a mom.
You ready?
We're going for a ride.
Oh, no, no.
l have to finish dinner.
Ma, Ma, one ride.
Oh. Oh...
Watch this, Ma, no hands.
Oh, Frank, don't do that!
l wouldn't do that.
Come on.
You!
l'm in for five.
Thank you, gentlemen.
My pleasure.
Hey, girl. Get in here.
Whoa!
-Oh!
-Whoa!
This is fun, right?
Maybe.
Yeah.
-Ooh, careful.
-Hey, l'm driving here.
l'm home.
Whoo!
Mortar's coming!
Mortar's coming in!
Machine gun, right flank!
Medic!
That's when you saw them, huh?
Well, it works.
My Spike works.
Okay. Okay.
Easy, easy.
Okay.
-Take it easy.
No!
l've got a headache.
Have you got some Wite-Out?
Ma!
You don't know
what it is you
got yourself into, bud,
but you're a long way from home.
Oh, but it's so confusing.
Where to go,
where to go... yes...
Ma!
Oh, bother.
What the hell are you?
They're doodles.
Cartoons?
Don't get too close, Doc.
l can't believe what l've done.
My Spike was supposed
to send me to your world,
but instead you're here.
This man's not dangerous
to anyone.
As for us, son, we may not
be real to you as yet...
...but we will be.
You've come
to a whole new world.
You've done something
extremely rare.
You see,
you're in a real place
called the Cool World.
Hmm.
Oh. How strange.
Say " ah."
Ah.
But when it comes to making
the trip in the body...
Did you hear about the wolf
that built the studio?
-No, not...
-...l've never seen it before.
Oh!
Oh, my goodness.
l'm sorry about your mother.
You're cartoons.
You're not real.
Oh-ho, we're real, all right.
The possibility
of interworld travel
has been an obsession of mine
for many, many years.
Ho-ho-ho-ho-ho!
Hey, Doc, wait.
This man is not for you.
He's not a police problem.
He's a mystery of science.
And a hero to boot.
l ain't no hero.
Oh, don't be so sure, friend.
With this hole l've opened,
there could be all kinds
of problems. Ha-ha.
They call me Doc Whiskers.
What's your name, son?
l'm Frank Harris.
What did you do
in your world?
l was a soldier.
Oh, you could be useful
here when l'm gone.
Where are you from?
Um, Vegas.
Tomorrow we're out of here.
You're just a drawing, Holli,
but without you,
l'd never have made it.
Oh, you look good tonight, babe.
lt's time you came to me, Jack.
Come to me.
Ooh, baby!
-Hey-ya, hey-ya.
l've been waiting for you,
darlin'
-Huh?
-Hmm?
Uh, Sparky,
uh, whatcha up to, huh?
What makes you think
l'd tell a little punk like you?
Why, he's going soft
for that tomato.
Uh... w-w-what's her name?
H-H-Holli or something. Yeah.
Enough out of you, kitty.
You're too young
to be thinking about girls.
Especially that girl.
Here.
A bunch of wooden nickels.
Don't spend them all
in one place.
W-W-What?
Philip flew the coop
last night.
Hey, Molina! Hey, Molina!
Come over here.
Did you step in it?
Hey, there's
a flower on your head.
There's are lots of...
Hey.
Look out!
l hate it when she meets guys
without tellin' me.
l light up like
Neon
Just a tiny section of your
affection in my direction
Will do
Ooh.
-Detective Harris.
What a pleasure.
l was just rehearsing.
Hello, Holli.
This is an exact replica
of the dress Marilyn Monroe wore
in Let's Make Love.
Oh!
l know that movie by heart.
The girl gets get everything
by the end of it.
Everything she ever wanted.
lt's real.
l mean it.
l even saw
a copyright date on it.
Rumor has it, Holli,
that you had a noid visitation
at the Slash Club last night.
lt was just a mind slip.
Nothin' special.
You're just a regular
true believer
in law and order, huh?
Give me a couple, Jack.
Come on, let's go.
Beat it, copper.
Yeah.
-Go on, beat it.
-Beat it...
Just doing my job.
-Come on let's go.
-Come on.
Hey, Frank?
Don't go just yet.
Come here.
l got somethin' to show you.
Guess what?
l've seen your little
museum of Vegas.
And don't start in
with your Vegas Vinnie rap.
l've heard it.
lt bores me.
Vegas Vinnie made the Spike--
crossed over and became the
owner of the Union Plaza Hotel.
Vegas Vinnie
is a fairy tale, Would.
Doodle moms tell it to doodle
kids to help them go to sleep.
lt could all be true.
You got over here.
So why couldn't he make it
over there?
Or for that matter,
why couldn't l?
You could help me.
There'll be no crossovers
while l'm around.
l've got news for you, pal.
l am not your ordinary doodle.
l've been checking up
on what these noid dames
have got going
in the real world,
and l want it!
Don't you see?
They're real.
They've got power.
When they touch something,
they feel it.
And when
they taste something...
...they really taste it.
And when they do it
with a man...
...they really do it.
Ooh...
What can l say, sweetheart?
l can't help you out
in that department.
Well, don't you see?
Believe it.
l've had enough.
Oh, yeah? Fine.
You don't want to help me?
Then l'll find somebody else
that will.
Like that noid cartoonist,
Jack Deebs.
He's been around a lot lately.
Yes, he has.
The whack-a-do who thinks
he invented this place.
What do you think l've been
talking about, Holli?
Well, l'd watch it, honey,
'cause there might be
two of you before long.
l'm going to tell you this once
'cause you got to be
smarter than you look.
You're dealing with shit here
that's way over your head.
Yeah...
Now, keep your legs crossed
and forget about the real world.
Hmm!
Thank you for your time.
Would you look at those legs!
Doh!
Hey...!
Yeah.
Stay cool, man.
l'm out of here.
Hey, Bobby, let's go.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hey.
What are you guys doing?
Get off the lawn.
-Shut up.
-What?
Get your ball
and get out of here.
No!
Hi, Gail, it's me, Jennifer.
What do you mean?
l'm here.
Yeah, l'll call you
later tonight, okay?
Thank you.
Oh, boy. Another addict, huh?
Uh-huh.
My God, it's you, isn't it?
You're Jack Deebs, the creator
of Cool World, right?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, my God.
l can't believe this.
Do you have any idea
what kind of an inspiration
your work is to people?
No, l, uh...
l mean, l know people--
friends of mine who want to be
Holli Would
when they grow up.
-Really?
-Yeah.
Sparks, the goons, all of them.
Oh, man.
Your stuff, it's like crucial
spiritual nourishment
for people.
They live on it.
Oh, man.
lf my boss was here,
he'd , like, throw himself
on the ground right now
and give you a lifetime
gift certificate
-to this place.
-Really?
Oh, yeah.
He's kind of crazy.
Hey, would you sign this
for him?
Thank you.
Thanks. Oh, go ahead.
Cool, Mike.
So, um...
you living here now again?
Yeah, l just, uh...
l just got back.
Yeah?
Well, um, when
this place closes down,
l go down to this place
right off the strip for coffee.
They, uh, read poetry,
do jazz, you know.
Problem is, you know,
l just, uh...
l just got, uh,
got back into town, as l said,
and l, uh, haven't really
got my feet, uh,
you know,
on the ground.
Uh... but it's really
nice of you to ask.
-Sure.
-Thank you.
Hey, Deebs,
why don't you do a book
on that guy you murdered?
You know, that guy
you found in bed with your wife.
So, uh, what do l...?
lt's on the house.
Oh, okay. Thanks.
So maybe, uh, some other time?
Thanks.
Who are you?
Who am l?
Who are you, yes.
l'm , uh...
l'm , uh, Jack Deebs.
Really?
l didn't realize that.
-Nice meeting you, Jack.
-Nice to meet you.
Stay well.
-Yeah.
-Thank you.
See ya.
Hey, bright eyes, yo!
You going to pay for that?
Jack!
Gee whiz, sis.
l don't know.
lt looks like
such fun down there.
All l need is a four
and l win.
lt's a four, yay!
Oops... snake eyes!
You lose.
But... but l won.
You lost.
Pay up.
Well, my dear,
we can always
take it out in trade.
Ooh-hoo-hoo!
Listen here, fleabag,
pay up or your inside...
is gonna be your outside.
Whee!
Look at that!
Slash?
ls that you?
Put her there, pal.
Get away from me!
Ooh, l look
fabulous, honey!
Get away from me!
You lost it, man!
That's why you're here.
Get away!
-Ooh, darling, l want your hair.
-Get off!
Ooh, and your neck, ooh!
-Ooh, l could just squeeze it.
Let me see your ear, sweetie.
Oh, don't be shy.
Get off!
He loves me, he loves me not.
He loves me...
mmm!
He loves me.
Now, be nice.
Nice.
Ooh, hello, Holli.
Ooh, you never cease
to amaze me.
How fabulous your hair
looks today.
Boy...
can she knock it back.
Hey, hey, how about
saving some for me?
Please!
Hey, come on, come on!
Holli wants to get
a look at you. Come on.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, that's a nice little boy.
Come, darling, she awaits.
A little closer.
Let her see you.
Ah, yeah.
Welcome to my world...
big man.
Am l...
Am l dreaming?
Am l dreaming you?
Or are you dreaming me?
l drew you.
l made you.
Hey, l...
maybe l can erase you.
You wouldn't erase me, baby.
You're too hungry
for what l got.
No, l'm , uh...
l'm trying to quit.
Since it's only a dream,
indulge your
fantasies, Jack.
You're so real, so strong.
You could help comb my hair,
tickle my mind, and...
Yes, l have failed.
Thank you.
l'm calm now.
Boo-hoo, boo-hoo!
Filthy bad guys
didn't play fair.
l want you to tear and rip
their miserable faces inside out
till their mother
doesn't recognize them.
Pretty please?
Let's go, guys.
Come on.
Wait for me!
l got news for you, baby.
l'm made of ink...
but l'm no dream.
Ah!
What'd you do that for?
Because l dig you.
This is a long dream.
lsn't it, Jack?
The poppers.
Let's burn.
What?
Let's go.
Come on.
To the left.
Do you like it, Deebs?
Yeah.
Course you do.
This is your idea
of heaven, right?
Yeah, it's , uh...
it's amazing, it's incredible.
But l won.
Little late for a lady
to be out on the streets,
don't you think?
l got a couple of questions
for you, miss.
Aw, come on, Officer.
Let it slide, would ya?
l'm tired.
Word is, you got
a thing for noids.
Yeah, l got a thing
for noids.
But what's it to you,
tough guy?
Baby, baby, you don't
know how tough it is.
You're late.
Aw, you're killing me.
Why are you so beautiful?
Mm-mm-mm.
What's wrong?
You don't look right.
Aw, it's Holli.
l think she's in heat again.
With that noid from last night?
Oh, don't worry about it.
You know that. Wh-Why you always
want to bust...?
Gotcha.
All right.
Where you wanna go?
Uh, movies?
Uh, dinner...?
We have abused the privilege...
Our color is fading.
Repent, repent, all toons.
Listen to me.
The end is near.
Hey, Boss, we gotta go. We...
A thousand pardons.
An informer told me
he's here again.
Holli and the goons got him.
He's not just coming
through on a dream.
Perhaps it is time
to pursue other avenues.
Right, let's hit the bricks.
Yeah, yeah, l know.
Be careful, Frank.
Oh, l think she's partial
to you.
Yeah, but facts is facts.
She's a doodle, and l'm not.
Eh, l guess,
but did l ever tell you
about the time
l took up with the most
delightfully-stacked hussy
from the projects?
Yeah.
Right. Where to, Boss?
The club.
All right.
Aye, aye, aye!
Hey, Baby, how you doing?
Chico?
Chico, is that you?
l ain't no Chico, runt.
And no noids.
He's with me.
Sorry, baby.
No noids.
He is with me, too.
Can't let the neighbors
push us around, can we?
Freeze, asshole.
Uh-oh!
Cool World Police.
Ooh!
Copper!
Up against the wall.
Get your hands off me.
Where are your manners, Harris?
You, be quiet.
Hey, who are you?
Who are you?
l didn't create you.
No shit, Sherlock.
What'd you do with this, Deebs?
l'm a cartoonist.
l drew all this.
l have visions, l...
l have visions.
l translate this.
You do nothing, man.
This place exists
with or without you.
You believe me, right?
l'm not one of your creations.
Don't believe him!
No, you're not pretty enough.
Good one.
Have a seat.
Ordinary fountain pen, right?
Yeah.
Wrong. Around here...
Sit down!
Around here, this
can be a big nuisance.
You thirsty, Nails?
Whoa!
Get it?
One should be careful
how they wave this thing.
No, l don't get it.
Of course
you don't get it,
because you're a wackadoo.
But here you are, Jack.
And around here,
everything goes.
Everything
except one thing!
-Yeah, what?
-Yeah, yeah,
we know.
What's that?
noids do not have sex
with doodles.
Right? noids do not
have sex with doodles!
lt's the oldest law
in Cool World.
l've never had to enforce it,
but you cross that line,
and l'll slap you around,
make you piss like a puppy.
Jack...
you think she's got a thing
for you, don't you?
That's sweet.
But don't flatter
yourself.
She's a waste of ink.
Oh, yeah?
The truth is,
she's been after me
and every other noid
who's come through here.
lt's just that no one's
been insane enough
to get involved with her.
You keep your pencil
in your pocket.
You know what l mean?
Yeah.
l'll remember that, Officer.
You can go now.
Where did you get your
hair done, by the way?
Get out of here.
All right, the show's over!
So, Harris,
you could have beat him.
You could have beat him.
You could of been somebody.
Oh, you're not yellow,
are you, Harris?
You did well, Jack.
Hey, sexy.
Mmm. lt's the man
with the badge.
ln the flesh.
Don't remind me.
Oh-ho-ho.
How can l help it?
-Ah.
-Mmm.
What are you doing to me?
You're messing me up.
Oh, honey, you're tense.
lt's Holli again, isn't it?
Yeah, Miss Holli
Would if she could.
That dame...
You heard anything?
Now, you know l don't listen
to that sleazy cow.
Mmm!
Don't . Just don't .
Well, why?
Because we can never finish it,
Lonette, you know?
lt-it-it's frustrating.
l'm , uh...
l'm like a... l'm like a plug
without a socket, you know?
Hey, Frank?
Hey, what?
Did you ever do it
in the Real World?
Do you ever think about
going back there so you can?
No.
No way.
Maybe you and me?
l can't have that
in the Real World.
Uh-uh. l can't live without you.
But l can't be with you,
you know?
lt's , jus... agh!
What do you do, huh?
What do you do?
Well, then...
we're just going to have
to pretend then, aren't we?
Hey, Boss!
Ooh!
Boss!
l heard you, Nails.
Oh, my God, Boss!
l wouldn't do it!
Oh! Whew!
Hey, Boss, did l ever
tell you about...?
Shut up, Nails.
Jack.
Come home, baby.
No... no... no...
No. No! No! No! No!
Glad you dropped in.
Well, here we are--
Holli's humble abode.
Do you think she'll let us in?
Forget it!
This party
is by invitation only.
This door has got an attitude.
How much further?
Oh, uh... l'd say
we're halfway up.
Or halfway down.
Right.
God, l hate heights.
Nails, this is no time
to catch a cold.
lt is not a cold, Boss.
l am allergic to clouds.
What?!
Ah... ah... ah...
Oh... oh...
Choo!
Pull this?
Ah... ah...
Don't even think about it.
Ah...
choo!
That step's smashingly good!
Smashingly!
Yeah.
Make sure no one
gets out this door.
Oh! Oh! Absolutemont,
Boss.
Oh!
Stretcher bearers!
Whoo-ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh!
Well, hello, Harris.
Welcome to the party.
And what a swell party it is.
Thanks for having me.
l should have known
riffraff like yourself
would be involved
in this equation, Sparks.
What equation
is that, Harris?
l've discovered
that if you look for trouble,
you find it.
What's your problem?
Bad childhood.
Where's the noid?
You're the only noid here,
Harris.
Ooh!
Last warning.
You stay away from the noid,
or you're closed
for business permanently.
Have a splendid evening.
You want to know
what it is about you
that really kicks my ass,
Harris?
How about my foot?
Well, you prance around here
waving that gun around
like you're some big deal.
And all this time,
you could cross over
to the Real World,
but you haven't got the guts.
You don't have what
it takes to be real.
That makes you
a wimp in my book.
You may be right, Slick.
Be content with the cards
you've been dealt.
Oh!
What's the deal?
lt's getting serious, Nails.
Holli.
We got to find Jack Deebs.
Right.
Go for it!
Should l get the door for you,
Jack?
Oh, yeah!
Oh, Yeah!
Go for it, Jack!
You better have an appointment!
Go on, Jack.
He does...
but you don't .
But Holli said we could watch.
Watch what?
Go on up.
Go on.
Bring me a souvenir, Jack.
Hey, Jack.
l've been waiting for you.
You like looking at me, Jack,
don't you?
Yow!
Man is in the bedroom.
Run, girls, run!
Oh-ho! Oh-ho!
-Okay...
-What?
You listen to me, uh, Holli.
That cop, uh, Harris, um,
he said we... we...
can't go any further
than this, Holli.
-l'm so hot for you, Jack.
-Yeah.
Are you going
to follow the rules?
No.
Or are you going to follow...
your instincts?
Yeah.
Oh, but Holli said
we could watch.
l'll be right back.
Yep! Oh, yeah! Oh! Yeah!
Ooh...
Ooh.
Ah... ah...
Mm-hmm.
We're almost there.
Whoa! Okay...
Whoa... whoa!
Whoa!
Ooh!
Holli!
Holli...
Whoa...
Mm, was it good for you?
lt wasn't what l expected.
Y-You gonna go in there
and-and make it up
to Lonette, boss?
Yeah, why not.
The fact is,
she's the best thing that
ever happened to me.
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
Oh, l could put overtime
in on Deebs' Porsche.
l'm tireless.
Forget it.
The goons can't touch him
in Sweet Place,
and we'd just run ourselves
ragged giving him the shadow.
-Well... what should l do?
-Hmm?
Man the phones,
keep pumping our informants.
Somebody might l.D. him.
And if that happens,
you call me.
You call me here or Lonette's ,
my place, l don't know.
Just don't make a move
without me, you got it?
l got it, boss!
Oh!
Come on, let's go, now!
Hey, Lonette...
where's my drink, babe?
You know, l live to serve you.
l heard you
the first ten times.
Hey, come on, l'm -l'm sorry.
Get a little closer here,
babe, give us a kiss.
Say it, don't spray it.
Go away.
l'm out of here!
Tough night?
The usual.
Yeah.
Why you want to hang
around here, huh?
This place should be erased.
Hey... it's a living.
Even a doodle's got to eat.
Why don't you put that arm
around me.
lt's been kind of a tough day.
Oh...
Ooh!
Yeah?
Listen, you sludge hog
excuse for a cop.
Deebs and Holli just made it,
and they're about to make
an unscheduled trip
to the other side.
Ooh... Oh! Doh!
Holli?! Sheesh!
No end of trouble that
a little minx like her can make.
Why, she might damage the entire
interworld matrix or something.
l don't give a doodle!
Just bust her ass!
Ooh, better call Frank.
Better call Frank.
Uh, oh,
l just can't take it anymore.
Where's Frank?!
Frank! Frank Harris?
Looking for Frank!
Frank! Frank!
Ooh-hoo-hoo!
Where is he?! Where is he?!
Oh, no!
Frank!
Frank Harris!
Whoo!
Aah, aah, aah! Frank!
Frank! Frank!
Thank God!
Okay.
Yeah, Nails, what is it?
You having a good time,
boss, eh? Heh-heh-heh!
Yeah, l guess l'm
having a good time.
-Are we having a good time?
-Yeah.
Nails, leave us alone.
Oh, l just love
your little ears.
Okay, Nails, what's the problem?
Ooh! No trouble.
Nothing l can't handle myself.
l was just checking in
with youse. You know.
Yeah. You sure?
All right. Okay, Nails.
-lt's ... incredible.
-Yeah.
No...
No... no...
Oh...
Wait a minute here!
What am l nervous for? Oh!
l could do this job myself!
Hmm.
Mm... mm.
Mm, mm, mm.
Mm.
Ooh-ooh! Ooh! Aah!
Holli, why do we have
to go back?
lt's ... it's so great here.
Oh... but, Jack,
we're noids and...
noids just...just can't
do doodle here and...
l want to do it all, Jack,
and together... together
we're gonna be unstoppable.
Oh.
But you know something
l go to do?
What?
l got to go tell
the boys good-bye.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, they're gonna be
so lost without me.
l bet.
l know you do.
Okay.
Oh, Jack...
l miss you already.
Oh, l know.
-l'll be back.
-Be back soon, okay?
Okay.
Bye.
Oh, yeah.
Jesus! Why the hell
did you do it?!
What, are those curtains
you're wearing?!
Oh, oh, you look horrendous.
You look horrible.
You look like
a high school hippie.
Peace, man.
That's right, boys.
l made it.
Uh... Halt!
Yeah, halt, uh, halt, eeeee...!
in the name of the law!
Eh... halt, l say!
Well, howdy, Nails.
As you see, there have been
some changes around here.
You are a biomorphic menace.
l forbid you to take one step
out of the Cool World.
You eight-armed ink spot.
Who do you think
you're dealing with?
l'm real.
You made it with a noid!
You don't know what you are.
Mark my words, girlie-pie,
you leave here
and it is trouble
for ya two.
l'm leaving, pencil dick.
You just try and stop me.
Don't do it.
Don't do it, girl!
Ah!
Hmm!
Oh, that's so beautiful!
Oh, so bad!
Oh, man, that's gotta hurt!
Oh, a pen job.
Oh. Yeah, yeah, pen me, too.
Pen me, pen me, pen me.
Ah! Oh! Oh, hit me.
Yeah, hit me.
Oh! Hit me again.
Hit me, hit me.
Lover Jack,
it's time to go.
Bounce out of here.
-We got to go.
-Holli... Holli...
Jack, we got to get out of here.
Hold on tight.
Jack?
Oh... Oh, Jack.
l really like it here.
Mmm.
l think l'll go change.
Mom, he may be in trouble.
We got to help him.
Come on, let's go.
lt's none of our business.
lt is our business.
He's our neighbor.
Come on.
Mm, l love her.
l love her.
Hello?
-Hey.
-Hi.
Hey.
This is me.
Holli...
Me.
Um...
Jack.
Uh, lsabelle
and Jennifer Malley,
this is, um...
This is Holli.
-Hello.
-Hi.
Holli's my friend.
This is Jack.
Hey.
Uh...
Holli is, uh...
she's from out of town.
Well, we didn't mean
to bother you.
lt's just...
Well, we were scared
you might be hurt.
No, no, no, uh...
No, but thanks
for asking.
-Well... thanks.
-Jack?
lt's -it's -it's , uh...
it's good to have
nice neighbors.
Nice neighbors.
l'm real.
Yeah, you sure are, honey.
Bye.
She was really
a cheap piece of work.
l don't know, l thought
she was kind of pretty.
You know, l got this
crazy feeling, Mom,
that l know that woman
from somewhere.
He looks full of life to me,
for goodness sakes.
Hey!
What happened, you ink stain?
He had a run-in with a noid,
and then he got inked.
That damn Deebs.
lt was Holli Would.
Holli is a doodle.
Not anymore.
She's made it
with that Deebs asshole.
She's changed.
Now you can buy me more fries,
dick head.
This is gonna be
the biggest shit storm
the Cool World has ever seen.
Round and round l go
Like a leaf on a tide
l should stay away,
but what can l do?
Oh...
Oh. Oh.
So many men. Oh...
And they're real.
Oh, smell.... them.
Holli, Holli...
you're with me, remember?
You know, you can't go
around smelling people.
Yeah, Jack.
You sit.
Hey.
So, uh, what do you
want to drink?
Oh.
Anything they have.
You know, they got
95 different things, Holli.
Mm... whoa.
95?
Uh-huh.
l'll have one of each.
Holli, you know, l'm into having
fun and everything,
but you got to slow down,
okay?
What l want to slow down for?
l'm gonna get everything
l ever wanted.
You think any of these men
are gonna say no to Holli?
Not on your life, pal.
Gentlemen prefer blondes.
Thank you very much,
everybody.
Glad you enjoyed that.
Wonderful old standard.
" Let's Make Love."
Hey! She's with me!
No, she's with us.
Hey!
Stay out!
Hit it.
Uh, Brian, please.
Here we sit and we chatter
What are we thinking of?
-Let's not make with the patter
-Oh, whoa.
Baby
Let's make love
Oh, my, but it's stifling
lf you roar like a lion
l could coo like a dove
lf you're sold, begin buying
Baby
Let's make love
Gosh, it's hot
No, don't turn TV on
lnstead just turn me on
l'll light up like neon...
When your partner gets inked,
you do something about it.
He was your partner,
so you do something.
Well, l'm not buying it.
Well, how about " a man's got to
do what a man's got to do" ?
Can't you just think about me
for a minute, Frank?
l mean, where does this
leave me?
What are you mad about?
Oh!
l'm mad because
you talk about crossing,
and-and you don't even care...
l don't care?
how it makes me feel.
Whoa, whoa.
How do you feel, Lon?
How do you feel?
Left out.
You think l want
to go back there?
You think l want to go back?
Well, why wouldn't you
want to go back?
That's real to you, isn't it?!
Let me tell you something
about over there.
lt hurts over there.
lt-lt's lonely over there.
lt's a war over there.
They got eight million ways
for you to die, hon,
and all of them are permanent.
This is real for me,
this. With you.
And if l want to stay
with you, l got to go back.
Because if Jack Deebs
and Holli Would
are after what
l think they are,
there won't be
any here or there.
Understand, Loni?
No more here.
Just go ahead!
Hey, hey, hey.
l'm comin' back.
Jack.
What's going on?
Something's wrong.
Something's very, very wrong.
No shit, pal.
So what is it?
l mean, l'm ... l'm up there,
and l was just...
l was moving and shaking
with the best of 'em.
And all of a sudden, l was...
l-l went doodle again.
l mean...
Look at this, Ma. No hands!
Oh, Frank, don't do that!
l wouldn't do that.
Come on!
No!
Good luck, Frank.
Please just let me think.
Let me think.
Cool, Jack.
Really cool.
l guess you have a tough time
driving and thinking
at the same time, huh?
Oh!
The Spike of Power!
The what?!
The Spike could heal me.
Ooh, l guess Vinnie put
the Spike
at the top of the casino.
You're nuts.
You are nuts.
Don't say l'm nuts.
l've had enough ego
out of you, pal.
And you used to think
you made me up.
You're thinking
like a doodle, Holli.
There is no Spike of Power.
There's got to be
a Spike of Power.
And l'm going to find it
right now.
No, you're not.
Okay? Yeah.
We're going there, Jack.
No, we're not.
You're a nice fellow, Jack.
Don't piss me off.
Oh, yeah?
What are you going to do
about it, Holli?
Huh?
Goddamn it!
What are you doing here, Harris?
l'm taking you
and the bimbo back.
What are you going to do?
Shoot me?
Why don't you shoot me,
goddamn it!?
Shoot me, Harris.
Go on, shoot...
Don't push me!
You just couldn't take
a piece of good advice,
could you?
No, Jack, you had to listen
to your Johnson.
l've had it with you, Harris.
l've had it with you,
goddamn it!
You've had it with me?!
You've had it with me,
you piece of shit?
You screw us all
for a piece of ass,
and you've had it with me?
Where is she?
Great.
lt's happening, Jack.
Got news for you, Harris.
lt's happening to her, too.
Jack!
Jack, l saw it this time.
-Jack, l saw it. l swear it.
-Jennifer...
l saw this thing.
lt ate your house again.
Remember when we came
over earlier?
Jennifer...
l wasn't imagining things. l...
All right, Jack.
Oh, this is another friend
from out of town?
Uh-huh, yeah.
l-l mean...
What happened to your suit?
What's going on
between this guy and me,
it's -it's -it's kind
of, uh... complex.
l-l can explain it
some other time.
l'll bet.
Look, we got no more time
for Goldilocks here.
Where do we find Holli?
Okay, she went
to the Union Plaza.
-The Spike.
-She went to meet this...
She went to meet
this guy, Vegas Vinnie.
The only problem is,
she took my car, so...
l've got my mom's car.
Let's go, miss.
We're trying
to protect the balance
of the entire known
universe here.
Oh, gee, l guess my mom
won't chuck a fit, then,
if we took it, huh?
Wow!
Miss?
Can l help you, Miss?
l'm looking for Vegas Vinnie.
There's no... there's no
Vegas Vinnie here.
l'm sorry.
He owns the place.
l don't ... l...
There's no Vegas Vinnie here.
l'm sorry.
l-l can't help you.
Do you know Vegas Vinnie?
No.
Sorry.
Do you know Vegas Vinnie?
Vegas Vinnie is a story
based on a real guy--
this doc l met--
when l first went across,
uh, 50 years ago.
Cool World's real?
Neat!
He and l,
we mapped out the tunnel,
the passageway
between both worlds.
And we saw how easily
one could disrupt that balance
and destroy both universes.
Destroy the universe?
When you have
some money to spend,
we'd love to see you, honey.
Until then,
you have to keep out.
l can't ...
Oh!
Uh, pretty-looking sign
we got up there, huh, Miss?
Yeah, that spike in the center.
lt's real bright.
You sound kind of down, Miss.
Uh, have bad luck
at the tables?
Let's just say it
ain't been my day.
Oh, well, don't worry, uh...
Good Lord!
l never thought
l'd see it happen!
Miss, what you looking for,
you can't find around here.
You better go.
How do you know
what l'm lookin' for?
You do know
what l am, don't you?
You know where l'm from.
Oh, my goodness.
Old man, l'm not leaving
till l find out
how you know so much. Talk!
Talk!
You're not telling me
everything you know.
Y-Y...
Y-You...
Y-Y-You're d-doodle!
ln Cool World,
they knew me as "Whiskers."
Dr. Vincent Whiskers.
Didn't you touch the Spike?
Sure, l touched it,
but l couldn't hold it.
No one can!
So it is up there!
And it is real,
and it's going to make me real.
Sure, it's up there,
but it's not going
to do you any good.
Just because you weren't
man enough to hold onto it.
l need the force
in that Spike.
And l'm going up there.
Whoo-whoo-whoo!
That power doesn't belong
to you!
l don't care.
l want it.
And l don't care...
Stop!
Cease! Desist!
l mean it!
-Ow, ow!
-Make this easy on yourself.
There she is.
She looks pretty.
Come on,
you little troublemaker.
Nobody's going to stop me now.
Harris, help me.
You've got to stop that girl.
lf she moves it,
it could be the end
of everything.
Doc? Oh, my God.
-l gotta get...
-Wait, wait.
Jack, please, l need you here
to take care
of my friend. Please.
This is my department.
l gotta stop her, Harris.
-Jack!
-Let go!
Wait, Jack!
Let me go, Harris.
l'm not gonna hurt her.
Help him.
Holli.
Crazy doodle bitch.
All right.
Hello, Holli.
Guess what. You're through.
You know, sweetheart,
you look good in the flesh.
lt's almost a shame
l gotta take you back.
You are going back, you know.
Would!
Um...
You're squeezing my head.
There.
As good as new.
Where do you think you're going?
lt's over.
What are you gonna do-- jump?
Just get down.
For Christ's sake.
What? You got ink
for brains? Get down.
Don't piss me off, Would.
You go on that roof,
you screw us all.
l'm not messing around here.
Oh, Christ.
There's nothing up there.
Let's just go home,
fix this mess.
Get down!
Would!
Don't .
Harris.
What?!
Harris, help me.
Ah...
Help me.
Oh, Harris... help me.
Hold on.
l should do the world a favor
and let you fall.
Easy.
Easy does it.
Good.
Now, hold on.
Here we go.
We're going home.
All right, careful.
Come on.
Oh, my God.
Jack, this is your chance
to make it right.
lt's up to you now.
Okay. Okay.
This time, l'm gonna
do something right.
He's gonna kill himself.
He's fulfilling his destiny.
He's becoming a hero.
Oh, please.
The Spike.
lt's up to me
to return the Spike.
Got it!
-Whoa.
Whoa.
The pain is unbearable.
Hit me.
Deuces wild?
Heh-heh-heh-heh.
The world has
only one chance left.
lt's up to me to return the
Spike and plug the hole.
Huh! You fiends!
Trying to stop me.
Baby, baby...
The king! Oh, it's the king!
Oh, l hate being
bottled up like that.
Oh, man, boss.
Hold on. Hold on.
Hmm?
Feel the air, Jack.
We're staying.
l like it here, Jack.
Come here.
Give me the Spike, Jack.
You love me, don't you, Jack?
Yes, l do.
Well, then, help me.
Give it to me, Jack.
Okay, honey-poo.
Hey, goodie-goodie-goodie.
Pencil dicks.
Aha!
A trick!
On second thought,
l must do what is right
and return the Spike.
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha.
Whoa!
Oh, golly, oh!
Hey!
Damn!
Jack?!
He-he's gone.
He's ...
He's gone.
Dead?
l don't know for sure,
but l don't think so.
You know,
maybe the Spike protected them.
lts power is beyond
our understanding.
Mm-hmm.
l'm sorry he didn't make it.
l got to take him
back with me.
There's a nice gal back there.
She deserves to see him,
dead or alive.
Okay, Doc, let 'er rip.
Wow.
Arriba, arriba, arriba, arriba!
Oh!
Oh, Nails!
He didn't make it.
l'm sorry.
Oh, Frank, honey! No, please!
Oh, no, please,
you can't leave me!
Oh, no!
Who killed him, Nails?
He was pushed off a building.
Who pushed him?
Holli Would.
Holli Would?
That bitch!
Nails,
was she a doodle
when she aced him?
Yeah! So what?!
So what?
Oh! So what?
Well, what happens
to noids who traffic
in the Cool World, Nails,
when they get killed
by a doodle?
They become a doodle themselves.
Hmm?
Hot dog! Dig it! Dig me!
Ba-ba-bum...
ba!
Oh, my God!
Oh, Nails, he's alive!
Ooh, and he's gorgeous, too.
Hubba-bubba, baby.
What do you think?
Ooh, you're a hero, Harris.
You saved the world.
So what are you waiting for?
Come and get it.
Ooh, Frankie...
so, did you do it
while you were back there
in the real world?
Did you do it
while you were real?
Do you ever think about
going back there so you can?
There's no reason now.
Hey, boss, we got to go.
Get out of here!
l'm sorry.
l'm so sorry.
l can't stand myself.
Oh! l should have
all eight legs.
Well, then,
we're just going
to have to stop pretending now,
aren't we?
Bum, bum, ba.
Bye-bye, folks.
Have a nice life.
What a beautiful landscape.
Let's see.
We can put the house
over here,
the studio over here.
l'll still draw, of course.
We'll raise children over here,
l'll fight crime over there.
Oh, we're going to be
deliriously happy, honey-poo.
Pencil dick.
Mohamed_sayed1993@yahoo.com
*Araby4All*