Hey, Ebony!
Ebony!
Open up!
Jesus, Ebony,
get this guy out of here!
There's no more room,
Ebony.
We've got to use this cell.
Cool it, or there'll be trouble!
I'll kill Dagger!
Lula was gonna knife him in
the back, the son of a bitch!
"Was"?
I still will!
Dagger! I'll kill you, you hear?
Stick you like a pig.
Ebony, Lula's freaked out,
says it 's his right to kill Dagger.
Lula needs to be taught a lesson!
Whatever's happened, it 's not for
you to decide, you little shit!
Dagger's gonna die!
Gonna die! Gonna die!
Calm down!
So you think you're gonna decide this,
Pimenta? Come on, then, I'm ready.
Shut up, Dagger!
Gonna die! Gonna die!
Like I said, I've got no one
waiting for me on the outside.
I'm in no hurry to get out.
Anyone wants a fight,
let 's get on with it.
I'll crush all of you.
So what are we
waiting for?
What the fuck's wrong with
you guys?! Let 's cool it, here!
What 's going on, Dagger?
Lula attacked him from behind,
Ebony! He's a bad ass!
- He was within his rights!
- He went for Dagger from behind!
Right out of line, man!
Let 's cool it,
man, calm down!
"Calm down", my ass.
He's gonna die!
Gonna die!
- You locking me in there, Ebony?
- First get in there, then speak!
- Don't throw Dagger in here, Ebony!
- We don't want trouble.
Get the hell out, damn it!
So? I'm all ears.
How come he's so mad at you?
You heard, Lula came out of nowhere
with a knife and tried to kill me.
I dodged, and we scuffled
till they broke us up.
The rest you know.
Good morning, Mr. Pires.
I do apologize for this
disgusting behavior...
which has invaded
our household today.
Only this idiot Lula, a young,
inexperienced con...
suddenly got this attitude, without
even asking permission!
Dagger killed my father!
He killed my father! It was him!
I sure did, kid.
And not only him,
I've killed plenty more besides!
Ebony!
Mr. Pires!
Dagger killed my father
in front of my mother.
He's been telling everyone he
recognized her on Visitors Day.
You gonna deny that, asshole?!
Are you gonna deny it? Are you?
Ebony, please.
What?
Tell the kid he doesn't know
half the story. If he did...
Son of a bitch!
I'll kill you!
Tell him to ask his mother if she
was really as upset as all that.
Or was it a relief when I came
and grabbed his belt from him?
Lies! That 's a lie!
Like hell it is!
I saw it for myself.
He'd have
thrashed her to death!
Hey, Lula!
I thought you'd have
heard by now, kid!
Your mother paid me
to kill your father!
Get it now?
It was your mother wiped him out!
Hear that?
He's calmed down!
I want them both out
here in their underwear.
Hey, Lula...
as far as I'm concerned,
we're quits.
Let 's forget it, shall we?
You've put me to shame, and on the
day of the doctor's first visit.
So, Lula, what brought
you back in here?
I left here, went home and found
my wife in bed with someone else.
The son of a bitch had the
nerve to tell me, "That 's life".
I shot him three times just
to prove the contrary.
You should know that whatever goes
on outside gets settled outside.
In here,
anyone who behaves...
knows we'll do what we can
to show him the front door...
where his family is waiting.
But anyone who's proud of being
a criminal, with blood in his eye...
we'll do everything to
prolong his life in here!
We usually forget people
like that in here.
Doctor, this is Ebony.
Yes, Doctor,
Ebony's got a problem.
My kitchen knife
is still missing!
Whoever took it,
I'll give you one chance...
return it, or there'll be
one prisoner dead every day!
I'd like to ask our visitors
to turn their backs...
since there's an ashamed
crook present.
But...
when I turn around...
I sure would like
to see that knife.
I'll count to three.
One...
two...
I'm turning...
Three!
- From your kitchen?
- Yes, sir!
This is the yellow wing, Doctor,
because they're afraid.
It 's like a jail within the jail.
They're locked up here for their
own safety. They're scared.
Career killers, rapists, stool
pigeons, bad payers.
In here, you know,
prisoners never forgive.
Mr. Pires, don't these people
ever get sun? It 's so musty!
Anyone want to go outside?
Take a walk in the yard?
Get some fresh air?
Mr. Pires, what do these
people do all day?
They come and go all day long,
think they're busy...
but it gets them nowhere.
Doctor, 7,OOO men in jail!
There are 1,8OO
in this pavilion alone.
If they knew how AIDS is spread,
that 'd already help.
They catch the disease, then have
sex with their wife, girlfriend...
so there's no stopping
the epidemic.
The only ones who'll listen to your
advice are the really smart ones...
who only want to get out alive
in order to keep robbing.
That 's their whole life.
Maybe. But they're living
at the center of the disease.
They're the prisoners here.
Prisoners? They own this jail.
The only reason...
this place doesn't explode
is because they don't want it to.
God bless you, child.
I didn't know you had a family.
I thought I'd lost it.
My whole life in jail, but even
so, I raised 18 kids...
and not one of them has even been
near a police station.
That girl, my youngest, she said
she no longer remembers my face...
so she's decided
to come and visit.
I'd like you to authorize
me to see her...
on a day other than Visitors Day.
I don't want my daughter
around all the scum.
That 's going to be tricky.
What if the 7,OOO others
ask me the same thing?
Excuse me.
Good morning!
Need anything, Doctor?
Coffee, sugar, chocolate?
Soap, toothpaste?
Joints are only two packs
of Marlboros each. Want one?
- I don't smoke.
- Too bad. Commerce, Doctor!
Makes the world go round!
Easy now...
that 's it.
He can't spit there.
Tuberculosis. Anyone steps
on that spreads the disease.
Doctor, if he had the strength,
he'd go to the sink.
It 's not easy.
He must be isolated.
But where, Doctor?
- Name?
- Everyone calls me The Beard.
Why are you here?
Well...
my brother was killed.
Two days later, the murderer
had a little meeting with death...
so suspicions fell upon my
good self. Some said I did it...
and others came along and
said they saw it wasrt me.
So what with some saying it was
me and others saying not...
here I am, five years now...
waiting for the judge to decide.
So, Beard, do you have
sex here in jail?
Anyone who denies that is a liar.
Use condoms?
If I've got one, I do.
- IV drugs?
- How dare you, Doctor?!
I wonder, Beard!
What 's that mark on your arm?
Bears next!
My name's Alpio.
Do you use drugs?
Needles?
No way, Doctor, I got AIDS from
all the ass I've had in jail.
Plenty of ass.
Is it still won'th
taking the test?
I listen, give advice, a little
tenderness, hold them tight...
and then they always give us
something nice in return...
a pack of cigarettes, some candy,
a slice of cheese.
So many men shut up
in here, Doctor...
without our feminine support.
Yeah, I've got AIDS, Doctor,
but I didn't get it in here.
I brought it in off the streets,
Doctor, and I can't complain.
You come in here sick and they
treat you with respect, dignity...
and that 's the greatest thing
in a crook's life.
I'm a junky and dealer.
In my business, if a guy doesn't
pay up, I can't take back...
what I sold him. The bastars
already smoked it, snorted it.
I take whatever he's got, and
if he's got nothing, I kill him.
The other day, I tried to get an
extra banana from the guy who...
delivers lunch. The bastard
said only if I kissed his banana.
So what the hell,
I'm just crazy about bananas.
Doctor, everyone in my cell's
got this itch. It 's unbearable.
Scabies. I'll give
you some medicine.
So how are you getting along?
Doctor, after shooting cocaine
in the dark with a blunt needle...
drawing blood with this rig
is hardly fair play, Doctor.
Too bad!
- Who are you?
- I'm the Doctor.
I was in the infirmary
taking blood samples.
Just ask...
Oh sure, like you have
to tell me who to ask!
I'm calling the duty officer.
Wait here.
If no one can identify you...
you're staying
right where you are.
Don't take it personally, Doctor.
It 's their job to escape
and mine not to let them.
Doctor!
You coming back?
I knew many of those men hadrt
shown thelrvlctlms any mercy...
but soclety has its judges.
And Iwasrt one of them.
At the same tlme,
what dld I have to do with all that?
I had two cholces:
Forget or go back.
Take a deep breath.
- Smoker?
- Just cigarettes, Doctor.
- No crack?
- Never.
Sleep well?
Hardly, Doctor.
The mind never stops...
what with one guy trying
to settle a score outside...
another collecting a debt,
another trying to dig a tunnel.
And there goes another day.
You still got much time to do?
A few more years.
- And why did you come here?
- Legitimate self-defense, Doctor.
That lands you
in jail nowadays?
It did in my case.
Here's what happened, Doctor.
It was Christmas, the bells
ringing, snow in the windows.
Me, Bristles and Fatso arranged
to do a jewelry store job.
Neat work, Doctor.
Never even fired a shot.
The problem was later.
How are we going to split it up?
Fatso and I will make three
piles, and you choose first.
Son, not now.
Get out! Go on!
You fucking moron!
We're splitting the loot...
and you come at me with
your hand covered?
It 's his own fault he died.
What the fuck's going on?
So you shot him in the heat of
the moment, but we'd agreed...
for me to shoot you,
so we could take your share.
So shoot!
Go on, fire away!
I can't, damn it.
Give me your rod.
Oh my God!
Being betrayed by your buddy for
nothing, Doctor...
like Judas, the guy who
spat in the face of Jesus!
So how does the story end?
It ends with me in here,
before your very eyes, Doctor.
Fatso was arrested
in under two months.
Doctor, ever seen a fat man
being beaten?
They even spill stuff they
werert asked.
A man was killed here.
Did you see anything?
No.
Jesus, Fatso, you turned
me in for Bristles' murder!
You could have just squealed
about the robbery.
I fingered you for murder
because Bristles' brother...
was going to kill me.
We left his place together
for the jewelry store...
then I came back alive,
and he got back dead.
I'm very upset.
I could turn you in as
an accomplice...
but I won't.
I'll back your story up...
I killed him and threw him
in the river all by myself.
Thanks, Ebony!
I knew I could count on you.
I'll forgive you,
but you owe me one.
And did Fatso ever pay his debt?
No way! Fatso died
trying to escape.
They spent two years
digging a tunnel.
Let 's go, come on!
Go on, Fatso.
Hurry up you big pile of shit!
Cado! Give me a hand!
I'm stuck.
Breathe in, man.
Suck yourself in.
What do you mean?
I can't!
Go back, then!
Go on!
Gimme a break, Cado.
Pull, go on, pull!
Shit, Fatso, I told you! Eating
everyone else's leftovers!
Pull, go on!
- Please!
- Get him out the way!
Fatso's frustrated
brothers knifed him.
Hell of a way to die,
eh Doctor?
Right under the Virgin Mary, and
not even she could protect him.
Too bad.
What about this pain?
Your problem, Ebony, is stress...
what big shot executives get.
Take one of these before bed.
They'll help you sleep.
If you don't get better,
come back.
God protect you, Doctor.
Doctor, come and see Chico's
balloon, quick!
It 's the old mars obsession,
Doctor.
Oh, too bad.
May I?
Hi, I'm Lady.
Lady Di.
I've come to take the test.
Please, take a seat.
First I'd like to ask you
a few questions, Lady Di.
I've seen this movie before,
Doctor.
I've never needed
a blood transfusion...
and I never pierce my veins.
The only drug I use is
a joint now and then...
when I watch
TV or for a little romance.
And partners, how many?
Oh, about 2,OOO.
May I?
Lady, the silicone you
used isn't meant for that.
As if I had the money for
something better, Doctor.
Ever taken hormones?
No way!
Hormones are dreadful!
You take them and
nothing happens.
And what our clients really like,
maybe you know, is to play the girl.
Well, Lady...
I think the time's come for you
to find out whether you're sick.
I'll do it, Doctor.
- Will it hurt?
- Not much.
Get out of here.
Get out, man!
Any room in there?
Sure.
Only it 'll cost you 2OO.
Pay for a bed?
I'm in jail, man!
So you lived for free
on the outside, did you?
If you want to stay,
sleep on the floor.
Deusdete ain't sleeping
on no floor.
He already has a place.
Deusdete...
just like I said,
right brother?
You ended up doing something
you shouldn't.
And the rat?
I smashed it against
the wall about ten times!
Damn thing wouldn't let go!
Sweet Mama, pray for me!
It died?
Like hell it did!
So I grabbed it tight and stuck
my teeth into its brain.
Then I just brushed my teeth,
and that was that.
Easy, man!
You've been beaten with iron bars
and never made a sound.
Cut your finger, Highness?
Jesus, Lula, smoking crack?
You can't operate like that!
Sorry, Doctor, only I operate
better when I smoke.
What?! You can't keep
a steady hand on crack!
Ah, that 's where
you're wrong, Doctor.
I see the veins all
shining and fluorescent.
Looks like that casino
in Las Vegas!
Take it easy, man!
See, steady as a rock, and hardly
a millimeter between stitches.
God protect you, Lula.
God bless you, God bless you all.
That 's enough of God, Highness,
you're not kidding anyone!
What, you married twice?
Well, Doctor, to me life's
a merry-go-round...
and just the one horse
isn't enough.
That one there, that 's Dalva's,
my princess!
Honey, score a goal for me?
Please?
Like it?
Yeah, I bet you do.
Do you believe in love
at first sight?
What?!
Come with me. I'm going to ask
your parents for your hand.
Get out of here!
You don't even know me!
- You're wrong!
- Wrong? You don't know me!
Sure I do.
I know you just love spicy...
- Sausage...
- Sausage!
And I know you look gorgeous
in that pretty dress...
And I know you deserve better
than that klutz over there.
- My fianc!
- Fianc?!
You're wasting your time.
Look what a great blend!
We'll have one kid of each color.
I'll be waiting in the car.
Were you serious?
Never been more.
What the hell's going on, Dalva?
What are you doing here?
Go on, go away, will you?
What?! Honey, who is this?
- I'm her husband.
- Husband?
Sure. We're marrying.
Don't grab me like that!
Stop it!
Get out of here, go on!
See?
If he were in love with you,
he wouldn't have run off!
Jesus! Letting some
guy steal his girl!
Tomorrow at eight,
get your family together...
and I'll ask for your hand.
I'd rather my daughter were dead
than marry a thieving nigger.
You offend me, sir.
You've only just met me.
I know enough to know you're
nothing but a lazy nigger!
- Look here, sir, I came here...
- Forget it!
You're too old to be
falling for some black man.
Get down there!
Go on!
Easy now!
Down you go.
Come on!
I marrled her rlght there.
I took my love with me; my black
flst In hercotton-white hand.
Best thing that could have
happened to me, Doctor.
Dalva gave me a family.
So you stopped stealing.
Of course not, Doctor! With her
by my side, I went up-market.
Took imported cars and
drove them to Paraguay.
With cash in my pocket, I returned
to the peace of home life.
Any kids?
Three with Dalva.
And one with Rosirene.
You know how it is, the devil
only tempts those close to God.
That ever happened to you?
Uncontrollable passion?
What 's with the babe over there?
What do you think?
She's over there.
Don't you dance samba, miss?
What am I, a monkey jumping
around for nothing?
Looking for something
to jump to?
Seems like you're the one wanting
to jump... jump ship.
Look, I'll take my wife home.
Get your bikini, and
I'll come and fetch you.
We'll go and spend the
weekend at the beach.
Does that sister know you
belong to me?
Ease up, Dalva!
I was only going to the john!
Like hell you were. And that,
why's that so hard then?
Doesrt look like it 's being
properly cared for.
Watch your mouth,
you stinking black bitch!
Get away from my man,
or you'll be sorry!
Hey, handsome! So I guess
the beach is off, then?
So what happened
to the black girl?
Ah, now that 's where I had
to do a bit of juggling, Doctor.
From Monday to Thursday, Dalva.
And the rest, Rosirene.
I rented a little room for us
near the old bus station.
We had this great love affair
going, Doctor.
Morning!
Give me that!
It 's mine!
Stop, you're messing me up!
Don't let go of me, Highness.
Don't let go!
Thanks, Powder, see you around!
You just can't quit this life,
can you?
I thought I told you
I'd take care of you.
I've always earned
my own money.
And that guy you were with,
know who he is?
What are you doing here?
I thought it was Snow White's day.
Don't change the subject!
You know who he is?
Sure!
So what?
So I told you... do your
thing if you have to...
but don't screw a friend of mine,
or I'll break your neck!
Powder's your friend?!
Highness, you're a nobody.
He said that when he leaves
his wife, we'll move to Miami.
- I'm off!
- Where to?
To Miami, honey!
Well you're taking a souvenir
of mine with you!
That was rough, Doctor,
screwing a friend of mine...
and the two of
them making plans!
That night I went back to the
room and what do I see?
Jesus...
get out of here!
No way.
Get out of here right now!
I won't go.
Get out, damn it!
No way, I'm staying.
Come on, Highness, bite me.
Come on, bite me...
bite me the way I like it.
Bite, go on, bite!
Bite harder...
harder!
It 's over!
There, that 's so you learn
not to take what 's not yours!
You arsonist bitch!
Slut!
Well, you might as well know that
this slut is expecting his child.
No!
Son of a bitch whore!
I'll kill you!
You haven't heard
the last of this, Highness...
you son of a bitch whore!
Son of a bitch!
Get your hands off my son!
To keep Dalva out of trouble,
I took the blame forthe flre.
Only the law was already
on my back for other stuff...
so I got 16 years for the fire,
reduced to 1O.
And was it won'th it?
But Doctor, the black chick put
a spell on me. I'm outta here!
Therefore, perfectly calmly,
we shall overcome the nlggllng...
Irresponslble and lylng attempts
to Involve the government...
and presldent In accusatlons
by fallures who only survlve...
through statements
Impregnated with jealousy...
fabrlcatlons and resentment.
Tlme wlll reveal the absurdity
of these attempts...
and the law wlll punlsh
those truly responslble...
forthe Irregularitles, for any
wrongdolngwhlch took place...
and the creators of the false
accusatlons.
Letter from Franci?
Your sister mention me at all?
Course she does, right?
Hey, Deusdete! What does
your sister say about me?
She asks if you're okay.
That all?
What do you think? If she knew
what you've been up to...
she wouldn't even be asking that.
I think she would...
but you think you know better.
Wasrt it you used to say,
"If you sell it, don't use it"?
May I?
So what 's up?
Come to settle your debt?
Hey man, right now Ezequiel's
in a tight spot.
So he thinks to himself,
"Zico's a reasonable guy...
He'll take the surfboard
as collateral for the debt."
Then Ezequiel can have another
little rock of crack, right man?
Wrong!
Pay what you owe!
Don't drink that, it 's blood!
Shit!
I thought it was water.
Doctor, this guy was
sweating all night long.
I've put him on antibiotics,
but if you ask me, it 's no use...
it 's AIDS.
Doctor! Doctor!
Who took away his oxygen?
I don't want to die.
Get me out of here, please!
That 's hardly likely.
He's 213, rape.
To us he's a patient.
Doctor...
send me
to the yellow wing.
I need to get somewhere safe.
I don't want to die!
I'm sorry, Doctor,
I'm against the death penalty...
but not for rape.
If you ask me,
it 's just too bad.
So that 's it, Doctor.
Come on, old man,
it 's past lock-down.
Get a move on!
What is it, what
are you looking at?
You think your kids will jump
over the wall?
You were asking for it this time,
werert you, Chico?
See you in 3O days.
Doctor, we're here to make
our relationship official.
You understand,
Doctor...
so we can be more open.
It 's not the same with a rubber.
There's not much sense,
her taking the test and not you.
See? I told him, Doctor,
but he's scared.
- Scared of what?
- Scared of injections.
Too Bad?!
It 's not that.
So you're scared
of getting married!
Doctor, you're needed, urgently!
Down you go, come on.
It 's all right now, Doctor.
I blacked out, Doctor.
Giving us all a fright, Zico?
It 's just as well, Doctor.
Maybe he'll learn what drugs do.
Tell him!
What 's there to tell?
Drugs kill.
- And you, who are you?
- That 's Deusdete.
We grew up together.
You know, Doctor, one day
my mom didn't come home.
I was left alone.
I waited and waited...
until he and his sister,
Franci, came...
and took me to live with them.
We grew up together.
Come on, Zico!
Wait, Zico!
Help! Help!
It was Zico saved me, Doctor.
That 's right, Doctor, I've always
looked after him, from early on.
Then you went the wrong way.
Doctor, what 's wrong with buying
some dope in Pernambuco...
and selling it to folks
who like it?
It wasrt even that much!
Another two years, and I'm free.
But I've never killed anyone.
Unlike Deusdete, here.
What was your crime?
Answer him, Deusdete!
To tell you the truth, Doctor,
he's not even a real criminal.
So what are you in here for?
One night, I was at home...
when my sister arrived,
acting strange.
What 's wrong, Franci?
What happened?
Franci!
Franci, what happened?
Open up, come on!
What happened?
What happened, Franci?
Tell me!
What happened?
There were two of them.
They grabbed me...
lifted my skirt...
one said he wanted to suck me.
I told him to go suck his mother!
- What did they do to you?
- They beat me.
What else, huh?
What else?!
- That 's all, Deusdete.
- Who was it?
I just ran off!
Hey, Zico!
Deusdete! What are you
doing here, man?
I need to talk.
Excuse us.
Is Mother all right?
It 's not her. Some guys
messed with Franci.
What did they do to her?
Nothing much, she says. But I
reported it to the cops, anyway.
The cops?! You think
the cops'll do anything?!
The problem is, the guys found
out, and now they're after me.
Leave it to me.
I'll sort them out.
No, Zico. Not your way.
I don't want that.
I just want a gun,
to defend myself.
Take your pick.
Even with a gun, Doctor, I never
thought anything would happen.
But...
it was my destiny.
And theirs,
when they found me.
So! Where's the stool pigeon
off to tonight, then?
I'm not looking for a fight.
Let me go home!
Sure thing, but first we're
going to caress you...
just like we did
your little sister.
Hey, man!
Give me a Coke.
You know how old I'll be
when I get out of here, Doctor?
Forty-eight!
There!
One...
two...
three...
four...
five...
six...
seven...
eight!
Found it!
So it 's Visitors Day, is it?
If you like, you can go now.
Ebony...
I've got a problem.
I need to talk.
This problem got a name?
Ezequiel.
He still owes me, and now he's
even trying to get more on account.
He comes to my cell, raises his
voice, what 's he playing at?!
- And you?
- Me?
If I don't get paid,
I can't pay Highness.
I want your permission
to kill the bastard.
This goes on much longer, I'll
start losing respect around here.
Cool it!
I'll tell Ezequiel to get
the money from his family.
If he doesn't pay,
you can go ahead.
This man has already lost a lung...
and the other's in pretty
bad shape.
Take the medicine, man, go on.
See, Doctor?
He won't take it.
What are you, a kid? You won't
get better if you don't take it.
Come on, that 's right.
Come on.
That 's it.
Right.
Good.
And on the outside?
What did he do?
We used to rob armored trucks.
Just the two of us, we planned
everything, remember?
Doctor, we'd spend six months
just gathering information.
We'd even make friends
with the guards' families.
And that paid off?
Sure, plenty.
Although we'd
only use half the money.
The rest we'd put aside
for a rainy day...
or to bribe the cops.
It 's coming.
Right, get over there!
Come on!
Stop!
Come on! You going to sit there
on top of other people's money?!
If you don't come out, it 'll be
too bad for your widows.
Open that door,
for Christ 's sake!
Come on, get out!
So we paid off the others...
and each went his own way,
back to the family.
So anyway, Antnio,
what 's on your mind?
Miro...
your wife's cheating on you.
With a cop.
Says who?
Says no one.
I saw her.
They were making out
in a squad car.
Near the old bakery.
Dina doesn't buy bread there.
Miro, I saw her. And it
wasrt bread she was after.
Clia...
is Antnio Carlos gay?
What a question, Dina!
I'm sorry, but he made
up this story...
and told Miro I've been
going out with a cop.
Like hell I made it up.
I saw you crawling all over him.
You nibbled his ear, damn it!
Then it 's me he's really after,
honey.
You forgot the best part:
How you asked me to run away
with you and dump Miro...
and that I turned you down
because I love my husband...
and your wife's my friend!
Liar! Evil slut!
Miro, you don't believe
that bitch, do you?
Man, how many jobs have
we pulled off together?
And our agreement!
Clia, see if you can't keep
your man around the house.
I don't want him pestering
me in the street anymore.
Miro!
Miro...
Bastard! You dirty bastard!
You've never fooled me...
I always knew you
had a crush on her.
Can't even respect your best
friens wife, you dog!
- Calm down.
- Dog!
Miro, I'm telling
you the truth!
I lost my friend and partner.
The first robbery without him...
there were so many cops, Doctor,
it looked more like...
- a military parade.
- What about him?
I only found out when
he arrived here.
I thought I'd gone to hell,
Doctor, but him?
Come here, come on.
Come here.
Miro, don't you think
it 's time you quit?
Take what you've got and start
a decent life someplace else?
Give the kid a better chance.
Stop!
Police!
Party's over, Miro!
I'll cut you in. It 's cheaper
for me to cut you guys in...
than give it to a lawyer.
You don't get it. We're taking
the lot. Everything.
Hand it over, the dough,
come on, quick!
Too bad, a smart guy like you
trusting his own wife.
Some guys are born
to be cheated on.
Are you all right?
Doctor...
do small kids remember
everything we do?
No, not a thing.
Doctor...
let him go.
And with you now,
our untamed diva of dance...
the woman who lives in all
thieves' hearts...
here at the Detention Center...
the one and only
Rita Cadillac!
Hello!
I know you all fool around
a lot, right?
But do you take care
of yourselves?
Our friend the doctor
came here today...
and he's taught me enough
to teach you, too, right?
That 's right!
Okay, so some of you are
careful, and others forget...
so I'm going to teach you
what to do.
This one's orange!
Dona Graa,
Ebony sent you this.
Thanks.
Oh, look, my man!
Want some?
No, thank you.
See, Franci,
that 's the sort of man I want.
Tell me, you think Deusdete
will like me?
That 's up to the two of you.
It 's easier for him if he has a
sweetheart waiting on the outside.
You're right. You need a heart full
of love to put up with this life.
Take my boy, he's always
asking about his father.
What did he say when you
told him I was coming?
That you could come
if you felt like it.
Good work, man.
Agenor Barbosa, Inmate 15027,
your brothers Pedro, Luls...
and Fellclo are waitlng
foryou at the barbershop.
Deusdete, this is Catarina
I told you about.
This is me.
Franci's told me a lot about you.
Nothing good, I hope!
Only the best.
She was even a bit jealous...
when I said I wanted to meet you,
right Franci?
Zico.
Hi, Franci.
Wow, you're so thin.
Been eating too much junk?
Sure thing. But that 's the least
of it, right Zico?
Son, have you been taking
good care of your brother?
You bet, Godmother!
The game's starting, the referee
blows the whistle...
and they're off! There goes Neto,
and he's through...
to the penalty area, playing
beautifully, passing one player...
dribbling that ball, and Highness
takes a shot...
Inmate Josu 'HIghness'Santos,
Sectlon 9302...
come Immedlately to the entrance
of Pavlllon 9.
Darling...
I'll be right back.
Joel Flrmlno and hls wlfe, Luclnda,
please come to the loudspeakers...
where your lost son
Is waitlng foryou.
Hi, honey!
Kiss me on the mouth!
Oh honey,
today's not a good day.
The boiler burst and the guy said
I've got to fix it by tonight.
Look here, Highness, you haven't
worked a day in your life.
You're not going to tell me
you've turned over a new leaf!
You've got that white
trash in there!
No way, I swear!
Where did you get that idea?!
Really?
So let 's go and take a look!
'Cause I think that white
slut is in there with you!
Get out of my way!
Do you think I'm stupid, an idiot?!
I know she's in there!
I know, you can't get rid of her!
What are you looking at?!
There! I just knew you
were with that whore!
Oh, so now I'm the whore,
am I?
Stop, stop!
Go on, Son.
Sit down, Dalva.
Rosirene, sit down.
Right, now you're here,
there's no turning back.
The three of us are going
to come to an agreement.
Rosirene, Dalva's no whore,
all right?
She works at the textile factory
and raises our kids.
They're my kids, damn it!
And you, too, you said
Rosirene's won'thless...
and that 's not true, either.
If it werert for her bringing
me some decent stuff...
to sell in here, we'd
all be going hungry.
If you like both of us,
that 's your problem.
Oh, Jesus!
Yeah, Highness...
you're going to have to choose
between us, right now.
Damn right!
Shit, you're breaking
my heart in two, damn it!
Two women, Doctor! What do these
crooks have that we haven't?
Have you kissed your
wife today, Mr. Pires?
No, why?
I rest my case.
Can I join you?
So, nothing to tell?
You're the one never told us
what happened that day.
That 's ancient history, Zico.
You never told me what
they did to you!
When you get out of here, promise
me you'll let your hair grow?
You believe in promises?!
Deusdete was right...
you're not the Zico
we used to know.
Anyone home?
What 's up, Dagger?
I've got a message for a friend.
I know.
What 's that look on your face?
I pretended I had AIDS,
so they'd leave me alone...
but it was no use. The bastard
who did me is infected.
Forget it, kid, he told me
to tell you he lied, too.
He hasn't got AIDS, either.
What is it?
Ezequiel wants to pay.
You don't owe me anything, man.
Ezequiel spoke to her
and she said yes.
I don't get it.
Ezequiel wants to pay with her.
Ezequiel's sister sleeps with...
some of the guys, raises some
cash and pays the debt with Zico.
Ezequiel has no other possessions.
Do whatever you think's best.
I was blind, I believed her.
Will you ever...
be able to trust me again?
I never stopped trusting you.
He's our family now.
Let 's sing "Happy Birthday"!
Here, sit on my lap.
Happy blrthday to you...
Sir, we're in love. Lady and
I would like your blessing.
It 's Dirceu. His name is Dirceu.
Son, do you believe in him?
Mother, I've never met
anyone like Matias.
I don't get this kid.
We're too old to know
what 's right, Antnio.
If it 's what Dirceu wants,
what 's the harm?
In here they can get up to all
the disgusting things they like.
Son...
bye!
Your attentlon, please!
Vlsitors Day Is almost over...
so wlll famlly members please
go to the exit.
The gates wlll close
In ten mlnutes.
Excuse me, Doctor.
This is my boy.
I know he's done wrong...
but when I think of him, I can't
believe he took someone's life.
I want to ask you to keep
an eye on Davilson for me.
I can't look after him in here.
Come and see me at the infirmary.
Thank you, Doctor.
So, can I come back next time?
If you think it 's won'th it.
It 'll be so long
before I get out.
I'm in no hurry.
Mr. Pires, his body was already
hanging here when we woke up.
This one won't be raping
anyone else.
The Doctor said it should
read positive.
No! Positive means you've
got it in your blood!
It has to be negative.
HIV-negative.
I'll go first; my case
is more desperate.
I'm clean!
Well, you've had your fun,
had over 2,OOO men...
and you're clean.
And me, as square as they come?
It 's just too bad.
I'm clean too, Lady.
What 's wrong?
"TOO BAD"
They're letting me out, Lady.
So why aren't you happy?
And leave you here all alone?
I'm not alone.
I have you.
No one works for me
who can't be trusted.
You ask permission to kill,
then change your mind?
But Ebony, I'll be
out in two years.
Better keep quiet and settle the
score on the outside, right?
Ezequiel...
you owed and didn't pay.
You're alive,
but you can't stay here.
Get your things and
go to the yellow wing.
As for you, Zico...
you're no criminal.
You're a clown.
It 's all right, Doctor.
So many years locked up...
the mind learns to control
the body.
Chico, how come you're in here?
Oh, Doctor, you want to hear
yet another lie?
No one in here is really guilty,
haven't you noticed?
Much longer to go?
I should have been out long ago.
It 's in the hands of the judge.
Oh, Doctor,
I can't wait.
Best thing about jail
is getting out!
And leave behind all
your friends, Chico?
Friends? I don't want
inmates for friends.
I finish talking to you,
close the door, and that 's that.
In here you have to walk alone...
or maybe with God.
What about your daughter?
What are you thinking, Chico?
I was imagining these two...
flying up...
higher into the sky.
It 's weird.
This is weird!
Weird.
Come out, you son of a bitch!
Come out!
What can you see?
It 's trying to stab me in the eye!
Want to stab me?
Son of a bitch!
There's no one there, man. Jesus,
brother, you're too crazy, Zico.
It 's me, man!
Give me that knife, Zico.
Come on, give me the knife!
Give me the knife!
Get a grip, Zico. You trying
to get yourself killed?
Stop smoking, Zico.
I don't want
that shit in here anymore!
So Mr. Pires, shall I go
and fetch the old man?
No, let him be.
Look, Ebony, I know that
when I went to visit Zico...
Deusdete didn't let us
do crack in there.
That 's no reason
to kill like a coward!
I was scared shitless.
Went to bed and woke up burned!
How dare he kill without
asking us?
Mind your own business.
He was a childhood friend. If you
had a friend to advise you...
would you have done
the same thing to him?
That 's their problem!
You're wrong.
Now it 's our problem.
Here she comes!
Too Bad, honey...
do you take Lady
as your true wife?
Yes.
And do you, Lady,
take Too Bad as your husband?
I do.
Then as the presiding queen...
I hereby declare you man...
and wife!
Kiss! Kiss!
First I want to propose
a toast...
to the Doctor!
Because thanks to all the
medicine this gentleman...
has taught me, I'm going out
to open my own clinic.
While I wait for you,
my beauty...
so we can start our own family.
Kiss! Kiss! Kiss!
Highness?
Can't I have some on account?
What the fuck?!
Son of a bitch!
Jesus, he chickened out!
Ezequiel...
come here!
Come here, Ezequiel!
Hey, Ezequiel, you think
that bastard Zico...
is to blame
for all your misery, right?
Sure, but Ezequiel's life has
always been miserable.
And wasrt it Zico made Ezequiel
offer his sister for the drugs?
Sure, what was I supposed to do?
So forget it, you did it.
Ezequiel stabbed Zico,
over 3O times.
But Highness...
Ezequiel will be
out in just two years.
If I do that I'll get another twenty!
Two years, twenty years, what 's the
difference to Ezequiel?
Ezequiel has AIDS.
At least you'll get a cell
to yourself, laundry...
and of course, crack to smoke.
I was the one wiped out Zico.
Now I don't owe anyone a thing.
Old man?
Go in peace.
Keep it, you need all the peace
you can get in there.
Why didn't you knife me?
I couldn't!
What about him?
He won't leave me alone,
follows me everywhere.
So, Zico, up in heaven,
did you meet anyone?
No one you know, just him.
No, Zico, what about God?
Not God in person,
haven't seen Him yet.
What 's wrong?
Doctor, how can you tell whether
you're going mad?
Zico came back...
to haunt me
because I couldn't kill him.
You been seeing ghosts,
Dagger?
A guy like me,
unable to kill?
Never happened before!
Isn't that a good thing?
I only know how to kill.
That 's how I grew up.
We change, Dagger.
Doctor, I have to know what 's
happening to me, Doctor!
Am I no longer myself?!
Maybe it 's your guilt over
having killed so many.
Doctor...
is there a cure for guilt?
If there were,
everyone would want some.
Father.
Enter, Brother.
Come!
Did you know the Lord
has a plan for you?
Enter!
This is your home.
You are lost, Brother.
You don't know it,
but it was He who brought you here.
Who, Father?
Jesus! He knows you can't sleep
if you haven't harmed someone...
that you have sleepless nights
unless you've thrown a man down.
Isn't that what it 's like
every day, Brother?
Come on, isn't it?
Yes, Father!
Yes it is!
There is so much blood on me,
Father!
So, Brother, kneel down.
Come on, kneel down!
Will you accept Jesus?
Well, Brother,
will you accept Jesus?!
Which of you has accepted Jesus?
Hallelujah!
Criminals of Brazil...
the big day is here,
the Pavilion 9 finals!
Marsh going
for the trophy with...
Vallent, Samuel,
Dad, Saint...
Indian Boa Ventura, Minimum Wage,
Valdir, ARI5...
Hildo Ribeiro and Gerer!
Tornado 2000
Is here with...
Little Eye, Sleeve,
White Feather, Grlngo...
Salomo Ayala, Ed Murphy,
Greenouse Joe, Zelo, Flavino...
Ebony Ten and Tafarel!
To kick off this glorious
sporting event...
none other than our healer,
the wizard of medicinal alchemy...
and official trainer of the
criminal classes!
And they're off! Saint passes
to ARI5,Dad covering him...
Marsh on the attack!
Forcing the ball back...
Into the hands of Tafarel.
Up goes the ball! And it's out...
So, Beard, you all right?
Couldn't be better.
Have a good weekend.
Unfortunately,
The Beard was wrong.
He needed some of old Chico's
wisdom, who once said to me:
'A quiet, obedient jail?
Sure sign of trouble.'
Two weeks later,
when I got back...
there were nothing but bullet
holes covering the walls.
Hey, you!
Go find your own line.
I'll use this one.
Go away!
Are you crazy, man?!
So let me dry my clothes!
You've got some nerve, man!
What's it got to do with you?
Stop!
Stop, or I shoot!
Some say it started because of
a debt for five packs of cigarettes.
Others that it was a fight over
the soccer game.
One or two say it was about
a pair of underpants.
Like they say,
"Jail's no home for the truth".
And Dad's down, it's a penalty!
Penalty for Marsh one minute
before the end!
The referee's surrounded, and he's
sending a playeroff!
Dad's taking the penalty himself.
Getting ready...
concentrating.
Go on, Dad!
Goal!!!
Jesus Christ!
Watch out,
Rabbit 's gang is coming!
Just look what you did to him.
- Greedy bastard!
- Could have used your hand, man!
Just over a pair of underpants,
Jesus!
Why couldn't you have waited?
- What 's it got to do with you?
- Go fuck yourself, damn it!
Fucking asshole!
We're the champions!
I was scared, Doctor!
All hell broke loose, and
when the blood boils...
criminals lose all control.
With the confusion, I could
easily have got hurt badly.
Sound the alarm!
Riot in nine!
The place is ours!
We're locked in!
Forget it, let them die if they
want. Let 's get to our cell!
The war's started!
War! Let 's torch the place!
Go on!
Another explosion in the
overcrowded Detention Center...
which is the biggest
In Latin America...
with a total capacity
of 4,000 Inmates.
0nly nowadays it's more crowded
than ever, with 7,500 prisoners!
The riot squad has been called
and is storming the jail-
over 300 men with revolvers,
machine guns and tear gas.
By then, no one could
hear a damn thing.
Through the bars we could see
a bunch of masked cops.
All you could see was their eyes,
the dogs, machine guns...
and an helicopter flying real low,
pointing a machine gun at us.
Certainly, sir, right away!
Orders from the governor...
you're in charge now, Colonel.
The troops are here to do
whatever's necessary.
You're an experienced man.
If you need to move in, go ahead.
No, I can't accept that!
This is my jail!
Squad... attention!
Pay attention, men!
Return to your cells!
Back to your cells, otherwise
the cops are coming in!
If they come in here,
they'll all die!
Mr. Pires, plenty of men should
have been released by now!
We want better conditions!
Mr. Pires, send the riot
squad away!
So go back to your cells!
Everyone back to his cell,
or you'll regret it!
No regrets in here!
How many hostages do you have?
Are there hostages in there?
We've no hostages, Mr. Pires!
This is our fight, Mr. Pires!
See, Colonel, they've no hostages,
no water, no electricity!
They can't hold out for long!
Save us, Mr. Pires!
Don't let them come in here.
Send the riot squad away!
I'm having a tough time
holding them back!
Let 's keep calm!
Now hand over your weapons!
Surrender your weapons!
See, Colonel? Everything's calm.
You can send them away.
Pay attention!
Everyone back to your cells!
Return to your cells!
Let 's stay calm!
Back to your cells!
With an election coming up...
the governor wasn't going to
let the jail explode.
You!
Show us the way, let 's go.
We may be a bunch of ignorant
thieves and murderers...
but we're not stupid.
No one wants to die.
We ran to our cells.
We couldn't put up a fight...
with knives and sticks.
Go back, I'm warning you, we've
all got AIDS! You're gonna die!
They came in to kill us, Doctor,
shouting we all had AIDS...
that they'd catch
it if they touched us.
Shit, I don't want to die!
Hey, get out!
Let me through!
Open the fuck up!
Sergeant, let 's play
cops and robbers!
Open! Open up!
They're killing everyone!
You're going to live
to tell the tale.
I changed my mind.
Like hell he changed his mind!
It was pure spite. He only fed
Ezequiel a glimmer of hope...
just so he could come
back and kill him.
You two been causing trouble?
No way, we're sports fans.
So, you thief, how do you like
some of your own medicine!
You got lucky this time.
Who knows?
I guess he didn't have the courage
to shoot a woman.
It was our love that saved us.
It was the cop's son who saved my
life. God bless the cop's son!
God bless that cop's son!
- Get out, scum, stand up!
- For God's sake, I'm unarmed!
Out of your cell!
I know you killed a cop!
No fooling me!
I never killed anyone, sir! I'm only in
for 3 years. Spare me, spare me!
Listen here, the only reason this
is your lucky day...
is because you look like my son.
Anyone alive, undress
and come out naked!
I want to hear you say,
"Long live the riot squad!" Go on!
Long live the riot squad!
Louder, you murderer!
- Long live the riot squad!
Everyone now!
Long live the riot squad!
- Long live the riot squad!
Lieutenant, the only ones left
inside won't be going anywhere.
Undress, everything,
come on!
Heads down!
Davilson, dear Son...
your mother weeps when she thinks
of you when you were little...
laughing deep into my eyes.
I know you never
believed in my God...
but today, as I read the Bible,
it was as if you were here...
in my lap again.
My heart trembled as
I read salm 91.
What beautiful words:
"A thousand may fall
at your right hand...
but no evil will come near you...
no scourge come near your tent."
In the late '80s, AIDS
prevention work in jails...
took me to the So Paulo
Detention Center. Carandiru.
There, I heard stories, made real
friends, learned medicine...
and penetrated a few of the
mysteries of life in jail...
which would have remained
Inaccessible were I not a doctor.
- Morning, Doctor.
- Good morning.
Even today, whenever I hear
the iron gates close behind me...
I feel that shudder, just like
all those matinees...
at the Rialto Cinema, where
I'd sit glued to my chair...
as I watched all those jail films
in black-and-white.
"On October 2, 1992, 111 men died
at the So Paulo Detention Center.
There were no police deaths.
The only ones who know what
really happened are God...
the police, and the inmates.
I just heard the latter."
"On September 15, 2OO2, the last
inmates were transferred.
Once empty,
Carandiru closed its doors."
"On December 9, Carandiru
was finally demolished."