I, Wakizaka, have defeated
Joseon's southern army,
achieving victory though far outnumbered.
I have aided our northern advance,
securing Joseon's capital Hanyang.
Only Joseon's navy continues to resurface
on the southern coast.
I now set out to destroy them.
Lord Chancellor,
we will be ready for your arrival
as planned.
Bunroku year one, Wakizaka of Awaji.
WAE ENEMY (FOREIGN ISLANDS) BASE,
BUSANPO, GYEONGSANG-DO, JUNE 1592
Thank you.
WAKIZAKA YASUHARU
Bokkaisen (sea monster)?
Dono. (lord)
Our foe Yi Sun-shin built a new ship.
It looked menacing,
just like a Bokkaisen,
the mythical sea monster.
Our guns were useless.
It had a dragon head spouting fire.
We were struck by sheer terror.
Bokkaisen, you say.
Fear is a contagion.
Was the ship rammed?
Wrecked off the Sacheon coast.
We hauled it here.
A MONTH AGO, SACHEON
GYEONGSANG-DO, SOUTHEAST JOSEON
CHIEF LEE EON-RYANG
Row backward!
We must break loose!
CHIEF NAH DAE-YONG
Prepare to fire the dragon head
and all front cannons at once!
Load them now!
Fire!
It's the Bokkaisen!
BUSAN FORTRESS
ON APRIL 13, 1592,
BUSAN FORTRESS WAS ATTACKED
BY WAE INVADERS.
HANYANG
WAE FORCES OVERTOOK BUSAN FORTRESS,
OCCUPYING JOSEON'S CAPITAL HANYANG
IN 20 DAYS.
PYEONGYANG
KING SEONJO FLED NORTH TO PYEONGYANG
AS THE WAE INVADERS SWEPT NORTHWARD.
GWANGGYOSAN
50,000 SOLDIERS FROM THE PROVINCES JEOLLA,
GYEONGSANG, AND CHUNGCHEONG
GATHERED AT GWANGGYOSAN MOUNTAIN
TO RECAPTURE THE CAPITAL HANYANG.
GWANGGYOSAN MOUNTAIN, YONGIN
BUT ON JUNE 5, 1592,
WAKIZAKA AMBUSHED WITH 2,000 MEN,
DESTROYING JOSEON'S ARMY.
JOSEON APPEARED TO BE
ON THE BRINK OF RUIN.
MEANWHILE, ON THE SOUTHERN COAST
OF GOSEONG, GYEONGSANG-DO,
20 WAE SHIPS WERE DESTROYED AT DANGHANGPO
AS THE LEFT JEOLLA NAVY ADMIRAL
YI SUN-SHIN BATTLED ALONE AT SEA.
IN HIS FIRST NAVAL CAMPAIGN
ACROSS OKPO, HAPPO, AND JEOKJINPO,
HE DESTROYED 42 WAE SHIPS.
BATTLING IN HIS SECOND CAMPAIGN
ACROSS SACHEON, DANGPO, DANGHANPO,
HE SUFFERED AN EARLY GUNSHOT WOUND.
HANSAN: RISING DRAGON
FIVE DAYS TILL THE THIRD NAVAL CAMPAIGN
The turtle ship...
Admiral. Sergeant Song reporting.
Admiral Won has arrived.
SERGEANT SONG HUI-RIP
I'll get ready. Send in the servant.
Yes, sir.
LEFT JEOLLA NAVY HEADQUARTERS, YEOSU
What? A preemptive strike?
RIGHT GYEONGSANG NAVY, ADMIRAL WON GYUN
Have you gone mad?
COMMANDER JUNG UN
We must hasten to recapture Busan.
Now is our time to catch
the Wae invaders off guard.
We must strike first.
Minor victories are useless
unless we attack their main base.
Well, well...
You're still drunk
on those minor victories.
The enemy general in Busan led
the Battle of Gwanggyosan in Yongin.
Do you not recall
Chief Commander Lee Gwang,
who attacked the enemy
at Gwanggyosan Mountain?
His men were annihilated!
He is blamed for the defeat,
deemed a traitor.
There is a tide of war.
We must defend, not attack!
Tell me. Do you agree with him?
Or have your underlings gone mad?
- Watch your words!
- Underlings?
Admiral Won,
RIGHT JEOLLA NAVY, ADMIRAL LEE EOK-GI
do you have a better idea?
Defense! Ironclad defense!
With an ironclad barrier on the sea,
we'll defend
the Left Jeolla Navy Headquarters.
I'll burn down the provisional
Right Gyeongsang Navy Headquarters,
joining you here instead.
With our joint fleet
fending off the enemy,
won't our headquarters here be
a steely fortress?
RIGHT GYEONGSANG NAVY
COMMANDER LEE UN-RYONG
An elder such as yourself
need not see me out.
LEFT JEOLLA NAVY, COMMANDER EO YOUNG-DAM
Since you're a former cadet
now busy as a commander,
this is an old teacher's chance
to enjoy rare company.
You're in good spirits as always.
And in good health, it seems.
By no means.
I'm suffering under a dreadful superior.
But you're no stranger
to dreadful superiors.
Alas, we suffer alike.
Good night, sir.
WAE (FOREIGN ISLANDS) ENEMY BASE,
BUSANPO, GYEONSANG-DO
The lord chancellor has
high hopes for you.
You are welcome here,
advisor.
I saw your men looking busy.
Isn't it too soon for haste?
KURODA KANBEI
LORD CHANCELLOR'S ADVISOR
Here.
The lord chancellor sends his reply.
In the Battle of Yongin
at Gwanggyosan Mountain,
do you know how I destroyed 50,000 men
with only 2,000?
Why,
you caught them unawares
with a preemptive ambush.
YEOSU
Yi Sun-shin's headquarters here
must be struck down immediately.
And then...
Then?
We must reinforce Konishi's division
up north in Pyeongyang.
Once we do,
our conquest of Joseon shall be complete.
Impressive.
Worthy of the lord chancellor's
preeminent warrior.
Konishi up north in Pyeongyang
will be beholden to you,
bowing in gratitude.
I thought you might hasten
like the other generals
straight to Ming China.
I was concerned.
No doubt, you also crave
the conquest of Ming China.
However,
I advise against a solo campaign.
As things now stand,
there is no need for risk.
Better to lead a joint campaign
at full force.
I understand.
Hence,
I have a request.
About Kato, I presume?
TURTLE SHIP DOCKYARD
LEFT JEOLLA NAVY HEADQUARTERS
You're removing the dragon head?
Since the Battle of Sacheon,
I've been thinking.
I stayed up nights
unable to shake the belief
that you need the turtle ship.
Will it no longer get lodged upon ramming?
It's the only way to solve that problem.
Will it also improve its speed?
Indeed, sir.
A headless turtle ship...
Have you heard?
The latest Wae invaders to arrive
in Busan...
I hear they're quite formidable.
How is Admiral Yi's order coming along?
Well...
GUNNERY MASTER
LEE BONG-SU
...we're gathering
all the gunpower ingredients we can,
sourcing it from the people.
But the turtle ships guzzle so much.
Gunpowder-guzzling monsters, they are.
The turtle ships can join
the admiral's fleet
only if you make haste.
The ramming ships must do more than ram.
Right.
By the way,
this is for you.
What's this?
I caught the critter myself.
If you ever get lonely or discouraged,
it can cheer you up.
- Mocking me, are you?
- Take it easy.
Cook a turtle soup for your health
if you'd like.
Before you become a shell of a man.
That impudence.
Defense! Ironclad defense!
We must defend, not attack!
I have a letter from Jeonju Fortress
sent by Chief Commander Lee Gwang.
He was pained
to recall his defeat
at Gwanggyosan Mountain.
The enemy Wakizaka
did not stay behind
to guard Suwon Fortress.
Instead, he advanced
to Yongin's Gwanggyosan Mountain,
tiring and luring our troops.
When our men lowered their guard,
setting up camp in an open field,
Wakizaka ambushed at dawn,
annihilating our army.
His stronghold was defended
without a defensive strategy.
Admiral Yi.
His Majesty sends word.
What has happened?
We received word from Pyeongyang.
HIS MAJESTY HAS DEPARTED TO UIJU
BY THE NORTHWEST BORDER.
How could he forsake Pyeongyang Fortress?
There is more at stake than Pyeongyang.
We must ask why His Majesty left for Uiju
by the northwest border.
The Chief Commander preferred
the northeast province Hamgyeong-do
as a defensible base,
but His Majesty chose Uiju
by the northwest border instead.
Will His Majesty
seek refuge westward in Ming China?
That cannot be.
It will destroy the people's morale
and threaten the fate of our land.
Based on our training
with Joseon prisoners,
Joseon's navy cannons reach a firing range
of 1,000 yards.
They are destructive within 500 yards.
WATANABE SHICHIEMON
They aim accurately within 100 yards.
One hundred yards.
Their panokseon (Joseon warships)
have a strange way of reloading cannons.
How so?
Instead of reloading,
they rotate their ships,
firing from the other side.
Interesting.
However,
even if their panokseon ships refire
faster that way,
we can press with speed
from 200 yards away,
overtaking their ships.
From 200 yards,
overtaking them.
Dono.
We must ambush again.
MANABE SAMANOSUKE
Deploy the fleet at once.
If they block us,
we will crush that troublesome thing.
You mean the sea monster Bokkaisen,
or rather their mekurabune (blind ship)?
Mekurabune.
Blind ship.
I like that name better than Bokkaisen.
The mekurabune fought only one battle.
But why?
Why won't they battle with a ship
rumored to be a monstrous Bokkaisen?
Sahei.
You have two days.
Go scout the Left Jeolla Navy.
Find out about the mekurabune.
Also,
about Yi Sun-shin.
Watanabe.
About Kobayakawa
leading the sixth division
in Geumsan near Jeolla-do.
I must send word to him.
Admiral.
Admiral Yi.
Our headquarters here might be
His Majesty's last refuge.
Instead of rushing to battle,
perhaps we should guard this place
as Admiral Won suggested.
Will you still attack
the Wae invaders' base at Busan Fortress?
Does it look so in your eyes?
Is it not so?
Perhaps it is.
But as Admiral Won has said,
we're on the defensive.
An attack on Busan requires caution.
If you will neither defend nor attack,
what is your battle plan?
Perhaps
our next battle will determine
the fate of this war.
HEUNGGUKSA TEMPLE REFUGE
Rice balls!
Rice!
Please have some food.
I saw that man at Busan Fortress.
Interesting.
- Be careful.
- All right.
I have received your letter.
I appreciate the offer,
but as commander of the sixth division,
I, Kobayakawa, will attack Jeonju Fortress
as planned.
Now that Geumsan Fortress is cleared
of the Joseon people's militia,
I can soon advance on Jeonju Fortress
in Jeolla-do.
Transcribe my reply.
Instead of attacking Jeonju Fortress
with the sixth division,
I ask you to strike Yi Sun-shin's
Left Jeolla Navy Headquarters.
Do so, and I will grant you
all my conquests in Jeolla-do.
The war's outcome depends on
the Left Jeolla Navy, not Jeonju Fortress.
Now, join me in this attack,
which will please the lord chancellor.
Dono.
Will you grant Kobayakawa
all of Jeolla-do?
Yi is a mere hindrance we can defeat
without his help.
A mere hindrance?
How will you defeat Yi?
By catching him off guard
with a preemptive strike!
As we did at Gwanggyosan!
Let's stay one step ahead.
We'll defeat him also on land.
It's a plan for total victory,
which I have while Yi doesn't.
- But we're ready...
- Joseon will fall soon.
The war will shift to Ming China.
By reaching Ming first,
we will conquer much more.
Jeolla-do pales in comparison.
Do you not understand?
But
will Kato's fleet arrive in time?
Kanbei is a man of his word.
He will make it happen.
Why did your men at Sacheon join
the division at Geumsan near Jeolla?
Will they deploy from Geumsan
to attack Jeonju Fortress?
When will they strike?
I know nothing.
Nothing at all.
Nothing.
You fools!
Jeonju Fortress matters little.
Our Wae army is gathering
in great numbers in Busan.
Joseon will be annihilated
on our way to Ming China and India.
You should beg for your lives!
Who are you?
- Admiral!
Why, you!
How dare you!
Dono!
What have they done to him?
Are you alright?
Dono!
You're the reason we endure.
You're a hero to us all!
Do not take his life.
I sense he has a veiled purpose.
This war...
What is it about?
I beseech you to tell me.
What is this war?
A battle of the righteous
against the unrighteous.
Not a battle of nations?
No.
I shot you at Sacheon.
I saw with my own eyes
how you stepped forth
to save your soldier.
But my commander
used us men as shields
to save himself.
Please. Let me serve you.
NOKDUNDO ISLAND,
HAMGYEONG-DO (NORTHEAST BORDER)
Why did I dream of this?
His stronghold was defended
without a defensive strategy.
Defended
THREE DAYS TILL THE THIRD NAVAL CAMPAIGN
Is this formation defensive? Or offensive?
Surely defensive.
Like a barrier on the sea.
A barrier on the sea?
Over there,
we're simulating the Wae invaders' attack.
It's quite realistic.
Crane wing formation.
Yes, Admiral.
Crane wing formation!
We must move to the left wing.
Yes, sir.
To the right wing's center.
On the double.
Yes, sir.
We're colliding!
Watch your position!
Go farther left!
We're due at the left wing's center!
The right wing looks unsteady.
Never mind. We'll go head-on.
- Raise the ladders.
- Raise them!
Rotate the ship.
Rotate!
Port oars, stop!
Starboard oars, row faster!
Back to formation!
- Rotate.
- Rotate!
Rotate!
Port oars, stop! Rotate!
Sir, we can't rotate
within such short distance.
Not with Admiral Won's ships
that lack training.
Keep him in the formation.
And deliver this to Admiral Lee Eok-gi.
Yes, sir.
Rotate the ship!
Reporting, sir.
Since the Battle of Sacheon,
the mekurabune was never seen in training.
There must be a problem
with the mekurabune.
We must find out what it is.
We'll enter their headquarters.
Let's move.
- Fire!
- What do you want?
- Who are you?
- We're on your side.
The prisoners' cells are on fire!
The prisoners are escaping! After them!
No wonder you looked murderous for a monk.
Catch them! Catch the prisoners!
The turtle ship is in flames!
Put out the fire! Now!
Follow me.
You call yourselves officers in charge?
It's your duty to guard the turtle ship!
At all times with no exception!
This is a failure in duty!
Admiral. I'm afraid the head spy escaped.
We've failed you, sir.
Move! Hurry up!
Hurry up!
Admiral.
A few prisoners are missing.
Hurry up!
- Admiral.
- Any damages to the turtle ship?
CHIEF LEE GI-NAM
Some scorches. Nothing serious.
The head spy stole
the turtle ship's construction plans.
Where is Chief Nah?
At the Suncheon dockyard
since two days ago.
Let us go there.
SECRET DOCKYARD, SUNCHEON, NEAR YEOSU
This turtle ship has to be better!
Seal that joint!
Admiral! Admiral.
I heard about the spies.
I'm relieved
that the turtle ships weren't damaged.
I am told
you're reattaching the dragon head.
Yes, sir.
We must wage battle soon.
Will this turtle ship be ready?
We're working night and day.
We need a few more days.
The spies escaped
with your construction plans.
Wakizaka will learn
about the turtle ship's weaknesses.
Admiral.
This new turtle ship is different.
I will fight this battle
without turtle ships.
I must leave now.
Admiral.
The sides look weak.
Good for firing cannons
but exposed to attack.
Also,
the head and cover must be heavy.
I wonder if it can sail with any speed.
Junsa, was it?
So you fought against the ship.
Yes, at the Battle of Sacheon.
Indeed, its movement seemed quite slow.
Go on.
At Sacheon,
we fell for Yi's luring tactic.
Luring tactic?
Yes, sir.
However,
as you pointed out,
we could've easily destroyed the ship
had we been prepared.
Once it rammed into our warship,
the dragon head was lodged,
unable to move.
The dragon head was lodged?
Yes, sir.
So, that was the flaw.
A flawed ram.
And yet,
it was called the Bokkaisen,
striking terror in our men.
Are you implying it was a false rumor?
Watanabe.
What do you think?
Since it was absent from training,
it probably won't be deployed.
However, I'm concerned
by Sahei's report
regarding their crane wing formation.
It appears to be an offensive.
I suspect they will surround Busanpo
to mount an attack.
No, sir.
Yi was using prisoners
to prepare defensive tactics.
Besides, without the mekurabune,
he cannot risk an attack.
Dono. These are baseless claims.
Enough.
Junsa.
Come closer.
Closer.
Justify your claim.
Even their king has fled
to the northwest border.
Hence, Yi will be looking to retreat.
He wouldn't dare advance in attack.
I must say,
it's decent reasoning.
Dono. Kato's fleet has arrived.
Arriving at the perfect time.
KATO YOSHIAKI
KUKI YOSHITAKA
The war god Hachiman
shines on me again.
Admiral!
Can you win your battle
without the turtle ship?
Can you truly win without the turtle ship?
Your wound has yet to heal.
Yet you're shooting arrows already.
Admiral.
I'm convinced by our training
that we need the turtle ships.
Do you not agree?
Admiral.
Sir,
Lim Jun-young brought his report
in person.
In person?
Until now, Wakizaka's fleet
had 30 large ships, 70 medium ships,
One hundred ships total.
Kato Yoshiaki's fleet
from the southern island Daemado
has now joined him
with 20 large ships and 20 small ships.
That makes 140 ships total.
Wakizaka's wait is over.
He will deploy soon.
The time has arrived.
But sir,
Kato's ships are unique.
Unique?
Several large ships have thicker hulls
and suspended cannons
we haven't seen before.
As for their flagship,
it's armed with cannons
and covered in iron plates.
A flagship covered in iron plates?
It is as expected.
They prepared
against our cannons and rams.
This enemy fleet...
COMMANDER GWON JUN
...will attack to secure a supply route
to the western coast.
The enemy's ground troops are gathered...
COMMANDER SHIN HO
...at Geumsan near Jeonju Fortress.
They will fight on two fronts at sea
and on land.
They will attack both Jeonju Fortress
and the Left Jeolla Navy.
If our navy falls as the enemy wishes,
Joseon's regime in Uiju will also fall.
We will surely face attack,
but Jeonju is under greater threat.
The Battle of Yongin has left
Chief Commander Lee Gwang
crippled by defeat.
In any case,
we must alert Jeonju Fortress.
Shouldn't we split our forces
to reinforce the army at Jeonju Fortress?
Have you gone mad?
We cannot split the navy.
Out of the question!
Hold your anger. I merely speak as I must.
Enough.
Admiral Yi.
How will you proceed?
The time has come for a critical battle.
Hence...
tomorrow at midnight,
we shall set out to war.
Prepare for deployment.
Instead of defending?
Load the shells and gunpowder!
Careful!
As ordered,
GUNNERY MASTER LEE BONG-SU
we stockpiled all the gunpowder we could.
Well done.
Why do you need more than usual?
For double-loading cannons
with both shells and shrapnel shells.
That will cause damage
only within short range.
- The enemy ships will close in...
- Noted.
Is Chief Nah on his way?
Let's enjoy this drink together.
By the way,
what kind of man is this Admiral Yi?
A surprisingly strong foe.
That is why we must face him together.
Joseon's commanders have been weak,
I heard.
Yi must be the exception.
Now that two war heroes have
joined us here,
Yi will not stand a chance.
This dull war will end sooner
than expected.
Dono.
We received word
from Kobayakawa's sixth division.
Everyone out.
Dither at your peril if you wish to die!
Hurry up!
Kobayakawa agreed to the inland attack
against the Left Jeolla Navy Headquarters.
In that case,
when will he deploy?
He asked
that you decide when and send your reply.
If so,
we set out tonight at midnight.
Absurd!
You can't do so without consulting me!
Wakizaka, please reconsider.
For procedure's sake.
We must attack
before the typhoon season arrives.
Pardon the haste.
You scoundrel!
Stop!
Your crude manner will cost you
my alliance.
You take war too lightly, Wakizaka!
Don't be rash,
Kato.
Sit down.
Calm down.
Kato. Put down your sword.
I demand an answer.
Tell me.
Do you wish to join forces with me or not?
Our dislike is mutual.
However,
the lord chancellor ordered
our joint attack.
Withdraw your sword,
and I'll overlook this outburst.
Kato.
Kato!
You can come out now.
Thank you. I heard crucial information.
I must report back at once
to the Left Jeolla Navy.
I've been watching you.
So that wench slipped you in.
Remarkable.
Even the courtesans are spies.
What a disappointment.
I'd hoped to take you with me.
Die!
Dono!
Stand back!
Run!
Sahei!
After him! Now!
You stay here!
Follow me, Manabe!
How much does he know?
Tell me.
There he is! By the shore!
- Hurry.
- After him.
Get in.
Fire!
Aim the fire arrows!
Release!
No.
Not until you spill everything you know.
Dono, We've failed you.
Please take our lives.
Hunt down all the spies.
Also,
keep her alive.
Please! I'm no spy!
I'm not!
Perhaps now is the time
to break with the past,
tying up all loose ends.
Please don't kill me!
Strike!
DAY ONE, THIRD NAVAL CAMPAIGN
We've reached Dangpo, our midway stopover.
Report to Admiral Yi.
Yes, sir.
We're allies! Stop!
Kill him, too!
Wakizaka!
Tell me.
Who is backing you?
Is it Kanbei?
Given our mutual hatred,
you and I will only clash
if we join forces.
Surrender your ships and begone.
Do so,
and I'll let you live.
You expect to steal my iron-plated ship
without retribution?
Mark my words.
I will repay this insult.
Now I know.
From the start, you had this planned.
But my ships won't matter.
Begone if you care to live!
Summoned by the lord chancellor,
I've returned to Osaka Castle.
Wakizaka, you shall now demolish
the Joseon navy
and reach Ming China's Tianjin.
Conquer the land!
Once you do,
the lord chancellor will bypass Joseon,
proceeding straight to Ming.
You shall be the one
to welcome him there.
The golden fan reflects
the lord chancellor's wishes.
Treasure it.
Brothers,
we will overtake Konishi's 1st
and Kiyomasa's 2nd divisions
as the first to reach Ming China.
Dono!
We congratulate you!
Row faster!
Dono. Yi deployed his fleet.
His ships are nearby, already at Dangpo.
I see.
A strong foe indeed.
Between Dangpo
and our current base Ungpo.
Look here.
This narrow sea route between us,
Gyeonnaeryang Strait.
GYEONNAERYANG STRAIT
Are you reminded of anywhere?
In the Battle of Yongin,
there was a narrow pass
en route to Hanyang.
In Gwanggyosan, was it not?
We'll sail to Gyeonnaeryang,
lying in ambush.
We'll wait for Yi's next move.
- Now go.
- Yes, sir!
DANGPO, JOSEON NAVY'S MIDWAY STOPOVER
I've sworn allegiance to Admiral Yi.
There is no time. You must go alone now.
Many lives were lost
to secure that report.
Deliver it without fail to Admiral Yi.
Hurry! We must pass Ungchi!
Ungchi... leads
to the Left Jeolla Navy Headquarters.
Hurry the rear guard! There is no time!
The shortcut to Jeonju Fortress is
this way...
DANGPO, JOSEON NAVY'S MIDWAY STOPOVER
We've checked these areas.
Now we're searching
near Angolpo and Ungpo...
So, have you located
the hidden enemy fleet?
We will, soon enough.
I was loath to turn my back so soon
immediately upon arrival yesterday.
But if the enemy is not found today,
I will withdraw my men
to help defend Jeonju Fortress.
We'll locate them today.
Admiral. We've found the enemy.
- Where?
- Gyeonnaeryang Strait.
Gyeonnaeryang is nearby.
Around 100 Wae ships are docked there.
GYEONNAERYANG
DANGPO
We must attack at once.
Fortune is on our side.
They're docked at Gyeonnaeryang
because they know
our fleet has sailed out to these shores.
That changes nothing.
We must be cautious.
Remove the other tables.
- Yes, sir.
We must lure them here
to the open sea of Hansan.
Gyeonnaeryang is too narrow.
Our panokseon warships
cannot battle there.
I disagree.
Narrow or not,
it'll be easier to attack
while the enemy is docked.
Wouldn't our previous battle formations
suit the circumstances?
Strong currents in the strait will hinder
our ships' movement.
Many will be destroyed.
Also, the attack may be ineffective
if the enemy flees to shore.
A leader in war should not shy away
from small damages.
And if the enemy flees to shore,
they can only run to Geojedo Island.
Since they'll be cut off
from reinforcement,
we can hunt them down
for a rare victory on land.
I say we strike at them.
In that case,
why don't you take lead
with the first attack?
What?
You want only my ships to get battered
and destroyed in vain?
I want you to lure the enemy ships
to this open sea of Hansan.
Lure out the fleet?
To battle
in crane wing formation?
Is that what you meant
by a barrier on the sea?
But I'm no fool.
I can't attack
with only seven ships in my fleet.
That's a suicide mission.
Wakizaka is no fool either.
You think he'll be lured so easily?
I'll take no part in this reckless plan.
Admiral Won!
The enemy is right before us.
A barrier on the sea? Nonsense!
I'll help defend Jeonju Fortress instead.
As a hyangdo (naval guide),
I can lure the enemy.
I know the waterways around Gyeonnaeryang.
Let me lure the enemy.
I shall go instead.
The task should not fall
to the elderly commander.
It is not befitting.
Please. Send me instead.
Admiral, I agree.
CAPTAIN LEE YEONG-NAM
Please send us instead.
I see you two are now serving Admiral Yi.
Admiral.
It's the last wish of an old commander.
Please grant it.
CRANE WING FORMATION PLAN
A barrier on the sea? Nonsense!
What is your battle plan?
Will the crane wing formation
ensure victory?
CHIEF NAH DAE-YONG
Admiral. Sergeant Song reporting.
Come in.
What brings you here?
A report requiring secrecy.
It's from Junsa.
Kobayakawa's troops left Geumsan to attack
the Left Jeolla Navy Headquarters,
not Jeonju Fortress.
The enemy's army and navy
will strike in unison.
Their fleet was deployed
on the fifth at midnight.
If their ground troops bypass
Jeonju Fortress
to strike our headquarters,
it will be a critical blow.
Have you alerted Jeonju Fortress?
Junsa is on his way to alert them.
If so,
who delivered this report instead of him?
UNGCHI PASS
Fasten the cannons tightly!
I don't trust the anti-Wae fighter.
ANTI-WAE FIGHTER:
FORMER WAE SOLDIER FIGHTING FOR JOSEON
Why would the enemy bypass Jeonju Fortress
to attack the navy headquarters?
Let's get rid of that anti-Wae fighter
and march to Jeonju as planned.
RIGHTEOUS MILITIA COMMANDER, HWANG BAK
Once the enemy passes Ungchi,
it's only a half-day's march
to the navy headquarters.
We'll receive orders soon.
Until then, we must defend this pass.
So you're the anti-Wae fighter?
Follow me.
If we survive this,
I'll treat you to a hearty drink.
Wait.
No need for that.
A shared, righteous spirit.
That's all you need.
Get some armor instead.
CRANE WING FORMATION PLAN
We will use the enemy's attack
to surround their fleet.
In the sea of Hansan,
we will battle in crane wing formation.
Flanking the flagship
on the right wing's center will be
Admiral Lee Eok-gi.
On the left wing's center,
there will be Admiral Won.
By his side,
there'll be the wise Commander Eo,
the hyangdo (naval guide)
well versed in Joseon's waterways.
Commander Lee Un-ryong,
who offers trustworthy counsel,
shall be next to him.
Captain Kim Wan,
who maneuvers with great skill,
will be at the tip of the left wing.
Commander Gwon Jun
has the speed and strength
to wage close combat
at the tip of the right wing.
As a proven warrior who leads
our navy's most forceful charges,
Commander Jung Un will be...
TO CHIEF NAH DAE-YONG
Were all ships ordered
to double-load their cannons?
Yes, sir.
We gave orders to double-load shells
and shrapnel shells.
Prepare for deployment.
Yes, sir.
All ships to war.
All ships!
To war!
- To war!
DAY FOUR, THIRD NAVAL CAMPAIGN
BATTLE OF HANSAN ISLAND
GYEONNAERYANG STRAIT
Dono! Yi has deployed his fleet.
Fifty six ships set sail from Dangpo.
All panokseon warships,
no mekurabune (blind ship) to be seen.
Could it be a deception?
Never mind the mekurabune.
You two will wait in ambush
on the right and left flanks.
- Yes, sir!
We must lure out the enemy.
Stay at least 200 yards away
from their ships.
Yes, sir.
Lower the anchor!
LEFT FLANK
MANABE SAMANOSUKE
RIGHT FLANK
WATANABE SHICHIEMON
Enemy ships! Enemy ships ahead!
Hold fire! Find the enemy ships!
Fire!
Rank two, prepare to fire!
Sahei. How many ships?
We cannot count yet.
Hold positions.
Keep the enemy at bay by returning fire.
Deplete their firepower.
- Yes, sir!
- To the right! Fire!
Hold fire!
To the left! They're on the left!
Fire!
Commander Manabe on the left flank
asks if he may attack.
Commander Watanabe on the right flank
asks the same.
Tell them to stay in position
and hold fire.
They must wait in ambush.
Yes, sir!
Commander. I will reverse the ship.
Advance 100 yards.
We should stop here.
We'll be surrounded by the enemy!
At this rate, the enemy won't budge.
We must deliver a blow to lure them out.
Row forward!
Yes, sir!
OUTSIDE GYEONNAERYANG STRAIT
Will the enemy be lured?
Deploy the ships on standby.
Yes, sir.
Commander! The fog is clearing.
We're running low on gunpowder and shells.
We must retreat!
Cannon fire! They're firing cannons!
Firing cannons?
Fire!
The fog is clearing! We can see the ships!
Only three ships.
How daring, Yi Sun-shin.
You shall soon regret
leaving your headquarters.
Wae ships on the right!
It's an ambush!
A brave move.
But three ships aren't enough to lure us.
How will Yi respond
once they've burned down?
I wonder.
It's too late.
Prepare for close combat.
Dono, enemy ships on the left!
Sir! They're Joseon ships.
COMMANDER LEE UN-RYONG
Row at full speed! We must retreat!
Row faster! We must retreat!
Chase after them at full speed.
Close in!
- Now!
- Yes, sir!
Sahei!
Signal Manabe at once to stop his chase.
He must not leave Gyeonnaeryang Strait.
Yes, sir!
Sir, over there!
Orders to stop!
What do we do, sir?
Our sword is drawn.
We'll catch them here in Gyeonnaeryang.
It's what the general wants. After them!
Their main fleet isn't joining the attack.
Rotate starboard!
Throw the grapnel! Board the ship!
Our ships are hitting the rocks.
No matter,
we'll board enemy ships instead.
Close in!
To port! Rotate to port!
My word. How is this possible?
Fire!
Manabe.
Dono.
Admiral! We received report
from Gyeonnaeryang.
Commander Lee's ships entered the strait,
but the enemy's main fleet
has yet to be lured.
All ships
to the mouth of Gyeonnaeryang Strait
in arrowhead formation.
Raise the command flag.
Admiral.
If the enemy attacks head-on,
we could be in danger.
The current is against us.
We need them to attack.
Raise the flag.
Yes, sir.
Raise the flag!
Dono.
The enemy's main fleet has arrived!
All ships, stop!
By now,
Kobayakawa will have passed Ungchi.
Fire the cannons!
We need more arrows!
Our hillside flank has fallen.
We're far outnumbered!
Fall back to line two!
Charge!
Line two cannot hold.
We must retreat to line three.
That'll be the end for us
and the navy headquarters.
No! For all of Jeolla-do!
Charge!
Enemy ships! The enemy is advancing!
Rotate all ships. Reinforce rowers.
All rowers to oars!
Add rowers!
Rotate the ship!
Get ready to fire!
Sir! It's the command kite.
We must join the formation!
Row harder!
CRANE WING
Add rowers. Full speed ahead!
- Speed ensures victory!
- Yes, sir!
Add more oars!
Row faster!
Faster!
Row with all your might!
We must sail faster!
I will avenge Manabe
by destroying you myself.
Wae ships are closing in!
Fire!
Shoot the arrows!
Admiral. They're grappling our ship!
Cut the ropes!
We must return to formation.
Sir! Commanders Eo Young-dam
and Lee Un-ryong are under attack.
Sir!
Cover for him!
- Commander Eo.
- Follow me!
Crane wing formation. As expected.
Sahei can battle those ships
while we charge in fish-scale formation.
Fish-scale formation!
Watanabe reports from the front rank
that he will charge at the ships
lagging behind at the right wing.
He thinks just like me.
Tell him I permit the attack.
Yes, sir!
Hurry!
Row backward and load the cannons!
Fire!
What in the world is he thinking?
He's firing without order
despite the waves.
He should know better!
The enemy ships are too fast.
We should've attacked sooner.
You blasted Yi Sun-shin,
why aren't you firing?
Admiral Won's ships are weakening
our formation.
Please give order to fire.
Please give order, sir!
Before firing,
we must complete the formation.
In the Battle of Mikatagahara,
Takeda Shingen destroyed
Tokugawa's crane wing formation
not by swords or guns.
He crushed it with cavalry.
Charge forth, Watanabe.
You and I will crush the foe
as we did at Gwanggyosan!
Charge forth.
You're not the only ones
with ramming ships.
Behold the might of our antaekseon
(WAE large warship).
Your crane will fall
before spreading its wings.
We've caught you now.
Mekurabune (blind ship).
It's the mekurabune!
Dono!
Bring the large gun!
Now!
It's the mekurabune!
Row harder!
Prepare to fire!
That flagship is shielded by iron plates.
Rotate to port and ram its stern.
It's slow.
Nothing but a blind mekurabune.
Charge toward Yi's flagship!
Signal the fleet!
- Yes, sir!
We'll go to the stern chaser.
I'll fire it myself.
The sides were its weakness.
It will rotate for sure.
I'll aim for the side.
Take fire, mekurabune.
Fire!
Right cannon, fire!
Aim!
Fire!
Dono,
the mekurabune is closing in sideways
out of our firing range.
Aim!
Sahei.
My trusty cousin.
Fire!
Wait and see, Yi Sun-shin.
Your mekurabune shall be your fall.
That one has a lower hull,
harder to target.
The mekurabune is charging at us!
Good.
Charge at us with all your might,
mekurabune.
Once you do,
your head will be lodged in my ship.
Prepare to board!
Bokkaisen (sea monster).
Dono!
Admiral.
The new turtle ship will achieve
more than ramming.
Please.
Deploy the turtle ship.
Yi Sun-shin.
Was this your final ploy?
Admiral. Thanks to the new turtle ship,
Commanders Eo Hyang-do and Lee Un-ryong
have returned to formation.
Admiral.
The enemy ships are near.
We must open fire.
Admiral!
Why is the turtle ship still
in their midst?
The mekurabune is charging at us!
Two hundred yards away.
We can overtake them.
All ships!
Break formation!
Engage the enemy!
Aim!
What in the world is he thinking?
The enemy is right before us.
We can't wait any longer!
Fire immediately!
Sir, we're out of shells.
Admiral.
We must win this battle.
Please fire.
One hundred yards.
Fifty yards.
Raise the ladders!
All ships.
Raise them!
Rotate.
Rotate!
Port oars, stop!
Starboard oars, row harder!
Too late, Yi Sun-shin.
Row harder!
Board their ships!
Fire.
A barrier on the sea.
Admiral, you have to shoot now!
Admiral!
A trap!
Fire!
Stop them!
We must not let them pass!
Fight to the death!
What the hell are you?
I wanted to treat you to a hearty drink.
It's too bad I can't.
Move!
You invaders will not
go beyond this Ungchi Pass.
We must guard this place...
RIGHTEOUS MILITIA COMMANDER, HWANG JIN
Charge!
What did I tell you?
It's a righteous battle.
Fought together
with a shared spirit.
Yours as well.
I'm thankful for it.
What is this war?
A battle of the righteous
against the unrighteous.
The enemy is fleeing!
Chase after them!
RIGHTEOUS
FOLLOW
Admiral. It is a total triumph.
No.
Let us press on.
What Joseon needs
is a decisive victory.
DAY SIX, THIRD NAVAL CAMPAIGN
ANGOLPO, NEAR BUSAN
DAY SEVEN, THIRD NAVAL CAMPAIGN
BUSANPO, FINAL BATTLEGROUND
WAE NAVAL COMMANDER IN CHIEF
AT BUSANPO, TODO TAKATORA
ON JULY 11, 1592,
ADMIRAL YI ENDED HIS THIRD NAVAL CAMPAIGN
WITH A CANNONADE ON THE ENEMY AT BUSANPO.
HASHIBA (TOYOTOMI) HIDEYOSHI QUIT
HIS PLANS TO DEFEAT JOSEON'S NAVY.
THIS SAFEGUARDED MING TO THE WEST
AND REVERSED THE TIDE OF WAR.
What made you bring me here, sir?
A YEAR LATER, HANSANDO ISLAND
Look at Geojedo Island.
The island is facing
the mouth of enemy waters.
We must secure tighter control
over this sea.
I agree, sir.
Thanks to our previous victory
in these waters,
the enemy at Busanpo
has yet to reappear
around Hansando Island.
I admire the name.
Hansan.
Indeed, it's a meaningful name.
It stands for "grand mountain,"
does it not?
It does.
This Gyeonnaeryang Strait facing Hansan
will be our front line.
May Hansan prove to be
a truly grand mountain
guarding our land.
Such is my hope.
The turtle ships have arrived!
HANSAN: RISING DRAGON