In pain, we may find
comfort, in sorrow, hope,
in death, resurrection.
Aim... fire!
They're almost finished out there, Ken.
What do you want me to tell you, Jack?
I can't get the damn thing open.
- Stripped?
- Nah, it's catching.
It's just stuck or something.
When was the last time you
opened one of these things?
First one we've had since
I've been with the VA.
That's, like, what, a decade?
Yeah. Let me try.
Okay, it's moving.
What's that smell?
You okay?
Give me a dollar!
Okay. What's wrong with that one?
The machine wouldn't take
it and I want a candy bar.
What's wrong with that candy bar?
It has nougat in it.
But you hate nougat.
I know!
It was a mistake, McGee!
Do you have a dollar?!
All I have are big bills.
What is nougat?
It's whipped dolphin fat.
No, that's the filling in Klowny Kake.
That is a myth!
Would someone please give me a dollar?!
Sure, I got one.
Thanks.
God, it's like some kind
of crime to not like nougat.
I don't even know what nougat is.
It's a cream made from
sugar, honey and nuts.
Grab your gear.
Got an explosion at a Marine's
funeral in James River National.
Did anyone else see what
just happened there with Abby?
Yeah, she stole my dollar.
Last ones to the party.
It's not really a party until
the bomb squad says it is.
What'd you find?
We got nothing.
No ordnance,
no residue, no electronics,
no time device,
no wiring, no remote.
No evidence of a bomb.
Except for the explosion.
We got two employees injured, both vets.
They were taken to the VA
with concussions and shrapnel wounds.
Got names?
Former Lance Corporal Lloyd Jackson,
36, and PFC Kenneth Dixon, 25.
Veterans keep getting younger.
The kid they were burying was only 22.
It's a family crypt.
- Tandem?
- His grandfather was in the back slot.
Still there as far as we could tell.
Your men cleared?
Fire readings are clean.
Air's safe to breathe, not
that I would recommend it.
Anything else?
Yeah. You might want
to cover your shoes.
That is truly appalling.
"Chief Warrant Officer Mitchell Waller."
Died, 1978. Should be the
one in the back of the crypt.
He appears to be undisturbed.
He would be the only one.
This is really the most
disgusting thing I've ever seen.
And believe me, that says a lot.
It's like porridge.
The word is "effluvium",
the result of decomposing
human organs and tissue.
This is people?
Yes, two, I'd say,
judging bye the volume.
And the two skulls, of course.
Mr. Palmer, we have
to recover all of this.
One Wet Vac for the Soylent
Green coming right up.
Somewhat claustrophobic.
And for all eternity.
Our friends here might agree with you.
They obviously needed to get out.
They didn't belong
there in the first place.
Vents are definitely clogged.
Careful, Doctor, we still haven't
found traces of what
caused the explosion.
If my suspicions are
correct, Officer David,
the bomb is all around us.
It's a phenomenon in the death industry
informally referred to as
"exploding casket syndrome."
Well, the floor's all yours, Duck.
Thank you, Jethro.
All bodies contain enzymes and bacteria.
Immediately upon death, they
start to break down tissue.
Yes, a body can liquefy within a week,
especially if it hasn't been embalmed.
It's possible that these remains
were human in appearance
as recently as two weeks ago.
And someone dumped them in here.
Yes, and in such a confined space,
as the gases were given off the bodies,
without any proper ventilation
the crypt itself could
become a pressure cooker.
The bodies were the bomb.
Not our first meat puzzle, Doctor.
And it certainly won't be the last.
Never forget, Mr. Palmer,
experience is the ultimate teacher.
Corner pieces are not as reliable
as the singular components.
Yes, as experience has taught us.
Skulls and torsos.
And judging by these pelvic structures,
we have a man and a woman.
Yes, well, let's put Adam
on the left and Eve on the right.
This reminds me of a summer
when I assisted at an archaeological dig
in North Africa.
Our team unearthed
two fossilized Neanderthals
from a primitive burial mound:
one man, one woman.
This rib structure's fractured, Doctor.
Possibly from the
force of the explosion?
Oh, no, no, no.
It's a clean, serrated edge.
Very unlikely.
Did you know that the Zulus burn
all the possessions of a dear departed
to ward off evil?
Some tribes even throw spears
and shoot arrows into the
air to kill hovering spirits.
Right ulna.
That evolved into the
modern military tradition
of firing a volley into the air.
Uh, right hand.
Yes, after the death of an African king,
right hand,
some of his subjects used
to cut off fingers and toes.
It was considered a mark of respect.
Humerus.
I suppose it depends
on what you find funny.
Oh, right,
humerus.
Right hand.
Didn't this happen the last time?
We're gonna need another table.
The mausoleum doesn't get many visitors
which makes it a creative place
to get rid of a few bodies,
- but...
- Whoever deposited them
would first have to know that a portion
of Chief Waller's crypt was vacant.
That would suggest an inside job.
With the knowledge to
access a sealed tomb.
Which would point to Jackson...
or Dixon.
If they hadn't practically
blown themselves up.
What do you think, McGee?
She definitely seemed un-Abby.
Who?
Abby.
Abby's unhappy?
No, Abby's un-Abby.
I need you to focus here,
okay? Pitch in?
I'll talk to her when I can.
Why you?
Because dealing with an angry
woman requires a great
deal of sensitivity.
Clearly not an area
of expertise for you.
Well, I don't doubt that you have
more experience with angry women.
Now, you see, that wasn't
very sensitive, was it?
The man has one serious relationship
and all of a sudden he's an expert.
All right, there is one
clear-cut undeniable reason
why I should be the one to talk to Abby.
She owes me a dollar. Now...
We ran down I. D.'s on the remains,
got a hit on the woman.
Classic DiNozzo.
One intact fingerprint
off her left hand
matches driver's license.
Marilyn Torrance, age
58 of Tyson's Corner.
There's no case file because
her nephew and his wife
never reported her missing.
They're on their way in.
That it?
McGee?
Is there Jethro right there?
Be right there, Ducky.
Saved by the bell.
They were dismembered
by severing tendons, muscles
from ligaments at every joint.
The neck, shoulder, elbow, wrist, hip,
knee, ankle,
et cetera.
There's very little damage
to the bones themselves,
except the rib cages, they were cut.
Probably using a bone saw.
Were they murdered?
One of them at least was.
Blunt-force trauma to the female skull.
A blow to the back of the head
that was certainly enough
to kill a woman of her age.
Fourth-rib-phase
analysis suggests
that she was in her 70s.
According to the DMV,
Marilyn Torrance was 58.
Women lie about their age.
But this is her hand.
Not her head.
Well, maybe that's her head.
That's a man's skull.
Well, maybe you reassembled
the pieces incorrectly.
The problem is we can't
reassemble the pieces.
We don't have two
full sets of remains.
We're missing pieces.
Yes, and these unrelated pieces, well,
they belong to at least
three different people.
Three more bodies?
We're missing a lot of pieces.
This is more than someone
just dumping two bodies.
I think you're looking
for a mass murderer.
Can't we talk about this?
There's no point...
What do you got, Abs?
Decaying flesh, organs and human tissue.
- The DNA confirms that...
- Five different people.
Well, if you already talked to Ducky,
there's not much I can tell you.
You didn't give me much
to work with, Gibbs.
There's barely any blood.
The bodies were probably drained.
So what, you think we're
looking for a vampire?
There are traces of cellulose, fiber,
common paper and string.
The parts were wrapped.
Yeah, but they're too degraded
to get any fingerprints off of.
There was one thing.
The screws from the marble frontispiece.
They've been collecting rust
since the interment in 1978.
But look at the heads.
They're scratched.
That's from the screwdriver.
it dislodged the rust.
But look at the other crypts.
See the screws?
Yeah. They're all rusted.
Except for these two crypts.
Anson Gage, USMC, Colonel;
Raymond Dalton, U. S. Army.
Might be vandalism, but
it might be something.
- DiNozzo.
- Contact next of kin
and get permission to open
those two crypts. On it, boss!
Nice catch, Abby.
Yeah.
I couldn't help but notice
how quiet it is in here.
- Where's the music?
- I just wasn't in the mood.
Anything...
you want to talk about?
Why would there be?
Yeah, I don't know,
it's just that McGee said
that you weren't really
acting like yourself,
- and so I thought...
- So you guys have been
talking about me?
Yeah. No.
We're wondering if there
was anything bothering you.
You want to know what bothers me?
It bothers me when people
gossip about other people
behind their backs.
Do you really think that that is okay?
Yeah. 'Cause...
I mean, it's the only way to gossip.
'Cause if we talked about you in front
of your face, then that would
just be talking about you.
You know what, we're just not gonna...
we're not gonna do that anymore.
Sorry.
Your aunt lived with you?
When she was in town, yes.
You're sure she was murdered?
Preliminary findings have been
inconclusive, Mr. Torrance,
but it's probable.
When was the last time you saw her?
It's been almost three months now.
And you never filed a
missing persons report?
Well, she does this.
She would meet a new man
with a yacht or a jet...
and disappear for a while.
We always expected she
would resurface eventually.
Just never like this.
Here.
I know how difficult it is to
lose a person you care about.
Thank you.
We'll also need a list
of anyone who has access to your home.
Contractors, workmen, employees.
And also the names of any
of her travel companions
- or associates.
- Of course.
Thank you for coming in so quickly.
If you learn anything...
Please call. As soon as we know more.
They were really cut up.
Sorry.
It's a poor choice of words.
How many more of these
are we going to do?
Uh, at least five.
So pace yourself.
What do you mean by that, McGee?
Nothing. Just, you know,
you got a little emotional in there.
I will meet you upstairs,
Miss Dalton, okay?
Okay.
Next of kin?
Abby thinks there might be more
body parts hidden in
her grandfather's crypt.
You talked to Abby?
- Yeah, McGee.
- I was right, wasn't I?
There's something wrong.
Let it go, probie.
- Why?
- Because I'm pretty sure
it's something you did.
Well, what did I do?
Well, think about it, probie.
I'm sure you'll come up with something.
I don't understand what I'm
supposed to be looking at.
These photos are of
your grandfather's tomb.
I get that.
I assure you this has nothing
to do with your grandfather.
How could it? He's been dead 13 years.
- I was at the funeral.
- Right.
It's been tampered with, okay?
And we believe that there's
evidence hidden inside
relating to an ongoing
murder investigation.
What kind of evidence?
I run my own business, Agent DiNozzo.
That means I'm losing
money every minute that
I have to spend here.
So why don't you just tell me
what it is that you want from me?
We need you to give us
permission to open it.
So if you could just sign...
these authorization forms.
My dad put me to work
right after my grandpa died.
You know the first
lesson that I learned?
What's that?
Don't sign any papers without
having a lawyer look at 'em.
That's a good lesson.
But if it's necessary,
we'll get a federal warrant.
Oh, that would be much easier for me.
You should just do that.
Okay.
Anything else you need?
Just a federal warrant.
Great.
Company, boss.
Special Agent Gibbs.
Colonel Mann.
I got a call your case might
be venturing into CID territory.
That call was premature.
Really? Here I thought
it was four weeks overdue.
I understand you were denied permission
by the family to access
Colonel Dalton's crypt.
Got a warrant.
And that got my attention.
Why don't you fill me in.
Wouldn't want to make a bad
situation worse, would you?
Don't look so nervous, Jethro.
- Do I look nervous?
- No.
You actually look, um...
you look pretty good.
David, DiNozzo, perimeter.
Sure you don't want us to
help you in there, boss?
'Course not, 'cause if
you did, you would've said,
"David, DiNozzo, follow me."
Probie, stop it.
We're not going anywhere.
Why? What'd I miss?
Not like you to leave
something unfinished.
The crime scene.
Ever worry you're slipping?
No.
Any suspects yet?
Nothing concrete.
What does your gut say?
Theory is it's an inside job.
But you don't like that.
So how else would he know
which crypts are vacant?
Ah, read the faceplates.
So the warrant didn't exactly specify
what we're looking for here.
Well, it's best to
not have expectations.
It staves off disappointment.
What are we hoping for?
You throw that "we" word
around pretty casually.
The last time someone tried to remove
one of these, it blew up in his face.
You might want to
step back a little bit.
Thank you for your concern.
I see what you mean.
Expectations.
Gibbs did not look happy to see her.
His body language suggested
he was not comfortable at all.
Eh, nothing makes Gibbs uncomfortable.
Nothing job-related.
You think he ended it with her?
Assuming that he started something.
I don't buy it.
- Why not?
- For one, she's not a redhead.
People do change, Tony.
It's true, even you have a girlfriend.
I haven't changed.
Really? What about the
pretty girl in the office.
- Natalie Dalton?
- Well, you noticed she was pretty,
but you didn't flirt with her.
That would've been unprofessional.
I don't know.
Might have gotten her to
sign the authorization.
Then we would not have need the warrant.
Then Colonel Mann
wouldn't have been here.
And we would be inside doing our job.
- Like professionals.
- All because
you don't flirt anymore. Why is that?
- Enough gossip, McGee.
- Tony, you like to talk about
everyone's private lives.
Talk, yes.
But I don't write entire
books about them, do I?
Does create a bit of a trust...
issue, McGee.
Excuse me. Hi.
Am I able to go inside today?
The mausoleum is closed, sir.
Here it is.
Are you gonna let me in?
I think we should be clear
on the implications first.
You're interfering
with my investigation.
- Is that what I'm doing?
- Honestly, I'm not sure.
If there's evidence in here,
I'm gonna be obligated to
see this through to the end.
- And if there's not?
- Then I don't see
why my involvement
shouldn't end right here.
If you wanted to see me,
you didn't have to manufacture a reason.
I follow the orders of
the United States Army,
even when they don't exactly make sense.
- You could've called.
- So could you.
I distinctly remember
the last thing you said
as you were slinking
out of my bedroom...
- I don't slink.
- "I'll call you."
For the record, I didn't
think the last time
we saw each other was gonna be
the last time we saw each other.
Neither did I.
Well, here we are.
Lucky for us.
Call it fate.
You're just gonna let fate decide
whether we go our separate ways?
Five bodies in total.
We've only recovered portions.
You're hoping the rest
- are in here.
- Aren't you?
Honestly, I'm not really sure.
That the answer you're looking for?
If the bodies recovered from
the mausoleum were, in fact,
the result of mass murder,
one might expect a certain modicum
of consistency in the manner of death.
One might.
Yes. And one would be wrong.
Shot, stabbed, strangled, bludgeoned,
and poor Miss Undetermined Torrance.
Three women, two men,
ages ranging from 19 to 70.
Three are Caucasian,
one Asian, and one black.
- No common traits.
- Not in life.
But the blood, however,
settled on different surfaces
on each of the bodies.
Her left thigh and back,
his chest and buttocks, meaning...
The bodies were moved repeatedly.
Precisely. They were
killed and then moved
for some sort of preparation.
You can see the
indentations on the ankles
here and here, here.
Chain-link.
Yes. I believe the bodies
were suspended and drained
prior to being, well,
there's only one word for it.
Butchered.
We sent the tissue samples
to Abby. Hopefully, she can...
Speak of the devil.
What we have here is
paradoxical behavior.
On one side, we have...
An emotional, unrestrained murderer
using whatever means at hand.
Yes. And, on the other,
someone tidy, meticulous,
and almost flawless
in the way he dissected these bodies.
That wasn't Abby.
That was the Director.
She wants to see you.
Both of you.
As far as we can tell,
the only thing that brought
these people together
is how they were taken apart.
In addition to Marilyn Torrance,
we have a 19-year-old runaway
from Florida. He was shot.
30-year-old
prostitute.
She was strangled.
No next of kin on either of them.
Wade Carlin, 26-year-old
Georgetown graduate
- from Michigan.
- He broke off contact with his parents
after his girlfriend
dumped him six months ago.
They thought he was Jack
Kerouac-ing around the country.
When, in fact, he was stabbed to death
a few weeks after the breakup.
All missing persons cases.
All have led to nowhere.
Until now.
Gloria Grady,
age 72. Ducky says she
was the first victim.
Blunt trauma.
Only one relative, her son,
Len Grady.
He was at James River.
With a bouquet of flowers.
Lilies. For who?
No record of any Grady at James River.
Could be under a different name.
Could be a friend.
But lilies. They're feminine.
The kind you give to a woman.
Like your mother.
Grady's mother. I
don't know your mother.
Could be visiting his trophies.
Fits the classic profile:
30s, single, white.
We should tell Gibbs.
Yeah? Why don't we
wait till he gets out?
Unlessyouwant to be the one
to interrupt his meeting.
Campfire's over.
Okay. Well, thank you, Colonel.
I will get her back to
you as soon as possible.
Your superiors have agreed
to loan us your
services for the interim.
I trust that there's
not a problem with that?
No. Of course not, Director.
As long as Special Agent Gibbs
continues to be forthcoming
with pertinent information.
Agent Gibbs?
As long as she follows my
lead, I can't foresee a problem.
You two have worked cases
together successfully in the past.
Nothing's changed
to interfere with that professional
relationship, has there?
What do we have so far?
Four confirmed homicides. Likely, five.
- That's all you know?
- I know we're wasting time
debating jurisdictional protocol
and discussing who's entitled to what.
Well, then, why don't
you get back to it?
Yeah. Thank you.
Not you,
Colonel Mann.
I'd like to have a
private word with you.
Breaking in a new pair?
No. I always wear these.
Why do I always wear these?
- Let me see your shoes.
- Okay.
Flat, sensible, functional.
Not very sexy, but..
- But they do the trick. - What
do I want three-inch platforms?
I'm already five-ten.
I love these shoes... just all wrong.
Wrong for who?
The tissue samples.
I don't follow.
You don't want to hear about shoes.
- You want to hearabout tissue samples.
- Sure.
I ran the Torrance tissues
through the mass spec,
and I found abnormal levels of chlorine.
- Chlorine?
- Yeah.
Like in a swimming pool.
Len Grady's Website.
He's a jack-of-all-trades.
Basically,
a guy with a big van.
And a little initiative.
Something of an amateur entrepreneur.
That's not easy to say.
Carpenter, plumber,
gardener, electrician,
TV installations,
- snow shoveling..
- But, most importantly,
pool cleaning.
That supposed to mean something?
Well, he's not just any pool man.
He's the Torrances' pool man.
Grady's got his own key.
Heated. Indoor. Regular monthly
maintenance. I looked into it.
Royalty checks burning a
hole in your pocket, McGee?
Already tied Grady to his mother.
Body number one.
- And now Torrance.
- Body number two.
Let's bring him in.
A lot of people
were pleased to see
Sharif off the streets.
My superiors acknowledged
your letter of commendation.
I want you to know I appreciate it.
The two make an effective team.
Gibbs and myself?
Well, it wasn't just a
flash in the pan, was it?
Your service at CID is up in six months.
You must have started considering life
after the military.
Yes. It has crossed my mind.
The question is how to
best serve your future.
Where the opportunity
for advancement lies.
It's not too early
for a cocktail, is it?
The sun must be down somewhere.
You drink bourbon?
No. Not regularly.
Spend enough time around
Gibbs, and you'll learn.
Believe me.
It's an acquired taste.
And when did you first acquire it?
It's been a while.
But it's something that
stays with you though.
Nobody's home, Boss.
Neighbor said he went
out about an hour ago.
What do we do?
We wait.
Okay.
Colonel Mann still in with the Director?
What do you think they're talking about?
We wait...
...silently.
Okay.
I got him.
Len Grady?
Freeze!
Federal agents.
Up, up, up!
What? What?
Bachelor living.
Not every bachelor.
This guy's got a card for everything.
"Len Grady, Painter."
"Len Grady, Fountain Design."
"Cottage cheese ceilings removed
and made smooth."
Anything with a blade on
it, we should get to Abby.
Not really what she wants.
She's upset about her shoes.
Doesn't sound like Abby.
Wrong pair of shoes can
reduce a woman to tears.
She was crying?
Practically.
It's not the shoes.
Got something.
Yep.
White paper package
tied with brown string.
What's that?
It's a pork chop.
- Hear you got our guy in there.
- Maybe.
- What?
- Nothing.
It seems like you were
thinking something.
That's been known to happen.
Something about me.
Thought I recognized your perfume.
I don't wear perfume.
Must have been something else.
So... can I just go ahead
and pay the fine and get out of here?
Fine?
I know I shouldn't have cashed
my mother's Social Security checks.
We're not the IRS.
She went missing last March.
She had dementia.
It was getting worse. She
must have gotten out one day.
We're talking about a
person here, not a dog.
I keep hoping she'll come back.
You already know where to find her.
How do I know that?
You went to visit her.
Brought her flowers.
My mother's at the cemetery?
What's left of her. She was dismembered.
Look at his mind spinning.
He's trying to figure
out how to play it.
I didn't do that.
I took care of my mother.
I fed her.
I cleaned up after her.
You must have been
praying for it to end.
I loved my mother!
Maybe you were right the first time.
It must have been like
putting down a dog.
Only no one ever noticed.
Getting away with it must have
been the real shocking part.
And a new career is born.
You did it again...
and again.
Kelly Camarda, Wade...
Something's not right.
What do you mean?
He looks relieved.
Gloria Grady.
Okay.
Stop.
You have something you want to tell us?
All these people were chopped up?
That's disgusting.
What kind of person do
you think could do that?
I mean, you're looking for a monster.
What do you want me to say?
It's not me.
What now?
Want me to do a lie-detector
test or something?
You just did.
He's telling the truth.
You think I'm wrong?
No. But he was relieved when
you connected her with
the rest of the bodies.
He has no feelings about them at all.
- Doesn't mean he wasn't involved.
- Maybe.
But that doesn't look like
a man who feels trapped.
That looks like a man who
knows he has a way out.
There's something much worse than
Len Grady out there.
Only he knows what it is.
We've got to push Grady harder
to tell us what he knows.
He won't.
You think he's protecting
the real killer?
He's protecting himself.
I can prove that he's not acting alone.
Trying to run down Grady's van.
No luck so far.
He was on foot when you apprehended him.
So what did he do with his ride?
And when did he do it?
After he spotted us at the cemetery.
What, he just happened to be visiting?
There's no such thing as a coincidence.
Well, he wanted information.
He was there to watch us.
But he got there as quickly as I did,
so how did he know
about the investigation?
He's got a friend on the inside.
One person's a psychopath,
two people's a conspiracy.
So who was he talking to?
Grady doesn't leave here
until we know everything about him.
You start with yesterday
and you work backwards.
Go.
Forensics?
- Boss...
- Yeah.
If you're going to go see Abby,
I think you should know she's
going through something...
I'm not going empty-handed, McGee.
Gibbs.
- And Lieutenant Colonel Mann.
- Abby.
Can I interest you in some knives?
I've got kitchen knives,
pen knives, pocket knives,
Swiss army knives, razor
blades, X-acto blades,
scissors, saws,
scalpels, hedge clippers,
an adze, an awl, a fish scaler
and even a golf-hole cutter.
All recovered from Grady's pigsty?
Reflected in the care he
used to maintain his cutlery,
there's dings and nicks and dull edges.
None of these correspond to
any of the precise incisions
used to dismember the corpses.
For such a slob,
he certainly is careful when it counts.
There wasn't a single trace
of human blood anywhere.
Human blood...
Your boy Grady is
something of a carnivore.
From the remnants on his silverware,
I could pretty much tell you
every meal he had for a week.
Liverwurst, knockwurst,
pastrami, roast beef, rack of lamb.
Which leads us to...
this.
The pork chop from his freezer.
Probably his next meal.
When I pull it up, it
gets really interesting.
It matches the incisions on the bodies.
Tool mark analysis isn't as precise
as say fingerprints or ballistics,
but I can conclusively tell
you that none of the blades
in Grady's possession carved that pig.
Well, why would they?
He probably had it carved.
His partner's a butcher.
Don't you have work to do?
Look, it's not something
that you can fix in the classic
Gibbs hit-and-run style, okay?
I got time, Abs.
It's stupid.
It's just...
... a guy.
I'm not going to start spilling my guts
just because you keep standing here.
All right, apparently
I am too much for him.
Can you imagine that?
Me?
And it's not what you think.
It's not all this.
He likes...
he likes small women.
I got dumped 'cause I'm too... too big.
And don't even bother
with the, "No, it's
him. He's too small."
or "If he can't accept
you for who you are
then it's his problem," thing.
He just doesn't think
that we could make it work
and I've done everything I can
to try to convince him that he's wrong.
So I guess. I'm just
going to have to accept it.
And let it go.
Thanks, Gibbs.
You always know what to say.
Metro P. D. responded to
the BOLO on Grady's van.
So far 13 possibles and counting.
McGee.
Supermarkets, slaughter houses,
any place with a butcher on site
within a 20-block radius
of Grady's residence.
Narrow the search to boutique shops.
They'd need their privacy.
There's just one.
Just one?
Boutique butcher's a dying industry.
- Where?
- Le Cochon, Mass Avenue.
All right, get a list of employees,
owners past and present.
Let's roll.
Ms. Dalton.
I thought you said you didn't need me.
What's your relationship with Len Grady?
Len, he's my boyfriend.
Why? What's going on?
You told Grady you
spoke with us earlier?
Yeah, I mentioned it.
Is this about the investigation?
Where is Len?
In custody.
We suspect he's committed
at least five murders.
That's impossible.
Len would never hurt any...
Five?
At least.
Where's your freezer?
Nothing in here, Boss.
Just pork, beef and lamb.
What else would there be?
Human blood.
Human?
What's in here?
It's a freezer I use
for overflow to store
geese and turkeys in the holidays.
Got a key?
What kind of evidence
did you say that you found
in my grandfather's crypt?
Does Grady has access to your store?
He's here all the time.
Look, this can't be happening, okay?
There must be some kind of...
He was a regular customer.
Every week like clockwork.
It was the only time that he
could get away from his mother.
He felt trapped.
I could tell that he needed
to get on with his life.
It started with a few
words here and there.
And then...
before long we were...
Together.
Not fully, no.
We didn't trade keys until...
after she disappeared.
He learned your trade.
I taught him.
He always wanted to try new things.
I never suspected that...
How could I not have seen it?
Love makes you blind.
I must be some kind of monster.
Is she the monster
you were talking about?
No,
she loves me.
How?
We're in love.
Then she had to know about it.
She had to know the real you.
She didn't do anything.
You're right.
She could have stopped you.
She should have stopped you.
If it was real.
She didn't know!
I hid it. I hid everything.
Just leave her out of it.
Natalie!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry, Natalie!
I'm so sorry!
I love you! I love you so much!
I'm sorry!
Let's try this again. Marilyn Torrance.
She was swimming in
her pool. I drowned her.
Wade Carlin.
Natalie was at the wholesale market.
He came in for a
sandwich. I stabbed him.
She was a hooker.
I was lonely. Natalie was out of town.
I strangled her.
And the kid was nobody.
Nobody. I just shot him.
You kept them in the
freezer for over a year.
Why'd you move the bodies?
Why did you move them?
He needed the space.
No one could stop me.
You were gonna kill again.
He already did.
What did you do with the body?
Doesn't matter.
No, no... No. No!
No! Natalie!
Find the van. Find the body.
Let her go.
Still at work?
Yeah, I was just catching
up on some things.
Cheek swabs.
Hey, your music's back on.
You're feeling good again.
Maybe not good.
Not yet. But better.
You know how sometimes a guy
can get you all tied up inside.
Yes.
And then you can't get the knots out?
Well, it just really helped me
to talk things out with Gibbs.
You know, unknot the knots.
'Cause even if you don't let it show,
people can still tell.
So, you know, if you ever want
to talk about Lieutenant Sanders...
I liked him.
He died. And,
what else is there to say?
Well,
I am glad you feel better.
With the right partner,
you can make the perfect, monster?
Oh yeah,
give me a little old-time romance.
Someone's got hidden
skeletons of his own.
You know, if I ever find
myself in a dire situation,
the proverbial body
I need to get rid of...
I think I would tell you.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
What makes you think
I wouldn't turn you in?
If there's one thing
you're good at, Jethro,
it's keeping your mouth shut.
You made the right call
letting the girl go.
Seems you always make the
call when it involves a case.
Oh, son of a...