God, you guys are so smart.
It's like a brain factory in here.
-I got some ideas too this morning.
-He got really, really good ones.
You know, in a Donald sort of way.
I'm putting--
Hey! What?
I'm putting in a chase sequence.
So the killer...
...flees on horseback with the girl.
The cop's after them on a motorcycle.
And it's like a battle between
motors and horses.
Like technology versus horse.
And they're still all one person, right?
Well, that's the big payoff.
-lt sounds exciting.
-Thanks, man.
-Thanks.
-See, I told you he was gonna like it.
-You're my muse. You are.
-I love being your muse.
I'm so happy about that.
I'm picking up an order for Kaufman.
-Valerie.
-Hi, Charlie.
It's quite a coincidence
bumping into you.
I'm sorry I didn't call you back.
I was away last week.
-That's okay.
-I meant to because...
...things are going really well now,
and I wanted you to know.
Well, that's great.
I'm anxious to see something.
You should sit down because
I'm here with Susan right now.
And she's dying to meet you,
so it's funny bumping into you.
-Have a seat.
-Susan Orlean is here?
Yeah, she's here in town for a reading
or something. She's just on the phone.
Sit down. Have a seat.
She's dying to meet you.
Well, I should probably go, because....
Well, I'd love to meet her too...
...but I don't want to be beholden.
And, well--
Because once you meet somebody
that you've been writing about...
...it becomes very hard to separate.
So....
Well, okay, I'll speak to you soon.
And I'm almost done.
I'm almost done.
And tell Susan that I would
love to meet with her at a future date.
-As she sees fit.
-Okay.
Who am I kidding?
This is not Susan Orlean's story.
I have no connection with her.
I can't even meet her.
I have no understanding of anything
but my own panic and self-loathing...
...and pathetic, little existence.
The only thing I'm actually qualified to
write about is myself and my own self--
We open on Charlie Kaufman.
Fat, old, bald, repulsive, sitting in
a Hollywood restaurant...
...across from Valerie Thomas,
a lovely, statuesque film executive.
Kaufman, trying to get
a writing assignment...
...wanting to impress her,
sweats profusely.
Fat, bald Kaufman paces furiously
in his bedroom.
He speaks into his hand-held
tape recorder, and he says:
"Charlie Kaufman, fat, bald,
repulsive, old...
...sits at a Hollywood restaurant
with Valerie Thomas."
Kaufman, repugnant, ridiculous...
...jerks off to the book jacket photo
of Susan Or--
What do you want?
I've finished my script.
I'm done.
So would you show it to your agent?
It's called The Three.
Thanks. I also want to
thank you for your idea.
It was very helpful.
I changed it a little.
Now the killer cuts off body pieces
and makes his victims eat them.
Caroline has this great tattoo of a snake
swallowing its own tail, and--
-Ourobouros.
-I don't know what that means.
The snake. It's called Ourobouros.
I don't think so. But it's cool for my
killer to have this modus operandi...
...because when he forces the woman
who's really him to eat herself...
...he's also eating himself to death.
I'm insane.
-I'm Ourobouros.
-I don't know what that word means.
-I've written myself into my screenplay.
-That's kind of weird, huh?
It's self-indulgent. It's narcissistic.
It's solipsistic. It's pathetic.
I'm pathetic.
I'm fat and pathetic.
I'm sure you had good reasons, Charles.
You're an artist.
It's because I'm too timid to speak to
the woman who wrote the book.
Because I'm pathetic.
Because I have no idea how to write.
Because I can't make flowers fascinating.
Because I suck.
-Hey, am I in the script?
-I'm going to New York.
I'll meet her. That's it.
That's what I have to do.
Don't get mad at me for saying this...
...but Bob's having a seminar
in New York this weekend.
So if you're stuck....
And she said,
"Laroche is such a fun character."
No shit, I'm a fun character.
Who's gonna play me?
Well, I've gotta write
the book first, John.
Then, you know, they get somebody
to write the screenplay.
Hey, I think I should play me.
Most people yearn for something
exceptional, something so inspiring...
...that they'd want to risk everything
for that passion, but few would act on it.
It was very powerful...
...and it's intoxicating to be
around someone so alive.
Come on, just follow me.
They're right nearby.
Okay.
Can I ask you a personal question?
Look, we're not lost.
I've done this a million times.
When everything is killing me, I just say,
"Screw it," and go straight ahead.
Oh, fuck....
Sundial.
I'll just set this up,
we'll wait a few minutes...
...and then we'll be able to tell
which way the sun's moving.
We should be headed southeast.
So, you collect anything?
Not really, no.
Yeah, well, you know...
...it's not really about
collecting the thing.
It's about being able....
The thing about computers,
the thing I like...
...is that I'm immersed in them...
...but it's not like a living thing
that's gonna leave or die or something.
-John, I'm sorry. I just--
-Okay.
-I don't--
-Hey. Okay.
Fuck the sundial.
I know how to get out of here.
I know this swamp like
the back of my goddamn hand.
You're just like everybody else.
Fucking leeches.
You just attach yourself to me
and suck me dry, spit me out.
Why don't you get your own fucking life?
Your own fucking interests?
Fucking spoiled bitch.
Life seemed to be filled with things
that were just like the ghost orchid.
Wonderful to imagine
and easy to fall in love with...
...but a little fantastic...
...and fleeting...
...and out of reach.
"--but a little fantastic
and fleeting and out of reach."
Hello?
Hey, it's Marty. How's it going?
Has it been helpful talking to the writer?
What's her name?
Susan Orlean. It's been okay.
Well, I mean, are you making headway?
Valerie's breathing down my neck.
-You can't rush inspiration.
-Okay. All right. Fair enough.
Listen, the other reason
I called was The Three.
It's just amazing.
-I don't know what that is.
-Donald's script.
A smart, edgy thriller.
It's the best script I've read all year.
-Good.
-Yeah, I'm gonna sell it for a shitload.
Two fucking talented guys in one family.
In fact, maybe you could get your
brother to help you with the orchid thing.
-Marty, don't say that. I mean--
-All right. It's just a thought, buddy.
I mean, he's really
goddamn amazing at structure.
-I have to go.
-All right. Adios, amigo.
Finish that--
Fuck!
Okay, thank you, thank you.
We have a long three days ahead.
Years from now, you'll be at a posh
cocktail party congratulating yourself...
...on how you spent a weekend with
an asshole from Hollywood for your art.
-I am pathetic. I am a loser.
-So...
...what is the substance of writing?
I have failed. I am panicked.
I have sold out. I am worthless.
I-- What the fuck am I doing here?
What the fuck am I doing here? Fuck!
It is my weakness, my ultimate lack
of conviction that brings me here.
Easy answers,
rules to shortcut yourself to success.
And here I am because my jaunt
into the abyss brought me nothing.
Well, isn't that just the risk one takes
for attempting something new?
I should leave right now. I'll start over.
I need to face this project head-on--
And God help you if you use
voice-over in your work, my friends.
God help you.
It's flaccid, sloppy writing.
Any idiot can write voice-over narration
to explain the thoughts of the character.
Okay, that's it.
One hour for lunch.
You cannot have a protagonist
without desire.
It doesn't make any sense.
Any fucking sense.
You follow? Good.
Anyone else?
What if a writer is attempting to create
a story where nothing much happens?
Where people don't change,
they don't have any epiphanies.
They struggle and are frustrated,
and nothing is resolved.
More a reflection of the real world.
The real world?
Yes, sir.
The real fucking world.
First of all, you write a screenplay
without conflict or crisis...
...you'll bore your audience to tears.
Secondly, nothing happens in the world?
Are you out of your fucking mind?
People are murdered every day.
There's genocide, war, corruption.
Every fucking day,
somewhere in the world...
...somebody sacrifices his life
to save somebody else.
Every fucking day, someone somewhere
takes a conscious decision...
...to destroy someone else.
People find love. People lose it.
Christ, a child watches a mother
beaten to death on the steps of a church.
Someone goes hungry.
Somebody else betrays
his best friend for a woman.
If you can't find that stuff in life...
...then you, my friend,
don't know crap about life!
And why the fuck are you wasting
my two precious hours with your movie?
I don't have any use for it!
I don't have any bloody use for it!
Okay, thanks.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
No. Thank you.
Thank you so much, Mr. McKee.
This course makes you look at writing
in a whole different way.
-Mr. McKee.
-Yes?
I'm the guy you yelled at this morning.
I need more.
I'm the one who thought
things didn't happen in life.
Right. Okay.
-Nice to see you.
-I need to talk.
Mr. McKee, my even
standing here is very scary.
I don't meet people well.
But what you said this morning
shook me to the bone.
What you said was bigger than
my screenwriting choices.
It was about my choices
as a human being. Please.
Yeah.
Well, you know...
...I could sure use a drink, my friend.
"--but a little fantastic
and fleeting and out of reach."
Then what happens?
Well, that's the end of the book.
I wanted to present it simply...
...without big character arcs
or sensationalizing the story.
I wanted to show flowers
as God's miracles.
I wanted to show that Orlean
never saw the blooming ghost orchid.
It was about disappointment.
I see.
That's not a movie.
You gotta go back, put in the drama.
I can't go back. I've got pages of
false starts and wrong approaches.
-I'm way past my deadline.
-I'll tell you a secret.
A last act makes a film.
Wow them in the end,
and you got a hit.
You can have flaws, problems,
but wow them in the end...
...and you've got a hit.
Find an ending.
But don't cheat.
And don't you dare bring in
a deus ex machina.
Your characters must change...
...and the change must come from them.
Do that and you'll be fine.
You promise?
Mr. McKee.
-Have you taken my course before?
-My brother did.
My twin brother, Donald.
He's the one who got me to come.
-Twin screenwriters?
-Yeah.
Well, Julius and Philip Epstein...
...who wrote Casablanca...
-...they were twins
-You mentioned that in class.
Finest screenplay ever written.
Great writers' residence.
-Donald.
-Hey, how's your trip going?
You getting it on with that
lady journalist, you dog you?
Yeah.
Listen, I'm just calling to say
congratulations on your script.
Isn't that cool? Marty says he can
get me high-sixes against a mil-five.
That's great, Donald.
I want to thank you for all your help.
I wasn't any help.
Come on,
you let me stay in your place.
And your integrity
inspired me to even try.
It's been a wild ride.
Catherine says
she wants to play Cassie.
Oh, please!
Please, Donald?
Catherine Keener?
-Catherine Keener's in my house?
-Yeah, we're playing Boggle.
She's so great. You should really
hang out with her, Charles.
Yeah. Look....
I've been thinking.
Maybe you'd be interested in hanging
out with me for a few days in New York.
Oh, my God, yes.
Yeah?
I was gonna show my script
to some people...
...and, well, maybe you could
read it too, you know, if you like.
Of course. I'd be flattered.
Okay.
Thanks, Charles.
Okay, bye.
So, like, what would you do?
The script kind of makes fun of me, huh?
-I'm sorry. I was trying something--
-Hey, I don't mind. It's funny.
Good. Okay.
So, what would you do?
You and me are so different, Charles.
We're different talents.
I know. Just for fun...
...how would the great Donald
end this script?
Shut up. "The great Donald."
I feel like you're missing something.
-All right. Like what?
-Look.
I did a little research on the airplane.
"Sometimes this kind of story turns out
to be something more...
...some glimpse of life that expands...
...Iike those Japanese paper balls
you drop in water...
...and they bloom into flowers
and the flower is so marvelous...
...you can't believe there was a time
all you saw in front of you...
...was a paper ball and a glass of water."
Well, first of all, that's inconsistent.
She said she didn't care about flowers.
-For God's sake, it's just a metaphor.
-Well, but for what?
What turned that paper ball into
a flower? It's not in the book, Charles.
-I don't know. You're reaching.
-Maybe.
But I think you actually need to speak
to this woman. To know her.
I can't.
-Really.
-I'll go.
I'll pretend I'm you.
I want to do it, Charles.
We'll get to the bottom of this.
We're gonna fix your movie, bro.
But you've gotta be exactly me.
I have a reputation to maintain.
You can't be a goofball.
You can't be an asshole.
-I'm not an asshole.
-You know what I mean.
No flirting. No bad jokes.
Don't laugh how you laugh.
I'm not gonna laugh.
I get to have people think I'm you.
It's an honor.
So I guess I'll bring out
the big guns now.
Do you keep in touch with Laroche?
I felt I detected an attraction to him
in the subtext. Care to comment?
Well, our relationship
was strictly reporter-subject.
I mean, certainly an intimacy does
evolve in this kind of relationship.
By definition, I was so interested
in everything he had to say.
But the relationship ends
when the book ends.
-Mendacious deceit.
-What?
Nothing.
I just have one more question.
If you could have dinner with one
historical personage, living or dead...
...who would it be?
Well, I would have to say...
...Einstein.
Or Jesus.
Very good.
Interesting answer.
-She's lying.
-What do you mean?
-What happened?
-Nothing. She said everything right.
-Too right.
-Well, maybe because they're true.
Did you embarrass me?
People who answer questions
too right are liars.
And everybody says Jesus and Einstein.
That's a prepackaged answer.
-"Jesus and Einstein"?
-Listen, Charles, I have an idea.
You'll need to buy me
a pair of binoculars.
What's "Jesus and Einstein"?
Come on.
Sing with me.
What the hell
do you need binoculars for?
Let's go, let's go.
She hung up the phone.
She's upset.
Stop watching her.
Leave her alone.
She's crying.
She's at her computer.
This is morally reprehensible.
United...
...to Miami.
Eleven...
...fifty-five a.m. tomorrow.
-I thought she was done with Laroche.
-Her parents live in Florida.
That was no parent phone call,
my friend.
Don't say "my friend."
A guy entering.
Handsome.
Must be her husband.
She's acting weird
with him, though, right?
Don't you think?
What's she hiding from him?
Maybe she's a lesbian
and doesn't know how to tell him.
What do you think?
Have you checked out
Laroche's porn site?
No. I'm trying to read.
Anyway, I'm gonna look
at the porn site.
Research.
-Don't tell my old lady.
-You mean Mom?
No, I don't mean Mom.
I still say we should go
to Miami tomorrow.
Forget it.
Some of these chicks look okay.
Hey, guess what.
We're going to Miami tomorrow.
-I said, no.
-I said, oh, yeah, baby. Come here.
What I came to understand
is that change is not a choice.
Not for a species of plant,
and not for me.
It happens, and you are different.
Maybe the only distinction
between the plant and me...
...is that afterward,
I lied about my change.
I lied in my book.
I pretended with my husband...
...that everything was the same.
But something happened
in the swamp that day.
Hey, look.
I told you I'd find
the jewel of the Fakahatchee.
It's a flower.
Just a flower.
Well, might as well grab it.
Long as I'm here.
Oh, man.
Boy, my porn site's gonna be big.
Look, something I didn't tell you...
...that I want to tell you about the ghost.
Okay?
I think it might help you.
I'd just started at the nursery.
And I went back one night
to pick up something.
They wanted the ghost
just to extract the drug.
It had been a ceremonial thing...
...but the young guys, you know,
they liked to get stoned.
So Matthew...?
-He was one of the guys who--?
-Sure.
Matthew lived on that shit
till they ran out.
Because there was this one day
he was fascinated by me.
By my hair and my sadness.
Yeah, well, it does that.
That's what I wanted to tell you.
I mean, I think you'd like it, Susie.
It seems to help people be fascinated.
You know, I can extract it for you.
I know how. I watched.
I'm probably the only white guy
who knows.
I want to do this, Susie.
I'm done with orchids, Laroche.
-Hello?
-Hi.
It's John.
Did you get my package?
John?
John!
Johnny.
-Hey, John?
-Yeah?
Very happy now.
Well, I'm glad.
Very happy.
Will you go like this--?
No. Keep going.
No. No.
I'm trying to make a dial tone.
And you have to sustain.
And then I will join you, and together--
-See, I can't do it by myself.
-Which one do you want me to do?
-Yes. Yes. Yes.
-Okay. Here we go.
-That's it.
-We got it.
We got it. That's fucking amazing.
Do you ever get
lonely sometimes, Johnny?
Well, I was a weird kid.
Nobody liked me.
But I had this idea...
...if I waited long
enough, someone would...
...come around and just...
...you know, understand me.
Like my mom.
Except someone else.
She'd look at me and quietly say:
"Yes. "
Just like that.
And I wouldn't be alone anymore.
I wish I were an ant.
They're so shiny.
You're shinier than any ant, darling.
That's the sweetest thing
anybody has ever said to me.
Well...
...I like you, that's why.
Hey.
I don't have time for that.
I'll get a closer look. You wait here.
No, wait!
I should go.
I mean, it should be me, right?
I mean...
...it's my....
-I was, you know--
-Go for it, bro.
You're the man.
Rip them.
Just rip them.
Darling, I don't know
what's come over you.
You came all over me last time
I was here, as I recall.
Goddamn!
Hey! Fuck.
Get in here!
Shut the fuck up, now!
Sit the fuck down!
-Who is that, Johnny?
-Who the fuck are you?
I just--
Nobody.
-I just-- I'm just--
-Wait a minute, wait a minute.
He's that screenwriter.
-The guy that's adapting our book?
-Yeah.
Well, that's wild.
It's nice to meet you.
Hey, dude...
-...who's gonna play me?
-I don't know that. I should--
Well, I thought I should play me.
Why--?
-Did he follow me?
-No, of course not. I should go.
Yeah, yeah. I mean,
it was nice to meet you...
...but let me give you my number.
I'm really freaking here, Johnny.
Why is he here?
Why did he follow me?
-What does he know?
-I don't know anything about anything.
-He did see the greenhouse.
-Oh, shit.
Oh, shit.
Are you gonna write about this
in your screenplay?
I really don't know what "this" is.
He's lying.
-Hold him.
-Stay! Just--
We have to kill him.
-What?
-What are we supposed to do?
-What can we do?
-Sit the fuck down!
Susie...
...you gotta calm down.
Now, you're getting a little emotional.
-You don't know--
-I can't have him writing about me.
I can't have the whole world,
all the people knowing about us...
...and about this.
Why?
-You ashamed of me, Susie?
-No, that's not it.
-No. How can you even think of that?
-Well--
I'm a professional journalist,
and the drugs and--
We can't kill anyone.
Okay. Okay.
Then I'll do it.
By myself.
-Susan--
-Hey! Come on. Fucking get down!
-I wouldn't tell any--
-Put him in his fucking car!
Turn it off. Just get out.
Run! Run! Go!
Susan! What the fuck was that?
-I don't know. I couldn't see.
-Shit. Fuck!
Come on! Help me find the flashlight.
So it was a guy?
Yeah. Fat.
That's all I could tell.
This is ridiculous.
We're gonna have to split up.
I can't. I can't be by myself out here.
I'm not gonna do that.
-They're gonna find us.
-I don't think so.
I don't want to die, Donald.
I've wasted my life. God, I've wasted it.
-You did not. And you're not gonna die.
-I wasted it.
I admire you, Donald, you know?
I spent my whole life paralyzed,
worrying about what people think of me...
-...and you, you're just oblivious.
-I'm not oblivious.
No, you don't understand.
I mean that as a compliment.
There was this time in high school.
I was watching you out
the library window...
-...you were talking to Sarah Marsh.
-Oh, God, I was so in love with her.
I know. And you were flirting with her,
and she was being really sweet to you.
-I remember that.
-And then, when you walked away...
...she started making fun of you
with Kim Canetti.
And it was like
they were laughing at me.
You didn't know at all?
-You seemed so happy.
-I knew. I heard them.
Well, how come you were so happy?
I loved Sarah, Charles.
It was mine, that love.
I owned it.
Even Sarah didn't have
the right to take it away.
I can love whoever I want.
But she thought you were pathetic.
That was her business, not mine.
You are what you love,
not what loves you.
That's what I decided a long time ago.
What's up?
Thank you.
For what?
No, shh!
Listen. I hear them.
I hear them. I hear them breathing.
Charlie?
-Charlie?
-Charlie!
-Guys?
Charlie!
Where's the van?
-Are they gone?
-I don't know. Maybe.
John? John!
Shit!
I can't believe I got shot.
Isn't that fucked up?
Shut up. Stop laughing.
Donald? You're gonna be okay.
It's gonna be okay, Donald.
Just don't go to sleep. Just don't
go to sleep, Donald. Look at me.
Look at me, Donald.
Keep looking at me.
Open your eyes.
Donald, please open your eyes.
Donald. Donald, please
open your eyes, Donald.
Donald! Donald, open your eyes!
Look at me.
Help!
John!
Halt!
I'm sorry.
Now I have to do this too.
I'm not a killer.
You put yourself in--
Johnny!
-Help!
-No, no!
Johnny! Johnny! John!
Oh, no, no, no.
Oh, God. You fat piece of shit!
-He's dead, you loser!
-Shut up!
-You ruined my life, you fat fuck!
-Shut up! Shut up!
Fuck you, lady! You're just a lonely,
old, desperate, pathetic drug addict!
Oh, my God.
It's over. Everything's over.
I did everything wrong.
I want my life back.
I want it back before it all got fucked up.
I want to be a baby again.
I want to be new.
Hello?
-Hello?
-Mom.
Charles? Charles, is that you?
Charles, what's the matter? You okay?
Donald says,
"That was her business, not mine.
You are what you love,
not what loves you.
I decided that a long time ago. "
Kaufman starts to cry.
He tries to thank his brother,
but he can't put it into words.
-So how you getting on?
-I'm okay.
I miss him, you know?
-How's the script coming?
-It's good. I'm almost finished.
I'll be really glad to move on
to something else.
I'll bet.
Things okay with you?
And then in January, David and I went
to Prague. That was a high point.
-That sounds great.
-There's amazing puppet theater there.
Yeah, I've heard. I've gotta see that.
And there's this church decorated
with, like, human skulls and bones.
Forty thousand skulls and bones.
I thought about you when I went there.
Charlie, I'm with someone.
Why are you doing this now?
I love you.
I should go. I have to....
Stuff I have to do.
I'm going away this weekend....
-Million things, okay?
-Yeah.
I love you too, you know.
I have to go right home.
I know how to finish the script now.
It ends with Kaufman driving home
after his lunch with Amelia...
...thinking he knows
how to finish the script.
Shit, that's voice-over.
McKee would not approve.
How else can I show his thoughts?
I don't know.
Well, who cares what McKee says?
It feels right.
Conclusive.
I wonder who's gonna play me.
Someone not too fat.
I like that Gerard Depardieu,
but can he not do the accent?
Anyway, it's done.
And that's something.
So: "Kaufman drives off from
his encounter with Amelia...
...filled for the first time with hope. "
I like this.
This is good.