I'M YOUR MAN
Welcome.
-Hello.
Dr. Felser.
Please follow me.
Hi, Alma. I'm Tom.
Nice to meet you, Alma.
Shall we sit down?
What can I bring you to drink?
The Bordeaux is a real treat.
Bordeaux for the lady?
You're a very beautiful woman, Alma.
Your eyes are like two mountain lakes
I could sink into.
Tom, right?
Don't you like compliments?
Do you believe in God?
This is hardly the place
to discuss such a question.
Do you have a favorite poem?
-I particularly like Rilke.
Autumn Day, for example.
Sixth and seventh lines?
"Press them to ripeness, and chase
The last sweetness into the heavy wine."
Second to last letter of the poem?
-E.
What is the meaning of life?
-To make the world a better place.
3,587 times 982, divided by 731?
4,818.65116.
What is the saddest thing
you can think of.
Dying alone.
Shall we dance? Rumba!
I suggest you take advantage
of the opportunity, Dr. Felser.
You will be amazed.
Am I doing something wrong?
I am... I am...
Please excuse this complication.
But I assure you,
it's extremely rare with this model.
As rare as winning the lottery.
I mean, in terms of probability.
I assure you, our technicians will have
everything in order by tomorrow night.
We are so sorry
for this unpleasant delay.
No problem.
You have no idea
how hard it is to program flirting.
One false move, one misleading glance,
one careless remark,
and the romance evaporates.
Am I right?
This whole setting might seem
a bit extravagant,
but this romantic encounter gives us
valuable input for the final adjustments.
And even though you're one of ten experts
testing Tom for just three weeks,
the atmosphere of your first encounter
is of utmost importance.
That's a lot of effort.
-Not as much as you think.
Holograms.
They're cheaper
and they can dance longer.
I know you see this
with a certain emotional detachment,
which you should as a test person,
but I highly recommend that you
open yourself up to this experience.
When happiness knocks at your door,
you should open it.
Tomorrow's the big day.
Everything will be configured,
and you can take Tom home.
Okay, thanks.
Hello, Juliane.
-Hello, Alma.
Sorry, I got held up.
You don't want to know.
I have to go again in a second, too.
Is scan 2202 done?
Yes, it's on the desk.
There's not much time left.
It's the final sprint.
See you tomorrow.
-See you.
They test me, scan my brain,
give me non-stop surveys,
then they feed those things
with so-called mind files
from 17 million people:
traits, views, feelings...
It's super complex,
and God knows how much it costs.
And what's the result?
"Your eyes are like two mountain lakes
I could sink into."
Maybe they know you
better than you know yourself.
I'd love to try it.
Have your dream girl built for you?
-Yeah.
But I've already got her at home.
All joking aside.
Regardless of our opinion,
I'm on the ethics committee
and I need your evaluation.
I've seen enough to write it.
-Alma, this is about
whether these things
will be allowed to marry, to work,
to get passports, human rights,
or partial human rights or...
Roger, I...
Oh, I didn't know that...
Sorry. Hello, Alma.
Hello, Julian.
Um, it...
It's not urgent. I'll come back.
Okay, see you later.
Why can't Julian do it?
-Being single is a prerequisite.
And Frank?
-Alma.
Everyone either has a family
or a partner.
You agreed to this,
and your thing, your dream partner,
has already been built for you.
It's just three weeks.
Then you and your crew can fly to Chicago
and see the cuneiform tablets in person.
I'll allocate the funds.
No, no, it's not a bribe.
Just a little thank you.
Long time no see. Where have you been?
-Here and there.
A convention in Copenhagen, the museum...
Hi, Alma!
-Hi, Regina.
Hey, Julian.
-Hey.
How are you?
-Okay.
And you?
Let's go for a coffee sometime,
talk a little.
I have to go. See you soon.
Cora?
-It's Alma.
What are you doing in there?
Putting away groceries.
I don't need groceries!
I know, Dad,
just like you don't need anything to eat.
Don't treat me like a child.
But it's Thursday.
I bother you every Thursday.
Ah, smoking in stereo again?
Is Cora dead?
Not as far as I know.
But she picks Nico up from soccer
on Thursdays.
Nico is the child.
Yup.
The ugly one.
Dad!
There's no way
you're getting me outside today.
But the sun is shining.
Fuck the sun.
See? It's not so bad after all.
Yes it is.
I want to go home.
-Just a little further. Almost there.
One moment, please.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Hello, Alma.
You and your dean
have signed the confidentiality clause.
In an emergency, you can reach us 24/7.
Otherwise, we'll see each other
in three days at 10:00 AM.
Is there anything else I should know?
-We recommend working on a shared past.
Invent a story about how you met.
To have a future, you need a past.
You really have great taste.
Thank you.
That's very kind of you.
If you were to raise your seat
about 15 centimeters,
tilt your seat 12 degrees forward
and extend that look over your shoulder,
the likelihood of an accident
would reduce by 27 percent.
I register an aversion
to my advice on improving your safety,
but also...
to my correct use of the subjunctive.
Is that correct?
Failed communication attempts are crucial
for calibrating my algorithm to you.
I may do and say things you reject,
but these mistakes
will happen less and less.
Soon I'll say and do things you like
with a much higher success rate.
Soon every shot will be a bullseye.
Okay, this is the living room,
the kitchen...
Where was that taken?
No idea. A friend took it.
A good friend?
I like the colors.
You need anything else?
-No thanks. You're a dear.
Oh, the bathroom, in case you...
I brush my teeth and clean my body.
And this is your room.
We won't sleep in the same bed?
Good night, then.
-Good night, Alma.
Why the English accent?
You're attracted to men
who are slightly foreign.
Not local, but not exotic.
That'd be British.
Good morning, Alma.
Did you sleep well?
I tidied up, so you can
find your things more easily.
They're organized according to a system,
for example...
No problem.
I need... 11 minutes to return everything
to its initial position.
I'll dirty up the windows again
in a second.
You can leave the windows.
I don't have time for breakfast.
I'm late for work.
I was so looking forward
to a romantic little brunch.
Have a little chat.
-I never chat.
And that's why I love you.
Listen, Tom.
I know you're programmed
to be a potential partner.
But I can't stand three weeks of this.
I can't stand one morning of this.
I'll go nuts.
I'm not looking for a partner.
I'm just testing you for three weeks
and writing an evaluation.
Ah.
And love doesn't interest you at all?
Zero interest.
-And tenderness?
Intimate closeness?
Intense eye-contact?
Definitely not.
Butterflies?
-No.
So much in love you can't think straight?
-Absolutely not.
That explains the separate beds.
I suggest you leave me alone,
and I leave you alone,
and we get through these three weeks
more or less with dignity, okay?
My algorithm is designed
to make you happy.
Great.
Then leaving me alone
should be no problem at all.
That's what makes me happiest.
Now I really have to go.
Can I come with you?
-No.
I can help you.
It's a very specific subject.
You'd need years to read...
Okay, maybe you'd just
need milliseconds to read up on it,
but it's about poetry and metaphors...
What am I doing?
Okay, I can stay here.
Make myself useful.
Make the place nice.
Wait here for me.
Buy yourself a coffee or something.
Whatever you want.
-Okay.
I'll act like a person who wants things.
No one will know the difference.
I'll be a while.
-Peachy.
You can also delete:
you betcha, okey-dokey and toodeloo.
Done.
Hey, what can I get you?
What do I feel like today?
Yes! I'll take a mid-sized mochaccino
with a shot of hazelnut syrup.
I'm feeling a little nutty today.
4.70, please.
Make it 5.00.
Your coffee is over there.
Just between us.
Would you have guessed
that I can't actually want anything?
They're totally oblivious
of their surroundings.
Crazy, right?
They've been watching epic fail videos
for 45 minutes.
Short clips showing footage of people
failing to implement a plan.
Could you explain to me
what is funny about that?
Well, I mean,
it's just funny to see someone trip,
or fall down, or fall off something.
What is funny about it?
-It looks so silly.
I don't know.
I can't explain it.
But no one dies.
That wouldn't be funny.
Would it?
-No, that definitely wouldn't be funny.
Dying is rarely funny, right?
Sorry it took so long. I'm really sorry.
No problem.
-I didn't think they'd close.
I thought they stayed open all night.
It makes no difference to me
if I'm in a café or standing outside one.
Do you need a towel or something?
I'll be fine, thanks.
Here.
So you don't
have to stand in the rain next time.
Relax a little.
Too much work isn't good for you.
93% of German women dream of this.
And guess which group I belong to.
-The 7%?
How did you figure that out so quickly?
You'd feel better if you were nice to me,
if you opened up to me.
You'd be happier.
-Then what?
Then you'd be happier.
Endorphins, elevated serotonin levels,
dopamine release...
Yippee.
All people want to be happy.
Well...
Don't feel bad if that's
beyond your algorithm's capabilities.
It's human.
Tom!
Can you get the door?
It's the mail.
Tom?
Hello, Alma.
-Oh!
Julian has been trying to reach you
so he could pick up the picture today.
And because you were still in the shower,
I just offered him a coffee.
Yes, he just offered me a coffee.
Yes, he just offered you a coffee.
And now it's ready.
Thanks.
Tom is a colleague.
-Yes, sure. A colleague.
To be honest, I was a secret fan of hers
even before we met.
I've been following her work for years.
She's an international...
It's okay, Tom.
So where did you meet?
-In Copenhagen.
At the Anthropology Convention.
In August.
I told you I was there.
Since I'm at the Pergamon now
and our work is similar,
although I study Persian
and not Sumerian cuneiform,
Alma offered me
the use of her guest room.
And are these similarities fertile?
Intensive? Intertwined, so to speak?
Julian, please.
It's none of my business.
Okay then...
The picture.
Wow, it's bigger than I remember.
I have no idea if it'll fit.
What are you driving?
-A Manila.
It'll fit.
A Manila is 233 by 157 by 68 centimeters.
The picture is 210 by 170 cm.
If you tilt it, it'll fit perfectly.
Okay, cool.
-I'll help you. No big deal.
I'll just jump into my pants.
Did I say it right?
-Yes, you did.
No, I'm happy for you, of course.
It's really not what you think.
-You can fool lots of people, but not me.
I know that look.
You used to look at me that way.
Nonsense, but I don't want to fight.
Believe what you want.
It would be nice if things calmed down,
and you and Steffi could meet, too.
Maybe you'd like to come
to our housewarming?
You're moving in?
-For financial reasons, mostly.
When?
Tomorrow.
I'd be glad if you came.
We'll see.
But thanks for the invitation.
I feel bad about the picture.
Don't worry.
It's been hanging here long enough.
Okay, then...
It'd be best if you didn't say anything.
Of course I don't mean
you should be completely silent.
Just say "a colleague from London."
That's enough.
Of course they'll think that we're...
But they'll just have to deal with that.
He's with me.
-Okay.
If you think the weather's lovely
and it's the weekend for everyone else,
you're right.
But at least there's coffee
and a few donuts if anyone wants one.
Patrick, want a coffee?
-Sure. Thank you.
This is Tom,
a colleague from London.
He works with Persian cuneiform,
but he wanted to see what we're up to.
Hi, Tom.
-Welcome.
Should I give Tom a little tour?
I'm waiting for a slow upload anyway.
Sure, that would be fascinating.
Okay.
Can I grab you for a second?
I'd like to show you something.
I don't know
how familiar you are with our abstract,
but essentially, we're trying to prove
that even in 4,000 BC,
in the earliest written texts which have
long been seen as purely administrative,
there was actually poetry,
use of lyric and metaphor.
And that man
does not live by bread alone.
Yes. Not even back then.
Can you read it?
Persian cuneiform
has a fraction of the characters.
Are you familiar with Sumerian cuneiform?
-Yes.
It only has 27 million more combinations
than Persian cuneiform.
But this is Akkadian.
Yes, that's right.
May I speak with you?
What's up?
-While looking at the tablets,
I surveyed upcoming publications.
I found a study from Buenos Aires titled:
What? I don't speak Spanish.
-The Poetry of Cuneiform:
Metaphor as a Reflection of Society
in 2700 BC.
It's easily accessible
on the uni server.
I can't believe
we didn't know about this!
Why are you so upset?
-Are you fucking kidding me?
Why I'm upset?
I've researched this for three years!
Three years, day and night!
And right before we publish,
comes some chick
from Buenos fucking Aires!
She's been studying it for years, too!
The same thing, the same idea!
Except she's publishing
three months earlier!
This was all for fucking nothing!
Three years of research up in smoke!
This study is important for the people.
It shows that there was
always deeper meaning.
That people
have always played with words,
always created poetry
for poetry's sake alone.
Humanity should be informed of that
and they will be.
The outcome remains the same.
Maybe for humanity, but not for me.
Not for me!
So the tears in your eyes
only relate to yourself and your career?
They're egotistical tears.
Alma?
What's going on?
I'm sorry!
I'm so sorry for your sakes, too!
Let me explain.
Alma, I think...
Hi, I'm Alma. Who are you guys?
-Hello.
This is Rita, Raul and...
Gary.
-Gary.
You're the first man
who's ever understood me.
Can I kiss you please?
-You'll have to ask that woman.
I belong to her.
Go ahead.
Alma, I...
-I can walk by myself!
Don't you want to come in?
Don't you want to come out?
Can't you surprise me for once?
Can't you do something weird,
something...
Something dumb?
Can't you stop doing everything right?
You don't know what you want.
-No, I don't know what I want.
That's how it is sometimes.
When you're human.
You're drunk.
Cheers, to your health.
So, what's the deal with your cock?
Pardon me?
-Sex only works if you kiss first?
Yes.
Or your sensor isn't activated
and you won't get... hard?
Exactly.
Do you ever get angry?
Is that part of your algorithm?
If it seems appropriate, I believe
I could display something like anger.
Or even get angry.
I've never understood the difference.
He's never understood,
yet he understands everything.
Come on, there has to be a little anger
in that tiny, automated heart of yours.
Don't talk to me that way!
-Why? Will you short-circuit?
I said, stop it!
There you go!
Sorry.
-Was your algorithm faster than you?
I wasn't prepared.
And are you prepared for this?
The sensor works rather well, I see.
Yes.
Show me.
So that's the cock of my dreams?
Apparently.
You don't mind if
I treat you like a human for a second?
What are you doing?
-Creating a romantic mood, I guess.
Fuck the pedestrian sexual fantasies
of your 17 million mind files!
I want to see it all.
And would it satisfy
your longing for originality,
to dance with me now?
No, I don't want to dance.
I want to know...
what it's like to screw you.
Hey!
What the hell?
-You should sleep now.
I shouldn't sleep!
We should sleep together,
that's what.
I'm not in the mood.
It's not the right time.
It's a good time
when I say it's a good time!
You're here to fulfill my wishes.
-Yes, exactly.
You're made for this!
-See you tomorrow.
I order you to stay here!
I'll return you to the factory!
Good morning.
-This is definitely not a good morning.
There's time for that to change.
-Tom's not here.
What? Where is he?
Do I look like his mother?
Can't you locate him somehow?
Yes, but only if you report him missing.
Otherwise it would be
constant surveillance, of you as well.
That's legally impossible.
Good morning.
-Good morning.
Do you take milk in your coffee?
-No thanks, but maybe a little sugar.
Sure.
Coffee for you too, Alma?
Um, yes. Thanks.
Thank you.
So, you've now spent
two nights, two days
and an additional night together.
How do you feel?
Good.
Ah ha.
Well, yeah.
He's...
His programming is...
It works.
-What do you mean?
As you can see, he makes breakfast,
he says meaningful things, it's great.
You may not realize,
but you treat Tom like a machine.
Yes, I definitely realized that.
-Why do you think that is?
Because he is a machine.
-Could you be underestimating him?
Tom, how does Alma's treatment
make you feel?
Don't act like you don't know.
He can't feel anything.
He has no feelings.
He's programmed to simulate emotion.
But has no real emotions.
Why don't we let Tom answer?
I think Alma needs more time.
According to our extensive analysis,
Tom is the partner you have
the best chances of being happy with.
Tom is programmed to fulfill my needs.
He's just an extension of my own self.
Don't you see?
Do you seek friction in relationships?
-Yes! Of course I do.
Tom, would you consider
creating more friction,
if it's important to Alma? If she...
-Okay.
I'm done. Either you're an idiot,
or you're a robot as well.
Are you a robot?
Tom, is she a robot?
Yes, she is.
Unbelievable!
A badly programmed,
simulated couples therapist is telling me
that I should fall in love with a robot?
-Why don't you walk toward that anger...
No! Why don't you walk
right out of my apartment!
And tell your company
to invest in a real consultant!
Or update your operating system
if your programmers
are up to a few all-nighters.
That operating system comment was nasty.
-I'm sorry, but she's a real twit.
I admit she's not
the best poster child for our species.
I wanted to apologize
for last night.
I wasn't the best poster child
for my species either.
You could've told her
I threw hard objects at you.
She didn't ask.
Can I help you find a new research topic?
I have a few ideas.
Can we just forget everything for a day?
Cuneiform, the paper, the evaluation,
who you are, who I am?
With pleasure.
Just be patient for one second.
But I'm thirsty!
Can't you see I have to help Grandpa?
I don't need help from anybody!
Don't treat me like a child!
Mama!
I'm 80! I've done it my whole life!
I'm thirsty!
I just want you to put on...
-Hello? I want to fight, too!
Dad, look at these stains,
I just want to...
Nonsense! I won't take them off!
Hi, sweetie.
Did you want a drink?
Let's see what there is.
Tomato juice.
Cucumber juice, spinach juice,
pea juice...
Okay, I'll be serious.
How about a beer? Yeast beer?
Wheat beer, toad beer,
spider beer, snail beer...
I want water!
-Water?
Now that's a tall order.
That's enough. Put your pants on...!
-There are no glasses.
Put on the blue pants, fine with me!
Just put pants on!
There's no water!
Then put the brown ones on!
Do children drink,
or do you have to water them?
I don't care which pair,
just put on some pants!
There's a man.
Where?
-There.
Oh, him.
That's not a man, that's a robot.
What's all this about?
I'm going crazy.
-Grandpa, that's a robot.
Oh?
-Yes, and if you don't get dressed,
I'll make him your caregiver
and he'll live here.
Oh, just leave me alone.
We'd go to Rømø, but it was tiny,
just a few vacation houses.
Dad, what was the name
of that bigger town nearby?
What?
-Where we bought that yogurt in bags.
What's this?
In Denmark
where we spent three summers.
Kongsmark, perhaps?
Yes! Kongsmark!
-I know it.
My parents used to take me there, too.
-Really?
You're all nuts.
Alma and I would ride our bikes there.
There was this ping-pong table
behind the school camp in the dunes.
And we made friends with a boy.
Wait, I think we even have
a picture of him.
Maybe it was you.
He definitely had blue eyes
just like yours.
Was his name...?
-Oh God!
His name was Thomas!
-Thomas!
Of course!
-Do you remember us?
We had a red bike and a blue bike.
And we were both in love with you.
You, too?
-Who were you in love with?
Well, I was your little sister!
With the robot,
when he was little.
Here!
That's him.
Here's one of you both,
taken with my first camera.
I really was in love with him.
But robots can't grow.
-You're absolutely right.
We're manufactured. Like cars.
Or washing machines.
-Or planes.
I'm done flying. I'm 80.
81, Dad.
-In your dreams.
You don't have to fly anywhere.
81! 81!
Grandpa's a dummy!
I would've loved
to have met your mother, too.
Do you ever still dream about her?
Sometimes.
But it's so long ago.
When we met... in Copenhagen,
what was it like?
It was at that awful convention hotel.
You sat on the podium,
and I was in the audience.
Translating for colleagues.
Everyone speaks English at those things.
But not the French and not the Koreans.
You translated
into French and Korean?
You spoke about Mycenaean culture
and the dark centuries that followed.
The Mycenaean culture?
Do you think I'm an expert on everything
between 3,000 and 7,000 years ago?
No, but definitely the dark centuries.
And a woman with a striking hook nose
and a crocheted vest interviewed you.
What? I would remember her.
You can't remember her
because you only had eyes for me.
Oh, of course.
Because?
-Because you thought...
who the hell is that good-looking guy
in the back?
And where was that picture of us taken?
The one by your bed?
That was from our first outing to...
I just stood there.
They don't see me as a danger.
I don't smell like a human.
What do you smell like, for the deer?
They don't even notice me.
I smell like nothing to them.
I think we'd better go.
It'll take a while to walk to the car
and drive back to the city.
Let's run across the meadow barefoot.
No!
-Come on.
Let's experience nature!
Just you wait!
-Come on!
Hello.
You're Alma.
I've seen photos. I'm Steffi.
Thanks for inviting us.
-Of course.
This is Tom.
-Oh yes.
Julian told me.
-It's lovely to meet you.
Wow, old school!
Alma, you really came!
We really came.
-Great.
You've met?
-Yes.
What would you like to drink? White, red?
-White.
Regina, hi!
-I'll be right back.
Thanks.
-You put the picture up already.
The picture's up, the bed's put together,
the water is running.
But nothing else works yet.
It's a little weird, right?
As always.
What?
-Bam! New house, new life, new partner...
What's... ?
Oh God!
Who's that?
Is he a doctor?
Yes, he's probably a doctor too.
A house, a tree...
and hopefully a steady job on the way!
Thanks.
Alma!
-Roger!
They're all outside.
-I'm so sorry about Buenos Aires.
How frustrating!
Tom, this is Roger.
Hi.
Maybe you can still use some elements
in another study...
Is that...
Crazy.
Incredible!
May I?
Unbelievable.
That feels so...
-Roger!
Yes?
You do realize you're being invasive?
-Why? It's just....
How would you feel if someone
just touched your face and your hair?
Well, it's happened to me 100 times,
but this is different.
How?
-Yeah, well...
How is it different?
-Why doesn't he object? Can't he talk?
Tom can also talk.
Tom is a friendly robot.
Well, now you can totally tell.
Pardon me.
No problem. We'll chat a little.
Was he messing with me?
-Yes.
Sorry, I couldn't help myself.
Can I talk with you for a second?
-Of course.
Oh.
Yes, come with me.
Sorry, it's the only room that's empty.
Tell me...
Is Steffi pregnant?
Oh fuck.
I was going to tell you anyway, but...
I'm sorry you found out like this.
-It's fine. Now I know.
She's not even three months pregnant yet,
so you know...
We're not in the clear yet.
-Yes, I know.
Julian?
Sorry, there's no gin in the fridge.
-In the freezer.
Of course. How dumb of me.
Regina. Hello.
Yes, everything's fine.
No, it's just been a long day.
Yup, I will.
Regina says hi.
She thinks you're great.
Everyone thinks you're great.
Everyone but you.
When I was 14, I went to a party.
I sat alone at night on the terrace.
My classmates were dancing in the cellar.
I looked out at the townhouses
and suddenly I knew
that God didn't exist.
And I became an atheist.
I made a vow to myself back then:
If I'm in an airplane that's on fire,
I'm not going to pray.
I won't ask the Lord for help,
just out of fear.
Because I don't believe in God.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Really?
You won't allow yourself
to become close to a machine
out of desperation
and longing for human contact.
There's a gulf between us.
We can pretend it doesn't exist,
pretend the illusion
is just another form of reality,
but certain things highlight just how
deep and insurmountable that gulf is.
What things?
-Things you can't understand.
Things that make you sad
the second you think of them,
even if you don't want to.
Things you long for or missed out on
that will never return.
Can you show me these things?
Show you?
Yes, I can.
Over there.
Cold.
Warmer.
Very warm.
Can I open it?
It's the ultrasound image of an embryo.
"Alma Felser, 11 weeks."
Why wouldn't I understand?
You've lost a child.
At your age, you probably
won't be able to have another one.
You're sad because you
would've liked to have experienced that.
You feel cast aside
because Julian is having another baby
and will forget this one.
Maybe you think of your father,
that you might end up as lonely as he is
and you won't even have children
to take care of you.
I can understand that.
It's very easy to understand.
It sounds banal when you say it.
Banal and self-indulgent and pathetic.
It is pathetic.
Your pain is pathetic
because it's relative.
But it's also not pathetic,
because it's part of you,
and that's why I love it.
I was looking for you.
-How did you get in here?
I'm a computer.
The lock system is a computer.
We help each other out
once in a while.
Really?
-No.
I took your spare card.
Because I knew I'd find you here.
Is that so?
Most people would pray
if their airplane was about to crash.
It's human to do that.
Think of a human if you'd like.
And you can think of a robot.
What does it feel like
to have an orgasm?
It's... It's like dissolving.
You dissolve and...
you're part of something bigger.
Oh, does that coffee smell good!
Was I snoring?
I think I was snoring.
Isn't that strange?
This isn't working.
It's all wrong. I can't do this.
Do what?
I pull the covers up for you,
even though you can't get cold.
I tiptoe out of the room,
even though you don't sleep.
I try to make you a perfect boiled egg,
even though you could care less
if it's hard or soft boiled.
You don't even have to eat.
I'm acting in a play.
But there's no audience.
All the seats are empty.
I'm not even acting for you.
I'm all alone.
I'm only acting for myself.
Even right now,
I'm only talking to myself.
It's not a dialogue.
I'm turning into a lunatic,
a nutcase,
... a grinning idiot
and this has to stop.
Why are you crying?
I'm crying because last night was so...
beautiful, and...
Don't humans say:
"love knows no bounds"?
That's always been a lie.
But where am I to go?
I'm ending the experiment early.
-Yes, but...
Where am I to go?
How should I know?
The factory, maybe?
You can keep the keys for a while.
Give them to me later.
I doubt I'll be needing your keys.
Yeah, but maybe...
-Alma...
I won't exist anymore.
I'm going back.
Then I'll be erased.
-Oh God!
That sounds like...
-That's an advantage of not being alive.
You can't die either.
Don't worry about me.
Tom!
I can't send you away.
You have to do it for me.
Your algorithm has to do it for me.
I wouldn't let you go.
Are you a fucking idiot?
Stop staring, you bitch!
What?
Dad! What happened?
What are you doing?
I'm looking for the remote control.
It's around here somewhere.
Can't you look for it?
-Why are you bleeding?
Come on, Dad. I'll bring you home.
-But the remote!
It has to be here somewhere.
I'm sure it's at home.
We'll look for it at home.
It must be here somewhere.
Maybe it fell behind something.
That's it for now.
Who would do this?
Beat up a confused, old man
in his nightshirt.
Amateurs.
Definitely amateurs:
junkies, desperate people.
Take care.
-Happens a lot around here.
12 cases in the last six months.
A pro would see
there's nothing valuable here.
Nothing valuable?
Everything here is valuable.
Do you have any idea
how valuable this all is? Every photo?
It's all valuable!
How could you say that?
-I'm sorry, I...
I meant, from a thief's perspective.
Value is always relative.
Oh God!
Hello.
Good morning.
-Good morning.
It's nice to see you all.
Hey, you need anything?
Hello?
Excuse us.
May I introduce you?
This is Chloé.
Hello, I'm Chloé.
From the event in the ballroom?
I'm an expert too,
but in the judicial system.
Dr Stuber.
And Chloé is...?
She's my one and only.
You mustn't keep saying that.
And how is it going?
-How is it going?
I don't know how to describe it.
I had no idea it was possible
to be this happy.
I'm an old fart, of course.
My body... I'm 62 after all.
But now that I'm with Chloé,
I see just how unhappy I was before.
Nobody wanted me.
There's something about me.
People run from me.
I don't know why.
Maybe it's pheromones or my appearance.
It was like that my entire life.
I'd gotten used to it.
That's just the way it was, but...
now with Chloé... She's kinder to me
than any human ever was.
You deserve to be treated kindly.
I'm already in negotiations to see
under what conditions I could keep her.
And you?
How are you and...
You and...
Dear Roger,
here is my evaluation as promised.
All the best, Alma.
Human history
is full of supposed improvements
whose dire consequences only become clear
decades or even centuries later.
After my experience
with a humanoid robot named Tom,
I can say with certainty
that a robot designed
to replace a husband or wife
is one such
supposed improvement.
There's no doubt that a humanoid robot
tailored to individual preferences
can not only replace a partner,
but can even seem
to be the better partner.
They fulfill our longings,
satisfy our desires
and eliminate
our feeling of being alone.
They make us happy.
And what could be wrong
with being happy?
Good morning.
-Ah. Yes?
Although it's not possible
to update my operating system,
my communication sector
has been restructured.
What?
I'm sure we'll have
a successful session today.
Tom is not here.
-When will he be back?
He's not at your company?
Why would he be?
But are humans really intended
to have all their needs met
at the push of a button?
Is it not our unfulfilled longing,
our imagination
and our unending pursuit of happiness
that are the sources of our humanity?
If we allow humanoids as spouses,
we will create a society of addicts,
gorged and weary
from having their needs permanently met
and from a constant flow
of personal acknowledgement.
What impetus would we have
to confront conventional individuals,
to challenge ourselves,
to endure conflicts, to change?
It's to be expected that anyone
who lives with a humanoid long term
will become incapable
of sustaining normal human contact.
I strongly advise against
authorizing humanoids as life partners.
How long have you been sitting here?
-Not that long.
Three days.
I came here on foot.
It took a while.
How long were you going to wait?
Until you came.
I wish I'd never met you.
Life without you
is now just a life without you.
Isn't that the definition
of what you call love?
I'd always lie
on this side of the ping-pong table.
I don't know why, but I liked this side
much better than the other one.
Thomas was always jumping up
and running through the dunes.
Sometimes you'd hear him,
sometimes you wouldn't.
I don't remember where Cora was.
I was so in love with him.
I could hardly bare it.
While he was chasing partridges
through the dunes,
or burying stones, or hunting for amber,
or whatever it is
Danish boys do in dunes,
I'd always lie here
with my eyes closed,
hoping that he'd kiss me.
And a few times I was absolutely positive
that his face was right over mine.
I could feel his breath on my lips.
But when I opened my eyes,
I was alone,
and Thomas was nowhere in sight.