Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
It's not over.
Hey! Hey! This is not flag football!
This is real football!
I'm fine! Stop worrying about me!
What about you?
What the hell are you doing out there?
What the hell are you doing, man?
Hey! Hey! Take a seat.
Not in front of them!
Don't look at the scoreboard.
We're still alive! All right.
Stop feeling sorry for yourselves.
We're down by two touchdowns.
They're doing better
than we are, but that's fine!
We just need to man up!
If you see an opponent in front of you,
tackle him and get him down!
Quit being petty with them
and letting them get into your heads.
That's their goal!
They're trying to get you mad.
That's their goal.
It's the second half.
Focus on football, not them.
You have to be aggressive.
Now we gotta stay focused.
Hey, hey! Amaree! Stop! Amaree! Stop it!
Why? Why? Take a breath.
I need you the whole game.
When they talk trash to you,
don't get in their face like that.
Just be cool.
You can do better! We need you!
Hey, hey, hey, accept it.
You need to accept what happened.
You think I don't accept this?
Screw you, man.
All right, okay.
It's just one loss, man. It's nothing!
Will I see you later?
It's our first loss of the season.
I know we're all upset.
Don't let the nerves get to you.
We beat Texas last year, remember?
We had a long winning streak.
It's our senior year.
We gotta finish strong.
You M-A-M-M-A-S-B-O-Y.
I became deaf when I had meningitis.
I was born hearing.
And later, at two
or three years old, I lost my hearing.
I was sick and close to dying,
and I had a brain infection and swelling.
I can't hear anything.
I can't hear cheering,
the fans yelling.
I feel their vibration.
I feel their footsteps when they run,
the boom, boom, boom of the vibration.
The cochlear implant, or CI,
gives you more ability to hear.
I have the cochlear implant,
and I only use it to listen to music,
and that's it.
I can feel the vibrations
and I can hear the music,
but I don't hear the lyrics.
Music helps me stay focused and calm.
I'm not crazy into basketball.
Honestly, football, that's my thing.
You know what keeps me motivated?
Working hard.
That's why I don't like baseball.
You know
I don't like that bullshit... Right.
True, true.
You're dumb.
So, Lera, are you going
to homecoming with Amaree or…?
I'm not sure. We'll see how it goes.
If things are good with us,
then we might go together. We'll see.
Amaree said he didn't really wanna go,
so we'll see about that.
Football is one of the avenues for them
to show the world what we're made of.
That's not the only way,
but it's one of the many great ways
to put that on display.
From here on out,
we are seriously focused.
Our goal is
to win all the way to homecoming
and win that homecoming game.
With a Deaf team, because they don't hear,
I believe
their other senses are heightened.
Our players
have a better feel on the field,
and I believe they see things better
because they can't hear.
How do we communicate on the field?
We huddle up and shoot our plays out.
We have a secret code.
The drum
is a very important part of cheering.
Yeah, we feel that vibration,
and it's great.
No, no, watch. Follow me.
I'm the only Deaf person in my family.
Yeah, I do feel lonely.
When I was a kid,
they would just talk around me.
And I didn't understand any of it,
so I'd just go off on my own.
When I run into hearing people
out in the world,
I feel, as a Deaf person, I am alone.
That's Dad?
Yes.
I was about two years old
when my dad left.
I do wonder why my dad left.
Is it because I'm Deaf?
Maybe. I don't know.
Teddy's gone. He was my best friend.
Teddy was on our football team
at Maryland School for the Deaf.
Jalen and Teddy,
that was Jalen's first relationship.
Jalen's first love.
The reason
I was attracted to Teddy is he was funny.
He always made me laugh.
Not only that, but we could have
really good conversations.
We could talk about anything.
And then sophomore year,
he transferred to a hearing school.
They were asking him, "Hey, you're Deaf,
what are you doing here?"
"You should go back to the Deaf school."
He was being bullied
because of his Deafness.
And he was wearing hearing aids,
and they would flick his hearing aid off.
He just had so many issues going on.
His identity, his family, his friends…
He was being bullied…
There were so many things going on,
and it took a toll on him.
Teddy hanged himself.
Teddy was my close friend.
We grew up together.
When he killed himself,
it was a huge shock to us.
It had a really big impact
on our community.
I felt like I wanted to hurt myself,
because he was gone.
I wanted to hurt myself.
I tried to cut myself.
I felt angry.
It was a mixture of anger,
feeling upset, sadness.
I feel that, now that he's gone,
it's made it a little bit tougher.
He's gone, but Teddy's always
going to have a special place in my heart.
Discrimination is everywhere.
It's pretty much inevitable for them.
I think
it's how we react to the discrimination.
Ready, ready…
A lot of the hearing teams
don't want to play us.
And most coaches
don't like to lose to Deaf coaches.
Out in the hearing world,
they tend to look down on Deaf people,
and they don't think
we can do things as well.
So the way to prove them wrong
is to beat them,
to crush them on the field, and teach them
that Deaf people can do anything.
And we prove to them that we are the same.
In the game, when we go to huddle,
pay attention to the next play.
Get in and get out.
So make sure
you're looking at the play call,
not messing around
and talking to each other.
The important thing is,
this is our last game.
I need 110% effort out there.
Work hard.
We don't need any heroes out there.
Let's tackle it. And we'll get the win.
That's all it takes.
Not showin' off. No messin' around.
Hey, what about homecoming?
Me? Who am I gonna ask?
What about Lera?
I'm just askin'. Just askin’.
She doesn't want me. She avoids me.
So I give her space.
Ya know? Thanks!
Yep! Well, "peace out."
I am copying your sign for that!
Hey, shut up! Blow out the candles!
Do you want to get some ice cream here?
Are you gonna pay?
Oh, am I paying for you?
I'm broke.
I'm just teasing you.
I'm just curious, what's goin' on with us?
What are we?
I don't know.
Are we together or we not? I don't know.
I'm a little scared.
We have a lot going on.
Are we together?
I had a strong throw.
You were a receiver?
-W-R.
-Oh, you were a wide receiver?
What happened?
Not now.
That was way back then. Way back.
Right, back in the day.
I was good!
-Oh, really?
-I was good.
Could you catch the ball
with only one hand?
When I was growing up without Dad,
he left,
and I was kind of disgusted with him.
It's tough.
It's difficult,
and my role model was gone.
But now I feel
like I'm connecting with Dad.
First down. Yeah.
So, tomorrow is our homecoming game
and our homecoming day.
It's homecoming.
We're expecting a big crowd.
We're playing the Virginia Spartans.
The Virginia Spartans are a hearing team.
It's my very last game.
I'm going to be very emotional about it.
You ready? Ready? The big announcement.
The homecoming king goes to…
Amaree McKenstry!
You know, any success is for Teddy.
When we win, we win for Teddy.
We keep him in our hearts.
Don't let up!
Let's come back stronger, together!
So don't give up! Don't give up! Come on!
I think their biggest challenge
is going to be coming out of this bubble.
Once they get out there,
it's not a guarantee.
So there are going to be
a lot of obstacles for them to face
that they haven't faced here on campus.
Life is short, you know…
anything can happen at any time.
Just be who you want to be
and be yourself,
and that's all it needs to be.
Be yourself, you know?
You know, I'll be 18 soon.
I'll be graduating
and going out into the real world.
I need to be prepared for that.
And what scares me
is the unknown.
Things that can get fucked up.
Those challenges, you know,
when I'm out in the world,
help me learn.
And I'm ready for the world.
I LOVE YOU.