Look, look,
they're shooting at us.
Open fire, shoot!
- Bah, it's a dance of dragons.
- Return to your posts.
Drums.
Master Wong, be careful
of the foreign ship's guns.
- Dare to come up?
- I dare.
Give me the lion's tail!
"Magnificent aspirations
soar to the skies."
"Chivalry shoots up into the sky."
Wong Fei-Hung, you take a look.
A growing number of western
warships anchored in our harbor.
Hong Kong was given to the United Kingdom.
Macao was given to Portugal.
Russia occupies Heilongjiang.
Even our own ancestors
couldn't keep the invaders out.
I, Lau Wing-Fook, have been sent to Vietnam,
someone else's region, to fight the French Army.
If Vietnamese people saw this 'My Land,
My People' plaque, what would they think?
- Come here!
- Yes, my lord!
Take it down.
- Hurry up!
- Yes!
Slow down.
Lord Lau, the current court makes frequent
changes. Maybe you'll be transferred back soon?
The court quarrels too much.
They sent me to war, and yet they despise
me for having too much military strength.
After I'm gone, this Navy, which I have
been with for so long, will be disbanded.
Wong Fei-Hung, you're the
coach of our Black Flag Army.
You incorporate them into a
militia and continue practising.
In case a powerful enemy attacks,
they can defend their homeland.
Master Wong...
Get up.
Lord Lau, don't worry.
I hope you'll be back soon.
Wong Fei-Hung, written on this fan are the unequal
treaties our country signed with westerners.
Seeing the fan is
like seeing the man.
I hope when I get back, these
treaties will have been forgotten.
UNEQUAL TREATY
ONCE UPON A TIME IN CHINA
Executive producer:
RAYMOND CHOW
Starring:
JET LI, YUAN BIAO
JACKY CHEUNG, ROSAMUND KWAN, KENT CHENG
Guest stars:
WU MA, LIU XUN, YUEN CHEUNG-YAN
Co-starring: QIU JIAN-GUO,
YAM SAI-KOON, KAREL WONG, TONY YUEN
Screenplay: TSUI HARK, YUEN KAI-CHI,
LEUNG YIU-MING, ELSA TANG
Martial arts directors: YUEN CHEUNG-YAN,
YUEN SHUN-YEE, LAU KAR-WING
Producer, director:
TSUI HARK
Barbecued pork buns.
Not again!
Third Uncle, what did you say?
Now the provincial capital has more
westerners, dates are difficult to arrange.
Old Cheung, you're impressive
doing business with foreign devils.
Couldn't make a living in Tangshan,
so I had to go to England and work hard.
This time, Old Chiu only brought 'The
Concubine Sparrow' to photograph with you.
This bird has made a
show of the limelight.
A photograph is a small token,
you'll have one in a while.
That's very considerate,
thanks for your blessing.
- Master.
- Master Wong.
Dear 'Brothers'.
Hello, everyone.
- Fei-Hung!
- Grand Uncle Gan, haven't seen you in years.
- You have more spirit.
- Thanks to you...
Fei-Hung, look who's come
back with me this time.
Master Wong, have you had tea?
A lot of people are waiting for you.
- 13th Aunt?
- Fei-Hung.
- She wants to shake your hand.
- Foreigners greet by shaking hands.
I'll introduce you.
Her name is Joanna.
- 'Do'? What's 'do'?
- She's greeting you: 'How do you do?'
You have to say 'thank you'.
I-kill you... I-kill you...
You're welcome, you're welcome.
- Fei-Hung, let's get a picture with the bird.
- Alright.
- Sit down.
- Fei-Hung, photographs are easy.
- How come?
- Look over there.
Don't move... otherwise it won't be pretty.
Sit up straight.
Ready.
1-2-3!
What's the matter?
It's boiling water!
- Are you alright? Have you been scalded?
- I'm fine.
- This foreign toy is too dangerous. Stop playing!
- A little too much magnesium powder.
- You're shameful, telling me not to move!
- Did you get frightened?
Grand Uncle Gan, fortunately you asked me to
come, otherwise, you'd be just like this bird.
You think so?
Old Chiu? Old Chiu?
Old Chiu?
I'm leaving in two days. Your 13th
Aunt went to England for two years.
Kept saying she wanted
to return to Tangshan.
This is fine, too.
Saves her from mixing with foreigners.
- Could you watch her for me?
- Eh, watch her?
Old Chiu, answer me!
Old Chiu, don't frighten me!
Acupoint...
Is anyone there?
I'm here to see Master Wong.
Who... who's there?
What can I do for you?
- I've just come from Meixian County.
- Oh, Meixian...
My name's Leung Foon.
I've come to be Master Wong's apprentice.
- He... he...
- He's not here?
- I... I... I am...
- You?
- You are?
- Wong... Master Wong...
- You're Master Wong?
- No...
- You?
- I am...
You're Master Wong!
I'm a cowherd, looking
for a cow to practice.
Carelessly, I let the cow kick my arm.
Can you check it for me?
Alright!
Not this one, this one.
Master Wong, I hurt my arm.
You're wrapping up my leg. Why?
Now... now you say.
Too... it's too late!
It's stiff, Master!
It's all stiff!
You... are you alright?
Master, did you wrap me up
like this to teach me Kung Fu?
Strive? You want me to work hard?
OK, let me show you hard work.
I can still move.
Can be high and low.
This stump is really amazing.
Work?
Work must be done, right?
Master, I get it.
I'll show you a few more flips.
Expel the burglar!
- Who is he?
- Master is teaching me Kung Fu.
'Toothbrush' So is
teaching you Kung Fu?
- Who is he?
- Toothbrush So.
You're not Master Wong?
You're this Toothbrush So.
Who's that?
He's Master Wong's apprentice.
- Hey, so who are you then?
- I'm Master Wong's favourite apprentice, Ling Wan-Kai.
- Hey, how did you end up like this?
- Don't ask. I must catch the opera troupe to find work.
I'm going!
If I don't go, he'll wrap up
my other leg the same way.
Leung Foon! Leung Foon, quickly
repair the hole in the roof.
The performance is about to open.
I came to be a martial actor, but you
order me to climb up and repair this roof.
Your way of doing it
isn't according to regulation.
If you don't climb, how do you
know how good your Kung Fu is?
As soon as I make it famous, I'll tell
you to climb up and repair the roof.
What are you doing?
Tearing down the building?
Tumbling on the roof?
I thought the foreign
ship opened fire.
When the heavens thunder,
you think it's a cannon.
I'll go with you to the USA to dig for
gold. No need to waste time here.
Country boy!
Doesn't know anything!
Now, don't move, otherwise
it won't look good.
Are you ready?
A foreign woman can speak Chinese?
Looks like Tangshan
will soon become foreign.
Hey, wait for me...
- 1-2-
- Wait for me!
Wait for you?
The bucket's stuck!
Leung Foon, where
the hell are you?
I'm changing my clothes.
Get to work!
Want to be lazy?
That Leung Foon talks about how
good his Kung Fu is all day long.
Insists on climbing
up to repair the roof.
Doing somersaults like you do
will make the stage collapse.
Collapsing the stage? You show me how to
do that by somersaulting! Talking nonsense!
Young lady, I'm really sorry.
The clothes have been washed clean.
- I've already asked someone to iron them.
- Thank you, Boss.
Oh, yes.
Do you want to change the water basin?
No need, I'm almost done.
OK?
Who's there?
You didn't...
- We have a new opera, please come take photographs.
- Good, Boss!
Be careful, rain has
made the road slippery.
Fake foreign woman, wearing
fancy clothes like a costume!
Miss!
Umbrella.
Uncle, come on up.
We have lots of girls here.
Inspection takes so long.
There's gunfire. What's up?
Who is it?
PO CHI LAM
Master! Master!
- Master!
- It's Sai-Wing. Open the main door now.
Master!
Lucky you opened up fast, or
I'd have burst the door open.
Later, I'll buy you tea.
Give way!
- Kai, who's been shot?
- It's the greengrocer, Uncle Nine.
- What's the grievance?
- I don't know, ask Master.
Toothbrush So, you're going
to spill the medicine again.
- Pork... pork... pork...
- Pork...? Butcher Wing!
Calling me fat makes me fat!
Been back in China so long and
you still can't speak Chinese!
- Pork... pork...
- T-t-toothbrush!
- 'Porky'!
- So, bring the medicine.
You don't understand Chinese,
what medicine are you taking?
You're brothers,
what's the arguing about?
Master, I'm teaching
him how to be Chinese.
- Get the metal trauma medicine.
- Metal trauma medicine?
Three words.
They're all three words.
Master, I can't read.
So, you laugh at people who don't
speak Chinese? Ah So, come on.
'Seven Wounds Powder'.
'Hemostatic Powder'.
That's Toothbrush So, they
say he came back from America.
I heard he studied Western medicine there,
and came back to study with Master Wong.
Then he's pretty good, too.
- Master, water's here!
- Finally, the bullet's out.
Uncle Nine, you'll be alright.
- Master, this bullet's from a rifle.
- Wrap up his wounds.
Now there are so many foreign ships
in the harbor, and flags of all kinds.
Uncle Nine couldn't distinguish between
the American and British flags.
So, he mistakenly boarded the
wrong ship and was injured.
Now the capital is engaged in
the Self-Strengthening Movement.
Whatever the dispute, it's us
Chinese that will come to grief.
Then how can we Chinese survive?
We don't depend on Manchurian dogs!
Manchurian tyrants have
occupied our Central Plain.
Now they collude with red-haired devils!
Selling out our mountains and rivers!
Militia Brothers, we're going
to take down the foreign ships!
- Calm... calm... calm down!
- You're teaching me?
- Pork... pork...
- Impudent, call me Senior!
- Sai-Wing!
- Master.
You're so impetuous,
don't you interfere.
Now it's about human life, I'll call on the imperial
court, and clarify matters with the Westerners.
Otherwise, how can we Chinese
continue living in Foshan?
Sir, excuse me...
Ah So, you explain
it to the manager.
How come... your words
are so... fluent?
Why put all these knives
and forks on the table?
Ah So, you take the decision
on ordering some dim sum.
Ah Foon, today I need your help.
You help me collect tickets at the door.
I'm here to learn martial acting,
and you ask me to collect tickets?
I have no choice. All the workers went
to San Francisco to dig for gold.
Gold digging?
If there's gold, then they should dig.
But is there really
such a thing, boss?
You think I'd cheat you?
All the newspapers are full of it.
If it weren't for so many people
working for me, I'd go, too!
Newspaper?
What's a newspaper?
They're here to collect
protection fees.
- Didn't you pay respect at the pier?
- Yes, they're Shahe killers here to grab land.
Those two can go eat shit!
So few men here to grab land?
Negotiating with them means
we would be the bullies.
Right!
- What are you doing?
- I know you've learnt a couple of moves.
Didn't you say you wanted to
make a name in the capital?
- Now's a great opportunity.
- That's not what I meant.
It's not a good idea to collect tickets here.
They said they came to visit you specially.
Testing my skill? Don't tease me.
Ah, Boss, open up!
Boss, open up quickly! Boss!
Oh, no matinee today,
no tickets.
- Thanks, boss! I'll come back another time.
- Brother! Come down!
- Thanks!
- Come down!
Damn it. Came all the way to the
theater and there's no tickets.
Next time I won't come,
even if they invite me.
I know you're Leung Foon,
here to negotiate with me.
- No, I collect tickets.
- We're here for the protection fee.
My brothers tell me
you're a good fighter.
A single man who dares
take on so many of us.
You really have guts!
I'm flattered.
I'm off to prepare your gift.
I'll visit all you
gentlemen later.
We can't accept that.
Don't be so formal.
Chopping off your hand, that will do!
Chop my hand?
Grab him!
Don't run!
That's enough!
So many people bullying one guy.
- Come here.
- Let's find a good time and place to duel.
No need, it's here and now.
Catch him!
Stop!
- Some people are fighting in the theater.
- Yes, they have knives.
Don't run! Stop!
Grab him!
- Excuse me, excuse me...
- What's going on?
Fighting?
Go outside and fight!
Don't get in the way of our business.
Get out!
Brother, is there trouble?
Those Shahe bullies are here to collect a protection
fee. They want to compete with me but there's too many.
Slaughter that bastard!
- Look, an argument!
- Whereabouts?
That's Porky,
Wong's Fei-Hung's apprentice.
Seems I've never met him.
Porky Wing, I'll give face to your master,
Wong Fei-Hung. Today, I'm letting you go.
Wouldn't waste my time fighting you!
- Ah, you're Wong Fei-Hung's apprentice?
- Of course I am.
I've been to Po Chi Lam. I saw your
fellow apprentice, Toothbrush So.
That fake foreign devil!
- Leung Foon!
- What?
Don't think I'm joking with you.
If you don't surrender your hand to Shahe,
I'll make you disappear from Foshan.
- Let's go back to Shahe.
- Let's go!
Eh, you daren't fight Wong Fei-Hung's apprentice?
Want a hand? I'll give you a big pig's trotter!
- Big Brother, do we stand down?
- Stand down? Tear his stand down!
- Brother Wing, this one's for him.
- Give it free, not doing business today!
You rotten brat!
Shahe's stupid, Shahe's clumsy!
Shahe's entire family getting wasted!
Still singing?
Making trouble?
I'll beat you to death!
Buy sweet cakes.
Eat sweet cakes, watch the fight.
A bowl of sweet tofu pudding.
Go to hell!
I'll chop you! Don't run!
You call this a fight?
Have some water, liven things up!
- Who's pouring boiling water?
- Them! Go up and see!
- Who's pouring boiling water? Come out!
- Let's go!
Old bastard, pouring
boiling water on us?
- Not me, I was eating barbecued pork buns.
- Barbecued pork buns?
This is General Wickens of the British ship,
and Mr Jackson of the US merchant ship.
They are most generous, and will
no longer investigate the shooting.
You mustn't persist in demanding
compensation for the grocer incident.
This isn't fair to the grocer.
How can we calm the people's anger?
People's anger? Wong Fei-Hung,
which court sent you here?
You're just the hoi polloi. What qualifies
you to discuss policy with an official?
Now the Capital is in the process
of the Self-Strengthening Movement...
relationships with foreigners
are to endure a period of calm.
Take a step back and
view the broader picture.
Here, this bread is
made from our flour.
So, you appreciate western cuisine?
Westerners carve out concessions in our
region, and set up restricted areas.
If our countrymen still doubt each other, and
are tolerant in all respects of foreigners...
sooner or later, we won't even have
the flour to make steamed buns.
Wong Fei-Hung, I know you have a deep friendship
with the Black Flag Army's Lau Wing-Fook.
He thinks the whip cannot reach him in the south,
even when expressing different views to the court.
Now the court has sent me south to watch you, and
find an individual to punish as an example to others.
Western lady, are you alright?
Master, it's people from our militia.
Master?
You stop them.
Stop!
Tell them not to fight.
Don't fight!
Kai, I didn't ask you to fight.
I said, tell them not to fight!
Fuck you, don't fight!
Drop your weapons!
Still fighting?
Don't do it!
- Good skills.
- Of course!
- Big Brother, that guy seems to be Wong Fei-Hung.
- Wong Fei-Hung...
We have many people,
so chop him as well!
- Don't fight!
- You dare hurt me?
Don't want to fight?
Here!
He hit you? Don't fight!
Don't fight, Ah Kai!
- Don't fight!
- I told you to stop fighting!
- Still fighting?
Really, stop fighting.
They're coming over. Let go!
Big Brother, are you alright?
- Who just kicked me?
- I don't know...
- Have you gone up yet?
- Sure...
Give it to me again!
Toothbrush So!
So, explain to them that
they shouldn't misunderstand.
No need to explain.
If there were no restricted areas
in China, we wouldn't be safe.
This foreign devil can speak Chinese.
Still coming?
Don't call me a foreign devil,
Chinese devil.
You listen to me.
We're doing business.
If you don't use your brains,
how can you earn a fortune?
Wong Fei-Hung, I'm warning you.
Stop messing about.
Or else you'll suffer!
Goodbye, foreign devil.
- Shoot whoever resists.
- Let's go.
The soldiers are here.
Run for it!
Out of the way, I'm going first.
Stop! Don't go!
Put the weapons down.
You call yourselves a militia?
Porky Wing ran away?
Nobody move!
Disobey and be killed.
Wong Fei-Hung, this district
is under western jurisdiction.
Now the militia come
in and cause trouble.
You're the militia's chief instructor.
How will you explain to the court?
My lord, they're the disbanded navy,
trained by the court.
- There must be a reason for them to do this.
- What reason? The court disbands, but you offer shelter?
The militia is now directly
supervised by the court.
Lord Governor!
Tell them to report for duty at the court,
otherwise, I'll arrest the men immediately.
- My lord...
- Furthermore...
All damages are the
responsibility of Wong Fei-Hung.
Yes, my lord.
Beware of fire.
Beware of thieves.
Master, I've lost my appetite. I heard
that those men came over from Shahe.
The court now wants the militia to report.
Would they seize the chance to detain us?
- Master!
- Master Wong...
Sit down.
The court has the right to prosecute. If someone
framed you, the truth will come to light.
After eating this meal, only once matters
are concluded can we sit together again.
Everyone eat.
Militia take order,
prepare to eat.
Pick up the food!
Eat!
Swallow!
Pick up the food.
Eat!
Swallow!
13th Aunt.
You needn't worry so much,
the militia men may be alright.
It's so late,
you're still awake?
I'm going to take your
measurements for a suit.
A suit? Why on earth would
a Chinese man wear a suit?
In future, you can wear
it in a foreign country.
13th Aunt, are foreign
countries really so good?
Why... what do we have
to learn from others?
They invented the steam engine,
among many other things.
Their science is more advanced than ours.
Without science, we fall behind.
If you have time, you really must
tell me what the outside world is like.
13th Aunt...
If it's so good over there,
why did you want to come back?
- There's something here they don't have.
- What don't they have?
People.
The people I want to see
don't exist over there.
Although I've been away this past
two years, my heart is still here.
In fact, I thought
of you every day.
You're most considerate.
- 13th Aunt!
- What's the matter?
I thought... excuse me.
Fei-Hung, you and I are related only
by two generations of family contract.
Actually, we don't have
a blood relationship.
We grew up together.
Don't call me Aunt anymore.
How can generational seniority switch?
I'll do it myself.
How much is this?
Close enough.
Some things can't be close enough.
If it's not exact, what's the point?
Therefore, a Chinese man
should never wear a suit.
Because Chinese are Chinese,
westerners are western.
The railway will be built here soon,
and the telegraph office opened.
In future, everything will change.
China must also change to follow the world.
You're right.
Now the foreigners are
here with guns and warships.
Everything is changing.
I don't know what's going
to happen in future.
Although I appreciate your gift,
you must take it back.
In future, when all Chinese men
wear suits, I'll wear it again.
Believe in Jesus,
an eternal life...
Get lost, Jesus devil!
Be cautious, meet
the God of Prosperity.
Sir, we bought the God of Prosperity.
Sir, we bought the...
- God of Prosperity.
- You, come here now!
- Sir, we bought the God of Prosperity...
- Over there!
Did you buy my God of Prosperity,
or buy the previous God of Prosperity?
He's already under a well.
Want to see him?
Buy another one.
If I pay him, what happens
when the other guy comes?
- Sir, are you hiring anyone?
- You want to flatter me?
- Sir, the situation is bad now.
- Give me that!
If the situation's bad,
I'll look after you.
Sir, take it, but don't leave it empty.
Leaving me profit would be good, too!
You want to profit,
so I don't profit?
Still profiteering at this
time of national hardship?
Wong Fei-Hung!
You guys came here from Shahe?
Come with me to the court.
Save me!
Killing one's own people?
Move it!
Run!
Where are those useless bastards?
Go to hell!
Fucking hell, it's too high!
- Run...
- Wow! Superb! Really good!
Master Wong just used his
'shadowless kick'. Did you see it?
No, I didn't.
Dear villagers and elders... this man
indiscriminately collects protection fees.
I'm taking him back to the court. Could
I trouble you to come and be witnesses?
This big brother's kung fu is amazing.
He dares to jump from such a height.
Boss... he forced you to give him a protection
fee. Come with me to the court and be a witness.
Be a witness?
I don't want to be like the theater boss,
startled by the wind all day long.
You were inside discussing martial arts. I
didn't see any fight... and don't want to know.
Over in America, everyone
has to be careful walking.
- Why?
- Because if you're not careful, you'll step on the gold.
- How can there be such a good thing?
- Not only that...
Wash your face by the river,
there's gold dust in the water.
- Is there really such a great place?
- Of course there's such a place.
Just one trip is better than struggling
for the rest of our lives here at home.
Come on, one sheet per person, take a look.
Don't say you weren't informed.
When you get there, you'll have to wear inky glasses,
because the dazzling gold will make your eyes blind.
If your eyes go blind, you won't be
able to see the gold much less pick it up.
Lamb that has lost his way, you should
get to know the Kingdom of Heaven.
- You're a publicist for San Francisco, too?
- Materials aren't eternal.
Only Jesus reveals the truth of life. You
should get close to him to witness life.
I caught a villain today.
Will Jesus be my witness?
Beware of thieves.
Beware of fire.
Big Brother...
- Big Brother, where is he?
- I'm here.
Everyone get ready.
- Master, aren't you hot?
- Well?
Idiot, so windy and
still drawing the fan?
- Is the court really holding the militia men in custody?
- I thought if they caught the suspects, they'd release them.
Master.
Who knew the court would call me a
suspect, with no right to bear witness?
Instead, they released
that Shahe named Hung.
- How long will the militia be shut down?
- Until someone testifies.
Master, look for Leung Foon.
- Foon? You know him?
- Yes.
You must be part of this.
What are you hiding from me?
I... Master, you
don't even believe me.
- So, I...
- I what? Say it.
Mas... Master!
The... there!
- Fire!
- Ah So, stay calm. Don't move!
Master!
Ah So!
- Master, what to do?
- The arrows were shot from the pharmacy roof.
Ah So, Master's
coming to save you!
Don... don't worry about me.
Gath... gather the things.
Ah Kai, we'll take weapons,
and go out to fight him.
Sai-Wing, you stay and put out the fire.
I'll go.
You go alone?
Fucking hell!
So, catch!
Slippery steps!
Lord Lau's fan?
It is.
- Wow! What a big fire on the roof!
- Bel... below it's... mor... more severe!
Someone's on the roof.
Shoot him!
It's Wong Fei-Hung, run.
Retreat...
Po Chi Lam's on fire.
If Po Chi Lam burns, it's gone.
- 13th Aunt, what are you doing?
- I'm taking a picture of Po Chi Lam.
- Fire's reaching our ass, and still taking pictures?
- You're blocking the sign.
Stand over a bit, otherwise
the camera can't see you.
Don't you want to
wait for Master?
The roof... is... on fire.
Hey, Ah So, look over here!
Ah Kai, you sit a
little to the right.
It was supposed to be with me, but I was
trying to photograph Po Chi Lam. So, I...
You're just like a foreign woman.
You don't understand the severity.
Playing with these
foreign toys all day.
In future, you're forbidden from
bringing these things into Po Chi Lam.
Otherwise, I'll
throw them all away.
The Lord Governor is here.
Master Wong, you open martial clubs, but in your spare
time specialise in sneaking around incense halls.
Helping common folk in the allocation of separatist
sites. Now your enemies come to your door.
You are to blame for the burning of Po Chi
Lam. You must repent and turn over a new leaf.
Lord Governor, opening a martial club is
not equal to setting up an incense hall.
If the court truly believes that practising
martial arts is breaking the law...
the tradition of martial arts our ancestors
left behind will henceforth become extinct.
If violent criminals attack us,
how do we defend ourselves then?
Won't this retreat be considered
a step back far and wide?
You couldn't even maintain Po Chi Lam, and yet you
want to lecture me about the military affairs?
Investigating the fire is
the court's responsibility.
- Then tell me, who set the fire?
- I don't know.
You don't know?
You're hiding the truth!
- Porky!
- Senior!
Sai-Wing!
- What are you doing? Get back inside!
- Master!
- Can I come in?
- Red-haired demon! What are you doing...?
- Sai-Wing!
- Master!
- If you do that again, don't call me master.
- Don't go.
You must be dissatisfied with Wong Fei-Hung. If you
have any complaints, don't hesitate to speak out.
Wong Fei-Hung, I know who burnt Po Chi Lam.
I can be your witness.
- Check if anyone's from Shahe.
- Right.
- Hey, are you from Shahe?
- I'm not!
You don't look
like it, let's go.
So many people. Hey, Big Brother, the
officers will catch you sooner or later.
Fuck!
That Jesus devil must've informed on me.
Big Brother, how about
returning to Shahe to hide?
No need. People are afraid of the court.
The court's afraid of the foreign devils.
Let's go find the most fierce devil.
Go!
Wait for me!
We want to see Mr Jackson.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
Fucking hell!
I don't speak foreign words.
Get on your knees. I beg you...
let us come in and see Mr Jackson.
Call together. Call together...
Mr Jackson. Jackson...
I only keep a dog if it can guard my door.
You're wanted by the court.
- What's the benefit of my helping you?
- I'm not afraid of being caught by the court.
It's my brothers, without a leader who knows how
to handle them, it's too much talent to waste.
You came all the way to Tangshan to seek wealth.
You're looking for so many coolies to go mining.
Why don't I send over some women for
you to take? Isn't that better?
No! Our government won't allow the
coolies to have wives or children.
They can't put down
roots in San Francisco.
I'm not talking about 'wives',
I'm talking about 'whores'.
I have as many as you want.
Worst is that Wong Fei-Hung,
he's always in the way.
Do you have the ability
to help me kill him?
- Wong Fei-Hung?
- Yes, yes!
I'll invite him to watch an opera.
If he doesn't die by my hand,
he'll die in the hands of the court.
Hey, the court's ordered the arrest
of the Shahe gang, Brother Wing.
Foon, how come you
show up only now?
I'm back in the troupe. Come, I'm inviting
you to see the opera. Come on, let's go.
- Hold on, hold on! I'll lock the door first.
- Come on, I'll help you.
- Hey, how will you get out?
- Oh, that's right.
Here, this is Lam Sai-Wing.
If you have any trouble, ask for his help.
Master Wong's apprentice.
You give me too much face.
I won't watch the opera for free,
I'll help you collect tickets.
I've always liked
being gatekeeper.
- Thank you...
- You're welcome...
Tickets, tickets...
Give me your tickets.
You have tickets, go in.
- Hey... do you have tickets?
- Tickets? You want my ticket?
Do you know who I am?
You look at this sign.
- He's 'Extraordinary' Ho, I'm Bak Yuk-Long.
- I'm Lam Sai-Wing, give me a ticket or get lost!
The opera's opening and
you want me to 'get lost'?
- OK, we'll get lost. You'll regret this!
- Go, go on, go...
Tickets, tickets...
Brother Wing, go in
and watch the opera.
- There's time, the stars haven't taken the stage.
- Thank you for your trouble.
Oh, have Extraordinary Ho
and Bak Yuk-Long arrived yet?
Arrived? They wanted to watch the opera
for free. I had to drive them away.
- You what? They're the stars!
- Ah, those people were actors?
Oh, no!
The opera can't be sung.
You stay here a while,
I'll quickly chase them back.
Tickets...
Oh, no! Master's here.
Could you watch for me? I'm taking a shit!
- Didn't expect the foreigners to invite you to the opera.
- Please...
13th Aunt.
Master Wong.
- Why regard me as an outsider?
- The rule of seniority can't change, not ever.
Fine, let's watch the opera.
- Please...
Brother Wing, Brother Wing!
Brother Wing, this time it's bad!
Master's here, I'm not
watching the opera.
My God! The stars have gone, you're
off again. What am I going to do?
- I can sing a few words.
- Huh? So what?
The two of us can go on
first, we'll save the show.
Hey, Master's arrival scared you into running.
You still dare to sing in front of him?
Silly, with painted faces
no one will recognize us.
Alright, let's take a chance.
We'll go backstage from here.
Without us this opera
wouldn't be sung at all.
- Is this OK?
- Aren't you Porky Wing?
- Who's Porky Wing? Let's go.
- Let's go.
The White Snake became a fat snake.
Porky Wing!
- Amazing that you could recognize me.
- We recognize... that's great...
Hey, now we won't
have any pork to eat.
Sai-Wing, again!
- Preposterous!
- I told him to do this, give me face, OK?
Shut up!
Pack up and get lost!
You're forbidden to
return to the troupe.
Then I'll leave.
Brother Wing, I'll sell pork with you.
Take care!
Get down!
Seal off the passages at once.
- Come here, escort the foreigners out safely.
- Yes.
Boss, there's fighting outside.
Leung Foon, you're dead! It must be the Shahe
gang here to catch you. Quick, chase them!
13th Aunt, be careful!
Still attacking?
Don't shoot, there are
innocent people below.
Don't shoot!
My heir, my heir...
Lime powder, close your eyes!
Don't get up.
- Is it Wong Fei-Hung?
- Leave him, come on.
Quickly, protect his Lordship!
Come on!
Foreign gun!
Foreign gun...
Find a place to hide.
13th Aunt, you take this gun,
and hide with the missionary.
They came to deal with me.
It's dangerous to follow me. Go!
Come with me!
Master, catch the staff!
Master, let me help you!
A little bit weak.
- Master, let me help you.
- Who are you?
Hurry, go protect 13th Aunt,
I don't need your help.
Go!
Don't grab her!
Missionary!
Missionary...
Sai-Wing, quick,
come protect 13th Aunt!
The murderers ran off stage.
Fuck you!
Come up if you have the guts.
Go to hell!
- Why did you try to assassinate me?
- Did you try to assassinate me or I you?
- Leung Foon?
- He's Leung Foon?
- He's Leung Foon.
- It's dangerous here, there are murderers inside.
Ask him about it, I'm going in.
- Hey, Ah Foon, what the hell's going on?
- I don't know.
As soon as he came in, he hit me without
thinking. I'm going to kill the bastard.
- Ah Foon!
- Don't move!
You told me not to move,
why did you hit me?
First we talk, then we fight.
Run for it!
Run!
Wong Fei-Hung, don't move!
- Lord Governor...
- You're not allowed to speak!
My Lord,
they left something behind.
'Militia wins honor,
kill all foreigners.'
Weren't all the militia
locked up by me?
How many of the militia
didn't you hand over?
Lord Governor, I'm being framed.
Don't trust him.
Those Shahe gangsters should be arrested.
What Shahe gangsters?
- You hit me for a second time.
- Get it straight before talking.
Get it straight?
This gangster is obviously
collecting protection fees.
- What? You're saying Master Wong charges protection?
- Isn't that right?
- Master Wong? He's not from Shahe?
- Who comes from Shahe?
You don't have to
explain anymore.
Your remnants will be captured
by the court sooner or later.
But first, one must capture
the enemy leader to win.
I'm going to imprison you first,
then close down your Po Chi Lam.
Let's see how you can
still make trouble.
Many people were
hurt at the theater.
Let me help stop the bleeding,
then I'll go to the court with you.
OK, I'll allow you to save lives.
I'm sending troops to guard the door.
If there's any sound of activity, I'll
immediately have you beheaded in public.
Don't move,
the wound will bleed.
Ah So, bring the gold medicine.
What're you looking at?
Never seen a building closed?
Just close it, yeah?
Why are you carrying things away?
Take them back!
- You dare hit us?
- Get lost!
Are you free to
fight with people?
Master, they're looting.
I'm getting everything back.
So that's how it is?
You want to fight? I'll fight with you.
- OK, together.
- Halt! I'll fight you.
- Master, you fight with me?
- Where do you want to be hit?
Is it there?
You want me taken
to court earlier?
No? Then don't prevent
me from saving people.
Master!
You really exploited this opportunity
and took advantage of us.
Don't think we won't arrest
you if you get in the way.
This Porky guy seems to be smart.
That way he gets to escape his master.
Hit me.
You sure can stand it.
'Uncle' Cheng!
Can't stop the bleeding.
Quick, get the emergency medicine.
Emergency medicine!
He's stopped breathing.
Remember to inform his family.
Ah So...
Fei-Hung!
What's that mark?
It's Arabic numerals. 'Jackson'.
Could it be the name of Jackson's ship?
Don't be afraid.
I'm Wong Fei-Hung.
You've been hurt.
If you move, it will affect the wound.
You're... Master Wong?
Help me, help me...
Get up, get up first.
'Uncle', where did you come from?
- San Francisco.
- San Francisco?
We men were on a ship crossing the ocean.
Midway there was sickness, but no medicine.
Many men were thrown into
the ocean along the way.
In San Francisco, we were beaten, and
branded on the body just like pigs.
Actually, we were tricked by the Chinese
comprador into signing a contract.
Paid the fare, paid for the meals.
It's unclear how much we owe them.
Many men tried to escape,
but they were beaten to death.
I ground my teeth to
come back to Tangshan.
I... I... Master Wong...
Uncle, don't you worry.
You're back in Tangshan.
Yes, rest a while.
I'll think of a solution for you.
I'll take you home as soon as possible.
You rest first.
Ah Kai... don't make public that he
signed a contract with the foreigners.
- The court will arrest him.
- I understand.
It's better to go to San Francisco
than struggle here all my life.
Don't miss a good thing.
Don't miss the opportunity.
Come, take a look.
A flyer for you.
Hey, is this for San Francisco?
How do I go?
Just take a look and see.
Is it the San Francisco
the newspaper speaks of?
Yes, you want to go? Pay 300 silver dragons per
capita export fee and 40 taels for a ship ticket.
Provide your own luggage and rations,
and sign a three-year contract.
Almost two years' wages?
- Eh? You don't have money?
- No.
You've no money to go to San Francisco?
Next. Don't obstruct others.
You want a flyer? Hey, San Francisco,
San Francisco... plenty gold to be picked.
Hey, seems like there's a
duel over at the factory.
- A duel?
- Let's go.
Hey, don't leave!
You're a northerner performing martial
arts in front of my in-law's door.
I told you to go,
but you injured my apprentice.
- What's your name?
- Yim Chun-Tung.
Our family's Seven Swords method
has fought in nineteen provinces.
This time, I act as host, and
will permit you three moves.
Please advise.
Second move.
Master Ngok, it's not yet three
moves, and you draw your sword?
I fear another move would prove fatal.
Enough already.
Don't go!
Plot against me?
Iron Cloth?
I've granted you three moves.
Give it up.
There must be a hole.
- Why are you following me?
- My Name's Leung Foon, I come from Meixian.
Here in the capital there are
people from all walks of life.
My kung fu isn't perfect.
I've been pursued to the end of my rope.
I get beaten like a street rat
when trying to making a living.
Your kung fu's so good.
Take me as an apprentice.
Good kung fu...
It's not your place.
Likewise, I'm at the end of my rope.
Master... are you hungry?
First, find a place to avoid the rain.
I'll think of something.
Hey... give me a chicken leg.
I won't eat if it's
not good food...
Gentlemen, come in
and rest a while.
The soup's too salty.
Don't drink it. Let's go.
The soup's too salty...
and bitter.
Hey, why are you
stealing my bowl?
- Gentlemen, come in, have a drink.
- Come up, gentlemen, I'll sing to you.
Master, have a bowl of soup.
Two men drinking a bowl of soup.
How immoral!
- Godmother, do you want me to call out Ah GAN?
- Drive them away.
I'll make a name in Foshan, see
who dares look down on me then.
Yes, you must make a name.
Who's the most able fighter in the capital?
Is it Wong Fei-Hung?
- Fei-Hung!
- 13th Aunt.
You're right, Tangshan must change.
You can't beat a gun with a fist.
I've become a prisoner and may
be forced to stand and fight.
- You take care.
- Fei-Hung, I'll be waiting for you.
It's no use. If you do that,
even if I die, I won't die content.
You won't.
I'm a man of flesh and blood.
Go back.
Sai-Wing, he...
- Sai-Wing, it's raining hard. Go inside.
- Master didn't tell me, I daren't go in.
Sai-Wing.
- Go inside Po Chi Lam.
- Master.
Come, come in.
I, I...
Master, allow me.
Ah So, you...
The rain's coming down heavier.
This place is closed.
Go!
I'm Shandong's Iron
Cloth, Yim Chun-Tung.
I've come to Po Chi Lam to find Wong
Fei-Hung; to learn from Master Wong.
May I ask, which of
you is Wong Fei-Hung?
- Master, a challenger's come.
- Sai-Wing, pour some tea.
- Master!
- Pour tea!
Please...
- Ah Kai, go and take care of the patients.
- Alright.
Please sit.
Still haven't put
down the umbrella?
Please, some tea.
- Leung Foon, what the hell are you doing?
- Leung Foon?
The martial arts world's stories of
Master Wong's Hung Fist are well-known.
I hear Master Wong's Shadowless Kick
and Cross Fist are tremendous.
I, Yim Chun-Tung, intend to
establish a school in Foshan.
Today, I come to you for a duel.
To let all the local elders of Foshan know
that my Yim family martial arts is unmatched.
I'm being watched by the court.
I'm afraid our meeting could implicate you.
The future is long. Forgive me,
I can't accompany you today.
Martial arts practitioner?
You gutless old woman!
Master Yim!
I have too many patients here.
This isn't the place for a contest.
- Leung Foon!
- Sai-Wing, Ah Kai!
You want to be kicked out again?
- Don't just stand there.
- Master?
Take all the patients
to the back.
Uncle, I'll help you in.
They're about to fight.
Hey! What are you
doing with my patient?
Helping him in, lest he
gets beaten by my master.
How arrogant? If it hadn't been for
my master, I'd have beaten you up!
- You won't let go?
- I won't.
- Let him go! You let go!
- You let go!
- Fuck! Leung Foon!
- What?
You're still fooling around?
Yim, stop fighting!
If you keep fighting,
I'll shoot!
Hey, don't hurt my master.
Give it to me!
- Master! Master, are you alright?
- Master!
I, Iron Cloth Yim Chun-Tung,
am not afraid of western guns.
Wong Fei-Hung, today I won too easily.
It doesn't count.
Tomorrow, we rematch in the street.
Don't come, and the three words 'Wong
Fei-Hung' will be written on my soles.
Leung Foon!
You fucking bastard!
You traitor.
Speak Chinese... fake foreign devil.
- Are you OK?
- I'm fine. I suddenly slipped.
He wounded the guards.
The court will put this on my head.
Soldiers will be coming. Ah Wing, Ah Kai;
take some silver taels for travel expenses.
13th Aunt, go wake the 'uncle'
who came back from San Francisco.
Why are you still standing there?
Go one at a time.
You go with the uncle.
Ah So, I didn't teach you kung fu.
You're the most disadvantaged.
You don't have to wait.
- Just go.
- Mast...
- You take care.
- I'll see you off.
Hey, don't act recklessly!
- Master.
- Don't be impulsive.
Don't you worry, this
time I'll do as I'm told.
Ah Kai, tell 13th Aunt
to go with the 'uncle'.
I released the tiger back to the mountain so as to
catch the militia's remnants in one fell swoop.
- Search!
- Yes!
Wait! Inside are seriously injured patients.
Unable to move, they had to stay here.
I hope your Lordship doesn't disturb
them, lest their conditions worsen.
That's telling me not to go inside.
Obviously you're hiding something.
I just want to take advantage of you
unguarded to come and arrest people.
Come, see how many
militia there are here.
- Search for me!
- Yes!
Someone's climbing the wall.
Back off!
So, hurry up and go!
- Bring the fugitives back.
- Yes!
- Sai-Wing, still not doing it?
- Doing what, Master?
Sai-Wing, I told you to do it.
- Manchu dog!
- You curse me? How impudent!
Overlord Lifts Cauldron!
- You're really fighting?
- Yes!
Where's my gun?
Where are you going?
Running? Come back!
Cross Fist!
Shadowless Kick!
- Go after them!
- Yes!
You don't have to go.
The man you want to arrest is here.
- Separate and rush him.
- OK.
This way.
Hold the bamboo pole,
the others break through.
Wong Fei-Hung, this time we're going to convict
you of plotting rebellion. You're a dead man!
My Lord, I'll come back
to the court with you.
- Ah Kai!
- Master?
Take liniment and help Big Brother
apply it to the bailiffs' bruises.
Our Po Chi Lam liniment is most famous.
How many do you have here?
- My Lord, are you alright?
- You good-for-nothing!
Uncle, we're almost there.
Hold on.
With the western guns,
we can get whatever we want.
We need to find girls
for the foreign devil.
Sha... Shahe gang!
Go!
A woman!
Let go of Ah So!
Uncle, go by yourself first.
Don't let her go!
Go!
Let her go!
Uncle, take care of yourself.
There's too many, don't worry about me.
Die!
Go!
- Let me go!
- Go!
There's another one over there.
Grab him!
Catch him! Come back!
Fucking bastard!
You're just going to help me now?
- Punching Po Chi Lam.
- Kicking Wong Fei-Hung?
Master's been challenged.
Hey, tell your aunt not to cook yet.
We'll just wait here and watch.
- When do you think Master will come?
- Just wait and see.
Open your mouth wider.
Open the door.
Get lost, still playing?
Let's go!
Shoot me?
I'm sending you to San Francisco tonight!
You hate me, don't you?
I want to taste your flesh.
Do you want to add some seasoning?
When the time comes... and you're serving those
dirty, smelly yokels, you're going to miss me.
- Take her to my room.
- Yes!
Big Brother, the master who
beat Wong Fei-Hung has come.
Invite him in. That's great, from
now on we'll be the kings of Foshan.
Master...
You must now recognise him as your senior.
What can you do for him?
So, you're our senior?
Hey, call him Senior.
- Senior...
- Bullshit!
- OK, you flatter me...
- Remember, he's Senior.
Master, I have something to do tonight.
Don't take offence.
Tomorrow, I'll talk to you
about opening the school.
Bring out the gift.
Master Yim, this money
is to open your school.
Needless to say, Yim's Fist
will sweep across Foshan.
Come... let's raise a toast to Master.
- Good... Master Yim.
- Cheers...
Don't move!
What are you doing?
Master Wong, we brothers
all admire you as a person.
We know you were
harmed by bad guys.
Master Wong, we've
decided to let you out.
If anything happens, we
brothers will deal with it.
Master Wong, please...
That's great!
Let's go, Master.
Master?
The state has national laws.
What right do I have to change the rules?
- Go, Master!
- Master Wong, go!
I won't.
My Lord, I appreciate your good intention.
- W... W... Wong...
- Master Wong's over there.
Master! Mast... Master!
Master, you're still not leaving?
Ah So!
- Mast... Mast... Mast...
- Ah So? Speak slowly.
Master... I took the 'uncle' out with 13th
Aunt. On the way we ran into the Shahe gang.
They started by killing the 'uncle',
then snatched 13th Aunt.
- Find a way to save her.
- What?
Master, hurry up and save her.
- Porky Wing, I'll send a few militia to help.
- Good.
- Release them.
- Yes.
- Ah So, how come you can now talk plainly?
- I was rehearsing... all the way here...
Isn't that Wong Fei-Hung?
They're all militia.
Master, your kung fu's so powerful. Even
Wong Fei-Hung wasn't up to fighting you.
You have some moves to show us?
A couple of moves,
just a couple.
Wow!
That's great...
You bitch, you're dead!
Great! Great...
That's enough, Master.
Don't show off!
Master, don't show off.
What the hell?
Master, this money is dubious.
Think clearly about accepting it.
What? You're insulting us? What are
you doing? What do you mean by that?
- You've embarrassed our Shahe gang!
- Foon, in this world, what isn't unbearable?
Even so-called righteous men slaughter dogs.
Most important now is to achieve fame in Foshan.
At that time, we can stand up and
preside over justice for the world.
Just wait.
Leung Foon, pick up the money.
Pick it up!
Pick it up...
- You really think you're our senior?
- You're just a tramp!
Leung Foon!
Become famous?
Just wait, just wait...
Senior!
You rapist!
Eat shit!
13th Aunt, 13th Aunt...
Wake up, wake up...
- You beast, don't touch me!
- Don't make a noise, I'm saving you.
Leung Foon, it's you?
There's too many coming!
Go quickly.
Grab that woman!
Leung Foon, keep fighting...
and I'll kill this woman.
Be our senior?
Go to hell!
- Master, they're inside.
- Let's go see.
What's the matter?
Master, it wasn't long before Leung Foon came in,
saw my beautiful wife, and tried to seduce her.
- I'm not...
- Shut up!
Leung Foon, you brute!
Admit your mistake to your junior.
- Yim, we met at Po Chi Lam...
- Still talking, you whore? Go!
Want to rebel?
Don't be so blind.
She's not his wife.
- Blind?
- She's a relative of Wong Fei-Hung.
Wong Fei-Hung?
- Leung Foon wants to escape.
- Escape?
You're daring!
- Don't go!
- Grab him!
- Careful!
- Yes, Big Brother!
- It hurts.
- Yes, yes...
Master, it's they who are driving me out.
Sooner or later, they'll do this to you.
You mustn't trust them!
One who doesn't trust his fellow students
still wants to invoke the name Wong?
What's up? Distressed?
Can't watch anymore?
If you let him go, I promise
I'll do what you want.
Is he worth your sacrifice?
So low as to bargain with me?
Fuck your ancestors!
So you're Wong Fei-Hung's woman?
When I'm done messing with your face, Wong
Fei-Hung won't ever be able to find you.
The woman you captured today,
where is she?
- Big Brother! Big Brother, Wong Fei-Hung is here!
- Wong Fei-Hung?
- Quick, get the weapons.
- Yes!
- Take out the western guns.
- OK!
Go, put the women on the ship.
Master, Wong Fei-Hung's here to attack
our base. I need you to stand up to him.
Don't worry.
- Leung Foon!
- Let's go!
13th Aunt! 13th Aunt!
Come on!
Hey, let's watch Master
Yim catch Wong Fei-Hung.
- I'll handle this, you split up to find 13th Aunt.
- Yes.
Wong Fei-Hung!
Master Yim, win or lose the contest,
there's no need to make a fuss.
Today you've got no
excuse not to fight.
I'll take you on.
They're down there.
- Hard qigong?
- Only one of us can get out.
How does this western gun work?
Don't be afraid, we have guns.
You're not able to fight?
Come out, come out...
Master, let me help you.
Porky Wing!
Porky Wing?
Is there anymore above?
Ah So, it's you?
Quick, come up and let me down. Hurry up!
13th Aunt's been taken on board by members
of the Shahe gang. Hurry up and save her.
13th Aunt's been taken on board
by members of the Shahe gang.
Hey, don't go! You haven't let me down yet!
Toothbrush So!
My Lord.
My Lord, it's too dangerous here.
You better hide first. Come on.
Militia brothers, charge in!
- Senior, how's it going?
- Ah Kai, I'll help Master, you save 13th Aunt.
No, I won't. I'll stay here and
help Master. You go save 13th Aunt.
I'm senior, I say forget it.
You go quick...
Neither of you need stay behind.
Just go and save 13th Aunt.
Still here?
Wong Fei-Hung!
This technique is self-defence.
Is this the Yim family's
martial arts also?
The world is dangerous,
one must guard against it.
Hurry up, the ship is leaving.
Take them aboard.
- Let's go, bitch!
- Fei-Hung! Fei-Hung, it's 13th Aunt! Fei-Hung!
Fei-Hung! Fei-Hung,
it's 13th Aunt! Fei-Hung!
- Take her aboard. Let's go, bitch!
- Fei-Hung! Fei-Hung!
Mr Jackson, Master Wong is here!
Wong Fei-Hung, go deal with him.
The ship's over there.
Hung, take all the women
down to the ship's hold.
Go down.
Hurry up!
Over... over there.
Wong... Wong Fei...
Master Yim, our fight is done.
Master Wong, be careful there!
Wong Fei-Hung, where are you?
We haven't finished the fight yet.
Master!
- I'm Iron Cloth...
- Master Yim! Master Yim!
- Wong Fei-Hung...
- Master Yim!
- Our kung fu is no match for their guns.
You fucking bastard!
Wong Fei-Hung, don't run!
Don't shoot!
- Leung Foon!
- Kill him!
Be careful!
The great Wong Fei-Hung.
Come over if you have the guts.
Fei-Hung, he's got
a gun on his knife.
- Be careful, don't fall into his trap.
- Shut up!
Bitch, you drew them here. I'll burn
your face so there's no need to fight.
Wong Fei-Hung, are you
quicker than my gun?
I'll burn you to death!
Let me go!
My Lord... Mr Jackson and the Shahe gang conspired
to snatch women and sell them to San Francisco.
My Lord, help us.
Brothers of the Shahe gang,
help me capture all the women.
There will be rewards.
Under the law, an ambassador must be turned
over to the Qing Empire for punishment.
- You're now violating international law.
- Put the guns down!
- Why won't it 'bang'?
- Did we forget to put the iron balls in?
If you don't put the
guns down, I'll kill him!
Put the guns down!
Although this is a restricted area,
you've hurt an imperial ambassador.
How will you explain
it to the government?
Chinese ghosts.
I can't let anyone go.
If all the dead are rebels against the US flag,
what do I have to explain to the government?
- Fucking bastards!
- You don't have to explain!
- My Lord...
- Wow, you dare jump so high?
A trivial matter,
a minor accomplishment.
Thank you, My Lord...
This time, Master Wong and
the court worked together.
- You're welcome...
- Now thank Master Wong.
Thanks, Master Wong!
Tangshan has changed so much.
How can I deal with it?
San Francisco?
Is there a 'San Francisco' in this world?
If there's really a 'Gold Mountain' in the world,
why are these foreign ships coming to our harbor?
Maybe we're already
standing on Gold Mountain?
After this cup of tea,
you'll be my master.
But 13th Aunt and I now
have a close relationship.
We'll see each other
all the time.
If one day she marries me,
will you call me 13th Uncle?
I'll be your elder.
As senior, you have to serve me.
Leung Foon,
what are you thinking?
Drink tea, Master!