15...
14...
- 13...
- 12...
- Stand up straight.
- 11.
- Ten.
- Stand up.
- Nine.
- Only fucking pussy little girls slouch.
- Seven.
- 43...
- Six...
- 42...
- Five...
- 41...
- Four...
- 40...
- Three...
- 39...
- Two...
- 38...
- One.
- 37.
You must do better. You must do better!
Say it.
I must do better, sir.
Ah!
The tomatoes go in the refrigerator
and the bananas go in the fruit bowl.
I do some of the grocery shopping,
and always do the tomatoes first.
We don't ask for information.
You say that's it?
That's the only problem.
People will do that, the tomato crop,
tomato prices will be part of the deal.
Well, I thought that they'll have
a much better product, yeah.
But this lot will grow in the back yard,
pick 'em whenever you want.
If you want to eat tomatoes
12 months out of the year,
you're gonna have to pick 'em
at one of these two stations.
What the hell's wrong with you?
Airport.
Wake Me
♪ Come with me
♪ Be anywhere you like with me
♪ Wake me with your warm arms
♪ Let me hear your voice
♪ Hold me, hold me near you
♪ It's your choice, oh, Lord
- Hello. You've reached...
- John McCleary.
After the tone, please leave a message.
It's done.
Just go inside.
- What?
- Go inside. Just go, just go.
$300? You parasite!
Mom, I'm back.
50, 60, 70,
75.
I'm not wealthy.
I'm just a woman with $75.
Hey.
Excited to see me, huh?
You actually got me.
- I got you.
- Yeah, pretty good.
Got you, got you!
What is this shit you're watching?
Oh...
Psycho was on today.
- Yeah.
That scared me. Oh, boy, it scared me.
Then why are you watching it alone?
I don't know. I should've waited for you.
Ohh...
- Joe?
- Yeah?
Would you just stay a little bit?
Just stay.
- Okay.
- Just...
Cos you watched some scary, fucking movie?
Just till I've finished the movie.
Joe?
Uh?
Mom?
Yeah?
I can't turn the tap off!
Oh, I don't have any of the...
I can't find anything.
- What are you looking for?
- I can't find my toothbrush.
It's right behind the mirror.
Wait...
Oh, oh, okay.
Mom? Come on!
- Let's go. I'm opening.
- No, no, no, no! Stop that!
- Just let me...
- I'm opening the door.
No, no, no!
What are you doing?
What are you fucking around with?
- There's water everywhere!
- I'm not fucking around!
You are! There's nothing.
You keep rearranging... Get out.
I need my space!
- Your what?
- My space.
Al right. Go get your space downstairs.
Okay, I just needed that...
Are you sure
you can get downstairs al right?
What? Yeah.
Yeah, if I do it really slow.
I know what to do.
The man called.
Said he wants to see you, right away.
Did your son tell you that he saw me?
Hey, he was... with a friend, you know.
It's just... just a coincidence, man.
Did he tell you where he saw me?
No.
No, I...
I know you wouldn't want me to know, man.
Moises didn't mean to see you, Joe. He...
Don't yell at me.
He's just a stupid freaking kid.
- I know, but...
- He...
We're done, Angel.
Joe, he didn't mean to see you.
Al right.
Take the money.
♪ J...
♪ We're like Jack and Jill
♪ K, you're so kissable
♪ L
♪ Is the love light in your eyes
♪ M, N, O, P
♪ I could go on all day
Yes, you could.
♪ Q, R, S, T
♪ Alphabetically speaking...
♪ You're okay
♪ You make my life complete
♪ V means you're very sweet
♪ W, X, Y, Z
- Mom...
- What?
This fridge is disgusting.
- What's wrong?
- You got...
And all this shit's rotten.
Well, honey, what are you looking for?
This cream cheese is from 1972.
I use it. Just leave it.
- How's Janice?
- Who's Janice?
Oh, come on. You know who Janice is.
You mean my girlfriend from 20 years ago?
She would've been a good mom.
Stop it!
Joe?
Coming!
Going up?
What's all this?
That Cincinnati kid.
Parents are florists.
A warm thank you for getting
their darling daughter back home safe.
Flowers.
Josephine loved flowers.
I could never see the point myself.
The fuckers die anyway
and stink up the whole damn place.
God bless her.
Hey, um...
Listen, we gotta lose Angel's number.
- I'll find a new service.
- Okay.
No problem.
So, Angel's out.
You could uh... just call me directly,
you know, like a normal person.
There's no green ones.
- I like green.
- Hm.
Fucking ass hole!
Why am I here?
State Senator Albert Votto.
I ran his father's security
back in the '80s.
Lost track of him after his arraignment.
I found a green one.
The wife - Votto Junior's wife -
kills herself a couple of years ago.
Their teenage daughter's
been running away from home ever since.
I'm listening.
Votto calls me this morning.
She's been missing all weekend.
He doesn't make it the cops involved
now that he's running
on Governor Williams's ticket.
Ahh!
He's paying 50 grand cash.
What's the lead?
He got an anonymous text with an address.
Meet him at the Union Club, 2pm.
Josephine II is coming out of dry dock,
thanks to this.
I'm gonna drive her through the harbor
with a big fucking fireworks display.
You, me, couple of steaks,
cold beers, setting sun...
What do you say to that?
What?
235 East 31st Street.
That's what the text said.
You have kids, Joe?
No.
Nina.
Her name is Nina.
I've heard of these places...
Under-age girls.
Senator, if she's there,
I'll get her.
McCleary said you were brutal.
I can be.
Gonna need this.
Be at this address, 3am.
Hotel Caribe, room 701.
I want you to hurt them.
- Keys.
- Have a nice day.
What are you doing?
Would you mind taking a picture for us?
What?
Would you mind taking a picture of us?
Thank you so much.
What the fuck are we doing?
Go, go!
He doesn't know...
He has no idea.
I've been waiting for you for 20 minutes.
Relax, man, relax. Chill the fuck up.
Don't make me late!
Run! Run!
Shut the fuck up.
♪ A You're adorable
♪ B You're so beautiful
♪ C You're a cutie full of charms
♪ D You're delightful and...
♪ E You're exciting and...
♪ F You're a feather in my arms
♪ 106.79 FM
From Times Square to the
South Street Seaport, I'm Chris Conley.
Here is Bon Jovi, Livin' On A Prayer.
- What the fuck are we doing?
- Wait. Nobody move till we see the money.
Go, go!
Hey, excuse me?
Do you know where 239 West is?
Argh!
Shh, shh, shh. Relax.
What's your name?
Scott.
I'm Mr. Rogers.
Listen, I'm gonna ask you some questions.
Please be honest with me.
Right, security - how many are there?
Huh? So one? More than one?
- Two, three? Come on, talk.
- Two.
Two? Where?
Where in the house are they?
One guy inside the front door.
The second guy on the top floor.
Where's the playground?
Playground?
- The under-age girls?
- Third floor.
I just...
I just work here. I just run errands.
I don't...
They're freaks, man.
It's okay.
Do you carry keys? No?
What's the code of the front door?
- 439.
- What is it?
Promise you won't kill me.
What's the fucking code?
4392.
Good boy.
Please.
Angel Baby
♪ It's just like heaven
♪ Being here with you
♪ You're like an angel
♪ Too good...
♪ To be true
♪ But...
♪ I do
♪ Angel baby
♪ My angel baby
♪ When you are near me
♪ My heart...
♪ My heart skips a beat
♪ Can hardly stand on
♪ My own two feet
♪ Because...
♪ Because I love you
♪ I love you
♪ I... I do
♪ Angel baby
♪ My angel baby
♪ Ooh, I love you
♪ Ooh, I do
♪ No one could love you
♪ Like I do
♪ Oooooh
♪ Oooh
35, 34, 33...
♪ Please never leave me
- 32, 31, 30...
♪ Blue and alone
- 29, 28, 27...
♪ If you ever go
- 26, 25...
♪ I'm sure you'll come back home
- 24, 23...
- Nina?
- Nina Votto?
- 22...
- 21, 20...
- My name is Joe.
- 19...
- I'm here to take you out of this place.
- Get up. Can you hear me?
♪ My angel baby
My name's Joe. Come here.
Oh!
Don't move. Don't move.
It's okay.
It's okay, come here. Come here.
Turn around. Turn around.
Stay there.
- Six, five, four...
♪ Because I love you
Three, two,
one.
Don't move.
♪ My angel baby
♪ Oooh
♪ Whispering promises in my ear
♪ He said he'd always be true to me
♪ To help him as I see
♪ I felt my world spinning round and round
♪ Around the wonderful love I'd found
Close your eyes.
♪ He held me and we kissed
49, 48, 47...
46, 45, 44...
43, 42...
41, 40...
Hey, you want something to drink?
I got you some water and some sodas.
Thirsty?
Yeah, I wouldn't touch that. It's gross.
Al right.
It's okay. It's okay.
No, no, no. No.
You don't have to do that.
I'm taking you home to your dad.
And we just have to wait here
a little while longer.
No, no, no.
I have to go.
What's your name?
Joe.
I'm finished now, Joe.
The Pacific Ocean.
Do you know what the Mexicans say
about the Pacific?
They say it has no memory.
That's where I want
to live the rest of my life.
Hey, don't worry,
your dad's gonna be here soon.
Are you al right?
Yes, sir.
Take my guests out charter fishing.
Zihuatanejo.
27-year-old passer-by Rebecca Couran
saw the body fall in front of the hotel.
He just stood there
for a second and then he stepped off.
Senator Votto's body was discovered
beneath the Tower Hotel
in mid-town Manhattan,
after he apparently leapt from a suite
on the 22nd floor.
Senator Votto was in the city campaigning
for Governor Williams
in next month's gubernatorial elections.
It's okay. Okay. Come here. Look at me.
He climbed up on the ledge, stood
there for a second, then stepped off.
Votto had been dogged
with rumors of sexual misconduct...
We got him.
Joe!
Cute.
Man... you think I don't know
what the fuck's going on here?
I'm just a hired gun.
I don't give a shit about...
..this is a complete smear campaign,
pure integrity...
Hello.
You have reached John McLeary.
After the tone, please leave a message.
John, you there? Pick up.
Pick up! John!
What the fuck is going on?
Hello, you have reached...
John McLeary.
After the tone, please leave a message.
John, pick up the fucking phone, man.
They fucking shot me, man.
They shot me in the face.
Where's your papa?
Huh?
Dumb fucker.
You have reached...
John!
Get out of the fucking way!
- Mummy.
- Sshh.
After The Lovin'
♪ So I sing you to sleep...
Who killed my mother?
Was it you or the other guy?
Where are you going?
You don't know?
Who are you?
You're in my fucking house.
Fuck!
Fuck.
Here. take this.
- Want some more?
- Uh-uh.
Al right.
So you killed Votto?
They killed Votto, is that what it is?
The Air That I Breathe
♪ ..is the air that I breathe
♪ And to love you
I don't want it out.
♪ All I need is the air that I breathe
There's always crying.
All of it is...
Okay.
♪ All I need is the air that I breathe
Hey, where is she?
Where is Nina now?
Williams.
Governor Williams?
She's his favorite.
He trades them.
I've Never Been To Me
♪ And I showed 'em what I've got
♪ I've been undressed by kings
♪ And I've seen some things
♪ That a woman ain't supposed to see
♪ Do you know what paradise is?
♪ It's a lie, a fantasy we create about
people and places as we'd like them to be
Was my mother afraid?
♪ It's that little baby you're holding
and it's the man you fought with
She was sleeping.
♪ The same one you're going
to make love with tonight
♪ That's truth, that's love
♪ Sometimes I've been to crying
♪ For unborn children:
♪ That might have made me complete
♪ But I took the sweet life
♪ And never knew I'd be bitter
♪ From the sweet
♪ I've spent my life exploring
♪ That cost too much to be free
♪ Hey, lady, I've been to paradise
♪ But I've never been to me
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ I've been to paradise
♪ I've been to Georgia and California
What are you doing?
40, 39, 38, 37, 36,
35, 34, 33, 32...
..31, 30, 29, 28, 27,
26, 25, 24, 23, 22,
21, 20, 19, 18, 17,16...
Nine...
..eight, seven, six,
five, four, three...
..probably a $50 cab fare.
Angel Baby
♪ It's just like heaven
♪ Being here with you
♪ You're like an angel
♪ Too good...
♪ Because I love you
♪ Please never leave me
♪ Blue and alone
♪ If you ever go
♪ I'm sure you'll come back home
♪ Because I love you
♪ I love you, I do
♪ Angel baby
♪ My angel baby
♪ It's just like heaven
♪ Being with you, dear
♪ I could never stay
♪ Away without you near
♪ Because I love you
♪ I love you, I do
♪ Angel baby
♪ My angel baby
♪ Ooh, I love you
♪ Ooh, I do
♪ No one could love you
♪ Like I do
♪ Oooh-ooh-ooh-ooh
I'm weak. I'm weak. I'm weak.
It's okay, Joe.
It's okay.
♪ If I knew you were coming,
I'd have baked a cake
♪ Hired a band, goodness' sake
♪ If I knew you were coming,
I'd have baked a cake
♪ How do you do,
how do you do, how do you do?
Where are we going?
Well...
We can go wherever you want.
Where do you want to go?
I-I don't know.
I don't know either.
♪ Baked a cake, baked a cake
♪ If I knew you were coming,
I'd have baked a cake
♪ How do you do,
how do you do, how do you do?
♪ Had you dropped me a letter,
I'd have hired a band
♪ Grandest band in the land
♪ Had you dropped me a letter,
I'd have hired a band
♪ And spread the welcome mat for you
♪ Oh, I don't know where you came from
♪ Cos I don't know where you've been
♪ But it really doesn't matter,
grab your chair and fill a platter
♪ And dig, dig, dig right in
♪ If I knew you were coming,
I'd have baked a cake
♪ Hired a band, goodness' sake...
Well, you look great.
Excuse me,
could I get a little bit of butter?
You know you're not supposed
to have butter.
How do you know
I'm not supposed to have it?
We all know you're
not supposed to have it.
Have a nice day.
Hey.
Joe? Wake up.
What?
Let's go.
It's a beautiful day.
It is a beautiful day.
♪ If I knew you were coming,
I'd have baked a cake
♪ Baked a cake, baked a cake
♪ If I knew you were coming,
I'd have baked a cake
♪ How do you do,
how do you do, how do you do?