'Norman Stanley Fletcher,
'you have pleaded guilty and
it is now my duty to pass sentence.
'You are a criminal who accepts
arrest as an occupational hazard,
'and presumably accepts imprisonment
in the same casual manner.
'We therefore commit you
to the maximum term
allowed for these offences.
'You will go to prison
for five years.'
# 'David Hamilton!
The happy sound of Radio One! #
'Here's a request from Bridget
in Dundee for Ricky, who has blue
eyes and looks like David Essex!
'Bridget is 16,
'works in a cake factory, and
her job is to spot flawed almonds.
'She met Ricky briefly at a dance
last summer on the Ayrshire coast.
'All she knows is that
he's from Glasgow...'
..And his hobby is beating up
lavatory attendants!
I'm listening to that!
And I'M not! Sentimental slush!
I have to listen
to Friday Night Is Music Night!
And I sit through Rosko! But
I draw the line at David Hamilton!
The wireless is never off
in this nick.
They're piping Tony Blackburn
into the kitchens.
Yes, they believe we're in prison
to be punished.
Anyway, I wanted to hear
the request slot - "Hello,
Young Lovers" corner. Oh, yeah?
I sent a request in for Denise.
Denise? My fiancee.
Oh, that Denise.
I wanted to express
my feelings of undying love.
I asked for "Everlasting Love".
You should have asked
for "My Ding-A-Ling" (!)
I've listened all week and it ain't
been on. You'd think MY needs were
greater than some almond sorter's.
Did you write on prison notepaper?
Yeah, you had my last sheet
of Basildon Bond. That's it then.
Are they biased against prisoners?!
Not officially, but I can't recall
hearing a prisoner's request.
Forces, yes, and ack-ack batteries,
but never no-one from no nick, no.
We have a bad enough time
without having requests denied!
That's discrimination!
AND five stamps up the spout.
You can see their point of view.
The public are bound
to take offence.
You're all listening to "Family
Favourites", and they read a
postcard with a Parkhurst postmark!
"Can 'Mad Dog' Hollister
have Clair de Lune?"
Clair de Lune?
Yes, that's French for
"by the light of the silvery moon".
I thought it might be
a cultural conversation. Hey,
maybe you can tell us the ruling.
Ruling, Godber?
Yeah, Miss Lonely Loins here...
..wants to know whether the BBC
ever play prisoners' requests.
No. The answer to that is no -
it could cause embarrassment.
Embarrassment?
The prisoner's family might
have excused his absence
by saying that he was abroad,
or working on an oil-rig.
Oh, I see. No doubt your wife,
Fletcher, has told your friends
you are on a five-year safari (!)
No, she just says I'm doing
missionary work in Scotland.
The practice was also open to abuse.
There was nothing to stop prisoners
sending messages in code
across our airwaves.
Oh, yeah. That is a point, innit?
Some heart-warming
Christmas message from an old lag
to his wife and family, eh?
"Can we have Harry Secombe
singing The Impossible Dream?"
He really meant, "Be outside E-wing
with a ladder on Boxing Day...
and a mince pie."
Good idea.
It's an abuse of privilege, which
is why I'm here. Not a social call?
Six soft toilet rolls
have disappeared
from the Governor's closet -
his personal water-closet.
Would you Adam and Eve it?
Whatever next?
Knowing you, probably the seat.
Don't look at ME, sir.
Nor me. It's writing-paper I'M
short of. It's not right. We've had
to give him prison-issue tissue.
That's rough (!)
Rough, yeah!
I'll say it is.
That'll wipe the smile off his face!
Fortune has given you two
privileged positions here.
Don't jeopardise them
by any infraction of the rules.
I'll say no more.
Thank you. Thanks for the advice.
To which we'll pay great heed.
Now naff off.
Certainly! Certainly!
He's always picking on us. It's his
suspicious mind, the nosey nerk.
Care for a glass of toilet roll?
You've got one!
Yeah. I did have six.
Where's the other five? I traded
them. Who to? There are still a few
felons with a bit of refinement.
There are two embezzlers
on the bottom landing.
There's an unfrocked dentist
and a lot of white-collar felons
who'd jump at this sort of stuff.
What do you get?
I'm owed some nice merchandise.
I'm promised a cricket sweater,
a pair of Hush Puppies
and a box of after-dinner mints.
Hey... What? Share and share alike!
What? It's a rule of the house,
isn't it?
Share my toilet roll?
It's only fair.
Share my toilet roll, Godber?!
Look at all these socks I've darned!
All right.
Mind how you go!
Hello, Dad! Hello, Ingrid, love.
Hey, Fletch, this is me mum.
Pleased to meet you, Mr Fletcher.
The pleasure's mine.
This is my eldest, Ingrid.
Sit down, Fletcher! And you, Godber!
This isn't a royal garden party,
you know!
Who's he? That's Mr Mackay.
Charmless Celtic nerk!
Who's the boy?
Eh? Oh, that's Lennie Godber -
my temporary cell-mate.
He's from Birmingham,
but he has got O-level geography.
You need it
to get around Birmingham.
How's your mother?
Oh, she's fine. She sends her love.
Oh, good.
How's your sister?
Marion's fine. She's got a new job!
Can't she keep a job
for more than three weeks?
The bosses molest her, she alleges.
She flaunts herself, don't she?
Skirts right up to her expectations.
Where is she now? Timothy Whites.
They won't molest her there -
they're all qualified pharmacists.
Her flat fell through. What flat?
The one she shared with six people.
Six! Fell through the floor,
I should think!
No, the rent went up,
so she's home, pro tem.
How's young Raymond? Fine! He won
the mile in the school sports.
Did he? Ah.
If I had, I might not be here now.
He swims for the school and he's
the stage manager in the school play.
Why isn't he in it? He played
Yum-Yum in the Mikado last year.
His voice has gone. Oh.
Well, he's on 30 a day. He's what?!
He's only 14!
30 a day! That's terrible!
That's a dreadful waste of money.
He saves the coupons!
That's OK then (!)
He wants an aqualung.
He'll need one if he has 30 a day!
He wants to go skin-diving
in St Ives.
It's all extra-curricular. Don't he
fancy anything INSIDE the classroom?
Mostly the girls, Dad!
'Ere, I don't want him getting
no girl into trouble!
Well, if YOU hadn't,
I wouldn't be here!
We don't want any coarse remarks
of that nature!
I can't believe my ears
when I hear kids today!
There's nothing wrong! You and Mum
have proved your love wasn't
an infatuation... Silver wedding!
I still don't want my love-life to
be a yardstick! Raymond's only 14!
When what happened
happened to your mother and me,
we were mature 16-year-olds.
In Highgate Cemetery, it was.
But WE had something behind us.
The tomb of Karl Marx.
No, but your mum had
a nice, steady job in Gamages,
and I had my plastering diploma
from borstal.
Talking of Highgate Cemetery, how's
YOUR love-life? Oh, least said...
Is it still Eddie Risley?
I've warned you about him.
He's a crook!
He's straight, Dad! He's just
a tough businessman. Yeah (!)
It isn't fair, people saying
he'd sell his own mother.
I heard that. Who from?!
The two blokes
who bought his mother.
It's no good talking to you.
You've got a blind spot about him.
So have you.
Giving you a bad time, isn't he?
I don't know where I am with him.
You don't half pick 'em, do you?
You're a bonny girl. You could have
anyone you wanted, you could.
And also, you're not
getting any younger - 24.
That's not old! It is
for a teenager! And a spinster!
Oh, Dad! Things have changed
since your day! Girls don't want
to be tied down so quick.
They see alternatives to marriage.
Not in Muswell Hill, they don't.
They've twinned the Odeon!
I'm talking about moral standards!
What do social commentators know?
Nothing about the real world!
They all live in NW1! Never been
further north than Hampstead or
further south than Sloane Square!
In the REAL world,
Birmingham, Muswell Hill...
Are you wearing a bra?
I don't need to, Dad!
What do you mean?
My breasts are firm and pliant.
Please, Ingrid!
This isn't St Tropez!
It's Slade bleeding Prison!
The men here would go berserk
at the sight of a shin,
never mind unfettered knockers!
Dad!
I'm sorry, but it has to be said.
You are very naive
about the effect your body
can have on a shackled male.
Dad, YOU are naive in some ways.
I'm sure no-one's even noticed!
Godber?
Godber!
GODBER!
What?! What? Are you awake?
What's the matter?
You got any snout?
No. Would you believe it? Yeah,
I would, you inconsiderate nerk!
I thought you'd given up!
I felt like starting again.
Mind your head.
Me mum bought me some Maltesers.
No, thanks. And cake. No, thanks!
If you haven't got snout, go back
to sleep! Thanks, you old scrote!
What's the matter, anyway?
I've got things on my mind.
Like what? MY business!
Oh, come on. You've woken me up now.
I just get depressed at times,
that's all. Stinking stir!
KICKS TABLE
That's not like you, Fletch.
A father's place is with his kids,
giving them affection and guidance.
I've got three, you know.
Yeah, I know. 14, 19 and 24.
Why the gap between each?
Circumstances dictated that.
How? Well, I had to keep going
in prison for five years, didn't I?
Teens is a terrible age -
you expect trouble.
But you'd think my Ingrid would
have learnt a few lessons by now.
She seemed a nice girl to me.
She had lovely...
I know what she had lovely!
I'm her father. Be careful, Godber!
Eyes! I was gonna say eyes.
Lovely eyes. Big and blue.
Oh, yeah. And a nice smile,
which seemed to indicate
a warm nature. True, true.
I hope you don't mind me
saying this...
..but I couldn't help overhearing
a bit of what you said.
Most of us did.
Oh, yeah?
This Eddie don't seem
good enough for her. He's not.
He says he's in the motor trade -
he forges car log-books.
Not that SHE'D believe it.
How can YOU be sure?
I bought two off him.
They weren't much cop either.
He spelt Citroen with an S.
Well, I shouldn't worry too much.
He'll get rumbled, and that'll
give her time to find someone new.
And I should think young Marion
will settle down now
at Timothy Whites.
Don't worry about Raymond -
I smoked at 14. And congratulations
on your silver wedding.
Did you earwig ALL my conversation?
Why didn't you talk to your mother?
It's a long schlep from Birmingham!
She's doesn't have much to say -
just a list of family ailments.
No news of Denise? She don't talk
about Denise - she don't approve.
Why not? She uses green
nail-varnish and doesn't wear a bra.
Her and Ingrid have a lot in common.
Your Ingrid's got nicer knockers!
Fletcher, could I have a word?
I'm playing draughts.
It IS important.
I wouldn't ask otherwise.
So is THIS, innit?
Duty calls.
We'll have to call it a draw.
Half each.
Sorry to disturb you in association
hour. That's OK. It's only draughts.
Not your game as a rule, is it? No.
There's not much else to do now.
Look at the Ping-Pong ball.
Oh, I am sorry! It is a mess. Yeah.
Anyhow, I wanted a quiet word.
I'm all ears.
Do you know where Godber is?
He'll be at one of his poxy evening
classes. Tuesday - woodwork.
He's up in front of the Governor.
Is he? The lad? What's he done?
He's attacked a prisoner in the
kitchen. He attacked Jackdaw with
a soup ladle. I don't believe it!
It's quite true! It was a severe and
unprovoked attack, the officer said.
I don't believe it! I know
Jackdaw gets on everybody's nerves,
but Lennie's a passive sort of boy.
He wouldn't hurt a fly!
I thought you might throw some light
on the matter.
I dunno... He seemed
his usual self this morning.
At lunchtime he was cheerful.
But Mr Pringle did slip on a bit
of orange peel and hurt his back,
so we was ALL cheerful.
Fletcher! Be serious!
Godber is in trouble!
It's so irrational, you see.
I like that lad, you know.
I think he shows a lot of promise.
It's the system, innit?
It's turning an affable young lad
into a violent criminal!
You're sitting on a volcano
which could at any time
erupt into violence and mayhem!
Fletcher, you've got your finger
on the pulse. How can we avert this?
Well, there is one thing you could
do to postpone the holocaust.
What? You could indent for
another Ping-Pong ball. Fletcher!
Well then?
Well then, what? I heard.
Heard what? I heard you hit Jackdaw
with a ladle.
Heard right then, didn't you?
Must've had your reasons. I did.
Ain't you going in the cooler then?
No. Lucky lad! Lucky, am I?!
Yeah! Assault, innit,
ladling a fellow prisoner?!
Automatic cooler offence, ladling.
I just got loss of privileges, due
to the mitigating circumstances.
You must have had
mitigating circumstances!
Look, you don't HAVE to tell me.
You don't HAVE to say what drove
you to launch into Jackdaw with
a deadly weapon, to wit, one ladle!
I won't then. I'd rather not.
Oh, I see.
I see!
It hasn't occurred to you that your
hitherto blameless record is due
in no small part to yours truly.
I'm only the guy who showed you
the ropes, kept you on the rails,
loaned you his soft toilet-paper!
I'm not ungrateful! Every time
I go to the bog, I'm not ungrateful.
Having eavesdropped into MY private
life, don't you think it's time
I knew something about yours?!
I got bad news!
Jackdaw took the mick, so I hit him
when my mind was disturbed!
News? Yeah!
What news?!
Oh.
It's a Dear John letter. In my case
it's Dear Lennie. Naturally.
Yours, but not forever, Denise, eh?
That's right.
So it's the DEMISE of Denise!
That's not funny, Fletcher!
Was that a joke?
Not what I call a joke!
Don't you think I've seen it happen
hundreds of times? It's inevitable.
At least she's honest. They're all
at it like knives while we're here!
But her main concern
in her last letter was whether
to get a budgerigar or a canary!
In your future life together?
Yeah.
One decision you won't have to make.
I suppose not.
Look, I know it's only
academic now, but...
..speaking personally,
from personal experience...
..I would say that always,
by and large...
..I would plump
for a budgerigar.
Oh.
Why? They're more friendly,
and canaries are prone to draughts,
you know.
I think it's the angle of the tail.
I speak from experience,
'cos we had a canary once.
Surly little bleeder!
As you say, it's academic.
Yeah. He's dead now.
So, Denise has had... Someone's...
There's another man, is there?
Do you know him?
His name's Kenneth.
He's in the merchant navy,
so there's no contest.
I see. Jolly Jack Tar,
the sailor with the navy-blue eyes
and all the gold braid?
Sun shines out of his port-hole,
I know.
Don't worry, it's only temporary.
Once he's at sea,
you'll be out with Denise,
and he'll be up the Persian Gulf.
Then you can just assume your
rightful place in her affections.
It's just temporary.
I don't think so. No sweat.
She's married him.
She's what?
Last Saturday.
She thought I should know.
Married him.
The Cross Keys did them proud -
pate and salad.
Well, I'm appalled.
I don't know what to say.
Pate and salad!
Mum's coming next month.
She would have come today,
only the doctor forbade it.
He said she'd be a fool to herself.
Nothing serious?
Just something going round.
Marion ain't with Timothy Whites
no longer.
Ain't she? Dispensed
with her services, have they?
She's got a job selling shirts.
She shows them round the offices.
Makes a change
from showing her knickers.
She's found another flat
in Maida Vale,
and what you'll be most glad to hear
is that me and Eddie have split up.
Have you? Not before time, girl!
That's a great relief to us all.
Yeah, we was very worried
about that liaison.
Do you mind?! Get on
with your own visit, please!
Sorry, Mrs Godber. Haven't you got
any news from the home front, dear?
Well, I can't think
of anything to say. It's like
visiting people in hospital.
Force yourself, love.
Here, here, here!
He does bird impressions.
You all know the procedure!
Conversation will be confined to
the person opposite the prisoner.
There will be no fratricide here.
That's what I told him.
So if you'll excuse us, Godber...
Sorry, Fletch. Sorry, miss.
That's all right.
So, you've given Eddie the big E.
That's good.
Stick to what I tell you
in future, right?
I do! Ain't you noticed how discreet
I am today? What do you mean?
Last time I embarrassed you,
so this time I've given you no cause.
I don't get you.
Oh, Dad, look! I'm wearing a bra!
Look at that, look at that!
What? It's a Ping-Pong ball, innit?
Two-star!
You don't play!
I don't, but some nerks here do!
Ping-Pong balls are scarce. I'll
get four ounces of snout for this!
Look at that!
Fletch... Yeah?
Can I ask you something?
# Feel free! #  No, no, no! What?
You know when I was worried
after that letter about the stigma
of being an ex-con? Yeah.
Do you think it'll be hard
working my way back into society?
Depends on the breaks.
Did YOU have any difficulty?
No, I've never had any trouble,
'cos I always go straight.
Straight back into crime.
But with you it's different. You're
young. You've got an honest face.
Is that enough? Yeah, I think so.
Character, that's what
you've got. Character.
You're a good lad.
So you think then, that if a girl
cared for me, she'd forgive
my past misdemeanours?
Yeah, if she's a human being.
Any human being would.
You've got to learn to believe
in yourself, 'cos I believe in you.
Do you? Of course.
I'll post this then.
Could you get Barrowclough
to post it outside? Who to? BBC?
Yes, on plain notepaper.
"Hello, Young Lovers" corner?!
Is all this for the benefit
of that slag, Denise?
No, not her! Who then?
Ingrid.
My Ingrid?
Our eyes met across the room.
My daughter Ingrid?
And we both knew.
You think I'll let my Ingrid
take up with you?!
A juvenile delinquent
from Birmingham!
Fletch! Be careful! Why?
You've crushed your Ping-Pong ball.
Subtitles by Jane Wolsey
- 1992 -