What'll it be?
Hey, buddy, you wanna order somethin'?
Hey, man, you wanna order somethin'?
Yeah. Give me a taco.
How you doin'?
- Anything to drink?
- Coffee.
Coffee and a taco.
- Yes, sir?
- Make mine the same.
Say, you got a payphone here?
Yeah, right over there.
Hello.
Foxy? It's Link.
Now, just listen. I gotta talk fast.
I'm in big trouble.
If you're dealing in dope again,
forget it because I'll...
Never mind that. Two big motherfuckers
are waitin' to beat the livin' shit out of me
as soon as these two cops finish lunch.
I'm at a taco stand,
corner of Brewster and Church Street.
So hurry up!
Foxy, for Christ's sake, I'm your brother.
You gotta help me. Please!
All right. All right.
When I see you I'll blink my lights, OK?
All right.
- More coffee?
- No, not me, thanks.
Hey, this is good coffee.
This is wonderful coffee.
Best goddamn coffee I ever tasted.
I'll have some more.
How about you?
Check.
Hey, officers, you're not gonna leave
without finishing your coffee?
All that nice, good coffee?
That stuff's expensive.
You shouldn't waste it like that.
Say, you know where I can find
an all-night men's room?
Argh!
Hey!
Agh!
Oh, shit! Get off!
Get off the goddamn front.
I can't see where I'm goin'. Shit!
All right, I'll get the son of a bitch off.
Get me off! Get me off of here!
For God's sake, stop!
You're gonna kill us all!
Whoa!
Somebody help me! Help!
Phew! Jesus!
You saved my beautiful black ass.
You really did.
Mm-hm.
And you better have a mighty good reason
why those hoods were after it, too.
Well, practically nothin'.
A lousy two or three days.
Come on, Link. You're not talking to
one of your jive-ass friends.
I'm your sister. Give it to me straight.
I am. Now, listen.
I had to borrow a few bucks
to go into business.
From a loan shark, right?
The Bank of America ain't started
givin' out mortgages on numbers banks.
OK, OK. So what happened?
What do you think the odds are
against 500 people hitting the number
on Martin Luther King's birthday?
- So how much did you go down for?
- A lousy 20 grand or so.
But I woulda had it all back if they'd just
give me a lousy two or three more days.
Oh, Link!
After all you've been through.
When are you gonna learn?
Look, it's a legitimate business.
Well, almost.
But it's better than bein' a paid informer
like that big-shot boyfriend of yours.
And where is he now?
Probably at the bottom of the river
polluting it in a bucket of cement.
Shut up about him, Link!
OK.
But I was doin' fine before, dealin' coke.
And then you came down on me for that.
Oh, all right.
I guess you're gonna have to stay here
until I can think of what to do.
Thanks, baby. And them people
don't know nothin' about you at all.
And that's another thing.
As long as you're under this roof
you gotta promise me to stay away
from them people and outta the rackets.
Foxy, look, I'm a black man.
I don't know how to sing,
I don't know how to dance,
or how to preach to no congregation.
I'm too small to be a football hero
and I'm too ugly to be elected mayor.
But I watch TV and I see all them people
in all them fine homes they live in
and all them nice cars they drive,
and I get all full of ambition.
Now, you tell me what I'm supposed to do
with all this ambition I got.
I don't know, Link.
I just don't wanna see you end up in jail
or shot down in the street somewhere.
Baby, jail is where some of the finest
people I know are these days.
A car came out of nowhere.
Now, what kind of a bullshit story is that?
What car? Who was it?
How should I know? You sent us to take
care of one little punk black-ass dealer.
You said nothin' about his havin' friends.
Eddie, junk dealers don't have friends.
- Did you at least get a look at him?
- It was pretty dark.
- But, I tell ya, it looked like a broad to me.
- A broad?
What do you suppose
these two were smokin'?
You know I don't drink
or smoke or nothin', Mr Elias.
Eddie!
Yes, Miss Katherine.
Of course,
things don't always go smoothly.
Especially when one becomes careless.
I'm sure he won't be so careless again.
No, Miss Katherine. I sure won't.
This man has cost us a lot of money.
D'you know what happens when
we let these people get away with it?
- Yeah, they'll do it again!
- No, stupid.
No, what she means is
the word gets out all over town
and then nothing we say means shit!
Huh?
He won't get away with it,
Miss Katherine. I promise.
Good.
You may go now.
Sometimes you have to talk tough
to these people to get 'em to listen to you.
Yes. You're right, Steve.
Kiss me.
Yeah...
Hey, what are you doing?
What does it feel like I'm doing?
Feels like you're doin' just what
you're doin', but I can't handle it this way.
I mean, a little taste of honey ain't enough
for me. I gotta have the whole beehive.
Oh, you're gonna get it, baby,
just as soon as you get the wraps
off that Christmas package.
Well, I got something to tell you.
That's gonna be today.
Hm.
That gives me a funny feeling.
I mean...
I don't know what you look like any more.
Maybe I won't want to.
It'll be like doin' it with a stranger.
Yeah? Well, the part that counts
is still just the same.
I noticed!
It really has been a long time, hasn't it?
- Listen, Foxy.
- Hm?
I'll tell you what.
Let's just pull this curtain closed.
- Like this?
- Yeah.
Both of them.
- I don't think we're supposed to do this.
- No, it's all right.
Now, come on up here...
...like this.
Yeah.
- A little more this way.
- Like this?
Oh, now, really, Mr Anderson!
You know perfectly well that's a no-no.
- Time for your bath, Mr Anderson.
- Oh, shit.
Now, Mr Anderson,
we'll have none of that nonsense.
Ooh!
Clean o' body, clean o' mind.
Then a body Jesus'll find.
Easy, now.
Just let me cut this one here.
There's that one.
Just one more here.
There we are. That's it.
There.
So that's it, huh?
It's a good job, Doc.
His own mother wouldn't recognise him.
I like it.
Well, there's the expert's opinion.
What man wouldn't be satisfied with that?
- It won't fall apart if I laugh, will it?
- No.
- Just no fistfights for a few months.
- No way. My fighting days are over.
- I've got other plans from now on.
- Yes, so I noticed.
Something to look forward to.
It's all right if I get out of here for a while,
isn't it? I really need some new scenery.
It's up to your boss.
Just so long as you're back tonight. I can't
check you out officially until tomorrow.
I guess he's gotta try it out
on the street sometime.
Well, you all have some things to talk
about. I'll see you tomorrow, Michael.
I guess this is the time
that you'll be needing these things, Mike.
There's a birth certificate.
Driver's licence, credit cards, social
security numbers, a lot of other things.
And...
You might not wanna keep this,
but I'd like you to read it.
It's from the boss.
From the director of
the Bureau of Narcotics.
He thanks me on behalf of
the US Government for all I've done.
For all I've done.
Nothing!
Two years undercover. The best case
put together against a dope syndicate,
and we couldn't even get an indictment
because the fix was in on the grand jury.
Only way to handle those hoods is with a
bullet in the gut, like they tried to get him.
I know how you feel.
It's hard not to agree with you, but...
Anyway, you're out of it now.
There is no more Dalton Ford.
From now on
you're officially Michael Anderson.
It's a pleasure to walk among people
and not have to worry about anybody.
Oscar? What are you doing?
Sh. Wait a second. Just watch.
Wait a second. Watch this.
My baby!
That's my baby!
Agh!
OK, get that asshole outta here.
Whoo!
Foxy, baby. What's happenin', mama?
Oscar. That wasn't exactly smooth, but
he had no business pickin' on a cripple.
That was one of them no-good niggers.
Been tryin' to catch him for a long time.
Mm-hm.
Oscar, I want you
to meet my friend Michael.
- You a friend of Foxy's, you all right.
- I'm glad to know that, man.
- He's with the neighbourhood committee.
- Yeah, what kind?
- The anti-slavery committee.
- Slavery?
Yeah, we're in the process of abolishing
what we call "new slavery".
- That's the slavery of hard dope. You dig?
- I sure do.
These pushers, they buy protection
from the police and from the man.
But from us there is no protection.
None whatsoever. You dig?
Right on, brother.
But what happens to the pusher?
He's gonna go on a very long train ride.
To some other town, that is.
What if he comes back?
He won't come back. No way indeed.
Dynamite.
Well, Oscar, we gotta run.
We'll check you later, OK?
Foxy's a good chick.
You treat her right, you hear?
The last fella she had
ran out on her at a bad time.
Later.
- Maybe he's got the right idea.
- Sure do.
But I don't know. Vigilante justice?
It's as American as apple pie.
Yeah.
Hello, Deb?
For Christ's sake, baby,
I've been trying to call you all day.
Yeah, I'm OK.
I'm at my sister's pad across the river.
Nobody here knows me.
They were looking for you,
and weren't nice about it.
What? Jesus Christ.
Baby, did they hurt you?
Oh, no, not too bad. I guess they knew
I really didn't know where you were.
Damn. It wasn't my fault the narcs found
that stash and picked up that half key.
All I need is another half or so
for a few days and I can pay it off.
I told them that, like you said.
There's gotta be another way
to raise 20 grand.
Deb, I gotta call you back later, OK?
Say, Foxy.
I didn't expect you back so early.
Mm-hm.
Mike, this is my brother Link.
He'll be visiting me for a while.
- Nice to meet you, man.
- Mm-hm. Hi, how you doin'?
- Mike, is it?
- Yeah. Anderson.
Say, I was just goin' out
for a breath of fresh air and a walk.
Good idea.
- Maybe get better acquainted next time.
- Yeah, maybe next time. See ya.
And stay out of trouble,
if you know what I mean.
For a moment
it seemed like he noticed something.
He's like that. He always has
his feelers out, like a cockroach.
- What time is it?
- It's pretty late.
I'm due back at the hospital
for a final checkup.
Mm. Come here. I'll give you a checkup.
You look pretty good to me.
I'd love to, but...
Tomorrow and all the tomorrows
after that.
- You got much stuff to pack?
- Mm-mm. I'm practically ready.
Been practising with that,
like I showed you?
Plenty, and I'm pretty good with it, too.
Good.
I hope you never have to use it.
What are you doin' in my things?
You remember this?
It don't hardly seem like
it was only three months ago.
Yeah. I'm trying to forget about it, Link.
Dalton Ford.
That name could be worth 20 grand, easy.
What are you talkin' about?
Well, the people I know,
when they want somebody that bad,
they get him for sure.
I bet somebody made a bundle
fingering that informer.
He was not an informer.
He was a federal cop.
Oh, sure, you're right.
Trouble is them people don't know
the difference sometimes.
Well, Link, I'm going on a little vacation.
You can have the place to yourself.
- Think you can get along all right?
- Baby, I'll be all right.
- You gonna need any help?
- No, no, uh-uh. You better stay inside.
And I'll be back
to pick up the bags in an hour.
And you better start thinkin' about
what you're gonna do, OK?
For Mexican heroin, it's pretty good stuff.
About 80.
I've seen better, but not lately.
- Good work, Leroy. Thank you.
- Thank you, Mr Elias. Call on me anytime.
Mr Tedesco, you have yourself a deal.
Tell your people the terms are acceptable.
You get $10,000 upfront,
the rest on delivery.
Now, how soon can you arrange this?
- I would say about five days.
-
Super. I'll have my boy
fly it in the usual way.
Mr Elias, Miss Katherine
wants to see you right away.
- It's urgent, she says.
- All right, Eddie.
Everything goes all right, I see no reason
why we can't do business together.
I am sure you'll be
more than satisfied, Mr Elias.
Well, I certainly hope so.
Are you trying to tell me
Dalton Ford is still alive?
- That's what the man says.
- What man?
- That coke dealer who lost that half key.
- Oh, him again.
I suppose he wants a clean ticket
in return for fingering him.
Steve, I heard the man's story myself.
It has the ring of truth.
Eddie, didn't you tell me
you took care of Ford?
No, sir. You sent Bunyan, remember?
Oh, yes.
I did, honest. I zapped him between
the blades. He fell just like in the movies.
Just... like in the movies?
And then he probably got up again, stupid,
just like in the movies!
- Jesus!
-  All right.
I'm not going to ask what went wrong.
All that matters is that that man never
be allowed to open his mouth in court.
Last time we were able to reach
some of the grand jurors.
We might not be so lucky again.
I want that man dead.
Eddie.
Now, you do it any way you wanna do it,
but I want that goddamn
nigger cop-fink burned!
I don't care
if you have to bring me his head!
I'll make sure this time, Mr Elias.
Come on, kid.
Don't go to a movie.
- Is that him?
- I don't know.
He sure looks different.
I got a couple of things
to pick up at the drugstore.
What do you say
we go take a closer look?
OK. Go ahead.
Link?
Link!
Oh, Link, you didn't.
You couldn't.
- I'm sorry, Foxy.
-
We tried, didn't we?
Oh, baby, no, no. No.
# I'm back in the saddle again
# I'm back where a friend needs a fr...
- Who is it?
- It's me, Link. Foxy.
Uh, what is it?
I need help, Link. Please let me in.
Baby, I'm really kind of busy right now.
Could you come back later?
Please, Link. I got Michael out in the car.
He's been shot! You gotta help me.
Just a second.
Stash that, baby.
Move, you son of a bitch!
You had to tell them, didn't you?
Look, baby! Look!
- What are you trying to do, kill me?
- I ought to, you rotten bastard!
If I don't, thank God you're my brother
cos there's no other reason.
Look, baby, let me alone!
I didn't do nothing to you!
- Agh!
- You know damn well what you did!
I'm not gonna argue with you. Tell me
who you talked to cos it's them or you.
I swear, baby,
I don't know what you're talkin' about.
Agh!
I only got so much control.
I'm liable to put one of these between
your eyes, no matter what Mama'd say.
Baby, look...
Look, all I know is what I hear.
I want the name, Link. The name!
All right, all right. Katherine Wall.
But don't you go messin' with her, baby.
She's mean.
Katherine Wall? What does she
have to do with the dope operation?
Baby, she's the protection. The fixer.
Without her, there's nothin'.
How does she do it?
She runs a stable
of the finest call girls in the country.
But they don't go out for just money.
You gotta be somebody big.
You gotta be a big man - a congressman
or a judge or on the grand jury.
OK, thanks.
What are you doin'?
No, no, no!
Hey! Foxy, what's goin' on?
Now, come on. Cut that shit out!
You're movin' out, brother. Out of town.
And I mean it, Link.
Think you're back with those people, but
they got a stick of dynamite up your ass.
Now, I want you out!
O- u-t.
- Who does she think she is?
- That's my sister, baby.
She's a whole lot of woman.
- Miss Cotton. Misty Cotton?
- Yes.
- Miss Katherine will see you now. Go in.
- Thank you.
You're welcome, dear,
but I can't stand all this green.
There's too much green in everything.
So, Miss Cotton, is it?
May I call you Misty?
It's a lovely name.
I can see you're quite lovely, too.
A unique type.
- Really?
- Yes. Most unusual features.
Almost classic.
Now, Miss Katherine, let's cut all the bull.
I know perfectly well the business you're
in. I couldn't care less about modelling.
I've come here for one reason:
This is where the money's at.
I know just how long I have to make it in
and I intend to make it good while I can.
So let's you and me stop
wasting each other's precious time.
You tell me who you want done
and I'll do the hell out of him,
if the price is right.
Vicki?
Set up wardrobe and hairdressing
for Miss Cotton right away, will you?
Misty Cotton, eh?
All right, Misty. We'll give you a try.
If you do well, you can go a long way.
But if you fail or try to quit,
you can go a long way, too,
in a different direction.
You understand that quite clearly?
If you say it, I believe it.
Good.
Be ready tomorrow.
- Four o'clock at my house. Don't be late.
- Thank you, Miss Katherine.
It'll look like an accident.
Your escort will have an emergency.
He will ask the other gentleman
if he can stay and have a drink with you.
The important thing is that
it should seem as if you go home with him
because you find him
irresistibly attractive.
The material should cling to the breasts
so the nipples show through.
Arabella, I want that fat toad
drooling in his pants over you.
Whenever he looks at you, think sex.
If you find him repulsive,
think of someone else who turns you on.
Why is that dress so tight?
I thought I told you to lose five pounds.
- You did?
- Yes. Five pounds.
- I'll give you three days to get rid of it.
- Yes, Miss Katherine. I'll do it. I promise.
You have the best hairdressers in the city.
You have everything you need
to look your absolute best.
There's no excuse for slovenliness.
You, Jennifer.
You look like you just woke up
from a three-day drunk.
Your face is puffy and your make-up
is too thick trying to cover it up.
Steve...
You're making Miss Cotton nervous.
I'm ready, Miss Katherine.
How do you like it?
It's very impressive.
It's rather late. You'd better get going.
Claudia will tell you what to do.
The gentlemen you'll be meeting
this evening have a preference for, uh...
your type.
Oh, I understand, Miss Katherine.
- Bunyan, we're ready for the car now.
- OK, Vicki.
Oh, sister. You almost
stepped on the tail of a tiger.
- You mean the big chief? Who is he?
- His name is Steve Elias,
her very personal private property.
Mustn't touch.
Oh, she's got a weak spot, huh?
True love hits the strangest people,
I guess.
Hey, don't worry, baby. Old Claudia's
gonna steer you through this mess.
I'm an old hand at these parties.
Look, all you have to do
is be nice... to certain people.
And tonight I have to be nice
to a certain Judge Fenton,
cos two dope dealers that work for Elias
come up for trial in his court tomorrow.
What happens if you're nice to the judge,
but the judge isn't nice to the dealer?
Ah, no, no, no,
cos that would mean I failed.
And that better not happen.
Then what happens?
There's a house in Haiti.
And men go there for...
what they can't get anywhere else.
Mama! Mama! Mama!
Jason!
Jason! Oh, my baby.
- You shouldn't be here.
- Hello, Claudia.
Willard!
What you doin' around here?
I got a new job in Seattle. I wanted him to
see his mama one last time before we go.
- You can't just take him away like that.
- You ain't seen him in six months.
- But that ain't my fault.
- Whose is it?
There ain't no reason why
you can't up and leave with us now.
Willard, I want to, I really do,
but you don't know these people.
- Once they got you, they don't let you go.
- Eddie.
What world is it if anybody could keep
a woman away from her man and child?
- You're trespassing. It's private property.
- I ain't afraid of you!
- I'm talking to my wife.
- We don't want any disturbance.
You wanna communicate with that lady,
I suggest you go write her a letter, OK?
Get him up here. I want him!
Miss Katherine, I'm sorry.
I didn't know he'd come here, honest.
Now get him out of here!
Feel better already.
Drop a couple of downers,
switch on automatic pilot,
wait till I reach cruising altitude.
And then what?
Maybe a couple more.
A martini or so.
Maybe then I can be nice
to that pig judge like I'm gonna have to.
Yeah, well, you do what you gotta do.
Hey, I've got an idea that might
make it more fun for him and us.
You and me, together.
Dig?
Yeah?
Mm-hm.
Well, I feel game
for just about anything tonight.
- I'll tell you.
- All right.
Ah, at last. Come on in.
Hiya, Judge.
Eddie, get the girls a drink.
Wowee. I see Your Honour
likes that dark meat.
The darker the berry,
the sweeter the juice, honey.
Think you can handle all of that, Fred?
Maybe you'll need a little help.
At your age you might have a heart attack.
Awful lot of chocolate for one man. No
wonder you cleared your calendar early.
Don't pay them fellas no nevermind, girls.
Come on, Eddie. Drink up.
Sure glad you got here.
I was tired watching those movies.
Then why don't we go and adjudicate
this matter in chambers, as they say,
and maybe we can make
a few motions or something.
- Well, if I don't hear any objection.
- Well, I sure don't object.
Matter of fact,
I ain't gonna object to nothin' today.
Good. You're the kind of counsellor
I like in my courtroom.
I object. She's supposed to be with me.
Uh-uh, honey. I want the top man.
Come on.
Come on in.
Speaking of courtrooms...
Oh, yes, your friends
who got into a little trouble.
Well, don't worry. I'm told they're
good boys who just made a few mistakes.
I'm sure we can manage
to give them another chance.
Oh, I do hope so.
Danny is such a good person.
He just has terrible luck, that's all.
Like when he was found in that alley with
a nine-year-old. He wasn't molesting her.
She was lovin' every minute of it
and them ropes didn't mean a thing.
What? Ropes?
And when he cut off that woman's fingers
that was only an accident.
- Huh, Claudia?
- Sure.
Elroy's not really bad either.
The dynamite he sells isn't nearly as good
as the smack he used to sell in school.
- School?
- High school.
He never dealt nothing more than grass
in grade school, you know.
Sounds like a public menace.
Oh, but he don't mean to be.
You'll be nice to them boys, won't you,
if we're nice to you?
Well, I guess we'll have to see
just how nice.
Hey. Not so fast.
Yeah, take it easy.
We've got very special plans for you.
Really? What?
Will you look at that?
Baby, is this what
you were gonna use on me?
- What?
- I mean, I've heard of a meat shortage,
but that's ridiculous.
Well, you gotta...
Well, the other girls liked it.
Oh, I'm sure I'll like it,
but I just can't find it.
Claudia, help me find it.
I'm sure it's under here somewhere.
Watch it. Don't roll on it.
The charge, Your Honour,
is assault with a very undeadly weapon.
I mean, you talk about
your blunt instrument.
You're different, all right,
I'll say that for you.
Mm... You too, little man.
But I can play along with the gag
as well as the next fella.
What happens now?
Now we get serious, lover.
Come on.
That's it.
Oh, yeah.
Now you're gonna get
the real taste of honey.
- Yeah?
- You ready?
You pink-ass, corrupt judge!
Take your little noodle outta here.
And if you see a man anywhere,
send him in because I do need a man.
Agh! Help me! Oh!
- Oh, help!
- What's he doing?
I'll handle this, girls.
Lecher! Shame!
Shame! Lecher! Lecher!
I mean, that was...
I think that was
the funniest thing I've ever seen.
Oh, man, was it worth it.
You know what
they're gonna do to us, baby?
Yeah, nothin'.
In fact, all the doin'
is gonna be done to them.
They're gonna kick our ass,
but I ain't afraid.
I mean, I know it's crazy cos I know what
they're gonna do to us, but I ain't afraid.
I ain't never gonna see little Jason again.
Or my man neither!
So I don't give a shit no more.
Oh, Misty, I love that little boy.
I really do.
I love him so much.
Claudia. Claudia, pull yourself together.
This is no time to fall apart.
Now, I'm gonna... Sh, sh, Claudia.
Listen to me. I'm gonna take you
to a place where you can wait for me.
You understand? Understand?
OK, now I got everything all worked out.
You just do what I tell you, OK?
Judge Fenton threw the book
at our dealers this morning.
- I can't understand it. What do you mean?
- 20 years apiece.
And after the trouble we took
getting them into his court.
- He wouldn't even talk to me.
- Oh, my God, why?
That's what I wanna know.
I thought you had the fix in.
How can I keep our dealers in line
if they see we can't deliver protection?
Yes, I know how important that is.
Well, do you know the word is out all over
town? The whole operation is in a panic.
Two of our street pushers have already
left the city. What went wrong?
I don't know.
I put him with Claudia
and that new girl, Misty Cotton.
Said it all went well. It was all set up.
Oh, she did, did she? I thought that
black bitch was too good to be true.
She wouldn't dare pull a trick like that.
We'll find out. I got the word out on 'em.
If either one shows their face anywhere
in the city, I know about it in five minutes.
Claudia.
Claudia?
Workin' in a factory's no life.
Turns you into a fuckin' machine.
I don't need that shit. I'm a goddamn lady.
I don't need to work in no fuckin' factory.
Scotch, water back.
There you go.
You see that little black chick
down at the end?
Funny you ask. I ain't taken
my eye off her since she come in.
Nothin' funny about it. The word is
keep her here. Any way you have to.
It'll be my pleasure.
Hey. You a model or somethin'?
- Somethin'.
- I always liked the idea of bein' a model.
Let the bastards look without lettin' 'em
touch. That always did appeal to me.
Claudia, what are you doin' in here?
I asked you to wait for me.
I needed a drink.
You're going to Seattle with your old man.
He's waiting at the airport. Come on.
Wait a minute, bitch.
Why don't you go find one of your own?
Now, you wait a minute.
This is none of your business.
Before you start talkin' tough, I better
warn you I got a black belt in karate.
So why don't you get out of here quietly
while you still got teeth in that ugly face?
And I got my black belt in bar stools.
Come on, Claudia. Let's get outta here.
Hold it. I don't like what you just did.
Bobbie happens to be a friend of ours.
Then maybe you'd like a taste
of what she just got.
Leave her alone. They're friends of ours.
Oh, shut up.
Grab that chair! Grab that chair!
Get your hands off me, you bitch!
Agh! Let go of my hair, bitch!
Come on. Let's shake ass!
- Hey, look.
- Haul ass. I'll slow 'em down.
All right, you get them.
I'll take care of the cops. No guns.
I've got her. Get the other one.
Get her!
Ow!
- No, no, no! Let go of me!
- Come on! Come on!
Come down, baby. This ain't gonna hurt.
That bitch. I'll kill her.
Come on, kid. Give it to her.
- No, Bunyan! Don't mess her up.
- She cut me, Elias! I'm gonna kill her.
Miss Katherine wants her clean.
Stop it, please! Please, don't.
Stop!
Bunyan.
Bunyan!
Ease off a minute, will you, man?
Have a little finesse.
Save some for later.
Oh, I've got plenty for later.
- What did you find out?
- Our boys ran a fingerprint check on her.
They made her through her driver's
licence. Her name is Foxy Brown.
You know something, Steve. What is it?
Well, it seems she was Dalton Ford's girl.
And, Eddie, she was with him
when he got it.
That's right. I remember.
Why didn't I recognise her?
So that's it.
No, there's more.
The dealer who fingered him for us...
- was her brother.
- That don't make sense.
Well, maybe those people
just don't believe in family loyalty, Eddie.
So it's just that simple, isn't it?
Yeah.
Just about.
But the game ain't over yet, bitch!
That ain't gonna do any good either.
You're gonna have to kill me,
or I'll kill you.
It's gotta be one way or the other.
- Let me do it, Miss Katherine.
- No.
Give her a shot of heroin
and send her out to the ranch.
The ranch.
Now, you know what the boys
at the ranch would do with her?
She'll probably love it.
Then when she's got a good habit
we'll send her to the islands.
She should bring a good price.
Maybe she'll pay us back
for some of the trouble she's caused us.
If there's enough of her left
when the boys get through with her.
# Oh, yeah...
# I know a girl who lives on a hill
# She don't put out, but her sister will
# Oh, yeah
Ba-ba-boo
# Ba-ba-boo, hm, hm, hm...
# Now this same little girl
that lives on a hill
# Gives you a thrill for a five-dollar bill
Oh, yeah...
Want some? Damn you!
Get up.
You give me any more trouble...
- What's the problem?
- There ain't no goddamn problem.
I'm just gettin' my kicks out of lettin' Miss
Big-jug-jiggerboo think she can escape.
Hm.
Time for another smack-O then, I'd say.
Sure.
One thing we've got
plenty of, baby, is dope.
You don't ever have to worry about
feelin' down with us.
You're a lucky nigger, you know that?
Yeah. It ain't every junkie broad's
got such good providers for a boyfriend.
I don't need any more. I'm doin' fine.
Now, now, now. Doctor knows best.
Anyway, you're gettin'
just a wee bit more this time.
Now, ain't that nice?
And you don't even say thanks.
Thank you, ugly, prickless,
white faggot, peasant motherfucker!
Did you hear that? Did your black mammy
teach you to talk like that?
And that ain't nice,
not here in our polite society.
Shit. We ought to wash
your mouth out with soap, lady.
Me, oh, my.
I'm beginning to get that old feeling.
Funny how fast it comes
when a chick has really got the goodies
to show you.
You might as well. I gotta go in town
and get some stuff to cut that smack.
# They call her Linda-Lu
# With eyes of blue
# Give her a few bucks
And she'll make love to you
# She had a beautiful smile
And plenty of style
# Give her a little kiss
And she would go completely wild
# They call her Linda-Lu
# With eyes of blue
# Give her a few bucks
And she'll make love to you
# She had a beautiful smile
And plenty of style
# Give her a little kiss
And she would go completely wild
What the hell are you doing? Get away...
Ow! Argh!
Help! Brandt, come and get me! Help!
- God!
- Help!
Hey, skinhead!
I can't see. Brandt, help!
- This is gasoline.
- You know it, motherfucker.
I can't see!
- Jesus!
- Help me!
No! Help, Brandt!
Argh!
No, nobody knows how the hell
it happened. The whole thing blew up.
I don't know. One of those idiots there
probably set off a gas tank or somethin'.
I know they're screaming for their stuff.
Just make do with what you've got
for a couple of days.
We've got a new shipment coming in
the first of the week.
Yes. All right, handle it.
It's that woman. She did it.
You know something?
I'm afraid you're right.
You've got to find her, Steve.
- And kill her.
- Yeah.
Yeah, and I know just
how to go about that. Eddie!
- Yes, Mr Elias.
- I want you to get me a sawed-off gun.
We're gonna kill ourselves
a couple of niggers.
Just as you say, Mr Elias.
Sometimes, baby, when you want
something done you gotta do it yourself.
I love it when you're like that, Steve.
So powerful.
Gonna take this thing off.
Oh, that new stuff is good, all right.
And expensive.
But good.
- You want another blow?
- Sure do.
Let's see how far this thing can go.
Ah, yeah.
Oh.
Shit!
I'll be back in a flash.
- Yeah, who is it?
- Open up, Link. It's Eddie.
- I got some stuff for you.
- Man, I'm balling my old lady.
- Can't you come back later?
- Are you kidding?
I can't carry this stuff around. Open up.
All right!
- Hand it through the door, man.
- OK.
No, Link. Drop it.
Spit it out, nigger. Where is she?
- What are you talkin' about?
- She's your sister.
- You know where she is.
- I don't know nothin', honest to God!
Talk or I'll blow your head off!
Help me! Help me!
Better finish him. Shut her up, will you?
Too bad. She was a good-Iookin' piece.
What? Link, too?
They say it was those
Steve Elias people that did it.
Was he dealin' again?
Yeah. Coke.
I guess I knew it all the time.
Once those people get their hooks in you,
there's only one way they'll let you off.
You ready?
We talked about your request and we're
not sure whether we want to help or not.
We're a neighbourhood committee and
this is sort of out of our neighbourhood.
Maybe the time has come
to grow a bit, brother.
- What is it you really want?
- Justice.
- For whom, your brother?
- Why not?
It could be your brother, too.
Or your sister.
Or your children.
I want justice for all of 'em.
And I want justice for all the other people
whose lives are bought and sold,
so that a few big shots can climb up
on their backs and laugh at the law
and laugh at human decency.
And most of all...
I want justice for a good man.
This man had love in his heart.
And he died because
he went out of his neighbourhood
to try to do what he thought was right.
Sister, I think what
you're asking for is revenge.
You just take care of the justice
and I'll handle the revenge myself.
You said you had a plan?
Do you have the name of the pilot
that flies the stuff in from Mexico?
And she nods like she understands.
Now, how the hell did I know that chick's
gotta take a leak? I pick up the cone...
I pick up the cone,
I put it all up in my ear like this and...
Uh, y'all gonna have to excuse me.
I think I found me a new friend.
Bartender.
Get this dusky, young lady
whatever it is she needs
to quench her magnificent thirst.
Why, thank you, handsome.
I couldn't help but hearin'
that marvellous story you was tellin'.
I ain't never been in an airplane before.
Sounds really marvellous.
- You ain't never been up before?
- Mm-mm.
Oh.
That's a tragedy
of the greatest dimension.
I'd sure like to, though. In fact,
I figured if I hung around here awhile
one of you guys would take me for a ride
in one of your airplanes.
Girl, you're some kind of lucky.
It just so happens I am the best damn
airplane driver there is in these parts.
- Is that an invite?
- Ain't it.
Oh, gosh. That makes me
tingle all over just to hear it.
- Steve?
- Yeah?
- Do you really have to go?
- What?
Why don't you let Eddie
make the pick-up for you tonight, hm?
I can't do that, darlin'.
This is too big a score.
I can't risk somebody else picking it up.
- I'm frightened.
- You? Oh, come on now.
It's that woman. She's crazy.
There's no telling what she'll do.
All right, listen. I'll leave Eddie and
one of the other boys here with you. OK?
I really do love you in this shirt.
Oh, you make me so wild.
- Tell me.
- Oh, I love you.
Tell me again.
I love you so much.
Oh, yes. Yes.
You can go now. I wanted you to know I'll
be waiting for you when you come back.
Oh, right.
Well, then I'll just get back
as fast as I can, huh?
And then I'll show you
how much you really turn me on.
Hey, babe, why don't you
put this on automatic pilot
so we can go in the back
and, you know, get it on?
This ain't no 747.
You just hang on in there
until I'm done with this job
and I'll take care of you real good.
You bet.
- I'm hanging, baby. I'm hanging.
- Hah! Don't do this to me!
Wait a minute. I gotta find a place
to land this motherfucker.
- How are you, Mr Elias?
- All right, O'Brien.
- Nobody comes in or out till I get back.
- You can count on it, sir.
- Mr Elias.
- Mr Tedesco, how are you?
Fine.
Count it.
Well, at least he's on time.
Hey, baby, why don't you keep your fuzzy
little head outta sight till this is over with?
We might get in a hell of a lotta trouble if
somebody found out I took you to Mexico.
OK, I wouldn't wanna cause you
any trouble, you understand?
I'm gonna get down here.
Sh. Put your head down.
- What's the trouble, Officer?
- Plenty of trouble for you, spook,
unless you go back where you came from.
- This road's closed.
- Yes, sir. We sure don't want no trouble.
- And neither do you, do you, whitey?
- No, sir. I sure don't.
What the hell's she doin'?
- What the hell's goin' on?
- I don't know.
- Bunyan!
- Argh!
- I'm all right.
- Go get him, sister.
What are you gonna do?
What do you want?
What are you guys gonna do?
What, are you crazy?
What are you...
- He's ready, sister.
- No! You...
You're crazy.
You can't do this!
You can't do that!
No! No, Foxy!
Oh, no! Shit!
Argh!
Hold it right there, spook.
Yeah, you're gonna be a spook
for real pretty soon. Hands up.
- Don't pinch the fruit.
- Watch your mouth...
No, Eddie. Later.
I want to know what she's doing here.
I'll take that, bigmouth.
Sure. I brought it for you, Miss Pimp.
It's a present from your faggot boyfriend.
See what it is, Eddie.
Well, what is it?
I don't know.
Looks like a pickle jar or somethin'.
Bring it here.
Oh, Steve! Agh!
Why don't you kill me, too?
Go on, shoot! I don't wanna live any more!
I know.
That's the idea.
The rest of your boyfriend is still around
and I hope you two live a long time.
And then maybe
you'll get to feel what I feel.
Death is too easy for you, bitch.
I want you to suffer.
The party's over, Oscar. Let's go.
Visiontext Subtitles: Natasha Cohn
ENHOH