Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
What the hell is going on?
Oh, she's not!
Is she?
Oh, you can't do that
with a ping-pong ball!
Do you want a bet?
Oh! Oh!
Help me!
He's taking me away! Help me!
I'm going!
Darling, there's nothing
we can't work out.
You no good man.
Now, don't be silly.
You want good wife -
you be good husband.
Darling, don't go.
I no like you anyway.
You got little ding-a-ling.
Some days you just shouldn't
get out of bed.
In my opinion, you should wait here
for the new gas tank
from Coober Pedy.
Then again,
you listened to my last opinion.
Forget it, Bob.
It's time we made a move.
I'm just a gifted amateur
around here.
There's no way a nice frock
and a catchy tune
can compete with three ping-pong
balls, two cigarettes and beer.
I'll play it safe and stick
to the main drag, pardon the pun.
Well, goodbye, Bob.
Thanks for a very educational stay.
I'd love to be able
to open a bottle like that.
Bernadette,
it's certainly been an honour
meeting a member of Les Girls.
And it's been an honour
to meet a gentleman.
Believe me, Bob, these days
gentlemen are an endangered species.
Unlike bloody drag queens
who just keep breeding like rabbits!
Oh, fuck it!
Bob! Fancy a free ride
to Coober Pedy?
Now, listen, Bob.
Let's get one thing straight.
We wear the frocks, but that
doesn't mean you wear the pants.
Right. Where do I sleep?
Oh! Anywhere that takes your fancy!
The roof will do me fine.
Thank you, Bob.
I don't know what to say.
That's alright. Might as well get
there earlier. Bit of R and R.
God knows I need it.
Can I ask you a personal question,
if you don't mind?
Sure.
Why?
Why do you... you know?
You mean the $64,000 question?
That's the girl.
Don't tear the wrapping paper.
Just slide the ribbon off and we can
see what Santa's brought you.
Here it comes now.
What is it?
Oh, it's a... It's a...
...cement mixer.
Have you been changing the cards
around again, Ralph?
So, I guess I had no choice
in the matter.
For fuck's sake! Watch where
you're driving, you stupid bitch!
You trying to fucken kill me?
My fault!
Sorry, Bob.
I thought it was Bernadette.
One-two-three, two-two-three,
three-two-three...
Now you're getting it.
Who taught you to waltz?
My wife.
Oh, how sweet.
You and the missus down at
Arthur Murray's every Tuesday
practising your hearts out.
Makes me want to sick up.
Married?
Yes, married.
We've only recently discovered
young Anthony here
bats for both teams.
I do not!
Oh, so we're straight?
No.
Oh, we're not?
We're a donut puncher after all?
No.
Then what are we?
I don't fucking know!
What the fuck's that?
Good evening.
Nice night for it.
Oh, OK. Goodnight then.
What a rude woman.
And that's the power steering pump.
And that's the radiator fan.
How interesting.
Simple.
That's the rubber band
that drives the whole thing...
Oh! Yes!
Hey! Who wants first bath?
Whoo-ooh!
I won!
Can I help you, ma'am?
OK! Turn her over!
I don't care
if the sun don't shine
I get my loving in the evening time
When I'm with my baby
It's no fun with the sun around
But I get going
when the sun goes down
And I meet my baby
That's when we kiss
and kiss and kiss
And then we kiss some more
Don't ask how many times we kiss
At a time like this
who keeps score?
So, I don't care
if the sun don't shine
I get my loving in the evening time
When I'm with my baby!
That's it over there.
It's an OK room - with a shower.
Bags first!
Is hot water all you think about?
No. A shower, bed
and nice meal will do fine.
If you think I'm just going to
watch television, you're wrong.
Now, look.
You blokes watch your back.
It's a pretty tough town.
They go down holes, blow things up,
then come up again.
That sums things up.
Oh, fabulous!
You're welcome to hang out
with us, Bob.
I'm meeting some of the boys
in the old drive-in for a booze-up.
Like the old days.
I want to go to the boys club!
You'll have supper with us
or stay in your room and watch TV.
Ha!
He's a good man, our Bob.
Yeah.
Not my type, though.
Oh! Don't come the raw prawn with me!
I can spot the fluttering
of a beaded lash from 300 paces!
Oh, get out! He's far too old.
Mind you, so am I.
Mmm.
Did you catch that mail-order bride?
Why'd he marry? I'm dying to ask.
Oops! Sorry.
It's alright.
Don't worry about it.
You're the world's best husband.
And, given the chance,
a perfectly good father too.
Do you really think so?
Why? Thinking about children?
Yes, as a matter of fact.
Um, do you have
'The Texas Chainsaw Mascara'?
You ever wanted kids?
Sure. But I've learned
not to think about it.
You think an old queen's
capable of raising a child?
Well, Elizabeth did
a pretty good job.
Prince Charles is a wonderful boy.
Edward's still a bit of a worry.
What happens
if they turn out like Adam?
You stuff them back in
and ask for a refund.
Stupid little shit.
I dread to think what he's up to.
Oooh.
Hello.
I'm new in town.
No kidding.
Could I have a bloody Mary, please?
It's a beer or nothing... sweetheart.
Well, I'd better have a beer then.
Cheers.
What are you all looking at?
I'm sorry.
Didn't mean to stare.
We don't usually get women down here.
Oh.
So what do women do around here
besides watching videos?
Well, well, well!
Look who we have here.
You know that bloke, do you?
No.
So... who's going to show me
the sights?
It'd be my pleasure.
Oh.
So, how about it?
I suppose a fuck's
now out of the question.
Get her, Frank!
Go, Frank!
Come on, boys! Who wants to see
my map of Tasmania?
I never got to tell my parents
what a wonderful childhood I'd had.
They never spoke to me again
after I'd had... the chop.
I think I have something
to tell you.
Oh, shit.
Get after her!
OK, fellas!
Don't forget how to treat a lady.
You fucking freak!
Hold him down.
Spread his legs apart.
Oh, no. Please, don't!
Frank, stop!
Stop! What the fuck
do you think you're doing?!
You mean you do know
this cocksucker.
Get off him, you mongrel!
He was joking, OK?
You leave the little bugger alone.
Get out of there, Bob.
Calm down, Frank.
Put the faggot down and get out
or you'll be next.
Frank!
Get out of there!
Stop flexing your muscles
you big pile of budgie turd.
Your mates will be more impressed
if you go back to the pub
and fuck a few pigs on the bar.
Bernadette, please...
Bernadette?!
Well, I'll be darned.
The whole circus is in town.
I suppose you want a fuck too,
do you?
Come on, Bernadette.
Come and fuck me.
That's it.
Come on. Come and fuck me.
Come on.
Fuck me.
There, now you're fucked.
You stupid bloody idiot!
Drugs, for Christ's sake!
Well, three cheers for you!
I hope you're happy now!
You bloody fuckwit!
It's funny.
We all sit around
mindlessly slagging off
that vile stink-hole of a city.
But in its own strange way
it takes care of us.
I don't know if that ugly wall
of suburbia's been put there
to stop them getting in
or us getting out.
Come on.
Don't let it drag you down.
Let it toughen you up.
I can only fight
because I've learnt to.
Being a man one day
and a woman the next isn't easy.
Sorry. Can't help you.
No worries, Pete.
Are we bunny-hopping
all the way to Alice?
The man to help's
a fair way out of town.
Like how fair?
Couple of hundred klicks fair.
No matter. I've go nothing else
to do today. Let's get out of here.
Come on, Adam. We're not here.
A fine romance
with no kisses
A fine romance,
my friend, this is
We should be like
a couple of hot tomatoes...
Some things are said
in the heat of the moment.
I'm sorry I got angry with you
last night.
Oh, I dare say you deserved it.
Anyway, that's enough of that.
This is quite an experience
sitting with you now.
I can quite safely say
that I think your taste in clothing
is absolutely terrible
because you can't say a word,
can you?
Oh, this is great fun!
We're going to have a problem
finding this guy with the tank.
Why say that?
Because he's not out here.
He's out here. He's in Alice.
I can't go back to Coober Pedy
for a while.
I'm not the most popular bloke
back there anymore.
Ooof!
Hello.
Hello!
Who are you?
I your wife!
Guess I'll be going home then.
You no going!
I coming too. I your wife!
See? I your wife!
Silly girl.
Should've done her homework better.
She always thought...
She thought I was from Sydney.
Why did you bring her home?
She was me wife.
Couldn't you sell her off?
Oh, the party's over, everyone.
It talks.
Can't keep a good bitch down.
What time
will we be in Alice Springs?
Late tomorrow arvo.
How long will you be staying?
Don't know.
A couple of days maybe.
A big day for you tomorrow!
We'll all meet the missus!
I saw that smile, Felicia!
One derogatory word
and I'll take you back
to your mate in Coober Pedy.
Please, everyone.
Tomorrow will be tough.
Please don't make it any harder.
We're only teasing. We won't open
our mouths until you give the word.
And then it's open season.
Oh, well. Time for bed.
Got to look good for the wife.
Come along, Adam.
Time for your beauty sleep.
Come on!
Will you two be joining us?
I just thought
I'd have one for the road.
How about you, Bob?
Sounds good to me.
Alright, then.
See you in the morning.
Goodnight!
Another piece of cake, Bob?
Ah, no.
Oh.
So... tell me about you.
Can't complain.
Life's a lot simpler now.
Spent 30 years
wandering around the world
only to find I was better off
where I started.
Not much, but it's my turf.
Oooh! Shit!
Adam!
What?
Guess who didn't come home?
I've waited all my life for this.
Bernice has left her cake
out in the rain!
Hava nagila
Have a hangover
Hi hi hi!
Di di, di-di-di-di
Hava nagila
V'nish m'cha, hey!
V'nish m'cha
Aaaahhhhhh, aaaahhhhhh,
aaaahhhhhh HEY!
My fucking back's killing me.
I need a crap.
Do you want me to go in?
I'll go.
Excuse me.
You can't park your bus here.
Are you planning on staying here?
I'm sorry...
Could you direct me to Marian Barber?
We're the cabaret act from Sydney.
Oh, right, right!
Just go through to reception.
Thanks.
No worries.
It's alright, Lenny.
It's the drag queens!
Come on, Bob. Let's go try on
your new frock.
G'day.
Just over there by the bar.
Thanks.
No, those three kegs
didn't arrive.
I need them today -
not tomorrow, but today.
You're a doll.
What an arsehole.
Oh, my God! Husband! Husband!
It's so good to see you!
Hiya, wife!
You're late. Where are the others?
Oh, they're outside.
You've lost weight, you old queer.
About fucken time!
I can fit into your old one-piece -
the one with the sunflowers.
What do you do with it?
'The Poseidon Adventure' routine.
You know, Shelley Winters.
Where is he?
I'd like to give you
a good spanking.
You can get it!
Spank, spank, spank!
I'll put you over my knee.
I'll "spank, spank" you back!
Oops!
Benj.
Do you remember Tick?
Hello, Tick.
Hello.
Where's the bloody bar?
Mr Belrose?
Yes?
Congratulations. It's a boy.
Oh!
Shit!
Are you OK?
What's the matter? Oh, my God!
Help.
Christ's sake, Mitz,
why didn't you tell us?
Why did you shock me like that?
Ooh!
This lump on my head's
growing by the second.
I'm making
my Northern Territory debut
looking like a fucking
Warner Bros cartoon character
has hit me with an iron.
You look more like a Disney witch.
Shut up!
At least I don't look like
somebody's tried to open
a can of beans with my face.
Sorry. I didn't want you
bagging me for two weeks.
What difference does it make now?
About two inches to my head.
See him? He's got my profile.
I'm gonna be sick.
Let's be practical -
does he know who you are?
Does he know what you do?
He knows his father's in
the show business cosmetics industry.
Oh, Lord! I don't understand.
You don't, so stop trying to.
It'll be fine!
It'd better be.
Hello! Oh, stop wearing out
that mirror!
Do you always knock?
Always.
Haven't got anything to hide,
have you?
Alright, girls,
you're on in 10 minutes.
You've been on since birth.
The word's out. There's a big crowd.
How big?
A full house.
Where's Benj?
Safe and sound, asleep in bed.
Don't worry about a thing,
my little powder puff.
Can I come in?
Now, there's a gentleman.
Of course you can, Bob.
My Aunt Minnie in here?
Just... wanted to wish you luck.
Thank you, Bob.
Thanks.
To make up for last time.
Thank you. That's so thoughtful.
Let's get this show on the road.
You, out.
10-minute curtain call. Good luck.
That's quite a wife you've got, Mitz.
What's her hobby - sanding back
oil tanker hulls with her tongue?
She sure is something!
Oh!
Chookers, girls.
Watch my jaw!
Mind my head.
Aren't we faaa-bulous!
Ladies and gentlemen,
Lasseters Casino, Alice Springs
presents Miss Mitzi del Gra,
Miss Felicia Jolly Good Fellow
and Miss Bernadette Basinger -
the Sisters of the Simpson Desert.
Meeting Mr Right
The man of my dreams
The one who showed me true love
or at least it seemed
With brown cocoa skin
and curly black hair
Just the way he looks at me -
that gentle, loving stare
Finally you came along
The way I feel about you
it just can't be wrong
If you only knew
the way I feel about you
I just can't describe it
Oh, no, no
Finally it's happened to me
Right in front of my face
My two lips can't describe it
Finally it's happened to me
Right in front of my face
and I just cannot hide it
Finally it's happened to me
Right in front of my face
My two lips can't describe it
Finally it's happened to me
Right in front of my face
and I just cannot hide it...
Seemed so many times
he seemed to be the one
But all he ever wanted
was to have a little fun
But now you've come along
and brightened up my world
In my heart I feel it
I'm that special kind of girl
Finally you came along
The way I feel about you
it just can't be wrong
If you only knew
the way I feel about you
I just can't describe it
Oh, no, no
Finally it's happened to me
Right in front of my face
My two lips can't describe it
Finally it's happened to me
Right in front of my face
and I just cannot hide it
Finally it's happened to me
Right in front of my face
My two lips can't describe it
Finally it's happened to me
Right in front of my face
and I just cannot hide it...
Finally
WWhoa
Yeah, yeah
Whoa-oh-oh
Finally, baby
Y ea h, yea h, ow
Baby, yeah, yeah
Finally it's happened to me
Right in front of my face
My two lips can't describe it
Finally it's happened to me
Right in front of my face
and I just cannot hide it
Finally
Oh, yeah
Yeah, yeah...
Finally
Oh, yeah.
More!
Bravo!
Beauty!
Come on, everybody!
Yay!
More!
Yes! More!
Hey-hey!
More! More!
More!
You were wonderful!
We want more!
Yes!
Magnificent!
Yay!
Bravo! Whoo!
More!
We want more!
Come on, snap out of it.
Come on, mate.
You'll be fine.
Come on, love.
Oh.
That's it, mate.
Scared us all for a minute.
Had to have extra attention,
didn't you?
Nice one, lovey, nice one.
Shit!
What are you doing, Marian?
You liar!
You said he was in bed.
Shh! Drink your daiquiri.
I hate bloody daiquiri!
You don't.
You love bloody daiquiris.
Now I know why drag queens
drink from big glasses.
To make their hands look smaller!
Oh, ha ha, Marian!
What do I tell the boy?
I've never been so embarrassed.
You're overreacting.
Really?!
Yes. You're being a drama queen.
You'd better drop that shit
if you're gonna be a good father.
And don't pretend to be surprised.
It's your turn.
Not forever -
maybe just a couple of months.
Yeah, but why now?
Because I haven't had a holiday
in eight years.
I need a rest, Tick. I need space.
Reminds me of something I said.
Well, I do.
It's time he knew his father anyway.
Yeah, that's the problem.
What do I tell him?
What do you assume I do - lie?
Assumption's the mother
of all fuck-ups.
Bitch to him, not me.
You might be surprised.
Thanks for the free advice.
Who is it?
It's me, Bob.
Your flowers were being mangled.
Thought I'd rescue them for you.
Good idea. Thanks.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Know what your father does
for a living?
Yeah.
So you know he doesn't
really like girls then?
Does he have a boyfriend
at the moment?
No.
Neither does Mum.
She had a girlfriend,
but she got over her.
Want to play in my room?
I've got Lego.
Sure.
Come on, Butch. Get moving.
We can't brand the cattle
by ourselves.
Great show last night.
You always end a number like that?
Always.
How'd you like to pick her up
every night, Sundance?
Be a pleasure.
That might include
tucking the lady into bed, Jeff.
What's the pay like, Marian?
He'll get himself into trouble
one day.
And you might just be
the lucky fellow.
All aboard!
So take a letter, Maria
Address it to my wife...
Watch it with the innuendos.
Give me a clear shot at this.
You call dressing like a Xanadu
production number a clear shot?
Come on, Tick! Who's kidding who?
He sure as shit isn't.
Sehd a ocopy to hmy awyer
Gotta start a new life
You've been many things
But most of all
a good secretary to me...
Um, wave...
What am I doing?
Swimming!
Um...
Murray.
Rock...
Murray rock...
River rock... Oh, Rock! Rock Hudson!
Silly dag!
Didn't you get Doris Day?
My turn! My turn!
OK, smartypants, you try.
Come on, then.
It's a...
Person.
A sexy woman.
Cat?
Famous woman.
Um...
Oh, ah...
Baby.
Oh, ah, rocking.
Oh, I know this one.
Racehorse!
Cat. Scary cat.
Er, scary moose.
Scary dog?
I know, I know!
No?
Oh, Lindy Chamberlain.
That was appalling, Benji.
Who taught you that?
Mum did.
Lies! All lies!
I thought so.
Come on, Adam.
Up!
Time is against us.
And we have things to do.
Come on, you butch thing, you.
No, no, count me out.
All for one...
Come on, Tick.
No.
Hmm.
Come on, Adam. Let's get frocked.
So, uh...
...er, what's it like
to finally have a father?
It's OK.
I'm sorry about last night.
I don't always dress up
in women's clothes.
I mean, you know,
don't get the wrong idea.
Um...
I do a lot of different stuff.
You know,
like... Elvis and Gary Glitter.
Abba?
I'm not supposed to know
about the Abba show.
But I'd really like to see it.
Would you do Abba for me?
Sure.
You know what I am, don't you?
Mum says you're the best
in the business.
Ah, well, your mother was always
prone to exaggeration.
Will you have a boyfriend
when we're in Sydney?
Maybe.
That's good.
Come on!
Where are we going?
To unleash the best in the business.
I had a dream.
Well...
...we did it.
It never ends, does it?
All that space.
So, what now?
I think I want to go home.
Me too.
Well, then...
...let's finish the shows
and go home.
Don't go without leaving me
your number.
Already taken care of, Jeff.
It's at the bar end
of the men's cubicle -
"For a good time, phone Felicia. "
Can we stop at McDonald's?
Good idea.
I've had enough of this shitty food.
Fucking crayfish.
Where the hell do you start?
Lay it on the line, husband.
Don't conceal anything -
that's the key.
If he doesn't like it, stiff
bickies, he can always come back.
What happens when people
hear about Mitzi's minor?
That's your problem, not his.
Morals are a choice. He'll decide
his own when he's ready.
Well, that's it. You're all packed.
You're joking?! Bernadette's shoes
aren't on board yet.
Hate to say this -
wish I was going with you.
Your gas tank will be fine.
Your axle... may be another matter.
The road will be filled
with bored mechanics
hoping some drag queens
will spirit them away.
We won't spirit gum at this rate.
Where the hell's Bernadette?
Here.
Come on, cabanossi tits.
Where are your bags?
In my room.
I'm not going.
I'm staying here for a while.
Oh, really? And you're choosing
to tell us about this now?
She told me a few weeks back.
Somebody's got to handle the guest
entertainment while I'm away.
I get it.
Who's been playing hide the sausage?
Let's go before I throw up.
Come on, Benj.
Hope you can drive.
Hey, not without a hug!
Waaaa!
Are you sure?
No, I'm not sure.
I'll never know
unless I give it a shot.
I'm as jealous as all hell.
Shit! Raccoon time again.
Don't forget to write!
See ya!
Wish I was staying.
'Bye!
'Bye! Take care of her now!
'Bye, Mum. 'Bye, Ralph!
Yeah, see ya, Ralph!
I've been cheated by you
since I don't know when
So I've made up my mind
it must come to an end
Look at me now
Will I ever learn?
I don't know how
But I suddenly lose control
There's a fire within my soul
Just one look
and I can hear a bell ring
One more look
and I forget everything
WWhoa
Mama mia
Here I go again
My, my, how can I resist you?
Mama mia
Does it show again
My, my, just how much I missed you?
Yes, I've been broken-hearted
Blue since the day we parted
Why, why
did I ever let you go?
Mama mia
Now I really know
My, my,
I could never let you go...
I've been angry and sad
about things that you do
I can't count all the times
that I told you we're through
How can you go
when you slam the door?
I think you know
that you won't be away too long
You know that I'm not that strong
Just one look
and I can hear a bell ring
One more look
and I forget everything
WWhoa
Mama mia
Here I go again
My, my, how can I resist you?
Mama mia
Does it show again
My, my,
just how much I missed you?
Yes, I've been broken-hearted
Blue since the day we parted
Why, why
did I ever let you go?
Mama mia
Now I really know
Why, why
I could never let you go.
No, that's enough.
Oh, my tits are falling down!
Oh, Jesus!
Thank you!
Thank you. It's good to be home!
Sometimes the snow
comes down in June
Sometimes the sun
goes round the moon
I see the passion in your eyes
Sometimes it's all a big surprise
'Cause there was a time
when all I did was wish
You'd tell me this was love
It's not the way I hoped
or how I planned
But somehow it's enough
And now we're standing face to face
Isn't this world a crazy place?
Just when I thought
our chance had passed
You go and save the best for last
All of the nights you came to me
When some silly girl
had set you free
You wondered
how you'd make it through
I wondered what was wrong with you
'Cause how could you give your love
to someone else
And share your dreams with me?
Sometimes the very thing
you're looking for
Is the one thing you can't see
But now we're standing face to face
Isn't this world a crazy place?
Just when I thought
our chance had passed
You go and save the best for last
Sometimes the snow
comes down in June
Sometimes the sun
goes round the moon
Just when I thought
our chance had passed
You go and save the best for last
You went and saved the best...
...for last
Yeah, yeah.
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player