What are you doing?
Watching you.
Why?
Do you have anything
you want to tell me?
No.
Are you sure about that?
Let's go, let's go!
Hey, uh, quick reminder,
The jaymester and I
have tee-ball tonight!
- Anne, you're working late?
- Yup.
Okay, alice,
you can fend for yourself?
- Yup.
- Great, let's go!
Um...
Is there a reason we're
just looking at each other?
Is there anything new at school?
Any new...
Friends?
Okay, I don't know
why you're being weird.
That, right there.
That.
Who... who're you texting?
Your drug dealer?
Okay, if you must know...
I've been seeing this guy.
I knew it!
That's interesting.
Were you ever gonna tell us?
I'm telling you now.
Well, maybe you
should have mentioned
This information before,
you know, so that people have
All the information
they need to move forward
With all of the information.
You know how secrets
affect your father!
I think secrets affect
everyone, really.
Is it serious?
I mean... It's not...
Not serious...?
Okay, you should
really tell us when things
Are not "not serious"!
Why?
'cause...
Okay, mom, I'll be sure
to keep you posted
About everything that's going on
in my life from now on.
Like right now,
I have to get to school.
That's not such a bad secret!
I bet he's really nice.
Alright, mama's just
gotta get caffeinated,
And then I will be out the door.
Good morning!
I brought coffee.
Manifest that shit, right?
So, how was your bundle date?
Uh, it was...
It was good.
Now I need to find my...
Keys?
Thank you!
So, what'd you guys talk about?
You know, all the weird
thoughts and feelings
You have when you
bring home a baby,
The ones you think
you're the only one having.
He had some I hadn't even
thought of, actually.
I'm sorry, "he"?
Yeah, this guy
came in place of his wife
Who couldn't make it.
I thought bundle app
was for new mothers
To meet other new mothers.
I'm sorry, are you jealous?
How sweet!
I'm not...
no, I'm just saying,
I don't know how much
this dude can know about
Lactating at work and...
I'm meeting alyssa today,
the mom.
The real mom, and we're
gonna talk "mom" things.
And I'm gonna be late, so, uh...
Now I just need my...
Phone.
It's like you know what I need
before I need it.
And don't you forget it.
Sorry.
Have fun on
your date with alyssa.
Getting seedless on
"the best lay" was brilliant.
In fact, we'd love to open up
the fronterraverse...
Time out...
"fronterraverse"?
No?
It's no good?
Oh, that's terrible.
It's just something
I'm trying out.
- Fronterra-sphere?
- Oh, boy.
Fronterra-opolis?
I mean, let's stick
with "fronterraverse."
Least offensive.
Well... We would just love to
get your eyes on another product
That we're excited about.
Really?
Okay, what is it?
It's called horamo.
It's a migraine pill
that's tested extremely well
In clinical trials.
You know,
I used to get migraines.
If I overdo it with salt,
It's like a wrecking ball
to my head.
And they're brutal.
But horamo is a miracle pill,
And branding it as such is key.
So, if you're interested,
I would love to spitball
some angles with you.
Uh, yeah, for sure.
I got a bunch of meetings today,
But you wanna
come back around 4?
Or we could ditch the office,
Maybe go somewhere
a little more inspiring?
- I know just the place.
- Oh.
So, what do you say?
You up for a field trip?
Yeah, I love field trips.
Okay, great.
I will text you the address.
Oh, mysterious.
Where are we going
on this field trip, huh?
Pioneer village?
See what life
was like before, uh,
Pharmaceutical companies?
Yeah.
Okay.
Listen, seamus.
I've really enjoyed
our time together,
But I'm afraid
I have some bad news.
No bad news today, doc.
Good news only!
Well...
I finally got
the green light from my girl.
What does that mean?
Sex?
What, uh...
What happened
to taking things slow?
To the...
To the rush of waiting?
Yeah, that, um...
That ship's kinda sailed.
I mean, we're...
We're ready.
Yeah, so, alice...
That's her name...
Is it?
Yeah, so alice invited
me over to her place.
To my... to her house?
Are her parents cool with it?
They probably don't know.
They might.
Yeah, but I think they're
gonna be out around 5.
That's when she said
to come over.
Is that today?
It's all goin' down today?
That's the plan.
Wow.
That's so... Fast.
Five o'clock?
Five o'fucking clock!
I'm gonna break his knees.
I'm gonna break his
goddamn fucking knees!
Well, someone's sounding
like their old selves again.
And, sorry, what exactly
is your plan here?
Oh, I got a plan.
I cancelled my end of day,
outta here by 4,
And I'm heading straight home
to scare the shit
Out of my daughter and put
that boy in a body cast.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
slow down, alright?
I thought you liked this kid.
I thought you said he was
nice and fun and exciting.
I mean, maybe he'd
be good for alice.
Yeah, I don't want him
to deflower her!
But you do realize
you'll blow your cover
The second you walk
through that door.
Shit, I didn't think of that.
Um...
Uh, fuck, okay.
New plan.
I need you to do it.
- What? I can't!
- Why?
First of all, it's psycho.
Second, I've got
a client meeting.
Lemme guess,
with your work crush?
No.
Yes.
Augh, just forget it.
I'll do it myself.
You're gonna bone yourself!
Well, as long as I'm
the only one getting boned!
So, what do you think?
Ding, ding, ding.
We have a winner.
Really?
What's it worth?
Beaut like that, get you 4k.
Holy shit!
I mean, 6k.
3k.
Thirty-five.
- Sold.
- Shit!
Fine.
There you go.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
Okay, zoe, let's get outta here.
So, let's get you
a little treat.
But first, something for mommy!
Hand it over!
Whatever you got!
Get out of here, fuckwad!
Okay.
Yeah, oh fuck, fuck.
Fine, fine.
You let him take it?
What else am I supposed to do?
It won't stop coming.
I'm engorged all the time.
And now I have all this milk
that nobody wants or needs.
Oh, I tried wrapping them in
cabbage, but they won't dry up.
You've come to the right place.
We're currently
accepting donations.
Okay, let's go.
Just a few more.
Not too, too many more,
I don't think.
Unbelievable.
I am so sorry.
I'll be done in a minute.
No, what's unbelievable
is that you have so much milk
And you're not
trying to sell it.
I can sell it?
You know what, sheila?
I'll be in touch.
Thank you.
I heard this class
was pretty good.
Yeah, I just felt like I
should take it, you know?
Single mom in the city!
I was actually advised
to take it, by the cops,
After I got mugged.
On your feet!
Welcome to
the citizen self-defence class.
I am your instructor,
gary goldman.
Oh, no.
Oh, hell no!
How 'bout...
This one?
Doesn't scream "tasking" to me.
Right.
Hey, here's a thought:
Maybe we don't
Do the image thing
on every chapter?
It's maggie's vision
for the book.
Take a walk with it.
What else have we got?
No.
We've used this one before.
Next.
No, I don't think we have.
But it could work.
No, I'm sure
I've seen her before.
Trust me.
I never forget
a stock image face.
Sloane, should I move on?
Sure.
Now, what do I mean
when I say "head on a swivel"?
I mean I want you to be
aware of your surroundings
And any possible dangers
at all times, okay?
You're telling me
you're all here for him?
So, imagine that
I am your attacker.
Who wants to volunteer
for a demonstration?
Great, jenny.
Perfect.
Yeah, but I didn't volunteer.
Now, your assailant will
not ask for a volunteer either.
Alright, now,
an unwavering centre of gravity
Is important in this situation.
So I take a stance like this,
And I want you to try
and knock me off balance.
You know I'm freakishly strong.
If you say so.
What the fuck is in there?
You were ready for me.
So I want another shot.
Feel free to surprise me.
Hey!
There.
Now you gonna let me do my job?
Uh-huh.
Thank you, jenny.
What was that?
And, like,
how are you so strong?
And, like...
Well, I train a lot.
Shut up!
What am I even doing?
Something wrong?
I've tried everything, val.
My baby won't drink formula
And my own milk
has suddenly dried up!
It just so happens that I might
have something that can help.
It'll cost you, though.
Money's not an issue!
I just don't know what...
Shh, shh... Lemme get you
somethin' real nice.
Ah, ah!
You want the milk,
you gotta cough up the cheese.
Is that enough?
Thank you.
Oh, hey, any of you mamas
havin' trouble with your supply?
I got the good stuff.
Tit to table.
I don't fuck around.
Listen up.
I've been downing apricots.
Sardines.
Nothing but yolks.
Looks like that hungry little
baby needs an upgrade
From skim...
To cream.
I'll see you tomorrow.
There you go.
Got your purple nerp, your
dairy daze, classic og skim.
Any takers for some
super sour grandma skunk?
Hey!
Me again!
Aw, wife couldn't make it?
No, no, no, no.
She got caught up
in another meeting, so...
Where's your... Baby?
Who are you and what the fuck
do you want from me?
What?
What are you talking about?
Is your wife
a stock photo model?
Okay, alright.
I'm sorry.
I saw your profile
on my sister's bundle app
And I borrowed her kid,
Because I'm an author
And I really would hope that you
would read my manuscript.
Oh, this is great.
It is great.
It's, um, a fantasy novel...
Yeah, of course it is.
About a cynical teen.
So, catcher in the rye.
He and his friends,
they get stranded.
Mm, meets lord of the flies.
But get this... he's a wizard!
Meets harry fucking potter!
Is there an original thought
in your head anywhere?
Whoa, you don't
have to be so mean!
No wonder you need
an app to find friends.
Yeah, that's right, I do.
Because new motherhood
is isolating.
And it's really hard to find
friends going through that
When you work as hard as I do.
Which you can't relate to,
since you're too busy
Borrowing babies to bait
and stalk innocent women.
You know what?
That's actually
a great idea for a book.
I might green-light that.
Really?
Should we work on that?
You might wanna fuck off.
When I look back on it,
I think my marriage
was destined to fail.
I think I've always been trying
to re-create a family unit...
- Mm.
- Ever since
My parents were ripped away
from me in the accident.
And that's our time, mark!
Okay.
I'm sorry to rush you,
I just... I have somewhere to be.
Uh, is it okay if I use
your bathroom real quick?
Oh, yeah.
There's just...
There's just a key that I
need you to return, so...
Uh, please?
Oh, uh, okay, if you could just,
uh, maybe be quick about it.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- You got it.
- Yup, thanks.
Hey, I don't mean to be rude,
But are you almost
done in there?
Uh, I'll just be a second!
Okay, it's just that it's
a bit of an emergency for me.
Mark?
Just... just keep the key!
Fuck!
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck!
Shit, fuck!
Okay...
Oh, hey!
I had a little oopsie!
I dinged your bumper.
I was about to leave you a note!
I'm so sorry!
No, it's okay!
No, no, I want to do things the
right way, okay, so I think...
My daughter is about
to be penetrated!
Please move, come on!
Centre?
This is your goldmine
of inspiration?
Look, you laugh,
but I've come up with
Some pretty
sophisticated ideas here.
Uh-huh.
Oh!
Okay, trust me.
- This is the place.
- Okay.
We just gotta try
and keep an open mind.
Alright, open.
We just...
- Mmm.
- Mm-hm.
Oh, I'm inspired.
Okay, maybe this is just
not the right display.
- Okay.
- Okay, let's, let's...
Okay.
This could be something
right here.
Uh...
No, yeah, it's nothing.
It's nothing.
How about a wrecking ball
to the skull, right?
Ooh!
How about, like, a woodpecker
right at your temple?
I mean, it's less impact...
Uh...
A little cartoony, maybe?
- Cartoony, cartoony.
- Something better.
- We don't like cartoons.
- No, no.
What... what...
What is this?
It's inspirational,
is what it is.
Clearly you've brought me
to the goldmine.
Okay, alright.
We're trying... I'm trying.
You are trying!
I'm so sorry,
I have to take this.
Uh, you wanna wrangle up
some of those dino costumes?
Maybe that'll help?
Hey, what's up?
Would you mind picking up
Some cheese on your way home
for pizza night?
Ella threw it
all over the floor.
Shit, I'm so sorry.
I'm, uh...
I'm gonna be late.
I'm brainstorming
a new drug for fronterra.
Oh, okay.
Just gonna eat at
the office, then?
I'm, uh...
I'm not at the office.
I'm at the science centre.
Cool.
That sounds fun.
You out there with
the whole team?
No, uh, it's funny, I'm just...
It's just ram and I.
The fronterra ceo.
Oh...
Okay.
Yeah.
Yeah, apparently it's a good
place to generate ideas.
I'm not sold yet.
Right.
Well...
You two have fun.
I mean, it's not gonna be fun.
Just work.
Anyway, I love you.
Bye!
- Hey.
- Mm, hi!
Uh, there's something
I want to show you.
Cool.
Let's get to work.
Okay...
I see the appeal.
- Right?
- Wow...
Oh my god.
Okay, what's that one?
Is that orion?
That's uranus.
Oh.
Oh, what's that one?
Ah, that's also uranus.
You don't know
what any of these are?
No!
I don't have to know
what they are to be amazed.
Call me a dork,
but when I need it,
This room is my escape.
I totally get it.
For me, it's the aquarium.
Another great place to look at
shit you know nothing about.
Yeah?
Man, it's quiet in here.
Yeah.
I mean, that's kinda
why I love it.
The outside world's all gone.
No noise, no distractions.
It's all gone.
Your headache,
the pain, the migraine.
"it's all gone."
Yeah, I like it.
Yeah, it's simple,
it's straightforward.
Yeah, it's a good
place to start.
I guess this place
isn't just for kids.
Alright, astro-boys and girls,
Get ready for blast-off!
Oh my god.
Clearly for children.
Is it?
Two-hundred
billion trillion stars.
Pick up, pick up, pick up!
Come on!
Hi, this is alice.
Please leave a message.
Fuck.
Turn off this goddamn...
Fuck sakes.
Hey, man!
Hey, is there any way
I can squeeze through?
No can do.
Gonna be another 10.
You can take bloor across.
What?
That's gonna take forever!
Put on a podcast.
Fucking put on a podcast...
Ugh!
Why does god hate me?!
Jesus fucking christ!
Gah!
Oh my god, oh my god, oh my god!
Alice!
Okay, you're by yourself.
I can work with this.
Mom!
What are you doing here?
I just, I thought that you...
Wait...
What are you looking at?
Your hair...
Cheeks...
Sweat beads...
Oh...
God, you did it, didn't you?
You motherfucker!
You had sex with my daughter?
Wait, doc, you're her mom?
You're his doctor?
- She's your daughter?
- He's your patient?
No more questions!
Who wants dinner?
Why are you all home?
Who's this?
What the fuck is that?!
- Oh my god!
Nobody move, nobody move!
Oh my god!
- Lionel, get it!
- It's getting away!
Okay!
I got 'er!
I got 'er.
Ha-ha!
Sorry, who are you?