Knockout week continues
on MasterChef.
The first eight contestants have
cooked their take
on John and Gregg's special brief.
I think it is superb.
Alex, George
and David stood out.
Now the remaining eight
get their chance
to secure their place in
the competition...
We now know what the standard is.
It's up to the second eight to
match it, or surpass it.
Good to see you. As you know,
the first eight contestants
have already cooked.
You have got to prove you're good
enough to go further.
We want from you one plate of food
inspired by a personal
or a family favourite.
At the end of this, four cooks will
be leaving the competition.
Ladies and gentlemen, 90 minutes,
let's cook.
Louise is our Welsh fitness
instructor.
We love her energy, and she's a
homely cook.
This is a great brief for Louise.
I'm making Welsh lamb cawl
with parsley and Caerphilly cheese
soda bread.
The translation from cawl into
English means soup, or broth.
The broth is going to be a consomme,
rather than a big hearty
bowl of cawl.
It's such a family favourite,
and it just means so much.
My mother's had a tough two years
so, yeah, I'm getting a
bit choked now,
but it's been a tough two years,
and I wanted to make something that
really made me think of her today.
Louise is going to clarify stock
to make a consomme.
If she gets the egg white wrong,
if she gets the stock
temperature wrong,
then the whole thing becomes
a cloudy mess.
When I'm cooking it, I'll be
thinking of my mother,
my grandmother.
I've got to do it justice, you know,
for myself, but for Wales!
Anthony is daring, he is bold and
his food is fun!
What he's got up his sleeve?
I have no idea!
I kind of like a dish to have a bit
of a back story.
I think it's nice to tell people
about the food and where it's from.
It's getting to the point now where
I've proven something in myself,
and I kind of want to see
how good I can be...
I'm making something based on a
Norwegian dish which I like
called plukkfisk.
Mashed potatoes, root vegetables,
fish and bacon.
And then this stuff here, this is
called brunost.
It's popular in Norway,
it's a caramelised cheese.
Why this dish then, Anthony?
My dad's mother's side of the
family, they're Norwegian.
It's kind of everything that
sums up Norway, in my opinion,
because it's all grassy flavours,
herbs.
Quite subtle but hopefully
enough flavour
to kind of be a bit, like,
substantial.
I can get fish, bacon and mash?
That's fine. But where does
caramelised cheese
fit with bacon and fish?
Nawamin is as flamboyant in his
nature as he is in his cookery.
That first round with the noodles
and the crab with the little bonbon
was absolutely fantastic.
Basically, my childhood memory
is cooking.
Making curry paste,
making coconut milk.
I want people to fall in love
with Thai food as I do.
By the looks of it, Nawamin, you're
doing a dessert?
So I'm going to make you coconut
sticky rice
with caramelised coconut,
butterfly pea and coconut sauce,
and white chocolate.
Today's dish is my grandmother's
favourite dish.
She loved it so much but she can't
eat it any more because she is
suffering from diabetes.
As a doctor, I want to see
her healthy,
but as a grandson, I want to see
her happy to eat this dish.
Nawamin has got coconut rice,
coconut tuile stuffed with coconut
and a coconut custard
to wash it all down with.
That boy and his nan
loved coconut!
On the side he's got butterfly pea
flowers which go bright blue,
so we've got this blue colour
running through the whole thing.
Kenny seems to have the lot.
Knowledge, skill, ability.
He goes the extra mile,
and his fig tart was delicious!
What are you going to cook for us?
Basically the story behind it is
my first real proper holiday with
my wife was to Mexico,
when we found this taco stand, loads
of bus drivers queueing up for it,
2 a taco, but the best
thing I've ever eaten.
So I'm doing this take on a taco.
It's got the corn tortilla,
pork, avocado.
It's got some charred baby corn
and some pickled onions.
I don't know about you, but I'm
really excited about Kenny's taco!
It's got lots and lots of spices,
including ancho chillies,
loads and loads of cumin.
For me, food is about the
experience.
I want them to want to eat it
and get stuck in.
I want it to be that sort of dish.
Guys, you're halfway.
45 minutes left, please.
James, now, there's a cook with some
very modern ideas.
Herb flavoured salts
across his sauces.
He's good, John.
James, what are you cooking for us?
I always used to play rugby,
lots of different sports.
And when I came back, all kind of
cold or muddy, or whatever,
I always loved having a
lovely kind of stew.
I don't really have enough time to
do a stew,
so I'm doing an inspired venison
with some mash, some Brussels,
honeyed walnuts and a red wine
blackberry jus.
What is... What is that?
So that is from 1694,
that was my...
I think it's about five greats,
so my great, great, great, great,
great grandmother's recipe book.
Brilliant! A little bit of nutmeg in
my mash that is kind of inspired
from the cookbook there.
James is doing a venison with
a blackberry sauce,
which is fine on its own but in a
room full of exciting dishes
from all over the world, it could
come up looking a little bit safe.
Nisha, I can honestly say, John,
I have loved everything
she has cooked.
The food I'm cooking today,
there's a skill in there,
a very old-fashioned art that I'm
bringing back.
I'm really excited to cook this.
I'm making a trio of Indian tapas,
and this is a mixture of yoghurt,
gram flour, it's got a bit of
ginger and chilli in it.
Once they dry, I'm going to roll up
into little sort of pasta rolls.
The second one is
an aloo tikki chaat,
which is like a spiced
potato cake.
And my last one is a crab potli
with a passion fruit chutney.
I have three aunties.
They bring these three dishes along
to whichever celebration
we're doing.
There's a lot to do here.
There's a lot to do but I want to
show you skills,
different things you might not
have seen before.
We've got this Indian pasta,
which is made from yoghurt
and gram flour,
a little potato pancake,
and then we've got a little tiny
wonton with crab inside it,
served with a passion fruit dip.
Let's just hope they all work
together as a collective.
You have 30 minutes left.
Just 30 minutes.
Greg does dainty, delicate food.
Almost minimalist food.
Very, very modern indeed.
Greg's going to cook us a lamb,
rosemary, thyme and olives
with juniper,
then he's got rosemary potatoes with
loads and loads of garlic.
That's fantastic, but it's all going
to be in Greg's style.
Why this lamb dish?
I got married two years ago in
Santorini. It was a fantastic day.
My wife looked amazing,
and they cooked a piece of
lamb for like 14 hours.
I haven't got 14 hours,
but the essence of the flavours
are all here.
With all these flavours
of Santorini,
where do the blueberries come in?
That's my little slant on it,
that's just going to give you that
little Greg piece in there as well!
It could split the judges,
but I'm not concerned about that.
As long as I deliver it how I want
to cook it, I'll be happy.
Moonira gets through twice
the amount of work
of any other contestant.
When she cooks family food and food
for a feast, it's brilliant.
I love to show off my food,
because I know it tastes good.
It's a traditional recipe that has
been passed down.
So as long as I cook it well
and the flavours are there,
hopefully they're going to like it.
I'm doing a chicken chilman biryani,
sealed with a puff pastry top to
keep the flavours in,
and some spinach and potato pakoras.
It brings back very happy memories.
The smell, the taste.
As a child, I knew that something
special was happening
or somebody was coming,
and that was amazing.
It really made me happy.
I want that biryani to really sing.
That chicken has got to be
brilliantly cooked inside,
and she's got to get flavour into
there without overpowering it.
Listen up, you have three minutes!
Three minutes!
Time's up!
That looks incredible!
You're so artistic!
I'm so proud.
Louise, come and join us.
Fitness instructor Louise has made a
lamb and root vegetable consomme
served with braised lamb neck,
leeks, potatoes,
and a parsley and Caerphilly cheese
soda bread.
Your consomme itself is rich and
tastes of lamb and vegetables,
and I love that. I love the salty
cheese inside your soda bread.
You've got a light
crust around the outside.
I'm really impressed. Oh!
When you dunk that
salty, tangy cheese
on your very good soda bread
inside that consomme,
the whole thing comes alive.
It's a light, tasty, beautiful
bowl of broth.
You're very happy, aren't you? This
really meant a lot to me today.
For my mother. So...
Sorry! Well... What's Mum's name?
Faye. Well, well done, Faye.
You've taught your
little girl very well.
Ambulance call operator Anthony has
cooked Norwegian plukkfisk,
salt cod with parsley and celeriac
mash, caramelised cheese mash,
smoky bacon and a bechamel sauce.
I based it off a Norwegian
mountain scene,
so it's quite sort of green
and grassy.
Is the bacon the waves?
It is, yeah!
Your fish is cooked really, really
beautifully.
It falls apart. The cheese, smoky
bacon, mashed potatoes, dill...
..that's quite comforting.
That caramelised cheese, it's not
over tangy like a Cheddar would be.
It's a kind of mildly sweet,
very nice accompaniment.
But that dish looks shocking!
Don't misunderstand me, Anthony,
I think food can be fun.
But it's got to look more elegant
than this if you are serious
about this competition.
I shouldn't have put so much on
the plate.
They liked the taste of it, though,
I'm happy about that.
I'd much rather be that way
than the other way around.
Bank manager Kenny has cooked a
pulled pork taco
on a smoked corn tortilla,
served with avocado puree,
chorizo crema, pickled onions,
deep-fried jalapeno peppers,
and charred baby corn.
Kenny, your pork is great.
It's really nicely flavoured,
it's still moist and I like the way
it falls apart.
I like your pickled onions
around the outside.
What I really want right now is a
big stack more of the tortillas,
a load more avocado, a lot more of
that mayonnaise,
because that's great.
For the sake of presentation,
we're losing,
I think, the heart of the dish.
However, the flavours that you've
got on there
are very, very good indeed.
I just want more, Kenny.
Totally get what they mean about
keeping the soul in food,
but the flavours of the taco
were there.
So, in that respect,
I'm really happy.
IT manager Greg has cooked
Greek-inspired cannon of lamb
served with rosemary potatoes,
compressed cucumber, lemon yoghurt,
a juniper and olive crumb,
dehydrated blueberries,
and a spiced wine
and Greek molasses reduction.
I've never seen potatoes so small.
It's tiny! I know.
Your lamb is cooked perfectly.
And the depth of sweetness of that
blueberry is lovely
against the tart yoghurt.
These are lovely, lovely
flavour combinations, Greg.
I think this is your best dish
so far, mate.
The big surprise for me -
the juniper, the blueberry,
the cucumber and the lamb.
Because suddenly you get all
those lovely spikes,
so you feel as though you may be
on a Greek island.
Really, really fascinating,
and delicious!
Thank you very much. Thank you.
I'm in shock, I can't quite process
what happened!
I didn't expect such an outpouring
from them.
Oh, well done!
Nisha has cooked a trio of Indian
tapas -
sweet potato cake on spicy
chickpeas,
topped with pomegranate
and a yoghurt, tamarind
and coriander chutney.
Chickpea flour and yoghurt rolls,
with a curry leaf, coriander and
coconut dressing,
and a crab potli,
crispy Indian wonton filled
with chilli,
garlic and lemon crab
with a passion fruit chutney.
I really like your crab wonton,
all that beautiful,
fresh crab meat inside quite a thin,
beautifully crisp wrapper.
The potato has got a sweetness to it
that I really like.
The one in the middle,
I'm not too sure about.
It tastes, to me,
like an unsauced pasta.
These little rolls, I want more of
those curry leaves,
and I want more of that coconut
across the top of it
so I can taste that, because that's
where the flavour is.
The rest of it,
I think, is really good.
That was a bit mixed.
I think, overall, they did like it.
I shouldn't be too down about it,
but I think it's the first sort of
real critique I've had.
Wine salesman James has cooked
venison, served with nutmeg mash,
Brussels sprouts, blackberries,
honeyed walnuts, shallots,
and a blackberry and red wine jus.
You have nicely cooked venison.
Nutmeg on the mash is a nice idea,
it gives it a sweetness.
That sauce, however,
does need to be thicker,
because it's the sauce that is going
to make that whole dish.
The potato needs a lot more
seasoning in it.
The Brussels sprouts, more buttery.
The issue here is, James,
that it hasn't been elevated.
Because this is a plate of food
which looks great,
but doesn't taste fantastic.
It wasn't the comments
I was kind of hoping for,
maybe I played it too safe.
We'll just have to wait and see.
Pharmacist Moonira has made a
chilman chicken biryani
with a pastry top,
served with spinach and potato
pakoras,
carrot and cucumber raita,
mango chutney
and poppadoms.
Looks great.
The bottom of that biryani,
there is turmeric, cumin,
absolutely loads of garlic
and ginger.
Soft, sweet chicken.
The rice is cooked very,
very nicely.
That's great.
You made your own poppadoms.
Fabulous, that's really good
as well.
I like the saltiness
on your pakoras.
I love the depth of flavour
on your mango chutney,
but that biryani
is an absolute triumph!
It's layer upon layer
of beautiful flavour.
I cannot praise you enough.
I'm really, really surprised,
really shocked.
I don't think I could have asked
for any more. So, I'm really happy.
Thank you.
Scented with a Thai aromatic smoke,
Nawamin has served a white chocolate
and coconut swan
with coconut sticky rice,
caramelised coconut,
set coconut custard,
golden coconut tuiles,
stuffed with fresh coconut
and toasted sesame seeds,
and a butterfly pea coconut sauce.
# Da da-da-da-da-da!
# Da-da-da-da-da. #
That's brilliant!
A swan with a blue sauce? Wow.
I tasted the blue custard
on its own,
and just couldn't understand it at
all, because it's salty.
I thought, what has he done?
But, actually, when you taste it
with all that beautiful,
sweet coconut sugary stickiness,
it's absolutely delicious!
And how you've played around with
that coconut
to make different textures,
I think is brilliant.
I think the amount of work that's in
there is incredible.
I love these little coconut tuiles
with coconut meat inside
and sesame seeds.
I think they're
absolutely delicious.
It's out of your imagination, and
it's a wild imagination you have!
I'm feeling so happy,
I'm feeling, like,
over the moon about those comments
with this dish.
I'm just so happy.
We've now seen all 16 of you cook.
We're going to work out which cooks
are going through to the next round,
and which four cooks are leaving
the competition.
Thank you very much.
I've got to say, I thought that was
a fantastic round.
I'm really, really impressed.
John, we had some brilliant dishes
in here today.
Nawamin's dessert was absolutely
fantastic.
John, it looked amazing
and it tasted great!
Greg took the memory of Santorini
and put it in Greg style.
Beautiful flavour. Delicate, light,
and actually looked a picture.
Well done, Greg!
Louise, that consomme was
beautifully flavoured,
and once you put that salty cheese
bread inside,
the whole thing came alive.
I like Moonira's biryani.
I thought that was delicious.
And delivering it all in 90 minutes?
Exceptional cook.
Kenny made us a taco, and what a
taco it was.
He can cook, and he's got some very
clever ideas.
So they definitely go through
with George,
Alex and David from the last round.
Do you not agree that Anthony
and Nisha have done enough
to secure themselves a place
in the next round?
Am I prepared to give them
another chance?
Yes. They're both exciting cooks.
Right, so that now leaves us with
six cooks left over.
We've only got two more places
to give,
four of them are going to be
leaving the competition.
James cooked for us venison
with blackberries.
It was a decent plate of food,
but it wasn't inspiring.
If I did leave today, I'd be gutted,
but I can only hope.
Chris has got a good touch.
He knows how to cook a pheasant.
He knows how to make a good, decent
pommes Anna.
However, he doesn't appear,
at the moment,
to know how to finish
a dish beautifully.
I'm feeling fairly nervous
about the outcome.
I don't think I've really nailed
this one.
Simon can cook.
He made a very good pie. Should it
have had Chinese duck in it?
I'm not sure.
Yeah, it's huge.
I'm loving this competition.
I don't want that to be the
lasting memory of me.
Mary, the liver she cooked for us
with polenta and honeyed onions
was unusual.
Also, she still hasn't
managed to nail presentation.
The thing is, there's so many
good cooks there.
I don't know whether I've done
enough to stay in the competition.
I just hope so.
Zaleha, that chicken
didn't work for me.
I mean, the skin wasn't cooked and
the sauce was on the skin.
I worked really hard today, so...
fingers crossed!
Sweta has had better rounds.
A mismatch of different dishes
from around Asia,
and not all of them
particularly well done.
Lesson learned, less is more
for next time.
If I go through.
Who do you believe has really got
the ability to up their game?
Not just move forward
but challenge the better cooks?
We said right at the start that four
of you
would be leaving this competition.
We have now made that decision.
From the first group that cooked,
Gregg and I thought there were three
who are absolutely outstanding.
Alex.
George.
David.
Congratulations, guys, you are
through to the next round.
From the second round, there were
five outstanding cooks.
Nawamin.
Greg.
Moonira.
Louise.
And Kenny.
Nisha, Anthony,
you also have done enough to secure
yourself a place
in the next round, congratulations.
We only have two more places.
The four cooks leaving the
competition are...
Sweta.
Mary.
James.
And Zaleha.
Guys, you had a great competition,
you've been brilliant, thank you.
I feel so disappointed.
At the end of the day, I did my best
but it didn't work.
I know that at any stage you're
going to leave,
it's always going to be awful,
so I've come quite far,
so I'm quite happy with that.
Really gutted because
I wanted to do more.
But it was an amazing journey
and I really appreciate that.
I'll miss all of this.
But, you know,
it'll live in my memory forever.
You did so well!
Very, very well done.
You guys are well on your way.
My heart was pumping out of my chest
in the line-up.
I feel absolutely amazing.
I dodged a bullet today
but it's really exciting.
I've just got to up game now.
I feel incredible,
really, really happy.
I am starting to believe in myself.
I am.
On Wednesday night,
the contestants are split into two
groups and six of them...
One minute on the pass, please.
..get their first taste of a
professional kitchen...
Time is over.
Pass me this food.
..before having to
impress one of the industry's most
respected chefs.
That's a very, very well
accomplished plate of food.