Can't he go any faster, Jesse?
Goin' fast enough, Ed.
- You watch them people, Frank.
- Shut up, Ed!
- What about that safe?
- There ain't no safe, Ed.
All the money's in the strongbox
and in the cash drawers.
I don't believe you!
You got a safe in here someplace.
You tell me where it is,
or I'm gonna put a bullet in your brain.
- Honest, Mister.
- Get out of here, Ed!
Are you going crazy, Ed?
Watch it, Jesse!
Jesse!
How long you think it'll take
that posse to get here?
There won't be one.
They'll go about 10 miles and get tired
and go back and call the Pinkertons.
- How come we're standing guard?
- 'Cause every once in a while, I'm wrong.
We'll take you upriver to Mimm's house.
Get the bullet out there.
- You stay quiet, now.
- Yeah.
Come here, Ed.
Jesse! Jesse!
- Shit, what'd you do that for?
- For panickin' and shootin' innocent folks.
Jesse!
That's for goddamn getting me near killed!
Shit, I didn't mean no harm.
You're through, Ed.
You ain't gonna ride with me no more.
You gonna take that off him?
I seen what you done.
You may be family and everything,
but I ain't sidin' with you.
You're on your own.
Cole, give him his cut.
You threw yourself away a good livin'.
Now, listen good.
Anybody connects the Jameses
or the Youngers with that bank...
...you're a dead man.
Hey, now, I saw her first.
Step back away. I saw her first.
What the hell was that all about?
Damned if I know.
"And although he may be poor
"Not a man shall be a slave
"Shoutin' the battle
"Cry of freedom"
You boys hear what I hear?
I hear it.
Yeah, better go talk to this fella.
I'm out.
"From the east and from the west
"Shouting the battle cry of freedom
"And we'll prove a loyal crew"
You've got real nice hands.
They're real pretty.
You want to keep them?
It was just a request.
Well, I got a request of my own.
I'm a Good Ol' Rebel.
"Oh, I'm a good old rebel
"Now, that's just what I am
"For this fair land of freedom
"I do not care a damn
"I'm glad I fought against it
"I only wish we'd won
"And I don't want no pardon
"For anything I done"
You keep losin', at this rate...
...you'll have to go out
and rob another train.
And scare some more innocent folk
half to death.
"I hates the declaration... "
- Never liked people standing behind me.
- Well, most people would be flattered.
Ain't often Belle Shirley
stands behind a man.
I reckon that's the truth.
"I fought it all I could"
Are you still asking $15?
I sure am.
Well, ain't nothing worth that price.
Well...
...I don't figure I'll miss much.
But I'll tell you what I will do.
I'll go $12.50 for you,
since you're about to go broke.
I only got $11.
Cut you for it.
Make your move.
I'll be go to hell.
When your luck changes,
you feel free to call on me.
Everybody ante up, huh?
Women.
Love 'em.
We's all in the war.
Robbed a first Yankee bank...
...'cause we didn't know no better.
It seemed like a good idea at the time.
After that, we's just in the habit.
So I guess we'll just keep on going...
...till they lock us up or hang us.
You've hardly given yourself
time enough to heal.
I gotta get back to things.
Ma needs money to help
keep the farm going.
I reckon your ma can keep the farm going
and a few more things to boot.
Well, the others ain't no good without me.
They gotta have somebody
to make the plans.
But...
...don't worry, Zee.
I'm coming back for you.
Thought you'd be over with that Tebbs girl.
Maybe I oughta be.
She's awfully pretty, ain't she?
If you think so.
'Course, every fellow around here's
been to visit her.
I don't guess you have
that problem, do you, Beth?
I have just as many visitors as I want.
- And you can count on it.
- Like who, for instance?
That's for me to know and you to find out.
How am I supposed to find out
if you won't tell me?
Jim Younger, there are some things
that a man does not ask a lady.
When you're old enough to call
yourself a lady, I'll keep that in mind.
Think maybe you oughta get married.
Is that what you want?
Seems that you proposed to me
during the war about seven years ago.
That was different.
'Cept...
...I always knew that you were the one.
I just didn't have nothing
worked out, that's all.
That's a mouthful, Mr. Jesse James.
Well, it's a mouthful of truth.
Now, what you gotta decide is if
you want to get on the horse with me.
Now, I'm gonna be honest about it, Zee.
I ain't gonna change the way I live.
Well...
...it ain't right to try to change a person.
Truth is, Jesse, I wouldn't
like you any other way.
Next thing you know,
they'll get married and settle down.
First part, anyway.
He's asking her today.
Doesn't go with the way he's living.
He'll be fine.
First gettin' shot, then gettin' married.
Bad habits.
I'd like to have a white dress...
...and a proper weddin'.
Sounds like you want
the whole county there.
I do.
A girl only gets married once, you know?
I never was the marrying kind myself.
Kind of life I lead, women just felt troubled.
Footloose and fancy free, that's my style.
What about you, friend?
I ain't felt the call yet, but...
...if I was to meet a gal
as nice and pretty as this one here...
...I expect I could be persuaded.
I tell you something, Mister.
You best be watching your mouth...
...and not looking at my wife here.
Sorry.
Didn't mean no disrespect.
'Course he didn't. Just bein' polite.
Hey, old man, put a cork in it a while.
Vernon, be polite.
Goddamn outlaws.
Vernon, why don't you
just hand that over here?
Damn. You son of a bitch,
you're in it with 'em.
I would toss that shotgun away.
Throw down the box.
Any of you men fight
for the Stars and Bars?
Yes, sir. Proud of it.
May I shake your hand?
Bob Younger.
- George. George Arthur.
- Who were you with, George?
General Joe Shelby.
What about you?
- I was with Shelby, too.
- Where?
Coleharbor.
Shelby weren't at Coleharbor.
You're a goddamned liar.
- Should I kill him?
- I would. I'd shoot the son of a bitch.
Bob, I want you to take
everything he has. You hear?
- Everything.
- Let me give you a hand.
You're lucky you ain't dead,
you son of a bitch.
Hope we didn't disturb
you too much, ma'am.
- Didn't mean you no harm.
- You scum! Take your hands off my wife.
If you shut up,
maybe I won't put a bullet in you.
Forgive me for saying so, ma'am but you
could've done better than Vernon here.
I'll be goddamned and go to hell.
"Jack of diamonds, jack of diamonds
"I know you from old
"You robbed my poor pockets
"Of silver and gold"
- Most people knock.
- I expect they do.
How many women you visited
before you come to see me?
This is my first stop.
Well, here I am.
"I'll bring the blind by way they know not.
"I will lead them into paths
they have not known.
"I will make darkness
light before them and...
"... I'll make crooked things straight. "
Isaiah: 42:16.
"Poor drunkard, poor drunkard
"How bad I do feel"
You and me seem to be
gettin' along real good.
You might think about makin'
an honest woman out of me.
- You're serious, aren't you?
- Don't I sound it?
Well, then you gotta be crazy.
Just want to find out what it
feels like to be respectable.
For a while, anyway.
You'll never be respectable, Belle.
You're a whore.
You'll always be a whore.
It's why I like you.
Ready?
One.
Two.
Three.
- How you been, Beth?
- Fine.
Ain't you heard the news?
I'm engaged to Ed Miller.
Ed Miller?
He ain't no good.
- Besides, you're too young for all that.
- I'm 19 on the 23rd of September.
I don't want to wait around
forever like Zee did.
I don't want you saying
nothing bad about Ed...
...just 'cause Jesse picked on him.
Wasn't but a few months ago
I was pushing you in a swing.
Well, while you was pushing,
other people was noticing.
I noticed you, Beth.
You don't want to rush into things, Beth.
You can't undo 'em later.
I can't undo this one.
Ed's already bought land
over past Russellville.
'Sides, we told everybody.
Well, ain't much else to say, I guess.
You can wish me a good life.
I wish you that.
What you got to say for yourself, Jim?
Not much, Ed.
Be seeing you around.
How you been, Ed?
Oh, I'm fine.
How you doin', Clell?
Oh, I'm gettin' on pretty good.
This is my girl here. This is Beth Mimms.
We're gettin' married.
I heard you two took up together.
It's good to see you, Beth.
I'm doin' real fine, Clell.
Don't miss you boys none.
Come on, Beth.
Let's get to dancing here.
You scared?
Little bit. I expect I am.
Just walk up to 'em real steady, though.
We got nothin' to lose.
Now you let me do the talking, Bob.
You got that?
Say, do I look ok?
You look fine, Charlie.
You Frank James?
Who wants to know?
Charlie Ford, his little brother Bob.
What the hell you boys doin' here?
We want to join up.
We heard you were lookin'
for some new men.
Where'd you hear it from?
Your brother.
There ain't a horse we can't ride,
target we can't hit...
...or bank we can't rob.
You know how it is.
It was there. It seemed easy.
Just hauled out our guns
and made off with it.
Up in Joplin it was.
They chased us for two days.
You know how it is,
being out on the trail and all.
We only been out once, but we're willing.
What the hell were we talkin' about?
Hey, Coleman Younger!
Come on over here and say hello.
Evenin', ma'am.
Looks like everybody's havin'
a real good time at this affair.
I expect so.
Free drinks and food and all.
How come I wasn't invited?
'Cause you're a whore.
Yeah, well, at least I ain't a cheap one.
- See you later, Jess.
- See you, Jim.
- Bye.
- Bye, Zee.
Ain't gonna be too long that'll
be you and me, eh, Beth?
I reckon.
How are you?
I hear you bought a horse today.
I got a question for you.
Fire away, Frank.
Fire away and fall back.
You ever been in love?
Oh, God.
Yeah.
It was terrible.
An affliction.
Really miserable. Nothin' but trouble.
Drove me crazy.
That bad? Really?
Yeah.
She was wonderful.
What the hell you aiming to do?
I ain't aiming to do nothin'.
I'm doing it.
- Who are you, Jesse James?
- Hell, no. I'm Bob Younger.
Jesse James rides with the Youngers.
Now stop the damn train.
Don't worry, ladies and gentlemen.
We're just taking a permanent loan
from the Rock Island payroll.
Pinkerton Company, in conjunction with
the Union Pacific Railroad...
...is offering a reward of $5,000...
...for information leading to the arrest of
any member of the James-Younger gang.
- Mr. Rixley?
- That's right.
I'm Carl Reddick.
New York Herald sent me out...
...to cover the story
of the James-Younger gang.
You might say I'm interested
in the same thing.
What do you think your chances
are of bringing 'em in?
That's an amazingly stupid question.
I want your sons, Mrs. Samuel.
- What do you want 'em for?
- For robbing banks and trains.
Then you Yankees can just turn
around and head on back.
Sounds like you got
the wrong James family.
Yes, ma'am, I am a Yankee and a city man.
But these men with me here,
they're southern.
They rode with the Stars and Bars
during the struggle.
What are they chasing my boys for then?
Because they steal, ma'am.
I'm afraid I'll have to go
in there and look for 'em.
This paper here gives me
the right to do that.
Things have come to a pretty place
when a widow woman...
...with a 15-year-old backward baby boy...
...gets treated like this,
and they call it legal!
I am sorry, ma'am.
How come I never been asked?
Maybe you ain't cut out for it.
We got enough hands the way it is.
You keep me in mind.
I can rob banks as good as them
Millers or your brother Bob.
- Ain't nothin' to it.
- Think so?
Shit, what's to know
about robbing a bank?
You ride into town like
thunder and cannonballs...
...guns blazin', scaring the Jesus
out of everyone in sight...
...until they're frozen.
Then you ride right
in the bank on your horse...
...you dynamite the safe
and ride off with the loot.
Hootin' and hollerin'
same damn way as you came in.
That right?
Good afternoon.
Afternoon.
What's the trouble, friend?
No trouble.
We're looking for the Youngers.
You know them?
Sure I do.
Lot of 'em around these parts.
Big family.
- Who are you fellas?
- Come here to buy cattle.
This ain't Texas.
What about the Youngers?
You're lookin' at two of 'em.
And you ain't here to buy cattle.
Who are you fellas?
Goddamn Pinkertons!
- Which Younger are you?
- Question is who are you?
I told you.
- We're cattle buyers.
- How dumb you think we are?
You're Pinkerton men!
I'm Jim Younger.
This is my cousin John. You ain't lookin'
for him, he don't ride with us.
Is that right?
I told you he was my cousin.
He never rode with us once.
Eighteen years old, and I gotta take
him back to his family dead.
You broke the law.
People say they got one of the Youngers.
People say they got the wrong Younger.
Stand back.
All right, now everybody ready.
Wait for 'em to come out.
God.
- What in the hell happened?
- I don't know.
We put a smoker in the cabin.
All of a sudden it blew.
The only thing we meant to do
was drive 'em out to us.
- Now, you're sure it was not a bomb?
- No. It wasn't no bomb.
The old lady must've thrown
the smoker in the fireplace...
...and the kerosene went up.
That's the only thing I can figure at.
Killing a simple-minded 15-year-old boy.
You men did excellent at making heroes
out of every one of those gentlemen.
Archie Payton Samuel
was an innocent boy.
It's a sad day when murder
is committed in the name of justice.
This act tries the forbearance
of good Christian men.
We commend this child's body
to the ground.
His soul belongs to the Lord.
Beth.
Ed.
Didn't bring no gun.
I ain't got no quarrel with them Pinkertons.
I'm sorry about what happened
to Archie, but...
...since you boys kicked me out you can
just go ahead and fight your own fights.
That how you feel about it, Beth?
- No, it ain't.
- Come on, Beth.
- I've had enough talkin' with this fella here.
- You go your own way.
Now you hold it, woman.
You gotta learn to mind me.
Hey, Ed...
...start walkin'.
Is that what you want, Beth?
Then to hell with you.
To hell with both of you.
Awful sorry about your little brother.
Sorry.
Mama.
Just rest now.
We're gonna take you over
to Scofield's house directly.
I'm sorry, ma.
I'm so sorry.
You gonna make 'em pay, Jesse?
You got it wrong, Mister.
We didn't do nothin'.
Yes, you did.
Some of our friends saw you
on the north road that night.
Please, Mister. It wasn't really a bomb.
It was just supposed
to smoke everybody out.
My little brother was 15 years old.
Now, you think about that...
...on your way to hell.
The funeral will be in Chicago,
and the governor will be there.
I'm sure it'll cheer their souls
just to hear you say that.
It'd cheer them to know how many men
we have out combing those hills.
Those boys got a lot of friends out there.
What are these two doing here?
Visiting.
- You got a law against that?
- No, ma'am.
I got a law against murder,
and I got a warrant right here.
I don't suppose it'd do me any good
to ask polite, would it?
It won't do you any good to ask at all.
These men of yours
are gonna end up dead...
...or they're gonna end up worse.
You ladies will be left all alone
just to think about it.
Mr. Rowe!
I want people in the house.
I want people in the woods.
All right, men, off your horses.
Let's go.
Morning, boys.
Morning, Cole.
You boys wasted the best part of the day.
Hard to say y'all are farm bred,
the way you sleep in.
What's for breakfast?
Grits. Cracklin' grits.
Had 'em yesterday.
- I'm sick of this damn hiding out.
- Who ain't?
Better mind your manners, Bob
and thank McCorkindale here.
Don't be picking on Bob, Jesse.
- Hey, shut up, Jim.
- Shut up yourself, Frank.
I ain't got nothing but respect
for Mr. McCorkindale.
You boys just got holdup fever.
I know it.
All y'all need's a little fresh air.
I'll get y'all some milk
soon as I feed the chickens.
- What about McCorkindale?
- He's dead.
- You sure?
Piss on you!
Cover him, damn it!
Next volley, we go.
Frank's hurt, he goes first.
"Jesus, my Lord
"To heaven is gone
"Where there's no more
"Stormy clouds arising
"He whom I
"Fit my hopes upon
"Where there's no more
stormy clouds arising
"His track I'll see and I'll pursue
"Where there's no more... "
What is your full name, Mrs. Samuel?
My paper would like to get it right.
Zerelda Cole Samuel.
My husband Robert James
died in California.
My second husband
was called Ruben Samuel.
Ruben.
And where did you and Mr. Samuel live?
Clay County, Missouri.
Are you the mother of Jesse James?
I am.
"His track I'll see
"And I'll pursue
"Where there's no more
stormy clouds arising... "
Mrs. Samuel, you've already lost one son.
Aren't you afraid your other
two boys are gonna end up...
...the same as McCorkindale there?
"Where there's no more
stormy clouds arising"
Ed, you identify the James boys...
...and the Youngers,
might mean a reward for you.
- How much?
- Couple thousand dollars.
Shit.
I got a question for you.
How do I identify
what you can't even catch?
They are gonna get caught.
Jesse and his boys are
done with you anyway.
Let me tell you one damn thing.
I turn 'em in, and I'm gonna get killed
by one of their relatives, sure as hell.
I got six months to go here
for busting up a place drunk...
...so I'm just gonna take
my chances, all right?
Besides, Jesse just
might change his mind...
...and he pays better wages than you do...
...Pinkerton man.
Frank, I never saw myself as a farm girl.
We ain't gonna be farming, Annie.
We're gonna raise horses.
I don't know anything
about raising horses, either.
You know, it's funny.
Outside of being a banker...
...about the only thing I ever wanted to do
was to raise horses.
Thanks to the Pinkertons,
you're getting your chance.
Ha, mule!
And we're not the only ones
going our own way.
Everybody's doing it.
Jim Younger's off in the hills somewhere.
God only knows where Jesse is.
Bob and Cole are heading for Texas.
The only reason why
Cole Younger went to Texas...
...is 'cause he heard Belle Shirley
got married down there.
It's a long way to go looking for trouble.
He'll be just fine, Annie.
Ha, mule! Yo!
Ha, mule!
You're late.
I'm not much for being on time.
You don't look real happy.
Well, I'll tell you something about Texas.
It's loud.
I never figured you for the homesick type.
I ain't the homesick type.
I ain't the waiting-around type either.
I ain't the reliable type.
You ought to try getting married.
Might improve your character.
What do you do with that...
...husband of yours,
leave him home, tied to the bed?
Don't you make no fun of him.
The way I got it figured,
you're gonna wear that Indian out.
Double-thump side swoop of yours.
I do what I want with who I want,
and don't make no mistake about it.
Everybody says that.
They always have.
You want to see something,
you watch this.
Come here.
- You done?
- Not by a damn sight.
Now you're done.
Sam.
You Cole Younger?
Who's asking?
Sam Starr.
I'm married to that lady.
Pleased to meet you.
Boys, there is no need
to fight over little old me.
But if you've got to,
you make it man-to-man.
Hand-to-hand.
Why not?
I'm glad I caught you in a good mood.
Here you go, both of you.
Have a chew.
What does the winner get?
Nothing you both ain't already had.
Don't make much sense, does it?
Nope.
You're both crazy.
But you keep me occupied.
I am having a real good time.
Ten bucks on the half-breed, right here.
Get off of me!
Come on, Missouri.
What's the matter?
You got what you wanted.
Sir, we met a few months back.
I remember.
I'd like to ask you a couple of questions
for my newspaper if you don't mind.
Like why you're having so much trouble
bringing in the James-Younger gang.
A lot of reasons.
Came down here with four men
that didn't know the territory.
They were murdered.
Most the people around here
are related to each other...
...so they're very clannish.
What about the local police?
Local police get tired and quit
after chasing the gang a couple of miles.
There are also newspapers like your own
that print lies about the gang...
...saying they're Robin Hoods.
That doesn't help either.
My readers may want to know
why you're sitting...
...here next to this warm, friendly fire
when you should be out on the chase.
Right now the whole bunch of them
are spread out across five states.
But they will be back.
Zee, did you have any visitors
while I was gone?
Do you mean was there
anybody poking around...
...trying to straighten up your
sheets and fluff your pillow?
I'm just asking.
Why don't you just mind your
manners, Mr. Jesse James?
Just 'cause you're off
fighting railroads and banks...
...don't mean you get a free
tongue around this house.
I sent out a word to the rest.
Gonna be meeting up real soon.
Going on a mission.
I'm gonna get myself a little cash.
Start looking around this here state
of Missouri for some girl to marry.
Any prospects?
I'm looking.
I don't know, Annie.
Maybe we're just going
in different directions.
Maybe so.
Can't help wanting what we want, can we?
My going's got nothing
to do with big dreams.
Nobody ever made you go anywhere
you didn't want to go, Frank.
Good night.
- How you doin', Jim?
- I'm doin', okay.
So, gents. Let's get down to it.
What's our next job gonna be?
Minnesota.
Them squareheads,
they got 'em a real fat bank up there.
Scouted it out myself.
Northfield.
A lot of banks and cat houses
in Missouri we ain't done.
Cole's right.
Minnesota...
...it's a fair piece off our mark.
Clell says that bank's
full to the brim with money.
It sounds good to me.
I want Bill Chadwell
and Charlie Pitts to go with us.
They're goddamn good men.
Who says?
I do.
I used to do this all the time.
But I...
...I got married a few years back.
I guess it slowed me down a bit.
If you know what I mean.
Morning, Jess.
I hope you boys had a good time last night.
How was yours?
I got better things to think about.
Family man.
My family is something you don't
talk about, Cole Younger.
"Well, I walked the street
with a tap to my feet
"Heard a voice above me
"A maid looked out the window up above
needed somebody to love me
"My father, he's a minister
and virgins he doth cherish
"Now she's got five boys, seven little girls
and a baby on her shoulder"
You know, Frank...
...when this is all over,
I think I'll write me a book.
Make myself even more famous than I am.
If a pig had wings, it would fly.
A book about my exploits...
...as a gentleman and a lover.
I expect a free copy.
Free copy?
You gotta pay, Frank.
You gotta pay.
You ever been up North before?
Got to Fetterman once.
Went to shoot buffalo.
How'd you do?
The price of hides went to hell,
and I got the clap off some squaw.
The bank's plumb in the center of town.
Right between the dry goods store
and the mortuary.
You reckon we ought to send in
a couple of scouts? Check it all out?
We rob banks, Jim.
We don't need any checking.
Talking soft I might expect
from Cole or Frank.
I gave up trying to talk sense
to you a long time ago.
Come on, let's take the damn bank.
There ain't nothin' over there
but squareheads anyhow.
All right, you people, nobody move.
Let's just show God
the palms of our hands.
Now you don't give us no trouble, Mister.
Clell, get to the vault.
No, he's not for sale.
Just move on, squarehead.
Now you open that safe
or I'll blow your head right off.
I can't, it's a time lock.
- What are you talking about?
- Time lock, hell.
You open that safe, Mister, you hear?
The Pinkertons told us
you might be coming.
The lock is set just for you.
It only works at 4:30.
The whole town is ready.
No, no, mister, please don't shoot.
I have a family.
Now you got five seconds
to open up that vault, mister.
What the hell? Get out of here.
Be quiet, lady!
They're robbing the bank!
Jesus, Clell!
- Let's get the hell out of here.
- Come on, Clell.
- Clell, come on!
- Yankee bastard.
Jim!
Bob!
Cole!
Jesse!
Oh, God!
Cole!
We gotta move, Frank.
They'll get the rest of 'em to a doctor.
Who will?
The posse that's gonna be chasing us.
We can't do that.
We can't just leave 'em here alone.
Jim.
Cole.
We gotta ride.
What about the rest?
This just ain't no time
to argue with you, Cole.
Either you stay here and die,
or you come with us.
Frank and I are going.
Kill me.
Goddamn it. Kill me.
Frank?
You're not leaving, are you?
I gotta stick with my brother, Cole.
The Youngers don't need you.
I like it better this way, Jesse.
I get to see you run.
Jim? Oh, Cole.
Yeah, we're here, Bobby boy.
We're all here.
Goddamned squareheads.
Where the hell's Missouri?
Come on, Frank.
We're gonna get us a new gang together.
It's gonna be better than ever.
You're not gonna quit on me now.
All we got to do is get across the river.
All we got to do is get home.
We never should have left.
You could say we was drove to it.
How's that?
If it weren't for the war,
we might have been something else.
You're a little too young
to have fought in the war.
That's true, but my brothers weren't.
And we all go one direction together.
You tell me who they are,
it might mean a lighter sentence.
You think about that.
You and I both know it was
the James boys, don't we?
Sure do feel poorly.
Ain't a surprise. Eleven bullets
must be some kind of record.
What do you and your brothers
think about a life sentence?
You're lucky they don't allow
hanging in this state.
Come on, Cole.
Tell me what you think about all this.
Hell, we played a rough game.
We lost.
I spent four years in the army.
Eleven trying to get out of it.
What about the James boys?
- I don't know nothing about 'em.
- Sure you do.
Far as I'm concerned,
they never been in this state.
You another reporter?
No. My name is Jacob Rixley.
I'm with the Pinkerton agency.
I've been chasing you boys
for a long time, Bob.
Yes, sir, I guess you have.
I want to talk to you
about the James boys.
You don't owe them a thing.
You know that, don't you?
They wouldn't protect you if
it'd get them one day less.
But unless you help me...
...you and your brothers
are going to be in this jail for life.
What's he trying to say?
He said to tell you we done it
for Dixie and nothin' else.
15,000 for Jesse.
Another 10,000 will get you Frank.
The Pinkerton company and
the governor can't afford that.
You know who you're talking to?
You know what kind of a man
sprung out of Missouri?
The Jameses, Youngers, Clantons, Earps.
And now Bob and Charlie Ford.
Word's out you and Jesse
aren't even friends anyway.
Is that so?
That same Mr. Jesse James
you can't find at all...
...just asked us to come and visit him.
Let's go, Bob.
Wait a minute.
$15,000.
Half before and half when it's done.
Got yourself a deal.
No more for me.
Heard you were thinking
of a bank in Kansas, Jesse.
We don't talk business at the table, Bob.
Sorry.
How'd you boys like a drink?
Sounds good.
Don't it, Bob?
Sure thing.
Could I have your plate, please, Jesse?
Charlie.
- You feelin' all right?
- She ain't real fond of the company.
Don't worry none, ladies.
Just talking some things over, that's all.
Can you say, "good night"?
He might be carryin' a hideout.
I bet he is.
He knows.
I know he knows.
Pour me one, Bob.
You look spooked, Charlie.
Like hell.
Nothing spooks me, Jesse.
You know that.
Now, I been thinking about
the Platte City bank.
It's gonna be a big one.
We ain't too sure.
- Why not?
- I don't know.
You're a hard man to do business with.
It's crooked.
What did you say?
Said it's not straight.
I really like this old sampler.
Ma gave this to me for my wedding day.
Is that straight?
I shot Jesse James.
- Mr. Rixley?
- That's right.
My name is Frank James.
I came here to turn myself in.
Here's my gun.
I want something in return.
I want to be able to bury my brother.
Suppose I don't agree to your terms?
I'll kill you.
"Jesse James, we understand
"Has killed a many man
"He robbed the Union trains
"But history does record
"That Bob and Charlie Ford
"Have laid Jesse James in his grave
"It was on a Saturday night
"The stars were shining bright
"When they robbed that Union train
"And it was one of the Younger boys
"That gathered in the spoils
"And carried that money away
"In his small home unaware
"A-straghtenin' pictures there
"He thought he heard a noise
"And as he turned his head
"Well, a bullet killed him dead
"Why, by Bob Ford, one of the boys
"Poor Jesse had a wife
"She lived a lady all her life
"The children they were brave
"But history does record
"That Bob and Charlie Ford
"Have laid poor Jesse
"Laid poor Jesse
"Have laid Jesse James
"In his grave"