If you've ever been afraid of anything,
This song's for you
I know you're feeling me
If you ever wanted to do something big
But then you stopped just couldn't handle it
You can take a chance that it'll be all right
Come on come on come on come on come on
Come on you know it's time
Just pu-pu-push it down
And then you'll win the fight
You're better than this you're better than that
Come on let's make it right
Nothing's getting in my way now
Nothing ever will again
And if you're with me come on say now
We're gonna make it
Hey we're gonna take what we can
You're gonna sit up and let them know
Just find the courage to get up and go
You're not gonna take it slow
If you know what I'm sayin'
There's no time for waitin'
A wish comes true every day
It's happening.
Today's the day
You know it is
Make it happen
I know you can
You know you want to do just something big
Sorry Joey.
Just take the plunge
It can happen to me
It can happen to you
Go on go on go on go on go on
Go make your wish come true
It's just the chance you got
To do what you want to
You're better than this, you're better than that.
You're gonna make it through
Nothing's getting in my way now
Nothing ever will again
I love him.
Mm-hmm. 16. Yeah.
Today as a matter of fact.
You're gonna sit up and let them know
Just find the courage, get up and go
Surprise!
Happy Birthday Abby.
Oh my baby's 16. I can't believe it.
Bob are you crying?
What? No Sue.
I've got an eyelash in my eye. Oh.
Look it's your first 16th birthday picture.
Ech Dad.
What? I like it.
It's going to go on our family Web page.
- No.  - Come on sweetheart.
Make a wish.
Okay.
You know what I wish?
I wish my dear sweet family would finally understand
they can't just barge into my room any time they want.
I'm not a kid anymore.
I need privacy and boundaries.
I need my own space.
I've been looking forward to this day all my life
and now that it's here I wish you would all just get out
and stop spoiling it.
Love you.
I don't know.
Mm. Ow. Ow! Eww.
I'm 16 finally.
Today is going to be magical.
Told you she wouldn't like it.
I don't understand her.
She's probably nervous about her Sweet 16 party.
Oh Bob the party lights. They're in the garage.
I'm on it.
Wow. Thanks.
Ah-ah. It's for your sister.
Too yellow.
Too blue.
Too pink.
Too nighttime.
Too daytime.
Too...15.
Perfect.
Hey Abs.
Hello. Knock much?
What?
Mom made you a special birthday breakfast.
Aw that's sweet. Just put it over there.
Not you. The food.
Two secs.
This is your breakfast
Da na na na no
But I'm gonna eat it
You do realize that's not a real guitar.
Da na na now
- Mike! - Whoa.
Can I have a loan?
No you cannot have a loan.
I have been saving up for my Sweet 16 party tonight.
The best Sweet 16 party ever.
Ah yes. Wish number 15.
What?
Abby's 16 wishes.
When I'm 16 I'll have the best party ever.
Hey that's private.
Yeah not really.
You honestly thought you'd get all this today?
I'm an essentially hopeful person.
The first one's hilarious.
When I am sixteen, I'll meet Joey Lockhart.
The Joey Lockhart.
He's an international pop star with about a bazillion fans.
Why would you even wish that?
- I was 7.  - You were delusional.
You were 5 and wore a cape to school.
The other wishes are more realistic like wish number 3.
When I am sixteen, I'll decorate my room the way I want.
No no no.
Sassy.
Mm not a good idea Abs.
Why not?
If you decorate your room the way you dress ouch.
Ucch.
And what's with the mug shot on 16?
It's not a mug shot.
It's Logan Buchanan.
Your crushed on the quarterback?
For your information he's also in the drama club
and once attended Chess Masters.
I know. I was there.
He wanted to buy my chem notes.
He's perfect.
And if I get my wish he'll talk to me today.
Aah! Ha ha ha!
Ohh. Krista Cook.
Cool car.
It's perfect! I love it!
It's not cool. It's terrible.
I don't know what I did to deserve this.
Why was Krista of all people born on the same day I was?
Yeah that must be annoying
how she always gets better stuff than you for her birthday.
I don't know why she hates me so much.
Ever since the third grade
she's always trying to ruin my birthday.
Which is also her birthday.
Why are you still here? Get out.
Dibs on the bathroom.
Excuse you.
Golden hair a perfect face
There's something missing
Are you theirs?
Hard and sad
That someone's listening
Come on Abs. You've been in there for a year.
32 minutes.
Most girls take twice that.
Hold your horses.
Perfect.
It's all yours.
Shouldn't have skipped breakfast.
Today is going to be perfect and nothing
not even Krista Cook is going to ruin it.
Wow. it's a major infestation.
Looks like it's been building for about oh 16 years
by the looks of it.
How long will it take to get them out?
Several days. A year at the most.
A year?
Oh.
I managed to save this.
Ohh.
This can't be happening not to me not today.
Daddy I left some clothes in my gym locker.
Please please please drive me to school.
I don't think so Pumpkin.
Sweet. Hey Krista.
Hey can I ride?
Hop in.
Buckle up.
Great. I'll just take the bus.
By myself on my birthday.
Hmm.
Here.
Mm.
Thanks Jay.
You look pathetic.
Nice to know I can count on you to state the obvious.
Sorry about your house.
How'd you know?
Krista texted the entire junior class.
That's just peachy.
What's this?
Happy Birthday?
Not really.
Come on.
It's beautiful Jay. Where's the other half?
Best friends forever.
Oh Jay that's sweet.
Do you like it?
I love it.
It's the best thing that's happened to me all day.
That bad huh?
Yes.
I've been planning for this day for eight years.
I mean this was supposed to be the day
I started acquiring all of the wonderful things
that come with being grown up...
things like freedom and privacy and respect.
But what do I get?
Wasps. Wasps.
Even my backyard is infested.
Where am I going to have my Sweet 16 party?
You could use my basement.
Ew. No.
All right.
Well the day is young.
Good things could still happen.
Like what? Like taking the bus?
I hate taking the bus.
This is the worst birthdays in the history of birthdays.
Today wasn't supposed to be like this.
Today was supposed to be... magical.
Abigail Jensen?
Y-Y-Yes.
This is for you.
Happy Birthday sweetie.
- Don't open it. - Why?
Real mail is delivered to your house not your bus stop.
- So?  - It could be a bomb.
It's not a bomb. It's a birthday present.
And I'm opening it.
"Make a wish light a candle
and watch your Sweet 16 birthday wishes come true."
Great.
Candles.
Not even a stupid gift card.
Wait there's something else.
Hold this.
What are you doing?
Read wish number 8.
"When I'm 16..."
"I'll have my own car, preferably red."
I'm lighting one of these candles.
What if something bad happens?
What if something good happens?
And look if it's a joke
the worst that can happen is we take the bus.
Here.
Ladies and gentlemen
Joey Lockhart
You Abby Jensen?
Yes.
Hurry up
Put on my pretty shoes
Happy Birthday Abby.
Fairytales come true.
Thanks.
Here we are just us girls
All of the stuff having fun
In the princess world
The princess world
Oh what just happened?
I've had a crush on him since I was 7.
When I'm 16 I'll meet Joey Lockhart.
What are you talking about?
It's wish number 1.
Look Jay. The candles work.
Yeah but we're still stuck taking the bus.
Maybe not.
I lit candle number 1 and wish number 1 on my list came true.
I think the numbers on the candles
correspond with the numbers on my wish list.
Give me number 8.
When I'm 16 I'll have my own car preferably red.
No way.
Way.
Check it out.
Gosh this is fun.
I can't believe it. This is my dream car.
It's all yours sweetie. Want to drive?
- Yes. - No.
Come on. I have my permit.
My dad lets me practice
in the Hasty Mart parking lot all the time.
Yeah at midnight when it's empty.
Abby when a total stranger drives up to you on the street
and offers you a car you can't just take it.
She's not a total stranger. You look very familiar.
Well we're not doing this.
- Why not? - Yeah why not?
Because... you don't have a driver's license
until you take the test after school.
Good point. I'll drive. You two get in.
What? Not until you tell us who you are.
I'm Celeste. I'm here to make Abby's 16 wishes come true.
Oh. Well that explains pretty much exactly nothing.
Come on Jay. This is the most
wonderful amazing magical thing that's ever happened to me.
50 years from now when you're looking back at your life
don't you want to be able to say
you had the guts to get in the car?
I'm going to regret this.
Yes! Get your stuff. Come on. Get in the car.
All right go go go.
Just so we're clear you're some kind of magical being
like an elf or a fairy?
Sure. Why not?
You don't sound so sure.
Jay.
You just do birthdays or other events too?
He babbles when he's nervous.
Why don't you relax Jay and enjoy the ride?
Hold on.
Whoa! Mommy!
That was awesome.
Have we landed yet? What's it look like?
- What does what look like?  - Her home planet.
Sorry Jay.
The only alien planet you'll be visiting today is high school.
I already have my license. My dad has connections at the DMV.
Yo Logan check out that ride.
Hey Jensen did you get new wheels too?
Yeah. These are my new wheels
which I bought myself for my birthday which is today.
Cool.
No way this is yours.
What can I say? I'm a saver not a spender like you.
Oh man. I got to make some bank.
Come on.
- What are you doing?  - Saving you from more humiliation.
What? I'm not humiliated.
This is the best birthday ever.
Look. Wish number 15.
When I'm 16 I'll have the best party ever.
If the candles keep working like this
my party's going to be sick.
Hey party tonight at my house. You're all invited.
Come on.
Come on. It's okay.
It's okay.
- Want to make some cash?  - Yes.
Put these up everywhere.
Meet me at the voting table after first period.
Okay. You go find some real clothes to wear.
I'll tell Miss Hackl you got a late time okay?
Thanks Jay.
When I'm 16 I'll have the cutest clothes in school.
Oh... For me? Thank you.
Okay.
Wish number 2. All right.
What?
What's going on? Come on.
- Uh Miss Duffy.  -Jensen.
I'll take that.
Keep it up Theodore and you'll be president one day.
- You really think so?  - Absolutely.
So you can tell the future too?
Oh no. Just gave Ted hope.
Come on in.
So what's up sweetie?
What's up? You know what's up.
That's why you're here pretending to be the counselor.
Why didn't that stupid candle light?
- Because of the rules.  - The rules?
Oh boy. You don't get out much do you?
What are you talking about?
The candles are magic and all magic has rules.
One candle and one wish per hour.
You lit candle number 1 at 7:58 this morning
and Joey Lockhart showed up.
Then you lit candle number 8 at precisely 8 A.M.
Your wishes were two minutes apart but within different hours.
Oh. So now I have to wait...
- 27 minutes... - before I make another wish.
Great. You could have printed that on the box you know.
Any other magic candle rules I should know about?
Only one but it's a doozy.
The magic in the candles expires at midnight tonight
so no more wishes after then.
Oh and all the wishes you've made by then become permanent.
- At midnight. - Yeah.
So at midnight that gorgeous car out there is mine forever?
Absolutely.
And in 26 1/2 minutes I'll have cuter clothes than Krista Cook.
Yeah.
She really can't stand you.
Oh. You know about that?
I shouldn't do this but...
Read for yourself.
Oh no. I couldn't.
Well maybe just a page or two.
I suggest 10 23 and 37.
Oh. Be a little more careful where you light those puppies.
Thanks.
Whoa. Good stuff?
You have no idea.
Thanks for voting for me.
Krista!
I know you've loathed me since we were 8 years old
but I didn't know you've been keeping score.
- Where did you get that?  - From the Birthday Fairy.
Right. Give it to me.
When we were 10 I had my first sleepover
so you decided to have one too
but you paid everybody to come to yours.
You have no right to read that. It's mine.
Well then why is it all about me?
When we were 12 I entered the school talent show
with my baton twirling act.
So you entered too. Juggling 12 batons.
Every year you competed with me and every year you've won.
You've tortured me since the third grade.
Can you just give it a rest?
Don't play innocent with me. You know what you did.
And for this
I'm going to make sure nobody comes to your party.
Here.
What's this?
It's an invitation to my Sweet 16 birthday party tonight.
Everybody's going to be there.
Now if you'll excuse me I have some campaigning to do.
Krista you don't need to campaign.
You're the only name on the ballot running for president.
Well then I'm sure to win.
Why are you doing this?
You're not even interested in student government.
And you are?
- Well I...  - I didn't think so.
Hey Krista.
So they said you needed help with something?
- Hand these out for me.  - Sure.
Thanks.
She's doing it. She's ruining my birthday.
Again.
Just don't let her get to you.
You're right Jay.
I'm going to put an end to her reign of terror.
Right about now.
List. Okay.
When I'm 16 I'll have the cutest clothes in school.
Hi-hi.
- Celeste it's beautiful. - I know right?
I've been waiting for you to make this wish.
I just love shopping especially when it's free.
I don't even know where to start.
That's what I'm here for.
Now close your eyes and let me work my magic.
Ever since the third grade whatever I did Krista did better.
She's never satisfied unless she's winning and I'm losing.
But today I decided
she's not going to make me miserable anymore.
I have a plan and this wish it's the first part.
Would you say Krista Cook always has
the cutest clothes in school?
And shoes and handbags.
Not anymore.
That top is not an original you-know-who is it?
- It is.  - Shut up.
Oh those shoes are so to die for. I hate you.
- Want to have lunch near us? - Sure.
Yay. I totally just want to sit next to that handbag.
You mean this handbag?
I got it for my birthday last year.
You're not all that Jensen.
Yoo-hoo Abby!
I'm so sorry.
Give me that old thing.
This one's so hot it hasn't even come out yet.
Thank you so much.
I'll just ship you the rest of the collection
when the infestation's over.
Auf Wiedersehen.
I know what you're doing and it's not going to work.
I'm just trying to have the best birthday of my entire life.
Well good luck with that because it's not over yet.
All right everybody. On the track in five.
Late again Jensen.
Yes Miss Duffy I am late.
I had to go back to my locker for this.
I see.
That's still no excuse for tardiness
but that is a beautiful bag.
- It's for you.  - Me?
I was saving it for your Christmas present
but look it matches your track suit perfectly.
Ha ha! It actually does.
Happy Monday.
Well Happy Monday to me.
Well ladies what do you say instead of running killer laps
we all have a nice friendly game of volleyball?
Way to go Abby.
Come on. We need her.
Jensen!
Get out here!
When I'm 16 I'll beat Krista at something, anything,
everything...
Play ball!
You sure you're ready for this?
Why shouldn't I be sure?
Because you're the least athletic person I know.
Not anymore. I got the birthday mojo.
Duck!
1-zip.
You tried to hit me.
It's called spiking. It's how you win.
Play ball!
MVP! MVP!
Hey, are you all right? I'm going to call the nurse okay?
Just hanging there.
MVP! MVP! MVP!
Oh well look who's awake.
- How are you feeling? - I'm fine.
I had a weird nightmare.
Oh honey that was real. Abby Jensen creamed you.
Oh and you're wanted in the principal's office.
- Yeah, that's classical.  - Yeah that's so true, so true.
- Makes my day.  -Y eah.
You wanted to see me, Mr. Smith?
Yeah. Yeah.
Big news, Cook. The election's over.
How can it be over? A lot of people haven't voted yet.
Actually we had a 100% voter turnout.
What's going on here?
Good morning students!
I'm very pleased to announce
the winner of the most votes for the Student Body President
is Abby Jensen!
Yes!
I just want to thank everyone who voted for me
and made this dream possible.
No! It's not possible. Her name isn't even on the ballot.
Let... go.
That is all.
Abby was a write-in.
Better luck next time Krista.
Ha! I finally beat Krista Cook.
- Had a little help.  -I  know. Isn't it amazing?
This day just keeps getting better and better.
Yeah for you.
I know right?
Can we just do this experiment? We both need extra credit.
Nah.
I'll just give the teacher
some strappy sandals and a pashmina.
- No. Just give it a rest.  - What's wrong with you?
I don't know. This whole wish thing.
You're changing too fast Abby. I can't keep up.
What do you mean?
You've always been allergic to volunteer work.
And now all of a sudden you're Student Body President?
What can I say?
The people spoke and they wanted me.
The candles spoke and you have no idea what you just wished for.
Yes I do.
Being president is like an honor.
Being president is an important job Abby.
It should do to someone who really wants it.
Oh like who? Like Krista?
No.
Well I'm sure I'll do just fine.
I'll have you to help me.
Come on. You can't be mad at me.
Why not?
Because it's my birthday.
Because we're best friends.
Because I'm Student Body President
and I get free lunch. Ta-da!
No way.
Way way. Every day.
Now hand over your goofy glasses
and let your commander in chief buy you a sandwich.
- What kind of sandwich?   - Any kind you want.
Come on.
There she is!
You see? Ha ha. They love me.
What have you done now?
Wish number 10.
I looked in the mirror and I was tired of being invisible.
When I'm 16 I'll be popular.
Oh hi Joey.
Abby smile!
Sure I'll sign it.
I loved that wish.
Right.
Okay people make a hole!
Here she comes!
Back up. Come on.
Thank you. Okay.
Peeps.
And I don't have to do a thing. Just show up.
They're planning your birthday party.
Mm-hmm.
Their dads are business partners.
Apparently they own half of Vegas.
They're throwing my party at one of their hotels.
Not to rain on your birthday parade Abs but Vegas?
That's not really your style.
And your basement is?
Hey I have foosball.
Good point.
Look this is my one and only Sweet 16 birthday party.
I... I want it to be spectacular.
I don't have anything to wear.
Well we both have a free period right now.
Let's go buy you a dress.
We can't. The wasps are holding my party money hostage.
I'll supply you the cash.
You'd do that?
Sure.
Jay you're the best.
We can't go.
I don't have my license yet.
A reading from the Wish List of Abigail Jensen.
Wish number 7... When I'm 16...
I'll get my driver's license.
Abigail Louise Jensen?
Yes.
This is highly unusual.
My driver's license!
And there ya go.
Thank you so much!
Oh lighten up Harry.
You needed to get out of that cubicle anyway.
But we really don't do this kind of thing.
I know.
But wasn't it fun?
My cubicle was fun.
My baby
Goin' for a ride
Ride and ride and ride
Ride and ride and ride...
- Jay?  - Yes Abs.
This is now officially the best 16th birthday
in the history of 16th birthdays.
Abby you can't afford a hanger here.
Not true.
Since I don't have to pay for my own party
I'm spending every penny I saved on the perfect dress.
Come on!
- What do you think?  - It's nice.
No. Too disco.
What about this one?
You're... It's beautiful.
But do you think Logan will like it?
How should I know?
Touchy.
Why don't you just light No. 16 right now
and make the stupid wish?
Poof. Logan Buchanan is yours.
It doesn't work that way.
Uh yes it does.
It's worked that way all day.
No, I want Logan to like me for me
not because I put some magic birthday spell on him.
I'm trying this on.
And these.
I'll take these.
I really feel for you.
Wasting your time on kids like that.
A customer's a customer.
Oh trust me.
They won't be buying anything.
Look Jay. It's perfect isn't it?
Sure.
Well I love it and I think Logan's going to love it too.
Good. Sold.
Can we go now?
Don't be so grumpy.
I'm sorry.
This is a store not a playground.
Exactly.
I like this one.
I'm sure you do.
Why don't you kids just come back with your parents?
We're not kids. I'm 16.
Congratulations.
Now give me the dress.
No we're buying it!
Jay show her your money.
- My wallet...  - You out.
But. No no no, you can't.
Watch me.
But we're customers!
No you're children.
Get that dress off now.
Wish number 9...
When I'm 16 people will stop treating me like a kid.
Um excuse me where's my friend?
There was a boy here
but he left with a girl in the cutest little yellow car...
Wait. He left with Krista?
It appears so.
Turn around.
That outfit is all wrong.
It's far too young for you.
And suddenly really tight.
Let's get you into something more age appropriate.
Let's try these.
But I don't have any money.
Oh we'll just put them on your charge account.
I have a charge account?
Is everything all right Miss Jensen?
Oh yeah.
Everything is just fine.
It's a picture perfect world
A picture perfect world
This time we're doing it our way
Thank you so much.
We've got a new perspective
It's time for us to make the grade
Head in a new direction
So it's a picture perfect world we live in
Starting today
It's a picture perfect world we're given
Make no mistake
The sun's in the sky
Sorry Miss Duffy.
Do we know each other?
Yeah.
Ah you're the new substitute teacher
which means I don't have to babysit those little monsters.
They're all yours.
Jay!
I'll be right back.
Oh great.
Leave me to wrangle the blob all alone.
Okay go.
Yes?
Get out here!
What's wrong with you?
Excuse me?
You left me stranded on my birthday.
What kind of a best friend does that?
Best friend? What are you talking about?
Oh hi. My name is Abby Jensen.
Have we met?
Yeah. A long time ago I think.
Shut up.
Stop it.
I'm not your best friend.
I'm a sophomore. You're a... woman.
Thank you but I'm just four months older than you.
Yeah in dog years.
Listen I'm in the middle of an important experiment...
And I'm in the middle of an important birthday!
I'm sorry. I gotta go.
- No wait...  - Let go.
Jay Kepler!
You're the worst best friend ever!
I don't understand.
Am I being expelled?
I'm sure they'll explain everything.
Mom? Dad?
What's the truck for?
Are we moving?
Just come with us.
Not until somebody tells me what's going on?
Abby you can't go to high school anymore.
What? Why not?
Because it's time you grow up.
- Bob.  - What?
Sweetheart while the house is being fumigated
there just really isn't room for you.
So your dad and I were talking...
We found you an apartment...
A what?
An apartment.
To live in.
By myself?
It's a very safe neighborhood.
Is that what you call it?
I call it pricey.
Your dad and I paid the security deposit
but the first month's rent is your responsibility.
Okay I'll get the last load.
You're going to need a full-time job.
I circled some good ones...
What? No. I can't go to school and have a job.
Oh well if you're ready for college... Bob!
Yeah!
She wants to go to college!
No not yet!
Never mind.
Ok.
Mom I'm just a kid!
I can't live here by myself!
Abby don't be so dramatic.
Lots of girls your age have their own apartments.
I moved out when I was 18.
But I'm not 18.
No you're 21.
22 today.
Happy Birthday sweetheart.
What are you talking about?
Let's go Sue.
No! Don't go!
Just remember we did this out of love...
Yeah tough love.
Bob!
You'll be fine Pumpkin.
Dad Dad...
- Mom...  - Come and visit anytime.
Except Wednesdays.
Wednesday is our bowling night.
High school memories?
No.
When I'm 16 people will stop treating me like a kid.
Let's get you into something more age appropriate.
You're the new substitute teacher.
Stop it! I'm not your best friend.
I'm a sophomore.
You're a... woman.
- No you're 21.  - 22 today.
Happy Birthday sweetheart.
Oh no.
No no no.
This isn't what I wanted!
Celeste!
Celeste I need to talk to you!
Right now!
The list.
There's gotta be a wish.
That's it! Wish number 3.
That should do it.
When I'm 16 I'll decorate my room the way I want.
Yoo-hoo!
Decorator's Delight!
- Celeste! I'm so glad you're here...  - Me too.
Okay. Nice.
Lots of potential.
- I need your help.  - You sure do.
- Maybe some wallpaper...  - No no wallpaper.
Paint then.
Let's look at some samples.
No listen to me.
Your magic candles made a mistake.
Candles don't make mistakes.
- People do.  - No.
I made a wish but it wasn't really my wish.
How about some curtains?
No!
Oo bad decision.
You need privacy.
You're alone.
- You're a woman... - No I'm not!
I'm not a woman!
I'm 16 years old!
I made a wish... wish number 9.
I didn't want to be an adult!
I just wanted to be treated like one!
The candles have their own logic.
They don't always give you what you want.
Sometimes they give you what you need.
And sweetie you need drapes pronto.
I don't need drapes!
I need my life back!
I just wished away my friends
my Sweet 16 party my senior prom...
I missed graduation!
I need to take that wish back!
Oh sweetie.
I'm afraid that's not possible.
The candles and your wishes go together.
Since there's no do-over wish on your list...
I'm afraid when midnight comes this is your life.
But...
Decorator's Delight.
Uh-huh.
On my way.
Slipcover emergency.
Gotta run.
What? No no no!
Wait!
Celeste Celeste...
You trying to run out on the rent?
- No!  - Good.
First month is due in three days.
Pay up or move out.
Move out.
Stupid wishes!
Why did I ever write you down!
I'll just change one.
Ha!
Gotcha!
I hate sushi and I always will!
Hey...
What about you Wish No. 14?
When I'm 16, my parents will understand me.
There you are sweetheart.
Mom don't you ever knock?
I need privacy.
What?
Privacy. I need privacy.
Hold on a minute.
Bob come here a minute.
Tell your dad.
I need privacy.
One more time.
I need privacy. I need privacy.
I don't understand a word she's saying. Do you?
No. Then again I never do.
This has to work.
Please understand.
- Abby!  - Hi Daddy.
Honey look who it is.
- Hello sweetheart.  - Hi Mom.
Shouldn't you be at your own place unpacking those boxes?
Yeah but I missed you guys.
Aw that's sweet.
But we're kind of busy right now.
Your turn dear.
What's the use?
22 cards in my hand and I still can't play!
Can't this wait?
Of course it can.
What's up?
Well um...
I have something important to discuss with you
and I thought if you really listen to me you might understand.
Bob.
What? I'm listening.
We're listening.
Even if it sounds crazy?
I listen to your father all the time.
What's that supposed to mean?
Go on sweetheart.
When I woke up this morning I was 16 years old.
I thought this was going to be the best day of my life.
Then this Birthday Fairy appeared and gave me these.
Would you look at this hon.
Well that brings back memories doesn't it?
What? What memories?
Your father took me to the Lucky Duck Chinese Restaurant
on the night you were born.
I had the orange chicken.
We thought it was an omen.
We always felt so lucky
to have a daughter as wonderful as you are.
Really?
Really.
Then you'll understand when I say I need to come back
and live with you and go back to school..
I'm not ready to have my own apartment and my own job.
Please tell me you understand.
Abby look behind you.
Ever since you were a little girl
all you wanted was to be exactly what you are now.
Beautiful and independent.
I remember the day this photo was taken.
You wanted a grown-up birthday party.
All dressed up in my high heels and pearls.
You were never happier.
But being grown up is different
than dreaming about it isn't it?
Yes.
We understand you.
You do?
Of course.
You're scared your childhood is over and with it
- all the best times of your life. - Yes!
You probably want to just turn back the clock and start over.
Yes! Yes!
That's exactly what I want to do!
We know how that feels.
Then I'm still your little girl?
You'll always be our little girl Pumpkin...
Look! Wasps!
Time to go Pumpkin.
Drive safe.
And don't forget these.
But I thought you guys understood.
We do understand adulthood could be tough.
Sometimes it gets a little buggy.
Bye now sweetheart!
Love you!
So that's what that feels like.
Hi Logan.
Hey.
Cool ride.
Yeah you said that this morning.
Huh?
So... what are you doing here?
Party.
Right.
I wasn't invited.
Huh.
- Hey!  - Yeah?
- Will you do something for me?  - Sure.
Take a picture of me with your car.
Okay okay.
Thanks.
It's what I want when I'm your age.
There ya go.
Cool.
Oh man that's hot.
I can't wait to show Krista!
Joey Lockhart!
Get off of me!
Get off!
You have to believe me Jay.
You're my best friend and it's my 16th birthday
and I got these magic candles at the bus stop
and this big car pulled up and Joey Lockhart got out
- and kissed me...  - I don't know her. Okay.
You were there! You saw him!
Let go.
Not until you listen to me. Give me five minutes.
Four.
Okay.
I know this is hard to believe
but we're best friends and I can prove it.
So?
Look at your key ring.
"Happy Sweet 16. Love Jay."
You gave this to me this morning.
For my 16th birthday.
Abby.
You remember?
I think so.
So you believe me?
Yeah.
I do.
He believes me!
Whoa.
Volume.
But this doesn't change anything.
And when midnight comes I'm stuck like this forever.
Here lemme see the list.
Here ya go.
- Okay you've used 1 2 7 8 9...  - Skip ahead.
I can't believe you wasted a wish on sushi.
I was 8.
I had a very unsophisticated palate.
Had?
You're a great best friend Jay.
I know.
C'mon.
Most of these are kind of useless
since you're already an adult.
That leaves 15 and Logan Buchanan...
Yeah about that...
15 was always my favorite.
"When I'm 16 I'll have the best party ever."
But you're not 16 anymore.
Hey.
I kinda have to make an appearance at Krista's party.
Do you maybe want to come with me?
Not as my date or anything.
No.
Of course not.
Well?
I'd love to go with you Jay.
Okay.
Great party.
Ladies first.
Mike?
Give a shout-out to my big sis Abby everybody.
You're super old Abs but you're still cool!
So Mike can really play?
Yeah.
Something just clicked with him this year.
He got serious about playing guitar.
He's getting paid really well for this gig.
Wait. Did I miss something?
I mean besides senior year?
Jay you're here!
Hi! I'm so glad you could make it!
Yeah.
I'm... Abby Jensen.
I know silly.
We're neighbors?
Yes. Neighbors.
Your party looks awesome.
Thanks to your parents.
They found all these amazing decorations in their garage
after their house was infested by wasps.
I guess they were left over from your Sweet 16 Party
but never got used for some reason.
So they just gave them to me!
- Lucky you.  - I know right?
And you're just in time for the big celebration.
Thanks for coming everybody!
Man this is a dream come true for me.
What's happening?
Jay Kepler ladies and gentlemen.
Our new Student Body President!
Thank you.
I want to recognize my campaign manager Krista Cook.
What all of you don't know is that I really wanted this
but I was too afraid to try.
I couldn't have done it without your help Krista.
Thank you so much!
1 2 3 4...
- Have fun okay?  - Mm-hmm.
So you're Student Body President?
Yep.
I was Student Body President.
Oh yeah.
Weird.
I thought with me out of the way Krista would win for sure.
Krista?
She's hates competition.
Our Krista.
Yeah.
I think without you in her life
she just didn't have a reason to compete for anything.
She's kind super helpful
a good listener and a great friend.
You guys would like each other.
If y'know you were the same age right?
Look around it's dead of night
You've been losing every fight
Your hope is feeling broken
Your feet are rough
They're scraped and bruised
But still have strength to take you through
Into the dawn
Just close your eyes
This was supposed to be my party.
...and push right through
I know it's tough right now
This was meant for you
When the clouds are gone
Not a shadow in sight
You'll be drenched in the sun with open eyes
Oh oh oh...
Now at the beach the waves still crash
The tide can grab and pull you back
And the sun may be covered in gray
The sand will itch the salt can burn
The hurricane will take its turn
Until the dawn
Just close your eyes and push right through
I know it's tough right now
This was meant for you
When the clouds are gone
Not a storm in sight
You'll be drenched in the sun with open eyes
So close your eyes shut them tight
Let it be and it will fade away
Fade away
Push on through there's strength in you
Let it be and wish it all away
All away
So close your eyes shut them tight
Let it be and it will fade away
Push on through there's strength in you
Let it be and wish it all away
With open eyes opened wide it's all good
Now watch it fade away
Day by day
Just close your eyes and push right through
I know it's tough right now
But this was meant for you
When the clouds are gone not a storm in sight
You'll be drenched in the sun with open eyes
Large pepperoni pineapple for Jensen.
I didn't order a pizza.
I know.
I just thought you could use a friend.
Oh sweetie.
Dry those tears.
I'm starving.
You are?
Sure us magical beings have to eat too.
This day didn't go like I thought it would.
I can't believe I wasted my wishes on things
like beating Krista Cook.
Yeah.
She's pretty nice now that she is not out to destroy you.
Don't rub it in.
She's a really good friend to Jay.
Better than I was.
I didn't even know he wanted to be Student Body President.
How could I have been so thoughtless?
All I could think about
was having parties and clothes and popularity.
I can't believe those things were so important to me.
You were 16.
But I didn't appreciate it.
Ever since I was little I wanted to grow up.
I thought it was the only way to get what I wanted.
I guess I didn't realize what I already had.
You still have this little number.
Wish 16.
All those years I saved it for something really special.
Of all the wishes on this list
this is the one I wish I could change.
Wow that gum is still really fresh.
Maybe the rules don't know about gum.
There's only one way to find out.
I wish I could start this whole day over again.
Surprise!
Happy Birthday Abby.
Look.
Your first 16th birthday picture.
This is a great picture!
This is the best picture I've ever seen in my entire life!
Thank you thank you thank you!
You're welcome Pumpkin.
Make a wish sweetheart?
I wish for exactly this.
Everything is perfect.
Wasps!
Yeah.
I saw one crawl up the AC vent.
No not one. Thousands!
Nesting up there for 16 years!
Sweetheart we know.
No you don't know. You can't possibly know
that the house is going to be totally infested
and the wasps will take over the cars
and you and Dad'll have to live in the driveway
but then Joey Lockhart will come and kiss me
and I will get candles and wishes
and some really gorgeous clothes
and everything will look like it will be okay.
But then I will make a really stupid wish
that I didn't mean to make
and I will have to grow up and live alone and miss my party
and this will turn into the worst 16th birthday
in the history of 16th birthdays!
You have to call the exterminator now!
Okey dokey.
All done.
Whoo that was some wasps' nest.
Celeste?
Hi Abby.
You know her.
Yeah we just met this morning.
When Abby called me.
You're very lucky I showed up when I did.
So the wasps are all gone.
Like they never happened.
Everything is going to be okay?
Better than okay.
Wait. What do I owe ya?
Consider it a Sweet 16 gift.
Happy Birthday Abby.
Thank you.
For everything.
Well, go on down and start making that special birthday breakfast
you have planned for me Mom.
I'll be right there.
Hey!
This is for you.
I was saving it for my Sweet 16 party
but I think you need it more.
Whoa!
For what?
A real guitar.
I think you're really talented.
Thank you Abs.
I love you Mike.
Thanks for the yummy breakfast Mom and Dad.
Love you!
Love you too.
Krista! Krista! Wait!
Get back.
We need to talk.
I have nothing to say to you.
I have one quick question.
No you cannot have a ride.
I don't want a ride.
I want to understand.
What did I ever do to you?
Go away.
No.
Not until you answer me.
Why don't you like me?
You really don't know do you?
Not a clue.
It was in third grade.
Jay and I were best friends.
Then you moved to town.
It was my birthday.
Jay and I made a pact...
Cheese!
Best friends forever!
Yeah!
I stole your best friend.
On my birthday.
After that Jay and I did everything together.
Without me.
That must have been so horrible for you.
It was.
I can't imagine how you felt.
How I felt?
I felt like a loser.
Krista if I could turn back the clock and change that day
I would.
I am so sorry.
You are?
Any chance you can forgive me?
I don't know.
I made my own vow that day.
- Which was... - I vowed to win at everything
so you'd never get anything you wanted ever again.
Wow.
You did a great job.
Thank you.
Hey imagine if you used your powers for good instead of evil.
Like what?
Do you really want to be Student Body President?
Honestly? No.
It's exhausting having to win all the time.
Well, if you want to drop out
I know somebody who would love to take your place.
Hey Krista.
Hey... Abby?
Boys.
Cool ride!
Thanks!
Weird.
You're a terrible best friend.
- No I'm not. - Yes you are.
I had to take the bus by myself. Where were you?
I got a ride.
You two? In one vehicle?
And it didn't like explode?
Nope.
We have a surprise for you.
Why? It's not my birthday.
- No it's mine... - And mine...
And all we want is for your dream to come true.
What dream?
You're now the only person running
for Student Body President.
So you'll win for sure.
You think so?
Absolutely.
Jay Kepler ladies and gentlemen.
Our new... Student Body President!
Go Jay!
Thanks everybody.
Let's hear it for the hosts of this little party
Abby and Krista!
Happy Sweet 16 to the both of you
- Look who's here. - Huh?
Look!
Logan Buchanan he's so gorgeous!
You really like him don't you?
Yeah.
I thought you liked him to make me suffer.
Making you suffer was a bonus but
I would have liked him anyway.
Well I happen to know he really likes you too.
- Really? - Really.
Go talk to him.
About what?
Ask him about the red sports car he wants to drive someday.
Okay.
Hi Logan.
Thanks a lot for coming.
Thanks. You look great.
Thank you.
Happy Birthday Abby.
Yes it is.
It is now officially the best 16th birthday
in the history of 16th birthdays.
Good.
Check it out.
Happy Birthday Abby!
Just take a chance don't think it's your choice
Wake up don't you hear my voice
I'd swim through broken glass just to define
You left me there freaked out and swept aside
I think it's all been said before
So many times before
So... are you going to start a new wish list.
No.
No more wish lists.
Really? Why not?
Because I have everything I could ever want right here.
I don't want to grow up
Don't want to figure this out
I know you set me up
Don't want this dragging you down
I don't want to grow up
Don't want to figure this out
I know you set me up
Don't want this dragging you down
If you ever been  afraid of anything
This song's for you
I know you're feeling me
If you ever wanted to something big
But then you stopped just couldn't handle it
If you take a chance then it'll be all right
Come on come on come on
You know it's time
Just pu-pu-push it down
And then you'll win the fight
You're better than this you're better than that
Come on let's make it right
Nothing's getting in my way now
Nothing ever will again
If you're with me come on say now
We're gonna make it
We're gonna take what we can
You're gonna sit up and let them know
Just find the courage get up and go
Oh no we're not gonna take it slow
If you know what I'm sayin'
There's no time for waitin'
A wish comes true every day
I wish I could...
That's okay keep going.
When I'm 16 I will have my own car preferably red.
You don't get that wish.
I didn't know what it was.
Jensen!
Wha... bltha... hello?
Bye now sweetheart.
Hold on guys!
I will get you to school on time.
I can't keep my eyes open.
Yup still going.
Ahhhh!
Who's the cutest?
Me!
Okay I got it.
What?
Since I'm not paying for my own party
I don't have to spend...
What?
When I'm 15... What?
Nope.
Work it! Work it!
Hey Mark!
Is he a good dancer?
That was a "not". That was a "not".