- Morning.
- Good morning, Johann.
Morning.
What is it, boy?
Dear God, when shall we be free?
When shall we be free of his evil?
A year has passed since Dracula...
perpetrator of these obscene evils,
was destroyed...
and I, Ernst Muller...
Monsignor of the Holy Catholic Church
in the province of Keinenberg...
decided it was time I paid a visit
to the little village in the valley...
to see that all was well.
Giddap.
Boy.
Boy, come here. You need not fear me.
Where is the Reverend Father?
Can you understand me?
Where is your priest?
Why is he not here saying Mass?
Poor boy.
Then show me where he is.
I have just inspected your church.
But for this boy here, it was empty.
Why was it empty?
Why were you not there saying Mass?
I was there, Monsignor.
I have said Mass.
You have said Mass already
into an empty church?
- Yes.
- Then why was the church empty?
Well?
I think you know, Monsignor.
No, I do not know.
I know that your church
was once vilely desecrated.
But the perpetrator of that ghastly deed...
was destroyed some 12 months ago.
Is that not so?
Was he not sent to his doom
in the waters of your mountains?
And was he not, therefore,
destroyed forever?
Is that not so?
Then why were you not there
in church this morning?
It's the shadow, sir.
- Shadow?
- The shadow of his castle, sir.
It touches the church.
In the evenings it touches it.
Whose castle?
Count Dracula? Is that who you mean?
Why do you not speak his name?
He cannot harm you anymore.
He is destroyed, is he not? And he is dead.
Is he dead or not?
- Yes, he is dead.
- Well, then.
But the evil is still there.
We can feel it in the shadow,
even in the church.
There is no evil in a house of God!
Landlord...
I wish to talk to my priest in private.
Now then, perhaps you'd better tell me
all about it.
It's as they say, Monsignor.
The castle is still evil.
You can feel it.
You can't imagine what it's like.
I am not unacquainted with evil.
The question is,
what are we going to do about it?
I don't know.
Has anybody been up there
since that time?
- To the castle?
- Yes.
- Have you been?
- No. Never.
Then you should have gone
to prove there is nothing to fear.
Me?
I will come with you.
- When?
- Tomorrow, first light.
You will be ready.
Otherwise I shall have to go alone.
That would not be easy for me.
You know the mountains well. I do not.
I will go with you.
Thank you, Father.
I never doubted you.
Dawn will be about 6:00 tomorrow.
We will meet at 5:30.
Please do not be late.
All ready, Father?
Let us pray together.
Dear God.
Come.
No, I can't.
You must follow me.
- There is nothing to fear.
- There is.
It will soon be dark.
- I'm not coming.
- I tell you, there is nothing to fear.
- Have courage.
- Please.
Very well.
You need not come with me.
But you must wait here until I return,
you understand?
Yes.
You'll be quite safe here.
When I return,
we will go down again together.
I understand.
- Wish me well then.
- I do.
And may God protect you.
Father!
Open up!
A brandy. Give him a brandy.
Bar the door.
It's done.
The evil is destroyed forever.
- You went there to the castle?
- Yes.
I read the service of exorcism...
and sealed the door with a cross.
His spirit will never leave there
to trouble you again.
It's a miracle.
You have the thanks of everyone here.
- Has your priest not returned yet?
- The priest?
I had to leave him.
He came down before me.
Yes. The priest was here, Monsignor.
Thank God. Where is he now?
He went off by himself.
He said he wished to be alone.
- I don't know where he's gone.
- I see.
I understand how he must feel.
When he returns,
please tell him what I have done...
and that I wish him Godspeed.
- Then you're leaving now, sir?
- Yes.
There's nothing more to be done here,
and I must go home to Keinenberg.
Who has done this thing?
Monsignor.
It was the Monsignor.
Anna.
Ernst. You're back. That's good.
I wasn't expecting you.
You look tired.
Yes, Anna, I am tired.
- I traveled through the night.
- Not only tired, but worried.
- Did something happen?
- Yes.
Can you tell me about it?
Not just now, Anna. Later, perhaps.
Later will be best.
Now you sit there and rest a moment.
I'll fetch your slippers.
These long journeys are too much for you
at your age.
You should speak to your superiors.
If you don't, I shall.
There are plenty of younger men
who could do your work.
Young men whom you have trained.
You should be allowed
to stay here in Keinenberg with us.
There are six churches here. Or near here.
Enough for you to keep your eye on...
without all this journeying
around the countryside.
Let me take your boots off.
I'll put these slippers on.
- You're as good as a wife to me, Anna.
- Not quite, Ernst.
I shouldn't joke about such things to you,
I know.
There. Off you go and rest.
- Plenty of time for joking tonight.
- Tonight?
Yes. We're having a little dinner party.
It's Maria's birthday.
Did you not remember?
Of course.
- How is she, Anna?
- Maria?
She's as happy as ever.
Why should she not be?
A fine education, a beautiful home.
You're very good to her, you know, Ernst.
I owe it to my brother.
Yes.
Anyone can give charity.
You give us more than that.
You give us your love.
Now off you go and rest.
I'll wake you in plenty of time
for the party.
Try not to worry so.
I'm sure whatever it was that was wrong,
you will have put it to right.
God knows I hope so, Anna.
- You rested? You look much better.
- I feel much better.
- Who is our guest to be?
- Maria has invited a friend.
A young man, Ernst.
Be gentle with him.
He's very precious to her.
He works in the Cafe Johann in the bakery.
That's just to keep him while he studies.
He's a clever boy, Ernst.
He's going to be a doctor,
or professor, or something.
Good.
Making ourselves pretty, are we?
You're going to meet her mama
for the first time tonight, aren't you?
Now, you take a good look at her mama,
my boy...
because that's exactly what your girl's
going to look like after you've married her.
- That is, if her mama lets you marry her.
- And why shouldn't she?
Why shouldn't she?
Why should she? What are you?
Young, hard-working,
good-Iooking, abstemious.
You're a second-class pastry cook.
And if you work hard...
you may in time
become a first-class pastry cook.
And who will want to marry you then?
Up every morning before dawn.
- That's not for me, Max.
- No?
- No. I'm ambitious.
- I see.
Those books of yours.
Where are they going to get you?
Away from here for a start.
- So, you don't like it here?
- I didn't say that, Max.
I do like it here.
It keeps me fit.
And I have time off to study.
- And the food's good?
- And the food's good.
I'm grateful. Really, I am.
Funny way to show it.
What I don't understand is what you hope
to get out of these books of yours.
What life's about, something of the truth.
The truth. What do you want with that?
Look, if you want to be a success in life,
forget the truth.
I can't just forget it.
Then stay a pastry cook.
That way it doesn't matter.
Do you want any money?
Not tonight, Max.
Mind your manners.
And don't go telling her mother
the truth about the way she looks...
and what her cooking tastes like.
That truth she can do without.
Come on, out of the way, all of you.
Move along.
Your dumplings are boiling over, Zena.
And your fly's undone,
but I didn't want to mention it.
Teach you to be cheeky.
Hello. You're looking pretty.
Yes, that's what I thought.
Maria here?
Always Maria.
What about giving me a chance?
Zena, you've got more boyfriends
than you can remember.
I've always got room for one more.
Come on, Paul. Come on, join in.
Very good, Paul.
Here, take this glass. What now?
What indeed.
It's my best suit.
- Zena, I'm going out tonight.
- Not with me, you're not.
I'm meeting Maria's mother.
I want to make a good impression.
I don't want to go through
soaked through smelling of beer.
Now please!
Maria, I'm afraid your boyfriend's
a bit wet about the ears.
Hello, Maria.
Look, I'm sorry about this, but l...
Look at you, and tonight of all nights.
- Don't worry. He'll dry out in the night air.
- Come on, you'll have to come as you are.
Mother hates me to be late,
especially tonight.
Yes, Paul, don't be late for mama!
- Am I forgiven?
- Yes, I suppose so.
- But we must hurry.
- Does it still smell?
- Yes, a bit.
- Do you think your mother will notice?
She'll notice all right,
but she won't say anything.
- Good job your uncle isn't home yet.
- Paul.
Come on, I'll race you home.
Maybe it will dry you out.
Mother, this is...
Happy birthday, Maria.
That's a fine way to greet your uncle.
Uncle Ernst, it's lovely to see you.
- I just didn't expect you, that's all.
- So I gathered.
Paul, I'm terribly sorry.
Mother, this is Paul.
I've told you all about him, haven't I?
Yes, you have, frequently.
- How are you, Paul?
- Frau Muller.
And this is my Uncle Ernst.
So you're on your best behavior.
Sir.
Just the way to make the poor boy
feel at his ease.
Pay no attention to her, Paul.
Make yourself at home.
- Ernst, give Paul a drink.
- Certainly. A glass of wine?
Paul doesn't drink. Do you, Paul?
No, sir. That is, only beer.
I haven't any beer, I'm afraid.
That's all right. I had one before I left.
Only one?
You noticed.
It was rather noticeable.
It was the students at the Cafe Johann.
They played a trick on Paul
and spilled beer all over him.
It was a sort of game, you see...
where the glass
was on the end of a stick...
and I went around
with another glass of beer.
I had to drink, and there was beer in the...
- Would you accept these, Frau Muller?
- Thank you.
You know, Anna, when I'm on my travels,
there's only one thing I dream about:
Your cooking.
Your mind should be
on higher things, Ernst.
- Give Paul a cigar.
- Would you like a cigar, Paul?
No, thank you, sir. To be truthful,
they make me feel a little sick.
You know, I like that in a man, Paul.
Not enough people
say what they really mean these days.
Many people speak only to impress...
not stopping to think
if what they're saying is really true.
Happens in the church, too, you know.
I hear it only too often on my rounds.
- There are six churches here, you know.
- Yes, sir.
Which one do you attend, by the way?
Paul doesn't come from Keinenberg, Uncle.
- This isn't his home.
- I know, but...
He works very hard in the bakery.
He doesn't have much time.
- But on Sundays?
- I don't go to church, sir.
- You don't go to church?
- No, sir.
- You're not a Protestant, are you?
Thank Heaven for that.
I'm an atheist, sir.
- I beg your pardon?
- I'm an atheist, sir.
You mean you deny the existence of God?
I don't deny it. I just don't believe it.
It's my own opinion, sir.
- Do you know who I am?
- Yes, sir.
And you come here to my house,
speaking this blasphemy?
You asked for my beliefs, sir,
and I've given them.
It was an honest answer, sir.
You said you liked people to be honest.
Don't be impertinent.
Would you like me to leave, Frau Muller?
Yes, I think it would be best.
I'm sorry, Frau Muller.
Thank you very much for your hospitality.
Good night, sir.
- Paul...
- Maria, you will stay here.
Oh, Mama.
- Night-night, Zena.
- Good night. Go on, go home.
Come on, girl. Let's go and have a party.
- Give me a schnapps, Zena.
- Back so soon?
Give me a schnapps. A large one.
- You don't drink schnapps.
- Well, I'm starting now.
No need to ask you
if something went wrong.
No, it did. Her uncle turned up.
And you had a row with him.
He asked my opinion.
And you gave it.
- I only told him the truth.
- When will you learn?
- How can people enjoy that?
- They don't. They just like the effect.
- I don't feel any effect.
- You will.
I'll have another one while I'm waiting.
Go to bed.
You coming with me?
You want to be careful what you're saying.
What have you done with my legs?
Come on.
Up to your room before Max gets back.
- Zena.
- Come on.
- What are you doing, Zena?
- I'm undoing your jacket.
You can put me down now, Zena.
Hello, Zena.
What are you doing in my bed?
- You may well ask.
- Yes.
Well, I am asking.
Does she kiss you like that?
I bet she doesn't.
Might as well make you comfortable.
- Zena.
- Hello.
What's going on?
- Nothing.
- What happened?
Three large schnapps.
That's what happened. He's not used to it.
You better help me get him into bed.
Zena, don't...
Well, he's your boyfriend.
You tuck him up.
What are you doing in my bedroom?
I feel sick.
- I think I'll have a glass of water.
- I'll get it.
That's better. Have some. It's delicious.
- I can't think why I drink anything else.
- Nor can I.
- I spoiled everything at dinner, didn't I?
- I'm afraid so, Paul.
It's because I always have to
go and tell the truth.
Why can't I make
a lot of polite conversation...
like everybody else?
What do I have to take things
so seriously for?
Because you're you, I suppose.
Fat lot of good it does me.
That's why I love you, Paul.
Do you love me, Maria?
In spite of everything?
Do you still love me?
I think you must...
otherwise you wouldn't be here like this...
with me.
Zena, you still here?
- Is Paul back yet?
- He's upstairs studying.
- He's a good boy. He'll go far.
- Not too far, I hope.
Well, I... What are you doing here?
I've locked up
and you've got a long way to go.
Do you want to stay the night
or something?
No, thanks.
I've had enough trouble with
all those students, without you as well.
Besides, a walk's good for my figure.
- Off you go, straight home.
- Good night.
Don't come with me.
- Are you sure?
- I'm quite sure.
- Shall I see you tonight?
- I'll try.
Goodbye.
You gave me a shock.
What are you doing here?
I didn't go home last night.
You've been here all night? But why?
I just didn't feel like going home.
Do you want some coffee?
- Hey, what's the matter...
- I'm all right!
Now do you want some coffee?
Yes, please.
Serve the priest, will you, Zena?
You want something, Father?
Breakfast, hot rolls, chocolate?
I wondered if perhaps there was a room...
which I could rent for a few days?
- Sorry.
- We do have a room.
The one next to Paul is empty.
If I could have it.
It's a very small room, Father.
You couldn't swing a cat in it...
and it's right at the top of the house.
I don't care what it's like or where it is.
If you'd be so kind.
You can have it for a few days.
Paul, show him up, will you?
Do you have any baggage, Father?
- Just this.
- I'll take it.
You're very kind.
What's come over you?
I don't want a priest here.
Is this your first visit
to Keinenberg, Father?
Yes.
I'm here on church business.
Do you know the Monsignor
by any chance?
We have met. I know his niece better.
His niece?
Paul, get me some more glasses. Please?
- Paul!
- Coming.
Would you take over for me for a minute?
I don't feel very well.
I said you didn't look well.
- Just for a while.
- Yes, of course.
What's the matter? What have I done?
- There is a girl.
- A girl? What girl?
- The niece of the Monsignor.
- Maria?
Bring her to me.
What do you want her for? You've got me.
Bring her to me!
Hey, now, Paul.
Come on, that's not enough.
Hello. You feeling better?
Yes, I'm fine now.
You can go back to your studies.
Thanks. You sure you feel all right?
Yes. Back to your dreary old books.
Paul, is Maria coming in tonight?
- I hope so, if she can get away.
- I'll call you when she comes.
Thanks, Zena. You're a good sort.
Some more beer, Zena. Hurry up.
I'm dying of thirst.
I'll give you a hand, Zena.
- Zena, hurry up.
- Come back, Zena.
We'll never get a drink now.
- Hello, Zena.
- Hello, Maria.
- Where's Paul?
- He's downstairs in the bakery.
Thank you.
- Hello, Maria.
- Hello, Max.
Lovely girl, that.
Paul, come on.
No!
- What have you done with Maria, Paul?
- Maria?
She was looking for you.
Stop messing about.
You know she's not here.
Where is she, Paul?
- Who?
- Maria.
What have you done with her, Paul?
- Is she really here?
- Yeah, she went down there to find you.
- Where's Maria, Paul?
- He can't find her.
She's not down there, Max.
You'd better go and try upstairs,
but I'm sure she went down to the bakery.
Sneaked her up to his room.
That's what he's done.
Are you hurt? What happened?
- Don't leave me!
- I won't.
But how did you get here like this?
I don't know.
I came to look for you, and then I...
It's all right, darling.
- You have failed me.
- But I...
- You must be punished.
- Forgive me.
I wasn't to know. I tried.
But what do you want her for?
You've got me.
Well, you've got me!
Here, have a drink of this.
It will do you good.
- Now what was it?
- She went down there to find me...
and the next thing she knew,
somebody had attacked her.
Something about a man with burning eyes
staring at her.
I saw him. I know I did.
No, love. It was in your mind.
You just thought you saw him, that's all.
She may have fainted.
Do you think she should go to bed?
Yes, come upstairs and rest.
No, I can't. I must go home.
Mother will be wondering where I am.
Just until you feel a little better, Maria.
I can't understand it.
Now come on up.
Destroy her.
It's all right, darling. There's nobody here.
I must have been dreaming.
Here, drink this.
Then I'll take you home.
No, you can't. My mother will see.
But if you tell her what happened...
No, how can I?
I don't even know what happened myself.
She'd be furious if she knew I'd come here.
I could explain.
No, I don't suppose
that would help much either.
I'm all right, really.
When shall I see you again?
I don't know.
I'll try and come tomorrow.
If not, I'll get a message to you.
I'll come with you part of the way anyway.
- Where have you been?
- Mother...
You've been with Paul, haven't you?
- I know it looks like...
- What does it look like?
You should be ashamed of yourself.
Maria, my darling.
Ernst!
Girls. Unreliable, the whole lot of them.
Come and go just as they please.
No sense of responsibility.
That's what I like about you, Paul.
I can rely on you.
That Zena hasn't turned up all day.
- Went off and never said she was going.
- She was here last night.
Last night. I know all about last night.
What's the matter with you today?
Off with some student, I suppose.
Come back again in about a fortnight
and want her job back.
Father.
Will you do something for me?
Will you go and find out how Maria is?
Go to her home?
Yes, she lives with her uncle,
the Monsignor.
You must know him.
Will you go and find out how she is
and give her this note?
- Very well.
- Thanks.
- I brought you some soup, Maria.
- Thank you, Uncle Ernst.
Sit up now.
Drink it while it's... I've forgotten a spoon.
It doesn't matter, Uncle Ernst.
I'm not hungry.
Please forgive me.
There, there.
Do you love him, Maria?
- Yes, I do.
- Do you want to tell me about it?
Not now.
All right. When you're ready.
Sleep now.
God bless you, Maria.
Father, what happened?
Maria. How is she? Is she well?
Did you give her the note?
- Yes.
- And?
- She is well.
- When can I see her?
- Not yet.
Later she will come here to see you.
- When?
- As soon as she can.
- You are still working here, are you?
- Sorry, Max.
Come on. I need you.
She was lying here just like this.
Not moving and scarcely breathing.
She's sick. She's very sick.
- Was the window open?
- Yes.
Yes, it was open, just like this.
I didn't touch it.
You think she's caught a chill, is that it?
Possibly.
The night air can be very treacherous
at this time of year.
- Possibly.
- Ernst, shouldn't we call the doctor?
If she's not better tomorrow.
Tomorrow, yes.
- How is she?
- Sleeping like a child.
Did you close the window?
- Yes, but on such a warm night.
- Good.
Don't stay up too late, Ernst.
Good night, Anna.
You.
There, my love. Tell me, what is it?
Maria, tell me what happened. What is it?
Anna, help me!
Oh, dear God!
Here, lean on me.
You must go.
You must get him to come here.
- You should rest.
- No, Anna.
Listen to me.
You must fetch that boy.
- The one who was here.
- Paul?
- Bring him here to me.
- Why Paul?
Because he loves her. He will help her.
- I'll go now, Ernst.
- No. Anna.
Perhaps it is better you do not go
until daylight.
Count Dracula is alive.
During the hours of darkness...
she must never be left alone.
You understand that?
Not for one moment
must you leave her side.
Protect yourself as best you can.
There are devices
which may be of some effect:
Charms, herbs.
You will find it all here.
You are a scholar of sorts, I understand.
- Well, I...
- They are all in Latin.
Do the best you can. What little time...
- I'll get a doctor.
- No time.
You must swear
to do what I have told you.
- I promise.
- You should swear by almighty God...
but you have denied yourself this.
You have my word.
I know I have.
Thank you.
Anna, the boy must stay here.
Yes, of course. Hurry. Get your things.
Come back quickly.
There is much to do before dark.
- What on earth are you doing?
- Keep my job open for me.
I'll explain later.
Father, I need your help. Hurry up.
Come with me, please. Please hurry.
What happened?
"The flowers of garlic should be placed...
"on either side of the head
of the one to be protected.
"No more than a hand's breadth
away from the throat.
"The oil from the clove of garlic...
"should be smeared around the edges
of any aperture in the wall...
"doors and windows...
"lest the vampire try to gain ingress."
He meant to give it to her for her birthday.
It's all right, Frau Muller. You go and rest.
I promise you, I'll call you if I need you.
Why don't you go and rest, Father?
No.
Yes. You go and lie down. I can manage.
I can't!
What are you trying to do?
- He told me to do it.
- He who?
- Who told you?
- Dracula.
How could he tell you? You, a priest?
- Where is he?
- He willed me to do it.
I cannot disobey him.
Now I'm willing you. Do you understand?
- First you'll tell me where he is.
- No, I can't.
- Second, you'll take me to him.
- No.
You will take me to him, now!
Quickly, before he wakes.
Quickly.
You must do it now!
Pray! You must pray!
- I can't!
- You must.
- You must, or he won't die.
- You pray! You're a priest!
He won't die!
He isn't going to die!
Maria, get away from here!
Now my revenge is complete.
- What's the matter, lad?
- Max.
It's Maria.
Good evening. It isn't often
we see strangers in these parts.
There's a castle
somewhere in the mountains here...
belonging to a Count Dracula.
- Do you know him?
- We know who you mean.
I have to go there.
- Why? It's empty. There's no one there.
- Not for long. He's on his way here.
- Dracula? Impossible.
- It's true. I swear it.
- He's dead. He died months ago.
- No, he's alive.
- He's alive, and he's coming here.
- Then you brought him.
Why can't you leave us alone?
Why must you meddle?
- Please listen to me.
- Quiet!
Let me by!
- I must get by!
- Be silent!
Please, I have to follow.
If you take my advice, you'll go
straight back to where you came from.
Will someone show me the way
to the castle?
You won't get anyone to go up there
with you, son. Not even in daylight.
Will someone just show me the way then?
Surely one of you
has got the courage to do that.
- Come on then.
- You're not going anywhere!
We're sick of people
interfering with our lives.
And if we leave things alone,
then maybe he'll leave us alone.
But he's evil, and while he's alive,
none of you will be safe.
Take him upstairs and lock him up
until he cools off.
No, let him go.
He'll be sorry.
Get that thing out of my sight.
Throw it away!
Maria!
Amen.