I'm driving.
I'm going to Twentynine Palms.
Yes.
I do not know.
I'll  be just a few days.
Back in a few days.
Good. Thank you.
No, I will set up places, the hotel,
And go back again.
Who was he?
No I said  I would.
All right?
All is well ...
My love.
Look!
It's great.
Listen.
It's fantastic.
It's perfect.
Someday, I'd like  to see you pee.
No..
You're not even echo the picture?
What do you think?
Do not think of anything.
Are you thinking something.
No nothing.
Not true.
It's true.
Why do not you tell me?
I'm driving. What?
What?
Katia!
What do I say?
Come ...
What? What?
Do you love me?
Hold me tap.
Do you like  my penis?
Put it inside.
Put it ...
Open  up.
Put it in!
Do you feel  my penis?
More,more!
Katia!
Do you feel it?
Sorry! Sorry!
What do you eat?
Do not  know.
Chinese?
Do you know  any site?
Yes.
Good.
It's always  the same.
Yes.
What is  that?
Do not  know.
I think it's ...
An art  film.
It's amazing.
Come on, I'm done.
I want  that.
I can not find in the letter what is
Eating man.
Why do not  you ask?
As you wish, but I can find
And ask the waitress.
Want me to do it?
I can go and ask.
When the waitress comes, I will tell
what we want, and we share.
Whatever.
- Are you going to ask?
- Yes please.
A vapeur menu.
What do you eat this man?
Thanks.
Is it easy eh?
That there.
Can you tell me who is that?
Shrimp Foo-yong.
I'll take that.
- Anything else?
- No.
We share it.
Did I miss something wrong?
The bartender is disgusted by that
We have asked recently. It's normal.
- Shrimp.
- Thanks.
Are you happy to start the exploration?
I am happy ...
To be here ...
You.
Come.
You can go  with it.
Want me to go with it?
Go..
Why?
Why watch it?
Want  ...
It's a normal reaction to look  at the people
happens to me.
It's normal to look at people.
But it means nothing
I'm sorry.
What can  I say?
Sorry, it is ridiculous ...
I did not  want ...
When we begin to go down ...
We will see a great ...
Plain  ...
The Joshua Tree!
You'll like it.
Look  ...
Come!
It leads you.
- Well?
- Yes.
Let's  go.
Can you tell me which is the brake
and as is the accelerator?
You tread there.
Wait  ...
The brake. Pisa there.
Let's  go.
Slow down.
Katia, slowly.
Okay.
Turn left.
You are going to scratch the car.
Please ...
Do not  move.
Shit.
Is it serious?
Maybe  ...
Yes, it worked.
I think we can do something
to fix ...
Perhaps if we found some rocks.
Not that you laugh.
It's no fun!
It's my fault, but it is fun.
No, fine.
Forgive me for a fool.
Do you think  this right?
Sorry.
And that has not yet finished.
Over there, over there.
To.
To the left!
To the left  ... Left!
If you help me ...
If I help you, you may not hit
shrubs.
Over there!
Sorry, if you want to help,
will have to help either.
No, David, still.
Para.
Why not?
Please.
Well.
Let's  go.
Spread your legs.
I am very dry, my love.
I have bad feet.
Let's  go.
We're going to lie down.
It hurts.
Oh, my  ass.
You can lie down on my foot.
Yes.
We're going to burn.
Quemémonos!
Well wrapped!
I'm burning.
I..
It's nice here.
Let's  go.
I do not want.
Please ...
Why?
Why yes.
You hear that?
A thunder ...
We gotta go.
It's dangerous.
No, not  true.
No way.
Not true.
OH, than good.
You're crazy.
It was not wanting, Katia.
Sorry.
Sorry  ...
I've echo  damage.
What is  that?
A father confesses to his wife ...
Who has slept with his daughter.
That poor.
Who?
The mother.
You'd do that?
What?
Are you  crazy?
What can  we do?
Do not  know.
I have hunger.
Ya!!
Okay.
I'm going to  buy polish.
Well done!
Stupid!
Outside of the street!
This street is ours!
Out of  here!
Do you  feel?
Yes.
But that does not catch.
- #;And you who have bought?
- Cream to me.
Sure it's the same product,
But with different names.
Come here.
I'm starving?
A cold.
A cold?
Two ice  cream.
Hey, she's great.
What?
You think?
And what do  you think?
What?
Would you like to ...
... Shave my head like that?
If you want, I ...
I think I understand better
if the words.
If you want ...
I'll leave you.
Do not you like the Marines?
Yes, of course! They are beautiful.
So what?
They are.
#But you're saying?
Is this  good?
Is not this good?
But is this right?
I do not understand.
You say things that  do not understand.
There is nothing  to understand.
Well.
Are you sulking?
No, I'm not angry.
Yes, those sulky.
I wish that our conversations
had some logic.
Because sometimes you say something,, I say otherwise
and not to talk.
Talks are meaningless ...
I love  you.
And I to you, my love.
Are we going?
Let's  go!
Here comes ...
- David, do you lock?
- Yes.
What happpens?
This hard.
Pull yourself.
Does it  work?
It is miraculous.
Are we going?
What you're lying in your hair?
I drive.
Not so fast, I  have to pee.
Stop!
See how we are not alone.
Want to  drive?
Drive.
Come.
I know..Pisa
- brake.
- I know.
Now is ...
Perfect.
I can?
It's all  yours.
794 000 hectares.
I do not understand.
What is  that?
794 000 hectares!
What does that mean?
I think this road  leads to the 62.
Perhaps you should check the road.
Well?
Here.
Hey, a  home.
Watch the dogs!
Dogs!
Good dog.
Good boy.
You're a real dog.
I do not think you understand French
affection.
Are we going?
Look.
Come  go.
Let's  go.
Come with me.
Run, run ...
I can not see in the mirror.Care
eh ....
Stop!
You have stepped on the dog!
Look!
Shit  ...
I did not see in the mirror!
Do something. Come  on, do something!
What do you want? I can not
do anything.
Call someone!
Look. Okay.
Katia.  Mira.
Call someone!
Look!
Do something for the dog!
Do something for once!
I can not do anything, do not understand
mita or the things you say.
If you feel better, then, perhaps
can help.
But I can not do anything for you.
You do not do anything! I do not care
Do something, is ...
Doggy  ...
Look!
You see!
Look, fine.
Okay.
You've done nothing.
You have not done anything.
Not true!
- Do not have a heart.
- You know you're wrong.
Almost kill him.
Male disggusting!
It was all  black ...
With three  legs ...
I'm leaving ...
There you go!
My love.
Open the door.
Open the fucking door.
If you're not going to open? Do not open.
We no longer see more.
I'll take back to Los Angeles.
We should not have come here ever.
Did you know that you behave as
Princess a whore!
There is no reason  for
to do this.
I'm out.
Go..
I never want to  see your face!
Come here,, Katia.
Beware! The car!
You are not good, Katia.
Fuck you!
Stop!
I hate you! I hate  you! I hate you!
They're  crazy!
I have  fear.
What?
Do not know. Shall we go?
Yes.
What can we  do, David?
Do not  know.
Do we turn?
Where?
I drive.
Make  me.
Oh god, I turn  away dammit!
David 's crazy!
Go!
I can not go faster!
Away from me, asshole!
Let me, motherfucker!
We have to call the police.
I love  you.
Are we going to  eat something?
Subtitle by heremony