got it all got everything
you need just name it everything got some Gucci
got it all i could give you one for free so far
as you promised me a date
what up st James
oh up st James
hold self hold self
hold self got them squeakers
yo see these zivities
mate and the black and white
white and yellow and shit with the red we become butterfly
though i got everything
my highlight me already looks
give my money
yo sixteen in a box
it's not a 20 box
hello beautiful
Louis Vuitton
coach products and what the fuck you mean
i'm hustling like fuck
yo you always look that freshly
freshly you feel me
what's the weaker with today
what do you need
got it all i got a Gucci fraud
it's just named it
got everything
go to the back frame so all the way to the back back
let me open that door for you everything you need
watch your head
please no damn
like what you see you see what i got the air you know
your man is right
the new j's new forces i got the Gucci
new far see what i got
got mercy for my people
you don't even worry about the prices is man
lovely too you know
yo you see that LeBron right there
got the uptown store right
the orange stripes yeah so how much is there
that's what it is that's love right there
so you coming back always always
see i did you change right
sweetie you got signaling
yo he's mad money outside you need to come outside
get the fuck out of here let's make some money Nigga
Louis Vuitton
coach Prada got it all
the box Mama you need that talk to the man
can we be beautiful don't be scared i don't bite
this is a good old New York city
all right i'll be back next month two boxes
all right Tony Chill talk to me i got Gucci
the Prada
Tony and peg
all the way to bring them out here no
no we cannot do that let me get this
don't worry girls
it's only merchandise there it's right through there
you see
aren't you helping her Chinese man stitch that shit by hand
you know hand stitch
Chinese shit fine play
that's why we get all
you give them ten percent for charity
you know goes to Chinese kid
ten percent goes to Chinese charity
two fifteen now yeah
i should do a straw base my good wrist is driving
go get your ass in the street come on
it's crazy it's cold too
and the mayor says get back in your fucking car
ratchet my homie we not having that can't pack keeps thinking
it's a good jokes
i'm never blood money
i would drop it from motherfucking resume catch half
with a motherfucking Cheddar bay
oh shit is cold
hi hi
how are you
i'm fine how are you good
are we eating anything
i'm going up anywhere
i wish you told me i did tell you
you should listen
like who is talking we got what you try
i got everything
yo he got two containers company for the twenty five oh
i haven't been on bro with for a week now they got new jordans
who got them shit air forces
why don't white nigga
the other day you know what something
i ask you for tip you know i mean they talk to me
while i'm rolling weak yeah
you fuck up my concentration
yo you heard about it how Nasty shit
they given bush please give them Nasty nigga what they gonna
do they gonna give you a paper and send your ass to you right
look in my eyes if you fucked there yet well
what should i told you for fuck
you gotta wish it if you beat it on one nigga you hear me
get a fuck out of you
可是我的裤子
多
hmm somebody's been smoking
no i got it all too just just yeah yeah
the boss went ahead of us yeah yeah
maybe take them close
so if i need that
okay boulevard was alright
but i suppose what you want to say was boulevard
hmm is she my Ben lucky hustler
no no
no
i'm a salesman basically professional assaultsman professionals
yeah with degrees with degrees
with type of degrees
from the school of you know Broadway
check it out start some restart box
hello baby
i've saved 2d
are you serious 2000
i'm getting champagne
no no
no you're not getting champagne no no
no no you're going to school remember
i
guess some one more time can i hit that shit
real quick you want to hear like shit can i make love to you
oh yeah
i like that better go downtown
go downtown baby
please
oh my god this kid is mad heavy
and it's fucking freezing out here tired of this shit
i'm about to get sick
he looks for people that look
like they got money and hustles them to get inside
takes them upstairs go ahead and fucking you know
make some buy some fake ass shit
get off my earring man
whoa to need my dude
you need some bags of towns and jordans simblings nah
i mean see him today
what do you think
yeah you're not great
you're stressing me out
i don't know i'm not trying to stress you at all
i can do it all and allow them when you momma
i got bags Louis Vuitton
coach Prada
Gucci i got everything
you need that judas flavor puppy
judas flavor yeah you do yeah
i have everything everything
this doesn't feel right doesn't feel right at all
just shut up let's just do it unless
it's not gonna hurt you you get fast quality
you got second quality
and ten quality all you do with fast quality because i do hustle
you know
we're around the corner right
around the corner we're story seven time to kill why
don't we go
please mom swear to god i don't eventually
let's go all right
all right
you're not police though right
you never know why people come in different college hey
you want to take this lady
swimming to ladies from bed you crazy him to plug
his hut no go to Alex
no Jake get out of here
go all right let's go
i'll take care of you all right
lucky
i don't think so oh
mama listen i just hit the surgery oh mommy
you know what
if you cannot climb it from the middle
i'll carry you up or i'll make it up to you
i'll give it a discount okay
thank you yeah
lucky
hey Ling Dong
what's fucking you
looking good what the fuck you been
you hold the farmer real quick
i'm not here for that shit no
let me finish with this customer no man i got customers here
take away
what you need Louis Baton coach pride
i'm about to take this lady look
that's your son
and i need you to stay with him for a couple of weeks
listen to me
i'm not playing this is not a game this is your son
and i need you to help me with him come on listen to me
he's your son just take him come on
i've been taking care of him for a year and a half and now
it's your fucking turn to take care of him
i'm serious and i gotta go
so you do whatever
you have to do sell your bags do whatever
make your money but make sure you take care of him all right yo
yo yo
yo wait wait wait wait wait wait Linda Linda
Linda
never get go you know you might never get me saved you nigga
what are you trying to say that i'm man
i used to stop on my shit and shine
that's your son look at him
look at him that's your son look at him
so we gotta go
you guys you guys are playing right
this is a joke you crazy let's go
take the bag here
let's go where are you
no don't touch him
don't touch him and
yo
Linda be a responsible father
be a man for once take care of your fucking kid i'm out man
listen why you doing this to me man you crazy
where the fuck you coming from Linda listen
Linda you crazy
no stop
what the fuck is going on
listen listen
no no Linda
no listen
whoa what the fuck is going on man listen
imma give it some money
oh shit
stop that shit man
yo what the fuck is wrong with you
what the fuck is this man get man take care
of the fucking take care of this
or you can get with that make your son up
man niggas know fuck with us
you getting glad fuck the way i scream my game
get in the fucking car
get
in the car
come get your fucking son nigga baby
you nasty and you gotta keep your fucking legs closed
you do not stupid bitch
i'm a fucking nerves nigga
you already in the car why the fuck you have to get out
i'm tired of you watching me
fucking jump and you put me in the middle of this stupid shit
you got me fighting in the street with this blood diamond
nigga
if you one hundred seventy six degree yo
Linda get on the fucking phone
stand clear of the closing doors
please Linda
Linda
where the fuck are you Linda
yes
hello who are you
please please
where the fuck is Lin oh
for what the fuck is Linda
man don't be cursing on my window she moved out two weeks ago
and don't be coming to my fucking window
saying nothing about her i don't want nothing to do with it
listen
listen listen
i'm really stressed up
she can't believe this baby
she left with her boyfriend to do her life
i don't got nothing to do with it listen
i have no people i'll be gone i'm getting hearted Jack
and no one the fuck got me
she got me tired already
don't wanna deal with our crazy life no more
that's that's your man you take responsibility of him
this baby is not my baby
please she don't send care for him
why should i care
i don't wanna be bothered what the fucking shit
in the back of your fucking
boyfriend
she moved towards for them somewhere i don't know listen
i have no people i'll be gone what can i do with this baby
please
oh oh
oh
shit
listen you listening now
you hear me this is my house
all right listen
hey i know you can hear me this is my house
you don't walk out of that door without me without telling me
yeah i know you got pretty hair
stop bothering with your white looking hair
you don't you don't touch those
those are my ponos
you know that was my special collection go to jail to touch
those open the fridge i got come on drink
i'm talking about
gotta in the everything alright
don't touch you don't touch my smoke
you don't look like me i swear to god you don't look like
but i know you know that i never did don't cry you make me cry
oh god
look at your face
okay please
your lips maybe
hello baby
can you come over tonight please
咪咪咪
all right call me when i get off the train
all right
bye
oh baby
almost yeah
such a pain come on
i have to pee with it come on do it do it gotta go
nice
still right here don't look sit right here you look that way
okay
shit off
listen still listen still right here
no fucking move that's my shit
what is it
fucking shit
what
so freaking shit
just so ah no what do you want to come in just come in
you're asking very weird what's wrong with you
just talk to me
look baby
listen spit it up
just promise me you're not gonna freak out
promise what
please why do you want me to promise
that everyone wants to tell
just come this shit is driving me crazy baby
listen don't freak out
i told you don't freak out on me
i am gonna freak out if you keep talking about that yo
look how this freaking baby
fuck baby listen this shit is oh my god
what is it
this shit is really
this freaking girl
i used to date right
no my god he's stressing out
okay what happened
i don't even know how to would you stop mumbling
and tell me what it's about baby
you don't even know what's going on
why didn't tell me what's going on
i don't even know this stupid baby this stupid girl
don't even remember oh my god
she came to my job
i don't even know why she found out my job
she came to the job she
dubbed this baby
or she said it's my baby
so just let the baby on the street and left what should i do
okay
no no
no you need to rewind this for me okay
rewind this for me
yes you are what are
you telling me
you gotta tell me
something tell me the whole story
what i left it upstairs when you run upstairs
holy oh baby
i told you i told you
you think i'm joking what is that
i'm not joking baby
what is that that's it
that's your baby
what that's not my baby baby listen
let's go downstairs
all right let's try and talk about this downstairs oh
my god do you have a baby
this doesn't look like me
look at it please don't even go
we could don't let me go crazy
right now have a baby please baby come downstairs the long lord
please don't do that shh
my god you have a fuck
i'm also tired of you
you still right there no
you have a baby oh
baby
this is crazy
that's what i get from the story right
right baby
i don't have a baby
you don't have a baby what is that
that's a baby
he asked me yeah fuck
you can say that
stop screaming
i am kiddosters get nervous right now
kiddosters please look at this
look at look at his face
look at his hairs
look there's nothing
like me look look
look he's got to be a little dark baby look
look at his hair
look at his hair look
if i ask you okay
what woman baby listen
listen i know somebody with a mixed kid baby
i know somebody with a mixier doesn't look
like that i know so many people with mixed kids
they don't look like you
she just wakes up in the morning and thinks to herself hey
i'm just gonna pick this guy
randomly in the street and drop the baby off
i'm telling you the truth all right
i slept with it i didn't even come inside here
i swear to god anytime
i'm coming i don't want to know that i swear to god no
no no i don't want to know that
Ew okay
okay okay
uh what did you call the police do something
how can i call the police
you crazy no
i have no pimpies you crazy
didn't didn't
i don't know chuck
that's what i'm going crazy
i would have taken it to the prisoner right here
children service is something what type of mother would do this
anyway what type of girl do you sleep with
please all right
she said two weeks okay
please just just just help me out for two weeks list
i'm just praying she comes to pick this thing up
do some man
so has it eaten
yet i was about to go get Chinese for all of us
you're gonna have Chinese for dinner
it was so funny i'm not playing right here
shut up and do what no
you're eating everything go to sleep
so we can make some love hey
don't even think you're getting love stress that name
hey don't go there
啊哈啊哈啊哈啊哈啊哈
it's okay
it's just a i counted but why don't you count it
one more time
by the way that shit
you gave me two weeks ago that fucking luck cost
what about old navy shit man
come on what are you talking
listen listen you know
you sold them all and you know
you don't even have one piece left
don't give me a penny on that
what air force
one got another air force
oh yeah yeah
i heard about that shit
yeah yeah
towns right yeah
how much you got four container
i'm gonna drop you a nice price nice price
you sell a 55 a pop how much is it
20 pieces of box
size seven to 13 free package how much man 32 dollars
you kidding me 32 dollars
32 what do you mean you kidding me 32
i'll tell you full shipment how much money
you make some money 28 dollars
will
you know we'll call it
a deal no big twenty eight bucks no big English
we should talking about no big English
i'm telling you i can't do it no fuck that no
no no i'm not paying you 34 bucks let me
let me finish you know
let me talk yeah
i'm telling you tell me
this is what i cuff for you two weeks cash
complete amount money
i charge you 30 apart and well
i'll have a nice day two weeks
two weeks all right put them
big ass lips look at yours
look at the nose
yeah look at the nose
that is not a white boy's nose fuck
this shit come on
even give me a fucking love god
this shit is crazy shut up
air for DVDs air for DVDs
knock
knock yo what's up baby
what are you going
who is this man
this fucking bitch
i used to you know remember that fucking bitch what bitch
no no
no no no no no you you playing right homie
you don't even know what i'm going to nigga
he white you black son i know what the fuck are you doing
oh my god oh my god
what the fuck
what's his name
i don't know his fucking man you know you know the fucking baby
no the baby is white you black you got
an Oreo cookies this is not funny listen
this shit is serious man this is some serious shit man
this shit is killing me this is your color
this shit is hotline
this is hot
oh boss what oh boss
what is this is the shit
that happened yesterday boss
that's why could
it come back do i deserve this boy
just look what deserve this
this bitch broke this shit on Broadway and throw it on me
oh my god hold on brother hold on
she's like hold the baby for me
one second i hold the baby she's like take the baby so baby
i'm like what the fuck you crazy
why didn't you i need help
i need help
i cannot go to the police yeah
i can never go to the police
right boss how am i gonna go to the police
i have everything for you
we'll come back
come on my friend is in trouble
let me see sorry about that huh get it get
it
are you fucking crazy
are you kidding me
think that bitch is on fucking drugs niggas
that bitch is smoking some fucking oh man shit
you see yours man
on the real a fucking raw
Mrs fucker a fucking raw twice
you don't understand what you're getting yourself into
do you know what i'm saying
do you understand what you are getting yourself into
this is a little baby man
what am i gonna do with this shit
i don't know what you gonna do to buy it out
what the fuck is that
that's some money just just go home tonight
don't work get the kid buy him
some milk get out of here keep him warm
man if you can look on my face i don't look like you
don't look like me don't look on my face
don't look on my face
where's the daddy
where's your daddy
yo this is not funny boss don't take this ass into it all right
here
hold on to him
hold him nicely
you don't hold the kid like that
hold it with the other hand there you go okay
put the hat on him
all right
go
come on
i'll see you tomorrow
go
i'll call you
what i get hold the kid
man
you're gonna drop
i don't get a fuck
are you fucking kidding
me hold the kid all
right now you go
oh
fuck damn what the fuck
you doing still
oh my god
please do me a favor go to sleep
i don't want to scream by you okay
ah shit shit
hit you back
you want to get like that huh what the fuck
am i gonna do with you
teach you how to hustle
didn't have a problem with they didn't do anything
you got a Hustle
you know how to hustle
absent James
you all need some cakes some sneakers need some cakes
Louis Vuitton
Mama coach
Prada got it all
fuck you here
nobody even want to look at me so give me
the give me the 25 for the joiners right there
oh come on man
how could i do jakes
just one pair for you man
this is one sign they can make it
happen you have breakfast
come on hold on let me
low
you're gonna take 2.5 for the abs
man he said 27 nigga
啊
啊啊啊啊
嗯啊啊
啊
after getting some cakes boy got it look good just like me
got the Louis printed all over it see the buckles right here
this real shape so take a couple take two more
you need even more pink right there now pink coat
that's not pink enough oh
we want pinky pinky
yeah you have all the rounds and stuff go right to there
there's a guy waiting for you see what
we
got with that sure
but for y'all gotta guess saying i'm saying whatever
it is seventy five forty five i need to say seventy
one thirty five forty dollars she deserves
that's all i do what we got to do forty five dollars like one
Tony you need some bags still get big
i got everything i got bags
i want these you got these in thirteen you got those in thirteen
yeah i bought those i'm like thirteen okay
two plays of thirteenth they're going out back
don't worry
i got a lot of them i've got cold cheese like a prada
what time is it
i don't know what time is it
it's four o'clock what is it
yeah
where were you
i was out
oh where
Manhattan
where Manhattan
dance club
guys
what guys
that is a dumb question live on
sexy dancing
live on
are you flirting
i know you love to flirt when you're drunk
you know i love to flirt when i'm drunk
how do i flirt when i'm drunk
hi
i'm an idea
i'm an artist
i'm married do you say that stuff when you're flirting
stupid question
what the fuck
let's go
you know i'm not on the pill
hello
what fuck Linda what the fuck you been
listen
i need you to do me a huge face
listen just wait how the fuck
can you leave a king
you crazy ain't nobody would do that shitty
just oh man shit you know why listen
i need you to stay with the baby for two more weeks
oh shit you stupid
listen to me
i just need some more time i have a lot of things going on
right now
i'm fucking frustrated with this thing around me
and you know you know how my situation is
how am i gonna take off this fucking stupid
why are you being so fucking
difficult Linda what you doing in here
i gotta go
i gotta go no
you can't let's talk about this two more ways
Linda i gotta go
are you still there
哎呀哎呀
啊
do you have any bad ideas
hey don't touch the heater
do you understand it
so not time all right
go to sleep
yeah like that
yo son you know his dude named lucky
yeah but what's up
i got whatever you need baby
no no
no i gotta talk to him about my man
i told you i got better prices yo boy
i gotta talk to him about some personal shit man
check out the corner over there
right front of the store over there
you know whatever
i'm with round the corner
round the corner
look at them all right my nigga
hey what up man
you seen lucky
oh lucky
it's lucky your boy
lucky man a hustle for you man
what's up with lucky
look man
i need to speak to somebody soon
what do you want to talk to him about
listen man just tell that motherfucker to stop
calling my girl
Linda you understand i'm gonna break that nigga's face again
are you the guy who dropped a kid on him
what
what was a fucked up thing to do
why would you do that
you're watching
what is fucking
what the fuck is wrong with
you
get the fuck out of here
i said you fucking fuck you nigga you suck
my thick
fan motherfucker
you only spending two hours on Broadway
how much you make ten dollars
today you get a buy diapers food
you spend four hundred dollars on toys and your landlord chasing
you for these fucking money
red money look going through shit nigga nothing
that feel no beer nothing nothing
yo i gotta feel nothing what you doing that's not your son
you not listening
哈哈哈哈哈哈
what is it
oh baby listen
it is 7 a m
i'm gonna kill this baby
please i'm gonna kill this baby baby
what a look what a look it's crazy
it's gonna be good i'm telling you all the way here
baby i'm sorry oh
yeah you better
啊哈哈哈哈哈哈哈哈哈哈哈
哈哈哈
高高
哎呀哎呀呀哎呀呀啊哈哈哈啊
uptown Jordan
need some coaches mama
Louis dog brother
put this show on you gonna look cold
killing me
yeah i know it's cold pop pop you know we got to do this
fuck this shit
yo yo yo
which one looks like good
that one tell us what that was taken hold
on a second what's up
oh shit nigga keep it low
all right please just be quiet thanks
hey
no it's okay don't worry about it
it's police out there outside let's do it gotta here all right
no right
outside i mean if you want to get something else hurry up
but you know what i mean let's do it gotta here
everybody's shutting down right now don't worry about it
don't be scared woman
啊啊
look what you've done to me look
look at me look what i'm wearing this
look good for hustler huh
look at me like freaking
what's her name matter
whatever the one on tv life
sucks life sucks with you shit
man
this shit is gonna
kill me i hate being made to you bastard trust me
i'm stressed up and don't fall yeah
please speak for me please
banana
banana yeah
cookie
cookie they got no money for cookies
no money for cookies
what you doing
i'm packing all my stuff
i've been waiting long enough for you to come and pick it up
Ayma don't start with me now don't start
nothing Linda
and take care to ledito stuff
too you take all his stuff
and by the way there was this guy with the baby with ledito
coming looking for you yelling
like a crazy ass calling Linda
so you wanna take it out you wanna take a nine
you wanna take it mine
take all this
take it take it
i don't care wanna leave you take it
take all his stuff
when you left out of here you left out of my house with your son
and then this man come out the window yelling Linda
Linda
like he's crazy cursing me out and with the wallito in his arm
he didn't even know how to carry him
don't you think about your son how he's suffering
can't you take it okay
all right
he's fine he's not fine
he's fine he's not he sleeps
he's not looking at everything look at those pictures
that's your baby you don't miss him
look at his picture
look look at a
little look
you got your eyes your nose
that big food
not even gonna remember this one he gets older mmm
that's what you think he gonna be grown
he ain't gonna remember this
he's still gonna love his mommy mmm
like you didn't remember anything right
when your father walked away from me and left me
and i had two jobs
ah
okay
no
don't let it go
this one over here has a hologram
give it back
hey lucky
will you pay attention here for a second
you see these over here
they come in black and gold
with a little bit of red on the inside
dude yo show me the other one the one before this the one before
this she hold on just a second yeah
this came in last week
i got these available four colors size 7 half to 13
everything you need wanna blow yeah
he's the number 20s
go take care of your son right now
listen
he's making too much noise spilling milk all over the place
let me talk to the dude right here
man go do what you do
it's not even his kid it's a white kid
that kid is almost Lebanese
i think look at him
don't be saying shit like that
i mean little kids
man mix kids when they're young
they like they like that color man they darken up now
man does he look like him look at him
of course
he looks like him look at his eyebrows dude please okay
seriously
just because he's light that doesn't mean he's not your child
if you're gonna
take the quantity that you promised me
i'm gonna give it to you for that much let me see
what a little bit what you talk listen you know what come here
come here come here
you want to do me a favor you want to do us both a favor here
take this in this go roll that shit leave us alone
i'm holding on to this
don't play me don't fuck with that shit man
just roll that shit and come back
i need the orange air force ones
as many
as you could get me now i'm talking about three hundred pairs
five hundred look at me
i'm serious look
i got a saw down there they put like air force ones you know
i got my air force ones
i got my air force blasted outside
and all these crunkheads they go there
and they like buying it like hotcakes
you're lucky
i mean i gotta talk about the pink elephant
in the room you didn't know what happened
she couldn't pull it through the baby or me and bounce nigga
is it your baby
i don't think so man
if you're serious and you want to know for sure
so you could make the right decision all you got to do puppy
is just like you know this is
a thing called dna test
just go get it it's 300 bucks and you get a dna test
i'm gonna come back next month
no doubt i'll be right here for you
hey baby
i got you a purse you're lucky
all seriousness get that dna test
you got a boss go bless i need freaking help all right
i am here i am here
okay i'm just trying to say just be a mother
why can't you act like a mother
if you cannot be listen you're going over
listen to me listen to me
listen to me because i'm gonna tell you this
once okay i'm gonna tell you this just once
i'm not trying to be crazy it is not my baby
all right it is not my baby i did not do this baby with you
i am not even supposed to be here do you know
how many girls would have left you
do you know look at me
i didn't say whoosh
no no no all right
i got the message
no no no what's his name
you don't even have a name for the child and you're out
you're asking me me
who didn't even bear the child to act like a mother
hey don't touch me don't touch me lucky lucky
i'm very angry right now
please don't touch me
you don't say it i'm a party i just think
you look pretty
what no pretty
i'm pretty
you recognize the
restaurant
yeah
what about it
forgot
this is where we had the first aim
it's
funny nothing
there's something on my mind i can say
how many fuck your birthdays are gonna have here
man
just a rest in another birthday hall
Jesus
what's up little man
that should live on audit i need that trip boxes man
i got my life series i want to flip it over the weekend i know
i know i know i know i know
that's just i know my man all that them things but i need him
listen i gotta double
my mother that's just for him they shouldn't yours
he already paid for me
i know nigga i'll give you a dollar extra
please give me two dollars
and i'll think about it
let me give you one fifty thirty two dollars
i'll think about it
just let me do what i'm doing
don't make this shit hot for me
now fuck let me give you thirty two dollars i need that shit
but listen this ain't no shit
just i'm not delivering three boxes i got a three boxes
i'm going to pick you you bring your man
you do whatever right
thirty two man is between me
and you just move let me do my shit go
do what you do
yo i think we can flip at least three boxes in a day man
no we three three boxes in a day we can flip i got the
money in my hand right now two g's all i need is the van
stupid shit stupid shit
man i'm not making no money with this stupid
baby and karina is about to leave me
got to do this now
Ralph i got to do this now
what you talking about warming i'm cool too
i said that we should get together
i said i just call me back in the hour you want to tell me
tell me you one two three four five
six seven eight nine ten tell me
you see this sweet out there my nigga
everyone sell all these vodkas check it out
that's that
right
give me the money
hi that's your commission boy
all right hold on to it
top top
look at us they go
you take a good look
bitch you might be the you know my man is signs two arms
signs eleven you and size nine hurry up man
yours man money on the street
哈哈哈yes
right
哈哈哈哎哎哎哎
哎哎哎哎哎
yo you're living do this man
you should learn to do this shit
are you kidding me skills no
giving me my skills
nigga you got it boy
make this one make make this one make this one make this one
make this one
yo yo what the fuck happened here
i don't see no shit in the car you came here
oh man what the fuck what
the fuck is what
where the fuck
you are then
yo you better run down here right now
yo what the fuck is going on
look at this shit
nigga my shit this shit is different what the fuck
what happened
yo i just want you to start right now
nigga i want you to start to change this bitch
you left the door open
i don't know oh
man fuck
yo biting this
so what the fuck is going on here fuck
old
you homie i call everybody nobody knows nothing you
you're lucky
啊
啊啊
it's me moving in with Serena can we talk about this horse
no she's not discussing it
she's leaving
she's just give me a minute
there's nothing to talk about just give me a minute
i want to talk to you have a sit here sit down
will you stop
she's leaving okay
just i'm just five minutes with me five minutes
sit down a second sit down
we gotta come down
get the fuck out of here
man what is wrong with you
remember you were talking about that consuling thing
i don't want to do that anymore hey
come on
it's past that what do you mean
it's past that it's been i wanted to do that a year ago
we're married people
married people
don't take this this is not a real marriage
what do you mean
it's not a fucking real
marriage
and we all know if it hadn't been for years green card oh
Jesus fuck why would you bring that now
why would you say such a thing we all know
that i wouldn't get married for a green card
we had the whole fucking big marriage
you put this ring on my hand
we were in the church
the king our parents
what are you talking about
i was overwhelmed i was 23 years old
and my mother wanted to shame on you
you know
shame on you
i can't believe you don't see this
it's so obvious i'm sick of it i really am
i'm 26 years old
why are you standing here
i don't know what to do cause i don't know what to do okay
shut the fuck up
don't she is not one of your hustlers on Broadway
you can't talk to everybody like the way you talk to them
just let's just get out of here you know what
this is not fucking happening yes
it is fucking happening
okay i'll leave that one there will you just stop this over
no i'm not stopping this is dope it okay
Jesus
will you let this go go
come on please
excuse me hey
Nadia this is me
it's low excuse me
it's the third message
i've been living in can i please be lucky
at least have some decency to return
my phone call
please play with them thing yo anybody want
to buy a little boy
yo give me twenty five dollars
you want to play all
you want to me give me the sneakers
i'm a show this niggas right
yo yo get a fuck out of here get a fuck out of here
i don't like jordan's
i don't want them no more sure get up
you guys get up
come on man what you gonna do
good lucky how you been
dollar sub little man
how you doing
so how's business
yo yo
where i got these
i got these from
i got these from me man
ralphie why you pull off
my leg like that
yeah ralphie lucky yeah
whatever you
what are you doing
man take off my kid
what are you crazy
gotta take off these businesses i was right back nigga all right
i gotta take off this shit shit
just hopping babysitter
now boss shit hop
he sees black man
you know that
what
where'd your daddy go
mama
oh he's so Eddie
do you want to be like daddy
when you grow up hey
do you want to be a hustler
or you like ladies
strong
you can't pull it can open it do it one more time
there you go
what are you
doing about
what you doing about
see the fucking
orange sneakers always thinking for that one dude that talk
like a black man
one two three哈哈哈
come
here
come here come here
come here you
my only man man
you my nigga how you gonna do that to me you
my fucking nigga man
you sitting right there that's a white boy say you you
you you were sitting right there
when i saw that size step into the man
in the bed remember
i came by the window you were sitting right there
with your little man remember
size thirteen i came back and give you the money i took my shell
i give you the i give you the money what are you talking about
after all these day
you gonna tell me
i still i stole some from you i bet i'm just fucked up man
right now i don't know why i can't pay my right
i can't do nothing you remember what
i'm talking about all the sneakers over there so you cool
you calm now
you come
you come you go
you cool i'm cool i'm cool man you cool all right
happen to your face
take it off take it off
what happened
oh baby i'm a man you know it should happen
how did that happen a
little fight a little fight
a little fight yes
don't put a fin in it don't change this object shake him up
you know niggas fucking with my shit
eat all right no
i am not
i am not listen no
i wanna know what happened
i'm hungry
i lost i lost everything everything
i lost a lot of money
are you talking about the VCR
money yeah
i'm going to get some of that money back all right
i want to know what happened to that money from the vcr
you are supposed to help you start off
that's what i used for this yeah
that's what i took off for this
that's what you took off for what for this
are you telling me all that money
oh my god
let's finish go home
and we can talk about this i feel like talking about this now
let's talk about this
i don't want my shit in pop
you don't want your shit i don't give a fuck it's public lucky
okay you know what i'm done with it there's nothing more
i can do man eat
all right good boy
eat something i'll take you just my problem
this is your problem
this is your priority looking
but you don't seem to understand that listen
i told you i told you it's not my baby it's gotta go back
that's the reason why i'm so afraid i am so tired
i am i am gone i am gone
i can't do this anymore i'm just Lisa take the keys
you go home with chill
i am not going home
where you are i am going
take the keys going leaving chill where are you going
i gotta go
do something like that how could
this change
like that change what do it suddenly change
how do i change
when did i change
because my question would then be when did you stop being a man
shut up and eat
yo it's something let's get out of here yo
i'm feeling tired of you all right shit
what the fuck
i'm not your daddy
i'm tired of playing daddy go
find your new daddy all right
i'm out of here that's it it's over
i can make you drive you more than
he's a monster
that's what he is he's a devil in my life
you moistu moistu moistu moistu moistu
watch the monster's name anyway
i decide to call him price Prince yeah
Prince mini you're the king
who's the Prince
are you like the musician
do my dad how the dog call Prince
are you calling him after a dog
we have two dogs ringer
this thing is funny
here's a pickle
want a pickle
get a little brother
get a pickle get it grab it grab it get it no
he's like you picky
too picky like a pickyo
be careful we might get hurt
there you go little prince
one two
come on in are you
a cop sir
no i'm just kidding man oh
he just played don't let go come on
these are 50 bucks for two
oh Linda
Linda stay stay
stay there i'll be right
back stay there
no Linda Linda Linda
Linda stay
right there Linda
what the fuck is going on
you take only two weeks
man i've been holding this baby now for the month
what the fuck is that man get the fuck out of here you said
two weeks it's been a month the fucking fuck
i need you right
because i fuck with you be a fucking father fuck you
we the fuck is go
my baby you crazy
you making me stop
for this shit you making me stop
so i can hear this shit
i have to go i have to go listen
listen i'm telling you this shit
it hates to seize you
he's gonna fuck you up again
listen Linda
i'm gonna tell you this and this is the last time alright
i'm gonna get a dna Tesla
i swear to god
and i swear my dad is great
is that baby it's mine
you never you never see the baby again
you make it on the wall you go to heaven and come back to
as you never see that baby again
i swear to god and he's got to grow up to be a big man
you see you see
i like living with my man i like it
i'm good where i'm at right now
he takes care of everything i need i only know he knows
he takes care
of everything
i need what about them why he can't take care of gualito
he belongs to you
he's yours but he don't belong to him but he's yours
and i think you should stick at voila and go back in the v moms
i don't want to live her i can't live her no
more can't stand live her
and now this nigga fucking lucky
wants to get a dna test so fucking one
he is the father right
hmm fuckland did you serious
i think so i hope so
are you crazy
you crazy
what's up what's going on
i'm good
what you mean you good
i'm good come on
man i know you better than that what
she's trying to make you do now
hmm are you talking about what
i'm trying come on dwayna
please i already know you're stelo
oh
please come on
would you tell her to leave
nigga please want some shit start off over here
man please are you so call feel for her
why you can't feel for the kid
why are you making her send him to listen
come on listen that's scandalous
and i'm not gonna have that in my crib she's lucky
i got her my crib
now whatever Hector whatever whatever yeah
whatever just listen just listen
listen listen just go ahead you need me you call me
i'm here for you
mm hmm she's there for you
that's right
fold
fold hecta fold fold
hectafold you
see what i gotta go through with her
i hate that fucking girl
yo hate that little bitch always beefing with her
that's my only fucking friend with her so
she lives in my farm she ain't got a fucking place to live yes
she just pops that shit she looks
i understand where she's coming from man
every time she come over you got this little man
running around doing what you got you got toys
all over like you got toys i rest also
oh no man you're not crying on me oh fuck
that shit my nigga i'm just motion on the game crying the game
oh Beck listen i want to take that fucking test
y'all now you talking because you want to do this man
i want to help you on this one don't worry i got you you know
i got you so do what you gotta do you know
say get this little monkey off your back
bless niggas i bless you bless you motherfucker
hello kareda baby
my phone has been cut off i'm calling from a payphone so
if you see i don't recognize number on your phone it's me baby
i'm on my way to get a dna test done right now
and
i miss you talk to you later
咯咯咯咯
啊啊
有没有baby
Linda
did you say Linda
lucky and prince
no
this time boy
妈妈啊啊
啊
啊啊啊
maybe you should put him just hold
it here hold it with the tip
and swarve it for about a minute of both sides
啊哈哈哈
啊哈哈啊啊
OK个场啊OK
you should get a notice in the mail in about seven to ten days
thank you
thanks a lot appreciate it
bye little guy
and these shits ain't no good exchange yes cuz
these shits is booty
i'ma be honest with you
what this man talking about these shits
right here my brother is booty what you mean is booty
look at this shit right here man
what the fuck is this
on it man
man she look like you working it look like you painted it on
this you mean man
you didn't even buy this for me what you talking about yo
my brother you wanna know how i know
i bought this shit from here
how i wanna know
how i know how cause it's the only fucking room
i'm Broadway with a baby working with y'all
hey
come on god do it Jesus Christ
your fucking name
stop someone
touch your husband
you're scared you're married stop
just concentrate what i'm saying Terry
i'm your husband
you have to be my wife
okay come on
if you don't get out of here i'm calling security okay
just wrong with this every time
you have to come in when i'm talking to my wife
what is wrong with you
you got your green card
don't go away
leave her alone
get the fact at it is this
what you got people is this you
stop it look
at your fucking hands
what the fuck
look at you just look at you stop
i'm taking you fucking home
come on come on
come on
stop it coming fucking home
Jesus fucking
come here come on Jesus
stop it
you are destroying me
no leave me alone
whoa
what the fuck
oh my god
the fuck is the problem
fucking slow we gonna make money today huh
you got a good number
come on foster
this guy got give me a deal
where i could give it away
not worry about
23 i'll take this off your hand
i gotta tell you you see the stitching right there
right there like right there yeah
but then i gotta get somebody to do it for everyone of this
he's hitting the dog
come on that's a five dollar discount right there
you got the dna test for this guy
yeah i should find out anything now
till it's eighteen
i saw it at me
lock it down by wall
on the corner
pull repeat five wall on the corner close that shit down
you will walking towards you right now
hey lucky
you didn't see me
you don't know me man
i'll come see you later all right
so yo buddy get the fuck
inside now hands up against the wall
check the back
hands up against
the wall everybody
everybody down
everybody down up
get down on the ground
get down the ground
get down let the bully
get down get down let the bully
any needles on you yeah
i have needles
i'm not shut up
get down everybody shut up shut up
that's my fucking personal money
man put the
please action
oh
please it's nothing going on
man it's nothing going on
this is some bossy
i don't know these people let me see your pocket
i don't know these people what's in the pocket slowly
oh they're starting them
young aren't you
how many men in the back
shut the fuck up
we got five heads back here and a dog and a kid all right
turn around put your heads against the walls
talk to Johnson i was just walking my dog is that shit
that's plastic bags for picking up
that bag of shit don't come back
don't do this again
as illegal what are you slowly picking it up
shut your mouth turn around
shut the fuck up out of here
can i take my bag
shit guy
in the clown suit you want to leave or you want to go downtown
please get your kid
get your kid and get the hell out of here thank you
god bless you thank you
you gonna read me my rights
or what
i'm not interrogating you i'm fucking arresting you
how many pieces like
four fifty bags like two something sneakers beggaming taggle
the defendant is a flight risk
he's not even a us citizen
and to take his passport wouldn't be enough to secure honor
this is ridiculous
my client is not a flight risk
he's a newlywed he's got an apartment in Queens
he's a simple salesman he is not a counterfeiter in fact
we haven't even established whether these goods are counterfeit
or not incidentally
we are considering a civil rights action against the city
if this goes to trial
Mr Krikorian what's your background
i'm an Armenian from Lebanon
he's being unfairly targeted
his court is not
in the business of dismissing cases to protect the city
from a lawsuit now
come on Roger
you got something on your mind
don't make me guess it give me a number
one hundred thousand dollars your honor
i'm gonna set bail at one hundred thousand dollars your honor
that's totally insufficient to protect the right
to the trademark owners
and all right
that's enough
gentlemen take it up with federal court
if you wish our jurisdiction is penal law
not trademark law have a nice day thank you
your honor
you ready for this listen sleep time
not supposed to touch it's supposed to look up and go to sleep
look
look at the lights up there
look you see the light going round round
all right go to sleep you look up and you fall asleep in two
minutes please
i bought this to put you to sleep man better start waking else
i'll take you back for my money ma
bo bo
bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo
bo bo bo
bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo
bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo
bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo
bo bo bo
bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo
bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo
bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo
bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo
bo bo bo bo bo bo bo
bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo
bo bo bo bo
bo bo
bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo
bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo
bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo bo
are you going to sleep
look at the lights
i go to sleep look
look at the lights papa
please come this man
狗狗狗
it is one has a seventy street
if you mount eaten
Adam
lebon
hey i'm in the back man
haha Po Po
Po Po
police get on the floor
get on the floor
anyway police oh shit
hahaha
what happened to ralphie
yeah i don't
think he can come out right now
he ain't got no bail shit and these days
he got arrested a couple of times that might give you
trianas man
hooro migration
might get your ass out of here nigga oh
saw that shit into miracles long what's that
oh you didn't even fucking
open it
open it me you crazy
open it yourself
should i i want to open it
open it
i'm going to open it
open that
please open that all right
you ready
as it say what do you think
it says
it's yours
it's yours Poppy
vivi
that's your dad right
there vivi vivi
that's the daddy
where is the daddy right
there
very
congratulations not figured for real
that's why i never let them didn't want to let it go i mean
they said if i take you to the cops must you or daddy somebody
your father matter whatever drop you off
though this motherfucker would have gone through shit you know
that's the reason i didn't want to throw him away
you know a father and a father
he was always there for me i put that nigga through hell
he was always there for me
so that's why for some funny reason you know
i felt i got to do the right and went
i figured out shit right for real it's good i held them down
for real
listen in about in about a week or 10 days
you call me okay
for real two week stops
yeah i'm getting a place upstairs you crazy
you motherfuckers are tough
you tough
give me a call all right
i will
ay
ay ay see you later boss