瞧谁来了
Lookie here.
我今天太幸运了
My day is made. [Laughs]
我连早饭都还来不及吃 就要杀死我今天的第一个印第安人
I didn't even finish breakfast and I get to kill me a stinkin' Injun.
印第安人？
Injun?
你丫放屁 我才不是
Nah
我穿成这样是为了不会在大草原上被割掉头皮
I just dress like this so's I don't get scalped out on the prairie.
恩 衣服看起来是让人很信服
Oh, well, that's a convincing outfit.
也是 在外面那么多野蛮的人 很危险的
yeah u can't be too safe out there with savages running around
那么 你需要买什么
So, what can I do you for?
我要买5包面粉 一根上面加有花生酱的胡萝卜
Need some flour. Five sacks.And a carrot with peanut butter on it.
一共多少钱
what's that gonna run me?
一袋面粉45美分 那么5袋面粉就是...
Well, sack of flour's 45 cents. So, five sacks...
就是40...
is 40...
需要我重复一遍吗
Wanna get back to me on that?
恩 对了面粉在地下室 你可以自己去拿
Yeah, look... the flour's in the basement.You can fetch it yourself.
非常感谢
Much obliged.
哟 瞧瞧站着的这位美女
Well, lookie what we got here.
在红色大草原上独自站立的一朵金花
Sweet piece of red prairie meat out all by her lonesome.
-Nelly 你觉得如何 -我觉得这位美人在等你
- What do you make of that, Nelly?-Oh, I think she's waiting on you, Will.
我们来鸟
Here we go.
你肯定在想 像我们5个风流倜傥 有着完美下颚弧度的男淫
Now, you must be wondering why five badass hombres with perfect jawlines...
都喜欢像你一样的印第安妞
all spot the same stylish Apatch.
关我毛线事
Not my business.
我们几个都把眼睛挖出来了 这是我们帮派的象征
We all carved our eyeballs out our skull to show how devoted we are to this gang.
我们是左眼帮派
We the Left-Eye Boys!
美女 你的眼睛太漂亮了 你觉得我们可不可以...借一只？
You got real pretty eyes, miss.You reckon we can, I don't know, borrow one?
你们觉得问女士这种问题合适吗
Now, is that a proper question to ask a lady?
小子 你特么谁啊? 男盆友?
Who are you, slick? The boyfriend?
马上就是丈夫了
Soon to be the husband.
等一下 我看出来了 他是个白人!
Oh, wait a minute! That's a white boy under that getup.
操 是个白人！
That's a white boy? Oh, shit.
你这个黄脸白种人是不是电影《风中奇缘》看多了 喜欢印第安人装扮？
You partial to pale faces, Poca-hot-tits?
我让你见识一下真正的白人什么样
'Cause I can show you what a real white man's like.
对 Will 让他见识一下 跳起来 赶紧儿得 真有白人范儿
Yeah, show her, Will. Yeah, go on. Yeah, shuffle up, Will.
现在我倒真想把眼睛挖出来了
Now, I do want to carve my eyes out.
你特么说什么？ -同志们 注意了
- What'd you say? - Hey, fellers
在我还没有正式开始之前 我就会打到你们
I'd hit the trail before you get hurt.
你有没有搞错？ 你会打到我们？
Before we get hurt?
我觉得你是不是抽印第安人的烟斗抽多了 假印第安人
I think you've been smokin' too much of that peace pipe, kemo-slobby.
你不要忘了 我们有5个人 而你只有1个人
Now, from what I see, there's one of you,
现在只剩4个人了你们
Four of you
刚才发生了什么事情？
What just happened?
傻逼们 还想看一次吗？
You wanna see it again?
呃...宝宝想看
Uh... yes.
-宝宝觉得不好玩了- 别吭气 傻逼
I don't like this shit.- Shut up.
恩...你的佛山无影脚练的不错嘛
Well, that's some, uh...real fancy footwork.
但是觉得这场胡闹该用武器来结束了
But I think this hullabaloo has escalated to the firearms stage.
伙伴们 把枪上膛
Boys, let's ventilate this.
谁能告诉宝宝刚才发生什么事情了？|
What the shit that just happened?
动手之前 撂倒你们 就这么简单
"Hit the trail." It was so simple.
小白飞刀 你不能再这样做了 以后万一人多起来怎么办？
You must stop doing this, White Knife. One day, there will be too many.
今天肯定不会了 小狐狸
But not today, Smoking Fox.
拜托亲爱的 我们应该出发了
Please, my love... we must go.
外面都发生了什么事情！
What the hell happened out here?
来了一群印第安人 他们朝那个方向走了
Injuns. They went that way.
你他妈才不是白人 你是那个孤儿 小白飞刀 像个野兽一样的被印第安人带大 你以为你骗得了那群人吗？
You ain't no white man. You're that orphan, White Knife. Raised like an animal with those Apaches. You think you can fool of them?
对不起了 我的小马孩子~
Aorry Ringo
现在我要开枪把你和你的印第安小婊砸打死
Well, now I'm gonna shoot you and your Injun whore.
借用一下你的早餐
Gotta cut breakfast short.
你这个贱人！
You suck, mister!
电影名-《傻逼6人帮》
小狐狸 你真幸运 小白飞刀是一个非常勇敢的男人
You lucky, Smoking Fox. White Knife all man. Bravest of all braves.
才不勇敢 傻乎乎的
Not brave. Foolish.
我才不想这么早当寡妇
I want to be wife, not widow
女士们 下午好啊
Afternoon, ladies.
这是我们印第安人的地盘
This is Apache land.
酋长 我不是来这里掠夺你们的土地的 我只是来找一个男人
I'm not here to take your land, Chief. I'm just looking for a particular boy.
我叫Frank Stockburn
I'm Frank Stockburn.
这个男人的母亲是我妻子
This boy's mother was my wife.
这个男人叫Tommy 他是我的儿子
And the boy, Tommy...he's my son.
有时候相信未必不是一件好事 小白飞刀 万事开端是需要你简单地向前跨出第一步
It is wise to be slow to trust, White Knife. But every new journey begins with a single step.
主动和你父亲谈谈吧
Speak with your father.
苍鹰 你才是我的父亲 在我母亲...之后 你找到并且抚养我成人
But you are my father, Screaming Eagle.Ever since my mother...Ever since you found me...
你教我如何打猎 如何斗争 何时该说话 何时保持沉默 如何做人
you taught me to hunt, to fight...when to speak and when to be silent.To be a man.
做一个好人
A good man.
这个自称我父亲的人 满嘴谎言  和其他白人没什么区别
And this Frank Stockburn,he is filled with lies, just like every other white man.
有时白人也说实话 但是只有千分之一的概率
Sometimes, the whiteman speaks the truth.Like, one in 20, 25 times.
我觉得这次就是那千分之一的概率
I believe this is one of those times.
他毕竟认识你的母亲 跟他谈谈吧 说不定能带给你内心的平静
He knew your mother, White Knife. Maybe he can give you some peace. Talk to him.
让我好好睡一觉再说吧
Maybe after I close my eyes to dream.
你都知道我做了很多坏事吧？
One look at me, and you knew your old man had done a lot of bad things, didn't ya?
我偷拐抢骗 杀人放火
I cheated men, I killed men...
所以我活该现在这样
So I deserve whatever's comin' to me.
曾经只有你母亲看到了我善良的一面
The only one that ever saw any good in me was your mother.
你到底来这做什么?
Why have you come here?
肯定不是过来给你闲聊的
Not a man for chitchat, huh? Well, me neither.
孩子 我快活不久了
Kid, I'm dying...of consumption.
不用担心 我不是过来和你叙旧的
Don't worry...I'm not looking for no big father-son hoo-ah.
"我爱你 儿子" "我也爱你 爸爸"
"I love you, son.""I love you too, Daddy."
肯定不可能像这样 我来这里是为了你
No I've come for a more tangible reason
Tommy 我从9岁就开始偷东西 到现在我已经积累了一笔不小的财富
Tommy, I've been stealing from folks since I was nine years old...and that's the way I've amassed a good little fortune.
我想在我死前做点正派的事情 我想把这笔钱留给你
I wanna do something decent with it.I want to give it to you, son.
我是不会要你的一分钱的
I don't want your money.
但是你可以把这笔...5万美元给抚养过你的善良的印第安人呀
But maybe you could give...$50,000 to these nice Injuns who raised you.
我们收下啦！
We'll take it.
快回你的帐篷里去
Go back to bed.
不好意思 但是我真的觉得我们应该收下
Sorry. Seriously, though, we'll take it.
听着 钱埋在 铁路旁边的草地上 一颗松树下 我们明早就去挖 怎样？
Look, it's buried in the meadow just up the trail,next to a big ol' pine tree.What do you say we go dig it up in the morning
顺便过下圣诞节？
and start playing Santa Claus?
虽然关于我母亲的事情我已经记不太清楚了...但是我很清楚记得她告诉过我...
I don't remember much about my mother...but I do remember her telling me...
你早就已经死了
you were dead.
可能是因为...她不想你来找我
Maybe it was because...she didn't want you to come looking for me.
她是一位聪明的女士 唯一做的蠢事就是爱上我
She was a smart lady.Only stupid thing she ever did was fall for me.
遇到你母亲 是我这辈子最幸运的事
Meeting Betty Dunson...was the luckiest thing that ever happened to me.
当时在银色峡谷 我第一眼看倒你母亲 她正在向一个喝醉酒的大块头铁匠大吼大叫
From the first day I laid eyes on her...she was bawlin' out this...half-drunk, big ol' burly blacksmith... down at Silver Canyon.
她是我今生的唯一
She's been the only one, Tommy.
我母亲原来脾气这么暴躁？
Mom had a temper?
糟糕？ 你妈发起火来 谁都要遭殃
Temper? When she got her dander up, look out.
有次我们在一个酒吧里 你妈旁边坐了个人 他开始说如何做一个完美的樱桃派...
We was in a saloon once.This fellow sitting next to her starts talking about the perfect way to make a cherry pie...
然后你妈跟我说 你到底从哪里找来的花送给他们的？
So your mom says to me, Frank, come here a minute.Tell me again, just where did you get them flowers?"
我回答说 我知道你认为我是从墓地里面偷来的 哈哈
I said, "I know that you think I stole them from the graveyard."
帅哥们 早上好
Good morning, boys.
早上好 从来不穿咪咪罩的美女
Morning, Never Wears Bra.
小白飞刀 昨天晚上我梦到你了
I had dream about you last night, White Knife.
恩 很好啊
Oh, that's nice.
可不怎么好哦 在梦里你很淘气 灰常灰常淘气哦
Not nice dream.In dream, you naughty. You naughty, white knife.
看起来 我儿子很受欢迎嘛
Mmm, somebody's got an admirer.
话虽如此 但是和你一样 我这一辈子只有一个女人
Yes, yes.But like you, there's only one woman for me.
我们一家人都是...
I guess we Stockburns are...
用情都很专一
partial to the sweet ones.
的确如此
Yes, sir.
就像我对你母亲一样
Like your mother.
她怎么死的?
How did she die, Tommy?
能告诉我吗
You tell me?
有一天 学校里的一群大孩子决定要揍我
Well, there were these big kids at school fixin' to beat me up.
我自己不敢面对 于是我让我她一起陪我过去
Instead of facing them myself,I had her walk me there.
突然冒出一个人 掏出手枪击中了我母亲
This feller comes out of nowhere...walks right up to her and shoots her dead.
她当场就死掉了 要不是保护我这个没用的儿子 她本应该在家里 毫发无损的
So that's how she died,protecting her gutless son instead of being home,safe where she belonged.
谁过来了？Bony Express？
Who's that? Is that Bony Express?
Bony Express怎么会找到这里
Bony Express on't come around here.
他就在这里 让我们把他熏出来
He's here somewhere, boys.Let's burn him out!
下一个目标就是你的额头
Next one goes through your forehead.
嘿嘿 不要动手！
Hey, hey! No need to burn nothing, boys!
好久不见 老大
Howdy, boss.
Cicero...我退休了 你也不放过我
Cicero...you're not gonna let a man enjoy his retirement, are ya?
Frank  当然不是 你金盆洗手 我当然没有意见 只不过那笔钱...
No, Frank, I salute your decision to turn from your sinful ways.But the money...
是我们共同的财产
that belongs to all of us.
小子 你只要动手 我枪子儿里的子弹可手下不留情
Touch that steel, boy,I got plenty of bullets left over after I put one in...
第一个遭殃的就是你父亲
your father.
噢 看来你已经找到了你失散多年儿子 我也不想打扰你们的全家团圆的
Oh, you finally found your long lost son. Well, I sure hate to break up this nice family reunion.
那为何你不干脆把钱交出来 不然你就等着吃子弹吧
So, why don't you give us the money you stole before I put lead in your head.
钱已经被埋起来了
The money's buried.
儿子 不要多说
Way to run your mouth, son.
被埋起来了？
It's buried?
对 我把钱深埋在地下 在一架风车旁边
Yeah, I buried it.Deep in the ground...next to a windmill.
一架风车旁边？我操 这范围也太特么大了
A windmill in the West...doesn't narrow it down much, Frank.
这架风车不一样...它会唱歌
Well, this is a special windmill.It's a singing windmill.
你他妈当我傻逼呢？
A singing windmill!
从这里出发要10天 我答应带你去找钱 只要你保证...
It's about a ten-day ride from here.I'll lead you to it presently on one condition.
不要伤害我的儿子 和其他这些善良的印第安人
You don't hurt my boy...or any of these kindly Injuns here.
走 我们现在就出发
Let's ride, Frank.
如果到时候风车下面没有挖到钱 我会把你活埋 只露出头 让沙漠上的动物活生生地吃了你
Frank, if that $50,000 isn't under that windmill,I'm gonna bury you up to your neck and let the desert critters eat you alive.
我保证钱在那里 我很高兴我找到了我的儿子
It's there, Cicero, it's there.I'm glad I got to meet Betty Dunson's son.
待在这里 好好的和你的未婚妻生活
You just stay here, Tommy.Enjoy your life with your beautiful bride...
在这些巨大的松树下面
amongst these majestic pine trees.
我们走！
Let's go!
我擦 这太不友好了
Well, that was uncool.
小白飞刀 你该休息了
White Knife, you must rest.
我怎能休息 如果到时他们到了风车那里 发现没有钱 会杀了我父亲的
How can I rest? When they get to the singing windmill and find no money, they will kill him.
孩子 松树太多 时间太紧迫了
My son, there are too many trees and too little time.
那我就要从其他途径获得这笔钱了
Then I must get this $50,000 another way.
什么途径 偷吗 这太不正直了
How? By stealing? There is no honor in that.
那我也可以从那些不正直的人那儿偷钱
Unless I steal from those who have no honor.
哦 这样就没什么问题了
Ooh... I like that.
但这样太危险了
But it is too dangerous.
我会派最勇敢的10名勇士帮助你
I will send ten of our strongest braves with you.
千万不要 印第安人在白人的世界里太危险了
No. The braves would be treated too cruelly in the white man's world.
莫事 很多勇士脸白 可以混淆过去 而且有个孩子还能很好地模仿白人的动作
A lot of them can pass for pale face. Raging Bear can actually do a great impression of a white guy.
让我们下会棋 再吃薯条吧
Hey, guys, let's play with our chest hair and eat potato chips.
不错吧 这不知道这熊孩子在哪里看到的
Wasn't that great? Where does he come up with this stuff?
是很不错 但是这事我必须一个人去了断
That's very good, Bear, but I must walk this path alone.
亲爱的 我会弄到钱 然后带去风车那里 等我回来参加我们的婚礼
My love... I will get this money...bring it to the singing windmill,and be back in time for our wedding.
我不会让你走的 这些人都是杀手
I won't let you go.Those men are killers.
我曾经的懦弱害死了母亲 这次我不会连累我父亲
I was a coward once and my mother paid the price.That will not happen to my father.
早上好
Morning
你从哪里冒出来的？
Where in the hell did you come from?
我遇到了点麻烦 我骑马到这里淘金 结果半路我的马死了
I'm in a bit of a bind, boys.I rode all the way out here to pan for gold and my horse up and died on me.
马怎么死的?
How'd he die?
自杀 在它小溪喝水的时候 头一直不抬起来把自己给淹死了 太惨了
Suicide. Drowned himself.Put his head in the stream and just kept it there.Saddest thing you ever seen.
常有的事 虽然不想承认 但这傻逼事就是会发生
It happens.Powers that be don't like to admit it, but it happens.
他看起来像是个诚实的白人 跳上来把
He looks like an honest white guy.Hop on.
感激不尽
Much obliged.
我在最近的一个镇上下就可以了
Just drop me off at the nearest town.
女士先生们 来来来 这是我最新发明的护理精油 包治百病
Ladies and gentlemen, gather around.Hear the wondrous effects of Dr.Chubb's Vita Oil,the miracle cure for 1001 ailments.
只要滴上一滴...你就马上...这谁啊这?
Put the pep back in your...Who's this asshole?
看 那个人居然在马槽里面喝水
Well, now, look at this fella,drinking from the horse trough.
那谁谁 你这样做 看着太让人作呕了
Excuse me.You there!What you're doing is disgusting.
这是牲口才喝的水
That water is for our filthy horses.
水是大自然给我们的恩惠 谁都可以喝 对吧老兄？
Water flows from the sky spirit for all its children.Isn't that right, cousin?
你那些歪门邪说在我们这里不管用 明白？"老兄"
We don't cotton to that peyote-smoking nonsense around these parts.Do you hear me, "cousin"?
算了 William 别跟他废话
Okay,William, come on back.
喂 小伙子 你打算留在镇上吗？
Hey, amigo.You planning on staying in town?
可能需要一个地方躺会儿
Might need a place to lay my head for a bit.
刚才那个男人那样说你 太不像话了
Sorry about that ugly man that insulted you.
他开了家银行 觉得自己理所当然可以对人霸道无理
He runs the bank, so he thinks he's entitled to be mean to everyone.
镇上有家银行？
There's a bank in this town?
为何这样问 难不成你还想抢银行呢？
Why? You wanna rob it?
夫人 我看起来难像抢银行的？
I look like a bank robber to you, ma'am?
很奇特啊 你让我想起来某个银行抢劫犯
Funny, there's something about you that reminds me of a certain bank robber.
他的名字叫Frank Stockburn
His name was Frank Stockburn.
你认识Frank Stockburn？
You know Frank Stockburn?
认识？没有见过面那种?
"Know"? Like, in the biblical sense?
不是 夫人 你以前亲自见过他吗?
No, ma'am. You've met him before is what I'm asking.
是的 我见过他
Yes, I met him.
认识他20分钟后 我在床上"见过”了他 就在那里
Then, 20 minutes later,I knew him in the biblical sense on that bed, right there.
接着 在这个扶手旁 我又“见过”了他2次
And, I knew him, in the biblical sense, twice on this railing.
然后 我们又倒立着"见面" 就在你靠着的梳妆台那里
And then, while doing a handstand on that dresser you're leaning against.
他有没有提起过一架会唱歌的风车？
Did he happen to mention a singing windmill?
他确实提起过一架会唱歌的风车 他说听起来就像天使的合唱一样
He did mention a singing windmill.He said it sounded like a choir of angels.
他有没有说风车在哪儿？
Where'd he say it was?
他说在那里 赢得了他人生中最大的一次比赛 然后就笑了
He said that it was in a place where he made his biggest score. Whatever that was,then he laughed.
他很喜欢笑
He liked to laugh...
还有倒立的性爱
and have handstand sex.
呃 这个可以pass掉
Yeah, we gotta get past that.
我很想念他 不过他确实留下了一件纪念品
I miss him.But he did leave me something to remember him by.
什么纪念品？
What's this?
niño,Ramon.
我还有一个兄弟？
I have a brother?
Burro 好兄弟 我们在一起这么久了 虽然都在慢慢变老 但是我们一起经历的冒险旅途 都是宝贵的记忆
Oh, Burro, we had many adventures together, you and me.We're not getting any younger.At least we have our memories.
记得在南达科他州的那2个姐妹吗？ 我知道你喜欢更肥的那只 哈哈哈 不要不承认
Remember the two girls,the sisters, in Deadwood?You liked the fat one.You know it's true.
Ramon Lopez?
我是
我刚刚见过你的母亲 结果... 偶然发现 你的父亲和我的父亲...
I just came from conversating with your mother, Esmerelda.We stumbled upon the fact that your dad and my dad...
是同一人...
are the same fella.
真是开门见山
Oh, that's neat.
简洁如我
Yeah
同一个父亲 那我们就是同父异母的兄弟 你怎么看 Burro?
Same father.Half-brothers.What do you think about that, Burro?
那么 我们父亲怎么样？
So, how is Dad?
他被绑架了 我需要筹够5万元 才能救他的命
Well, he went and go himself kidnapped,and I need to come up with $50,000 to save his life.
需要这么多银子？
That's a lot of pesos.
可不是吗 所以我决定抢劫镇上的银行
Sure is.That's why I'm fixin' to rob the bank here in town.
等一下 你意思是 我的父亲遇到了麻烦？
Hang on.My father is in trouble.
我的兄弟又需要我的帮忙
My brother, he needs my help.
我和你一起去抢银行
I'll rob the bank with you.
我必须独自完成这事儿
I must do this alone.
你要干嘛 兄弟
What's happening right now?
当我还是小孩子的时候 我就期待有一天见到我的父亲 一起吃饭 把他介绍给我的驴子朋友
Ever since I'm pequeño,I dream about spending one magical day with mi padre,sharing meals, introducing him to the burro.
除非你答应让我帮你 不然我不会松手的
I will not let go of you until you say I can help you.
如果你停止用刷子刷我 我就答应你
Will you stop brushing me if I say yes?
当然可以
Yes.
那你可以帮我忙
Then you can help.
它打屁意味着喜欢你
That means he likes you.
女士 你需要借的这笔款项不是小数目 通常情况下 我们会要求你出示2份证明
That's a good amount of money you want us to lend you.Now, normally, we would require two forms of identification, madam,
但是您这种大美女就不需要了
but that won't benecessary in your case.
Burro 想到要从好人这里抢钱 我感到好愧疚
I feel kinda guilty about this, Burro,taking money from nice people.
你幸好不是那种看起来脏兮兮的墨西哥人
I mean, it's not like you're some greasy Mexican.
突然感觉没那么愧疚了
I feel less guilty now.
你在干什么！这里是银行！赶紧把那头驴弄出去！
What are you doing?This is a bank!Get that donkey out of here!
先生 这是美国西部小毛驴
It is a burro, señor.
我不管这是什么傻逼玩意儿 “先生” 赶紧给我弄出去！
I don't care, "señor."Get it out!
行行 我们走吧...小毛驴不想走...
All right. Vámonos.The burro don't want to vámonos.
我才不管这头牲口想怎样！！
Well, I don't really care what the burro wants.
赶紧给我滚出去 你这个畜生！！！
Get out of my bank, you beast!
我知道你在想什么 但现在还不是时候 给我稳住
I know what you're thinking, but not yet.Hold it.
这个傻逼怎么会卡在这里 刚才它明明能从这里进来 现在怎么可能出不去了呢！！见了鬼了！！！
How is this jackass stuck?If it got in here, it can certainly get out!It doesn't make sense, it's not logical.
他们把钱藏的真好
They got it locked up good, do they?
我操 我不信还治不了你了！！！
Oh! You are leaving!
看啊 那个傻逼摔了个狗吃屎!
Gall dang, 1he felled on his pooper!
这太特么不正常了!
That makes no sense!
很...很抱歉...我马上弄它走...
I apologize.- I don't know how many times I could...
朋友好啊 需要我帮忙把它弄出来吗？
Hey, friend.Need any help gettin' her out?
她不是真的被卡住了 我的朋友 她只是用来分散注意力的
She's not really stuck,amigo.She's just a diversion.
她是处女？刚好我也是处男...
She's a virgin?I'm a virgin, too...
从不是很严格的意义上说
unless you count canty-loupes.
我相信你 小处男 听着 这头驴是用来分散银行老板注意力的 我的兄弟才好去偷银行的钱
I believe that, but she's a diversion to keep the banker busy so that my brother has time to rob the bank.
你们要抢银行?? 太牛逼了！!
You're robbin' the bank?Gall dang!
大事不妙！ Virgil 快吧钥匙给我！！
No! Virgil! Virgil, the key!
我的名字小皮特
叫I'm Lil Pete.
那你爸的名字就叫大皮特咯？
So, is your father, like, Big Pete?
我没见过我的粑粑 但他和你们一样都是银行抢劫犯 他叫Frank
I didn't know my pa.But he was a bank robber like y'all! His name was Frank.
姓Stockburn
Stockburn?
你怎么知道？？难不成你是巫师？？！！
How'd you know?Are you a wizard?
“儿子 我们会在Jawbone大瀑布那里等你 你的父亲留”
Frank Hey, Johnny Law.We'll be waiting for you up at Jawbone Falls.Frank Stockburn.
来人啊 来人啊 有人在抢银行！！！
Robbery!We're being burgled!
原来是你！！你就是那天喝我马槽水的那个人！！
You! Horse-water-drinker!
你被逮捕了！！
You are caught, sir!
你特么到底谁啊！！
What are you?
大哥 你猜怎么着？我又找到了一个失散多年的弟弟
Hey, Tommy, guess what? We got ourselves a little brother.
都是 我们的母亲都被同一个抢银行的给哼哼了 是不是很赞啊！！
Yeah! All our moms got porked by the same outlaw. Ain't that a pip
对 我很赞同
Yeah, that's something.
大家来看啊 这些土匪刚刚把银行抢了
Hey! Those bandidos just robbed the bank!
吃我枪子儿把 你们这些肮脏的外国佬
Taste my bullets, you dirty foreigners!
就是现在！！！
Now!
Burro 干的好！
Nice one, Burro
他们在那里！！
There they are!
我们得赶紧逃
We better make tracks.
我能加入你们吗 我有辆马车
Can I come with? I got a wagon.
没问题 我觉得可以有 我们走！！
All right, that ain't a bad idea, let's go.
如果你们是我兄弟的话 你们是不是也和我一样 有3颗奶头？
So, if you guys are my brothers,you must got three nipples, too.
我只有2颗
I only got two.
对 我也只有2颗
Yeah, just got the two.
呃 那肯定是我妈遗传给我的 当我没说
Oh, must be from my mama's side.Forget I tolded you that, okay?
莫问题呀
Will do.
Clem 你准备好了吗？
Are you ready, Clem?
恩恩 我准备好了...
Yep, yep. I'm... I'm ready.
这勺子...看着真锋利啊...
Spoon. Damn sharp
听着大伙儿 我真的想和你们一起去追捕那个白人印第安人 但是我的眼睛有点问题
Look, fellas, I wanna hunt this white Injun down same as you.I have some problems with my eyes.
你如果想真心加入"左眼帮派"的话 你就必须挖出你的右眼
You wanna join the Left-Eye Gang,that right eye has gotta come out.
疼一会会就不疼了
It'll only hurt for a second.
就是 就疼那么一小小会
Yeah, like a hundred seconds.
然后你就正式加入我们了
Then you're one of us.
一辈子的好基友
For life.
好吧 听起来有道理...
Okay, that makes sense.
我...能不能...把左眼挖出来 本来左眼视力就不是很好 但是右边的视力很好 如果挖掉的话是不是太可惜了...?
Is it okay if I scoop this left eye out?This is... I'm basically blind here.This right one sees like an eagle.Yeah, it just seems like a waste that I'd...
我明白你的难处 但是这是规定
I understand your predicament but rules is rules.
好吧 这我了解...
Yeah, it... makes sense.
这样做是不是有点过分了...
That ain't right!
挖了一半掉在那里了 还连着血管...
It's half way there...dangled by a van
太疯狂了 这样我还看得见
It's crazy, I can still see out of it!
天哪 我快吐了
I think I'm gonna puke.
像是黏在脱衣舞女奶子上的流苏一样
It's just going round and round like a tassel on a stripper's titty!
马上就好了 马上就好了
Ok gotta get it gotta get it
我不行了 我快晕了
I'm getting dizzy!
恭喜你成功了 欢迎成为我们左眼帮派的一员！
You done it, partner. Welcome to the Left-Eye Gang.
我做到了！
I did it!
太好了 我终于做到了！
I'm glad that's done.
现在我们一起去追捕那个喜欢印第安人的白人吧
Let's just go get that Injun-loving son of a bitch, huh?
赞同 我们现在出发吧
Yeah! Let's get him. Yeah.
哦 我不小心摸到眼窝了 操！
Oh, I touched the hole.I touched the hole!
我现在也是有眼罩的人了
Got me a patch!
亲爱的麻麻 自从我上次去买了一个冰淇淋后就消失了 你是不是觉得很奇怪捏
Dear Mama,you may be wondering why I have not returned from my trip to the ice cream store.
那是因为我遇到我的兄弟 Ramon 和 Tommy  我们现在准备去偷钱
It's because I met my brothers, Ramon and Tommy.And we're trying to steal money.
因为我们的粑粑被坏淫抓走了 带到了一架会唱歌的风车那里 所以我们需要钱去救他
We need the money to give to the bad men who took Pa away to the land of the singing windmill.
Tommy 说我们不能去偷正直人的钱 幸好西部有太多不正直的人了
Tommy says it's not okay to take money from decent folks. Luckily, there's a lot of bad people here in the West.
吃吧 享受地吃吧 我知道你喜欢的啦
Eat it! You know you like it.You know you like it.
我的个天
Good God!
真是一头"好"驴子啊
Good burro!
对对对... 就这样...
That's right.Enjoy it!
这也太特么恶心了
That's just wrong.
这个萝卜比香瓜好使多了 哈哈哈
This is so much better than the cantaloupe.
哈哈哈哈 小毛驴真是好样的
Good burro!
慢慢地 我们快筹集到了救粑粑的5万美金了 偶从来没见过这么多钱啊 妈妈
Slowly, but surely,we're chippin' away at the $50,000 we need to save Pa.That's a lot of money, isn't it, Mama?
我在干什么？ 哦 哈哈哈 我想起来了 我给你写信 妈妈 哈哈 我已经迫不及待想见我的粑粑了
Mama? Oh, yeah, that's right.I'm writing you a letter.Anyways, I can't wait to actually meet my pa.
我想让粑粑教我如何生孩子 女淫们怎样拉屎屎的 我会尽快赶回来 爱你的蠢儿子
I want him to teach me how you make babies.And how the lady poops 'em out.Be home quick as I can.}Your loving son, Lil Pete.
Tommy?
肿么了？我的弱智弟弟？
Yeah, Lil Pete?
这个会唱歌的风车到底在哪里？
Where's the singing windmill?
粑粑在那里赢得了最大的一次比赛
It's where dad made his biggest score.
或许我们去Jawbone大瀑布那里可以找到一些线索 粑粑以前被通缉时经常躲在那里
Maybe we'll get another clue up at Jawbone Falls.That's where he used to hide out when he was an outlaw.
太棒啦！！
Oh, cool beans.
Tommy?
又怎么了 我的弱智蠢弟弟？
Yeah, Lil Pete?
如果我们被抓住了 是不是很麻烦？
If we get caught stealing...would we be in trouble?
我们会被绞死的
I reckon we'll hang.
恩...那我没什么问题了  我的脖子很结实的
Well... that's no bother.I got a real strong neck.
以前我功课没有按时完成的话 妈妈就会惩罚我 把耕地的犁套在我脖子上 然后耕地
Mama makes me pull the plow with my head if I don't finish my schoolwork.Which occurs regularilly.
硬脖子总有一天派上用场 我们现在睡了吧
Strong neck might come in handy.Okay, let's get our rest.
晚安啦 Tommy
Good night, Tommy.
晚安 蠢弟弟
Good night, Lil Pete.
晚安 Ramon
Good night, Ramon.
晚安 兄弟们
Good night, brothers.
晚安 我的小毛驴
Good night, Burro.
打的屁是干的 明天会是个好天气
That's a dry one.We will have good dry weather tomorrow.
走开！ 该死的苍蝇！走开！！
Shoo, fly!Shoo!!
赶紧走开 死苍蝇 不要打扰我们睡觉！
Oh, come on, fly, vámonos! We need our sleep.
让我把它解决了
Let me take care of this.
黑漆漆的你怎么看得见？
How can you see a fly in the dark?
一个真正的猎者是感官并用的
A true hunter sees with all his senses.
你真有一手 佩服
That was some mystical shit, man.
我觉得你刚才是把苍蝇的食物打掉了
I think you just nicked his biscuits off.
我就是这样做的
That's what I was aiming for.
它用不着死 它需要知道的是它在这里并不受欢迎
He didn't deserve to die.He deserved to know he was not welcome here.
不愧是被印第安人抚养大的 你有着他们的思想
Raised by Indians, huh?That had some impact on you.
让我来解决这一只
Well, let me get this one.
听起来像马蝇一样
Sounded like a horse fly.
那不是马蝇 那是我的马！！
That wasn't a horse fly, that was my horse!
Peanut?
Oh, Peanut!
现在我的小毛驴该遭殃了...
Oh, the burro's gonna be pissed.
小毛驴 你做的很好 不要怕你旁边的马 你和它做的一样好！
You're doing bueno,Burro!Don't be intimidated by the horse,you're just as good as him.
哥哥们 我好饿啊！
I'm so hungry.
周围有很多吃的啊 坚果啊 浆果啊 树皮 以及各种泥土
There's breakfast all around.Nuts, berries, bark,different kinds of mud.
如果附近有塔可树就好了
I wish there were taco trees.
塔可是什么东东？
What's a taco?
墨西哥煎饼卷 把肉末 起司 番茄酱都夹在薄皮卷里 超级好吃
They're the best.Meat and cheese and tomatoes in a crispy shell.You'd love it, man.
啊啊啊 我受不了了 我要一口气吃50个
Ooh, I want one. I want 50.
兄弟们 不得不打断你们 我们到了 Jawbone 大瀑布
Hate to put an end to this fascinating conversation, but we're here, Jawbone Falls
旁边还居然有间房子
And there's a mansion next to it!
我们干脆直接进去吧
Should we just go in?
我赞成
I reckon.
呵呵哒 这里看着真舒服
haha this is cozy
不要伤害我的哥哥们!!!
Don't hurt my brother!
不要怕 我们只是来找我们的父亲的
We don't mean no harm.just looking for our dad.
这是你的家吗？... 那这是谁的家？|
Is this your place?Whose place is it?
这是你的妈妈家？
Your mother?
噢 那她现在在家吗？
Oh, is she here right now?
哦 她已经去世了 我很抱歉 她肯定是位好母亲
Oh, she's dead.I'm so sorry, I'm sure she was a good woman.
她三年前去世的？
She died three years ago?
三个月前?!
Three months ago?
噢 我知道了 你妈妈有3个奶头！！
Oh, your mama has three nipples?
对对 我们有3个人
Yeah, there's three of us.
你和你妈妈不会是在这里非法酿酒吧？
You and your mom were making moonshine up here, huh?
你们非法酿的酒商标是...Frank Stockburn?!
Making moonshine for... Frank Stockburn?
你认识 Stockburn？
You know Frank Stockburn?
他在这里呆过？和你妈妈在一起过？
He slept here?With your mama?
哦哈哈 我看懂了 你的妈妈是只猫头鹰!
Your mama was an owl.
才不是呢 蠢弟弟 是我们的粑粑把她麻麻弄出了那样的声音
No, our dad made his mom make owl noises.
很对 朋友 确切来说 应该是叫你 我们的兄弟
Yeah, that's right, friend.We're your brothers.
来来来 干杯 干杯
Down the hatch, boys!Salud. Salud.
你有名字吗?
What's your name, anyways?
H... R... M...
我们干脆叫你Herm好了
How 'bout we just call you Herm?
Herm 我们之所以来这 是因为我们的粑粑被坏淫们绑架了
Herm, so you know,our dad was kidnapped by some bad muchachos.
都是 我们需要大笔的银子赎回老豆
we need money to get him back
所以我们决定去偷钱
So we're going to steal the money.
准确来说 我们只去偷坏淫们的钱
No, we're only stealing the money from folks what are bad.
你知道附近有没有坏人 我们好去偷他们的钱？
So do you know of any place where we could steal a lot of money from some bad folks?
大金块酒吧？
The Gold Nugget Saloon, huh?
你要和我们一同去吧
I reckon you're coming with us?
小狐狸担心小白飞刀 寝食难安 她必须得吃点东西
Smoking Fox so worried about White Knife.We must get her to eat something.
哟 看谁在这里吃午餐呢
Oh, we having a little picnic here, huh?
你们没有权利来这里 这是我们印第安人的地盘！
You have no right to be here! This Apache land!
那你又能怎么着我呢 海狸鼠？
And what you gonna do about it, beaver breath?
他怎么知道我的名字？
How he know my name?
我操 这真是她的名字！
That's really her name!
我觉得你应该叫“巫婆" "猪肉荣"或者是"呕吐脸"
Yeah, I think you also could havegone with "Face Like Witch."Or "Eats Like Pig."Or "Hit In Face With Diarrhea Stick."
没了 就这些绰号？ 没其他的了？
That's it? Nobody else?Babyface? Stumbles?
头儿 看啊！我抓住了谁！！！哈哈这下我们拿小白飞刀有辙了
Hey, boss!Look what I got here!He ain't gonna be happy about this.
这个小镇以前是很繁荣的 后来金子被挖完了 连火车都不运行了
Yep, used to be a prosperous town.Then the gold mine dried up and the train stopped stopping.
但是那家酒吧生意一直很好 从开业以来生意一直很好 从早到晚都是人 从来没有关门过
The saloon's the only place left that still does a good business.Open day and night since they built it. Ain't even a lock on the front door.It never closes.
他们在酒吧里面的壁炉里挂了一个很大的金块 人们总是来参观 据说金块至少值---20000美元
They got a big ol' golden nugget hanging above the fireplace.Folks come from all over just to take a look.They say it's worth about $20,000, easy.
我很惊奇居然没有人会去偷那块金子
I'm surprised no one's ever tried to stolen that nugget.
有人试过啊 但是没人成功过 酒吧吧台上挂的全部是失败者的手指 酒店老板干的事情 所以没人敢惹他
Oh, folks have tried.If you go in there, you see their thumbs hanging above the bar.Smiley Harris, the owner, bit them clean off.So nobody messes with Smiley.
感觉像搔痒痒一样
That sort of tickled.
你有什么问题吗 打开你的袍子 我来瞧瞧...噢我从来没有看过这么大范围的皮疹 都感染成绿色了
What we got going over here, friend?Just open your robe, please.I have never seen that big of a rash...or infection or whatever this green bubble is.
骚年... 不论现在你在做什么... 都请停下来... 这样让我...我的手很难受...
Now, son, I would simply recommend that you stop doingwhatever it is you've been doing,with whoever...or whatever you've been doing it with.
知道为什么叫酒店老板Smiley吗？因为无论当他在做任何残忍的事情时候 他脸上都挂着一种诡异的微笑
Yep, now they call him Smiley,'cause even when committing the most unspeakable atrocities,a cheerful grin never leaves his face.
OK 请把你的屁股太高
All right, just lift yourtail for me, please.
因为如此 金块才未曾偷过 也不会被偷
Now, he's why that nugget has never been stolen.And never will be stolen.
涂上这个可以预防感染
This'll prevent infection.
尝起来味道不错捏
It tastes good, too.
这个叫Smiley的人听起来倒像是一个当地恶霸
This Smiley fella, sounds more like a hooligan than a barkeep.
就是这么回事 传说他以前是和Frank Stockburn 帮派一伙的
You're not far off.Rumor has it that back in the old dayshe used to run with the Frank Stockburn Gang.
要不要涂唇膏？
Lip balm?
不用了 谢谢
I reckon I'm good.
看来那个叫Smiley的人 不是那么简单
That Smiley fellow,he don't joke around.
噢  话说严重了 我平时很和蔼可亲的 只要不和我过不去
Oh... I joke around...but never when it comes to my business.
欢迎来到我的“大金块酒吧”
Welcome to the Gold Nugget, gentlemen.
哈里斯先生 久闻大名
Mr. Harris, it's quite a nice spread you got here.
什么风把你们几位吹来了？
So what brings you gentlemen to town?
事实上 哈里斯先生 我们来想向您打听点消息
Actually, we wanted to ask you about something, Mr. Harris.
我现在正在同这几位先生谈话 等会再和你交谈
I am conversing with these gentlemen, sir.I shall be with you in a moment.
我需要和你谈谈Frank Stockburn
I need to talk to you about Frank Stockburn.
我已经有很多年没有听到过这个名字了
I haven't heard that name in many a year.
这么说来你认识他
You know him.
Stockburn先生和我以前是生意伙伴
Mr. Stockburn and I were business partners.
我这里有张照片 看 这是他 这是你 你当时是他帮派中的一员吧
I got a photograph.You see, that there's him...and that's you.You rode in his gang.
准确来说 应该是我们共同的帮派
To be precise... it was our gang.
他在黑帮派里混的很出名 我做的却是正派的生意 也很成功
He went on to a criminal career of some renown,while I achieved great success in the legitimate business world.
请帮帮我
Please help me.
先生 你这样做有点过分了
Sir, you are becoming a nuisance.
我需要告诉他我做过些什么
I just need to tell him what I've done.
老板 差不多了 再不停手就要出人命了
I think he's had enough, boss.
确实 各位不好意思 我也不想弄成这样
Yes.My apologies, gentlemen.Not my favorite subject.
下一轮酒全部免费
A round on the house.
还有 Chico, 如果你下次再这样抓住我的手臂的话 我就让你吃6颗枪子儿
And, Chico, if you ever grab my arm like that again,I'll put six bullets in your head.
刚才你被打的好惨 没事吧？
That's quite a beating.Hope you and your drink are okay.
为什么你这么急切的想找到Frank Stockburn？
Why do you want to meet this Frank Stockburn so badly, huh?
因为他是我的父亲
Frank Stockburn's my father.
如果Frank Stockburn是你父亲的话 把手举起来
If Frank Stockburn is your father, raise your hand.
Chico是对的 到了晚上 人就少点了
Chico's right. Getting late, starting to thin out.
兄弟们 想给你们说点事情 不想我们之间有秘密
Can I tell you guys something?Because I don't wanna have no secrets between us.
-当然可以 -我们是兄弟嘛
-Of course. Yeah -we're brothers.Yeah.
你们看 我父亲是白人 但是我母亲是黑人 所以我是黑白混血儿
Now, I know Dad is a white man, but my mother...was actually black.So that, technically,makes me half-black.
你确定 兄弟？
Is that right?
我不想隐瞒你们我是黑人 不是纯种的白人 是不想以后你们无意中说出种族歧视的话
Well, I didn't wanna hide that from you in case you guys slipped up and made some racial slurs not knowing I wasn't 100% white.
我敢肯定你母亲很健壮 但是我不确定 她居然是个黑人
I mean, I knew she must've been really muscular,but I had no idea she was black.
既然你提起来了 我觉得你母亲好像就是黑人
Yeah, I mean, I guess,now that you mention it,I see it a little bit.
我的母亲是瑞典人
My mother's Swedish.
我不这么认为 我觉得她应该是墨西哥人
I don't think so. I
reckon she's Mexican.
特么的 居然敢骗我
Lying bitch!
那么我的兄弟们 你们有什么本事 今天晚上能够帮上忙的？
So do you new brothers have any special skills that could help us out here tonight?
比如说呢？
Like what?
比如 Tommy是个用刀能手 小皮特有三个奶头 我有一头小毛驴
Like, you know, Tommy'sgood with knives. Lil Pete's got a bonus nipple.I got a burro.
Herm能一手把人给掐死
Herm is good at strangling.
我能在水下憋气6分钟
I can hold my breath for six minutes.
我能用鸡巴弹钢琴
Well, I can play the piano with my dick.
那么 我们就所向无敌了 我需要你们这些帅小伙来帮忙偷那块大金子
Well, we're unstoppable then.Anyways, any of you handsome brothers ready to go steal a big hunk of gold?
我准备好了
I'm ready.
我饿了
I'm hungry.
我醉了
I'm drunk.
我是小皮特
And I'm Lil Pete.
(我特么不知道你在说什么鸟语 死胖子)
既然大家准备好了 我们就动手吧
Let's get that nugget then.
You've got some pair of huevos
coming into my place, son.
I sure am sorry about what
happened, Mr. Harris.
In fact, I'd like to buy you a drink...
of the good stuff, if that's okay?
Barkeep, you got any scotch,
real scotch, from scotch-land?
We keep the imported stuff in the back.
I'll go and fetch it for you.
That's wonderful.
[glass shattering]
Now, I didn't hear that, did you?
I did.
[speaks gibberish]
[grunting]
[donkey brays]
I don't know, maybe I'm turned round.
I thought that, like, tonight
was gonna be Fajita Friday
or line dancing or something.
It just seems quiet, but y'all be good.
Stay warm.
- Hey, he's got the thumbs!
- They came with the pants!
Right on the rocks, right on the rocks.
Oh, you're gaining on me!
You're gaining on me!
You don't even understand
what we're gonna do to...
[laughing]
Teach them not to mess with
the Stockburn brothers!
[Tommy] Smiley...
I'm watching you!
Who's that?
[giggling]
Ladies.
[Tommy] What's behind
door number three?
Okay, ladies, take your clothes off
and start punching me in the face.
- [women laughing]
- Sorry, carry on.
[man] Hallelujah!
[woman] Smiley, why don't
you visit your grandma...
[demonic voice] In hell!
- [groans]
- [maniacal laughter]
[multiple voices] Smiley.
[demonic voice] You
cannot escape me, Smiley!
[breathing heavily]
Give me my thumbs back.
[speaking gibberish]
[screaming]
[shouting] It's too big, Lil Pete!
What's too big?
Uh... plan B's too big?
What the hell is plan B?
Let me show you.
[shouting] Plan B!
[screaming]
[grunts]
Yeah, works better if you have knives.
[laughs] Yeah, that makes sense.
Come on.
You can take 'em! Come on!
I got the nugget! I got the nugget!
What do we do?
- He's shooting like a madman!
- Come on!
[Chico] Big bullets! Big bullets!
[Danny] Come on! Come on!
[all exclaiming]
- Next man who moves will die!
- [all screaming]
Who are you people?
We are the Stockburn brothers.
Frank's kids?
[Smiley laughing]
Well... this is interesting.
You know, the last time I saw
your father was in Utah.
Just rang up our biggest score.
But when we was dividing it up,
we started having trouble
with the arithmetic.
And somehow I ended up
abandoned beside a windmill,
knife stuck in my guts,
left to die like a dog.
Frank had taken it all.
But now, I get to take something.
The lives of his five ridiculous sons.
[laughing]
Don't forget about número seis!
[screams]
[all screaming]
Holy moly!
No! Hell, no!
He's giving himself six
bullets to the head!
And he's still smiling!
I was just trying to knock him out.
Well, you succeeded.
I don't think he's
waking up from that one.
You done a number on him, Ramon.
You did! You did a number there.
- Yeah, you did!
- Hey! Hey!
- [imitating gunshots]
- [all laughing]
[indistinct chatter]
[Chico] Plan B was officially insane!
[Tommy] Here you are, Danny.
It's an old Apache remedy.
[Danny groans]
Clears your head after
too much firewater.
You know everything, Tommy.
Where'd you learn all this stuff?
[grunts] My father taught me.
Dad? I thought you just
met him last week.
Not our father. Screaming Eagle.
He raised me since I was a kid.
He's the kindest... wisest
man I've ever known.
Wow...
must've been nice to have a dad.
Oh, yeah, someone to wrastle with
and teach you how to cut
up your panny-cakes.
Someone to give you advice when
you screwed up real, real bad.
Well, we do got a dad.
[speaks gibberish]
And we're gonna see him real soon.
Yeah... I can't wait.
[chuckling]
Yeah.
♪ When I meet Dad I must insist ♪
♪ On making up for all
the time we missed ♪
♪ We'll talk and drink ♪
♪ And he'll bounce me on his knee ♪
♪ Then we'll search hand in
hand for the taco tree ♪
[laughs]
♪ When I meet Dad I'm
gonna ask him why ♪
♪ Did he pork my mother
then say goodbye ♪
♪ We're gonna be just
like birds of a feather ♪
♪ Playing piano with
our dicks together ♪
[all laughing]
♪ When I meet Dad ♪
♪ Yippie-yo-yo-yea ♪
♪ He'll take away my sad ♪
♪ When I see Pa ♪
♪ I'm gonna scream, "Gall dang!" ♪
♪ You're the handsomest man and
you're really, really good ♪
♪ I love you, Pa And I'm
glad you're my pa ♪
♪ Why do I have three nipples? ♪
[all laughing]
♪ Yippie-yo-yo-yea ♪
♪ When we meet Dad ♪
♪ Why does he have three nipples? ♪
[all laughing]
[singing gibberish]
Hit it, Herm!
[Herm continues singing]
♪ Yippie-yo-yo-yea ♪
♪ It's fun to have brothers ♪
♪ All from different mothers ♪
♪ Well, I had a dad
And now I have two ♪
♪ But one thing I never had
was a mother like you ♪
♪ She lost her life 'cause of
me and I miss her every day ♪
♪ Why, oh, why did that evil man ♪
♪ Take my mama away? ♪
♪ Yippie-yo-yo-yea ♪
♪ I think I'm gonna cry ♪
♪ Quick, Herm, do the headless guy ♪
- [imitating gunshots]
- [all laughing]
[Herm grunts]
[Tommy] What the...
Okay, boys.
I'm gonna check this out.
The ball is in your hand, twist
the leg, then you let it go!
Now, let me see. Ready, men?
No, no, no!
You're not listening to me, Hung Shin!
You have to be very precise.
Precise...
I say!
You there!
I have a proposition.
How would you men like to participate
in the birth of something
extraordinary?
Well, we ain't got time for that, but
you can have your brown thing back.
What's so damnably important
that you need to miss your
rendezvous with history?
We gotta save our
daddy, Frank Stockburn.
Frank Stockburn, the outlaw?
- You know our dad?
- Without a doubt.
One of the best poker players
I've ever played against.
I played him in Ezekiel Grant's annual
Valentine's Day game down in Yuma.
Thousands of dollars on the table, but
Stockburn doesn't bat an eyelash.
He happen to mention anything
about what his biggest score was?
Over in Utah? A guy
named Smiley Harris?
I'll make you a deal.
Help me out a bit and
I'll tell you all I know.
Deal. Tommy Dunson.
Abner Doubleday. Let's play ball.
[screaming]
Welcome, my friends, to the first
ever playing of a new sport.
A sport of my own devising.
On this field, two ten-person teams
will engage in a battle of...
Yes, Qi?
Only 18 people here.
Two nine-person teams will engage in a
battle of strength, speed, and strategy.
One team will go out onto
the field to play defense
while the other team will take
turns hitting this ball...
with a stickie.
What are you gonna call this game?
What else?
Stickie McSchnickens.
Now your goal, ball thrower, is
to get the ball past me two times
without my hitting it.
Fire when ready.
[grunts]
I didn't know you were going to toss
it quite so hard, ball thrower.
All right.
[grunts]
Okay, that's two past ya.
So you're done, right?
No, no, I said three times.
No, you said two.
I said three! Three
strikes and I'm out.
I know what I said, shortstop.
That's your new name.
Short Stop, that's right.
Now and forever. Forever and ever!
Short Stop. Short Stop, Short Stop.
Short Stop.
[laughs]
Yes, all right.
Strike three! You're out!
No, no, the ball was... too low.
In order for it to count as a strike,
it has to pass through the...
strike zone.
- Strike zone?
- That's right.
And if you don't get the ball past
me, between my knees and my titties,
it's not a strike.
[stammering] It's a non-strike.
And if you throw me four non-strikes,
I get an express ticket to first
base without my even hitting it.
Oh.
All right, are we ready?
[screaming]
That also gets me to first base...
as well.
Where you going? Nobody hit it.
I stole the base. You weren't
looking, so I stole it.
You said you could only advance
after you hit the ball!
Not when you're stealing.
That's bullshit.
Okay, Short Stop.
[Chico] He's moving!
Safe!
[cheering]
Gall dang, I don't know.
- That was a tie.
- Yes, and tie goes to the runner!
Why's that?
Because those are the rules of
Stickie McSchnickens, that's why.
All right, it's all mine, I've got it!
No! No, you can't run. You cannot run.
Infield fly rule... in full effect.
[speaking Spanish]
You're out.
- Here we go, Herm.
- [Ramon] Okay, Herm!
[Lil Pete] Yeah.
[grunts]
[Ramon] Oh!
Oh, I'm not getting that.
[Ramon] Yeah, bueno!
You can just run all the way home.
A home runner.
I need a cold drink.
Let's take a five-minute stretch
and then start the second half.
Mr. Doubleday, we're done.
But we've only played nine innings.
Nine innings is enough. Tell
us about Dad's biggest score.
Fine.
Your father and his gang knocked off
an entire cavalry regiment, 120 men,
five trunks filled with Yankee money.
Where'd that happen?
Up at Sweet Hog Rock...
100 miles due north.
You'll know it when you see it.
Well, fellas,
looks like we're going to Sweet Hog Rock
to find ourselves a singing windmill.
But we still need another 10,000 bucks.
I reckon we'll make a quick stop, then.
Before you go...
do you wanna line up and shake hands
and say "good game" to each other?
No.
Them boys were nice fellers.
Paid in cash. Kept the
profanity to a minimum.
And the Mexican brother knocked this
hard-ass' head off with a shovel?
Dang thing flew nearly 40 feet!
And still a-smilin'.
Oh! Man!
And hasn't stopped yet.
[chuckles]
Oh, hell, no! My man
gluing on heads and shit!
Wish he'd glue the head
back on my pecker.
What happened to your pecker?
I was part of another gang
before I joined up with y'all.
Texas Stubbies.
[stammering] Okay, never
mind all that. Okay?
Now, Doc, you know which way them
there Ridiculous 6 rode off to?
We're traveling with a
friend of theirs who, uh...
- will be real excited to see them.
- [snickering]
Well, they headed up north
to the Turquoise Trail.
I can show you on the map over here.
Looking forward to seeing
your man beg for his life?
[Clem chuckles]
'Cause that's what's gonna
happen, Smoking Fox.
Chicken pox! [Laughs]
We're gaining on his
Injun-loving ass every day.
He messed with the Left-Eye Gang!
He's gonna be like,
"Wait, how did you find me, and where...
How did you get my girl?" [laughs]
And then old Dumb Knife's gonna realize
that he's in way over his head.
[laughing and imitating gunshots]
See, when George Washington
invented America...
[indistinct chatter]
Excuse me, Sheriff.
Is there a church in this town?
This is Rattler's Gulch, you halfwit.
The meanest, crookedest, most
hellacious town in the West.
We don't need no preacher telling
us what we can and cannot do.
So it's all right if I
do this to your wife?
[screaming]
[laughing]
[crowd shouting]
I can't wait to see all you
nice people when I'm dangling!
You sick bastard.
Get this over with.
You're in for a real treat today.
This is gonna be so much fun.
[crowd cheering]
[choking]
[laughing]
I'm just messing with y'all. I'm fine!
[Lil Pete laughing]
I call this one Fish Out of Water.
- [laughing]
- [crowd gasping]
[woman screaming]
♪ He flies through the air
with the greatest of ease ♪
♪ That daring young man
on the flying trapeze ♪
Yeah!
[Chico] Yeah! [Chuckles]
Herm, put the hookers back.
[sighs]
Come on!
[Lil Pete cackling]
Yeah, you can't catch me! [laughing]
[crowd booing]
He ain't dying, Billy!
He's making a fool of you!
[laughing] Whoo-hoo!
All right, that's it!
We'll shoot the son of a bitch!
- [Lil Pete continues laughing]
- On my command!
- Ready...
- [guns cocking]
Aim...
Fire!
[Lil Pete cackling]
Wind took him, Tommy. Came damn close.
I'm okay!
Come on, Billy! Get him!
We did it!
[laughing]
[Lil Pete] I told ya I got
a strong neck! [Laughs]
♪ Yippie-yo-yo-yea ♪
♪ Won't be so sad ♪
♪ We're gonna save Dad ♪
[all laughing and cheering]
We still gotta get to Sweet
Hog Rock before they do.
Gotta find that singing
windmill, so it ain't over yet.
We got the money!
- The Ridiculous 6 got all the money!
- [Chico] Yeah!
Yeah!
[all cheering]
Tommy! Tommy! What's Dad like?
Is he funny?
Yeah, is he a good listener?
Is he strong?
[speaking gibberish]
All great questions.
I'll tell you this.
I think you guys are gonna love him.
But I'm sure he's gonna love you guys.
[chuckles]
So sorry to interrupt
such a tender moment.
[Nelly Patch] Looks like we
stumbled on bath day, boys!
[Left-Eye Boys laughing]
I heard you picked up some
brothers along the way, tough guy.
But I don't see no resemblance.
- I do, they all look like my butthole.
- [laughing]
So guess what time it is, boys?
Payback time!
Any last words, No Knife? [Laughs]
I told ya I could hold my breath good.
Yeah, Danny boy!
What are you doing, man?
We gotta go! [Gasps]
[chortles]
- Oh, jackpot, boys!
- No!
- [Left-Eye Gang cheering]
- [gun clicks]
- That's ours!
- [Will Patch] Hyah!
- [horse whinnying]
- [Letf-Eye Gang whooping]
Rusty!
Rusty, no, come back!
[mouthing] No.
[birds chirping]
[eagle screeching]
How are we gonna save him?
We're startin' all over.
Is there any more good
places we can rob?
You know like a burro-grooming
place or a shoe store for burros?
Half the lawmen in the West
are already looking for us.
So what? Look, we can't stop.
They're going to kill him!
Ain't no difference.
He's dying anyways.
Dad's sick.
I'm sorry I didn't tell y'all.
There's a good chance
he's dead already.
But there's a chance he's not.
You got to meet him, Tommy.
The rest of us...
Even if it was just for five
minutes, it'd be worth it.
If I don't talk to Dad, I'll die with this
dirty secret burnin' a hole in my guts.
Danito, whatever it is you did, you
have to forgive yourself, man.
You wouldn't say that if
you know what I done.
- Everybody's got secrets, Danny.
- [Ramon] Yeah.
You guys are the first
people I told I was black.
You know how good that made me feel?
We're your brothers.
You can tell us anything.
I, uh...
[sighs]
I used to work for the President
of the United States.
[grunts]
I was his personal bodyguard.
One of the best.
Till one night...
[indistinct talking]
Mr. President, say, I'm gonna
go hit the little boys' room.
Are you shitting me?
Come on! You'll be fine, superstar.
Can I get ya something on the way back?
Agua? Brewski?
No!
Mrs. Lincoln, how about one of them
big pretzels or a little pillow?
I hear this play's kind of a long one.
All right, fair enough.
I'll be back in two.
[gasps]
Where's the president's box?
- John Wilkes Booth, the actor?
- Yeah.
No way, man! Big fan!
- You wanna say hi to the president?
- Yeah.
He'd get a real kick out of that.
Last door on the left.
- Thank you. [Chuckles nervously]
- Really cool.
Wow! Love that guy!
-[gunshot] [woman screams]
[screaming] Abe!
[sighs] How can you go on living your
life knowing you harmed so many people?
That's what I wanna ask Dad.
Hey, you ain't the one
who pulled that trigger.
But if Dad's gotta be the
one who tells you that...
then let's go get that money.
I just wish I knew how.
[speaking gibberish]
Herm's got an idea.
He just can't express it.
I just wish somebody
here could speak Herm.
[chanting]
[man] Tomorrow is Valentine's Day.
That's when Ezekiel Grant has his
annual high-stakes poker game.
There'll be oodles of money there.
Oodles, I say.
Ooh.
- I don't know. That sounds risky.
- What's risky?
He's suggesting we... knock off
Ezekiel Grant's poker game.
- It's in Yuma tomorrow night.
- [speaks gibberish]
Yuma's less than a
day's walk from here.
That poker game, there's practically
gonna be an army protectin' it.
If Tommy says we can beat
'em, I'll believe him.
- We all will.
- [grunts]
We can beat 'em...
for Dad.
[all] For Dad!
[speaks gibberish]
I hope you like the gift I'm giving
you for Valentine's Day, Ezekiel.
I'll give you a hint.
One-hour massage, no charge.
Oh, Susannah.
You know what gift I'd really love?
If you would just shut up!
Nothing ruins a good poker game more...
than a lady jabbering on and on...
- How romantic.
- [knocking on door]
[clears throat]
- Hello!
Well, General Custer!
Yes, at your service.
Mr. Mark Twain.
- Word up!
- Gentlemen, do come in.
Yo, Zeke, big boy, I was just going off
to the General here about my new book.
- It's a sequel to Tom Sawyer.
- Ooh.
It's about Sawyer's home
slice, Huckleberry Finn.
White boy goes raftin' with a brother.
People gonna lose their shit!
[all laughing]
And, General Custer, I see you've let
your dashing blond hair grow out.
Well, yes, the barber down at
the regiment is just awful,
so I had two choices, either
let it grow or get scalped.
- And I ain't gonna let that happen.
- [Mark and Ezekiel laughing]
Now, will our old friend from
Tombstone be joining us?
[Ezekiel] Late as usual.
But we have a new player, a wealthy
Mexican coffee bean rancher.
Am I tardy-o?
Oh. [Laughing] Sneaky little Mexican.
May I present Don Don Diego.
[speaking Spanish]
We run a gentleman's game here, Mr.
Diego.
Your, uh, two bodyguards are
completely unnecessary.
Bodyguards? [Laughing]
[lisping] You're mistaken, General.
This is, um...
Chimichanga... my loyal manservant.
[speaking gibberish]
God bless you.
[Ramon] And, um...
Blanco Beardio.
He'll be providing the entertainment
for this afternoon's festivities.
Well, drop me a beat.
[piano playing]
Okay.
All right.
Here we go now.
[laughing]
Gentlemen, the buy-in is $15,000.
Fifteen large?
Are you sure General
Custard can swing that?
It's Custer, not "Custard." There
is no "D." I'm not a dessert.
Boom, I just dropped some
satire on your ass, General!
[all laughing]
You got me!
Hey! Now, when Ramon gives the
signal that the time is right,
that's when we move in.
You remember the signal, right?
- [man] Gentlemen.
- You know where to go, Marshal.
Oh, hell, no!
That's Wyatt Earp!
The fastest gun in the West?
All right, all right, all right!
- Oh, Wyatt Earp, as I live and breathe!
- [whispers] Wyatt Earp.
[Ezekiel] You're here!
[General Custer] Wyatt Earp.
[Wyatt] Sorry I'm late, everybody.
But apparently, there's some new gang
out there robbing everybody blind.
Oh, they call themselves
the Ridiculous 6.
I swear, a man can't ride
five miles in this territory
without running into outlaws,
rattlesnakes, Injuns and...
Hey! Why don't you let me
worry about the Injuns?
- [all laughing]
- [Wyatt] Will do, General.
[all continue laughing]
What's shakin', Twain?
Hey, I'm good on anything.
Just like gravy, baby.
- Good to see you, my man.
- You too, man.
Hey! I finally read
Prince and the Pauper.
Oh, is that right?
Didn't get it.
For reals?
- Satire! Boom! I got ya!
- [all laughing]
- I'm just pulling your leg.
- Oh, man.
I can't read.
Good one with the... satire.
[laughs] Funny.
Who's this idiot?
Um... I am Don...
Don Don Diego.
Well, Don, I'm Wyatt...
Wyatt Wyatt Earp.
- [clock chimes]
- [cuckoo chirps]
Got him.
[in sing-song voice] Now
let's play some cards!
♪ Say, say Tom Sawyer ♪
♪ Tom Sawyer ♪
♪ Say Tom Sawyer ♪
♪ Say the blacks and the
whites are getting along ♪
♪ The blacks and the
♪ I can't read ♪
[whooping]
- [screaming]
- [Ezekiel] Please calm yourself!
Let's get inside before this
Wyatt Earp ruins our plan.
But there's no way for you to
sneak past them guys, Tommy.
There's no rocks, no trees,
no nothing to hide behind.
No need to hide, brother, when
you are friends with the wind.
I'm telling you, down there,
they don't call it "Mexico."
It's "Mehico." The "X" is an "H."
I'm presuming Texas is "Tehas."
Now, what's this?
Just a tumbleweed, you jumpy bastard.
[Tommy speaking gibberish]
That is some mystical shit.
[piano music playing]
I wish to move the dresser in my
bedroom closer to the window,
but I haven't the
strength to do it myself.
I'd love to help, ma'am, but I really
should keep playing the piano.
[lever squeaks]
- [piano music continues playing]
- No one will even know you're gone.
[exclaiming]
- Gentlemen, cough up your buy-ins.
- All right!
Make it rain like Twain.
[General Custer] Take that and that.
[Mark] Yeah!
Sure is some good hooch there, Zeke.
Where'd you find that?
Oh, I got that from a case
about, uh, 20 years ago.
In fact, uh, you know that
shack up by Jawbone Falls?
- Yeah.
- There was a lady living there.
It was one of Frank
Stockburn's many paramours.
Now this was one of the ugliest
ladies I've ever seen in my life.
Sounds like a real bucket of turds.
But she was a very talented
distiller of alcohol.
[chucking] So, while she...
While she's loading up my
coach, her young boy comes out,
this big shambling oaf,
mute, filthy as a hog,
and he starts doing this
horrible little tap dance
whilst singing "The
Star-Spangled Banner."
Well, not singing it, really, but
grunting it, like a caveman!
[grunting] ♪ Oh, say can you see ♪
[laughing]
You know, he wants me to
throw him some pennies,
so I fished a coin out of my pocket
and I guess I don't
know my own strength.
I tossed it, hit him in the
mouth, and knocked his tooth out!
[laughing]
What an asshole!
[mumbles] Mama.
In any event, I still have one
bottle left from that case.
I'll go fetch it and we can drink a toast
to that awful woman and her hideous son.
[laughing]
Oh, she was ugly! You
wouldn't even sleep with her.
Say, Don Don Diego...
where's your buy-in?
I thought it was 15 grand a man.
- Yeah.
Uh...
[sighs]
Let's see. Ah!
[Herm singing gibberish]
It's you!
Uh-huh.
- [continues singing]
- [choking]
What?
What "what"?
What are you so surprised about?
Just so surprised at all the...
the fun that we're having here,
with the card and the money
and the booze and...
You know, I make that same face when
I put my cologne on in the morning,
especially when I'm home alone.
You know what I think?
I think Don Don Diego isn't really
a coffee bean rancher at all.
And his true purpose here is to rob us.
Don't make me kill you, Mr. Earp.
Hands up high.
Oh, snap! You got the
drop on Wyatt Earp?
It's mi hermano. He's one bad hombre.
[laughs]
[Herm laughing]
[Tommy] No disrespect, fellas.
We're gonna have to tie you up, and
we'll have to borrow your horses.
Ooh, what'd I miss?
[cheering and laughing]
[Ramon] Sweet Hog Rock, here we come!
[Ramon] Giddy up, Burro.
[Danny] Come on, Ramon!
[Chico] Right behind you, Tommy!
[Ramon] Hurry up, Burro! Move your ass!
- [Tommy] Whoa! Whoa, whoa.
- [horse whinnying]
[Tommy] Yeah, I think we found it.
That is one sweet hog right there.
That is a sweet, majestic hog.
Yeah, that's a sweet one for sure.
It's all right.
I'm confused. I don't see
a hog or a pig anywhere.
[chuckling] All I see is the big old
rock that looks like a weenie pee-pee.
[speaks gibberish]
- Oh, you guys call a pee-pee a "hog."
- Yeah.
- That's weird. I like it, though. [Laughs]
- Yeah. Okay.
Problem is, I don't see no
singing windmill anywhere.
- [distant humming]
- Wait...
I hear it.
Yeah, it's coming from over there.
[Lil Pete] Ah! Daddy! Daddy!
Daddy! [Gasps] Huh?
[Danny] Whoa...
We're saved! We're saved!
[chuckles]
Oh, it's just these assholes.
What the hell happened to you guys?
[spits] We was headed west to Frisco
after we absconded with your loot.
[chuckles and spits]
But we ran into these
real bad characters.
It was Cicero something
and his crazy-ass gang.
[screams]
Cicero was here? Then he left?
[voice breaking] He left
us in the dirt for fun.
- [crow caws]
- Ow! Ow, ow!
Who does that?
Sicko! [Screams]
- [crow caws]
- [crying]
If this is where the singing windmill is,
then why would they just up and leave?
Maybe that Stickie McSchnickens
guy was just pulling our leg.
They went north... about two hours ago.
Oh, yeah! Tommy can track 'em.
Let's saddle up. We're
burning daylight.
[Left-Eye Boys] Wait!
[Will Patch] You can't just leave
us here, you gotta get us out!
- [snake rattling]
- You don't need to... Hey, hey, hey!
We still got the money!
Yeah, I hid it in my pants.
[stuttering] We'll give it back to ya!
We don't need no more. Let's go!
[Left-Eye Boys shouting indistinctly]
Hey! Can you at least
help me pick these ants
out of my beard before you head out?
Please?
Tell you what, we'll dig
you up on one condition.
- [all exclaiming]
- You say it, we'll do it!
That you give up your lives of crime
and take this second chance to
start doing good by people.
- I'd rather die!
- Hell, no! I ain't doing that!
No way! Dumb Indian half!
That was a joke! That was a joke!
I'll be a good boy! I'll
be a good boy, Daddy!
[Ramon] Now what? East or west?
[Tommy] Whoa.
Late in the day.
Lot of traffic been going through here.
It's going to take a minute.
Well, we must be getting mighty close.
They'd better be treating Dad well, or
they're gonna have to answer to us.
There he is.
- There's the man himself.
- [Herm grunting]
- Look at that handsome hombre.
- [Danny] Yeah.
- That's where we get our good looks.
- [chuckling]
Let me see ol' Pop.
[Ramon] Does he still
look like that, Tommy?
Tommy?
Yeah, he does.
Let's set up camp tonight.
Right out there.
But we can't waste any time.
Chico... I can't figure
it out right now.
I gotta...
Just give me till sunrise.
Let me think.
[snoring]
[Tommy] Dear brothers,
by the time you read this, I
will have caught up with Dad.
And I'm sure you're sore at
me for sneaking out on you.
But this fellow, Cicero, who took
Pa, also took my mother's life,
and I mean to make him pay for that.
Things might get messy.
I can live with all the
bad stuff we've done,
the hold-ups, the burglaries,
the accidental decapitation,
but I couldn't live with myself if
something happened to one of you.
So stay put and I'll be back
with Dad as soon as I can.
And if I don't come back,
know that I love you
boys with all my heart.
Your brother, Tommy.
[Tommy] Whoa.
[Frank] Down at Silver Canyon...
Meeting Betty Dunson...
was the luckiest thing
that ever happened to me.
Mom was his biggest score.
Hyah.
[Cicero] Here we are.
We'd better not have come
all this way for nothing.
- I want the money, Frank.
- I know what you want.
[Tommy] There's your money.
Count it.
Tommy!
Oh, look who showed up.
I didn't know if somebody
dug up what you buried, Pa,
so I wanted to make sure you
were covered either way.
Thank you, son.
Well, ain't that a good boy.
That's my boy.
Well, it's been a pleasure, Frank.
But, uh...
we'll be on our way.
Not so fast.
You and me got some
unfinished business.
No, our business is done.
Pa... you remember how
I told you Ma died?
Yeah.
Well, the son of a
bitch who shot her...
had a tattoo on his hand...
just like Cicero here.
What, you mean...
my little horseshoe?
That's always brought me luck.
Especially when I was
shooting somebody.
Well, killer, your luck just ran out.
Your hand touch that knife, boy,
it'll be the last thing you ever touch.
Oh, I ain't using these knives.
No.
Not for my mama.
I saved a special one just for you.
Now you die, Injun-lover.
He dies, you die.
Fourteen of us, six of you.
Doesn't seem quite fair, does it?
Make that twelve of us.
[shouting] Twelve of us!
I ain't sign up for this shit.
[grunting]
You seeing this?
- It's not working.
- What are you doing?
Don't look like a
tumbleweed at all, Herm.
Herm, come back! Come back, Herm.
All right, all right. Now,
everybody just calm down.
A man's entitled... to
kill his mother's killer.
Plus... that's one less guy you've
got to split the money with!
Good thinking, Frank. Let's ride!
[Gus Patch] Yeah! [Will Patch]
Yeah, get on out of here!
[Left-Eye Boys shouting indistinctly]
Good job, son. I'm really proud of you.
And getting your friends to come all
the way out here with you, brilliant.
Well, sir... they ain't just
my friends, they, uh...
They're my brothers.
[stutters]
Five?
You had fun, didn't you, sir?
[breathes heavily]
Well, I'm gonna introduce myself.
- I think they'd like that.
- [clears throat]
[Frank sighs]
Frank Stockburn, your dad.
- Nice to meet you.
- Father.
- Son.
[both chuckle]
This is my burro.
Proud to know you, Burro.
He's proud.
You must be, uh, Saint Louis, right?
Chico.
Boy, you got your mom's muscles.
[chuckles]
You a prizefighter?
No, actually, I'm a... piano player.
Oh, well, I'll be!
You know, I've been known to
tickle the ivories myself.
Now and then, you know.
We should play together sometime.
[chuckles]
I'd like that, Dad.
[voice breaking] I'd like that a lot.
Yeah, son, we'll do that.
[sniffles]
[both laughing]
- [speaks gibberish]
- [Frank chuckles]
You must be Delilah's boy.
[both chuckling]
Boy, she made some fine, fine whiskey.
[grunts] Ooh, yeah.
[both laughing]
She must've been really hitting it
hard when she was pregnant with you.
[laughing]
[grunting]
Atta boy, atta boy.
[grunts] Da-da.
And, uh... you are?
I'm Lil Pete. I'm your son!
I love you so much, Dad!
- I have three nipples.
- Yeah, well...
It's always good to have a spare.
[Lil Pete laughs]
- Gall dang, you have one, too?
- Yeah.
Do you like to play with the extra one?
Oh, you betcha.
Oh, Pa, I have a question for you.
Yeah.
Where do babies come from?
Well, son, the mom just poops 'em out.
[laughing] I knewed it!
I knewed it, Dad!
Well, look at this handsome devil.
Sir, I'm Danny.
It's awful nice to finally meet ya.
Could you help me with a problem?
I did a real stupid thing
that inadvertently led to the death
of a United States President,
and I'm feeling pretty lousy about it.
Well, son...
look in my eyes.
Shit happens.
Yeah.
- Yeah, right.
- [both chuckling]
Thanks. Thank you, sir.
- [Frank] You're welcome.
- [exhales]
So, where to now, huh?
Well, sir, Smoking Fox and me are
getting married in a few days,
and Screaming Eagle's
walking her down the aisle,
and I was hoping...
you could be there, next to me.
Oh, you mean your best man?
Yes, sir.
Oh, Tommy...
You know, that's...
that's quite an honor.
- It would be my honor, sir.
- Yeah. Well, uh...
[clicks tongue]
But unfortunately, I...
I got some business up north
that I gotta attend to.
I gotta collect some
gambling debts and...
You know, just to pay
the doctors and such.
Say, Dad. You don't ever gotta
worry about money ever again.
We had to conjure up 50 grand twice!
So we ended up with 100!
- A hundred?
- [Tommy] Yes, sir.
There's another 50 grand?
Yes, sir.
Right here, in the burro's saddlebag.
So that business can wait up
north, can't it... best man?
Well, now that you mention it,
maybe I should change my plans.
- Bueno. Bueno. [laughs]
- [Frank] Yeah. [Whistles]
[men shouting indistinctly]
Hey! What are they doing back?
What is this?
I guess it's time you kids
learned the truth about
your dear old dad, huh?
I'm just too famous.
I can't walk into any
town west of the Rockies
without someone calling the law.
So, I came up with a way
we could make 50 grand
without lifting a finger. [Chuckles]
And you rascals brought us double!
Are these my kids or what?
[laughing]
Son of a bitch!
If our two gangs joined forces,
there's not a lawman in the West
that would stand up against us.
What makes you think we'd
turn to a life of crime?
'Cause it's in your blood.
Answer me something.
Were you ever great at anything
in your life besides stealing?
No. No.
You apples didn't fall
far from this tree.
Don't deny who you are.
If you knew who we really were,
you'd be very scared right now.
Don't overplay your hand, son.
I'm still holding an ace.
[woman whimpering]
I found her. I...
I told you I'd find her.
This little beauty stumbled
into our camp a few days ago.
[chuckling]
She actually tried to rescue me.
I'm guessing this means you don't want
me to be your best man no more, huh?
[all laughing]
Well, I'm gonna make this
real simple for you.
Hand over the other 50 grand...
in that stupid ass' saddlebag,
or I put a bullet in her
pretty Apache head.
That ain't gonna happen.
Oh, it ain't?
No, sir.
Why's that?
Mmm... kind of a secret.
Well, you can tell your
old man, can't ya?
[snickers]
You know that bag...
- your boy's holding?
- Uh-huh.
It was meant for Cicero.
So there's something special in there.
- Plan B.
- Plan B?
[garbled] Plan B.
Give me that bag.
[ticking]
[brays]
Oh, shit!
- [screaming]
- [horse neighing]
[groaning]
[indistinct talking]
[Tommy whispering] Where is she?
Smoking Fox.
[groans]
Nighty-night, son.
[gun clicks]
- Danny, are you all right?
- [groaning]
You done good, Daniel. You saved me.
It's my duty, Mr. President.
Mrs. Lincoln.
[Smoking Fox struggling]
Come on! Come on! Come here.
[shouting and gunshots]
[horse whinnying]
[Frank] Get in.
[grunting]
[Herm grunting]
I got one!
Clem, you almost shot me!
[man] Come on, get the horses!
My ass! My ass!
Hey!
Is this here still valid,
or is it too burnt up?
Let me take a look here.
Uh, that looks good to me.
I mean, this looks good.
What in the hell?
You didn't scoop yours out, did you?
[stammering]
What was the question again?
What?
Did any of you really do it?
Well, then whose eyes are in that jar?
Uh...
Well, Babyface found some
rocks, and, uh, painted them.
Surprise?
[screams]
- [thudding]
- [Smoking Fox screams]
[Frank chuckling]
[echoing] Hey, Tom,
you wanna play a game
to make up for all the
father-son time we missed?
Peek-a-boo.
- [Smoking Fox screams]
- [Frank whooping]
[Frank] Hey, come over here!
No, come over there!
[laughter echoing]
You could have had everything, son.
But you had to do the right thing.
[Frank chuckling]
Let me leave you with a
bit of fatherly advice.
- Never bring a knife to a gunfight.
- [gun cocking]
[Tommy] One day, there
will be too many, my love.
[Smoking Fox] But not today.
That was some mystical shit.
[breathing heavily]
Tommy.
You knew Cicero killed my mother.
No!
No, I didn't know that.
No more lies!
Yeah, I knew. I knew.
Your mother insisted on telling.
She was going to rat the whole gang
out, and I tried to convince her...
[stammers]
Tommy, look, I'm your
father, for God's sake.
You don't kill your father, Tommy.
His name is White Knife.
I ain't gonna kill you.
'Cause my true father
taught me otherwise.
You can't leave me like this!
Tommy!
You can't leave me here alone!
[piano music playing]
[speaking gibberish]
[Lil Pete] Dear Mama, so much has
changed since my last letter.
I scarcely know where to begin.
First off, it turns out our
daddy is a bad, bad man,
and he got thrown in jail.
[all cheering]
But it's okay, 'cause Screaming Eagle,
the Indian chief who raised Tommy,
said he'd be all our dads, too.
I really like it here in this village.
Our new brothers and
sisters love to have fun
and have been so nice to all of us.
These white guys cannot dance.
[whooping]
[Lil Pete] Danny don't
drink whiskey no more.
- No.
- [man] Yee-haw!
[Lil Pete] And Ramon and Herm are
trying to learn Indian ways.
[speaking Spanish]
[both screaming]
[Lil Pete] Oh, and big news...
I finally have a girlfriend,
and she's much prettier
than a canty-loupe.
Come on, you two! You're
missing all the fun.
Anyways, Mama, thanks for raising me.
Your loving son, Lil Pete,
proud member of the Ridiculous 6.
- sync and corrections by Caio -
- www.addic7ed.com -
[Western music playing]
[bluegrass music playing]
[Abner] Before you go...
Two, four, six, eight.
Who do we appreciate?
The Stockburns! The Stockburns!
Yeah! The Stockburns!