Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Hey hey hey hey
Ooh
Ooh whoa
Won't you come see about me
I'll be alone
Dancing, you know it, baby
Tell me your troubles and doubts
givin' me everything
lnside and out and
Love's strange
So real in the dark
Think of the tender things
That we were working on
Slow change may pull us apart
When the light gets
into your heart, baby
Don't you
Forget about me
Don't, don't, don't, don't
Don't you
Forget about me
Will you stand above me
Look my way but never love me
Rain keeps fallin'
Down
Saturday,
March 24, 1984.
Shermer High School,
Shermer, lllinois, 60062.
Dear Mr. Vernon...
We accept that
we had to sacrifice...
a whole Saturday in detention
for whatever it was we did wrong.
What we did was wrong...
but we think you're crazy
to make us write an essay...
telling you who we think we are.
What do you care?
You see us as you want to see us...
in the simplest terms,
the most convenient definitions.
You see us as a brain...
an athlete...
a basket case...
a princess...
and a criminal.
Correct?
That's the way we saw each other
at 7:00 this morning.
We were brainwashed.
I can't believe
you can't get me out of this.
It's so absurd
I have to be here on a Saturday.
It's not like
I'm a defective or anything.
I'll make it up to you.
Honey, ditching class to go shopping
doesn't make you a defective.
Have a good day.
Is this the first
or last time we do this?
Last.
get in there and use the time
to your advantage.
Mom, we're not supposed to study.
- Mister, you figure out a way to study.
- Yeah.
Well, go!
Hey, I screwed around.
There's nothing
wrong with that...
except you got caught, sport.
Yeah, Mom already
reamed me, all right?
You want to miss a match?
Blow your ride?
No school is going to give
a scholarship to a discipline case.
Well, well.
Here we are.
I want to congratulate you
for being on time.
Excuse me, sir?
I think there's been a mistake.
I know it's detention, but, um,
I don't think I belong in here.
It is now 7:06.
You have exactly 8 hours and 54 minutes
to think about why you're here.
- Ponder the error of your ways.
- [ Spits ]
You may not talk.
You will not move
from these seats.
And you...
will not sleep.
All right, people, we're going to
try something different today.
We are going to write an essay...
of no less than 1,000 words...
describing to me
who you think you are.
- Is this a test?
- When I say "essay," I mean essay.
I do not mean a single word
repeated 1,000 times.
Is that clear, Mr. Bender?
- Crystal.
- good.
Maybe you'll learn a little something
about yourself.
Maybe you'll even decide
whether you care to return.
You know,
I can answer that right now, sir.
- That'd be "no" for me, because--
- Sit down, Johnson.
Thank you, sir.
My office is
right across that hall.
Any monkey business is ill-advised.
Any questions?
Yeah, I got a question.
Does Barry Manilow know
you raid his wardrobe?
I'll answer that, Mr. Bender,
next Saturday.
Don't mess with the bull, young man,
you'll get the horns.
That man is a brownie hound.
[ Click ]
Keep eating your hand,
you won't be hungry for lunch.
I've seen you
before, you know.
Who I think I am.
Who are you?
I am a walrus.
It's the shits, huh?
[ Humming lntroduction To
"Sunshine Of Your Love" ]
I can't believe
this is really happening to me.
[ Bender ] Oh, shit!
What if we have to take a piss?
Please.
You got to go, you got to go.
[ Unzipping Fly ]
- Oh, my god.
- You're not urinating in here, man.
Don't talk.
It'll crawl back up.
Whip it out and you're dead
before the first drop hits the floor.
You're pretty sexy
when you get angry.
Hey, home boy,
why don't you go close that door?
We'll get the prom queen impregnated.
- Hey. Hey!
- What?
If I lose my temper,
you're totalled, man.
Totally?
Totally.
Why don't you shut up?
Nobody's interested.
Really.
Buttface.
Hey, sporto,
what'd you do to get in here?
Forget to wash your jock?
Excuse me, fellas,
we should just write our papers.
Because you live here
doesn't mean you can be a pain...
so knock it off!
It's a free country.
He's doing it to get a rise out of you.
Just ignore him.
Sweets.
You couldn't ignore
me if you tried.
So...
So.
Are you guys like
boyfriend-girlfriend?
Steady dates?
Lovers?
Come on, sporto.
Level with me.
Do you slip her
the hot beef injection?
- go to hell!
- Enough!
Hey! What's going on in there?
Spoiled little pricks.
Scumbag.
Let's close that door.
We can't have a party with Vernon
checking every few seconds.
The door's supposed to stay open.
- So what?
- So why don't you shut up?
- There's four other people here.
- god, you can count.
I knew you had to be smart
to be a wrestler.
- Who are you to judge anybody?
- Really.
Bender, you don't even count.
If you disappeared forever,
it wouldn't make any difference.
You may as well
not even exist at this school.
Well, I'll run right out and
join the wrestling team.
Maybe the prep club, too,
student council.
- Nah, they wouldn't take you.
- I'm hurt.
- You know why you knock everything?
- This should be stunning.
- Because you're afraid.
- Oh, god, you richies are so smart.
That's exactly why I'm not heavy
into activities.
- You're a big coward.
- I'm in the math club.
You're afraid you don't belong,
so you just dump all over it.
It wouldn't have
anything to do with...
you activities people
being assholes, would it?
You wouldn't know.
You don't know any of us.
Well, I don't know
any lepers either...
but I'm not joining
their fucking clubs.
- Watch the mouth.
- I'm in the physics club too.
Excuse me a sec.
What are you babbling about?
What I said was that...
I'm in the math club, the Latin club
and the physics club. Physics club.
Hey. Cherry.
- Do you belong to the physics club?
- That's an academic club.
So?
So academic clubs aren't
the same as other kinds of clubs.
Ah, but to dorks
like him, they are.
What do you guys do in your club?
In physics, well, we talk about
physics, uh, properties of physics.
So it's sort of social.
Demented and sad,
but social, right?
I guess you could consider it
a social situation.
Um, there are
other children in my club.
And, uh, at the end of the year,
we have, um...
- a big banquet at the Hilton.
- You load up. You party.
No. We get dressed up,
but we don't get high.
Only burners like you get high.
I didn't have shoes,
so I had to borrow my dad's.
My mom doesn't like me to wear
other people's shoes.
My cousin Kendall
from lndiana got high once.
He started eating, like,
really weird foods...
and then he felt
like he didn't belong anywhere.
Kind of "Twilight Zone," kinda.
Sounds like you.
You guys keep talking
and Vernon's gonna come in here.
I got a meet Saturday, and I'm not
missing it because of you boneheads.
Oh, wouldn't that be a bite, huh?
Missing a whole wrestling meet?
You wouldn't know about it, faggot.
You never competed
in your life.
Oh, I know.
I feel all empty inside.
I have such a deep admiration for guys
who roll around with other guys.
You'd never miss it.
You don't have any goals.
- But I do.
- Yeah?
I want to be just like you.
I figure all I need's
a lobotomy and some tights.
You wear tights?
No, I don't wear tights.
I wear the required uniform.
Tights.
Shut up.
Ooh.
There's not supposed to
be any monkey business.
Young man, have you
finished your paper?
Bender, don't screw around.
- What are you gonna do?
- Drop dead, I hope.
All right!
Bender, that's school property.
It doesn't belong to us.
It's not to be toyed with.
- Very funny. Fix it.
- You should fix that.
- Am I a genius?
- No, you're an asshole.
- Funny guy. Everyone, just shh.
- Fix the door, Bender!
- I know what I'm doing.
- Fix the door!
Shut up!
[ Vernon ] goddamn it!
Why is that door closed?
Why is that door closed!
How are we supposed to know?
We can't move, right?
Why?
We're just sitting here,
like we're supposed to.
Who closed that door?
- I think a screw fell out of it.
- It just closed, sir.
- Who!
- Aah!
- She doesn't talk, sir.
- Eek!
- give me that screw.
- I don't have it.
You want me
to shake it out of you?
I don't have it.
Screws fall out all the time.
- The world's an imperfect place.
- give it to me, Bender.
- Sir, why would anybody steal a screw?
- Watch it, young lady.
The door's way too heavy, sir.
Damn it!
Andrew Clark, get up here.
Front and center.
Let's go.
- How come Andrew gets to get up?
- [ Vernon ] That's right.
If he gets up, we'll all get up.
It'll be anarchy.
- Okay, watch the magazines.
- [ Bender ] It's out of my hands.
That's very clever, sir...
but what if there's a fire?
I think violating fire codes...
and endangering the lives
of children would be unwise...
at this juncture
in your career, sir.
What are you doing?
get this out, for god's sake.
- What's the matter with you?
- The school's equipped with fire exits.
- Show Dick some respect.
- Let's go.
get in your seat.
I expected more
from a varsity letterman.
You're not fooling anybody, Bender.
The next screw that
falls out will be you.
Eat my shorts.
What was that?
Eat...
my...
shorts.
You just bought
another Saturday, mister.
Oh, I'm crushed.
- One more right there.
- I'm free the next Saturday.
- Beyond that, I'll check my calendar.
- good! It's gonna be filled.
We'll keep going.
You want another one?
Say the word. Just say it.
Instead of going to prison,
you'll come here.
- Are you through?
- No.
- I'm doing society a favor.
- So?
That's another!
I've got you the rest of your life
if you don't watch it.
- You want another?
- Yes.
You got it!
That's another one, pal.
Cut it out!
- Stop.
- You through?
- Not even close, bud.
- good!
- You got one more.
- You really think I give a shit?
Another.
- You through?
- How many is that?
That's seven including the first one
when you asked...
whether Barry Manilow knew
he raided his closet.
- Now it's eight. Stay out of it.
- Sir, it's seven.
Shut up, peewee.
You're mine, Bender.
For two months, I got you.
I got you.
What can I say?
I'm thrilled.
That's exactly what you
want them to believe.
You know something?
You should spend more time
doing something with yourself...
and less time trying
to impress people.
Might be better off.
Right, that's it!
I'll be outside those doors.
The next time I have to come in here,
I'm cracking skulls.
Fuck you!
Fuck.
Wake up!
Who has to go to the lavatory?
That's real intelligent.
You're right.
It's wrong to destroy literature.
It's such fun to read.
And...
"Molay" really pumps my 'nads.
Moliere.
I love his work.
Big deal.
Nothing to do,
locked in a vacancy.
Ah, speak for yourself.
You think I'd speak for you?
I don't know your language.
Hey...
you grounded tonight?
I don't know. My mom said I was,
but my dad said to blow her off.
There's a big party at Stubby's.
Parents are in Europe.
- It should be pretty wild.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. Are you going to go?
- I doubt it.
How come?
If I disobey my mother,
it's because my father says it's okay.
It's like this whole monster deal.
It's endless and a total drag.
- Any minute, divorce.
- Who do you like better?
- What?
- You like your old man better?
- They're both screwed.
- I mean if you had to choose.
I don't know.
I'd probably go live
with my brother.
I don't think either one
gives a shit about me.
They use me to get back
at each other.
Ha!
Shut up!
- You're feeling sorry for yourself.
- If I didn't, nobody else would.
You're breaking my heart.
- Sporto?
- What?
You get along with your parents?
If I say yes,
I'm an idiot, right?
You're an idiot anyway...
but if you say yes,
you're a liar too.
You know something, man?
If we weren't in school right now,
I'd waste you.
Can you hear this?
You want me to turn it up?
Hey, fellas, I mean--
I don't like my parents, either.
I mean, I don't--
I mean, I don't get along
with them when...
their idea of parental compassion
is just, you know...
wacko, you know?
- Dork.
- Yeah?
You are a parent's wet dream, okay?
That's the problem.
Look, I can see you're getting
all bunged up...
for them making you wear
these clothes...
but, face it,
you're a neo-maxi-zoom-dweeby.
What would you do if you weren't out
making yourself a better citizen?
Why do you have to
insult everybody?
I'm being honest, asshole.
I would expect you
to know the difference.
- Well, he's got a name.
- Yeah?
Yeah. What's your name?
- Brian.
- See?
My condolences.
What's your name?
What's yours?
- Claire.
- Claire?
- Claire. It's a family name.
- It's a fat girl's name.
- Thank you.
- Your welcome.
- I'm not fat.
- Not now...
but I can see you really
pushing maximum density.
You see, I'm not sure
if you know this...
but there are
two kinds of fat people.
There's fat people
that were born to be fat...
and fat people that were
once thin but became fat.
When you look at them, you can
sorta see that thin person inside.
You're gonna get married,
squeeze out a few puppies and then...
Oh.
Obscene finger gestures
from such a pristine girl.
I'm not that pristine.
Are you a virgin?
I'll bet you
a million dollars that you are.
Let's end the suspense.
Is it gonna to be
a white wedding?
Why don't you just shut up?
Have you kissed
a boy on the mouth?
Have you ever been felt up...
over the bra...
under the blouse...
shoes off...
hoping to god
your parents don't walk in?
Do you want me to puke?
Over the panties...
no bra...
blouse unbuttoned...
Calvin's in a ball on the front seat
past 11:00 on a school night?
Leave her alone.
I said leave her alone.
You going to make me?
Yeah.
You and how many
of your friends?
Just me.
Just you and me.
Two hits. Me hitting you.
You hitting the floor.
Anytime you're ready, pal.
I don't want to get
into this with you, man.
Why not?
'Cause I'd kill you.
It's real simple.
I'd kill you, and your
fucking parents would sue me.
And it'd be a big mess, and I don't
care enough about you to bother.
Chicken shit.
Let's end this now.
You don't talk to her.
You don't look at her.
And you don't even think about her!
Understand me?
I'm trying to help her.
Brian, how you doing?
Your dad work here?
- Uh, Carl?
- What?
- Can I ask you a question?
- Sure.
- How does one become a janitor?
- You want to be a janitor?
No, I want to know
how one becomes a janitor...
because Andrew's very interested
in a career in the custodial arts.
Really?
You think I'm some
untouchable peasant, serf, peon?
Yeah?
Maybe so.
From following a broom
after shitheads like you...
I've learned
a couple of things.
I look through your letters.
Look through your lockers.
I listen to your conversations.
You don't know that, but I do.
I am the eyes and ears
of this institution, my friends.
By the way,
that clock's 20 minutes fast.
Shit.
[ Whistling "Colonel Bogie's March" ]
[ Whistling "Beethoven's
Fifth Symphony" ]
All right, girls.
Thirty minutes for lunch.
- Here?
- Here.
I think the cafeteria would be
a more suitable place, sir.
I don't care what
you think, Andrew.
Dick.
Excuse me, Rich.
Will milk be made available?
We're extremely thirsty.
I have a really low tolerance
for dehydration.
I've seen her dehydrate, sir.
It's pretty gross.
- Relax. I'll get it.
- Uh-uh-uh.
grab some wood, bub.
You think I was born yesterday?
Think I'm going to let you
roam these halls?
You.
And you.
Hey!
What's her name?
Wake her up.
Hey! Come on!
On your feet, Missy. Let's go.
This isn't a rest home.
There's soda
in the teachers' lounge.
Let's go!
So...
what's your poison?
What do you drink?
Okay. Forget I asked.
Vodka.
Vodka?
When do you drink vodka?
Whenever.
- A lot?
- Tons.
Is that why
you're here today?
- Why are you here?
Um...
I'm here today because...
my coach and my father...
don't want me
to blow my ride.
I get treated differently...
because Coach thinks I'm a winner.
So does my old man.
I'm not a winner
because I want to be.
I'm a winner because
I have strength and speed.
Kinda like a racehorse.
That's about how involved I am
in what's happening to me.
Yeah?
That's very interesting.
Now, why don't you tell me
why you're really in here?
Forget it.
Claire, want to see a picture of a guy
with elephantitis of the nuts?
- It's pretty tasty.
- No, thank you.
How do you think
he rides a bike?
Oh, Claire?
Would you ever consider
dating a guy like this?
- Can't you just leave me alone?
- If he had a great personality...
was a good dancer
and had a cool car?
You'd probably have to
ride in the backseat...
because his nuts
would ride shotgun.
- You know what I wish I was doing?
- Careful. Brian is a cherry.
- Cherry?
- I wish I was on a plane...
- to France.
- I'm not a cherry.
- When have you ever been laid?
- I've laid lots of times.
- Name one.
- She lives in Canada.
Met her at Niagara Falls.
You wouldn't know her.
Ever laid anyone around here?
Oh. You and Claire did it?
- What are you talking about?
- Nothing. Nothing.
- Drop it. We'll talk about it later.
- Drop what?
Brian's telling me that,
in addition to a number of girls...
in the Niagara Falls area,
that presently...
you and he are
riding the hobby horse.
- Little pig.
- No, I'm not!
John said I was a cherry,
and I said I wasn't. That's it.
What were you motioning
to Claire for?
- I don't appreciate this, Brian.
- He is lying.
You weren't motioning
to Claire?
- You know he's lying.
- Were you or were you not?
Yeah, but it was only--
It was only because
I didn't want her to know I'm a virgin.
Excuse me for being a virgin.
Why didn't you want me to know?
Because it's personal.
It's my personal, private business.
It doesn't sound like
you're doing any business.
I think it's okay
for a guy to be a virgin.
You do?
- What's in there?
- guess.
Where's your lunch?
You're wearing it.
You're nauseating.
What's that?
- Sushi.
- Sushi?
Rice, raw fish and seaweed.
You won't accept a guy's tongue
in your mouth but you'll eat that?
Can I eat?
I don't know.
give it a try.
What's your problem?
What are we having?
Uh...it's your standard
regular lunch, I guess.
Milk?
Soup.
- Uh...that's apple juice.
- I can read.
PB&J with the crusts cut off.
Well, Brian, this is
a very nutritious lunch.
All the food groups
are represented.
Did your Mom marry Mr. Rogers?
- No, Mr. Johnson.
- Ah.
Here's my impression...
of life at big Bri's house.
Son?
Yeah, Dad?
How's your day, pal?
great, Dad. How's yours?
Super.
Say, son, how'd you like
to go fishing this weekend?
great, Dad, but I've got
homework to do.
That's all right, son.
You can do it on the boat.
gee!
Dear, isn't our son swell?
Yes, dear.
Isn't life swell?
Oh.
[ grunting ]
All right.
What about your family?
- Who, mine?
- Yeah.
It's real easy.
Stupid...
worthless...
no good, goddamn...
freeloading, son of a bitch.
Retarded, big mouth, know-it-all...
asshole, jerk.
You forgot ugly,
lazy and disrespectful.
Shut up, bitch!
go fix me a turkey potpie.
What about you, Dad?
Fuck you.
No, Dad. What about you?
Fuck you!
What about you!
Bam!
- Is that for real?
- You wanna come over some time?
That's bullshit.
It's all part of your image.
- I don't believe a word of it.
- You don't believe me?
- No.
- No?
Did I stutter?
Do you believe this?
Huh?
It's about the size of a cigar.
Do I stutter?
This is what you get in my house
when you spill paint in the garage.
See, I don't think I need to sit
with you fucking dildos anymore.
Ahh!
Fuck!
You shouldn't have said that.
How did I know?
I mean he lies
about everything anyway.
Oh, shit.
Coffee.
Looks like it's scraped off
the bottom of the Mississippi River.
Everything's polluted.
The coffee, the kids are polluted.
- How do you know where Vernon went?
- I don't.
- How do you know when he'll be back?
Being bad feels pretty good, huh?
What's the point
in going to Bender's locker?
Beats me.
This is so stupid.
Why do you think--
- Why are we risking getting caught?
- I don't know.
So then what are we doing?
Ask one more question and I'm beating
the shit out of you.
Sorry.
- You're such a slob.
- My maid's on vacation.
It's drugs.
Screw that, Bender.
Put it back.
Drugs.
The boy has marijuana.
- That was marijuana.
- Shut up, dick.
Do you approve of this?
[ Bender ] We'll cross
through the lab and double back.
You better be right.
If Vernon cuts us off, it's your fault.
[ Brian ] What'd he say?
Where are we going?
[ Bender ]
Wait. Wait. Hold it.
- We have to go through the cafeteria.
- No, the activities hall.
- You don't know what you're saying.
- No, you don't!
We're through listening to you.
We're going this way.
go where you want, motorhead.
Come on!
- Shit!
- great idea, jagoff.
- Fuck you.
- Why didn't you listen to John?
We're dead.
No.
- Just me.
- What do you mean?
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player