Subtitles by explosiveskull
Beautiful items for sale!
Anything written! Anything read!
Pashto and Dari!
Beautiful items for sale!
Anything written.
Anything read.
Pashto and Dari. Beautiful
items for sale.
I saw you serve a woman!
I saw you with my own eyes!
- Uh, I really don't think...
- You were!
Anything written.
Anything read.
Pashto and Dari. Beautiful
items for sale.
Parvana.
It's the only thing
of value we have left.
I never wore it.
Not even once.
Where would you wear it,
Parvana?
- Let's continue your studies. All right?
- Yes, Baba.
Now, what can you tell me
about the Silk Road?
The Silk Road.
Baba, I can't remember
about the Silk Road.
Maybe if we think of it
like a story.
Stories remain in our hearts
even when all else is gone.
Our people have always told
stories, from our very beginning,
when we were Parthia
and Khorasan.
A fractured land in the
claws of the Hindu Kush mountains,
scorched by the fiery eyes
of the Northern Deserts,
black rubble earth
against ice peaks.
Our land was the petrified
skeleton of a monster.
We were Ariana,
the land of the noble
and honorable.
We were a pathway
to everywhere,
carrying goods
from east to west.
We studied the stars
and began to see order
amidst the chaos.
We were scientists,
philosophers, and storytellers.
Questions sought answers
and then more questions.
We began to see our place
in the universe.
But we were at the edges of
empires at war with each other,
as borders were defined
and redefined...
over thousands of years.
Of these mighty rulers
came Cyrus the Great of Persia.
Then Alexander the Great
of Macedon.
There came the Mauryan Empire,
Genghis Khan,
and so on and so on.
Each time
there was bloodshed,
and each time
there were survivors.
A pattern repeating itself
endlessly.
When I was young, Parvana,
I knew what peace felt like,
here in this city.
Children went to school,
women went to university.
All the empires
forgot about us,
for a while at least.
But it did not last.
The ground became weak
under our feet,
always uncertain.
First came a coup d'état,
then an invasion,
then a civil war.
In the chaos,
some looked to those
who might restore order.
But at a great cost.
We have determined
specific dignity for women!
Women should not go outside and
attract unnecessary attention!
If a woman shows herself, she will
be cursed by the Islamic Sharia
and should never expect
to go to heaven.
Everything changes,
Parvana.
Stories remind us of that.
Parvana, were you
listening at all?
Yes, Baba.
Why don't you tell me
about our nomadic ancestors
and their hills of gold?
Well?
2,000 years ago...
- Yes?
- 2,000 years ago...
there was a Bactrian princess
who had a crown.
And?
- And...
- Parvana?
Away.
Keep away from my things.
Go away. I said go
away, you silly dog!
Hey, you! What do you
think you're doing?
Why is this girl
shouting?
She is only a child.
She meant nothing by it.
She's drawing attention
to herself!
She should be at home, not
displaying herself in the market.
I have no son at home, except an infant.
I need my daughter to help me.
- Stand up when we talk to you.
- I am a cr...
I said stand up!
- I know you.
- Yes, Idrees.
I was your teacher once.
You were a good student.
You wasted my time, teaching
me things of no worth.
I have joined the Taliban and now
I fight the enemies of Islam.
Well, if I am an enemy, then for
my sins God has taken my leg.
Are you making fun of me,
old man?
I lost my leg in the war.
The war we fought together.
- How old is the girl?
- Idrees.
- She is a child.
- She's old enough to marry.
I'll be looking
for a wife soon.
She's already been promised
to someone.
Well, she should
cover herself properly.
- Maybe you should stop looking at her.
- What did you say to me?
I said
stop looking at her.
- I can have you killed!
- Idrees.
- You watch what you say!
- That's enough. Come on.
Are you all right?
Yes, Baba.
That's my girl.
Let's go home now.
Parvana?
You told that boy
I was promised to someone.
Am I getting married?
Of course not.
You are still a child.
I want you playing
and telling stories.
I'm too old for that now.
Too old for stories?
You've always loved stories.
What's the use?
I'll have a word with Mama-jan
and we'll sort it all out.
Please don't mention
the dress.
Then I'll never
hear the end of it.
- The end of what?
- Nothing, Mama-jan.
We're not selling
Parvana's good dress.
Baba, that's not
what I meant.
We need the money,
Baba.
We'll hold off for a bit. I
think business will pick up.
If business picks up, then we
won't have to sell it, sure.
But the sky is far and the earth is hard.
We will have to sell it soon.
Well, what about a little story
before dinner?
And we'll forget all about
dresses for a while.
Maybe Parvana would like
to read something for us?
Not right now, Mama-jan.
I'm tired.
She's not a child
anymore, she tells me.
So she doesn't
like stories.
Don't be in such a hurry
to grow up, my sweet girl.
It might not be
all that you expect.
We're out of water. You didn't
bring enough this morning.
But there's half a bucket
by the door.
When I was young enough to fetch
water, the buckets were never empty.
- Hey!
- Girls, stop it.
Either you go out and get more water after dinner...
or you can wash
Zaki's dirty diapers.
- How are you feeling?
- Better.
Now that you're here.
Maybe if you didn't wash your hair so
much, we wouldn't run out so quickly.
- Parvana.
- You should have some respect.
Why don't you eat,
hmm?
- Things always look better when your belly is full.
- Yes, Maudar.
Zaki, Zaki, wait till I
pull up your sleeves.
No, Mama-jan.
There. There you go.
Don't eat all the raisins, Parvana.
Leave them for Zaki.
Why don't you give him that big
raisin on your chin, Soraya?
Oh, but it's
not a raisin.
It's a big,
hairy mole.
Parvana,
apologize to Soraya.
Parvana?
He's in there! I saw him!
- If there are women present...
- Baba?
Cover yourselves now!
That's the man.
An enemy of Islam.
He's got forbidden books, and he's
teaching the women with them!
- Leave us be!
- He's done nothing!
Nurullah Alizai, you must come with us.
Baba!
- You can't take him!
- Baba!
Baba-jan!
Where is he being taken?
To prison.
They'll teach him a good lesson
in Pul-e-Charkhi.
Baba!
Mama-jan?
Can I light the lamp?
Hush, Parvana.
You'll wake Zaki.
But if they
let Baba go,
he'll need a light in
the window to see home.
How could he come home? He doesn't
even have his stick to walk with.
Go back to sleep.
It will be all right.
How do you know that, Mama-jan?
How do you know?
Be quiet, Parvana. She has
enough to worry about.
Hey!
Zaki, stop it.
Get up, Parvana.
Stop playing around.
Why?
What's going on?
You and I
are going to find Baba.
The boy said he was being taken to Pul-e-Charkhi
prison, so that's where we are going.
But we can't go outside
without Baba.
Soraya is writing a letter
for the prison governor
to protest Nurullah's arrest
and ask for his release.
- At least I can give them that.
- Mama-jan, it's not allowed.
We might be all right if we don't
draw attention to ourselves.
- But we can't...
- Come on, Parvana.
And bring Baba's walking stick.
We have to get going.
Mama.
Hey.
Hey, you!
Salaam. Can you tell me
the way to Pul-e-Charkhi?
Salaam. Uh, it's east,
past the river.
- But it's a long way.
- Thank you, sir.
Listen. Go through the old
town, or you'll be caught.
Why are you out here by yourself?
- Where is your husband?
- I have no choice.
It's not permitted to be out here
without your husband or your brother.
- I'm sorry. I know.
- Do you understand?
- I am bringing a letter protesting my husband's arrest...
- Just go home.
- No!
- What do you mean, "no"?
This is Nurullah Alizai,
my husband.
- He was arrested last night with no charges laid against him.
- Photographs are forbidden!
- I have no one at home...
- What are you doing, showing me a photograph?
- Out here by yourself. Go home!
- There is no one in my house except for children.
You have no business out here. Do you
understand? Go home. Immediately.
You're looking
for trouble now!
You are an insult to your
husband, to your race!
I need to find out
what happened to him!
Shut up!
Going to the prison
will change nothing.
If you make trouble like this,
your husband will be punished
severely for your insolence.
And if I find you out here again
by yourself, I will arrest you.
Now go.
Mama-jan?
Take me home.
- More!
- Shh.
Go get water, Parvana.
We have none left.
Come on.
Get out!
What are you up to?
Get out of here.
They'll see you!
Hey, stop!
Stop when I tell you!
Through here!
Stop!
Where did
that boy go?
Did you see?
- Hey, you! Girl!
- Hey!
- Come on!
- Forget about her!
Parvana, this is
only half a bucket.
Couldn't you fill them up
all the way?
Zaki, shh. Don't wake her.
- Hush, Zaki.
- Mama-jan!
- Shh.
- Sooth him, Parvana.
Mama-jan.
Tell him a story.
Mama...
One time
in the distant past,
there was a little village at the
foot of the Hindu Kush mountains.
- I want Mama-jan.
- Shh. Listen.
The villagers had just managed
to gather precious seeds.
And so, there was dancing and
singing and laughing and eating.
Everyone was happy.
Especially for one boy
who danced and sang and laughed
and ate more than anyone else.
While the villagers were dancing and
singing and laughing and eating,
monsters were coming.
The monsters frightened the
donkeys and ate the trees.
They stole the most precious
thing in the whole village...
the seeds
for next year's crop.
Then they ran back to the Hindu Kush
mountains where their master lay...
the dreadful Elephant King
with spikes for tusks.
Grrrroar!
Grroar! Grroar!
Grroar!
Mama-jan.
Please eat, Mama-jan. You'll feel
better when your belly is full.
There's hardly
any food left.
I'll go
to the market.
- Salaam.
- Salaam. Twelve oranges, please.
100 afghani.
Thank you.
Salaam. How much
for six apples, please?
Salaam, child.
I can't serve you.
But, sir, can I please
have six apples?
- Get your father to buy food for you.
- My father has been taken.
I'm sorry.
Maybe come back later.
Literally stolen.
But you know...
Salaam. Can I have
a kilo of rice, please?
- Salaam.
- Hey, you!
Girl!
Hey, stop!
Stop when I tell you!
Go! Go home!
I dropped the bag.
- Hush.
- I lost the money.
- Keep your head back.
- I can get the water though.
Don't worry
about that now.
I saved you
a piece of naan.
I'll heat it up for you so it's
nice and fresh. All right?
- What are we going to do?
- I don't know.
Maybe if I go out early,
before it's crowded.
It won't work,
Parvana.
Market sellers won't risk getting
in trouble for serving you.
Mama-jan has cousins
in Mazar-e-Sharif.
I could write to them
for help.
But we've never even met them.
How do you know they will help?
We need food now.
These were
your brother's clothes.
They will be big,
but we can take them up a bit.
Do I look like
a boy?
You look like
Sulayman.
- So much like him.
- Mama-jan.
He was such a good boy.
Not much older
than you are now.
Shh.
It's all right,
Mama-jan.
Parvana is going to the
market for food and water.
It's the only way, Mama-Jan.
We have nothing left.
But these juices are warm.
I don't want warm juice.
Yes, that's what I said, but you know...
Salaam. Salaam!
Excuse me. Salaam!
Salaam! Salaam!
Come inside, boy!
I'm not going to deliver, am I?
But you
know how it goes, right?
Well, let's hear it.
I need a kilo of rice, a half kilo of
lentils, and a small amount of raisins.
A small amount?
Should I go
by my imagination?
Yes.
Not very bright, this one.
Poor iron won't make a sharp sword.
Look at him smiling!
Little guy doesn't even know
when he's being made fun of.
Thank you.
Thank you very, very much.
You're spilling
the tea.
Sorry, Uncle.
Who are you? Why were
you staring at me?
- What is your name?
- My name?
- I know you from somewhere.
- No... I wasn't...
- Wasn't what?
- You don't know me.
- I do know you.
- No!
- I do know you! You're Parvana!
- I'm not!
I am Shauzia! Remember?
From school?
- Shauzia?
- I had long hair then, but so did you.
- Deliwar.
- Don't tell anyone.
Here's your cap.
You need to get
a boy's name
so you don't hesitate
next time somebody asks you.
I am Deliwar now.
It means "brave."
- Where are you?
- I-I have to run.
It was good to see you.
Deliwar.
Mama-jan, please sit down.
- It will be curfew soon. What if she's not back by then?
- She's fine. I'm...
Who's hungry?
Parvana.
Praise Allah. He has
returned you to me.
Mama-jan,
you're squashing the naan.
It smells delicious,
Parvana.
Zaki.
It's me. See?
I bought them
especially for you.
Parvana?
If you run out
and get some water,
he'll get used to you
by the time you come back.
- But I'm tired.
- Hurry on, Parvana.
It's almost curfew.
You look
so much like him.
Go change
Sulayman's clothes,
or you'll
get them dirty.
They are already
dirty.
Elephant.
What?
He wants you to continue your
story about the elephant.
Elephant.
Well, um...
in the village,
under the
Hindu Kush mountains,
the poor villagers
cried bitter tears.
They did not know what they would do
without their precious bag of seeds.
They would have nothing
to sow come next spring
and nothing to eat
come next winter.
But the boy,
he did not cry bitter tears.
He looked toward the mountain
and he shouted...
I am not afraid of you,
big, spiky,
bad Elephant King!
Well, maybe he was
a little bit afraid.
He told the villagers who had
been weeping bitter tears
that he would get the bag
of seed back before spring.
I will get the bag of
seed back before spring.
But they laughed.
They laughed and laughed, because he
was a child and not a great warrior.
Yet the boy
repeated his promise.
I said, I will get the bag
of seed back before spring.
And he left the village
to the sound of the Elephant
King's roars ahead of him.
Roar!
Mama-jan,
now that I am a boy
we can go to the
prison and find Baba.
No, Parvana,
we can't do that.
- Why not?
- Shh.
It's not that simple,
Parvana.
But we have to try.
- There's nothing we can do.
- That's not true.
Stop it, Parvana.
You're upsetting her.
Hey! Hey! I told you to stop!
Why do you keep running?
You should have stopped
when you were told to.
Where's your burqa? Why are you
dressed like this outside your house?
My husband took my burqa.
I needed to buy medicine.
Stop it. Stop it.
He should be punished for
letting you outside like this!
- Please, please! Please!
- You have to take his punishment!
Stay inside
where you belong!
Deliwar. Deliwar!
Well? Have you remembered
your name yet?
I don't think
I can go on like this.
Too bad.
I could use some help.
- I saw something.
- What do you want me to say?
I should have helped.
- You'd have helped yourself to a good whipping, that's all.
- But I'm not a boy.
You're not a boy,
you're not a girl.
I need a helper because this tray
is too heavy. Will you help?
Scratch my nose. Quickly. If I let go
of the tray, the strap will break.
That's better.
- Aatish.
- What?
I remembered my name.
It's Aatish.
- That's not really a name.
- It means "fire."
I know what it means,
but it's still not a name.
Then it suits me fine.
I'll call you
Aatish then.
When you're a boy you can
go anywhere you like,
Aatish Khan.
Where are we going?
You'll see.
What if someone
sees us?
I usually just pretend
I work here.
If you look like you believe
it, then they will too.
See? We're cleaners.
What are you
waiting for?
It's either ours,
or the mice eat it.
I need to find a way
to see my Baba.
You can have mine if you like.
I don't want him.
My father was taken to prison and
we've heard nothing of him since.
- They won't let you see him, Parvana.
- But I'm a boy now.
Doesn't make a difference. They'll keep him or
let him go, but there's nothing you can do.
You don't know that.
I'm sorry.
It's just the way it is.
There might be a way, but
you'll need lots of money.
What for?
You can get a lot done
with bribes. A lot.
Anything written.
Anything read.
Pashto and Dari.
Wonderful items
for sale.
Anything written!
Anything read!
What happened to the man
who used to sit here?
It is a simple question.
Don't you know?
How should I know? Answer the question.
Where is he?
- He left for Mazar-e-Sharif.
- And what are you to him?
I'm his nephew,
uh... Aatish.
Do you know
how to read?
- Do you have something to read? I read Pashto and Dari.
- Read this.
Let's see
if you're any good.
Come on. Take it out
of the envelope.
"Dear Razaq..."
Louder, or I will have to
take my business elsewhere.
"Dear Razaq, I hope this
letter reaches you in Kabul.
I'm writing to you
with sad news.
I am sorry to tell you that Hala Begum
died on the way to her sister's wedding.
The bus she was traveling on
hit a land mine.
Her injuries
were too great to bear
and she died
some hours afterward.
I know this must be
a great shock to you,
but please know that when
I last spoke to Hala,
she told me of your
kindness toward her.
May Allah bless you now,
guide your path,
and give you courage."
I'm sorry.
Ah, there's
my sweet little girl
underneath
all the dust of Kabul.
Parvana,
what did you give Zaki?
- It's a piece of candy.
- A piece?
Oh!
It's big enough
to choke him!
Let him be, Soraya.
You're spoiling his fun.
Ow!
Continue
the story, Parvana.
For Zaki.
There was this young boy,
and he promised his people
to find the precious seeds.
Elephant?
Yes,
and the elephant.
At night, the boy walked
through the pine trees
on his way to the mountain
to face the Elephant King.
Something was following him
in the darkness,
but he was too terrified
to turn around and face it.
He began to run,
and the thing
that chased him also ran.
The boy ran faster
and so did his pursuer.
He ran into the night,
chased by the unknown demons
until he could run no more.
He tumbled down a hill.
Down.
Dear Cousin, it has been
many years since we have spoken,
but I am writing to you now to tell
you that my husband has been arrested
and we have no word on when
he will be released, if at all.
My family is in a desperate
situation and I need your help.
My eldest daughter
is now of age,
and I am asking that you consider her as
a bride for your youngest son, Ajmal.
Please take us out of Kabul
so that we may have
a chance of survival.
We will not be
a burden to you.
We are skilled and strong
and need little
by the way of means.
May the blessings of Allah
be upon you. Fattema.
Anything written!
Anything read!
How much
for the dress?
Salaam. It's handmade.
- How much?
- 3,000.
Don't be stupid.
I'll give you 300.
2,000.
Handmade
in Mazar-e-Sharif.
Your daughter will be very happy
to wear such a beautiful dress.
She is my wife.
1,500.
See how it sparkles?
Here's 1,000.
- How much did you make?
- A thousand.
That might be enough
for a good bribe.
- Really?
- Definitely.
I'm saving up too. Whatever money I
can hide from my father, I keep.
And it's mounting up
to a nice little sum.
See?
I'm not going to stay
here forever, you know.
- Have you ever been to the sea?
- No.
Neither have I.
But I've heard that the moon
pulls the water onto the shore
and then
back out again.
I want to see that.
I want to put my feet on the warm sand and
have them cooled by the lapping water.
What about your father?
Doesn't he depend on you?
I am a good son.
But he is not
a good father.
What will you do by the sea?
I'd buy things and sell things,
like I do here, but for myself.
There are people who go to the
edge of the water to do nothing.
They just sit there and they look
at the sea with their sunglasses on
or swim about
on floating tubes.
So I could sell them
those things.
Hmm. That sounds nice, Deliwar.
And maybe
I'll join you.
- Where are you going?
- Wish me luck.
- Why are you back so early?
- I have brought some bread and raisins for Zaki.
What are you doing,
Parvana?
I'm going to find Baba.
- No, you're not.
- I'm going.
You won't make it home
before curfew.
I'm going. There's nothing
you can do to stop me.
Mama-jan has been through enough
without you doing something so stupid.
- I have to find him.
- Parvana!
Parvana!
Excuse me.
Salaam. Hello!
Excuse me!
What do you want?
- I said, what do you want?
- I want to see my father.
- Who?
- My father, Nurullah Alizai.
Brought here two weeks ago
without charge.
- Get out of here.
- I have money... 1,000 afghani.
- I can give it to you if you promise to help.
- Hey, what are you doing?
Nothing.
Just getting rid of a kid.
Please! Open up!
I have to see my father!
I have to see him!
Now get out of here
unless you want some more.
They say it doesn't always
rain the way it thunders.
Last we heard of him,
the boy had fallen down.
He had fallen down the hill
and into the deepest of sleeps.
But all was not lost.
He was discovered
by an old woman.
She had a drum.
A magic drum
that beat so beautifully
that his heart woke up.
She knew he must be on a
quest, and so she asked him...
What is it you seek?
Well, you see, the dreadful Elephant
King sent his jaguars to steal the...
No one has ever overcome
the Elephant King.
- I know.
- Well, what makes you think you can?
I need to.
I just need to,
that's all.
That's not
a very good answer.
Nevertheless, the woman told
him he'd need to find three things...
something that shines,
something that ensnares,
and something that soothes.
Only then would he overcome
the Elephant King.
Give them to me,
please!
I don't have them,
so you'd better
go look for them.
And hurry! If the seeds are not planted
soon, there will be no harvest.
Yes, I know.
She told him to head east.
East is the other way.
Still something
followed the boy,
and still
he could not face it.
- He didn't take the money?
- I don't think bribes work on them.
No, no.
It probably wasn't enough.
It might have
insulted him.
You'll just have to save up more
and be even smarter next time.
- Aaah!
- I have to be smarter?
I've heard there is a guy who
pays well for small jobs.
Come on.
Sir, we have come to work.
- And you are?
- I'm Deliwar. And this is Aatish.
We are brothers.
What kind of a name
is Aatish?
I don't know.
Ask our father.
- Where is your father?
- He was martyred by the Russians.
We can do
any job you want.
For the right price.
That's the
last one, I think.
Where are we anyway?
About time. You boys
are not very strong.
It was more work
than you said.
Here you are.
Now be off.
Hey, we did all
that you asked.
Wait! You said
you'd drive us back.
I'm not a taxi.
Make your own way home.
I'm late already because you
took so long to load the truck.
Wait!
I need to rest
a moment.
Stay on the path.
This place might be mined.
This is not nearly enough.
We need better jobs.
- Like what?
- I heard brick making pays well.
But it's hard work.
I wish I was stronger.
But you have an older
brother, don't you?
He used to bring you to
school on his shoulders.
What's his name?
Sulayman.
He died.
How?
Was it the sickness?
- I don't know.
- But your mother must have told you.
She doesn't speak of it.
All right?
All right.
Hey, look
what I've got.
I found it in a little box where
my father keeps his things.
Can you believe
the water is that blue?
It's very nice.
Anything written!
Anything read!
I didn't pay you
last time.
- How much do I owe you?
- It's okay. I...
What, you don't charge
for bad news?
Who taught you to read?
The crippled teacher?
Yes. My uncle.
Can you write
as good as you read?
I can.
Here.
I kept this
in case you wanted it.
Show me. Show me
where it says her name.
Where it says
"Hala."
There. See?
Hala.
Do you know
what it means?
No.
Sometimes, on a clear night
when you look at the moon,
you can see a bright
outline around it.
That outline
is called hala.
My wife was named
for that light.
- Here.
- This is too much.
Don't argue with me.
Thank you.
Stop it, Zaki.
Can I pull yours?
Keep him quiet.
I'm trying to sleep.
- What's the matter with you?
- Why don't you tell Zaki a story, hmm?
We'd all like that.
Well, Zaki, do you want to know
what happened to the boy?
Yes, yes,
and the elephant.
The boy ran and ran, his
heart beating fast in fear.
And the thing that chased him
never stopped.
So the boy hid behind a tree
and he waited for courage.
An ancient woman
had been trying to milk a goat,
but her back was very sore.
My back is very sore.
The boy took pity on her and told her
to rest under the shade of a tree
and he would do
the milking instead.
Please sit under
the shade of this tree,
and I will do
the milking instead.
When he finished
milking the goat,
the old woman shared
the lovely, warm milk with him.
It was the nicest milk he had ever tasted,
and he complimented the woman
on her goats.
Your goats
are very generous.
In return, the old woman
gave him a mirror.
See how it shines!
The boy was delighted
with the mirror,
but as he looked into it, he saw the
reflection of the thing that followed him!
What are you doing,
Mama-jan?
I'm laying out
Soraya's good clothes.
Am I to sell them
at the market?
Shh, shh, shh, Parvana.
It's time to sleep.
I just need to find
a way to get to Peshawar,
and I can figure it out
from there.
I think there's
a beach in Goa
where the tourists
are very rich.
If they're rich, they
would buy my blue stones,
and that's where I'd set up my
business, and you could join me.
Once I find Baba.
Once you find your Baba.
100.
I'll give you 85.
- Ninety.
- Eighty-two.
Eighty-five,
and that's final.
Eighty-five and a bunch of
grapes, and that's final.
You're leaning too hard on the
pen, but your writing is good.
If you try it more gently,
it'll be easier.
Wait!
Wait a moment!
What is it, child?
You asked me before about the man who
used to sit there... the teacher.
- Your uncle?
- He didn't go to Mazar-e-Sharif.
He was taken to prison.
But he did nothing wrong.
- Which one?
- What?
- Which prison?
- Pul-e-Charkhi.
It's been weeks now, and my
family has had no word of him.
Go to the prison
on Wednesday.
Ask for Roshan.
He's my cousin.
Tell him Razaq sent you and
he will help you, if he can.
Deliwar!
With work like this, I'll be an old
woman by the time I get to the sea.
Or an old man.
You sit and rest, Deliwar,
and I'll tell you a story.
- A story?
- Yes, a story.
One time
in the deep past,
there was a boy who had to return a stolen
bag of precious seeds to his village.
Is it a happy story
or a sad story?
Just wait and see.
The boy had been told
he needed three things
in order to overcome
the Elephant King...
something that shines, something
that ensnares and something that...
Hey, you two! Come here!
Come on!
I know that boy.
Hurry up. Come here.
Come on.
We'd better do
what we're told.
Get a move on,
lazy kids.
So these are
the new workers?
Where are your tongues? Are you stupid?
Idrees suggested we have a
little arm-wrestling match.
To see if you're strong
enough to work for me.
I saw you sitting down
over there instead of working.
Idrees, stop now.
Make me some tea.
Let me see how feeble
you are, little one.
He can't even
lift his hand.
Get up and make us tea.
Uncle, I think
you need new workers.
- These ones are no good.
- Enough, Idrees.
Leave the poor kids alone.
They are
a little undercooked.
I know you.
You're the teacher's daugh...
Idrees.
Bring the gun back!
I said
bring the gun back!
Idrees!
Come out now!
Idrees, it has begun!
We are moving west.
We have been given orders
to go immediately!
I know who you are!
Do you hear?
Get up here! Come on!
Right now!
You little coward!
You want to fight? Now
is your chance to fight!
You become a man.
He's gone.
What if he comes back?
He'd be lucky.
Where are we?
I came here once
when I ran away.
I think the way in has gotten
smaller or I have gotten bigger.
It looks old.
I lost a shoe.
I lost my cap, although
I think it's outside.
Why did you hit him?
When they took my father,
he was one of them.
Tell me more
about the boy.
What boy?
The story boy.
The boy was cold.
Though the sun burned in
the sky, it gave no heat.
But he had a
warm hat and a big coat.
No, he didn't.
He had already found
one of the three things...
a mirror that shone.
But when he looked at it,
he saw something behind him.
Something scary.
Something dreadful!
- A horse!
- No, Shauzia, not a horse.
Yes, it was.
And it was a very old horse whose bones
clattered together when it walked.
It wasn't scary at all.
Fine. The boy felt sad for the
old horse and fed him hay.
And they all lived
happily ever after.
It's the middle of the
story, not the end!
From a door carved
into the stone,
out came a round man.
You wasted my hay on an old
horse that will soon be dead!
The round man threw the boy deep
into the belly of an ancient well.
Aaah!
At the bottom of the well
there were emeralds,
and the round man wanted them brought up
to him as payment for the wasted hay.
You will bring
the emeralds to me.
- What's his name?
- The round man?
No, the boy.
You can't have a story about a
boy and not give him a name.
Give him a name
before I do.
Sulayman.
His name is Sulayman.
That's a good name.
Sulayman lay
at the bottom of the well.
Suddenly, he could see skeletons.
Three skeletons, each with an
emerald clutched in its bony hands.
- He called out for help.
- Help!
The poor old horse looked
back at him from way above.
But the horse did
something extraordinary.
He neighed with the voice
of all the world's animals.
Sulayman climbed up, up,
all the way to the top,
and he thanked the horse
for saving his life.
Thank you for saving my life.
Sulayman had just
three emeralds with him...
And asked the round man for food in return.
He was hungry.
But the round man
was wicked and cheap.
He threw a fishing net at Sulayman
and he told him to get his own food.
- That was exactly what Sulayman needed.
- Ha-ha!
Something that ensnares.
But as Sulayman left,
the ghosts of the three skeletons
came out of the three emeralds
and swirled and twirled
and scared the round man
in frightful vengeance for
having lost them their lives.
Sulayman and the horse continued
their journey toward the mountain,
but the horse was getting
slower and slower.
He needed to rest,
being very, very old,
and so Sulayman made a
shelter for the horse
and told him
to wait for him.
The horse protested...
but Sulayman knew he had to face
the Elephant King and the jaguars
all by himself.
I will see you again,
old horse.
And so on he went alone.
Tomorrow is Wednesday.
I'm going back there,
to the prison.
They'll have to
let me see him then.
From now on,
you're staying inside.
- It's much too dangerous.
- No, Mama-jan.
- We manage all right out there.
- "We"?
Me and Deliwar. She's a girl too.
We work together.
We've written to my cousin to arrange
a marriage for your sister in Mazar.
They wrote back,
and it was accepted.
Someone will come for us the day
after tomorrow to take us away.
- You don't need to do this anymore.
- What?
We can't go on
like this.
- We can't depend on you to keep us alive.
- Why?
I provide for you
just fine.
It's not the job of a child.
How can we leave
without Baba?
Every day you come home
with cuts and blisters.
Every day you go out there, and I don't
know if I'll see you back again.
I can't lose you too.
I'm not going.
Baba could come back, and no one
will be here waiting for him.
So how long
should we wait?
Until you're found out
and taken away from me?
Until I have to send Zaki out
to earn our keep?
Let me go see him
before we leave.
Let me tell him
where we are going.
- Parvana!
- Let me bring him his walking stick.
Then I will go with you.
Then I will be a good sister
and a good daughter.
I promise.
Please don't go.
Please, it is much
too dangerous now.
Mama-jan, I'm going.
I'll be back tonight
before curfew.
- No, Sulayman.
- Mama-jan.
- You won't come back.
- Let her go now.
Let Parvana go.
Oh!
Parvana.
Deliwar!
You frightened
me half to death.
I've been looking
for you everywhere.
Why? You want to work at the
chai shop with me this morning?
- No, I can't.
- Hey, you want some candy for Zaki?
We are leaving Kabul
tomorrow.
You are leaving me?
It's been arranged.
There's nothing I can do.
My sister is getting
married in Mazar-e-Sharif.
I'm going back
to the prison.
I found someone
who can help me,
and I need to get more money
to bribe the guard.
I'll need it today.
You'll just get another punch in the guts.
It's a stupid idea.
I won't let that happen
this time.
- I said it's a stupid idea.
- Please help me.
What do you want me to do?
Magic some money into your hand
like in your kids' stories?
It doesn't work like that,
Parvana.
I can't help you.
Now run away to Mazar-e-Sharif
and have a nice wedding party.
Maybe they'll find a husband for you
too and your troubles will be over.
Until after the wedding,
at least.
You fool!
Deliwar!
Shauzia.
Come with us.
I can't.
My father would come all the
way to Mazar to kill me.
I can't leave Kabul,
Parvana, not like this.
- Here, take this.
- I can't take your money.
Please take it.
Go and see your Baba.
Tell him that his daughter
is a good daughter.
Tell him
that Deliwar said so.
Hey, Deliwar.
What?
I'll meet you at that beach
you were talking about,
where the moon
pulls the water,
20 years from today.
I don't think I'll
recognize you then, Aatish.
Well, you can sell me some pretty
blue stones for a great price.
Until next time then.
Until next time.
Peace be upon you.
Are you Fattema?
Yes, I am Fattema.
I am your second cousin. Mohammed
Abdul sent me from Mazar.
Gather your family.
We must leave immediately.
No, you see, you weren't
supposed to come so soon.
My son is away. We must
wait for him to return.
There is a war coming.
Have you not heard?
We have to leave now
before they block the roads.
We have to wait until she comes home.
I have to wait for my daughter.
Son? Daughter? Which is it?
Gather your things.
We are leaving now!
I'm not leaving without Parvana.
We have to wait.
Count yourself lucky
I'm taking you, old woman.
The girl and the baby
are of more worth.
I didn't come all this way
for nothing.
If we do not go now, we won't
get out of here at all.
- My baby! Give him to me!
- Let's go! Argh!
Zaki! Zaki!
Give me my baby.
Give him to me!
- No! Give him to me!
- Let go! Let go!
- Salaam, little one.
- Salaam.
Where are you going to
with an old man's stick?
It belongs to my Baba.
I'm taking it to him,
to the prison.
I see.
We're going that way.
Give me my baby!
- Let's go! If you want to keep the baby, come with me!
- Zaki!
My daughter
is out there.
Then what kind of fool are you
to have sent her out alone?
Get in, or she won't be the
only child you'll lose today!
Don't...
Give me my baby!
Keep him quiet!
I am begging you.
Wait for my daughter!
Come, Soraya.
We must start a fire.
I am looking for Roshan.
Hey!
- Open the door!
- Get away from the door, you stupid kid!
- I am looking for Roshan!
- Get out of here!
- Are you stupid?
- I am looking for Roshan.
- Shut up!
What are you doing here?
It's all right.
He's my son.
You're wanted inside.
That boy needs
some discipline.
That's my business.
What in the name of the
merciful are you doing here?
It's Wednesday. I've come
to meet your cousin Roshan.
There's a war started.
Roshan has gone to fight.
We've been brought from the city to clear the
prison of anyone who won't fight for us.
- The teacher...
- Is he alive?
I don't know.
The teacher is my father.
I am Parvana, his daughter.
Help him, please.
If I'm not back before the
sun has gone down, you run.
Run as far away as you can from
here and you keep on running.
You can't stay here after sunset.
Do you understand?
- Thank you.
- Do you understand?
- Yes.
- Hide yourself until then.
Once there was a young boy
called Sulayman.
He knew his heart was fated
to serve his people,
and he was running
out of time.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
- Come on! Get in the car.
- We have to go back for my daughter.
I said come here. Now!
We're not going with you.
Mama-jan?
You, come now!
Do you hear me?
You come here like I told you to!
You come now!
We will not go with you.
Just drive away from us.
Get in the car.
Get in the car now!
Mama-jan!
Sulayman! Sulayman!
Be brave, Sulayman.
Run, Soraya.
- Take Zaki and run now!
- Mama!
Go! Keep running!
You... let... us... go.
Open the door.
What are you doing
with that?
He's dead. I'm putting him with the others.
Open the door. Let me through.
- Move, move, move, move, move!
- Stop!
- Line up. All of you, all of you.
I said stop!
It will be dark soon.
Razaq?
Razaq? Razaq?
Sulayman.
The mirror shines!
Use it to blind the jaguars!
The net ensnares!
Throw it over them!
Hah!
Razaq. Razaq!
Razaq! I have come
for my father.
I have come for my Baba!
Put him down!
I said put him down.
Do you see
what is happening?
Where are you taking him?
Who's out there?
Look away, can't you?
It is just one man.
What does it matter?
Go.
Go!
Go, unless you're going
to kill me.
I will scream and curse you
until the last breath
leaves my body.
Go.
You're crazy. Crazy.
You can die out here
for all I care.
Die.
Sulayman.
I have not come
to kill you.
Sulayman!
Soothe him with your story,
the one that Mama-jan
can't speak of.
Tell him.
Sulayman!
My name is Sulayman.
Tell him what happened.
Tell him your story.
My name is Sulayman.
My mother is a writer.
My father is a teacher.
And my sisters
always fight each other.
One day I found
a toy on the street.
I picked it up.
It exploded.
I don't remember
what happened after that
because it was the end.
It's working, Sulayman!
Tell him. Tell him!
My name is Sulayman.
My mother is a writer.
My father is a teacher.
And my sisters
always fight each other.
One day I found a toy
on the street.
I picked it up.
It exploded.
It was the end.
My name is Sulayman.
My mother is a writer.
One day I
found a toy on the street.
My father is a teacher.
- I picked it up.
- And my sisters always fight each other.
It exploded.
One day I found a toy
on the street.
I don't remember
what happened after that.
I picked it up.
Because it was the end.
The Elephant was transformed.
He took the bag of seed
from the center of the mountain
and gave it back to Sulayman.
Sulayman returned
to his village.
There was much dancing
and singing
and laughing and eating.
Razaq?
Baba?
Baba!
Is he alive?
It is not his blood.
He lives.
Get out of here now,
child. Go on.
As fast as you can.
It's the moon.
Soraya.
S... Sora... Soraya!
- Mama?
- Soraya!
So...
We are a land whose
people are its greatest treasure.
We are at the edges of empires
at war with each other.
Par...
Parvana.
We are a fractured land in the
claws of the Hindu Kush mountains,
scorched by the fiery eyes
of the northern deserts.
Black rubble earth
against ice peaks.
We are Ariana,
the land of the noble.
Raise your
words, not your voice.
It is rain
that makes the flowers grow,
not thunder.
Subtitles by explosiveskull