Bye, L.A.!
Here we go.
My friends are morons.
You better be careful, you might
end up in the Tower of London.
Criminal.
But it's gonna be you.
- Forget the plane.
- This is backwards, by the way.
And here in front of us,
we have the beautiful...
Danube river.
We're doing Prague.
Hi, Paul! We're at
the Tower of London!
Here we come, Kiev. We're
coming to see you, Paul.
You guys are ridiculous.
- Dude, it was so much fun, man.
- Yeah, I can imagine.
Hey, ladies! You wanna
put your stuff away?
- Sure.
- Some place you got here, Paul.
I'm never leaving.
Best place ever. Ain't
it right, Chris?
- I got it, it's fine.
- I'll take it. I got it. I insist.
Where are we sleeping?
I told you, I put a pillow
on the patio for you.
"I told you, I put a pillow
on the patio for you."
You're sleeping in my room! Where
do you think you're sleeping?
Oh, great. Even better. Some
chick still sleeping in there?
Quite possibly.
I hope you cleaned those sheets.
Or burned them.
I heard that!
- So, Kiev, huh?
- Kiev, baby!
I thought for sure your add
would have kicked in by now.
Dude, I'm telling you, man.
I don't think I'm leaving.
I love it here! The chicks,
they're fuckin' amazing.
They absolutely love Americans and
they are completely fucking insane.
Yeah, well, they have to be if
they want anything to do with you.
- So, Amanda.
- Yeah, okay.
- What? Chris!
- I knew this was coming.
Come on.
Rob literally broke up with her three
weeks before we were supposed...
To come out here and Natalie had
to drag her ass onto the airplane.
Perfect! Look at her.
She's lonely, she's in Europe.
Best way to get over an ex is with a fling.
I could be her fling.
- You're a sick son-of-a-bitch.
- I'm not sick, dude!
Would you stop?
- Do I have a shot with her?
- No, you don't.
- No? All right.
- Zero. Fine.
- I'll leave it alone.
- Thank you.
What about you and Natalie?
You guys going good?
It's creepy when you look
at me like that, dude.
Hold this.
Are you serious?
Yeah, dude!
I haven't asked her yet. I'm
gonna propose in Moscow.
- Does she have any idea?
- Ah, well, I hope not.
- What about Amanda?
- No.
That's awesome, dude.
Unbelievable.
A fucking riot.
Oh, man, thank you so much.
This was such a good night.
Yeah, it was.
Told you, man. Okay. Save it
for the apartment. Get a room!
Go to town, we're in Europe!
Don't listen to him.
- Whoa! You all right?
- Hello! Thank you, good save.
Watch out! These cobblestones,
they'll get you.
Thank you for being a good host.
We've had a lot of fun.
My pleasure. You enjoying
yourself in Kiev?
I am! Yes, it's a
beautiful little city.
- It's not bad, right?
- Yeah, it's great.
Wait till Moscow.
Wait until you get to Moscow.
You believe me?
I don't know.
Do you trust me? I don't trust
you in those heels. Come here.
- Paul. Hands off!
- Sorry.
- You're trouble.
- I am trouble!
I can't promise what's gonna happen
at the end of the road, but...
Don't fall.
Those stairs are slippery.
Please, lock your door tonight.
I don't trust him.
- Christopher.
- Yeah.
- You are visiting your brother in Kiev.
- Yeah, well, I had to chase you down.
I didn't know when you booked this
trip, it was a one-way ticket.
I missed you, buddy.
Yeah, I missed you too, man.
It's good to see you.
- How are things back home? Good?
- Yeah, things are great.
Mom's worried sick, of course.
You know how she is.
You spoken to Dad?
No, I, uh... no.
- You should call him.
- I know I should.
- Paul, which way should we go?
- Left.
Hey, hey, hey, we don't want
any trouble, seriously.
- Don't touch me.
- Come on.
- Good night.
- Have a good night.
Good night. Bye-bye.
Come on, come on, come on.
- Fucking losers.
- Real friendly people here.
Don't worry about it. We
got a big day tomorrow.
Okay, I'm assuming that this is the
breakfast menu? But I don't know.
Excuse me, is...
Yeah, she hasn't had
her coffee yet.
Where's Paul? He's supposed
to help us with this.
I don't know, I just
want something greasy.
Can you just point out
something greasy, please?
You need the hangover special.
Amanda, I want to apologize for
Paul's behaviour last night.
Oh, please. He's fine. I mean,
I know the type, you know?
Just all talk.
Yeah, well, with him, it's
not always just talk.
I can handle him, I'm not too
worried about it. You know?
And I'm sure, deep
down in there...
- Very deep down, very...
- Somewhere...
He's a good guy, you know?
It's just an act, that's all.
I mean, he's related to you, baby,
and you turned out all right.
- That's true.
- Yeah, you're okay.
That's true. Just let me know if
I need to kick his ass for you.
- Thanks, dude. Hello!
- Morning, children.
- How are you doing?
- Hello.
- How are you?
- Fantastic.
So, I know I said we're
going to Moscow.
But I'm gonna ask you a
question, and I want an answer.
The answer is already no.
You guys ever heard
of Chernobyl?
- Yeah.
Isn't that where the
nuclear disaster happened?
Yes. I met this really
cool guy, Uri, who's a...
Have you heard of
extreme tourism?
Somehow, I haven't, no.
You guys see where
this is going, right?
We're going to Moscow,
as we talked about.
Chris? Can I please finish?
So, there's this place called Pripyat.
It's a town right next to Chernobyl.
Uri, who is very excited to take us
there, is an extreme tour guide.
He's gonna show us this city
that was abandoned overnight.
Literally. They had no
time to take anything.
Factories, schools, stores, homes,
apartments, everything's still there.
Imagine the photo shoot you
can have there, Amanda?
Yeah, but, radiation
levels or something.
- It's probably pretty dangerous, right?
- We're only gonna be there for a day.
A few hours, see some cool
shit and then we split.
- How are we gonna get there?
- Uri's gonna take us.
- He's got a van.
- A van?
- Yeah.
- He has a van?
He has a van!
Okay...
Aside from the sketchy
van situation...
And if you promise that
this tour is safe...
I think it could be kinda cool.
- That's what I'm talking about.
- You're kidding.
No. I mean-I don't know.
He's right.
We're in Europe, we
might as well...
See as much as we possibly
can while we're here.
I don't know.
- Tell me you don't want to meet Uri.
- I don't want to meet Uri.
How can you say that? You
haven't even met him yet.
Okay, we'll take some pictures, explore
a bit, and then we'll be on our way.
Just as planned. Right?
I don't like that he's
rubbing off on you.
He's definitely not rubbing off.
You're incredible,
you know that?
All right, let's just settle
this by a show of hands, please?
Who's coming with
Paul to Chernobyl?
- Yeah!
- You're kidding me, right?
You guys are so weak.
All right, kids! Welcome to Uri's
extreme travel. Let's do it.
Welcome to Uri's extreme.
Uri!
What's up, buddy?
Good morning.
- Come in! Welcome, welcome.
- All right, man! The gang is all here.
- This is my little brother Chris.
- How you doing?
His girlfriend Natalie.
The lovely Amanda.
- Guys, this is Uri.
- Hi.
Hello.
So, I was telling them about
our little adventure today...
And Chris got
parental, as usual.
So I figured you'd give him
a little peace of mind...
Before he pisses his pants.
- You're feeling, uh, nervous?
- No, I'm not. I'm not nervous.
It's a nice shop you got here,
it's very, uh, professional.
Thank you. It's all mine.
- It's all yours, huh?
- Yeah, very nice.
- Yes, it's all mine.
- Well, what are you, ex-military?
Yes, special forces.
What does it matter if he's
a fuckin' magician, dude?
I'm just asking a
fucking question.
Okay. Uri, what's the plan for today?
What are we doing?
Well, this is a very
well organized tour.
I've been taking special adventurous
tourists for a while now...
So you should feel
very, how do you say?
- Special?
- Special, I like that.
Okay, so imagine, you have big city
and no one's there. All to yourself.
Is it safe?
Of course it's safe. This is
not my first rodeo, Natalika.
- So sorry we're late!
- We're here.
Hey, you guys are for
the special tour, yeah?
Yeah!
I'm Michael, this
is my viking Zoe.
How you doing? Chris.
Nice to meet.
What's up, man? I'm Paul.
Nice to meet you, buddy.
- Okay, we go!
- We go now.
- Come, come.
- All right.
Sweet.
- We didn't keep you waiting?
- No. You guys are fine.
Zoe, I told you!
Go with the flow!
So, tell me, what's up with
the whole viking thing?
He calls me that all the time.
I'm from Norway, so...
And he's my Australian
surfer dude.
All right, let's rock and roll!
Yes.
Yeah, buddy! Are you kidding?
That's what we're riding in?
- Might as well just... roll with it.
- Put your bags in the back.
First time there?
Pripyat? Yeah. How
about you guys?
Yeah. How about you guys?
Yes. Someone said that
it's pretty fantastic.
- You two sweethearts Moonin'?
- "Moonin" '?
- Are we what?
- Honeymooning.
Yeah, actually, we
are honeymooning.
We're just friends. Barely.
You're cute.
- Are you guys?
- Oh, yeah, we're timeless.
A month.
You guys have only been together a month?
God bless.
These two are
practically married.
- We go.
- Shotgun!
Thank you.
Anybody gets hungry,
I have beef jerky.
Pripyat is two hours from here, and
Chernobyl is not far from there.
Good time!
What exactly happened
in Chernobyl?
The Chernobyl disaster was a
result of failed systems tests.
It caused sudden power surge.
And reactor number four
became one with the air.
- One with the air?
- Vaporized.
It exploded.
I'm sorry, what does that mean?
Nature has reclaimed
its rightful home.
Here we are.
Welcome to Pripyat.
Photo.
We're now entering
exclusion zone.
How long is it safe to be here?
It's very safe. We'll only
be in Pripyat for two hours.
What is this place? Is
it like a checkpoint?
Looks like it.
Why would there be a checkpoint
at an abandoned town?
Tourists.
Okay...
- Let me do the talking.
- Well, you think?
- Put your cameras away.
- Yeah, got it.
Look at this guy over there.
These guys look pretty serious.
I don't know what they're saying,
but this guy is saying no.
Look at this guy.
What do you think is going on?
It's scary!
God, look at that guy.
He's huge.
- Thanks, baby.
- Come on, you.
Hide me so he doesn't see me.
How's that?
- You have a criminal soul?
- Do I look like one of them?
He is not letting us in today.
There's maintenance going on.
Maintenance work? I thought you
said this place was abandoned.
It is unusual.
Usually, they let me
know in advance...
...if something like this
is going to happen.
Wait, I thought you said everything
was gonna be taken care of.
- We paid for this tour, bro.
- I know, I know.
Don't worry.
There's more than one
way into Pripyat.
Make it happen.
It's so bizarre, I don't
see any birds or anything.
This must be Uri's
special entrance.
Paul, this looks
fuckin' sketchy, man.
Stop being a pussy. We came all this
way, enjoy yourself, all right?
It's called being sensible.
This is not right, you guys.
We're gonna end up in a
Ukrainian jail or something.
Come on, just think of
it as an adventure.
It's okay.
- This is the awesomest.
- Really?
Okay, no problem. Today we
have Pripyat to ourselves.
- Sweet.
- All right.
Here we go.
I was not expecting
a lake out here.
And there is Pripyat.
Home to the workers and
families of Chernobyl.
It's incredible.
Hold on! This is going
to be a little bumpy.
A little bumpy.
Oh, you're not gonna...
And down we go!
And up!
Oh, my God!
When are you putting seat
belts in this thing?
- Jesus.
- Or barf-bags.
It's ridiculous.
Okay. Now, I want to show
you something in water.
He wants to show us
something in water.
Thank you.
After you. After you.
- Stay close behind me.
- Like we're gonna go anywhere.
- Paul?
- Yeah?
I want you to tell me if you see
something moving in water. Okay?
Okay...
You don't want to get
your booties wet.
Give me your hand!
You okay? You okay, mate?
Funny, bugger.
- Are you fucking kidding me?
- He's a fucking comedian.
- It's jerky.
- Jerky, you jerk.
Hey, guys, can we go, please?
- Fucking got me!
- Yeah. He got me, too.
Oh, shit!
It was a joke.
Sorry about that.
Come have look at this.
Is this another joke?
No. No, come.
Holy cow.
- Don't get too close.
- Why? It's dead.
- It's disgusting.
- Look at the chompers on him.
What is that thing?
Touch it, mate.
Who's the pussy now, huh?
- Can we go? This is disgusting.
- Keep it up.
Can we go? That's disgusting.
- That's awesome.
- And moving on.
See its teeth? It's cool, huh?
Oh, my God!
- Did you just make a rhyme, Uri?
- Yes.
Make small joke.
- Not to worry.
- Here is Uri.
So, Uri, how long has this
place been abandoned?
It's been 25 years. Only recently
have radiation levels gone down.
Man, this is crazy.
It's creepy as fuck.
We are back on main road. It's
only way in and out of Pripyat.
Yeah, except for your
shortcut, right?
This is where the
families Chernobyl lived.
- See?
- Yeah.
- These were all full at one point.
- Yes. Very sad.
Fifty thousand people,
families, just left.
Okay, hold on. Little
bump, little bump.
- The Ferris.
- All right.
- I used to love those things.
- We're here.
Still want to go home, Chris?
I'm happy we're here. Thanks.
- You're welcome.
- There we go. Brotherly love.
Guys, look at this.
Ah, man.
Okay, everyone.
Stay near me and you'll be safe.
I have geiger counter.
It will let us know if the
radiation levels are high.
That's good.
Levels are good.
Can you guys imagine this like,
full with kids? Like... playing?
- It's really sad, actually.
- They had no idea.
I mean, this is
just unbelievable.
I have never seen
anything like this.
It's like they were getting ready
for a carnival or something.
They were preparing for
"may day", the celebration of spring.
Never happened.
Okay, let's go. This way.
Can we get a photo? Uri, you
want to take it? A photo.
- Hey, guys?
- All right. Quick photo.
And new friends.
Okay...
Good.
It's so American.
In a way, it's like...
There was life, and it just...
Hey, you hear that?
Silence.
It's like nature
really has taken over.
One last thing.
- Are we going in?
- Yes.
What is it, babe? Whoa, Zoe.
Hey, babe, it's okay.
They usually don't come so close to town.
Must have been starving.
I reckon he's right.
Come in.
That's disgusting.
That's the V.I.P.  entrance.
Treatment.
Poor guy...
Are there any other
animals here?
Unlikely. Especially
during the day.
Just you.
Stop it.
Here's one of a thousand
apartments that were abandoned.
Cool.
The people were not even
given five minutes...
To collect their
personal possessions.
You can't take that.
It's contaminated.
I was just look... spot the convict.
Cheers, man.
It's contaminated.
For a while, people came here and
they looted through these buildings.
They took these things,
sold them on black market.
People who bought
them got sick...
Not knowing they were
contaminated by radiation.
Sorry, I was just...
Come, let's have a look.
But it's okay to be
here and breathe?
Yes, yes.
We're not here long
enough to get exposure.
Chernobyl reactor number four.
Where the disaster happened.
- That's pretty close.
- Have you, you been inside?
No. You can only go inside
with radiation suit.
Only for short period of time.
Here, take picture.
- Take a nice, romantic photo?
- All right, all right.
Hey, I wasn't gonna...
- Yeah, he was.
- This is going on the fridge.
That's a metaphor here,
by the way, guys.
Do tell.
- That's beautiful.
- Our love is just exploding.
Oh, God.
The one good thing
about the radiation...
Is that I'll probably
finally grow a penis.
These guys are funny.
I know, I know.
- Can you beat that kiss?
- What?
We should go now.
It's going to get dark soon, we
should get back to van before then.
Fuck was that?
Right, it's gonna be a trick.
Stay.
Fuck is that?
Holy shit! Go, go, go!
- Jesus!
- Motherfucker!
Oh, my God!
Fuck!
- Is everyone okay?
- Don't fucking stand there!
Let's go, move, move, move!
Go!
Fuck! What the fuck was that?
Go, go.
Black bear or it's a fucking brown bear?
Oh, Jesus!
- What is a bear doing here?
- Can we just get the fuck out of here?
- Jeez.
- Watch out for that.
Oh, fuck!
- Okay.
- Holy shit.
- Can we just get the fuck out of here?
- Yes.
- Thanks for that.
- Yeah. Don't mention it.
Told you it'd be
exciting, didn't I?
Yeah, almost getting
mauled to death...
By a radioactive bear from hell?
It's pretty exciting.
Anybody else have a
story like this?
- Funny.
- You okay?
Anyone get a photo?
A photo. This guy.
Jesus.
Bear! Bear, bear! I'm kidding.
That's bad.
So, Uri, all the animals,
they stay in the woods, huh?
It's very unusual.
I've been doing this for five years.
I've never seen anything like this.
It's kind of chilly
out here, huh?
A dog, a wolf. But
a bear, very odd.
- It was exciting, right?
- Yeah, mate.
No extra charge for bear attack.
Say goodbye to Pripyat.
- Ciao.
- Yeah, ciao-ciao.
Hey, Christopher?
Moscow! Thank you.
- I'll have to get your e-mail, eh?
- Yeah, for sure, dude.
- Catch up again? I'll be back to Kiev.
- Done, dude.
- It was a blast.
- It's been a pleasure.
Turn the heater on, buddy.
Pump it.
Give it some gas.
- What's up, is there gas in there?
- Yes. Half a tank.
Is it the starter, mate?
Has this happened before?
I don't suppose you guys
have triple a out here?
Do you have reception?
I haven't had reception all day, guys.
There's no kind of reception out here.
Look, look.
What the fuck could've
done that, mate?
That's fucking been chewed on.
- Wait, what's happening?
- What's going on?
- The wires have been destroyed.
- Chewed on.
What do you mean chewed on?
What, by what? An animal?
What kind of animal
chews on car parts?
Are you sure we're
out here alone?
Yes. You heard the soldiers this
morning, this place is off-limits.
We are here alone.
What the fuck is it, Michael?
That's the spark-plug
leads, been chewed on...
- Can you call someone?
- By a raccoon, a rat, or some animal.
But how would an
animal get in here?
Under the car.
Through the engine.
- Underneath?
- Yeah, yeah.
He said there aren't any around
here and all of a sudden...
I don't know.
Guys! Let's just shut up and
let him-we're trying to-to...
Fuck me.
Uri?
What's the plan, mate?
Hey, big fella? What's the plan?
I'm so hungry, I could die.
Well, this is great.
Gotta hand it to you. Some
fucking tour, mister.
- This is not my fault.
- Oh, really? Not your fault?
Cause last time I checked, you were
the one that drove us out here.
Well, if it weren't for you,
we wouldn't be here either.
Oh, I'm sorry to try and
show you guys some fun...
- While you're out here visiting me.
- Oh, yeah. Lot of fun.
Hey, Chris. All
right, you know what?
Relax.
- We're fine.
- We're fucking stranded out here.
And don't tell me to relax.
I swear to God...
This is the last time I listen to
one of your dumb fuckin' ideas.
Hey, you know what, Chris? Your fucking
whining isn't helping right now.
- He's got every right to be pissed.
- Okay, guys. Hey, Uri.
Someone has to know
we're out here, right?
I work alone.
Fucking great.
So, tell me, Uri.
What are our options right now?
We stay in van.
- Are we safe here?
- Yes, we're safe.
We close windows, lock doors.
In morning, I fix van, we drive up.
Or we all walk back to checkpoint.
Wait, wait, I'm sorry.
Are you suggesting that
we spend the night here?
Okay, okay, guys
I'm sorry, but we're gonna have
to hike outta here, all right?
Uri, how far to the checkpoint?
- It's 20 kilometers.
- That's like 12, 13 miles.
Exactly. We can hike that.
No, no, not at night!
- It is not safe.
- Be quiet!
What the fuck was that?
- Are there people here?
- It's impossible.
It sounds like a baby.
- What is that?
- It's not a baby.
Then what the fuck is it, Uri?
Whoa, whoa. What's
with the gun, man?
- You have problem?
- Yeah. What's with the fucking gun?
You should all be
glad I have this.
Everyone stay here.
- A gun?
- Where is he going?
Do you trust him?
- Do you want to go out there with him?
- Easy, bro.
I don't know, it's
just that the...
Stay here. He'll come back.
- Chris, what the fuck...?
- Where's he going?
- Chris, I'm coming with you.
- No, I don't want you to come with me.
Just sit in the car and
think of another way...
You can fuck this
up even further.
I swear to God, Paul, it's a fucking
hazard having you as a brother.
Chris!
- What's he gonna do?
- I don't know, babe.
- Where is he going?
- Uri, wait up!
I can't see him. Can
you guys see him?
Oh, God.
Chris!
- Chris! Chris!
- Chris! No!
Oh, my God, Chris, no!
Can you see anything?
- Can you see them?
- I don't know. I can't see.
Chris!
Michael, can you see?
Open the door!
Get him in, get him in!
Chris! Oh, my God, Chris!
Okay, look at me. Breathe, buddy.
Chris, mate, keep breathing.
Fuck!
- Chris! What happened?
- I don't fucking know!
- There were a lot of them!
- Where's Uri? Where's Uri?
Chris.
Chris, what happened to Uri?
They got him! They
fucking got him!
What the fuck got Uri?
Just breathe, baby!
- Hold him, hold him.
- Don't look!
- Where's your first aid Kit? He's cut.
- I don't know, check in here.
That's fucking fishing tackle!
Fuck!
Holy shit!
- What is that?
- Stay away from the windows!
Fuck off!
Hey, everyone away from
the fucking windows!
Stay away from the windows.
Chris. Chris, look at me, buddy.
Look at me, buddy.
It's gonna be all
right, brother.
Look at me, buddy. Stay
with me, all right?
- Get me the fuck outta here!
- I'm gonna get you home.
Chris, I'm gonna get you outta here.
Chris, look at me, look at me.
I'm gonna get you out. What
the fuck is with the lights?
Just relax. The battery's dying.
The fucking car battery is dying.
What the fuck is going on?
- Tie it tight.
- Can somebody please hold the light?
Good, good.
Fuck. Sorry, mate.
- Breathe, baby, just breathe.
- Breathe. Just breathe, mate.
Here, hold it up. Fuck. Here, mate.
Just breathe.
- I'm so sorry.
- Try not to look at it, mate.
Breathe, breathe.
I know, I know, I know!
It's gotta be tight,
I'm sorry, brother.
I'm so sorry, baby.
- What the fuck?
- Turn off the light, turn off the light!
Ah, fuck. Sorry, Chris.
Take it, take it.
Ah, fuck.
Here, Zoe. It'll be
all right, baby.
Just breathe, mate.
You're doing good.
- You're doing good.
- We're gonna get you out of this place.
I'm freezing.
- I know.
- Fuck!
You're gonna be okay.
It's okay, baby.
- How are you feeling?
- He needs a doctor.
I know he needs a doctor.
How are you doing?
I just want to get the
fuck out of here.
I can't fix it. I'm sorry. I'm
sorry, the, the leads have rotted.
I mean, if we could get some new
leads, we could roll-start it, but...
I ain't fuckin' seen this before.
Try it.
Uri, this is Paul.
Can you hear me?
- That the other walkie?
- Yeah.
Uri, are you there?
Can you hear me?
Come on.
- All right, I'm gonna go look for him.
- You don't know your way around.
But he does. He can help
us get out of here.
And what if the dogs come back?
Uri said the dogs
come out at night.
So just stay in the van
and keep the door shut.
I'll go with you.
No, you will not.
Uri is a big fellow and it might
take two of us to carry him back.
Yeah, what if he's dead?
Don't say that. Uri knows how
to get the fuck outta here.
We might find new leads...
You saw what attacked the car. He says
that there's other things out here.
- Come on. Just stay here.
- Please!
- Stay.
Yeah, I'm gonna come too. I'm
gonna help these guys, okay?
All right, let's go.
You stay in the car, you keep the door shut.
We'll be back for you.
You'll be all right, mate.
We'll be back.
- Stay with them. Help them.
- Michael, this is stupid.
- Why would you do that?
- I'll be back.
How well you know Uri?
Not well. You?
Same, same.
You think he's still here?
It's been overnight.
He could be gone.
Yeah, I know.
What are you thinking?
I think Chris got
attacked by dogs.
Dogs didn't do that.
Maybe a bear? I mean, we saw a bear
run by us at the apartment yesterday.
- He said there was something else.
- Yeah, and it could be a bear.
He said there was a lot of dogs.
It was dark, he was in shock.
Try the walkie-talkie, will you?
Hey, Uri, are you there?
It's Paul.
- Lets go around here.
- Uri, can you hear me?
Just stay close and keep
your eyes open, all right?
I don't believe him when he said that
animals don't come out during the day.
I don't know what to believe.
Fuck.
This is where he went
off last night, right?
Let's just try and figure out
how we get back to the van.
Good idea, mate.
Check your walkie-talkie again.
Hey, Uri, this is Paul.
Can you hear me, buddy?
- What?
- Do it again, do it again, do it again.
Uri, do you come...
- Did you hear that?
- Yeah.
Holy shit.
Something fucking got him.
Okay, let's go. We need to go.
No, we can't, mate.
We have to see if he's alive.
Uri?
It's okay.
There's too much blood.
- There's no way that he's still alive.
- I know, I know.
We need to be smart about this.
We're not going back there.
We are. I'm gonna go.
Besides, he's got the gun.
He's right.
Let's do it.
Uri?
Uri!
Oh, fuck!
Holy shit!
Look!
Gotta check his pockets.
- Shit! Where's the gun?
- Oh, shit.
Wait. I've got the clip.
Lock the fucking door!
Oh, what the fuck is that?
- Holy shit!
- Gun, gun, gun!
- Fuck, there's no bullets!
- Right here!
All right, I got it! I'll do it!
Go!
Oh, shit!
Forget it!
Motherfucker!
Get the fuck outta. We're
getting the fuck outta here.
- What do you mean? Where we going?
- What's going on?
- We gotta go.
- Where's Uri? Did you find him?
- Yeah, what's left of him.
- What?
What he said, man. Uri's dead.
- We better go, we can't stay here.
- He cannot walk.
We can't stay here.
- I don't have a choice. Help me.
- He's right.
- What? Babe, no!
- Come on, I'll help you.
- Ah, fuck.
- Real slow.
- Just do it real slow.
- Easy, easy, easy.
All right.
- Aw, fuck.
- There you go. There you go.
- Fuck!
- Goddamn it, I told you, he can't walk!
- Put it back up, put it back up.
- Easy, easy.
- What's going on?
- All right, we gotta carry him.
- Don't be fucking stupid.
- We're not gonna leave you here!
It'll take three of you to
carry me and twice as long!
Fine. I'm staying here with him.
- I'm not leaving him!
- Well, I'm not leaving him either!
Would you listen to me?
You live here. You're the only
one that speaks the language.
Go get help and bring it back.
We're staying in the van.
All right.
- Take this.
- We'll be back. Come on, Zoe.
Stay on channel one.
If you guys need anything, if
anything happens, you call us.
It's 13 miles. We're gonna leave now.
If we hurry...
- We'll be back before it's dark.
- What if you're not back?
Take it.
- You know how to use that?
- Yeah, I think so.
All right, let's go.
- Paul, wait.
- We'll be back, mate.
Come on, let's go, Zoe.
- Look, I'm sorry...
- Stop. Stop.
I'm gonna get you home.
We'll be back
before you know it.
It's okay, babe. It's okay.
Way to go, Paul. Fucked
things up this time.
Okay, don't think like that. Come
on, that's not helping anyone.
I've been doing this his
whole fucking life.
I always get him into shit.
He always pays for it.
Well, despite all that,
you're his big brother.
So right now he's counting on you
to get him out of this. Okay?
Wait, wait!
Holy shit.
- Come on.
- We got to find a way around.
- Michael?
- Stay quiet.
- We'll loop around.
- Oh, God. Okay, go. Go, go-go.
Zoe, Zoe! Come on.
Shit. Guys.
The radiation's getting worse.
Let's go.
What is that? Look.
Holly shit.
- Will any of them start?
- No, babe, the batteries would be dead.
We might be able to find some cables, though.
Check the cars. Let's go!
Oh, fuck.
Wait! Wait!
Jesus! What the fuck?
- Who would shoot at a bus?
- I don't know, babe.
The guards?
These are exit holes.
Whatever was shooting was
shooting from the inside out.
- Can we just find these cables, please?
- Yeah.
Paul?
Amanda, there's
shells everywhere.
Maybe there's a gun in here.
Well, let's look.
Okay, wait, no. No. Come on, let's
get back to Michael and Zoe.
What if something's back there?
Goddamn it.
Nothing.
Oh, shit!
You okay?
Yeah.
Come on.
- Any bullets?
- No.
- It's broken, it won't fire.
- Look.
It works.
That's a piece of
a guard uniform.
Oh, let's get out of here.
Let's go.
What?
- Is it the same one?
- Oh, yeah!
- Will it work? Do you think it'll work?
- I think so.
- Are you fucking kidding me?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. Call your bro.
Hey, Natalie? This is Paul.
Are you guys there?
Yeah, we're here.
Where are you guys?
You're not gonna believe this.
We got cables for the van.
When are you coming back?
Uh, we're heading back now.
Uh, how's my brother doing?
He's fine. Please hurry back.
'Cause we want to get
the fuck out of here.
Come on, come on!
Hey, Chris? You hang in there, buddy.
We're coming back for you right now!
We're on our way.
Come on, Zoe!
I can't run!
- Go! Go, go, go!
- Oh, my God!
This way. Here, here, here!
All right, come on, come on!
Come on!
You're good, babe.
You gotta go! You gotta go.
Keep moving, come on! Come on!
- You've gotta go!
- All right, all right.
Come on, come on.
Zoe, you've gotta
keep moving, babe!
- Zoe, it's okay.
- Come on, Zoe.
Yes!
- Come on, Zoe!
- You can do it, Zoe! Come on!
- Keep moving!
- Zoe, come on!
Oh, shit!
'Zoe! 'Zoe!
- Good. Here.
- Get back.
Michael!
Get him out!
Get him up.
- Oh, my leg! My leg!
- Are you okay?
- It's just a scratch. It's okay.
- Get him up. Let's get him up.
Pull me up!
- Come on!
- We gotta move!
- Look at me! Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
Guys, come on. Let's get
the fuck out of here!
Damn it!
How's the leg?
Yeah, I'm all right, mate. I
just want to get us out of here.
Chris should be in
Moscow right now.
Exactly, but he's not.
So tell me what you know so we
can figure out what is going on.
Just urban legend, man.
They say this place
isn't really abandoned.
Well, obviously, the radiation
hasn't killed everything.
- I don't believe any of that shit.
- Why not can't you believe it?
There's so much that's
been going on...
There's people gotta be
out here doing this shit.
- Think about it!
- There has to be something. He's right.
- I mean, think about it.
- Chris.
Uri. That thing in the kitchen.
What was that?
And I swear there was something
in a photo I took the other day.
I didn't think anything
of it at the time, but...
- See? The photo.
- It was a shadow...
It didn't make sense at the time,
nothing had happened then.
Listen. Listen, okay?
- Zoe, come on.
- Come on, let's go!
What? This is where we were.
- Did they get it started?
- And they wouldn't call us?
- Natalie?
- Wait, look! Over here.
What? Is that from the van?
Oh, my God.
What the fuck?
Oh, fuck. Oh, fuck.
Chris!
Fuck!
- Chris!
- Whoa! Keep it down, mate.
Hey, come here!
- Chris!
- Hey, guys! It's recording.
What, what?
I don't know. It's Chris.
- What are you talking about?
- Just listen.
- I love you, Natalie.
- I love you, too, baby.
- I love you so much.
- I know.
I just need you to know that.
I was gonna wait
'til Moscow, but...
No, babe, wait till Moscow.
We're gonna be there tomorrow...
And then you can do
everything as planned, okay?
I know, but I just...
What was that?
Babe, grab the camera.
Shine it over here.
- Is that them?
- I don't know.
- Can you see anything?
- I don't see anybody.
- Is it Paul?
- I don't know.
- What the fuck is happening? No...
- Keep it down.
- Chris!
- Keep your shit together!
Stay the fuck away from me!
Shit! Just keep it down.
- I'm not leaving my brother!
- He's not here.
- Chris!
- What was that?
- Chris? Chris? Chris!
- Please, be quiet.
Shit!
Chris!
We can't leave them. We can't leave them.
We need to find them.
We need to find them!
Please! Let's go!
Please, Michael, we
need to find them.
- Fucking hell!
- Please!
There, through there.
Careful.
Oh, Chris!
Natalie?
Is that Chris?
Chris?
Come on, Zoe.
Baby, we have to, he's got the gun.
Come on.
Chris?
Nat?
- He's not here.
- I heard him. I heard him.
- Paul! We've got to go!
- We can't stay here. Let's go.
Come on, please? Please,
mate, we'll find him.
I'm sorry. Come on.
Ri-in!
Natalie!
Come on. Come on, nat, come on!
Oh, Jesus!
Come on! This way, this way!
I got her! I got her! Okay,
you're okay, baby. You're okay.
Michael?
I got you. It's okay, it's okay.
It's a fucking map. Look!
Natalie, where's Chris?
Paul!
What happened to my brother?
While we're going this
way, he's in there!
Hey, leave her alone!
Shit.
Natalie, where's Chris?
The people... they got him.
That's the road we came in on.
So then we came onto the checkpoint,
and that's another checkpoint.
And we're here. Hey, there's
another checkpoint!
It's close. We can get there. We'll
find help and come back. I promise.
- I can't leave yet.
- I understand, but we got to go.
I'm not leaving
without my brother!
We need to! We don't even
know if Chris is still...
Don't you fucking say that!
Give me the gun! Back off! Back off!
I'm sorry, mate. We want to help you.
We'll find your brother, I promise,
but we gotta go. We need help.
- Please? Please?
- Paul, Paul?
No, Paul!
We're gonna find Chris but we are
no good to him if we're dead, okay?
Listen to me! Listen
to me, Paul, okay?
We're gonna go find help, and
then we're gonna come back...
And we're gonna get
your brother, okay?
Fuck. We need to get out of here.
Show me the map again.
Right now, I need you
to get it together.
For everyone else's
sake and mine.
All right?
Come on!
That doesn't make sense.
The radiation's getting worse.
We've got to keep going. Come on.
We've got to keep going, come on!
Zoe, come on.
- Here, Michael, it doesn't make sense.
- What do you mean?
Because the map says that...
- Zoe, come on. We gotta go that way.
- ...we're supposed to be here. No, but look.
It says that this way
is supposed to be...
Michael, look at it, it stops!
- Then we have to go back.
- Which way do we have to go?
- If we go back here...
- I know it's not. Zoe, Zoe, please?
- Michael, no, we have to go!
- Guys, guys!
What the fuck?
Wait!
Hello?
What are you saying?
Natalie!
Oh, my God!
No!
- Where is she?
- She's gone!
Natalie!
Listen, listen, listen!
This way, this way!
Zoe, stay in front of me.
Holy shit! That's a guard!
- Oh, my God.
- Go, go, go!
Natalie?
- Shit!
- We've got to go.
Nat!
- Where is she?
- I don't know, I don't know!
Oh, fuck. Oh, fuck.
Move, move, move! Come on!
Michael! Michael!
- Fuck, there's too many!
- Come on!
Keep going, keep going.
Here, there.
Hurry the fuck up!
Come on.
Come on!
Boxes! Shut the fucking door!
Push! Push!
- Come on, come on.
- Ah, they're coming!
- Kick it!
- There's another room back here!
Michael, come on!
Zoe, just get going! Go, go!
Michael!
- Go, get in, get in.
- Michael!
Zoe, get inside!
- Come on! Close the door.
- Michael!
- Push it! Push it!
- It's stuck!
Michael, get in! Get in!
Michael!
He's trapped in there!
He can't get out!
No, we have to go.
Go!
Zoe, Zoe, Zoe, Zoe.
It's okay. It's okay.
- No, no, no, no, Zoe!
- Get up, Zoe, come on.
I got you, I got you. Come on.
What is this place?
Shit.
Not down. Not down.
Fuck!
Go, go, go, go, go! Go!
Oh, fuck. Put the light on!
Zoe.
Put the fucking lighten!
Put the fucking light on!
This must be where
they were living.
Keep moving. Come
on, keep moving.
Chris? Chris?
Chris?
Go, go, go!
Which way?
Come on, I'll help you.
- Paul, go!
- Give me your hand. Come on.
- Oh, my God! They're coming!
- Give me your hand!
Come on, come on!
No! "Go!"
Don't let go, Zoe!
No!
No! No!
Up here, up here.
Come on, come on, come on!
Paul?
I let them all go.
It's my fault.
Come on, come on. We
can still find them.
We can still find them.
Come on, let's just go. We can
still find them. Come on.
Please? Just take my hand.
Come on.
We gotta get outta here.
There's something
wrong with my eyes.
Oh, fuck.
Hey, my face is burning.
Fuck, you look all blurry.
What is that?
Oh, shit! Oh, shit!
Come on! Come on! Please, hurry!
- Fuck! Everything's blurry.
- I know. Okay, I got you.
We gotta find a way out of here
before the radiation kills us.
- Are you okay?
- -Yeah, go. I'm fine.
Careful. Okay.
Oh, no.
I'm so sorry, Amanda.
No.
Amanda, we can't stay here.
We can't stay here.
We have to go.
And I can't leave without you.
So please, let's just go.
- Wait.
- A way out.
Oh, fuck.
Holy shit.
No!
Run! Run!
I can't see anything.
I can't see... Help!
- Help!
Help!
- We need help!
- Help!
Please!
Stop! Don't come any closer!
Help us, please!
Stop!
- Please, help us!
- Please, stop!
- No!
- Please!
Hello? Hello? Can you hear me?
What is your name?
Where are you taking me?
Ow, my face!
It's okay. How did you
get into Pripyat?
There were people.
They were chasing us.
Yes, patients, victim of radiation.
They escaped.
You saw them, yes?
They killed my friends.
- Anyone else know you're here?
- No.
Where are you taking me?
What is this place?
We're in the hospital. We're
taking you to doctor.
What is the status of the
patients that escaped?
We got them all.
And the Americans?
All dead, except for this one.
- Where did you find her?
- Outside the reactor.
We can't let her go.
She's seen them.
My skin is burning.
You were inside reactor.
It's extremely dangerous.
Okay...
We will help.
- No, no, no!
- Go! Go!
Who's there?