Newspaper.
Newspaper, today's news.
Hi Joe.
Hi James.
Where are you going?
Dad, I saw your picture.
You used to plait your hair.
Qing Dynasty was still in power when I was
studying abroad.
The RC Government then ordered people to
cut their plait.
Still conservative people
can't accept that China's changed.
Aren't we going to Wu Dang Mt?
The train will set off in 2 hours.
Why are we here in the leased territory?
Heard that the thing we've been looking for
is here. I have to find out.
Dad, what's so important?
Wait here. I'll be right back.
Wang, take care of her.
You said you won't leave me.
Don't worry.
I won't ever leave you.
- Are you Prof.Tang?
- Yes.
Please.
Prof. Tang, thanks for coming to examine it.
You're welcome.
I've studied it for years.
I'm very glad to be able to see it.
Prof.Tang, nice to meet you.
You too, Mr. Paul Chen.
You're famous for collecting goodies
worldwide.
Now you've even got Xuan Tian Sword.
It was made two thousand years ago.
Thanks to its mysterious power
Tang became a magnificent country.
Prof.Tang, please.
It was made of meteoric stone
that has an unique magnetic field.
It belonged to a mysterious clan
but they lost it after being wiped out in wars.
Said it appeared once on Wu Dang Mt.
Your Highness, you can have it for 300000
dollars.
If you bring it back to China, it'll be worth a lot
more.
Prof.Tang, you...
Seven spirits on the mountain. Zhenjing
sleeps on Tiandan.
Wushou hidden outside Ba Mai Cave.
Precious bead of Lei Huo on the clouds.
Seems like it's true.
This Sword is only one of the 7 Treasures.
What did you say, 7 Treasures?
Is this a treasure map?
Tang Yunlong, what are you up to?
I should be asking you.
This Xuan Tian Sword is fake.
Paul Chen, dare you fool me!
You guys could be in cahoots.
Whatever...
you've destroyed my sword.
You've got to pay for it.
Go get the map.
Wang, let's go.
Dad, you in a fight?
I'm fine. Let's go to the station, hurry.
while men are fighting at the borders.
They do the weaving at home.
They farm on days and weave at nights.
They work all day and all night.
So soldiers have things to eat and clothes to
wear.
Look at me now if you don't believe.
Look at all of them.
Our shoes, socks, and clothes
Ms. Why staring at me like that?
Are you fond of me?
You represent Beijing to attend the WDM
Martial Arts Competition?
I'm the most handsome martial artist in Beijing
and Tianjin.
Pretty things on a pretty girl.
Leave her alone.
Don't be afraid.
You're going to Hubei, what for?
To steal.
Interesting.
Steal what?
Steal an invitation card.
Like this one.
You want to steal my invitation card?
You want to go to the competition instead of
me?
You should either go home or go to the
hospital.
Dare you talk to me like that.
Who's going to represent Wu Dang to attend
the competition?
Has our Mentor decided yet?
Bailong, he's sleeping. Don't bother him. Let's
go.
Not yet arrived.
Who's he waiting for?
Watch out, Ning.
You okay?
Go.
What a careless guys!
Popped up out of nowhere.
What's wrong?
It's down. We have to continue on foot.
Okay.
Dad, was that a Taoist?
I think so.
I think he's kind. Let's go.
Shui Heyi, you're late.
Bro, I...
Why so little water?
Bro, I came across a motorbike on the way.
It almost ran me over so...
Don't be lying.
You know how strict Bailong is, right?
Go clean out the grass over there.
Sure.
Hi, we're attending the competition.
Master Xie's gone.
- Let's go, hurry.
- What happened?
Master Xie's gone.
Our Mentor's gone.
Excuse me.
His heartbeat has stopped.
Our Mentor's gone. We're all sad.
Life's short.
I think he's gone to Heaven.
Who is he?
He's Tang Yunlong, the sponsor for the
competition.
His vital signs are all gone
but I guess he's breathing like a tortoise.
Scientifically speaking, he's hibernating.
Hibernating.
Yeah, sort of in a conscious sleep.
He's so unpredictable.
Master Xie... Xie's awake.
Master, you're awake.
Thank God. You're here finally.
Guys, Shui Heyi will represent Wu Dang.
Awesome. You made him awake.
It's you.
Shui Heyi's a secular man.
He knows just a little bit of martial arts.
He's not a senior. He can't.
Right, Master Xie.
I'm not skiIful at all.
I just want to spend time with my mother
and take care of her illness.
I can't represent Wu Dang to attend the
competition.
The useless are the most useful. Nothing is
impossible.
Master, if you let him, we'll lose.
This event takes place once every 500 years.
We can't afford to lose.
If you're too desperate to win, you'll lose.
Go get ready for the competition.
No. I should talk to my mother first.
Is there a treasure map in your hands?
No, there isn't.
You're here to steal something?
I'm sorry, Taoist Master, I'm lost.
Is this Xiao Yao Palace?
I'm not a Taoist Master.
A Taoist Master's over there, Ma'am.
Hi there.
I'm the representative of Beijing-Tianjin.
I'm here for the competition.
My brother's sick.
So I came instead of him.
My name's Tianxin, not Ma'am.
To celebrate 500th anniversary of the
re-establishment of...
Wu Long Palace on Wu Dang Mt.
We're holding this competition for Taoist
juniors
from all over the country
and overseas Chinese organizations.
It's to promote Taoist martial arts
and encourage youngsters
to communicate and learn from each other.
Now, please welcome Wei Chunyang for Kong
Dong Clan, Sichuan.
His opponent is from Beijing-Tianjin of Henan
and Hebei
the representative of Long Men Clan, Tianxin.
I don't fight women. Go home.
This could be the biggest mistake you've ever
made.
That's called Paocui.
If you get hit by that, you'll be in trouble.
If you're up against a man like that
don't fight, just admit defeat.
You think she's going to lose?
Good.
Is she playing Tai Chi? What is that?
Is that Zhang Sangfeng's Changsijing?
Not quite.
Changsijing?
Good.
Tianxin won.
Second match,
Tangning for the ATA
- Dear,
- versus Wanglei for Shang Qing
Clan, Taiwan.
you're here to learn.
Take it easy.
- Taiyi Five Elements Form versus Silken Palms.
- Admit defeat if you can't win.
Dad, you've said it many times.
Alright, I'll give you signs.
Tangning won.
Good.
It hurts?
Hang in there. I'll be gentle.
Dad, was I great back there?
Dare you mention it again.
I told you to take it easy, didn't I?
You played it hard. I was worried.
Why did you tell me not to be serious
while you're indeed serious about everything?
Alright, it's late.
I shall go back to sleep. Good night.
Dad,
what did mom come down with?
I wonder how you got to know her.
I told you, didn't I?
I used to plait my hair.
I met your mother in a Chinese restaurant
while I was studying in America.
Alright, it's late. Go to bed.
Dad, you're here with a treasure map.
I think you're up to something.
Are we here just to watch and learn Kung fu?
I'll get you a boyfriend.
Don't be kidding.
Alright, don't be mad.
Golden Palace. Nan Yan.
Seven spirits on the mountain. Wu Long
Palace.
Dad.
You should've got married and had kids if your
dad was here.
I'm so weak here.
Mom, you know
we're here on Wu Dang Mt, a very spiritual
place.
You will get well for sure.
All I want now is to get you a wife.
Dad, you promised me
that we'd be like partners.
I'm not your dad.
- What's going on?
- It's okay, mom.
Be calm.
What happened?
- Who is that?
It's you.
Why? You know her?
She's Taoist Xie's guest.
What a girl. Son, you don't have to be a monk
now.
Dear, you alright?
Tianxin, Xuan Tian Sword is a holy thing of
ours.
It was made of meteoric stone, and powerful.
Your dad looked for it for years, but couldn't
find it.
When his body was discovered in the desert
there was such a bead in his hand.
It could be related with the Sword's
whereabouts.
You must finish what you dad didn't when you
grow up.
You theif.
Got a partner huh?
Hurry.
Dear, you're awake.
You fell from the top.
I was worried
that you might be paralyzed like me.
Sorry for ruining your roofs.
My dad will pay for it.
No need. I've fixed it.
Aren't you the representative of Wu Dang?
I'm one of the participants.
I won a match today.
We may compete against each other in the
future.
I won't attend the competition.
Why?
I have to take care of my mom here.
You should get married soon.
Then you don't have to look after me yourself.
Dear, what's your name?
Tangning.
Ning, this is my son.
His name's Shui Heyi, not yet married.
How about you?
Mom, she's still young. Don't embarrass her.
She's not I guess.
Mom, time to sleep.
Son, you two are a good match.
I'll fall asleep soon.
You have a good talk. I won't overhear you.
Alright, sleep.
Ms, you must be lost.
You can call me Tangning.
Mosquitoes are bad insects.
Still they're living things like us.
Plus, I promised
not to kill so mom will get well.
When it gets cool at nights, mosquitoes will go
naturally.
We humans are part of the nature.
So are mosquitoes and everything else.
Do we secular beings have to learn Taoism?
I'm stupid anyway.
Taoist Xie taught me how to reunite with
Heaves
and to meditate so as to feel life.
I just can't.
Can you?
I feel like...
I'm losing it.
It's you. Aren't you the sponsor?
Glad that I was there.
You would've been caught if not for me.
Nonsense. I saved you.
You wouldn't have escaped if not for my last
powerful strike.
You're here to steal the Sword?
It belongs to my family.
I've been looking for it for years.
Good.
There're 7 treasures here on Wu Dang Mt.
Let's work together and steal them.
You'll get the Sword, and I'll have the rest.
You know how good Bailong is, don't you?
You can't pull it off alone.
Let's work together alright?
Why not? Our motives are different anyway.
I'm here to retrieve what's mine, but you're
here to steal.
I wonder...
why you're here with your daughter. You
almost got her killed.
What? Got her killed?
She mistook me as you back there.
She followed me and fell off the cliff.
Don't worry, she probably...
Here's Wu Dang Mt. Any illness can't be
cured.
Ning.
Dad, what's wrong with you?
You okay? Did you fall off the cliff?
Yes, but I know martial arts.
I'm fine. See?
I was worried sick.
Liukun from Da Mao CIan, Yunnan, won.
Next match...
Li Xuande from Quan Zhen Clan, North Korea
versus Zhangyang from Feng Lai Clan,
Shangdong.
Li Xuande won.
Last match, Tangning for the ATA
Ning, remember admit defeat if you can't win.
- versus Tianxin from Long Men Clan, Beijing-Tianjin.
- Alright.
I will fight hard.
You should do the same. Don't let your dad
down.
Come on.
I admit defeat.
You're better.
Tangning won.
You were lucky. Where are you going?
It's a secret.
Prof.Tang, did you...?
I lost. What a pity!
Sorry, did I hurt you?
Ms Tianxin, did you sleep well last night?
No. I had bad dreams.
Mom, hang in there.
Shui Heyi.
Mom, we're almost there, hold on.
If my guess is right
Bailong is suspicious of both of us.
That's why you deliberately admitted defeat.
You want to act in the broad daylight.
Bailong is kind of busy now.
The Sword is not guarded. We have a better
chance.
The next line indicates our next target.
Zhenjing and Tiandan...
Why not going to steal the Sword?
I'm not that stupid. If you get the Sword, you'll
be gone.
Zhenjing could mean Laozi's Daodejing.
It's in Xiao Yao Palace.
Another treasure is Tiandan
that's the answer to all illnesses, made by
Physician Zhang.
It's hidden...
The Prince should rest in the bed of Dragon.
No big deal.
It's just Tiandan.
Poetry is nothing difficult.
Let's split up then.
Alright.
If you think
you can do it alone.
How about this? You go get Zhenjing,
I'll go for Tiandan.
Why should I go for Zhenjing?
I've checked.
Only two Taoists to guard Xiao Yao Palace. It
should be easy.
The biggest mistake you've ever made...
I'm kidding.
Everyone here is a Master. You better watch
out.
See who'll get it first before the sunset.
Mom, you're awake.
Tangning...
Ma'am.
Now she's physically well.
She was just mentally sick.
Alright, you can get off the bed and have a
walk.
Have a walk?
Give it a try.
Mom, have a try.
One, two, three.
Mom, you can walk now.
- Sit down first.
- I can walk now.
Thank God. You're so lucky.
Your mom's all right now.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
Now you can focus on the competition.
I...
No need to be a monk now. Go enjoy the
competition.
Should I thank Taoist Xie.
Yeah I know.
Who is it?
Get him.
Freeze.
Thanks a lot.
Master, I'm Zixu from Jiu Tian
Palace on Hua Mt.
Can we have a talk?
Can we have a talk, Master?
Master, be frank with you.
Someone stole Laozi's Zhenjing from us.
I think since...
Yinjing... you have Yangjing right?
Our Yinjing has been stolen.
So has your Yangjing right?
I've got you.
I've got you, fool.
Why no guards?
I shouldn't have wasted my breath.
Could Zhenjing be in this place?
Could this be a trap?
What is this? Such a piece of cake.
I shouldn't have wasted time practicing
for so long.
Tang Yunlong, you're late.
You lost.
Tianxin, you won.
You're injured.
You too.
The Taoist you mentioned was awesome.
He almost got me.
Here. It's rusted.
What's the use of it?
Look.
What's our next target?
Wushou hidden outside Ba Mai Cave.
You said it's simple. Tell me what it means.
It's simple.
Yeah.
Ba Mai Cave... I think it means two treasures
here.
Look... Ba Mai in a cave...
Wushou, it could mean the black...
Shouwu.
Wu Dang Mt is a holy place.
Said there're two thousand-year-old
human-like Shouwu.
Only two? I guess there's a lot.
They're like a couple fighting a lot.
That's why I hate men. I Iike being single.
You women are annoying. I like freedom.
We could never be on the same wavelength.
I guess you'd sell all your treasures soon
after you get them.
I just want to go home.
I'm not that greedy, selfish
and money-minded as you think.
Alright, don't waste my time here.
You think you're righteous?
You said the Sword belongs to your family.
Prove it.
It does belong to my family.
It is mine, believe it or not.
I'll get the Sword even without you.
Yes, I can.
Sleeping Kung fu is the best of Internal Martial
Arts.
Zhuangzi dreams of being a butterfly
A butterfly dreams of being Zhuangzi.
Our ancestor, Chenbo, once spent 800 years
sleeping
during the best times of Song Dynasty.
Su Qier learned in his sleep
how to fight in Luohan style.
A day will pass in a blink of an eye.
A sleeping fairy will forget the time.
Concentrate on breaths and be mindful.
Let Qi run into Xuanqiao and breathe with the
nature.
That's What Master Zhang Sangfeng lectured
on sleeping Kung fu.
You should keep it in mind.
Something's up in Wo Long Palace.
Master's asleep. What happened?
We seven tried to chase him down but failed.
Got to tell Master about it.
Someone stole something from Wo Long
Palace.
What did he steal?
Nothing seems to be missing
but we saw him
steal something like a sphere.
Ma'am, why did you let Shui attend the
competition?
We're grateful to Taoist Xie. That's to thank
him.
I dreamed of you and Heyi at the altar, getting
married.
Getting what?
Nothing.
Ning, go open the box beside my bed.
Nice. I've never tried Mandarin clothes.
Try them on then.
What do you think?
You picked the right one.
It's fated. This wedding dress is from my
mom.
Nice.
Seems like I've disturbed you.
Why are you in my mom's dress?
She gave it to me. Nice?
Yes. Where is my mom?
She's asIeep. I'm here for you.
I'm practicing Kung fu. Thanks for taking care
of my mom.
My pleasure.
She sleeps like a baby.
I told her a story then she fell asleep.
You and your mom are close. So are my dad
and I.
He's been teaching me
how to fight and live well.
He did some researches.
He thinks Taoism is pretty scientific.
I've said too much I guess.
Don't worry. I'll come visit your mom as long
as I have time.
Show me your hand.
Close your eyes.
I once used it to help Taoist Xie out.
I'm giving it to you.
What's wrong?
It's just a little caterpillar. Why so scared?
Liukun for Da Mao Clan, Yunnan
versus Tangning for the ATA.
Honey.
Dad, I feel confident with you here.
Tang Yunlong, come with me.
Why? I can't leave now.
Look over there.
They're looking for you.
Don't worry. I'll admit defeat if I can't win.
You guys go.
Hurry.
Boss, Tang Yunlong's over there.
Follow him. Kill him if necessary.
Okay.
I'm fine. Don't worry.
Wake up, will you?
We're being followed.
They're not from Wu Dang. Their shoes are
different.
Never mind. Let's go.
Tangning won.
This should be Ba Mai Cave.
Lots of people to welcome us.
You sneak in through Long Tou Xiang.
Let's split up and lead them to the woods on
the left.
Stop right there.
Stop. Don't run.
Let's go.
This is Ba Mai PaIace, not Ba Mai Cave.
It can't be wrong.
It must have something to do with Ba Mai.
They're all broken statues, nothing precious.
It's got to be around. Let's look for it.
You think you could fool me?
I've been waiting for you, Prof.Tang.
Go ahead.
I...
I may lose to a woman.
I won't tear my clothes up and pretend I'm hurt.
You go look for the treasure.
Hurry, please.
Seriously,
you know what Ba Mai means?
Ba Mai means 8 extraordinary channels of the
body.
Got it?
Take that.
Got it.
Tianxin, I've got the gold figure.
Tang YunIong, surprised that I'm still alive?
Sorry for hurting your leg.
You know you owe me much huh? Give me
that gold figure.
And your bag?
Get him.
You take it and go. I'll take care of them.
I won't leave without you.
Let's fight then.
Watch out.
Your sleeping Kung fu is lousy. You'll lose.
It's just that I'm stupid.
I'm only here to want to fix my mom's illness.
I'd like to have that caterpillar back.
Not afraid?
No.
Here.
I'm not afraid of it
because I know it'll become a butterfly one
day.
Now it can only crawl, but soon it'll fly
freely in the sky.
It's like going to another space.
Will men go to another space
while dreaming?
Dreams, butterflies, another space?
Just imagine your mom's recovered, and
you're relieved
like a leaf
floating in the air.
Like a butterfly flying to wherever you want.
Thank you. I feel so much better now.
Reunite with the nature.
What a beautiful leaf.
Let me see.
No.
Shui, you think dying is
like sleeping?
I mean, if I die one day
will I meet you in another space?
What are you talking about?
I have a genetic strange disease.
It can't be fixed.
My mom and grandma all died of it
when they were young.
I'm not afraid anyway. I just don't want to be
made useless.
You won't.
You won't die young either.
Alright, let's drop it.
I have a wish as a healthy girl here.
Let's present a great match tomorrow
like you and I attending the graduation
ceremony alright?
Sure.
You're a man.
You should never lie.
We've got three of them.
Fourth line... Lei Huo...
it should be Lei Huo Palace.
On the clouds... it could mean
clouds upon the top of the mountain.
The Big Dipper.
Shouwu hidden outside Ba Mai Cave.
Here we're outside Ba Mai Cave.
We should be seeing a lot of Shouwu here.
Isn't Shouwu precious?
No precious things will grow all over here.
Are you Shouwu? Are you?
Actually we're looking for the spirit of Wu
Dang Mt.
Rumor has it that it attaches to the roots of
Shouwu.
Like human vessels connecting with the whole
Wu Dang Mt.
More amazingly...
it can communicate with us after it takes
human shape.
Don't you think
it was too easy to get all of this?
Plus, your map and mine are basically the
same.
You have doubts about the map?
Maybe I'm too paranoid.
I've lost my faith in men and things.
At least you believe in Tiandan.
I believed in science
not anything that can't be proved by science.
But later I realized
there're things that can't be explained by
science.
Lots of diseases can't be fixed by science
either.
I really have no clue
how to find the spirit of Shouwu.
You said it can communicate with us.
You can try to locate it with your heart.
It's only a rumor.
Like you said,
science can't explain a lot of things.
The Big Dipper.
I remember my grandpa used to say...
when a man dies,
he'll become a star in the sky
to watch his beloved.
So I'd always like...
to wish upon a star.
You try it.
It shows up.
You must be sincere.
According to Compendium of Materia Medica
Male Shouwu is red. Female one is white.
They're indeed like a couple.
Got them.
Smells nice.
You're here, Ning.
Where's Shui?
He went to pick firewood.
Please God, let Tangning get well soon.
Or pass her illness to me, please.
Hungry? Let's go.
I'm here for my father, Prof.Tang.
Could you please call him out?
We're looking for him too. Go back to your
room. Don't come out.
He won't be back tonight.
He's fine, but he's worried about you
so he let me come.
I know. I'll take good care of myself.
Tianxin, I'm so lucky.
I'll enter the final tomorrow.
Could my dad come and watch me?
Ning, he's doing the stealing for you.
You know?
Yes.
Lots of Taoists are searching for him.
My dad's a great man.
But now
he's doing the stealing for me.
Have a rest. You've got a match tomorrow.
I'm afraid.
Do you believe in miracles?
I used to think that with faith and hopes
I could live on well.
Now I've reaIized that
they can't really change what's become.
Tianxin...
my dad...
didn't believe in miracles at all
but now he's buying it for me.
I guess you've had a hard life
just like your dad.
He may
appear to be happy on the outside
while he's really worried inside.
Tianxin
could you do me a favor
and fulfill my one last wish?
Don't say something bad.
Sure, as long as you promise to live well.
Alright, please marry my dad.
Ever since my mom passed away
I've seldom seen smiles upon his face.
I realize that he's kind of happy with you.
I like to be free you know?
I don't think I can help you with that.
I'm afraid.
What if I have to leave him one day?
I really don't want to leave him alone.
Stop crying.
Your dad won't be left alone.
Here you are at such a high altitude.
Let's go back down and talk.
Go back down, you serious?
Tang Yunlong and that girl have disappeared.
Are they gone with those treasures?
I don't think so since his daughter's still here.
I suggest we kill him and take one or two of his
treasures.
No, I want all 7 of them.
They're more precious than any wealth and
power in the world.
I made treasure maps and gave them out.
That's why Tang Yunlong's here.
So is the long lost Ding Feng Bead.
Shui, finally we're here in a match.
Ning, I don't want to fight you. I'll admit defeat.
You promised me.
You're a man. You should never lie.
Stop.
Stop it.
Ning.
I wish to stay here as long as I can.
Let's carry on.
Okay.
It's just a sword made of stone.
It has an unique magnetic field
unlike anything on Earth. Apologies.
Look, this is the mark of our family.
I'll go get the lightning rod on top.
Then all we need is Ding Feng Bead.
Don't go yet.
It attracts lightning. It's dangerous.
It's made to pass voltage currents to ground.
That's why the Golden Palace has never been
struck by lightning
in the last 500 years.
You've got the Sword. You going home now?
I will, but not now.
I promised Ning that I won't go till her illness is
cured.
She knows already?
Thought I could keep her in the dark
and let her live happily.
She pretended that she didn't know
just not to make you worry.
Ning's a good girl.
Fetch me the gold needle.
Ning.
Taoist Xie.
Not an internal injury. This is a weird illness.
She's bleeding all over inside.
Taoist Xie.
You could cure my mom.
I guess you can cure her too.
It's all about fortune and fate.
Ning.
- Dad.
- Ning.
Dad's here,
Ning.
Dad, I admitted defeat.
I...
Can't you cure her with Tiandan?
What are you waiting for?
Haven't got all 7 of them. Don't know if it's
going to work.
Don't hesitate. Try it now.
Tang YunIong, you're here for your daughter.
Let's set it straight then.
I have to save my daughter first.
All the treasures should be mine.
Give them to me.
Or I'll kill your daughter.
This is what I need, right?
Bailong, this lightning rod is a holy thing.
You crazy?
I'm not.
Things are going as I planned.
This is fate. This is to reunite with the nature.
You want to the Mentor huh?
No way.
I want to be more than a Mentor.
You've got me wrong.
I've planned this for years
to want to get Ding Feng Bead.
That's the necklace from my dad.
Is that the Ding Feng Bead?
Back then your dad Tianyu and I
came to Wu Dang
to want to retrieve Xuan Tian Sword that
belongs to us.
Then he discovered my secret
of wanting to collect all 7 treasures to be a
holy spirit.
So he decided to ruin it by stealing
the Ding Feng Bead from me.
He just never thought
I had collected 6 of them already.
I made a fake treasure map
and surprisingly his daughter presented
the Ding Feng bead herself.
You...
You have to take the right course
to be a holy spirit.
Bailong, what you've done is all evil.
Ning's not making it.
Ning.
I'm afraid.
Don't be.
7 treasures will make me a holy spirit.
Yin and Yang are not balancing here.
A nightmare has truly come.
No one's going to stop me now.
Tiandan's working.
I'll soon be a holy spirit.
Taoist Xie, Ning's not making it.
She needs Tiandan now.
Sleeping Kung fu will make you
see emptiness and feel free
like Bailong is feeling now.
Bailong, no one dares lie to me.
Got to get Tiandan back.
You really want to try?
A sleeping fairy will forget the time.
Concentrate on breaths and be mindful.
Let Qi run into Xuanqiao and
breathe with the nature.
Master.
Take Tiandan and save Ning now.
You're a secular being.
Not a match for me.
Dear.
Dad.
Ning, you okay?
Tianxin.
Tang Yunlong, you're a strong man
but you seem weak every time
you talk about your daughter.
The Sword...
I'll leave it here on Wu Dang Mt.
I'm not going home anyway.
The Sword has found its home here.
This is where my heart belongs too.
Thank you.
Tianxin.
Is there a treasure map in your hands?
No, there isn't.
You're here to steal the Sword?
It belongs to my family.
The biggest mistake you've ever made...
I'm kidding.
Everyone here is a Master.
You better watch out.
I remember my grandpa used to say...
when a man dies,
he'll become a star in the sky
to watch his beloved.
Tianxin.