London 1939
You saw that? He could not play it.
It has nearly nine years. But may not move their feet so il.
You are a boy. I am an officer and a gentleman.
Well, certainly you're an officer.
Come back.
You are worried?
Of course not.
You'll come back.
These last three weeks have been the best week of my life.
I met you and ... I love you.
What is it? Nothing.
What were you saying? Jack?
It can wait. Jack!
Germany four months later. Camp soldiers Biberach.
He is free.
Let's go.
Du-te.
Fuck.
Come on, faster!
Where? Well you're an officer.
... South or West.
Calm down hell once and let go.
McGrade, where are you going?
Collins! Oh God! Collins!
Jack! Jack's dead! Let's go!
They caught.
McGrade?
What to do now?
The border is about 80 kilometers away.
That's south.
You're right, Jack. Jack!
You have to wash.
Here.
How fast can you Jack.
McGrade ends.
We were supposed to meet somewhere.
That Dilinjon. You walk in a circle.
Let's go.
Stay where you are.
Good boy.
Sit down.
Bravo.
Do you like dogs?
I grew up with them.
I thought so.
Dogs are better than people sometimes.
Dogs not disappoint you.
Total submission. Like the army.
Let's go. We should wait until it gets dark.
I said move, corporal.
Good. There are three hours until dark.
If we take the time that has passed and our speed may not be quite as much to the border.
You have no idea what you're talking. Shut McGrade.Esti lucky you're here.
We are all lucky that we are here.
I was thinking about Coliins.
You have to forget what happened. Yes it is, old man.
And everything whereon they could do. And then in an instant everything is lost.
Who is she?
Lizy Carter.
Not even a dog. Neither departe.Frumoasa.
It's the only reason to go back. Even if only for one night.
The only thing I would have to do was to ask the Lizy Carter marriage.
Want to know why I joined the army? To fight the Germans like us.
Do not go to jail. See Captain, I was not hurt nor bottom of your army.
Some older children who play the soldiers.
He wants his face, I just want to live.
God no one wants to go back and fight.
That's Switzerland, damn either.
It's a border area. Check the entire lumea.Trebuie to see how to get around.
Let's go.
Whatever happens, do not run away.
Guards.
What's the plan, sir?
We can go there.
One by one.
Go te.O them distracting. They will shoot.
Just do one thing for me. Find it on Lizy Carter.
Hello gentlemen. Welcome to Castle Ofleckosicolditz.
My name is Fritz Werner and I'm chief officer in charge of security.
This castle will be your home throughout the war.
He was elected voi.Pentru especially for people like you.
Surely you try to escape in the future, but you can not be sure of that.
If you try you will be shot.
Eventually you give up. The sooner the better
Do you have any questions.
When I get back to England to send a picture of Buckingham Palace and Piazza Truham?
You're very kind, thank you.
Welcome, guys.
Not esteemed, is Canadian. Benning my name.
Willis. Jethrow.
Welcome. Thank you.
Beam. Switzerland.
Gentlemen, allow me to introduce our first successful escape of the war.
Corporal Nicholas McGrade.
So tomorrow we should think you take here.
I'm not going anywhere. I did datoria.Eu I'm happy here.
I'm afraid that's not possible. Why?
You can not stay here is a neutral country and you're a British soldier.
If Speaking of business, the military owes me six months' pay.
Very good.
Each station at a distance of 40 km is equipped with well-armed guards day and night
and to the border of a neutral country are 600 km.
Since you are here? Several saptamani.Bret is longer, about a month.
Where are you from? Bevorack, you? Brandenburg. I escaped with another pilot, I tecut through the gate.
About 20 km from the border I came across some Germans who apparently never heard of the Geneva Convention.
My friend was killed on the spot, I survived.
It's not as bad as it looks. The bullet passed and I did not hit any major organ.
Receive e happen, bulldog-ul.
Tomorrow morning we will try to get out of here. So I want!
Hi.
Hello. Can I get something to drink.
No, thanks. Why not?
I meet a friend.
Nicholas McGrade.
Come on do not be scared I will not bite you.
Valeri. I am pleased.
You must not be shy Valeri. What are you drinking?
Sorry I did not quite understand. I said can not you understand that the lady does not want to have anything to do with a drunk like you.
May be! As they see it, a Swiss who wants to fight.
I think the dream, the Swiss do not fight. Just sit and rub mint.
Surprise surprise.
Multumesc.Perfect.Poftim here.
How are you old? You've had bad luck.
Are you okay? I got some bad news.
It seems like that that I've beaten bar is the son of a local judge. So would not let you get away that easy.
Oh, Lord, do not you do something? Well we'll hand you over to us but
British government will give you the punishment you deserve and your file think il give you at least 10 years.
Do not despair, there are always ways to get out of these situations.
I do not believe you you did not realize one thing.
I think you're cut out for it. You have a tendency to crime.
When you arrive in London you will be contacted by Lt.Col.Fordoms a very nice bath.
I'll tell him what's up.
You planned all this.
Be happy, go home.
Dear Lizy, I write in the other camp now.
I gave the last just to get here.
It's not that bad.
The food is not even sides, so we can handle.
Others here are doing pretty good and we keep each other company.
This place is an ancient castle that looks like Dracula.
How are you? We do not receive news here than the Germans who tell us that London was bombed by Lutwafer.
Hope you're well.
Sorry I'm not very good at writing thing.
There are so many things I want to tell you that you had to have told them.
All I know is that I really miss you.
Coloum reporter? In front and to the left.
Corporal McGrade? Da.Pe here please.
I need special parts, not nonsense.
Components man! And biscuits where crackers.
Corporal McGrade, sir. Ah yes, McGrade well excellent.
Thanks Mary. Welcome to MI9 and congratulations.
The first who managed to escape from war, counting what's best for us Bunny.
Did they tell us? Who tell asshole? You were supposed to be top secret.
That is ML9, a division of the Secret Service and I ganditca want to know who McGrade if you still work together.
Wrong ... and do not forget those components.
Um unique man. Where were we?
Ah yes, we are here to help people like tine.Oameni who escaped from POW camps.
Moral.Te is very good for you in the socket. Good. How was it?
Slow.
But that house in Marseille?
That where I stayed for a week without food and acolo.Pai crowded you could not go up in a plane and send you to hell.
Unfortunately where I was bine.Din McGrade still is war and you have to do and aprt of it, we understand?
Are you clear it, Corporal McGrade? Da.Da and what else?
Yes, sir.
Bravo! E, and one more thing. From now on you'll be lieutenant McGrade.
I think after the first part of the war deserve a promotion.
Your office is right here next workshop Mr. Warren.
I would be preferred over the top.
Do you need anything else? No, thanks.
Do you have a place to stay? No, I know nimeni.Asta is the first time I come here.
I will prepare a room. You must take your uniform.
Good. I'll leave you to accustom. In fact, it is someone they know.
O Lizy Carter.
I promised a friend that I seek. I'll see what I can do.
Thank you. You're welcome, Lieutenant.
Excuse me sir. Leave me alone.
Lieutenant McGrade are head ... I mean sir.
What the hell are you doing? Fell. Of course it fell. This is and should be.
Both are separate. Beautiful shoe boots becomes.
What do you want? I'm busy.
Jesus, what's that smell?
It's natural gelatin. You can write to her on almost anything.
Silk, folds, it is easy to hide. God, you're worse than I thought.
We could use it. I was also a POW.
Yes I know. Why do you think they are so reasonable?
Want to see my compasses? Sure.
This?
It is a channel. Yes I know.
And there's latrine. Come! January Meet Jack Jack he is in January.
January is an engineer and believe that we can escape through the channel.
Let's take a look.
Can you see anything. Oh yes.
One more thing. Come.
After about 50 meters channel that is connected to the main drainage holes.
If we assume that we take on where you get to latrines and get there.
And where we go?
Unfortunately this is the only outlet that we can see.
The problem is that it is guarded 24 hours a day. You can not leave without you shoot or give way to alarm first.
It is just an option. What is it? Do something with the guard.
What? ll buy. Well, can we buy them?
There are three guards in rotation between Ala 24 hours.
The first two are motionless, but the third guard, Meisner, is a little weak.
I have a feeling about him. He's not a puppy too happy and I think he is the man you are looking for.
Want to play? I think you like to play.
I think you lost your wedding ring. I think your wife is very angry with you.
Less'll lose your ears. I'll you a bite, right?
What you need to get another ring?
Leaves. Go!
Keep the change, old man!
How did it go?
Damn! It's done.
You're a wonderful human being! That's how it is.
Are you ready? Come on.
You sure do not want to join us? Inside there got to be kidding.
Oh gosh!
Haide Jack!
Acolo.Acolo's section on prisoners. We have to take the left.
What is Willis?
Beware this thread.
Willis!
Willis, if we here we'll go to hell.
Oh, God, what ugly stinks!
Willis!
Willis can not see any way out.
Willis look!
Look up here.
We get out here.
Are you sure? Yes.
Let then skinny, you push!
Stop! Move away from the door! Hands up!
Well gentlemen.
You tried to escape.
Let us look better.
Return!
Return! Come on. What are you doing?
Oh no, God!
Do not do this, please!
Fire!
Next time will not joking.
Lieutenant McGrade girlfriend that he wanted to look for.
They were hit pretty bad last night. Yes it is.
Sleep, slept only.
Oh God help me.
Excuse me. Lieutenant sorry but we have to wait your turn.
If your house has been hit must wait about noon equipment.
If you talk to Mrs. missing persons there. You Lizy Carter?
Da, de ce?
I do not think it's time nor place but I have some information about Jack Rawles.
Jack? Around here.
Thank God.
The last letter that I have of him is of two months ago. I started to think ...
No, it's all right. He has a sprained ankle and a bump soundly, but besides this has nothing.
Sorry but how did you two meet? I escaped together.
He hit his ankle and caught the Germans. I escaped, I'm sorry.
You know where he is now? No, all I tried to find out when I returned.
I was assigned to a special unit that helps soldiers POW.
If you hear anything let me know.
I hate this. I really do not like.
Know.
But if it's any consolation, I think you do a great job.
Thank you, Lieutenant ... McGrade Nick McGrade.
I have to go. Of course.
How did you know what I look like? Jack makes us admire your picture all the time.
Jack asked me to find you. Lizy's war if you have not noticed.
I'm coming, I'm sorry but I have to go ...
Where can I find you if I find out something new? Here, we work impreuna.Mi was nice to meet you.
Thank you bothered. There was no trouble.
Bravo guys, bravo!
Calm down!
Stuff like that happens. You can not trust everyone.
I am sorry. Sure.
An offering of pace.De where did you get this? I changed something.
And that's not the only change here.
Everyone here is evadati.Se seems that the Germans have decided to put the bad guys in one place.
Aici.Oameni you everything you need to dig tunnels that break locks, anything you want.
Welcome Fugitive Academy. He escaped anyone here?
Yes, some friends last week but struggled like hell.
Who's that? It's our big celebrity. Sawyer.
A famous writer.
I did not never heard of him. Me neither.
He says he did the portrait of King before the war.
Anyway, come to know him at Le Blanc. Not a bad guy for a thief.
He will make you acquainted with some of the other guys.
That's yours.
Alright guys.
Fancy that's Johnny Barnes. Nice to meet you sir.
Is that Malon, most often can not do anything but do not catch you as you touch his books.
Rommy and Hewitt, four escapes before. Two tunnels, one of the threads and once was disguised as an officer.
Nice to meet you. Me too.
Mr. Jack Rawles. The answer is no.
But you would not even heard the question.
You've heard that you are an artist and want to draw a picture of your girlfriend, that you're willing to give me 10 shillings.
Leaves! Possible. On the other hand I came to tell you to give a new law in connection with all who are called Sawyer as
a car waiting outside to take you home.
The car that I think you missed it.
Nice try.
How much will it cost? More than you might imagine. Now become very boring.
The lighter it is silver belonged to my grandfather.
You just do not understand.
What about this ring. That's all I have.
Go away.
Good.
You can then to keep that.
Indian paint. Where did you get this?
Well, Red Barket can get everything from guards.
I thought help. Does not matter.
Wait.
Do you know what that means.
What will work? Got a photo? Not quite, not exactly.
Slightly lower.
Yes, perfect.
A big, beautiful smile.
I guess what I mean is ... more radiant.
Let's get going.
5 to 7, a little help on the table.
Deserved? Of course.
Are you going to stare at that wall for life? If you must.
What is her name? Lizy.
It would be wrong, but I like to look at Lizy and a stripped thought.
Lighten up! Are you serious? I'm serious.
You know quite well if you look at a beautiful girl can also see under clothes, in her true beauty.
Cam asa e.
So I see it when I look at that wall.
Good ziua.Buna. I'm glad I caught you.
Jill, he is Lt. McGrade. It is Jill.Imi looks good.
I was not sure if I'll remember to bring my mine.Sigur.
I'll go then. Goodbye.
You have some great news about Jack? Do you want to go for a drink?
I'm kinda tired, but if something bad happened please tell me.
There is nothing bad. In fact we think we know where he is.
Where? Let me lead you.
It is a maximum security prison, near LEIBZIG.
It looks like to stay there for longer.
But it's safe? Yes, we know.
You are you know this and know that it is safe or not.
Not so sure appreciate working simplu.Sunt asta.Desigur.
It was nice of you to come, thank you very much.
Come on, let me get you a drink. Jack is alive, we should celebrate. I do not feel desarbatorit.
Because you leave affected by everything happening around you.
Have you heard the bombing last night? Yes it was about rau.A was terrible.
I saw some things ... people died in our arms.
Their lives ... destroyed in a second.
Sorry ... you've probably heard this. "Do not let the bastards to get depressed. If I leave means they have won."
It may not be dead but it's like you are.
I'm sure it's a pub just around the corner. I am very tired. Thanks for coming, Lieutenant.
Good. Tell me Nick. Please.
E de la Lizy.
Mcgrade returned and told where we are. We know we're safe.
What he said damn corporal. There's a corporal, but is Lt. McGrade.
I wish him luck. At least he got rid us.
We'll do it we must.
I reusit.Ce? I found the solution.
Hewitt give me the binoculars guy, that all play voi.Vino Jack, I want to show you something.
That window from the third floor does not have lights on at night. It means that the room is unused.
Watch reflection. You see her? Not quite, not exactly.
We came for help.
Do you have a light?
I think reflects that means that there is a window in that room.
A room that give acoperis.Daca reach the acoperis..am escaped.
But how do we get in that room? The cart, my dear.
That's it. Bingo!
Let's see who gets first. Dam with money.
You're skinny anyway.
Are you ready? Yes.
You should reach.
Not a window, it's a goddamn mirror.
We do not have to go around. Main guards are there.
It looks like we have no choice. Those guards have to move.
Germans guys is something that we all uitati.Si who's that?
As nemtesti wearing uniforms. Who makes them?
There must be someone here who pote make us get some uniforms.
Buddy Lindom. A Dutchman who will have to take it with you.
But we must find him first.
After you, old man.
It's better this way. But to sit with your back straight.
But we will not march but we leave here
Like me.
Can you see?
That's all I can do.
Damn, how did you do stamps?
Poftim.Nu not keep them. Are you sure?
You can come along with us.
I'm afraid not much of a team player, but thank you.
Who's that? What? There.
Ala is Willy electrician. He came to repair the light.
You are late.
You solved? Price increased.
These are all the money that I have.
I think we get along with these guys.
Grade sheath or ...
You fooled.
Hey how are you?
Fuck!
What happens?
It's a power outage.
So far everything is going well.
Stop.
Do not even think about it.
Don't move.
Tony, Tony! Now!
Very good. But not enough.
Take it back!
Jesus!
I know it looks a bit unconventional, but it should be.
We know that will never end ideas of escape, the problem is disguising.
Here come into play these guys. Gentlemen!
End and pull out a knife.
Put it back and inside is ... no, not out
It should be a vial. Of course I used to ...
I think the assistant's fault.
Dinti.O paste squeeze and after a while becomes gray. The same color as the German uniforms.
A tin of beans. An open and have ... damn.
A false bottom, is a piece of silk inside.
Perfect for hiding. Silk is a model very nice.
It is actually a detailed map by Bavaria to the Swiss border.
This man is a genius. You're an asshole.
Lighten up old! You've demonstrated point of view.
Not really, the other capat..vezi there beans. Just as written on the label
The most practical and useful of evedare.
A nuca.Nu is a nut. It's a compass.
And finally, from the British Museum ...
a grand plan Colditz Castle.
Look at this matter. They are brilliant.
You could go with them throughout Europe.
It was a good show.
I think we should pass on to those operations, let's shake her.
Yes, sir.
If you put a metal wire in a siret.Ce you?
A saw. That you.
You know, you're just as dumb as people think you are.
Excuse me sir. Of course.
Move here buddy.
Now that's a surprise.
It bothers you? Not.
Maybe I am pleased to speak to this gentleman.
Yes it's fucking este.Te thought that, but were too polite to tell.
I like you. Just doing my job.
I never thought you agree with this. Follow your advice, you should be happy. There are, believe me.
I just got word from Jack last week.
I received a letter. Hoping bine.Asa seems.
El e cam optimist, dar asa e Jack.
You do not seem happy. No, thanks ...
... just is ... difficult. Yes.
I feel that I live life every day and ...
and I have a lot of things that revolve my head.
Sometimes even ... Whatever.
Sometimes you do not remember what it looks like.
Neobisnuit.Asa not happen, it should not be ashamed.
But I feel so guilty. You have nothing to feel guilty. This is war and you have a life of your own.
And if not I could be dead.
You have to pay me for it. Oh no, oh yes.
What? A dance with me.
I have to think about it. A dance with me even if you have to crawl up there.
I should go, it's late.
You're somehow turn into a pumpkin.
Lizy, asteapta.Te lead you back. No, I'll handle it.
Let me get my purse.
Approaching again.
We should go to the shelter.
It's very beautiful! How can you say that! People die there.
You want me to win? I do not want us to win.
I was nothing before all this started.
We should go to the shelter.
You all right?
We must get out of here.
What are you doing? Nick!
We are in the midst of war Lizy. Come on!
I may feel heart Lizy, that's how life is struggling inside you.
Everything is blown. And suddenly it was all over.
We're just us now.
We can do whatever we want. We can be what we want.
We have what we want.
I want you!
Not!
Lizy!
Tell us confirm his identity number.
What's the commotion? Someone escaped from Colditz.
Who? I do not know.
Sherpshire royal infantry. Captain Edward Sawyer.
Contact regiment and learn as much as you can about it.
Who runs our shelter in Marseille? Mrs. M.Spune I will be a guest.
Danziger is an American agent that I wanted to use it.
If we can get him put it on the Baltic Sea in a boat to Sweden and take it from there.
What do you think? Sounds good.
Be happier man, this is the best news we have for several weeks now.
I said you do not do anything else, I promit.De like I was born yesterday.
I want you two to finish the job and ready to date.
I think this is yours.
It's just junk.
Lizy.
Lizy, look at me.
Actually, I'm kinda busy. Not true.
Last night was crazy. You could have killed us both.
Was awesome. It was a mistake.
There was no mistake, just know this thing.
I made a promise. I love Jack.
You can not wait forever. He might not return.
You said something terrible. I'll be back.
Look ... Lizy. Do not touch me please.
I think you should leave. I want to go.
I do not want to come back here. Lizy please!
Lieutenant McGrade want to leave.
Lizy please! Get out!
Mary! Hi, how are you?
Would you do me a favor? That prisoner of Colditz, I know what has regiment.
Of course. How I cheama.Rawles, Lt. Jack Rawles.Bine. Thank you.
Arise! Your month is over.
Good old!
McGrade, MI9.
Yes, sir.
From now on I want all letters from Lt.Jack Rawles from Colditz to be sent to me.
You do not have to know why.
Yes, sir.
See it's there!
And of course what is particularly interesting here is the definition of a Soviet Truska. According to a Soviet is a ...
Garbage is taken out in every Thursday. So we can to hide in it the night before. Let's see out the window!
Does it mind? We apologise. Shut up, man, we're busy here! And we are.
See, turn left and then right tower.
Did not you tired of this childish obsessions about escape?
If you want to rot here that's your job. What you said?
Return to your communist bullshit! Goddamn you!
Come here!
Look Mulon, it seems you do not want to understand is that we rot here.
Escaped French, Dutch and Polish. Everyone laughs at us.
Why can not you see that?
Le Blanc, look at him. What he wants?
I think pants world. Oh yes.
Barnes. Here. Raise your hand! Or I'm flying out of here!
What a gentleman!
Hello. How are you?
I heard a new escape plan on the guards. Correct.
I fear that my people were planning the same escape.
What a shame.
It's just one thing we can do.
Dam with money!
I can not believe.
I always luck.
Data-goes or part!
Another failed attempt. The more failed attempts the less chance for us to escape.
Here I come again. Jill, get away from the window.
I think we should go to the shelter. There will be leaving soon.
Anyway, what's the point? Look, I know what happened to Jack's horrible but I have to move on.
You have to go on. Otherwise even they win. So everyone tells me.
You did it with Jack?
You did it? Not.
But have you kissed.
You did anyone ever? Not.
So you did any of the other? Which?
You know. Lieutenant Nicholas McGrade.
No, I did. But have you kissed.
What is this. Not interested in you. I'll take that as a positive response.
I think you should do with it.
Think you've been keeping you very long for that special person.
And suddenly bang. You inbolnavesti or die. And you do not grab it before.
Never.
,, I call this tragic situation. '' I think this does not apply to you?
That was close.
Go to the shelter? It's a bit late now. But the lights were off.
However, if it hits you and hits you over.
Excuse me.
Thank God you're all right. I learned that you were hit.
Your face does not look too great. But it's not changed anything.
I no longer feel my head, sir.
It'll be all right girl.
It was nice of you for coming.
A boy to tell him to move his ass back here immediately.
You know Jack? Yes.
I wanted to come and see you. But I was not sure if you do not.
Do not know what happened.
From what I heard, he was shot while trying to escape.
Is everything okay? I do not know anymore.
I am sorry.
He was a brave man and good.
I would have never wanted to happen that. Know.
I am sorry. Lizy ...
I do not think I can live ... I know, I know.
You know where to find me.
Thank you.
We can see as friends.
Good.
We have to start out as many people there.
And if we succeed, these routes must be updated. And be safe.
Of course. A sending you here. Eager Stein's our man inside.
He'll be your eyes and ears.
These must be safe routes to France. We have several options available.
Better work here, same thing. Not.
This job is for you. Do you think you're doing?
Yes, sir. Good.
However, I fear that will not stick around for long. How so?
Ti found as a replacement.
Captain Sawyer, I suppose.
Welcome to MI9.
Good back? Oddish.
They told me you're an artist. I was.
I'm sure you regain your talent. Painting is like riding a bicycle.
Let me introduce you to another one that escaped. McGrade.
You get to handle his duties. I'll tell him how it works.
Let me show you around.
Hewitt.
Manning.
Lance yes I am.
Lizy's from? It's from a man who heard of it. From whom you have received?
Christmas came early guys. Well let's get back to our business.
What is this? What are those? Discs.
Did you find anything good there? Beans. Oh Lord, if you can not like hell here!
Either it is better than the food that we give here.
A small change from the crap you put Willis us to listen.
It's not for nothing that!
See if it's good?
It's a map.
Who says you sent that?
Mrs. Maplin. You know Mrs. Maplin?
And I thought that the British invented pickup. But that's your problem, huh?
Invent things others have to build.
Guys I think it's a code. Do not get carried away.
Check everything else.
I'll take this one.
Look what's here.
What's that? It's a telescope.
What did you find there? Numic, these were only discs.
You saw that back?
Well I have not slept.
A good evening. A good evening Miss Carter.
A good evening.
Well, good night.
God Lizy, you must give me something. I feel like going crazy.
I have to go. Thank you. Not. Please!
Haide Lizy, you can not waste your life for nothing.
Please, Nick. It's a memory. A fantasy.
I need time. You do not have time. None of us has.
I am sorry.
I leave here. You go?
Gives.
I should ... I can not see you.
Where? For how long?
Lizy, you will not see him ever Jack.
There could not see me or me.
If you want to help us. Move it, move.
Came reinforcements. Since the French escape.
More weapons. More guards.
What the hell is that?
A German physicist discovered x-rays.
They want radiography packages.
We have to get our hands on packages before they radiography.
I think I'll join him cumunistilor Malone's. Haide Jack can not quit now.
What are you doing? Oh Lord, prostovanule.
I was to blow my finger. What do you want?
Go. I left a note.
I refer to the Italian border.
Must provide some routes. And you want a kiss?
Not from you.
Are you married?
Yes, like a coconut, which is hollow.
I have not told you? Want to give you some friendly advice? You will not get it here.
You should take one of these with you.
It is all I can do.
A piece of chocolate, two chocolates, matches, magnetized blade and some nylon fishing.
Do not catch a fish and keep your pants up.
Thank you.
I give the bunker after all. Nobody will bother me there. Perfect.
Hopefully I will not be here when you return. If I ever return.
You'll come back. You die young Ala luck.
Macey greet and said that she and the girls will come to see you as soon as I can.
Macey, that with big boobs.
One that has bad breath and smelly feet.
He came to see you the boy that? Which?
You know, the one who works with Nick.
Call.
However I did not like.
At least you managed to ...
Do not complain that they deserve.
I never ... What you ...
did.
But I thought ... I wanted to believe that ...
It was the only thing I had done it you do not.
Jill. Who's gonna want me now, Lizy?
Or they want. Of course they'll want you.
The top floor, door near corner. Thank you.
Go back Nick!
I'll be back. Believe me that I will return.
Please come back.
That, gentlemen, is a cross-shaped clasp. Yes it is very beautiful, why we can not break?
Well it looks a conventional mechanism.
We can force? Not.
His name that one, olendezul that? Van Dahl. Give it.
Van de Boer. Is not it their locksmith. We could ask but do not tell us.
Why not?
It is deaf and dumb.
He can help you. Tell me the price, what does?
Escape. What? With us?
We want to go through a vent hole to go on the roof at a height of 50 m and descend to the other side.
We'll move like shit hard Calm down. Can we get rid of it.
Good. You have a week available.
Hi. Lord Willis!
You all right?
And you started with your games?
Three people have escaped our all while you're lalaiesti.
Yes, and a hundred were caught.
Pathetic.
Did you know that the Germans have reduced guards guarding the shed just to draw in trap.
All your disguises and fake uniforms and your tunnels are in vain.
A direct fall to them in the net.
Comunistule Maybe you're right, but I like.
Lieutenant think again.
It's free guys!
Hurry!
Good. Let's go! Bunny Good luck!
Up there!
Do not pull.
Do not pull. E deaf, can not hear you.
Let it get to me.
Damn.
What happens?
Nu e ala Jack Rawles si
Willis e cu el.
Grab the rope!
Come on!
He took it. Come on! So!
I hope you're proud of yourself.
I know that dead prisoner's body found behind was examined.
I am happy to say that my men shot him. It has no bullet wound.
A man escapes, but other die trying. His death is entirely your responsibility.
I hope you can live with that thought, gentlemen.
And to think about before next time.
25. You said 20.
Wait. Wait.
This is gonna get him! Just give me time ... I'll get him!
My lucky coin.
Look here! I brought you something.
Where are my clothes?
Motherfucker!
It ended months.
Good old!
Come on!
By the way...
I left everyone to leave. Besides you.
Merry Christmas!
You're back! What happened?
In fact, old everything goes well.
Who came to us guys? Hello sir.
As before, the third window. I think I deserve to see that after a month the state alone.
Still appear to show off those beauties.
This place is stagnant!
What is this?
Where is the portrait? Haide Jack, there's no time for that.
Where's my picture?
Where is? Jack, Jack.
Which of you I ... Jack
I will kill you all. Lighten up, wake the neighbors.
Keep. Did not you see how these guys do when they see a woman?
Good. Now let's tell the boys about the next plan.
Do not you see I'm only hopes up, Willis?
None of us will escape from here. Benny escaped.
Deaf and mute? Jack's war, people die.
I did not have to die.
Lizy and what about?
You know it's a beautiful girl. I thought I want to go back as soon as possible.
You know what happens when the cat's home. Shut up, Willis!
Shut up!
You do wishful thinking, Jack.
It will not be impressed when they find out that the man I expected too leave to come back to it.
Jack.
What are you looking at?
I was behind that wall. And makes us fear for the patrols were on the other side.
And how did you manage to escape? I hid in a truck.
Only you know me. Shape each time.
Sawyer, come here.
Bravo. Thank you.
Give the man something to drink that. Give him a beer and put it on my account.
You came back! I returned.
You're beautiful! You are so beautiful!
So beautiful that you come to drink before coming to me.
Duty. I was not until I returned. I missed you.
I missed you too.
Come and get to know the guys.
Ladies and gentlemen I would like to introduce you to the most beautiful woman in the world.
Lizy Carter.
Buna.
Do you want to drink something? Yes.
Who is? McGrade's girlfriend.
Two whiskey please.
Extraordinary. I drew it once. And went quite well.
One in Colditz. There must be boyfriend.
Since he died McGrade not let alone. You can not blame him, right?
Jack Rawles is dead? It was shot while trying to escape.
You want one? No, thanks.
I think you'll be rewarded. A medal. Yes.
It's kind of confidential for now. No need to let everyone know.
You? Yes, why not me. There is not great.
I should tell you something. I love war. Do not say that Nick.
It is only pain and suffering.
Are we unhappy? Not.
Not right now. Now I am very happy.
Even you would not be looking at me if it were not this war. We would not be here now.
Yes, but many people have died. Yes but we are still here.
It's like a jungle. Fight, survive. It's a beauty in that.
What kind of medal is?
One thing that shines.
Why are you laughing? Nothing, do not be so impressed.
Technically, our department does not exist.
You exist. And I'm very proud of you.
A to sprout something out of these ruins.
And I'll be there when it happens.
And you.
I love you.
God how I love you! Stay with me. Do not ever leave me!
I did not understand a word the whole ceremony.
A good show, though. Thank you sir.
Do not tell me. Good job.
I bring now sir. Do you want to know him and to tell him how it works.
I'll talk to him. Because I know you want.
View McGrade lose all updates.
New escaped from Colditz.
Hi Benny, I'm glad to see you.
Sawyer, nebunaticu!
What bothered us the best was that I did not get to see you in a disguise of yours.
It was a capadopera. Especially mustache that I had.
I was sorry to hear what happened to Jack Rawles. Jack?
Yes, I heard he was shot while trying to escape.
You did not know? It was shot?
I have not seen anything official but rumors.
Yes, I'm sorry.
It was Tom Willis him?
Come on, Sawyer must know something.
Is everything okay? Yes.
Got a minute? Of course. Excuse me gentlemen.
Rawles? Yes, it says he was shot while trying to escape.
Of course, the man from Colditz. Benny was friends with him and wants to know if you have more details.
To my knowledge, no.
But you know his beloved Lizy? Yes a little.
I thought maybe he heard something. From relatives or ... Do not mix her in this business!
Of course.
It's been through a lot. Jack's death broke his heart.
I just tried to keep her away from all this. Make me look.
I understand.
Probably best to leave it as is.
Dear Jack, if you're alive and reading this letter
then I think you did a great injustice.
For more than a year in London everyone here thought you were killed
While trying to escape from Colditz.
Recent events led me to do some investigation.
According to your regiment you're dead.
But then I went to the Swiss consulate where they kept files on prisoners of war.
And they told me they did not know anything about your death.
It could be a typo,
but then I began to wonder who would benefit from your death.
Which brings me to the most difficult part of this letter.
Oh Jackie, I think I know of who is scisoarea it.
That's not her handwriting.
I did not written anything for months.
Here comes Jack zombie.
I need to talk to you. Only one minutes. Now!
I gotta get out of here! You can not come and give me orders!
Read this! Read it!
I am sorry.
What plans have you done? I'm afraid things have changed little during your deception.
Really? Your request will be argued before the committee.
What? All plans must be approved and scheduled in order.
No time for that crap, Willis! It's my life here.
You have to wait your turn. I can not!
You wait your turn like everyone else, Lieutenant Rawles.
Wait! Willis!
I understand.
Just tell me one thing. Who's next?
Tell me please.
I am.
Mary, my daughter. I am sorry.
My father. He grandee? Brigadier general.
A war began last bottom. And stood up.
Confusing story. That fathers.
I am lucky in that regard. Mine was the seller.
I remember everything. School games.
Even when I was in scouts.
I remember we put on me and my brother to raise the tent blindfolded.
That was the best chance.
The best!
When I get out of here ...
Tom Willis.
Ian Norbeck.
I'll help you contact them in English. And is a good man, volunteered to come here.
You have the necessary documents? Yes.
German Cata you know? At all.
You need help in Liebtzieg.
When you get to go to church Liebtzieg St. Augustine. You meet with an escort.
I'll be talking to you on the train German. And take you to the shelter of Orso.
How will you escape tomorrow?
On the northeast corner. It's a small window.
Down, go along the wall on the terrace and then through the woods.
Success! Thank you.
Willis.
Something is up. Coming from the east wall.
Jesus will Rawles!
Run Jack! Faster!
Run! Move!
You succeed.
You knew! Motherfucker!
He stole my plan of escape.
Motherfuckers! It was my last chance.
Move out! Scumbag!
Bagami-as.
It's great news guys.
You heard? They say it is someone from Colditz.
You know who he is. Lieutenant Jack Rawles.
Good news.
Congratulations. You know where he is now?
Currently we do not know. But we think is going to Leibtzeig where he expects Poles.
Do you want me to do this? In fact I would like to me to handle this problem sir.
I was also in Colditz and you know Jack Rawles. He helped me to get out of there.
I owe. McGrade of any objections? No sir.
Then let go to work.
Willis? No, Jack Rawles.Willis not escaped. Change of plans.
Come! I'm not safe here.
Not!
Stay away from the window.
I'll be back soon.
Met liaison.
The place is full of Germans. They have to keep him there for a while.
Sawyer!
We have to talk. Is that so?
E cam melodramatic, nu-i asa?
Tell me what you know about Jack Rawles.
You tell me McGrade.
Do not get smart with me, motherfucker!
Well, I tell you.
I think you fell in love with his girlfriend. I do not know how or where, but I think he was loyal to.
I think maybe you become desperate, I do not know.
Maybe you panicked.
I think I have faked his death so that you may have on it. Do you think so?
Someone thought safe. You do not believe?
What will you do?
Nothing. This story is about me only.
Once Rawles will return will be between you and him. I did what had to be done.
What do you want to say? How come you did the right thing?
You told him. However learn sooner or later.
Who knows? Who you said.
Nobody.
It's between you and him.
It is too late McGrade.
What do you think, man.
You hoped never to return again.
Or you thought comes back, he sees his girlfriend and says, quite correctly
buddy, you've faked death is not so well, but all is fair in love and war '.
He was obsessed with this girl. I made her draw from his memory. He knew every inch of his face.
How have hair that had her lips as if it smelled as he described.
Shut up!
Sawyer!
It's not me. Come friend!
Do you have a train to catch.
Prisoners will be moved.
Decision has been taken by the command. From now on Colditz Castle will host the only British and American prisoners.
Prisoners will be moved to Stanislau Dutch and the French in Liebeq.
This will happen as soon as possible.
This is all.
I told you I'd get you out of here. They remained tools, documents and a tunnel that have worked for over a year.
What do you owe?
Besides money?
House wife, eldest daughter. The French should not bet.
Are you feeling alright?
It's just the flu. I get over.
Meisner? Jesus, why did it take so ...
It will be executed in a week.
He left it.
Not yet!
I think we will fall to a different understanding.
I'm not interested in money.
Excellent news. A to transmit on. Goodbye.
Good morning. Good morning.
Sawyer has not come yet? Not.
Not too stand wires.
How we decurcam? He arrived in Warsaw. Good for him.
Do you know where? Covered.
Thank you. I did and I know it.
Do you know where? Captain Sawyer insisted that this information be kept strictly secret.
So how do I get it out there?
What tolomac are!
I'll bring Captain Sawyer file.
Good luck. Thank you.
Come in, please.
She is my daughter. Hi.
Englez?
Da, Jack Rawles.
Where are you from? Colditz.
He is McNall. I am pleased.
And Holster. Do not wake up.
Sit down.
Thank you.
Since you are here? Six weeks.
Lizy!
I'm glad you came.
Little angel.
Is everything okay?
Can we talk?
Lizy
Will you marry me?
Do not you think we should do an honest woman out of you?
Gives.
Let's get out of here. Stupid in this country.
Let's start from scratch. To go to America.
Take it slowly.
Away from all this nonsense.
I want to be where you are.
What was that?
Germans who come to check their homes. It happens.
Do not move.
Damn.
Killed? It looks like it, sir.
Oh my God. Poor boy.
You wanted to see me, sir? Yes.
They found Sawyer. It seems he was murdered.
Jesus, why would anyone want to kill Sawyer?
Only God knows.
Sir. News about shelter in Warsaw.
I've lost them.
God knows how it expic them.
Do you think they were betrayed? Someone gave expose.
Sir, you just do not think that would be related to Sawyer?
What? He handles this route. I thought...
Why would Sawyer as Rawles wanted to die?
Who said anything Rawles.
Well, with any of them.
Wait. Sawyer was in Colditz, right?
See what you can find. It must have been a link between them.
You take escape plan that night. And?
I was wondering if you found something new.
Nothing. I had reported.
Come on man!
What the hell are you wearing?
Are you all right, sir? I'm fine, thanks.
It's not too late to change your mind.
Maybe another time.
Thank you.
Came.
Tom.
I admire your will.
I can not.
Jack.
They are the best news for weeks.
McGrade, merry man. Someone managed to escape from that mess in Warsaw.
Jack Rawles. Did he tell anyone?
I guessed.
When he returned? It should arrive momentarily.
He met someone in Stockholm and have it sent by plane Red Cross.
McGrade.
I'm afraid Colonel Fullham wants to talk to you first.
Then you can do whatever you want.
Sir. You should see it.
McGrade. Oh my God!
By MI9. We have two officers.
Lieutenant!
Nick. Get your things!
What happens? Leave. Go?
Yes, I'm out of here. Just as I spoke.
Did something happen? No nothing.
But we can not leave now.
Must.
Something happened, huh? No nothing happened. I do not mind!
You must come with me, Lizy!
If you love me.
If you did something you must tell me!
I only want you. This is all that matters. Everything is nothing without you.
Remember the night bombing?
We can be what we can be what we want.
Just you and me.
We do not need anyone else.
Now pack your luggage.
Do this for me. Please! For us.
Trust me. I love you.
Trust me. Go. You're crazy.
You're too late, Jack! Where is it?
He left. We both lost. Lie!
Know. It's a hard habit bad.
I will kill you! I doubt.
Nick.
Do not make a sound! Who are you talking to?
Get out!
I do not want to kill you, Jack. But I do, believe me.
Nothing. Because I'll be back again.
Not this time.
What would make Lizy if I kill them? Whatever I want it.
Me love me, Jack. It's mine. You're too late.
Nick, I left my coat ...
Jack!
Get your bag!
Jack, are you yourself?
I turned to you, Lizy.
Lizy, Come on!
What are you doing? She told they are dead, Lizy.
And then he gave a house full of innocent people in the hands of the Nazis.
He lied and killed. Shut up! Nick!
Talking nonsense, Lizy. Get your luggage.
It's nothing. It's garbage.
Stop!
It is mine. Not!
Hands up! Drop the gun, McGrade!
I love you!
Motherfucker!
They did it! Passed.
Americans crossed the border. Soon to finish everything.
It's not good.
Hi, Peter!
Stay! Stop!
Fritz Werner. Number 324 576.
From this moment is your prisoner.
Lizy and came.
All week it was here.
What is with all the flowers?
Hi. Hi.
All repeat this for weeks. But I do not know where to start.
Jack! No no. I have to say a few things.
We ... We were both young when they started all this.
I still can not say I'm a grown man.
Yes you are.
Let's sit down a little.
We both had to do some things.
There were no rules.
Now we must try to live again.
What we had two was a dream.
Know. I know all about dreams.
My dream was a picture of you.
And not for you. That's you now.
And after everything that happened ...
I still love you.
I thought I will not see you again.
Know.
I understand.
Umpteenth love I have in me I can give someone.
I do not care how long it takes.
Better go. Of course.
However, I think I'd like to bring me flowers.
What about tomorrow?