WALSH: Job came in about
an hour ago from sanitation.
DANNY: There was nothing else?
Just the head?
So far. M.E.'s office
is on the way.
Pretty decomposed.
Why don't you go on up there
and have a closer look?
He just said M.E.'s on the way.
I'll look out
for them. Go on.
(sighs)
(ship horn blowing)
When you were
taking the test,
you ever think you'd be
climbing up a pile of garbage
to get to a severed head?
No. Thought I'd be more like
Paul Newman
in Fort Apache, The Bronx.
It was Cagney & Lacey for me.
(flies buzzing)
You know we could just retire,
and go to a tropical island
and solve crimes there.
We could,
but you would
never survive outside
the five boroughs.
That's true.
(flies buzzing)
Yeah, it's Mano Sangriento.
Black hand?
No, just the fingers.
But it was a hand.
That's the calling card.
Yeah. Now we're gonna
have to figure out
why this guy lost his head.
Jose Cortez, 30,
from Sunset Park.
Cops found him in possession
of a half-ounce of cocaine.
ERIN: Criminal possession
in the third degree.
But Cortez has no priors,
so he's eligible
for judicial diversion.
So he'll get drug treatment
instead of jail time.
And Schneiderman is on deck, so
no doubt she'll recommend rehab.
You run a triple I check
to make sure he doesn't have
a record outside of New York?
His record's clean.
Legal aid's gonna ask for R.O.R.
What do you want to do?
I'll ask for 500 bail.
She'll R.O.R. him anyway.
And so it goes.
All right, well, you seem to
have everything under control.
You need anything from me?
A raise.
(laughs softly)
Get in line.
(blender whirring)
You want some breakfast?
Kale and protein powder?
I think I'll pass.
If you show me what's under
that robe, I'll make you
whatever you want.
- Well, in that case,
you're gonna have to produce
some pretty killer pancakes.
Mm-hmm.
Wish I didn't have court.
Mm. It's better than being stuck
in Jersey traffic.
No, I mean, I wish
I could come with you.
It's no biggie.
Telling your mom that
we're engaged is a biggie.
- Mm...
- Plus, I haven't even met her yet.
Exactly. Let's keep it that way.
What does that mean?
My mother has scared off
every boyfriend
I've ever introduced her to.
I'm not every boyfriend.
Well, then you'll see
for yourself when you meet her.
At the wedding.
(phone vibrating)
- Ridiculous.
- (laughs)
Eddie, great news. My court date
got pushed to tomorrow.
Oh.
- I can come with you.
- Wait, what?
Yeah, I'll just take the
day and come with you.
No, definitely not.
Invisibility.
Definitely invisibility.
No, man. Spidey-sense.
Then, you get fair warning
when something's gonna go down.
How about X-ray vision?
Ugh, no. There are things
I don't want to see.
I've always had a thing
for the Lasso of Truth.
- (chuckles)
- Come in handy when we make detective.
Hey, why do you guys
always weigh the brain?
To see how much they weigh.
Actually, it's to look
for abnormalities.
This one is
three pounds
of memories, emotions
and 86 billion nerve cells.
Hmm.
I've always wondered about the
part that controls your emotion.
Oh, the amygdala.
Kind of wish I could have it
removed sometimes.
Yeah, but then you'd
be a serial killer.
Uh, what can you
tell us about
the head you found
at the garbage dump?
I'm waiting on DNA, but the time
of death and the injuries
are consistent
with that headless corpse
you guys brought me
a few weeks ago.
You mean the one belonging
to Luis Delgado?
That body wasn't Luis Delgado.
What are you talking about?
That body and the head that
you pulled out from the garbage
this morning appear
to belong to the same person.
No, the body
we found on the beach
with Luis Delgado's clothes on
and Luis Delgado's tattoos
belong to Luis Delgado.
Trust me.
I had to get dental records
from Mexico to confirm.
Great. Then the son of a bitch
who burned down my house
is still alive.
(sighs)
(elevator bell chimes)
What is it?
Two officers sitting
on a witness's house
were shot multiple times
inside their patrol car.
Both critical.
- Anyone likely?
- Information's still coming in.
They're at Saint Irene's.
And the shooter?
No word yet.
Frank, one of the officers
is Abigail's husband.
♪ Blue Bloods 9x07 ♪
By Hook or by Crook
Original Air Date on November
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
♪
Hey.
Two cops were shot
in their patrol car.
I heard. Any word
on their condition?
Still waiting. But Erin,
they just picked up
the shooter.
It's Jose Cortez.
The guy we released
this morning?
He went straight from
arraignment court
to his apartment,
he picked up a .45
and he opened fire. He's got
a record for murder and assault.
No. His rap sheet came up empty.
It came up empty
in our system
because his priors
were in Mexico.
Anthony, this is my fault.
No.
Your A.D.A. followed
the bail recommendations
to the letter.
Tell that to the two cops
laying in the hospital.
(filtered breathing)
Officer Davis is out of surgery.
He's in recovery.
Brian took a bullet to his neck,
which severed his jugular.
Did I ever show you
Brian's department photo?
You're not supposed to,
but... he smiled.
On purpose.
He said every time
you see a cop shot
on the front page of the paper,
it's always the official photo
and they look so serious.
He figured if he smiled,
it was...
some sort of guarantee that
nothing bad would happen to him.
He might be right.
I've promised him all kinds
of things if he gets better.
(sighs)
Brian,
it's Commissioner Reagan.
(exhales)
(sighs)
Whatever it takes, Abigail.
DANNY:
I'm telling you,
Delgado had this guy
made up to look like him,
even down to the tattoo,
so he could pull
one over on us.
Mano Sangriento is all over
Long Island and Manhattan now.
- They all use the black hand.
- He played us.
I've checked every ship
and airline passenger list.
I don't think he left town.
Look, it's been weeks, okay?
He could be anywhere by
now, including Mexico.
Just speak to the DEA.
See if they'll give you
anything they got on him.
I'll check the warrant my sister
gave me on his cell phone
and see if that
turns anything up.
(sighs)
I think someone else
should find Delgado.
It's way too personal
between you and him.
I'm not gonna go
off the rails, if that's
what you're thinking, okay?
I promise.
You already did.
Do you really want to put us
in the crosshairs?
Look, I'm gonna get
that son of a bitch,
no matter what it takes.
You don't want
to be a part of that,
then I suggest
you walk away on this one.
You really want me to walk away?
JANKO:
Mom.
Hi.
- Hmm.
- This is Jamie.
Hi.
You didn't tell me
you were bringing someone.
- I know. I'm sorry.
- Jamie Reagan. Nice to meet you.
How do you do?
Very well.
You're welcome.
Um...
Can I steal this?
Yes, no problem.
So...
are you dating?
Is this, like,
a new boyfriend?
Uh, he-he's my fiancé.
Fiancé?
And this is the first time
I'm meeting you?
Well, we didn't
really date date.
You didn't date?
What he means
is we've known each other
for a long time.
We were partners on the job.
So you're a cop.
He's a sergeant.
He went to Harvard.
A quarter of a million dollars
in tuition
and you decided to be a cop.
Well, my whole family's
in law enforcement,
so I guess it was in the blood.
It's too bad doctor or lawyer
wasn't in the blood.
Then you two could
actually afford
a nice lifestyle.
We love our lifestyle, Mom.
Do you own a house?
I have an apartment.
Eddie likes being in the city.
- "Eddie"?
- No one calls me Edit, Mom.
I do. Your father does.
Well, I like Eddie.
So, you use a boy's name
and he uses a girl's name.
Mom.
(laughs):
I'm just saying.
That's okay.
My real name's Jameson.
Like the whiskey.
Yeah, like the whiskey.
It's a good thing your parents
didn't like to drink Smirnoff.
- Mom.
- What?
So, Reagan, is that, is that
any relation to...
The police commissioner,
yes, he's my dad.
(sighs)
What?
You must see the humor
in this, Edit.
Your father's in jail,
and you're marrying
the police commissioner's son.
That's going to make for some
very interesting conversation
at the wedding reception,
don't you think?
Looks like Davis has permanent
nerve damage to his hand.
GORMLEY:
His shooting hand,
so he'll be off
the street for good.
Well, not necessarily.
Not with the kind of things
they can do today.
And Brian Baker?
Still the same.
A.D.A. Reagan, boss.
GORMLEY:
Erin.
Garrett. Sid.
- Erin.
- How's Brian?
Still unconscious.
It's a waiting game right now.
And Abigail?
Abigail hasn't left his side.
Where's your boss?
He's not coming.
Okay.
I'll be in my office, boss.
(door closes)
Cortez was my case.
I supervised it.
It was my responsibility.
What were you thinking
letting him walk?
He didn't walk.
He made bail.
Bail was set at 500 bucks, Erin.
Of course he walked.
That's chump change
for a drug dealer.
The arrest was
for a nonviolent drug charge.
We are not in the business
of asking
for high bail because we think
someone might become dangerous.
He has a felony record
in Mexico: murder, assault.
My office didn't have access
to that information.
So the D.A.'s office
is in a rush to hold his hand,
and he goes out
and shoots two of my cops.
What do you want me to say, Dad?
The department policy is to ask
for little or no bail
for nonviolent crimes.
The policy has had success.
Not so much.
♪
(doorbell rings)
Where is he?
I don't know who
you're talking about.
The guy you're
standing next to
in the painting over
there. Where is he?
- Uh-uh.
- No...
Don't even think about it.
You're trespassing.
You broke into my house.
You mean like
your husband trespassed
when he burned my house down?
Mom?
Is everything okay?
Go back inside.
- Where's your phone?
- In the kitchen.
Let's go get it.
Your husband's making a lot
of money terrorizing people.
Who's terrorizing who?
Get the phone.
Pick it up.
Call your husband.
Come on.
Turn around.
Don't do anything crazy.
Luis?
Hey, remember me?
Where's Isabel?
She's right here.
Kids are here, too.
But don't worry, they're safe.
Unless, of course,
I decide to burn your house down
like you burned down mine.
If you harm them,
I swear I'll kill you.
Well, then you better
hurry up and get home.
Sit down.
Officer Davis took a bullet
to his right hand,
which has caused
permanent nerve damage.
Officer Baker was hit
with a bullet in his neck,
which punctured his jugular.
The bullet was removed, but he
has not regained consciousness.
We will have updates
as things progress.
(reporters clamoring)
What about the shooter?
Uh, the shooter,
Jose Cortez,
was apprehended
shortly after the shooting.
He has been charged
with attempted murder
in the first degree
and will be arraigned
later this afternoon.
Initial reports said Cortez
had been arrested before,
but released on bail.
- That's correct.
He was arrested for
drug possession
and released on bail
this morning.
MAN:
Why was he released on bail?
The nonviolent nature
of his crimes
and the lack
of prior criminal history.
Why was he released
in the first place?
He was
a member of Mano Sangriento.
Mr. Cortez had
no criminal history
or gang affiliation
on record.
It was handled
as a first-time offense.
What do you mean, "on record"?
Mr. Cortez had
a prior record in Mexico
that did not come up
on the initial background check.
In light of what happened,
is the D.A.'s office
going to rethink this policy?
The policy was established
to decrease overcrowded prisons
filled with
nonviolent offenders.
In this regard,
the policy is a success.
The NYPD has two good officers
in the hospital,
one facing disability,
one may not survive.
Asking for minimum bail
for felonies
puts my officers
and, more importantly,
our citizens at risk,
because these criminals
will then be incentivized
to go out and commit more,
worse crimes.
And that is exactly
what happened today.
(reporters clamoring)
GARRETT:
That's all.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
I don't know how you
actually thought
you could avoid me
meeting your mother.
Oh, I was doing a great job
avoiding until today.
Eddie, you've met my whole
family; they're not perfect.
You have... you know, you have
a Norman Rockwell family.
You go to church on Sundays,
and you eat together on Sundays.
Just please don't.
Just saying, it doesn't
bother me what she says.
She just has no filter.
And she only cares
about money.
Eddie, do you know why we have
family dinner every Sunday?
No. Why?
Because my grandmother grew up
poor in a small town in Ireland.
She was the oldest of 12 kids,
and there was never
enough to eat.
She moved to New York
to make money.
She met my grandpa, and
when they got married,
she promised herself
that they would always
have more than enough to eat.
Family dinner was
just her way of proudly
proving that every week.
That meal was so important to
her because of how she grew up.
I'm just saying, there must be
some deep-seated reason
why your mother is
so obsessed about money.
My mother chooses to insult me
and to insult every person
I've ever brought home.
♪
(phone ringing)
Yeah.
Leave the car there
and walk to the garage.
Welcome home.
Come on in.
Right over there.
(garage door closing)
Keep your hands where
I can see 'em.
Where's my wife and my boys?
Why'd you set my house on fire?
You're really pretending
to be an innocent victim?
- (quietly): Who gave you the order?
- Doesn't matter.
You think if you
take him down, it's over?
You guys thought
you got El Chapo.
There's 20 guys lining up
to be the next El Chapo.
That's how
these organizations work.
How this works is that I'm
gonna find every son of a bitch
who had a hand in setting
my house on fire,
and I'm not gonna stop until
every one of them's behind bars,
or worse.
That's how it works.
Won't bring your wife back.
You have two sons.
You really want
to put them in danger?
Baez, I got Delgado.
Request a 10-85
to 12 Bayview Avenue.
You're under arrest.
Turn around.
Put your hands
behind your back.
(sighs)
You made a big mistake.
You're the one making
a mistake, bro.
- I'm one of you.
- Yeah?
(chuckles)
How's that?
I'm working for the DEA.
(laughs)
We have you
for the murder
of Melissa Sanchez.
- No, you don't.
DANNY: Yes, we do.
You told me you killed her
and her unborn baby.
I told you
I didn't think she was okay.
As it turns out, I was right.
She wasn't okay. She was dead.
And Manny Sanchez.
Reagan, what do you think
you're doing?
What the hell do you think
Can I talk to you outside?
What the hell are you doing
here? And more importantly,
what the hell
are you doing working
with a scumbag like Delgado?
- We made a deal with him.
- Yeah, I know you did.
You made a deal
with a cold-blooded killer
who murdered an innocent woman
and her unborn baby.
Delgado's a hired hand.
We're after José Rojas.
His boss. La Almeja. The Clam.
- Okay.
- Delgado is a hired gun.
Rojas has murdered or ordered
the murder of hundreds.
Okay? We get Rojas,
we bring down the organization.
Great, then go get him.
I already got Delgado.
He's mine.
No, you're gonna back off.
Go to hell.
Look, I get that this
has gotten personal for you.
- Don't go there.
- Okay, but we don't need you
going in there, being a hothead,
blowing our case.
I arrested Delgado.
It's my collar.
- Are you kidding me right now?
- I got him on murder charges. Okay?
That trumps any drug charge
you could possibly get.
So unless you want
to go before a judge
and try to get him
to give you a writ for me
to turn him over to the feds,
so be it. You go do that.
But until such time,
Delgado's mine.
He stays here with me.
Hey.
What?
Maybe we can work together
on this.
(laughs)
Well, it's the only way
we're both gonna get
what we want.
ALL: Bless us, O Lord,
and these Thy gifts,.
which we are about to receive
from Thy bounty,
through Christ our Lord. Amen.
(Danny clears throat)
You mind, uh, passing
me the mac and cheese?
Sure.
Here you go.
Looks good.
And what's the matter
with Daniel?
Nothing.
Well, you're not piling food
onto your plate,
so it must be something.
Well, I kind of lost my appetite
when I learned that the guy
who burned our house down
cut a deal with the DEA.
You know who burned
our house down?
DANNY: Yeah.
We'll talk about it later.
In the meantime, that guy's
walking around free as a bird.
Well, you could always
blame the D.A.'s office.
It seems to be the common
dumping ground around here.
HENRY:
No one's dumping
on the D.A.'s office.
NICKY:
You saw
the joint press conference.
System's broken.
Somebody had to call it out.
And here I thought
a press conference
was for dispensing information,
not calling people out.
My mistake.
DANNY: Well, last I heard,
you commit a crime,
you suffer the consequences,
end of story.
You know how many times
you and Jamie have come to me
for a search warrant
or a subpoena,
and you haven't had everything
to get it?
Yeah, about as many times
as you've said no.
SEAN: I'm sorry,
I still don't understand.
If you know who burned
our house down,
then why is he
still walking?
It's something called
judicial perversion.
JAMIE:
Judicial diversion.
It's a policy
where nonviolent offenders
get reduced bail
and rehab, community service
instead of jail time.
It's called
mollycoddling criminals.
- Exactly.
NICKY: Is there anything
that you guys don't blame
on the attorneys?
Well, I'm afraid at the moment,
there happens
to be plenty to blame.
Amen to that.
HENRY:
That's what you get for having
a liberal D.A.
and a liberal mayor.
Like cops don't
make mistakes?
Nobody's saying that.
JAMIE: To be fair, I understand
why he got a reduced bail.
His arrest wasn't
for a large felony weight.
Well, how about his affiliation
with an illegal gang?
Or his criminal record?
His criminal record
in Mexico
doesn't come up in
a background check.
It would if you ran him
through Interpol.
ERIN: Why would I run
a low-level drug dealer
through Interpol?
Why wouldn't you?
You know, when I first started
coming to these family dinners
and you guys would argue,
I would get really nervous
'cause I thought maybe you'd
never talk to each other again.
But...
you do.
You just keep talking.
Come hell or high water.
You saying we talk too much?
No.
Well, don't worry, Eddie.
No matter what you do,
you're golden at this table.
(chuckles) I am?
As long as you wear NYPD blue.
I didn't know
you were coming here.
Edit never called me.
I didn't tell her.
May I come in?
(sighs)
I bet she's mad at me.
Well, why wouldn't she be?
She came to give you
some good news,
and you rained on her parade.
The good news would've been
she's marrying someone
who could afford to give her
the life that she's used to.
And what life would that be?
One where your husband's
in prison for fraud
and she wants to cut you
out of her life?
She should be grateful.
We gave her everything.
Your husband cheated people
out of their savings.
You insulted every guy
she ever brought around.
I tell the truth.
And the truth about me
is I don't make
enough money? I'm
the wrong religion?
I live in the wrong borough?
I won't apologize
for wanting what's best
for my daughter.
- I'm what's best for your daughter.
- Oh, because you love her?
(chuckles) And that's gonna
take care of the bills?
I live a comfortable life,
and my family will, too.
Will it meet your standards?
I don't know.
But my family
will always come first.
That sounds great
on a Hallmark card.
But in reality?
Not so much.
I don't want Edit to end up...
Like you did?
Maybe you need to see the world
through a different set
of glasses.
Well, I certainly don't trust
the rose-colored ones you wear.
You haven't tried them on yet.
I'm in the middle
of pretrial hearings, Pop.
You call me
out here for this.
I made you your
favorite sandwich.
Thank you. Now,
what are we doing out here?
Getting you out
of the office.
My office is not
the problem. Dad is.
Oh, is he, now? Why?
'Cause he says
what he feels?
In front of
millions of viewers
at my first press conference
as bureau chief?
Yeah, he could've
tempered it down.
You mean watered it down?
Whatever you want
to call it.
(sighs)
You're upset because
he talked like the
police commissioner
and not your father.
I don't see how he could've
handled it any other way.
Of course you're gonna
take his side.
I'm not taking sides.
(scoffs)
Why are you taking this
so personally?
I can take the slings and arrows
from other attorneys
and the D.A.
and even the press, but...
But not your father?
He was criticizing
the D.A.'s office, not you.
That's not what it felt like,
and I was the one up there
taking the heat.
You're confusing work
and family.
Your father
has the right to disagree
with the D.A.--
yes, in public,
and yes, even with you
standing there next to him--
because it's his job.
But no matter what happens,
you'll always have his love
and support.
(device beeps)
Every time you leave the house,
you have to call first
to say where you're going.
If you're gonna be late
getting back
or your train is delayed,
your car breaks down,
you need to call us
with the details.
Then I should tell you
the coke and fentanyl exchange
may be going down tonight.
"May be going down tonight"?
I'll get a call
this afternoon to confirm.
Where?
The old candy factory.
I don't know how many people.
Usually six or seven total.
Members of the Double Treys,
Mano Sangriento, me.
DANNY: Good. Now we know
where it's going down.
So we don't need him to do this.
Rojas expects me to be
there to handle the money.
If he finds out I'm not,
he'll be in the wind.
Don't trust him.
Wipe that smile off your face.
That's hard to do 'cause
you're so damn entertaining.
- Danny. Danny.
- Reagan! Reagan!
MOLINA:
Outside.
(laughs)
Now!
This is too personal for you
and you cannot handle this...
- It's not personal.
I don't trust the son
of a bitch, okay?
Well, we're on it.
- You don't know how that guy works.
- No?
35 years ago,
my father crossed the border
to get away
from Mano Sangriento.
Okay, when he finally had
enough money,
he went back to get the rest
of his family.
Sangriento had killed
every last one of them.
So...
don't tell me I don't know him.
Look, I'm sorry.
I am.
But you're playing with fire,
trusting this guy.
You're the one playing
with fire,
letting him get to you
like that.
You either play by my rules,
or you get the hell off my team.
(sighs)
Okay. We got Delgado.
Amigo.
(speaks Spanish)
I know where you live.
On my signal, we're gonna go.
One.
Two.
Wait a minute.
Where the hell is he going?
I don't know. His
car's in the front.
What the hell is he doing?
- Three.
- No. Wait.
No, wait! No!
Go, go, go.
(men shouting)
Move, move!
Hey. It's a setup. Hold on!
(shouting continues)
Hey!
Help! Help me! Help me!
(screaming)
Come here, come here.
Hang on!
(coughs)
(people screaming)
Baez, it's pepper spray!
(coughing)
(groans)
(shouting continues)
MAN:
It's pepper spray!
(panting)
(tires squealing)
(coughs)
Delgado?!
(groans)
(panting)
Delgado?
(Danny grunts)
(panting)
(engine revving)
Aah!
It's a didgeridoo.
An Australian wind instrument,
a little bit like a trumpet.
Oh.
Thank you.
It's a gift from
the prime minister of Australia
for hosting him last week.
A donation to the NYPD Museum?
Brian's doing better.
He is, thank you.
Thought you weren't coming in
for a few weeks.
I told Jimmy
I'd relieve him for a few hours.
I could use the break.
Things are bad
if work's a break.
Actually, things are very good.
Brian is breathing on his own,
he's complaining
about hospital food,
and they're gonna release him
tomorrow.
Good news.
Well, maybe you should
rethink that no-smile policy.
I have accompanied you
on many, many hospital visits
to officers who have been
injured in the line of duty,
some who have died
in the line of duty.
I knew it was your job.
What I never fully understood
was just how important
your visit is
to the officer's family.
And now I know.
Thank you.
(door opens, closes)
Son of a bitch, he set us up.
I told you not to trust him.
We don't know that yet.
Of course he set us up.
He got the hell out of there
right before the boxes exploded.
- How the hell would he know?!
- He knew what was coming.
Then why did he go back
to his apartment?
What?
Look at the ankle monitor.
It proves that he's there.
Then, what happened?
- Well, I'll let you know after I see him.
- No, no, no, no.
You'll let 'em know
after we see him.
We're going with you.
Let's go.
Delgado? Police!
I thought the GPS said
he was here.
It did.
It's Agent Molina, Luis.
We need to talk to you.
Luis?
DELGADO:
Please, come in.
You know, I'm glad you came.
Something I've been wanting
to tell you.
What's that?
You know your wife's
helicopter accident?
It really wasn't an accident.
It was all arranged
by Mano Sangriento,
because you started
playing games with them.
You son of a bitch.
Where the hell are you?
Where are you?!
DELGADO: You really shouldn't
play games with them.
And do you know why?
I don't give a damn why.
DELGADO:
Because they always win.
Where are you, Delgado?
Real tough guy, huh?
Couldn't come face me?
Oh, I am facing you, Detective.
And you know what I see?
A loser.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I'm
gonna go mix myself a drink.
I'll get TARU in here,
run a trace on the video.
You told me
the GPS said he was here.
The son of a bitch isn't here!
It said that he was here.
(footsteps approaching)
(growling)
(laughter nearby)
LENA:
Good one.
Hello?
(both laughing)
Hey.
Eddie, uh, Mom and I--
we made dinner for you.
- My mom doesn't cook.
- What did I
always tell you, Edit?
"Forget the dishes on the shelf,
be a tasty dish yourself"?
(laughs)
So, we ordered takeout
from Balthazar's.
(both laugh)
Want some wine?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
She ordered from the most
expensive restaurant,
and we are gonna
foot the bill.
- Yeah, I know.
- You know?
What were you thinking?
I thought it would be good
to make amends.
She brought the
family photo album?
Well, that was my idea.
Does it get better
if she has a few drinks?
Well, it gets better if we do.
Edit, your first bikini!
It's a good thing
you grew some boobs after that.
Who was that guy
that you went with?
What was his name?
Oh. Stan.
Stan. That's right.
His father was a cardiologist.
- What ever happened to him?
- Well,
Mom, uh, Stan became
a cardiologist, too,
and he lives in Boca.
- Ah.
- Oh. Nice boy.
I'll have a refill.
Yeah.
Mom, you scared off every boy
I ever brought home.
If they were all scared off,
then none of them deserve you.
Is that your excuse?
It's true.
They all ran, except for one.
He's the only one who came back.
I love you.
Something wrong?
No.
LENA:
(gasps) You've got
to see this, Jamie.
Eddie dressed as
Jessica Rabbit
for Halloween.
Ooh, I actually look
pretty hot in that one.
- Well, what are we waiting for?
- Mm.
You already put the bait on?
- Thought I'd save you the trouble.
- It's a blood worm?
Sand worms.
I would have gone
with herring.
You want me to put
on a bottom bait?
No, I didn't ask you to come
out here to valet the tackle.
Okay.
You know how old you were
when I taught you to fish?
- No.
- Seven.
Actually, I wasn't
gonna teach you at all,
even though I
taught the boys.
Because I was a girl?
No.
Because it is
the kind of activity
where even
if you do everything perfectly,
there's no guarantee of a fish.
And what else is like that,
if I'm hearing you correctly?
Being a boss.
One slipup, and the searchlight
comes on hot and fast.
Tell me about it.
Pop told me I took
the press conference personally.
That I was expecting
you'd act more like
a protective father
than the PC.
And what do you think?
That my mistake was acting
like a respectful daughter,
letting you have the last word.
And the next time?
I will always
be respectful of you.
Couldn't be
any other way, but...
I need to respect
my office, too.
And maybe keep the joint press
conferences to a minimum.
Yeah. That, too.
Ooh.
Well, what do you know.
Results.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man