The city is shocked by missing baby cases.
Eighteen babies were taken
in the past three months.
The police have made no breakthrough
and the investigations
have reached the bottleneck.
-The Commissioner of Police…
-All my clients have good lives.
Here we are. Stop!
I'm coming!
Something is wrong.
Damn it.
Forget it.
Be careful.
Look!
It's a stylish building!
Let's take a look inside.
This way, please.
This way.
This house is elegant
and there is no one else here within 1 km.
It's only a five-minute ride
to the market.
This house can't be that perfect.
Surely there must be some defects.
There is a little defect,
but it won't be a problem.
This way.
The defect is that
it's not really renovated.
You call this as not really renovated?
The structure is fine.
There was just a little fire.
-Honey.
-Hush.
I'll show you something.
Nature!
You'll love this place in no time.
What do you think?
Damn it.
I've asked the owner
to renovate the house first.
What a waste of time!
How lucky!
Who the hell would buy it now?
Damn it!
-Let's go.
-Don't move!
Dear, let's buy it.
I like it.
It has character.
Character?
-Really?
-You know how I like it.
I know.
Pay the deposit first then.
Quiet!
Did you try to steal my car?
Put this on yourself.
Okay, I'll put it on myself.
Incredible!
Of course. My husband is a policeman.
Keep walking.
Aren't I walking now?
Up until today,
18 babies went missing
in the past two months.
They seem like the work of one person.
None of the missing babies' families
has received any blackmail letters so far.
Nor has any political or terrorist group
claimed responsibility.
Chief, this is bizarre.
Shall we approach Wonder Woman?
Even though she helped us before,
we still don't know who she is.
We can't reach her at all.
All missing babies are boys.
This shows that it's not blackmailing.
Hey…
Maybe it has something to do with cults.
Did anyone rush out
of the conference room?
No.
Chief!
Come with me.
The babies' ward is upstairs.
Operation rooms are over there.
I'm worried about our son.
-Let's take him home now.
-Lau!
He was just born this morning.
The doctor won't take the risk
if we discharge him now.
-Lau--
-Fine! We'll leave him here.
Why didn't you call Wonder Woman for help?
Ma'am, we have no way to contact her.
I've sent more men here.
Staying here is just as safe
as staying at home.
-Take care of her!
-Okay.
Chief, Officer Lau, there's a bus crash
in the Southern District just now.
The warden might need these beds,
so we need to think about it.
Lau.
You may leave first.
It's my son that they are after.
How about we find someone
to swap with my son?
Whose son?
I guess that's immoral.
They want your son.
They will find him eventually.
Yes, it'd be embarrassing if others knew.
Let's brace ourselves.
Brace ourselves.…
I'm sorry, ma'am.
Officer Lau said no one can enter
without his permission.
Forget it!
Look up there!
-What's wrong?
-The babies are falling down!
-Catch them!
-My son!
Catch our son!
Which one is our son?
Either one of them can be him!
Which one?
Wonder Woman!
-Wonder Woman!
She's coming down!
There's some blood on the wall.
Run some tests on it.
This is not our baby.
This is not our baby!
It's a girl!
-A girl? It's my daughter!
-Hey!
I'm so glad you are fine.
-I was so scared.
-This is bad.
Get someone to collect the blood sample.
-Yes, sir. Come with me.
-Okay.
-Hello?
-Tung-tung, another baby is missing.
I'll be back late tonight.
Okay.
Are you upset?
No. Work hard tonight.
-Goodbye.
You always like to fight.
I'll chop off your head next time.
Guard the door!
Master, here is the baby boy you want.
Take the 19th prince inside
to rest with the other princes.
Yes, Master.
Sum.
Your heart is beating too fast.
No, it's not.
Memories do you no good,
neither do feelings or emotions.
I don't have any.
I'll wait for the next auspicious day.
Among all the babies,
I'll choose one to be the emperor.
China must have an emperor.
-China must have an emperor.
Either you climb up by yourself
or you will fall!
No one can help you.
Climb up!
Ching-ching, climb up!
Don't fall! Climb!
Did you have a nightmare again?
May I come in?
I'm working.
You know
I don't want anyone to disturb me.
I've been dreaming of the invisible robe
every night for years.
Last night,
I dreamt that it was finally completed.
Has it always been kept in the safe?
Yes, why?
The police called today
and asked me how one can be invisible.
Before the invisible robe is finished,
you don't want others to know about it.
Even if it's finished,
I want to keep it a secret forever
because an invention like this
may easily be used as a war weapon.
Then why are you still working on it?
What does it mean to you?
I feel the happiest
when I'm glued to my work.
Don't you worry that I'd steal it?
No.
You can't steal what's already yours.
Do you want some coffee?
Yes, please.
FORTUNE-TELLER
Miss, the dates of birth
of those 18 babies…
Are they related in any way?
It's strange.
They all have a royal destiny.
They are all fated to be emperors!
Emperors?
Why would anyone kidnap
so many little emperors?
My sister!
Do you want some? Come over then.
Come.
Are you talking to me?
No.
May I kiss you?
Why are you smiling?
Am I? It's nothing.
Go down!
Stand on one side!
-Stand together! Quickly!
-Quickly!
Gosh! Who are they, Lau?
Three armed robbers with criminal records
just robbed a cash escort car
and were chased here by our men.
There are eight hostages inside
including drivers and guards.
What do we do now?
-We will force them out.
-Give me one!
Get ready!
Fire!
-Calm down, it's tear gas. Wear masks!
-Wear masks!
Get out!
Damn! Get out!
Quickly!
Give me the revolver!
-Don't fire!
-Listen up!
There are many more hostages inside!
Get me a helicopter in two hours
or I'll kill one hostage
every five minutes!
Hello, sirs!
Who is she?
A professional gunner, Chan Chat.
Sir, don't call me that.
I only kill those who deserve to die.
Call me Thief Catcher.
The police won't hire you.
Hire?
Sir, I'll do you a favor this time.
It's free of charge.
-Get them!
-Yes, sir!
I surrender! Don't fire!
I surrender! Don't…
Rescue the hostages!
-Rescue the hostages.
-Let's go.
-Come on!
Lie down!
-Get the hostages!
-Get them!
Go and see
if there are still hostages inside!
I'm married.
So?
It seems like
only I can get your son back.
Pay me 500,000 if he's alive
and 150,000 if you don't mind he's dead.
I only take gold. Here's my number.
Call me after you've thought about it.
The newspaper has been used.
The one who placed the advertisement is
not here for the babies. Warn the others.
-Yes, sir.
-Mrs. Lau, you may go.
Please show me your pass.
What brings you here tonight?
I promised the head nurse
to come and help every alternate day.
-The old lady up there--
-Won't do physiotherapy without you.
So you know that already.
I'm busy. I can't take care of you.
-Stay safe.
-You too.
Are you the one who placed
the advertisement?
Are you a cop?
Listen.
I'm going to kill all the babies tonight.
What are you doing?
No!
Don't move or I'll kill her!
Calm down.
Drop that!
Or I'll kill her!
Drop that knife first!
-I'll kill her!
-Okay! I'm dropping it!
Go inside!
I'll kill her!
Those doctors killed my son.
This is my revenge!
-I'll kill all those babies!
-Dr. Wong.
Please hurry to the emergency ward.
Dr. Wong, please hurry to the emergency--
I'll kill all the babies!
You're bleeding!
Wipe it off.
I'm fine.
Hey.
Do you think we can break down the door?
No way, it's too thick.
Let me try.
The keys are just outside.
Just a bit more and I could get them!
Calm down.
The madman won't be back so soon.
I'm only worried about the babies.
Didn't you hear what he said just now?
Let me try.
Why aren't you leaving?
Roger that.
Stay calm, speak slowly.
-Just one person?
-Yes!
You are late! Are you new here?
Take him out.
-Yes, sir!
Don't move! Get up!
-I'll kill all the babies!
-Move!
Dear!
Dear?
-I have captured the madman.
-I know.
Thank you for informing me on time.
-I didn't come here for nothing.
-Come here.
-Any rewards?
-No!
-Don't keep the old lady waiting.
-It's done already.
Naughty! Are you laughing at me?
Are you leaving with me?
No. The real one hasn't turned up yet.
What?
Why are you surprised?
You're nosy. Let's go for a ride.
Let's go!
Officer Lau, someone is kidnapping a baby.
Don't shoot! The baby might be in there!
Attention. Don't fire!
Don't fire!
I'm leaving!
-Go after her!
The Thief Catcher?
Hey, Nosy. What's with your mouth?
Don't sleep. More fun is coming.
Isn't it fun?
There you are. Follow me!
Let's take a rest first.
I can't believe you still can't get me.
What a shame.
Not even a noise? That's sinister!
So you're a woman!
So you're a bitch!
Hey.
Why did you kidnap all those babies?
What? You're blaming me for that?
You look pretty smart.
-Are you that Wonder Woman?
-Are you the Thief Catcher?
Don't get in my way then!
How could you use a baby
as your bait?
How despicable!
That's enough!
Put the baby down first.
Let's see if you can make me do that!
That was just a warm-up.
Now, it's the real thing!
Hey, wait!
What's happening?
Invisible Woman?
There's one more person here?
She seems to be on my side.
The baby!
Be careful!
How's the baby? Hey!
Wait, who are you? Hey!
Everything's fine now.
All right, don't test my patience!
Who are you?
Let's go, Chan Chat!
Chan Sum? It's you?
Let's go!
Don't pull me! I can walk on my own!
Chief, I suspect
the Thief Catcher you hired is the one
behind this incident today.
How do you know?
Ask her to bring the baby back at once.
Call the doctor.
How's the baby?
-Save him.
-You can count on me.
To the emergency ward!
PEOPLE'S HOSPITAL
Doctor, how's the baby?
I'm sorry, it's too late.
I couldn't save him.
Call his parents.
Yes, sir.
Ching-ching, don't go!
Our master hates idiots like me.
I'll miss you.
Take care of yourself.
Don't cry.
Ching-ching!
Let her go!
Kneel down.
Tung-tung.
You must stay here
and fulfill the fate you
and your martial sister shared alone.
You're going to uphold justice for me
on your own.
Tung-tung, why are you crying?
No, I'm not.
Tell me why.
It's nothing.
How's the case today?
The missing baby fell to his death.
It has been ten years. You're still great.
Where did that monster
get an invisible robe?
He's behind all this.
Are you going to interfere?
No, thank you.
When I escaped from that cave,
you spared me
even though you've already caught me.
Now I'm taking good care of myself.
What does he want so many babies for?
He'll choose one to be the emperor
in the next eclipse.
And the rest
will become his killers like us?
Moreover, Master would even
turn them into Chan Gau.
Chan Sum, do them a favor.
Just kill the babies.
That monster has corrupted me
for three years.
After I had escaped,
I've spent ten years
to return to normal!
I don't want the babies
to become monsters.
Just pretend that you know nothing
and leave them alone.
If Master gives the order,
I'd kill you as well.
Do it then!
You won't be so lucky next time!
Now that you've told me everything,
how can I feign ignorance?
You won't be called Ching-ching anymore.
From now on, you are Chan Sum!
You must get
the invisible robe in ten days
and kill the professor after that.
Do it or you'll die.
Hey, what are you doing?
I've told you many times.
It's dangerous here. Leave, please!
What's so dangerous? You're always here.
Are you keeping something from me?
You already know everything.
You said the robe is mine too,
but I didn't know it can stand UV light.
No, it still can't.
You'll be the first one to know if it can.
What have you been working on
these past few days then?
I'm working on this Revival Box.
These were dead before,
but they are alive again.
Do they have any flowers?
Yes. They will bloom in a month.
Sum-ching.
Will you put them under the sun every day
and water them at night?
You taught me
how to make these lucky stars.
You'll see them bloom.
You must get
the invisible robe in ten days
and kill the professor after that.
Do it or you'll die.
Hey! Your men kept me for over two hours!
Don't blame me. It was an accident!
Accident?
The baby died because of you!
What? I didn't drop him!
It's Wonder Woman's fault
that she couldn't save him!
You may go now,
but you can't deceive yourself.
Hey! Enough!
Stop making me the scapegoat!
Fine, it's my loss.
I'll keep an eye on it.
Keep an extra eye on my son, miss.
-Don't worry, I'll help my client.
-Thank you!
I'm just asking for trouble!
Done.
Why are there so many birdcages?
This is bad! That monster is here!
Hey!
I still got hit!
Let's see how long you can stand it.
Do you know
who the intruder was?
No.
I have someone in mind,
but she should have died ten years ago.
Yes.
I killed Chan Chat myself.
Now, only Wonder Woman
could get in by herself.
She has been meddling with our plan.
She's probably the intruder.
Let me kill her, Master.
Leave it to the others.
Chan Gau.
Kill the woman.
And if necessary,
die with her.
You damned monster.
I won't let the needles go up to my head.
We proved that this case is unrelated
to the previous incidents.
We promised the mayor
it wouldn't happen again.
Here's your deposit!
-What deposit?
-I'm not pursuing your son's case!
Hey!
We'll talk later. I'm in a meeting.
No!
The deal is off!
Miss.
You must have gotten hold of something.
Please tell us for the babies' sake.
What good would it do to me?
You won't hire me if you can handle it.
-For justice, you should--
-To hell with justice!
I almost got killed!
You killed the baby!
Tell me what you know.
Do you think I'd listen to you?
You will.
When that baby is falling down,
you saved it without a second thought.
Yes, I killed the baby.
But I'm dying too.
We are even now!
Won't you leave me alone?
I only want to die in peace!
I want to know who took the babies.
Don't hurt the Invisible Woman!
She's only a puppet.
That damned monster!
I won't let his needles kill me.
Don't do that!
Go away before I lose my mind.
I'm not leaving.
You'll die!
It's fine to die for a good reason.
I can stop the needles from going further,
but I can't get them out.
Okay, I'll use the time you bought me
to get the babies back.
If we succeed,
-we must get Chan Sum to help us.
-The Invisible Woman?
Yes.
Before I find her, we must be careful.
That monster discovered me
when I sneaked into his cave last time.
He thought it was you.
So he is sending Chan Gau to kill you now.
Officer Lau, a madman is holding hostage
dozens of people in the station
and destroyed
the station's computer system.
A cargo train is charging
toward the station now.
When will it hit the station?
In about five minutes.
Got it.
All units, get ready!
Be careful of the land mines!
Don't step on them!
Don't move!
Be careful! There are land mines!
Watch out!
Go now!
The train will crash in one minute.
Go in there!
Save the hostages inside first.
Why aren't you going in?
Run!
Brace yourself!
Leave it to me!
Run!
Sir, how can we stop the train?
The madman has destroyed the computer!
It can't be stopped. Go quickly!
LEI HO
CHEK FUNG
Run! The train is here!
Take it!
Let's go!
Dear.
What did the doctor say?
If you're lucky,
you can walk in six months.
Otherwise?
Otherwise,
you may become a cripple.
Cheer up.
As Wonder Woman's husband,
I'll always stand by you.
When did you find out?
At the station,
when you looked at me,
unwilling to go in.
No more secret smiles from now on
and no more secret tears.
Just tell me everything.
Okay?
Dear.
Hey! There's a flower bud--
What's wrong? Sit down first.
No, I just got a clue.
I must write it down now!
Sit down first.
Leave now!
How long have you known about it?
I've always known about it.
In the process,
I found that the invisible robe
emits toxins.
That's why I always tell you
to stay out of here.
But a flower bud has grown.
I'll be okay if the flowers can be saved.
Come on, get out of here.
We are partners.
How can I leave you like this?
Where are my glasses?
You're wearing them.
Before the robe is finished,
I will not die.
I can still smell the fragrance
in your hair.
Let's look at the flowers outside.
I'll be fine.
Get out of here!
Let me in!
I won't go out even if you can get in.
The robe will be ready
when the flowers bloom.
You promised
to take care of them until then.
Have you forgotten about that?
Chan Sum.
Why are you still meeting that monster?
He won't let the professor live anyway.
He'll kill him once the robe is finished!
How many needles were you attacked with?
If you help us,
Wonder Woman and I
may stand a chance to kill him.
If you fear death so much,
how can you help Wonder Woman?
I won't thank you.
You saved my life.
But to protect the professor,
you let that monster control you.
You have harmed so many babies.
You can deceive others but not yourself.
Wonder Woman can help you now.
I'll see you at the same spot tomorrow.
I'll wait until you come!
You'd better come.
I don't have time. Please hurry.
I did it!
Sum-ching!
Lucky star.
Sum-ching, the invisible robe
is finally finished.
Why haven't you gotten that robe?
It can't work under the sun yet.
The strength of the Emperor's army
will be reduced.
It'll soon be finished.
Give the professor a few more days.
Get it no matter what
before sunset tomorrow.
Chan Gau will help you then.
Master, all my work in your great plan
are inconsequential.
If I find an emperor among those babies,
you'll be honored for your services.
All princes should be asleep.
You should go to sleep too.
September 18th.
Today,
I've finally solved the UV light problem.
But I've also reached
the end of my life too.
From the first day when
I started working on the invisible robe,
I knew I would die from the toxins.
Without Sum-ching,
I wouldn't have been able to face it.
If she knows that my only hope now
is to take her hands
and witness the flowers bloom,
will she still kill me?
The day has come.
Regardless of the progress,
get the invisible robe
and kill the professor.
TELEPHONE BOOTH
Professor, I'll never return to you.
I won't leave until I see you.
Believe me.
You are in great danger.
Leave the lab now.
Damn it!
Even Wonder Woman is late.
I shouldn't have promised to come.
Should I leave or not?
Great. There you are.
Master sent me to kill you.
Wait, Chan Sum.
I won't let you go this time.
Can you really do it?
I must execute Master's order.
But I can promise you
that I'll do you a favor after you die.
Wait, it might be you who'll die.
Tell me your last wish. Tell me!
-Take care of the professor.
-The professor?
Save the professor for me.
Chan Sum, what are you doing?
She didn't come to kill you.
She came to kill herself.
You are giving up your life to save him?
My life?
I am just Master's killing machine.
A machine won't have feelings
or sacrifice themselves for someone.
Life is meaningful
if you can face yourself.
Not just myself,
but I can't even face him!
Chan Sum!
So you're all leaving?
Damn, can't you stay put?
My own bike is better.
Wait for me!
Chan Sum!
You can change yourself from now on!
So what? I'm still Chan Sum!
You can be another Chan Chat!
It's too late! Leave me alone!
Shit! Even a bike can't catch up?
Go!
You've shunned your past.
This is your true self!
I shouldn't live then!
No!
This is bad!
You two are in great trouble!
So lucky. Brace yourselves!
Tung-tung?
Ching-ching?
Let go of my hand
or we'll both fall!
No!
Grab it!
I can't hold on any longer!
I won't let go!
We must be together.
It's really you.
You two knew each other?
-I don't remember.
-The past is trivial.
What matters is
the thing you wish to do now.
Hey! What do you want to do?
Master sent Chan Gau
to kill the professor.
I want to save him.
The professor?
Give it to me.
The invisible robe
can withstand UV light now.
Nobody can find it.
No!
Sum-ching.
I have so much to tell you.
It's all inside the gift box.
It doesn't matter how hard you hit him.
He'll stick to what he wants.
No!
You can't give it to him.
I have lost everything.
I can't let him die.
I'm sorry.
I knew Master can't make you kill me.
It won't be that easy!
Wait, hold on!
Idiot, here's the tape.
Come and get it!
Goodbye!
It's too hot here!
Sum-ching, it's better
to have it destroyed
than to let him have it.
Hey! Let's go!
Go ahead.
-What about--
-Let her be.
Where are we going?
To save the babies from the cave.
Just the two of us?
Let me get my stuff first.
May I look at the blooming flowers?
All the babies are here.
Don't touch anything.
The babies will die if we fight here.
You damned monster, come on and die!
Beware. This place is full of methane.
You damned monster like methane
more than oxygen.
I'll kill you.
How dare you come here!
Attack her!
Special powers?
You are kneeling to him now?
Weren't you bold before?
I can't help it.
My legs feel like jelly.
Do you think someone like you can beat me?
It's no use kneeling to me. Guards, go!
-Yes!
We have no way out now.
Deal with Master, I'll handle the others.
Go!
It's an honor to die by my hands.
Damn it. I think I'm high on methane.
What should we do? We can't beat him.
Don't let him concentrate. Go!
I'll kill you this time.
Tung-tung, go with Chan Chat!
-No, I'll fight until the end!
-No!
You'll be poisoned if you stay.
Let's go!
I'll need some oxygen.
Go to hell, all of you!
He must have been
blown up to pieces this time.
Why is this one so late? He's still alive!
Damn you!
He's afraid of lights.
Give me some more.
Is my face still pretty?
What?
I don't know if you're fine or not,
but you scared me to death!
He's still alive?
How is this possible?
We destroyed his body,
but his mind is still there.
He has gained control over me!
Let me help you.
Don't come near me!
I can't control myself!
Go. Quick!
Go with Chan Chat!
-What should we do?
-Go!
Ching-ching!
Don't let me do it again!
Fuck you!
Die!
Go!
You son of a bitch!
He's controlling my body, go!
We won't leave you behind!
I'm happy to have met you again!
I'm sorry!
Chan Sum!
-Chan Sum!
-Ching-ching!
I'll die with you, damned monster!
China must have an emperor.
What's important is today, not the past.
China must have an emperor!
Can we see the blooming flowers together?
Professor!
Ching-ching.
You won't die.
Hey!
Get on the ground before you talk.
Otherwise, I'll die!
Are you okay?
Where's Chan Chat?
I got something good!
Take one, or when the press comes,
we'll look shabby!
Come on, put them on!
The police have solved
the missing babies case.
Most of the missing babies
have been found.
Here's our live report.
We heard that
three unknown heroines solved it.
How are they related to the police?
They are close friends of the police.
Who are they?
No comment.
When will they come again?
When we need them.
Do you know their names?
-Their names?
-Yes, their names.
They are called The Heroic Trio.
-The Heroic Trio?
-When did we get that name?
-How do you know that?
-Where does the name come from?
-It's top-secret, I'm sorry.
I was just improvising it a bit.