Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Julia...
Look at the camera.
-Way. I have my hair washed.
Say 'congratulations'.
Dad Are you his camera?
-It's for grandma. Say 'congratulations'.
Day, Mom.
Congratulations on your birthday. I love you.
And now on the side.
Joanne...
You should congratulate grandma.
-I'm busy.
Congratulations, Grandma. Satisfied?
Andrew, we must go now.
There you are. What are you doing?
-It's for grandma.
What do you mean?
-She's birthday?
Hello, Olivia.
We're about to sail. Nice to see you.
Congratulations. Another year there.
That's enough.
Come on, Andrew.
-Congratulations, Grandma.
Give it to mama.
-Where's his jacket?
The transcripts.
He ​​really said anything.
Gail, you can delete the journey from Calcutta
?
It must be a holiday look.
-I'm trying.
What would a holiday be like?
-Lndia.
Selective with the truth.
-If they do not see. But I must.
We received this morning a complaint from the widow of a certain someone.
A total of seven zeros.
I called him a liar.
And he is.
Is that it?
What beautiful.
What a fabulous zebra.
For Jack, Julia, Joanne and Andrew,
gave my life a new perspective.
We have a deal.
I was certainly not forgotten.
You have your whole life ugly.
-I hate you.
Look what I got.
-The newspaper.
No, tickets.
Morning, Mom.
Mom, Joanne wanted my...
-Dad has something.
Quiet, you.
Morning, honey.
I got here five return tickets
for lndia in my hand.
're Kidding.
-With Indians?
Lndia, sucker.
And then Corfu?
A week on the beach in Goa.
Delhi, the Taj Mahal and Agra.
And then to Bombay and back in time
for Chelsea against Spurs.
I'm going back to bed.
-Pick them at once.
Honey, forget lunch, do you?
You have canceled our trip, huh?
-Lndia is truly a unique opportunity.
The Germans want to build a dam in Madhya Pradesh
.
You did Europe do?
-It's just an article.
And some interviews.
-And the tea with the Prime Minister.
If you go to lndia,
need you to tea with the Prime Minister.
Nobody wants more time to spend in the office.
We go to lndia.
You could go sailing with Andy.
And Joanne...
The kids love it.
-Because you take them.
Before you know it, they're great.
Bit tumble?
Here you mean nothing.
Want something to eat?
It is amazing,
though this is our last safe meal.
I have unfortunately bad news. There is a small problem
and we must flee.
There is no danger,
but we must follow the rules...
And therefore we land in Limassol,
where the repair is performed.
You belt.
Why did you do that?
-Belt fixed.
Can not we stay?
Then we rent a fishing boat.
Nice sunbathing, swimming, sleeping.
Come on.
Mom, we're going back.
Boots.
That is not .
Sitting.
The August 15th Movement
takes flight. Stay put.
Stay put. It's okay.
We are being hijacked.
Thanks, friend. Well done.
Takeoff. Flying.
Here captain Mays.
The situation is very dangerous.
This is a U.S. aircraft.
Say Foreign Affairs...
Them in an hour
$ 50,000,000 wish.
I do not negotiate.
We're all going to.
The money is now created.
Let the others stand ready.
Okay?
-Yes.
He peed his pants.
'll Be fine.
I love you.
To our requirements.
The August 15th Movement
Therefore let all the women and children Fri
All others must wait.
Let  bags here. Come forward.
Grab your stuff, Andrew.
Go along with mom. I come later.
Stay with your mother.
Mommy, help me.
As if all your limbs...
Very slowly be deducted.
It's late. Dress it out,
Go on, boy.
Crying helps.
Not at all.
No, you're right.
It does not help.
You're early.
-I try the files for.
I'm trying to understand.
It to me to work.
It seems so...
It was a beautiful service.
She liked you very much.
Why I did not stay.
When it comes to emotions,
I am nowhere.
I have no milk, but...
-It only takes a minute.
The Sûreté, our embassy
these photos sent. They are from the CIA.
These are lvanic Loyvek
What is this?
-It is announced today.
I thought that I could tell you better.
What?
These are the surviving hijackers.
They were released two days ago.
No indictment. No arrest.
Not believe.
It's true.
They are at liberty.
There is no precedent in
national or international law.
And it is morally reprehensible.
The Minister of Foreign Affairs should
next week a motion at the UN.
If someone can prove that the U.S. has paid the ransom...
You might have a case there.
I'm sorry that we could not do.
What did the government?
-How does your son is?
I want to say that the British and American governments...
Should do something for the hijackers to justice.
There are 15 deaths.
My wife, my daughters...
And neither the U.S., nor the British government...
Should they just let you down.
What do you want the government doing?
The hijackers justice. Nothing more.
Thanks for your help.
Let the Russians they put pressure on, Senator.
Marley Wilson, New Yor tiimes.
And you have to call back Bobby.
I would really appreciate it if you can call your
committee.
Thank you.
Waste of time.
I hoped al Could you...
That would be great.
Does anyone on the U.S. embassy
what really happened?
Davidson, the American negotiator
in Cyprus.
Not a very high,
but he is not so timid.
Have I met him when Bush was here?
I'll make an appointment.
Your office?
Ln Washington comes
discussed in the Senate and then in Congress.
And what's it up to?
A motion of censure?
Here are the murderers of fear.
You do not even know that the Serbs.
The U.S. has little room to maneuver.
Sorry, but everyone says.
And nobody does anything.
Since the demise of the Soviet Union
is full of these gangs.
All have security specialists.
And a problem:
they talk to each other.
Our information comes from contacts that we have, insiders.
Your kind of work.
Where are you going?
Can we completely off the record talk?
Walk with me.
Officially we are powerless.
There is nothing happening.
If you want to get something done, you need to set
glitches make.
How?
Help me to help you.
Journalists know how to get a foot in the door.
Every week there seems to be a scandal.
-But we are not a tabloid.
I will try to help you.
On discreetly.
If you discovered something interesting...
Those things happen. Unofficially.
My son has no mother.
He ​​needs me.
Perhaps you owe them more.
Mrs. Tarnower?
Your husband was involved in the hijacking of the plane in Limassol.
Do you know why his name was not on the victim
list in the newspaper?
Thank you.
Whoever you are, get lost.
Kate...
I'm sorry...
-I need your help.
My best article ever I love you.
No one knew you was the source.
I know.
But then I got no promotion.
It probably had more to do with my tits
than my work.
I got a desk job.
You've got a great research department.
I'm not their possession.
And you know more than most people.
Are you flatter me or to decorate?
What the hell.
Do you know him?
Can you find out who he is?
American? Brit?
-Josse. He sat on the plane.
He was shot,
but he is not on the list.
What are you looking for?
I'm trying to figure out...
What's going on.
These people are released.
Was that a secret deal?
Are the Americans behind?
No one tells me anything.
You are looking  them, huh? It's scum. Even
governments have no control.
It does not matter who they have to kill or why.
And they do not like
if you are looking for.
I was not going to tell them.
This is all I have.
I wanted to maybe buy a boat.
A sailboat.
Nine meters long. Cabin on it.
A nice thing.
For a holiday or a flight?
Who knows.
You always think they're somewhere else
. But they're here.
France is a police state.
Germany has an efficient police.
No one seeks them here.
And your cells have
beds, tap water and TV.
So I should just see if I can loswroeten
.
And then?
Downing Street asking for a protest to?
That seems very sensible.
For whom?
Can I borrow your phone?
Mine is on the embassy.
I wish I could help you. But
because of my job, I can not.
They all say that.
I'm sorry, wrong number.
Sometimes what you want at your fingertips.
The Free Serbian Press.
What can I do for you?
I got it.
The editor called Matanovic.
I will look what I can find about him.
I'm looking for Mr. Matanovic.
-Right there.
Can you tell me what you know of
August 15th Movement?
No one knows them.
Says the date August 15 for something?
Nothing at all. If I knew what,
I have informed the authorities.
I leave this behind for
if you remember anything.
Can you help me? With whatever.
It might be nothing, but more
I have not.
A house in Albert Dock where
meetings.
I do not believe in the killing of innocents.
He expected you al
Jules Bernard.
FBI.
He's with us.
-Flown First Class?
He lets you see
official documents showing...
We are fond of.
I love me quiet.
Welcome to London. They say it is
hip again, but I know nothing about.
Why are you still on?
Small monkey of me.
-You're home.
He could not sleep, so we went
cards.
The three men were released are in Europe.
There is protested by
State Department and the U.S. Secretary Loomis.
I read.
What is "protest"?
-He accepts my definition.
You go upstairs.
Then I tell you that my definition.
You look like shit.
And I can know.
Have you discovered something about that bald?
A courier. Some bobo.
What did he have with him?
-No idea.
I do not know.
Are you okay?
I have some papers with me.
It's probably nothing,
but you can translate them for me?
A Serbia r.
Assassin.
Never afraid to return.
Wait, Jack.
If you've got there broke
and those papers have stolen...
Why do I ask it?
-Then I'm a murderer.
Self defense is not murder.
-Unless it feels good.
Everyone has dreams.
-And yours are about weapons?
And indescribable tools...
To torture.
They are a bit impatient.
I'm three minutes late. Let them
even 1000 years waiting to vote.
I'm talking about women.
The top expects you a little...
This jacket is standard here?
There is no dress code.
-Pity.
And the people I wanted to have?
You have five juniors
assigned. And me.
The dead in Shepherd's Bush Serf.
The Bosnian named Leo Hasse.
A political assassin.
That's it.
They probably had something in common.
Yes, they're all dead.
How can you be so sure this
something has to do with politics?
Everything is politics.
Philosophically speaking.
I suspect that the thieves were.
-If you want evidence or suspicions?
Hoods, Jules.
It was an American plane.
That's why Jules here.
To $ 50 million to trace.
And to bring the perpetrators to account.
He has unlimited co-
get.
That's a long time since someone I
'unlimited' I hear you say.
Maybe it's better if you take leave.
Write a book,
go to the beach.
Better for whom?
-Go to a therapist.
In order to process your anger.
-My anger is all I have left.
If you take away,
I can shake it.
Mr. Dusan, have you heard that
Maldic arrives at St Pancras?
You should not have called me.
Should I come to you?
-This conversation is pointless.
Do you sometimes prefer
I come home with you?
Okay. Tonight at ten o'clock
the old market.
Then.
If 15 oranges 6 pounds 75 costs...
How much does an orange then?
45 pence.
-Right.
I had you still help? Answers
-giving is not helping.
That is to say.
I tested you briefly.
Goodnight, genius.
I have another nightmare.
There was someone in the house
looking for something.
We will soon be gone.
Then we sail with a boat
to where the wind takes us.
You're talking like your neck.
You have your sister beaten, says mum.
Is that so?
You have the words to cope with this.
Apologize.
Goodnight. Give me mommy moment.
Should she leave? I should also hang.
Sorry, hearing.
Ordinary life goes on.
We think Albert Dock
went to a fight about money.
But Mr. Bernard
is not agree.
One of the weapons is also used for killing
Dusan Velikovic.
And what's the connection?
-I wish I knew.
Money.
We examine hairs and palm prints. Anything can be.
But that still does nothing. Money is not
't only motive for these murders.
With the right motive can we invent
perhaps related.
It would be nice if anyone was killed.
Welcome to St. Pancras.
Never leave your luggage unattended.
Unattended baggage must be reported to the stationmaster.
Are there any messages for me?
-Yes, one.
A pleasant stay.
He looks to his knees and says:
Knees, today you have become 84.
He looks down again...
And looks at the part where you just though and says:
And as for you...
If you had lived,
were you today become 84.
I just grab your change.
This is undrinkable. It has cork.
Not that expensive words.
Try it.
No, I do not drink.
I do not care, it's undrinkable.
-Keep my glass throughout.
Do not interfere with my customers.
You go.
And now I ask Mr. Peter John
back on stage...
With the beautiful song
After the War to sing.
Sorry I did unkind.
You have those days.
But the show was wonderful.
-So you'll come back again?
And then a little nicer, eh?
The calls he committed.
We work really that bad.
St. Pancras.
Good work.
-My favorite station.
Karadan Maldic is a taxi driver
£ 1 30 guilty.
But there were 100,000 Swiss francs in his locker.
And some very interesting documents.
For those who do not know Serbian...
There are two times a few
very American words:
$ 50,000,000.
The slachtofferwas one of the hijackers.
What was he doing here?
He was involved in the Balkan gangs
and Albert Dock.
Good work, Jules.
Foreign Affairs wants his money back.
That money's evidence.
-They look much more.
Once we found it.
We have something overlooked.
Check that passenger list again.
Every survivor needs to be questioned.
I'm their declarations
again read.
Check
anyone who has lost a family member.
A list of 15 Britons
who survived...
Or family of the dead.
Note Slavic connections,
a military background...
Or an academic degree.
Someone knows more than we do and pops them upside down.
And he she us on a silver platter delivered.
There is burgled last week.
Oh yeah?
What were they?
-My arms.
A couple of guys who murdered
hijackers seem to be.
Pity.
I've heard that the leader of that
hijacking in Paris.
Oh yeah? What's his name?
His name lvanic Loyvek.
This is a strange rabbit.
-I reacted purely instinctive.
I'm Jules Bernard. I work together with the
antiterrorist unit in London.
I already made a statement.
These are just...
Do you want a cup of coffee?
Seat.
No, I prefer to stand.
Can you tell me where you
Friday after eight uurwas?
This was still on Cyprus?
Everything has to do with each.
Really, this is just a routine...
-A routine examination.
But why Friday?
For a country where citizens
no weapons allowed to wear...
There are many deaths.
I'm an editor at a magazine.
Friday?
I'm gone to the West End.
In an old-fashioned musical
at The Players Theatre.
We did previously.
I hoped it would happen to me some.
Jean, The Players Theatre.
Check one
Jack Elgin was there at eight o'clock.
What time did you leave?
-When the show was over.
Right. And what time was that?
Half-elf, quarter to eleven.
I hope we do not have to fall back tricky.
Thanks.
Where you parked that night?
I am gone underground.
Can we see a trace evidence
into the use of firearms?
That makes no sense. I am Saturday with friends
been hunting. Rabbits.
What hit?
-I'm a bad shooter. Two, three.
And a pheasant.
Thanks for coming.
... A theory that the murderers
with hijacking face.
Maybe I like
on the trail of the hijackers.
We have 40 people spoke,
relatives of the victims.
We have no suspects.
And Jack Elgin?
Jack Elgin.
He ​​wanted me to speak last month.
Why?
The withholding evidence is a crime.
I got the strong feeling that he was looking
...
To unofficial help.
What?
-Finding the killers.
Nonsense.
What about there with you?
Why did Karadan Maldic
from his hotel to your embassy?
I'll figure it out.
I was told that we still have a
hijacker localized. In Paris.
Lvanic Loyvek.
We think he their leiderwas.
Not bad, huh?
-Do you have the French police?
I light up.
My French is not good enough.
I want the names of everyone who
thereof is.
Do not think that you can sew me, Bernard.
Sweet, huh? Have fun.
Thanks, Kate.
Wait, I gotta tell you something.
I do not wanna hear.
-Shut up.
There are rules. Eye for an eye, says Moses.
Turn the other cheek, says Jesus.
Those bastards programs are free.
-The law does not always triumph.
Innocent die.
Criminals live.
You need to know who you are.
Do not lose yourself.
That would be a crime.
Whatever mistakes you have committed.
Should you so hard? The lime...
My dochterwil eat.
Good afternoon. Are you Stephane Marit?
Can we see your papers?
I'll be.
The girl in the pub remembers him.
The time is correct.
He had never enough time.
-Why you mark him or not?
Maybe because that girl said that he complained.
Or because he said that he was a bad schutterwas.
But mainly because it all
very fortuitous.
He was going hunting.
Rabbits.
And a pheasant, which is not allowed.
Kulindos says that the off season.
Sat Simons at the restaurant?
Have you checked?
His friend took him to the train from Paris.
Maldic was killed with a Walther Automatic.
And who was there last week
one lost?
I want to talk to him.
Find him. I want to talk to him.
This is the main agent Kulindos.
And this is Jack Elgin.
Come on, Andrew.
-I need your help.
Give me your bag.
Ever heard of one Davidson?
Of Foreign Affairs.
Your government did not cooperate.
He ​​has encouraged you to see what you could rake up, huh?
You can tell me.
That was all.
Give your wallet.
-You heard him. Hurry up.
I had to catch up.
-I'm glad that finally happens.
I was screwed. Also American,
good connections, they said.
I close the file-Elgin.
No proof. No weapon.
No witness.
And a very good alibi.
-And a very good motive.
He is not addressing.
The head of the CIA
would still vouch for him.
Yes, I really do.
He was in Paris when
lvanic officer who slammed down.
Can I have a glass of water?
You must surely go to Paris?
-Maybe it's better this way.
Him alone.
Yes, I think that is wise.
Tentative.
Let him alone.
I will.
Are you all right, Bernard?
It's getting better.
Napoleon said an enemy
committed when he makes a mistake.
All I need to report.
Book a flight to Washington DC.
From Heathrow, around six o'clock.
Make sure you're here continuously.
What you need, let you bring.
If you hear anything, call me.
And nobody else.
Except when I'm dead.
And what if I have to pee?
Come.
It's beautiful. There is a kitchen.
And beds. Everything is there.
You can live there.
A fine boat.
Thanks for looking.
Is he inspected?
-There's nothing wrong with that.
A coat of paint. New fall.
But also he is fine.
You have no more wind.
Turn the mainsail.
Not too close to the water.
This is me bored.
How was Paris?
Fun.
Yes, so. Good.
What were you doing there?
That's part of my job.
I'm going a few times a month back.
It's part of my job
things out.
You're a tough one.
-Should I be flattered?
Paris.
I'm working on a story.
French Armagnac.
The rising star in the world of spirits.
Armagnac. A drink, but you
chats from your neck.
You write an article about hijackers.
You knew lvanic in Paris Sat
Why you went there.
So?
-How did you know he was there?
Sources.
Did you find him?
-No.
The police also went to see him, but he shot them dead
and escaped.
He ​​left his daughter in their bodies behind.
Did you want to murder him?
That solves nothing.
If the murderer of my family
would meet...
I would want him dead.
A civilized man distinguishes between
and want to do.
And you've always been civilized?
I was tracking a terrorist.
And suddenly there are three dead
in Albert Dock, one in a taxi...
And someone somewhere in a market.
Do you know anything about that?
Only what I read in the papers.
The guy in the taxi, Karadan Maldic...
Is slain with a Walther PPK.
Such a weapon is stolen by your best friend.
I hate that kind of coincidences.
Find the thief and you have your killer.
My best friend had given me the key.
Maybe. Did you know that your best friend
good buddies was with Davidson?
Was?
-Francois Duguay was killed yesterday.
Kill.
I want all the hijackers arrested
still roam freely.
Do you want me for help?
I know nothing.
I'm on your side.
Play the game with me.
Set as those men you've killed...
Fine, I do not care.
And the jury will feel the same way thinking.
I'm not very good at games.
-Duguay was murdered last night.
And you're in danger.
You are so close that they can hear you breathing.
And I can protect you.
I'm more of them.
He does not do it, Dad.
What have you done? These belong in the
middle. You should not arrive.
Keep them in the middle. Go.
Who are you?
-That's a friend of mine.
I would him in a safe place
bring. Right now.
You must take responsibility for your child.
Get it  Screw you, asshole.
I want your help.
To the murderers of your family to find.
You have to give me something. Whatever.
There was a diplomatic courier
on that flight. He was slain.
Who knows has that got to do.
-Tarnower?
Lrrelevant. This is nothing politieks.
Well. It is August 15th Movement.
-My stupid cat called Einstein.
It's not how you call it.
This seemed just politics.
No, they believed in something.
It is an ordinary robbery.
-No, that's nonsense.
Your wife and daughters have died
for a check of 50 million.
I do not...
This is it.
Let's go, Andrew. It's going to rain.
I'm on your side.
Jack, I'm here.
When I was nine, my father sent me to military school
.
I learned everything.
Also to hide my feelings.
Americans flaunt that still correct?
You also boarding school.
You know what it did to us.
You will be hard to fathom.
In case you have not
clear, I want you to know...
You're a decent guy.
Vat you? You're a decent guy.
I hope you have something interesting to say.
Henry Davidson kluste a bit.
So? Everyone has to eat.
He used Francois Duguay.
-Francois Nobody used.
He did not know he was used.
That's why he killed.
Francois told you about lvanic, huh?
He had again Davidson.
But why should  Davidson,
an agent of the CIA...
You manipulate someone to murder?
That I did not understand...
So I have a microphone
in Davidson's hidden room.
The CIA searches which rooms
once a week.
What you learned?
Davidson led the entire operation.
What do you mean?
-Everything. Only the hijacking itself.
He ​​made the money to the account in Monaco.
He ​​wanted certain people that you would find.
You had to kill his partner.
He ​​led you right to them.
He watched as they were slain...
And those you missed,
he killed himself.
There is a meeting of European finance ministers.
Where you going, huh?
-Right.
How do you know?
-Because he knows.
There they go do it.
Ln a conference center?
This is so well protected.
You will have lunch with people.
A stroll,
a beer in the pub.
There are dozens of possibilities.
I say it off.
-What?
Then they do it another time.
If you do not want life.
You do not constantly afraid.
You want me to become a target.
-They have you on your back signed.
I do not have enough evidence to arrest you
.
But now I know something else.
That engine of yours.
This is very casual.
Want your son has a father?
That is only in this way.
Dear Jonesy, I was
lately quite closed...
But I hope that this week all will be well.
If not,
should you care for Andrew.
I got you in my will as
guardian appointed.
It's a sweet kid.
I know that you will find.
What I did, I did for my family
...
Whom I loved more than
of life.
There is also a letter to Andrew.
That you give him when he's older.
Sorry I opzadel this.
Your good friend Jack.
This is a hand grenade.
-It's like a bomb.
There is a delay of 12 seconds.
Do you think the army or something?
The police has long been well armed.
You do only if it is not.
And then say that cigarettes are bad for you.
The papers that I had to fill this...
So I stole them. Kulindos
was so angry that he wanted to show me.
I had already been home if
I had done it by the book.
Not yet changed his mind?
Get out.
Take it.
There are 15 patterns in it. Suit.
Cartridge holder.
And one in your pocket.
Ready?
-And a grenade.
And this will go away.
-Come on.
Inside.
Low continue.
You can keep...
Or you can leave.
It's over.
I'm glad to see you.
Driving.
Bernard had no permission for that microphone.
This certificate is not valid.
Only you remain.
And without you...
Those stupid Bernard.
We're in the shit because he steals things
undocumented form.
Why? It had only 12 seconds from
last. 12 seconds.
12 seconds. Nothing more.
Shut up.
To bed. Monday starts school.
-I do not.
Saturday  If the weather is good,
shall we go sailing together?
And if you're really good, you become the master and I
crew.
Are you still my dad?
From me you will not be so easy.
And now sleep. See you tomorrow.
Doing well, buddy.
Do not be too hard on yourself.
He ​​is a good father.
Who has denied what he believed.
Except him.
Watch the sail.
I can do it, Dad. l can.
And the fourth angel poured out his bowl on the sun...
And power was given him to scorch men with fire.
Revelation 16:8
Movie & Subs Ripped By;
(^ 8 Booster 8 ^)
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.OpenSubtitles.org