¶ I left my love, my love I left
¶ 我离开了我的爱人, 我的爱人我离开了
¶ A-sleeping in her bed
¶ 在她的床上睡觉
¶ I turned my back on my true love
¶ 我把我的真爱转到了背后
¶ Went fighting Johnny Reb
¶ 去同南军战斗
¶ I left my love a letter
¶ 我给爱人留了一封信
¶ In the holler of a tree
¶ 在树下叫喊
¶ I told her she would find me
¶ 我告诉她, 她会找到我
¶ In the US Cavalry
¶ 就在美国骑兵队里
¶ Hi-ho, down they go
¶ Hi-ho, 他们向下走了
¶ There's no such word as "can't"
¶ 这里没有象“不能”这样的话
¶ We'll ride clean down to hell and back
¶ 我们将把地狱清除干净再骑乘回归
¶ For Ulysses Simpson Grant
¶ 为了辛普森尤利西斯格兰特
¶ Hi-ho, down they go
¶ Hi-ho, 他们向下走了
¶ There's no such word as "can't"
¶ 这里没有象“不能”这样的话
¶ We'll ride clean down to hell and back
¶ 我们将把地狱清除干净再骑乘回归
¶ For Ulysses Simpson Grant
¶ 为了辛普森尤利西斯格兰特
¶ I left my love, my love I left
¶ 我离开了我的爱人, 我的爱人我离开了
¶ A-sleeping in her bed
¶ 在她的床上睡觉
¶ I turned my back on my true love
¶ 我把我的真爱转到了背后
¶ Went fighting Johnny Reb
¶ 去同南军战斗
¶ I left my love a letter
¶ 我给爱人留了一封信
¶ In the holler of a tree
¶ 在树下叫喊
¶ I told her she would find me
¶ 我告诉她, 她会找到我
¶ In the US Cavalry
¶ 就在美国骑兵队里
¶ Hi-ho, down they go
¶ Hi-ho, 他们向下走了
¶ There's no such word as "can't"
¶ 这里没有象“不能”这样的话
¶ We'll ride clean down to New Orleans
¶ 我们将飞马驰骋打到新噢尔良去
¶ For Ulysses Simpson Grant ¶
¶ 为了辛普森尤利西斯格兰特
[bell dings]
（叮铛钟声）
[bugle call]
（军号吹响）
General Hurlburt, by appointment.
赫尔伯特将军，照章办事.
- General Hurlburt and Colonel Marlowe.
- Steve, come in.
- 赫尔伯特将军和马洛上校. - 史蒂夫，请进.
Hello, Sam. Colonel Marlowe.
你好，山姆. 马洛上校.
[foreign language]
（外国语）
- General Sherman, Colonel Marlowe.
- How do you do?
- 谢尔曼将军, 马洛上校. - 你好吗？
Marlowe, I've been anxious to meet you.
马洛上校， 我一直急着要见见你.
- It's a privilege, sir. - Sit down.
- 这是一种特权, 先生. - 坐下吧.
- Is this your first look at Vicksburg? - Yes, sir.
- 这是你第一次来维克斯堡？ - 是的，先生.
We've been looking at it
for ten months, and we don't like it.
我们一直看着它十个月了, 而我们并不喜欢它.
Colonel, for your benefit, the war on our side
上校,为了你的利益,  我们这一边的战争
hasn't been going well at all.
完全进展得不是很顺利.
Not in Washington, not in the newspapers, not in the field.
不是在华盛顿, 不在报纸上, 也不是在这一战场.
To put it mildly, with less men and less resources,
说得委婉些吧, 缺少的是人力和资源，
the South has whipped us to a standstill.
南方军队打得我们停滞不前.
[distant cannon fire]
（远处加农炮开火）
Now, if I could take Vicksburg...
现在，如果我能拿下维克斯堡...
...the whole picture would change, but I'd have to do it this summer.
...整个战局会改变，但我不得不等到今年夏天才进行部署.
Or sit out here another year.
否则的话在这里坐等一年.
Which might cost us 100,000 men. It might cost us a war.
这可能会让我们投入十万人. 花费一场战争.
Which brings all this talk down to their main source of supply...
才能让它所涉及的主要来源供应这一切谈下来…
...and a thorn in our side.
…还有我们的眼中钉.
- Newton Station. - Sam.
- 牛顿站. - 山姆.
Marlowe has worked out the details of your plan pretty thoroughly.
马洛上校已将你的计划细节制定的非常彻底.
Let's hear them.
让我们听听他们的.
If I could get back to La Grange right away, we could leave by Thursday.
如果我能立即回到La山庄, 我们可以在周四离开.
Good. Who would your people be?
好. 你的人马会是谁?
My own First Illinois with Secord's First Michigan and Second Iowa.
我自己的伊利诺斯州密歇根第一骑兵队
与西科德的第一和爱荷华州第二骑兵队.
We'd be culled down to a short brigade.
我们会为精编骑兵旅挑选人员.
Cross at La Grange, down through Ripley, New Albany, Houston...
走过La山庄, 穿过雷普利, 新奥尔巴尼, 休斯顿……
- Is there something wrong, sir?
- I know the map, Colonel. Proce.
- 先生, 出什么错了吗?
- 上校，我知道这个地理位置, 步骤.
Anyway, the main trick is no fighting until we hit Newton Station.
总之，在我们到达牛顿站前主要技巧不是战斗.
How much track do you figure to destroy?
你想要摧毁的路径有多少？
As much as I can get my hands on.
差不多我可以亲自动手做到.
At least enough to keep them busy for a couple of months rebuilding.
至少足以让他们忙活几个月重建.
Otherwise, the raid would just be another horse ride.
否则，这次袭击由另一个骑兵队完成.
All right, Colonel, go ahead.
好了,上校, 请便.
All the rails, ties, buildings, bridges,
所有的铁路、关系、建筑、桥梁、
all the rolling stock you can get your hands on.
所有的车辆你都可以亲自接手.
Sam, even if he should manage to get through to Newton Station,
山姆, 他应该设法通过牛顿站,
he'd be 300 miles dead center in the Confederacy.
他在南部联盟300英里的死区内.
- Have you thought how you'd get back?
- Have you, sir?
- 你有没有想过你怎么回来吗?
- 先生,你有吗?
Well, I guess I asked for that.
哦, 我在猜测我询问的那个.
But I hate to think of you sitting it out in Andersonville Prison.
但是我不想你去坐安德森威尔监狱.
- It's a hellhole.
- I'd think about that twice, too, sir.
- 它是个地狱.
- 我也一直在考虑着，先生.
Well, Colonel, your success.
好了, 上校, 祝你胜利.
[bugle call]
（军号吹响）
All right, here is La Grange.
好吧, 这里是La山庄.
- We will make 35 miles a day, average.
- 35?
- 我们平均一天走三十五英里.
- 三十五？
- 35? Isn't that stretching it a bit?
- It will be the first day, Ned.
- 三十五？路程是不是有点长?
- 第一天的路程是要长点，内德.
I intend to make twice that distance.
In an operation like this,
我尝试将距离延长一倍. 就像这次行动，
everything is stretched. Even our necks...
一切都在延长. 甚至是我们的脖子...
Now, just hold on a minute, John.
现在，暂时停留一分钟，约翰.
Regarding cutting the men's rations from five days to three...
想想切断他们三五天的粮食供应...
They'll have to live off the land eventually.
最终他们将不得不靠土地.
They might as well get used to it while they're fresh.
他们不妨习惯它, 因为他们毫无经验.
They actually seem excited.
他们看上去很兴奋.
There's a rumor around camp they're headed for Nashville in a parade.
营地里有谣言称他们前往纳什维尔去游行.
That was a good rumor to spread, with the help of the Sergeant Major.
这是一次很好的谣言传播, 对军士长有帮助的.
- Thank you, sir. - And, gentlemen,
- 谢谢你，先生. - 还有绅士，
I'll have to admit they had me fooled too. [chuckles]
我不得不承认他们愚弄了我. （轻声笑着）
You see, I was going to use my leave to do a little electioneering back home.
你看，我正为回家做一点竞选活动.
You know, shake a few hands, kiss a few babies.
你知道, 跟人们握下手, 亲吻婴儿.
You see, I'm running for Congress this fall.
今年秋天我去跑跑国会.
Well, there's 30,000 votes at Andersonville, Phil.
嗯, 在安德森威尔和菲尔有三万张选票..
I hope you don't get to shake any of their hands.
我希望你不会和他们任何人握手.
Leaves are being cancelled,
离开者的资格被取消了，
Orders to reshoe the whole blasted outfit,
遵照命令去重做全部坏掉的外套，
and some of them shoes ain't even shiny yet.
甚至和他们中的不是很亮的一些鞋子.
- Yep. - [strumming banjo]
- 是的.  - [弹奏班卓琴]
I'm trying to figure out what's up.
我正想弄清楚怎么回事.
They've been sitting under that tree all the morning.
他们整个早晨一直坐在那个树下.
I heard some scuttlebutt about us being pulled out for a big parade up North.
我听到一些是关于我们被扯到一个往北大游行的闲话.
- I figure we're heading for Nashville.
- That's to my liking.
- 我想我们正前往纳什维尔.
- 那正是我的喜好.
A parade, and then leave. Now this war is starting to shape up.
游行，然后离开. 现在这场战争开始成形了.
- Where's the officers' conference?
- Over under that tree yonder, sir.
- 军官会议在哪里开？
- 在那边的树下，先生.
- Thank you. - [man shouting orders]
- 谢谢你. -（喊着命令）
- My apologies for being late.
- Understood.
- 很抱歉我迟到了.
- 我理解.
- Sit down, Major.
- I don't believe I know the Major.
- 坐下吧，少校.
- 我不认为我认识少校.
I'm sorry. Colonel Marlowe, Major Kendall.
对不起，马洛上校. 这是肯德尔少校.
- How do you do?
- [Marlowe] Glad to know you.
- 你好吗？
-（马洛）很高兴认识你.
Major Kendall has just been assigned to us from General Grant's headquarters.
肯德尔少校刚刚被格兰特将军总部委派到我们这里.
The Major seems to be out of uniform. Where are your side arms, Kendall?
少校似乎卸下了军装. 你是哪方面军队的，肯德尔？
If you look in the book, you'll see a surgeon doesn't carry them.
如果你看这本书,你就会明白一个外科医生不带他们.
Surgeon? You cut out our artillery and our wagons. Nothing to slow us down.
外科医生？ 你删减掉我们的炮兵和马车. 一切让我们慢下来东西.
And now you saddle us with a doctor and a medical unit?
现在你却让医生和医疗器械成为我们的负担?
Regulations, John. Kendall goes along.
这是规定, 约翰. 肯德尔走.
Very well, sir. Any questions?
非常好，先生. 还有什么疑问？
All I can say is I'm glad for some action...
我所能说的是我乐意的一些行动...
No glory hunting, Richard.
并不是光荣的负伤，理查德.
If anything knocks this into a cocked hat, it'll be a firefight.
如果任何人敲这三角帽, 就交火.
- Is that all, sir?
- One thing.
- 是所有吗,先生?
- 一件事.
- Logan, is Brady ready?
- Yes, sir.
- 洛根, 布雷迪准备好了吗?
- 是的,先生.
Oh, a photograph... [trails off]
哦, 准备拍照…  (慢慢地)
Move away, move away. Move back.
移动，移动. 退后点.
Are you ready for us, Brady?
你为我们准备好了吗, 布雷迪?
[indistinct chatter]
(模糊地聊着)
[man] Colonel. Sit down, Colonel.
(人)上校. 坐下来, 上校.
- Thank you very much.
- That's all right.
- 非常感谢你.
- 好极了.
[Brady] Sit down, Marlowe. No hats, please, gentlemen.
(布雷迪)坐下来,马洛. 请摘掉帽子，先生们.
That's right. Nice and relaxed.
这才对. 放松点.
Now, roses are red, violets are blue, the camera's looking straight at you.
现在, 玫瑰是红色的, 紫罗兰是蓝色的, 相机正对着你.
Oh, I must have another one. That man in the white coat moved.
哦, 还有另外一个. 那个穿白色外套的人移动一下.
That isn't all he'll be moving before long. Sorry General, is that all?
这不是他将不久会移动.
对不起将军，都讲完了吗?
- That's all. Thank you, Mr. Brady.
- Kendall.
- 都讲完了. 谢谢，布雷迪先生.
- 肯德尔.
Thank you, General. Thank you very much.
谢谢你, 将军. 非常感谢你.
Sit down.
坐下.
Colonel, I gather you're not too happy about my going along.
上校, 我猜你不高兴我去.
I hadn't counted on you, that's all.
我没有指望你, 仅此而已.
I can understand your reasons for trying to avoid a fight,
我能理解你试图避免战斗的理由,
tactically speaking. But you're going very deep into enemy territory.
但从战术上来说. 你会很深入到敌占区.
Tell me, what did you intend to do about your wounded?
告诉我, 对于你的伤员你打算做什么?
I intend to move, and move fast.
我打算行动, 快速行动.
Those too badly shot up to carry on
那些太糟的伤员得坚持下去
will be left to the clemency of the enemy.
他们将会由仁慈的敌人来决定.
- Civilian or military.
- Including yourself?
- 平民或军人.
- 包括你自己吗?
Naturally.
理所当然的.
That's a pretty primitive attitude. Medically speaking.
从医学上来讲，这是一个非常原始的态度.
Well, Doctor, war isn't exactly a civilized business.
好吧, 医生, 战争并不是一个文明的业务.
Of course, I realize that it gives you fellas a wider field of opportunity...
当然, 我认为它将给你的伙计们更广领域的机会……
- For experimenting, Colonel?
- I didn't say that.
- 为了试验, 上校?
- 我没说.
- Mitch.
- Yes, sir?
- 米奇.
- 是的, 先生?
- Give the doctor a full roster.
- Yes, sir.
- 给医生一个完整的名单
- 是的, 先生.
Examine every man.
检查每个人.
Throw out any man who, in your unchallenged opinion,
淘汰任何你的不受挑战的观点的人，
of course, is unfit.
当然，是不合格的人.
Even those who might get sick a week from today.
即使是从今天起那些可能生病一个星期的人.
Look, Colonel, I didn't ask to be assigned to this mission.
看, 上校, 我没有要求接受这个任务.
I'm a military doctor. I've been ordered to go and I'm going to do my job.
我是军医. 得按命令去执行自己的本职工作.
So get off my back.
因此不要跟我罗嗦.
- Bugler!
- Yes, sir?
- 吹号手！
- 是，先生？
Get me Mitchell.
给我把米切尔叫来.
Sergeant Major Mitchell's in the hospital, sir.
米切尔军士长在医院里, 先生.
- How old are you?
- 32, sir.
- 你多大了？
- 三十二岁了，先生.
Join that group.
加入这个组.
Hang on, son. Here we go.
Yow!
[metal clanks]
This is going to hurt worse.
There. He'll be all right.
- I got your sick list, Kendall.
- Good. I'm glad it's a short one.
We'll let that drain full out.
- I approve of that, Doctor.
- The lad had quite a boil.
I didn't come here to watch you
carving anybody's behind.
- Why's Mitchell's name on that list?
- Sir, we observe quiet here.
- What's this?
- Hoppy, this is Colonel Marlowe.
How do you do? Stand in line.
We'll take care of you presently.
- Is he going with us?
- He's a good man. I need him.
And I need Mitchell.
He's strong as a bull...
Let me show you something.
Colonel, I've been trying to tell the
doctor that this is nothing unusual.
No, not for a man with malaria.
There's nothing new about this, Kendall.
I've seen him ride 40 miles
in one day, shivering in his saddle.
- He's had malaria twice as long as...
- So you concur in my diagnosis.
Come on Mitch, get out of bed.
I got some whiskey in my tent.
You stay where you are, Sergeant.
I was ordered to take off
the duty roster any man who,
in my unchallenged opinion, was unfit.
He's sick and he's going to stay here.
Those are my orders.
You've read the whole book, haven't you?
[kicks buckets]
Oh, Colonel!
We got that fella
with all them stripes for you.
- Bring him in.
- We hauled him right off the train.
- Sergeant Kirby reporting, sir.
- Well, Kirby.
Besides being slightly drunk,
what's got you riled up?
They got me in town.
Pulled me off the train.
Just gotten filled.
My first in two years.
They tell me you're good. You better be.
You're replacing the best soldier
in the regiment.
- I expect you to be happy about that.
- I could be happier where I was going.
- You got me there.
- No, sir, you got me here.
- Sir.
Alright, march this sergeant
down to the river and throw him in.
- Clothes and all?
- Clothes and all.
Pump him full of black coffee
till it runs out his ears.
Kirby, when you come back,
come back sober. You've got two hours.
- Parades, Nashville...
- You can leave that keg.
You're welcome to it... sir.
Kirby, you tangle with me
and I'll have your hide.
You're welcome to that too, sir.
If it's in the line of duty.
[clatters]
[bugle call]
- Forward, left!
- [man] Forward, left!
[men repeat]
- Yo!
- [man] Yo!
[men repeat]
¶ I left my love
My love I left, a-sleeping in her bed
¶ I turned my back on my true love
Went fighting Johnny Reb
¶ I left my love a letter
in the holler of a tree...
- Good luck, John.
- Thank you, sir.
¶ Hi-ho, down they go
There's no such word as "can't"
¶ We'll ride clean down to hell and back
for Ulysses Simpson Grant
¶ I left my love a letter
in the holler of a tree
¶ I told her she would find me
in the US Cavalry
¶ In the US Cavalry
¶ Hi-ho, down they go
There's no such word as "can't"
¶ We'll ride clean down to New Orleans
¶ For Ulysses Simpson Grant
[tempo slows] ¶ I left my love
My love I left
¶ A-sleeping in her bed ¶
Wait on here a minute.
The sun, it raises in the
east every time, don't it?
It sure does in Missouri.
For eight hours, with no turning,
we've been heading this way.
Now, if'n the sun raises in the east,
what direction is that?
- It ain't north.
- Course not. It's south.
Hey, we've been riding smack-dab
into reb territory.
[dog barking]
- Reb country, Richard.
- Yes, sir.
- Send out your scouts.
- [yells order]
[yells order]
[gunfire]
Are you going to call a halt, or lead
them to the clemency of the enemy?
Sound recall.
[blows bugle]
Just a patrol, sir. No sign of any
major force, as far as I could tell.
The fact remains we've been spotted.
The word's out for sure now.
They'll be back here with
everything available looking for us.
All right, Ned,
you can prepare to turn back.
That's a bad mistake, John,
splitting the force.
Now you need every man you've got.
Diversion be damned.
We've got to make them think that
we all turned back.
Oh, sure, sure.
But you out to remember that from now
on, every Johnny Reb with a gun
is going to be hiding behind a tree
trying to make a name for himself.
And you want to cut your force
by one third! Aw, John, listen to me.
There's an old axiom in politics:
you never split your ballot...
Richard, when the horses are watered
and the men are fed, we'll move out.
Yes, sir.
[man] Hey, Doctor.
These here contraband children say
there's something wrong at that cabin.
I guess they need a doctor.
All right.
- Are you the doctor?
- Yes, I am.
What happened?
It's Rainey, sir. Rainey the first.
He's dead.
Carry on.
Where's Kendall?
Dr. Kendall went over to that cabin
with some young colored people.
- An emergency, I believe.
- He what?!
He went over to that cabin
with some young colored people.
- Are you the doctor too?
- What? No, no.
[baby crying]
Kendall, what the devil are you doing?
We just delivered a baby.
It's a little girl.
You can take care of her now, Granny.
You're going to be all right.
We've got a couple of wounded men
out there, you know.
No, one's dead.
One's gone, one's born.
It's an amazing process, isn't it?
As many as I've delivered,
it never fails to awe me.
All right, children, you got a new
sister. Go in, take a look at her.
All right, Kendall.
Go back and take care of your wounded.
They'll be all right.
Hopkins knows what to do.
You're not a country sawbones. You're
an officer in the Union Army under oath.
I took an older oath before that one.
They didn't seem to be having any
trouble having babies around here
before you arrived.
I was sent for and I was asked to help
and I couldn't turn 'em down.
Now come off it Colonel.
Even you were born.
As of right now,
you are under officer's arrest.
Insubordination.
Do I still carry out my duties, sir?
From now on,
you'll confine them to the troops.
Very well, sir.
Don't push me too far, Kendall.
[men singing march]
Forward! Ho!
[dogs barking]
Lukey, what are the dogs
raising such a fuss about?
Dogs? You know how dogs
make such a fuss.
- Soldiers, Miss Hannah. Lots of 'em.
- Soldiers? How wonderful!
Thunder in the outhouse.
Them's Yankees.
Lukey, you go on downstairs
and meet them.
Lukey, do you hear?
[knocking]
[dog whining]
Come here, girl.
Come on.
- Who lives here?
- Miss Hannah Hunter lives here.
Tell her I want to see her.
Colonel Marlowe, Union Army.
Yes, sir.
Put that gun away.
- Sorry for this intrusion, ma'am.
- It isn't that, Colonel.
It's just that I never prepared myself
to see that uniform
within the walls of this house.
Ma'am, we no more wish to be here
than you do to have us.
Why, that's gallantly spoken, Colonel.
No matter what our...
well, our differences,
I fear I'm forgetting the amenities.
- Welcome to Greenbriar, gentlemen.
- Thank you.
Lukey, take the gentlemen's hats.
Uh...
- Sergeant Kirby.
- Sergeant.
Ma'am.
Well, shall we make ourselves
more comfortable in the Rose Room?
No, thank you, ma'am.
We'll only stay a moment.
You and your men are riding on?
No, we will bivouac
in your woods for the night.
Sleeping on the cold, cold ground?
When is this awful, wasteful,
terrible struggle going to end, Colonel?
Why, brother against brother...
And during our stay no one will
be allowed to leave the premises.
And wherever would we go, Colonel?
I'm sure you must agree that this war
makes loneliness for everyone.
Also, I must commandeer most
of the grain and horses,
if you have any.
You will be paid, Miss Hunter,
for everything, in Union greenbacks.
We will not bother you
any longer. Good evening.
- Kirby.
- By your leave, ma'am.
Why Hannah Hunter, what's got hold
of you, talking like a field hand?
- You alls, we alls.
- Yankees! [sighs]
[spits]
It's uncanny, Colonel.
I've heard about 'em,
but I didn't believe it.
I'll have you know,
I received my commission
from the Governor from
the sovereign state of Michigan!
- Young man...
- What's your question?
The question is this man's authority
in his present position.
As usual, I am trying to present
the grim facts of life.
Colonel Secord doesn't understand
that coffee tastes better
if the latrines are dug
downstream instead of upstream.
- How do you like your coffee, Colonel?
- [laughing]
- Ah, Secord, you oughta...
- Pardon.
Oh, Colonel! Colonel Marlowe!
I am forgetting my manners.
Why, how I ever...
Well, I don't believe
I've met these gentlemen.
Miss Hunter. Colonel Secord.
Major Gray. Major Kendall.
Ma'am.
[giggles] I'm just so scatterbrained.
Poor Papa and Mama must be
turning over in their graves at me
for not extending what little
hospitality Greenbriar can offer.
At least I can extend an invitation
to you and your officers for dinner.
- No, Miss Hunter...
- I insist.
There's three fat capons
that have to go anyhow.
What with our store of grain
being reduced, like you mentioned.
So, you see, you brought it
on yourself, didn't you?
Speaking for myself,
I would be delighted...
Very well, thank you.
Hot food is pretty hard to turn down.
Splendid. Now, how many can I count on?
- Would five or six be...?
- Not at all.
Perfectly wonderful.
At nine, gentlemen?
- Colonel Secord?
- Of the First Michigan, ma'am.
- Major Gray?
- Ma'am.
Major... Kendall, isn't it?
I'm afraid I'll have to regret, ma'am.
It's not of my choice, I assure you.
At the moment, I'm under arrest.
We will all be glad to accept
the invitation, Miss Hunter.
Ma'am?
You dropped your handkerchief.
Care for a little more,
Colonel Secord?
- No, thank you, ma'am.
- Colonel Marlowe?
- No, thank you.
- Oh, come now, Colonel.
A man with a big frame like yours
can’t just nibble away
like a little old titmouse.
Gentlemen, please be seated.
Now, what was your preference?
The leg... or the breast?
I've had quite enough of both,
thank you.
Oh... What a shame.
- Would anyone else like some more?
- [all] No, thank you.
Gentlemen, be seated.
I must warn you too, there's no coffee.
And a sweet or a dessert of any kind
was just out of the question.
Sugar's $150 a barrel.
"And yet your fair discourse
hath been as sweet as sugar,
making the hard way
sweet and delectable."
[men cheer]
How perfectly charming.
A little something of your own?
No, ma'am. Richard II.
- By profession, I'm an actor.
- Why, how fascinating!
Why, Major Ken... [gasps] Your cigar.
Gentlemen, please be seated.
[sighs]
Major Kendall a doctor. And
Colonel Secord almost a congressman.
And you an actor.
And now all military men.
Such a waste of talent.
But, of course, Colonel Marlowe,
I imagine that you are
a professional soldier.
No, prior to this insanity,
I was a railroad engineer.
Why, how thrilling.
To think of being able to steer one of
those huge things, puffing and steaming.
Ringing that little bell.
Ding-dong! Ding-dong!
Not quite. My job was
in the construction of railroads.
Why, my! Such brilliant minds.
Poor little me barely squeezed through
Miss Longstreet's Seminary for Ladies.
How did you ever manage
to remember all those books in college?
I didn't.
I started driving rail spikes
at ten cents a day and found.
And now, Miss Hunter,
I must ask you to leave us.
We are taking the privilege of using
this room for an hour or two. If we may.
Of course, but wouldn't you prefer
using another room? The study, perhaps?
- We're quite comfortable here.
- [men chatter in agreement]
I'm sorry,
but I must be rude and explain.
You see, Lukey and I must be in the
fields by five in the morning.
Gentlemen, go ahead
and light your cigars.
- [all] Thank you, ma'am.
- And you see, all this...
- Allow me.
- Thank you kindly.
All this and the dishes must be done
before she can get to bed.
- Am I being too inconsiderate?
- Of course not, ma'am.
- May I?
- Of course. This way, gentlemen.
- [all chattering]
- [man] How wonderful.
[man] Really, I thought it was a
charming dinner.
- Post this room.
- Yes, sir.
- I hope you'll be comfortable here.
- Oh, yes. This is fine.
Now, if you wish to light a fire,
it's all ready.
No, it's fine.
- Some brandy. I'll have Lukey bring it.
- No, thank you, no brandy.
Are you sure there's
nothing more that I can...
Oh, yes. Uh...
Doctor, there's no need
for you to be a part of this.
Perhaps Miss Hunter would show you
some of the beauties of Greenbriar.
Why, of course,
if he has any interest...
He'd be pleased to.
Very well. Come, then, Doctor.
I noticed a lovely garden outside.
Shall we take a stroll?
Why, of course.
You know, you gentlemen must be
comfortable in your heavy uniforms,
but I feel a definite chill in the
air... it's me and my thin blood.
Would you excuse me
while I go and fetch a shawl?
- Miss Hunter.
- Yes, Major?
I'm afraid I'll have to go with you.
Upstairs? With me?
- Why, Major!
- You're only getting a shawl.
Of course,
but in these parts it's unheard of...
It's something spicy
to tell your grandchildren.
This is war. At the moment,
Greenbriar is a military installation.
I don't suppose there's any real harm,
being that you're a doctor.
That's right.
Lukey, bring some brandy
to my sitting room, please.
I hope you'll be
comfortable here, Major.
Thank you.
Hey! Where are you going with that?
- Miss Hannah asked for this brandy.
- Yeah, yeah, I know, for the Major.
We never give any of our top-ranking
officers an unlabeled bottle,
unless somebody tastes it first.
- Is this what you does? Test things?
- Certainly.
See that second stripe? That means
I'm official taster for majors on up.
- Here's La Grange.
- [man] Mm-hm.
We've come down here
approximately 80 miles.
We're headed for Newton Station.
[Gray] Any word on
the enemy strength there?
No, not a word. Whatever it is,
we're obliged to take it on.
- Good. Maybe we'll see action.
- This is not play-acting.
- Here's your brandy, sir.
- Oh, thank you.
- And it's all tested.
- Tested?
By the man downstairs with
those tester's stripes,
for majors on up.
Oh, yes. Sergeant Kirby.
- He really tested it, didn't he?
- Yes, sir. Twice.
- [Hannah] Lukey?
- Yes, Miss Hannah.
Excuse me, sir.
[Marlowe] ...very lucky.
[men chattering in study]
That is the next piece of information.
We're not going back to La Grange.
- We're what?
- We're not going back north.
We're heading south to Baton Rouge
to join up with the Union forces there.
- Great Scott, when did you decide that?
- It's the best way. It's the only way.
John, it is 300 miles
from Newton Station to Baton Rouge.
And it is 300 miles
from Newton Station to La Grange.
Only the rebs will really have been
closed in behind us,
ready to chew us to bits.
So we'll go out the way
they least expect: straight south.
Damn it John, it's suicide.
Why we couldn't... Is it possible your
orders could have been misinterpreted?
My only duty after Newton Station
is to get as many of these men
back alive as I can.
[Secord] And so I still must protest.
And what's more, I want that
on the record for General Hurlburt.
It is impetuous mass suicide.
[Marlowe] It's on the record,
but get this.
Unless enemy action
allows you to take my place,
that's the way it will be.
Blow Newton Station off the map,
then through to Baton Rouge.
There will be no change.
Do you understand?
[Secord] All right, you're in command.
[Marlowe] Now let's go over it again.
Straight through to Baton Rouge.
We will not turn back.
Sorry for keeping you waiting.
Was the brandy satisfactory?
- Excellent. Won't you join me?
- Goodness me, no.
I never touch spirits.
My papa taught me that a girl ought
to keep her wits about her at all times.
Your father raised a very smart girl.
You're just being sweet.
Would you like to see the garden?
Didn't you forget your shawl?
Why, Lukey!
Now, Lukey, you take
that tray downstairs
and go about doing what you have to do.
You know, I remember the first time
I tried spirits,
at the Governor's Ball in Jackson.
My escort, Adam Lovelace from Biloxi,
well, he gave me a mint julep.
You know, those Lovelace boys
are all very handsome, but fast,
if you know what I mean.
Well, if I could tell you the thoughts
that went on in my mind
after that one julep... My!
I'd rather know the thoughts
going on in your mind right now.
- Kendall, what in the name of...?
- Ah-ah-ah. Sorry we have to interrupt.
Maybe we out to ask them
what they think your chances are
of blowing up Newton Station
and getting to Baton Rouge.
- Are you drunk?
- Unfortunately, no.
They were listening upstairs.
Makes a pretty good stethoscope.
Don't feel too guilty.
I was slower to catch on than you.
Where were you, Kendall?
Well, a gentlemen thinks twice
before peeking into a lady's bedroom,
but sometimes it pays off.
Looks like she's made
a fool out of both of us.
Ding-dong. Ding-dong.
[sighs]
You know something, Miss Hunter?
You have put me
to quite an inconvenience.
At least I've
accomplished something, sir.
I don't suppose I could accept
your word of honor
not to discuss this with anyone else.
I don't hold to honor
with any Yankees.
Exactly.
So the whole state of Mississippi
will be alerted.
So could you possibly suggest
what I should do with you?
I noticed she was getting on your
nerves. Now's your chance to shoot her.
- One more word out of you...
- Go ahead. Shoot us.
Shoot both of us. But you'll never
get away with the rest of your filthy,
murdering plans, Mr. Colonel Marlowe.
You Yankees and your holy principle
about saving the Union.
You're plundering pirates, that's what.
You think there's no Confederate army
where you're going?
Do you think our boys
are asleep down here?
They'll catch up to you
and they'll cut you to pieces,
you nameless, fatherless scum!
[sobs] And I wish I could be there
to see it.
If it happens, Miss Hunter, you will be.
- [man] Hurry it up.
- [man 2] All right.
You're an excellent rider, Miss Hunter.
Right interesting country, isn't it?
I'm more interested in why you vandals
confiscated my dead father's clothes.
Well, they're for our cadets.
- Scouts.
- Scouts!
Spies, you mean.
It's a wonder they don't crawl along
on their bellies like snakes.
You'll find out what happens
to spies down here.
My personal experience with spies
is limited. I've only known one.
Do you mind, Major?
I prefer to ride alone.
Ma'am.
Miss Hannah!
All right, forward! Yo-oh!
Back in line, Doctor.
[Hannah screams]
Well.
- These lady's drawers are almost dry.
- Yeah.
Aren't you getting a little chilly?
Don't tell me you're concerned
about my health.
If I give you back your clothes,
will you promise not to run away again?
I would, ma'am. There's a point
where pride becomes impractical.
Actually, if you could get a look
at yourself, I'd think you'd agree.
Very well. I do wish to keep my health.
- I shall not try to run away again.
- Your word of honor?
- My word of honor.
- To Yankees?
- To Yankees.
- Cross your heart?
- I gave you my word!
- All right, Lukey.
Help Miss Hunter with her clothes.
I'm glad you're being sensible.
You were beginning to worry me.
- From a medical standpoint.
- Thank you, Doctor.
I wish I could be of further assistance,
but fortunately you Southern people
have your own help.
[Kirby] Attention! Eyes front!
[man] Rebs, sir!
Hopping that riverbank.
A full brigade, coming fast.
Horse, foot and artillery, sir.
It ain't militia, neither.
- How far?
- Ten minutes.
All right, get out of sight,
get in those trees.
Enemy patrol. Take cover and choke up.
- Bugler!
- Not bugler, you idiot! Hand signals.
Enemy across the river.
Move out. Keep it quiet.
Why doesn't he stand and fight?
He's got a full brigade.
[rebel troops sing
The Bonnie Blue Flag]
¶ Hurrah! Hurrah!
For Southern rights, hurrah!
¶ Hurrah for the Bonnie Blue Flag
That bears a single star
¶ Hurrah! Hurrah!
For Southern rights, hurrah!
¶ Hurrah for the Bonnie Blue Flag
That bears a single star ¶
- [horse snorts]
- Take it easy. Oh!
Come on, stop it.
[singing continues]
Hannah!
Hey! Help! Over here!
[shrieks]
[muffled screams]
Ouch!
Let go with those teeth!
- I've got 800 men out there.
- Get some water.
Looks to be all clear across the river.
Well...
[gasps]
[sobs, growls]
How many men does it take
to keep one lone female quiet?
Colonel, the prisoner
would like a word with you.
Yes, Miss Hunter?
I'm not here to complain
about what you did.
It was your duty as you saw it,
and you did it.
I'm sorry you had to break your word.
I gave my word not to run away. I didn't
give it not to cry out for assistance.
I suppose there's a fine point there,
but I have to ask you to give me
your word on that too.
I do that, here and now.
Or I suppose when I testify against you,
I'd be handicapped with a broken jaw.
I'd say so. Anything else, ma'am?
One slight item.
My constant companions there.
I don't know how it is up North,
of course, but down South
there are times when Southern women
feel the need for privacy.
You two.
We was respectful. Real respectful, sir.
You told us it was all right
just as long as we could see
the top of her head.
- You told them that?
- Well...
Then there's one more item.
I suggest you see a doctor.
Ding-dong. Ding-dong.
[gunshot]
Over there in that barn. Come on.
[gunshots continue]
- We was bushwhacked, Colonel.
- All right, smoke 'em out.
Hold your fire.
Hey, there! We're Confederates,
but we ain't hostile.
- Honest!
- Drop your weapons and come on out.
Yes, sir.
Coming.
Hey, Virgil, come ahead on.
They's real bluebellies.
Watch it, Colonel.
Just the two of us, Cap.
And one captive.
Howdy, Cap. Jackie Jo and me is sorry
about popping away at you people.
We thought you was more
sheriff deputies coming to get us.
What have you got
against sheriff's deputies?
- That's a good one, huh?
- That's a slick one.
We just love sheriff's deputies.
They're deserters from the
Confederacy, sir. The lowest swine bred.
- I take it you're the sheriff?
- Captain Henry Goodbody, retired.
Acting sheriff of Lorena County.
I was about to apprehend these rats...
But we bushwhacked you,
you old goat, didn't we?
[Virgil] That we did, Jackie Jo.
But tell them about us, Captain Goodyo.
- Don't you dare touch him again!
- Miss Hunter.
You! You call yourself a man?
Treating with that scum?
Miss Hunter, that man is our enemy.
One word from you of any kind
and he will be shot. Understand?
That's right, ma'am.
Can I help you, miss?
I'm perfectly quite capable
of getting on by myself.
Seems you need
a little attention. Doctor!
Will you look to our good friend's ear?
Sorry but I got a weak stomach.
Otis, see what you can do
for our new recruit.
Hard to explain a man, isn't it?
Take care of this man.
Gunshot wound, sir.
Ow! Hey! You aim to stick that thing
clear through to the other side?
I seriously doubt it would have met
with any obstruction.
Sergeant, give me a couple
of those good cigars.
Ow! Hey!
- Did it hurt you, Virgil?
- This will make you feel better.
We'll have a talk, fellas.
Did you come through Newton Station?
- Sure did.
- Ah. Any troops there?
Oh, not no more.
Now, the Alabama Sixth, it was there.
But it moved to Vicksburg
with the Georgia Tenth.
The Tenth was Virg and my's old outfit.
[laughing] "Was" is right.
I guess there aren't any troops
within 30 or 40 miles.
- 60 at least.
- [man] You vile traitors!
Vicksburg, you say?
That's where we're headed for.
Looks like we're in for a little fight.
- Thanks, fellas. Untie the sheriff.
- High on the hog, huh, Virg?
Hey, looks like you Yankee boys
do all right with the women.
[Jackie Jo] And that's a pretty
towheaded one you've got there.
- Hi.
- Howdy, missy.
- Hi, missy.
- See what I told you about up North?
- Sergeant, your gauntlets.
- A pleasure, sir.
[Virgil] Hi, missy. Hey, missy.
Remove the prisoner.
Are you going to shoot him personal,
Cap? Let Jackie Jo here do it.
He's the best dang shot I ever seen.
I once saw him shoot
a runaway negro slave woman...
right through the... eyes.
[impact]
[Marlowe] Tie 'em up.
Sheriff, I'll leave them in your hands.
Pistol. It's loaded.
With the compliments
of Miss Hannah Hunter of Greenbriar.
- Thank you, sir.
- [Marlowe] You are welcome, sir.
Satisfied, Miss Hunter?
Well, your sense of justice
does surprise me a little.
Justice? Those men would
have been excess baggage.
I don't trust them any more
than I really trust...
- Than me?
- That's right.
Yes, ma'am. A hard man to understand.
- [man] Hi there, girls!
- [woman] Yankees! Get out of here!
[all shouting]
Get out, you dirty Yankees!
Get out of here!
- Jonathan!
- Miss Hunter. Sorry ma'am.
Mustn't talk to the prisoners.
We've got a nice room for you upstairs.
- A nice hot bath for you.
- You can change your clothes.
You see, we've got a lot of work to do.
- You're not going to burn the town?
- No. Just war supplies.
Cotton. Railway equipment.
Contraband, ma'am.
Contraband. That's me, ain't it?
[man] Come on! Dismount!
- Neatly done, Richard.
- Thank you, sir.
- Is this the whole garrison?
- Every last man.
They gave up without a struggle,
like Caesar to Cleopatra.
- [chuckles]
- Without a struggle, huh?
Kirby, set up headquarters
in this hotel.
- It would be a pleasure, sir.
- And close the bar.
- Yes, sir.
- Shall we set about the day's work?
I'm going to love setting a torch
to this nest of rebels.
[dog barking]
[man] Prisoner!
- Rebel Colonel, sir.
- Yes, sir?
What is the contraband in the warehouses
and on those cars in the sidings?
The property of the Confederate States
of America is not contraband, sir.
Oh?
Well, let's look at it
from my side, Colonel.
- Jonathan! Jonny Miles.
- You know the Colonel?
Sure. We're old friends. Last time
we served together was fighting Indians.
Sorry about the arm.
When did that happen?
I want neither your solicitude
nor to recall our association.
Have I your permission to retire, sir?
Take him away.
I can't figure a man like Miles
giving up that easy.
He's West Point. Tough as nails.
Maybe losing that arm
took a lot out of him.
The man I knew could lose both arms
and still try to kick you to death.
Hoppy?
- Did you picket this whole area?
- Yes, sir.
Colonel!
There's a reb train coming in, sir.
- Secord! Woodward!
- Yo!
This bar's closed.
[approaching train whistle]
Well, it must be a supply train,
rolling right into our laps.
I never saw a supply train
without guards on it before.
Well, they wouldn't be too alert
in their own territory.
- Where was that reb Colonel?
- The telegraph office.
- Telegraph office?
- Yes, sir.
All right, Secord, you know what to do.
- Get those horses under cover!
- [all yelling]
[man] Get them wagons!
[man] Get that bale off there.
Watch it!
[men continue yelling]
Down, out of sight.
Cover from inside.
[train whistle]
- Sir?
- No, I don't need it.
- Everyone's ready for action, sir.
- Thank you.
[bell clanging]
[gunshot]
[men shouting, cheering]
[gunshots]
[all yelling]
Fire!
I didn't want this.
I tried to avoid a fight.
That's why I took up medicine.
- Look at that idiot!
- Jonny! Jonny Miles!
Cease fire!
[bugle call]
- [Kendall] All right, move him up.
- [man] Move this man up.
Let me be of assistance.
I'm a physician. Dr. Marvin.
Major Kendall. We appreciate your help.
This man is next.
[man groans]
Go get some air.
- I can help.
- Get out.
Get him out of here.
Lou, you go and get some ice.
All you can find.
You too. You help him. Quick.
[steam hissing]
[booming]
How long are you going to be, Kendall?
Take a look for yourself.
We just started.
- I need a definite answer.
- I can't give you one.
I've got a job to do too, you know.
[sighs] At least five hours.
Colonel. Hey, Colonel.
Hello, trooper.
I'm Hoskins. Bud Hoskins.
K Company, sir.
- You don't know me.
- Sure I know you.
Good soldier. You just lie easy, son.
I put my hand on there and it's all...
Just lie still.
You'll write my ma, Colonel?
She'd love it if you...
You'll be writing her yourself
before long.
No.
No, I know.
- And I'm scared, Colonel.
- There's nothing to be scared of.
No, I'm all right.
Just hold onto me, sir.
And write my ma.
I'll be in your debt forever.
Aren't you proud?
Yes, I'm very proud of that boy.
- Report.
- Three dead, 18 wounded.
Demolition proceeding as ordered, sir.
And the bar is closed.
The bar is open!
- Get some laudanum.
- There is no more, sir.
[shouting]
Come down out of there, buster,
unless you want to go up with it.
- [boom]
- [glasses rattle]
Well, John, there goes half a million
dollars of railroad equipment.
That's how I made my living, you know.
Building railroads.
The railroad's finished for eight miles!
North and south...
John, what are you doing? Wait a minute!
- John!
- Get out!
- You figure this is a hospital?
- Listen to me.
And I can do it to Colonels, too!
Get out of here.
[distant booming]
[glass shatters]
When we move out, give your people,
the wounded, a lot of liquor.
I'd do that anyway.
- [glasses clattering]
- [booming continues]
[sobs]
Here, take this.
It will steady you down.
I've never seen it this way before.
I was with my father when he died.
But he died peacefully.
- Without pain.
- Well, it was lucky.
For both of you.
- [man groaning loudly]
- Go ahead, Kendall! Have a field day!
What do you mean, field day?
He's fighting to save men's lives.
Men's lives?
Or the reputation of his profession?
- You can't be serious, Colonel Marlowe.
- Have it your way, ma'am.
- Medicine is the most noble...
- Sure, noble profession, noble oath.
Lanterns held on high.
So high they won't admit
they're groping for...
You're...
- You're unfair and...
- Unfair?
There was a girl not much older
than that boy in there.
I wasn't unfair then, understand?
Because they used a lot of fancy words
that a section hand wouldn't understand.
So I held her down
while two of 'em worked on her.
I trusted doctors then. Believed in 'em.
Because I was in love
and I didn't want to see her die.
A tumor, they said it was.
And it had to come out right away.
So they stuck a leather strap in her
mouth so she could bite off her screams
while they cut away to get in there.
And what did they find? Nothing!
Oh, they were sorry.
Sure, they'd made a mistake.
They had something to talk about
before their next experiment.
But what about me?
They left me begging her not to die.
And I lost my wife.
I didn't kill either one of them.
I must have been crazy,
or too conventional.
Quite a speech.
I guess I'm feeling my liquor.
[men shouting]
- Thank you, Doctor.
- You're welcome, ma'am.
[bugle call]
Thanks, Hank.
- Well, we almost fooled you.
- Almost.
You'll never make it, Hank.
They're already closing in on you.
Bedford Forest
is sniffing at your heels.
You're headed straight
for that prison at Andersonville.
There's nothing we can do
to help you there, Hank.
The South is starving.
Jonathan, all I'm doing
is practicing medicine.
Old ironhead does all the thinking.
He thinks things pretty good.
West Point?
No, section hand.
- How are Susan and the kids?
- They're fine.
In Vicksburg.
I expect you'll be seeing them soon.
Nice try, Jonathan. Nice try.
See you in Vicksburg, Hoppy.
- Goodbye, Hoppy.
- Goodbye, Doctor.
I want to thank you
for all I've learned.
I shall endeavor
to get home alive as many as I can.
You're a good man, Hoppy.
After this thing is all over,
if we don't meet again,
be sure and finish medical school.
I shall make a point of it, sir.
Goodbye, Doctor. And good luck.
Thank you, Doctor, for all your help.
Vicksburg. They're headed
southwest to Baton Rouge.
Baton Rouge.
It's Baton Rouge, Major.
Tell General Forest.
[Secord] Yes, you can.
I'm on the board of inquiry.
I know exactly what can be done.
Now, he has no right, even as a...
[indistinct whispering]
- [Marlowe] Phil...
- Yes, John?
I'm sorry about what happened
back at Newton Station.
Ah, forget it, John.
You were under a strain.
But since you brought up the subject...
You know, John,
I'm an older man than you are.
What's more, I'm a politician.
We've knocked over Newton Station.
It's a glorious thing on my...
our records.
But now is the time to head north,
back to La Grange...
We're committed, Phil, and that's that.
Stubborn. Stubborn!
Ouch.
Can I have some of that liquor
to swallow, Doc?
You haven't got a good enough excuse.
How'd this happen, Dunker?
I was chopping down one of them
telegraph poles back there in Newton.
The axe ricocheted right onto my leg.
[men laughing]
- Go arrest the axe.
- It ain't nothing.
Nothing, huh? Almost blood poisoning.
You're lucky I saw you limping.
Aw, Doc...
What are you putting on there? Dirt?
No. Tree moss. Ordinary green mold.
It has some sort of healing agent,
I imagine.
- You imagine?
- I don't imagine the results, Colonel.
This is an old Cheyenne Indian cure.
Cheyenne Indian cure!
Green mold! Tree moss!
You keep this on.
Report any soreness to me.
[indistinct commotion]
Lukey!
[panting]
- What for they shoot me, Miss Hannah?
- It's all right.
[Kendall] Get my bag.
- She's gone, ma'am.
- Oh, no.
[sobbing]
Are you all right, Miss Hannah?
I brought you
a little bitty piece of candle.
We'll have some hot water
for you in the morning.
And lookee here. I found
a piece of looking glass for you.
Thank you.
I hope you'll... be able
to get some rest here.
You must know how we feel,
ma'am, about Lukey.
How much we regret...
how sorry I am...
that in some way we were the cause of...
Lukey isn't asking for that.
[Marlowe] I wish I could let you go.
If I gave you a horse
and turned you loose,
would you promise not to tell anybody
our plans for the next 24 hours?
It's too late.
It's too late for all of that.
No more promises.
No more anything now.
I'm sorry. Truly sorry.
Dunker.
- That leg was all right yesterday.
- Yes, but this morning it got swolled.
- I had to tear my trouser leg.
- Where's the poultice?
It started into itching, sir,
so I just yanked her off.
It was a sign it was
beginning to heal, you fool.
Come in here, or you're in trouble.
Brown, lend a hand.
Over there.
- Coffee?
- Thanks.
Report.
That's Salt Springs, all right, sir.
Nary a soldier inside, neither.
Just some old women,
a couple of salt mills
and a school for little boys.
- The salt mills will need burning.
- Why show ourselves? We've been lucky.
You call that coffee?
We can't pass 'em up.
Salt is as valuable as ammunition.
We'll bivouac here
and hit them in the morning.
All right, you're the boss.
[Dunker, drunk] ¶ Hi-ho, down we go
There ain't no such word as "can't"...
- What's going on?
- The doctor's working on Dunker's leg.
[Dunker continues singing]
¶ I left my love
My love I left...
Take another pull.
[drunken slurring]
Ah, that's good store liquor, Doc.
Who hit John?
- I've got to take it off, Dunker.
- What did you say?
I've got to take your leg off.
You've got to what?
The poison's gone too far.
You'll be dead by morning.
What can come of me after that, Doc?
One leg? What can come of me after that?
I'll rig a sling and leave you
with the closest civilian care.
Civilian care?
Then comes prison next, huh?
Andersonville?
Is that what happens to me, Doc?!
Andersonville?!
- Quite possibly.
- Yeah.
That's a hell of a tough choice
for a fella to have to make.
- Ain't it? Well, tell me. Ain't it?
- It's got to come off.
All right.
You just fire away.
But before you start sawing,
you give me some of that
chloroform stuff.
- You put me out, Doc.
- I'll give you what I got.
Now bite this.
Give me a hand here. Hold him down.
[straining] God... God!
It's obviously the column
that raided Newton Station.
That Vicksburg report was just a faint.
I thought a brigade of cavalry
was due here to reinforce your battery.
They won't get here
till late today, sir.
If what you suggest is most extreme.
- My oldest boy here is only 16.
- Damn it, sir!
I beg your pardon, Colonel.
I mean, Reverend...
Look, I've got a boy in my battery
that's 14, a man that's 72.
This is a war, sir.
I could start lobbing shrapnel and grape
at them critters, catch 'em napping.
Just a little show of force, sir
then maybe, perhaps we can hold them off
until the cavalry gets here.
- Cadet Major Barksdale.
- Sir?
- Assemble your battalion.
- Every man, sir?
- The entire complement.
- Taylor and Fitcher have the mumps.
Scratch them from the duty roster.
Well, you heard the Lieutenant.
You'll be pleased to inform the corps
we shall move at dawn.
[all] Thank you, sir!
[rooster crows]
[man] Attention!
Cadet Major Barksdale, you may move
your column forward. And God bless you.
[man] Right shoulder, arms!
Right, face!
Cadets, forward march!
Reverend, my boy Johnny.
He's all I've got left.
First his pa, then his uncles,
his brothers. Now him?
He's all I have left, Reverend.
I'm not going to let him go.
Cadet drummer Buford,
you are relieved of duty.
[boy screaming]
I'd save a little of that for Dunker.
I just lost him.
You lost Dunker, eh?
Well, you lost us a good man.
Blood poisoning. Amputation.
A shock to the heart, I guess.
I wouldn't have had to amputate
if he'd...
If, maybe, perhaps.
- What's the matter, medicine man?
- Section hand, I've had you!
Strip your blouse!
I think you're right. Come on.
Orderly! Horses! Bring 'em up!
Johnny!
Johnny Buford!
- What are the rules, Colonel?
- Just make up your own.
You said no rules, Colonel.
On your feet, croaker.
Fire Peter!
[shouting]
Fire Paul!
Artillery fire, sir. Hidden battery.
Those are nothing but children.
They're schoolboys.
Just some kids
from the military school.
Yeah, but they keep coming.
Sound assembly.
Well, at least that
Holy Joe ain't no kid.
[man shouting orders]
[man] Halt! Front rank, kneel!
- Ready!
- Miss Hunter...
[man] Aim! Fire!
[man] Rear rank, halt!
Kneel!
- Ready! Aim! Fire!
- [shrieks]
What do you want to do?
Set up a field hospital?
Yes, Mr. Colonel Marlowe,
what are you going to do now?
With all due respect
to your presence, ma'am,
I'm going to get
the hell out of here. Bugler!
Sound recall!
I told you to take care of this woman!
[explosion]
Hey Colonel, I got me a prisoner.
What do you want me to do with him?
- Spank him.
- On the bottom?
Where do you think?
[boy shouting]
[men cheering]
- [man] Halt!
- Hold it, Colonel.
[men shouting]
- Report.
- Rebs. They got the whole road blocked.
- How many?
- A full regiment of regulars, sir.
They got two pieces of artillery
and they're digging in along the road.
The only thing to do is fight our way
back to Salt Springs and head east.
- Haven't you seen that dust?
- Cavalry. Following us for three hours.
Colonel, the deacon says he knows this
country real good. Don't you, Deacon?
Preaching the gospel,
singing the praises of the Lord
hereabouts for years.
It might be a good idea
to start praying right now.
The deacon smuggled runaway slaves
north out of here through the swamp.
- With the underground railway.
- Could you smuggle us out south?
Wait a minute John. Wait a minute.
Why, that swamp is full
of quicksand, cotton mouth, rattlers...
The Garden of Eden
had its sufferance too.
Follow me, brother Colonel,
through the swamps
all the way to the river Amite.
Lead kindly, Lord.
All right, get yourself
a couple of fresh horses.
By the right flank, take cover.
Come on!
[horse whinnies]
[Marlowe] Come on! Come on! Come on!
[man] Move out. Come on, boy.
Come on, boy.
Keep moving! Keep moving! Come on!
Keep moving. Stay awake there, kid.
Keep moving. Pick up your feet.
John, how far do you figure
to Baton Rouge?
40 miles.
Keep alive in there!
- You want me to apologize now or later?
- For what?
- Keep moving!
- I never thought you could do it.
You know, John, I've given up
all thought of running for Congress.
With this on my record,
by George, I can be Governor.
- Keep moving!
- Governor of Michigan.
- Stay alive!
- And you can name your own job.
Railroad commissioner...
I wouldn't start making
campaign promises till we get there.
Join your regiment.
Colonel, my duty, medically speaking,
is to inform you that
some of these men may make it
on their hands and knees.
We've been 20 hours without a stop.
We need a rest.
I've got eyes, Kendall.
It's also my duty to inform you
that if we run into a fight...
That is all, Doctor.
Thank you, sir.
- Column, halt!
- Woodward.
- [man] Yo!
First squad,
scout the other side of the bridge.
First squad, forward, yo!
[hooves clatter on bridge]
I don't know if you've heard.
Your people are about an hour
behind us, coming fast.
I've heard.
We're going on to Baton Rouge.
We'll leave you here.
Your own kind can take care of you.
- I'm sure they can.
- Yes.
I...
I'm sorry for the hardship and...
the humiliation that we've...
that I've caused you.
[gunfire]
Get her out of here!
- [man] Recall!
- [men shouting]
[bugle call]
Get her in that cabin!
Come on, Miss Hannah.
Looks like they've got us in a trap.
[gunfire continues]
Knock on it!
Give us some cover!
Captain Woodward, move!
Leave me alone.
I'm all right. Let me alone, would you?
[gunfire continues]
Easy.
Get Colonel Secord right away.
Not that way, the other door.
- Report.
- It's alive with rebs, sir.
And I seen at least two cannons.
- They jumped us so quick.
- Infantry?
- The wood's full of 'em.
- Join your troop.
Yes sir.
- Cut his boot off, Sam.
- Nobody's cutting that boot off.
- I got a lot of work to do.
- Cut his boot off.
Take a good stiff jolt.
Those are $20 boots, trooper.
- Get some water.
- Who, me?
Take A-troop and that reverend,
or whatever he is.
Find a ford someway across that river.
Flank 'em. Take a bugler with you.
Yes sir. Thank you for the opportunity.
John, we've ridden right into a trap.
They want us to cross that bridge.
It'd be like going through a funnel.
We've accomplished our purpose, John.
In a position like this, there's nothing
disgraceful about honorable surrender.
Get back to your troop.
Keep 'em under cover.
- You mean... you're going on?
- Get out of here!
You're not going far
with that bullet in you.
You're taking your own sweet time
about cutting it out of there.
You're not the only wounded man
here, Colonel. Get me my bag.
Now, this is going to hurt a little.
Go on with it, Kendall.
- [grunts in pain]
- Keep that leg stretched.
Probe, please.
[Marlowe grunts]
Are you having fun?
You're lucky.
You may not believe it, Colonel,
but I bought you some time.
- A couple of hours?
- Maybe more.
Thanks.
- First Michigan in position, sir.
- First Illinois in position.
We were in position first.
I'm all right.
Get cracking.
God Almighty. Here he comes.
Mount up.
You heard me, Kirby. Mount up.
- You heard the Colonel! Mount up!
- [men shouting]
Colonel.
The deacon found a place to ford.
The men ought to be in position by now.
Thanks. Cover our rear.
See how much time we've got.
Yes, sir.
- Where's your horse?
- Back in the swamp, sir.
- Lips dry?
- Yes, sir. But my bugle ain't.
- Uncase the colors.
- You heard him.
You know your orders?
John, You're not fit.
Let me lead this charge.
With a success like this,
I could land in the White House.
- [bugle call]
- We'll probably all land in the...
[gunfire]
Get back to your regiment!
Bugler, sound charge!
[shouting]
Forwards! Fire Paul.
Company!
You're hurt, sir.
Blow... Trumpet, blow.
They can't give up.
Maybe it's crazy, maybe it's brave.
Don't ask me to explain it. Nobody can.
Come on, we're going to have
a lot of work to do.
Bugler, sound recall.
- [man] Got any more?
- [indistinct chatter]
[man] Come on, give us some more.
How much longer, Sergeant?
Sergeant Major.
Pretty near ready, sir.
All right, boys! Hurry it up! Lay it in!
Knock on it! Knock on it!
Come on out! Get out of there!
- Can those men be moved?
- They're all critical.
- May I speak to them?
- I'd rather you didn't.
They've got to be quiet.
I've given them all the laudanum I have.
It's a lousy finish for good men.
There'll be a medic with that
reb column. Get your horse.
I can't count on that.
You mean you're staying?
- Medicine's where you find it.
- Even in Andersonville?
Even in Andersonville.
I wouldn't blame you
if you slap it away. Shake hands?
- Doctor, Major Gray.
- All right, coming.
When your next doctor
takes that bandage off...
Yeah, I know. Tree moss.
So long, croaker.
Take care, section hand.
You're tired. You've helped a lot.
Thanks for it.
A poor way of being grateful
after what I've put you through.
- You'd better be going.
- Yes, I guess I'd better.
Look, Hannah Hunter.
Thank God I won't be the cause
of hurting you any more.
Because it happens I'm in love with you.
- [distant bugle call]
- [distant shouting]
Tell her the rest when you get back.
- One of your own, sir.
- Get going.
Colonel, they're right on my tail.
[Marlowe] Let's go. Yah!
Doctor, could our regimental surgeon
be of any service to you?
I'd be grateful.