♪ Won't you have to sing ♪
♪ these songs of freedom ♪
♪ is all I ever have ♪
♪ Redemption songs ♪
When you write that?
All my life.
Are you ready for Bob Marley &amp; The Wailers?
♪ Don’t let them fool ya ♪
It’s a hit.
Reggae is the people’s music.
You know, you're a superstar.
I ain’t a superstar.
You can't separate the music and the message.
You see, reggae music coming to unify the people.
Not everyone likes what you're saying.
For your own safety, you need to stop.
On December 3rd, 1976, would-be assassins invaded Bob Marley’s home
and attempted to take the life of the singer, his wife, and his-
Don’t worry about that.
- [kids laughing]
- Don’t worry...
...about a thing.
‘Cause every little thing is gonna be all right.
- You like that one?
- Yeah.
There's a war going on.
How I can bring peace?
I can’t even get peace for myself.
♪ Rise up this morning ♪
♪ Smiled with the rising sun ♪
♪ Three little birds ♪
♪ pitch by my doorstep ♪
Sometimes...
The messenger has to become the message.
♪ Don’t worry ♪
♪ About a thing ♪
Bob, I know it’s dangerous.
♪ Every little thing is gonna be alright ♪
But you're the only one who can unite the people.
♪ Singin’ don’t worry ♪
You're ready, Bob.
♪ About a thing ♪
No guns can stop this message.
♪ Every little thing is gonna be alright ♪
I want the world to change.
And that time is now.
♪ Singin’ don’t worry
About a thing ♪
(crowd singing)
♪ Every little thing is gonna be alright ♪
♪ This is my message to you ♪
♪ Don’t worry ♪