This is the Hungfa temple outside
the frontier
lt's a cold winter night
The top 28 fighters of the boxer world...
are here to eliminate a evil boxer
They're waging...
a world-shaking battle against him
No one knows the name of the demon
No one ever sees his face too
He always cover his face
with a black and white mask
His nickname is ''Bat without Wings''
lt's said that he's a lustful.
horny man...
who has raped and killed many women
So the righteous boxers united together
...and chased him to the Hungfa temple
waging a dead-or-alive battle against him
Unfortunately.
only two boxers survived at last
...and he killed 26 boxers
But it's said that...
the Bat was finally killed
...by lron Palm. Szma Zhongyuan
''Zhunyuan Security Bureau''
''Maple Wood''
Listen. there's a tea house ahead
Let's take a break
Listen up...
The madam instructed us
to take a rest here
...and eat something
Okay
Here...
Mister...
Madam. what's the matter?
Mister. we'd like to order
Okay
l'll serve you tea first
Are you from Zhenyuan Security Bureau?
Yes
ls a certain Miss Lei-feng here?
Here l am. What's the matter?
Here's a letter for you
Who left it here?
A Mr. Xiao
Xiao?
ls it Mr. Xiao Qi?
Madam. is he the most handsome man.
nicknamed the Broken-heart Sword. Xiao Qi?
Right
Green horse with purple silk rein
White Pearl Sword and White Gown
Come on. Open the letter
At the Tianlung Temple.
l need to talk to you
Madam. then l'll accompany you now
Why are you going there?
Captain Chen
Madam. what's the matter?
l'll meet an acquaintance at
the Tianlung Temple
You guys wait for me here
Tianlung Temple?
lt's already been abandoned
No monk stays there anymore
l'm not looking for a monk
Madam
What's the matter? What happened?
The tea is poisoned!
Who are you?
They call me the Bat
What? The Bat?
Right
There's only one Bat in the boxer's world
l'm the Bat without Wings
''Tianlung Temple''
Mr. Xiao
''Something urgent. Please enjoy the meal
Xiao Qi''
Oh. l see
lt's delicious
Why are you here?
l live here
Then your shop?
The shop didn't belong to me
l just killed the shop owner
...and used it for one day
One day?
What for?
To kill people
Who are you?
Are you using the name of Xiao Qi...
intentionally to lure me here?
You're smart
That's correct
l deceived you into coming here
...because l want you to stay here forever
lt's not as easy as you think
My people knew that l came here
They'll come here to look for me
Your people?
l'm afraid they can't come here
Unless you go to look for them
Why?
Because the road to hell is always
of no return
You want to see them...
unless you go to hell too
Quite an impressive swordplay!
What the hell is this place?
Anyone here?
Come out now
Who are you?
lt seems that l'm the owner of this place
Right
l'm their owner as well
But l've strangled them to death
These are the breasts of Long Yu
This is Li Fang
Right
These are the breasts of Cui Yu
l took all of their clothes off
l carve using them as models
Can't draw out their true beauty however!
Bat without Wings
What are you talking about?
l said you're the Bat without Wings
You're still alive
5 years ago. people said your death
is faked
The Bat without Wings?
The name sounds familiar
Who are you?
How do you know this name?
l remember now
l know you...
Don't come
Who is she?
Come on. Tell me who she is?
Who is it? Come out now
How come it's you again?
Of course it's me
l cheat you to come here on purpose
What's the matter?
Feeling dazzled?
How do you know?
Because you drank...
the poisonous wine
l don't know you
l've nothing to do with you
Why did you lure me here?
Right
You've nothing to do with me
But you look like somebody
l can exploit you to force him
to tell me...
the name of a person
Come over here
Look carefully
What's her name? Tell me
l know her
Who?
lt's her
Do you want me to strip her clothes off...
in order to refresh your memory?
No
lt seems l didn't strip her clothes off
l remember now
Who?
l'm very fond of her
l asked her to stand here as a model...
and sculptured a statue
She's the one in yellow
What's her name?
Come on! Think!
l remember her name
Yes?
Her name is beautiful
She's called Ximen Luoye
Open the door
Open the door...
Qiuju. what's the matter?
Where's the master?
What's the matter?
Master. something happens
Something dreadful happened!
The men of the security bureau...
were all killed in the Maple Wood
What? All killed?
What are you talking about?
Mr. Chen. the escort boxers were
all killed
Where's the lady?...
Tell me now
Hanshen...
Feng-erh is indeed your fiancee
But you need to be patient
...and tell us clearly
Qiuju. where's Feng-erh?
The lady got a letter from
Mr. Xiao Qi and went to
...the Tianlung Temple outside Maple Wood
l never saw her again
Mr. Xiao Qi?
How did Feng-erh know Xiao Qi?
Did Xiao kill the boxers?
No
The killer was a very horrible person
He's called the Bat without Wings
What? The Bat without Wings!
Could you be mistaken?
He died five years ago
How could he kill people?
He called himself the Bat without Wings
l did see him killing the boxers
No more bullshit about him anymore
Bring my sword here
Hurry to the temple now
Hurry up
Master...
Xiao wasn't at the temple
How do you know?
This morning someone said he had...
gone to Taibai restaurant in the east
of the town
He's expecting a friend
Taibai restaurant?
Stop arguing please...
l'm sorry
The whole restaurant...
is reserved by someone
Excuse me...
Take a look over the place
Yes
Mr. Xiao...
You've finally come
Shangguan Wangsun.
the wealthiest man in the south
Why are you looking for me eagerly?
Please take a look
This is the assassination order...
from the Hell Gang
lt asks to kill you at 1st hour
of Chongyang Festival
Today is Chongyang Festival
lt's the time now
Quick. Put it down
Hurry up...
These are the precious jewelry and jade
l hope you will take them. Mr. Xiao
The Hell Gang!
So you're hiding here. Go!
Yes
l didn't expect there're 4 extra punks...
in the menu of Taibai restaurant
Also l didn't expect that...
l need to kill someone else
besides Shangguan
Who are you?
Jewelry Sword and White Gown
Xiao Qi?
Shangguan had nothing to do with you
Besides. he is famous for his kindness
Why do you need to kill him?
The Hell Gang makes a living
by killing people
Mr. Xiao. you'd better stay away
from my business
Okay
Then you leave here now
Do you mean if we leave here now...
you'll stay away from our business
with Shangguan?
Mr. Xiao. you...
The money from you only...
guarantees your safety
in this restaurant...
but not in other places
So...
Okay
We're leaving here now
Wait
You didn't listen to my words clearly
What is it?
l mean you may leave here
...unless you left your life
Thanks for saving me. Mr. Xiao
Not at all
Mr. Shangguan.
can l ask you a favor?
Sure...
l heard there's serious flooding
in Jiangnan
Please take the jewels to help the victims
ls it okay?
But it belongs to you
l saved you today only
because you're a good man
...but not because you're wealthy
Excuse me...
Sorry for the trouble
Carry the stuff away
Yes
Goodbye
Okay
Pal...
You've been here for 2 hours
why do you still keep hiding?
Who are you?
l was the one who hired the Ghost King...
to kill Shangguan
l've something very important to do
l need a favor from you
But l want someone...
who is a real expert
So you sent the Ghost King to test me
Right. lf you couldn't kill
the Ghost King.
you wouldn't be able to kill
Bat without Wings
He is still alive?
l bet you know what happened at...
Hungfa temple in Mount Wudang 5 years ago
lt's said he did die that day
There is such rumor in the boxer world
But my father took...
the Bat Blades to the frontier
and he never returned
The Bat is the only one...
who wants my father dead for revenge
Your father is...
Szma Zhongyuan of Szma Villa
So you're Szma Dongcheng
People always talked about you
a few years ago
l'm here to ask you to find out...
where my father is
ln other words.
l want to know if the Bat is really dead
Many people are here today
Are you looking for me too?
You're wrong this time
We're looking for Miss Szma
l don't know you guys
You're...
Venomous Wuxie. the Stun-dude
l'm the poisonous Dr. Wang Wuxie
l'm the grim & bewitching Xu Fang
Another 2 excellent assassins are here
Did someone hire you to kill me?
No
There's a big secret in the boxer world
One of the Bat Blades is in your hands
So someone hired us...
to rob it from you
Didn't you hear...
my father and the blade were missing
in the frontier
Who will believe you?
l will
Miss Szma
l'll do as you request
You may leave now
Really?
How arrogant!
Miss Szma...
l said you may go now
No one can stop you leaving here
Thanks for your help
Xiao. why don't you
mind your own business?
lt's my nature
Go to hell!
l think you'd better go now
...or you'll be dead
Goodbye. Xiao Qi
ls Xiao here?
He's upstairs
Sir...
Taibai restaurant is very busy today
Are you Mr. Xiao?
Yes
Did you ask my daughter Lei-feng...
to see you at Tianlung Temple?
Your daughter?
Sir. l didn't even know you
How could l know your daughter?
l'm Lei Xun of Zhenyuan Security Bureau
He's my daughter's fiance. Han Shen
Did you see the Bat without Wings?
What? The Bat without Wings again?
Right
At the Maple Wood. my boxers...
were killed by a man called
the Bat without Wings
But before he killed my men.
he gave a letter to my daughter
saying that you'd see my daughter
at the temple
''Tianlung Temple''
Lei-feng...
Actually l myself have come here
for the first time
l didn't ask your daughter to see me here
Look
Matter to discuss at the Tianlung Temple
By Xiao Qi
This isn't my handwriting
This is a check with my handwriting
The handwriting of his name is different
lt must be the Bat deceiving...
Lei-feng to come here
Lei-feng...
Weird!
l heard that the Bat died 5 years ago
How could he appear again?
And get me involved?
Did you see Lei-feng?
No
There're only trees inside
Mr Lei. no matter what happens.
Miss Lei won't be here
l think you'd better go home first
Maybe she's safe and home now
''Zhunyuan Security Bureau''
Cai
Cai...
Who is it?
lt's me
You're...Who is it?
Keeper Feng! Don't you recognize me?
Our lady?
Right. lt's me
Great. The master is looking for you
everywhere
l know
l know he's looking for me
That's why l send my head back to him
Here is my head
Please give it to my father
Help! Someone please help!
What's the matter?
The lady...
The lady?
Where?
lt's her
Lady...
Where's she?
Look! Over there
Look!
That's her...
Lady...
Go
Where's the lady's left hand?
Keeper Feng!
Feng-erh! Where are you?
Uncle
l remember on the hill near the temple
There's a aunt Zheng living there
Feng and l used to go there as children
Wouldn't Lei-feng have gone to her house?
Okay. Let's go
Mr. Xiao. we'll be right back
Okay
You're...
l'm lost
Excuse me. which way should l
go to head west?
Are you going to the Tianlung Temple?
No
l need to go somewhere far far away
You go straight from here
Thanks
Miss
lt's late. Where are you from?
l was from the Black Lake near
the Maple Wood
Goodbye
Feng-erh
-Feng-erh...
-Lei-feng...
Lei-feng...
Feng-erh...
Mr. Xiao. where's Feng-erh going?
Feng-erh?
The one who just left is Lei-feng
No way
The woman l saw is quite old
Hasn't your daughterjust turned 16?
What?
ls she that old?
Sure
l think l didn't get it wrong
Your house is in the southeast
But she said she needs to head far west
West?
The paradise in the west?
Uncle. something is weird
We'd better go back to the security bureau
Old sir
Thank you
Are you alright?
l'm fine
The blind usually tend to stumble
What the hell!
Do you think my arm is pretty?
Yes
As pretty as a woman's hand
Let me give it to you then
This is the arm of Lei-feng
Aren't you blind?
Of course not
Where's my daughter?
Apart from the arm.
l've sent the rest of her
to the security bureau
Who the hell are you?
Me?
People call me the Bat without Wings
Didn't you die 5 years ago?
Do l look like a dead person?
The Broken-heart Sword Xiao Qi
is really good
lt's almost dawn. l need to leave now
Goodbye
The Bat
He's the Bat without Wings?
l don't know
Only a few people have seen him before
''Zhunyuan Security Bureau''
-Feng-erh...
-Lei-feng...
Master. you can't go...
Why?
Because she's cut into pieces
Her head is cut off as well
What?
Lei-feng...
Hold up the master
Get him some medicine. Hurry up
Hurry up
Did your lady come back without an arm?
How could you know?
Because l met the Bat without Wings...
in the Maple Wood
What?
Sir. where did you go?
l was looking for the Bat for revenge
Do you know where's he?
l don't know
l heard of the duel at the frontier
that year
26 boxers were killed by the Bat
Only the lron Palm.
Szma Zhongyuan and the...
thousand-faced Scholar.
Leng Qiuyun were alive
Szma was missing at the frontier lately
So Leng Qiuyun is the only one left
l'm going to see Leng now
Strange! Why're there many people
here tonight?
Hold it
These people are dead
What?
They're really dead people
The Bat knew we will pass here
if we're looking for Mr. Leng
He's giving us a warning here
Look
Wang Wuxie. Xu Fang
They're the top killers
Only few boxers can tackle them
You're right
Who is it?
Who's hiding here?
Come out...
No one is speaking here at all
The one who speaks has been here already
Well. who's really dead?
Who's faking to be dead?
lt's clear now
How could you know they're speaking?
Many people know ventriloquism
Their lips don't need to move
when speaking
No wonder you're famous in the boxer world
But it's pity you like to
meddle in affairs
You want to see my lifting skills
They forced us to the river bank
on purpose
Right
My nickname is the Venomous Wuxie
ln the pond l've put...
the most poisonous drug of...
our Tang School
Once you touch the water.
your whole body will be swollen to death
There's nothing in the pond.
Not even a leaf
You've nowhere to stand on
and you're surely dead
lt looks as if they knew...
we're looking for thousand-faced Scholar
Let's hurry for the Leng's Garden now
Look
''Spiritual Tablet of Leng Qiuyun''
How could he be dead as well?
Once again their moves proved to be faster
We're late
Right
You're late
Unfortunately my lord suddenly
died of a disease...
3 days ago
He didn't have many friends
when he's alive
But when he died.
many came looking for him
Seems like there's more than
one dead person here
Why are there so many dead people?
How do you know they're dead?
Stop
Please stop
Are you the Broken-heart Sword Xiao Qi?
Yes. l am
So you're not from the Bat's gang
We're here to look for the Bat
Why?
Because his daughter was killed by the Bat
He seeks the Bat for revenge
But we're late
l never expected Mr. Leng to be dead
The people here are strange...
just like them
Those who should have died
are still alive!
Do you want to see Leng Qiuyun?
Follow me
Old sir. are you bringing us
to see Mr. Leng?
Where's he now?
He's here
ln fact l wasn't dead
l just try to defend myself against
the Bat
So l pretended that l was dead
You do believe that the Bat is
still alive?
Yes
Because the Bat didn't die at all
He got hit in the forehead...
by the lron Palm of Mr. Szma...
and fainted
He became insane...
after he gaining consciousness
He didn't remember anything
To maintain peace amongst people...
we announced that he's dead
ln fact we locked him on the Bamboo lsland
Bamboo lsland?
Right
lt's an isolated island
lt's very close to the Szma Villa
Szma is an expert in setting up the traps
He sets up traps and land mines
on the island
Even a expert fighter...
can't get there easily
l really don't understand
He's a mad man
How could he possibly escape?
How can you be sure that it must be him?
lf it wasn't him.
who can kill Szma Zhongyuan?
Who stole the Bat Blades of
Szma Dongcheng?
You say. the blade which
Szma Dongcheng lost...
is the Bat Blade
Right
l believe it's that Bat Blade
lt's said that there're a pair
of Bat Blades
The Bat carried them wherever he went
That's the treasure that...
many boxers want to have it
How could Dongcheng get it?
lt's a long story
You probably knew that...
the Bat has kidnapped many pretty women
He raped and then killed them
Among those hundreds of victims.
there're only 2 exceptions
l heard that these 2 women...
too pretty to be spared
The Bat let them go...
and gave away his blades to both of them
One of them is Szma Dongcheng
Who is the other one?
Lei-feng
lt's not Lei-feng
lt's my fiancee
No one knows this secret
lt's because of her
l risked my life fighting against the Bat
Strange!
She looks like my daughter
Maybe that's why...
the Bat kidnapped your daughter
Where's she now?
Sorry
For her safety.
l cannot tell you
Why?
l heard that there's a big secret...
regarding these two Bat Blades
Now Miss Szma has lost her blade.
l'm afraid...
someone has got plans for her blade
Fine
Anyway. we're looking for the Bat only
lt would be better if you keep silent
l don't want any misunderstanding
Well. we shouldn't have disturbed you
Thanks for your information
Goodbye
See you
You go ahead in this direction
Passing Lingding lsle.
you'll see Bamboo lsland
We saw a road here a moment ago
Why are there bamboos
blocking the road here?
Right. l feel like when we're
making our way.
the bamboo is moving with us
at the same time
Right
The bamboo is moving along
What?
Have you heard of the Taoist magic?
Yeah sure
There're few people in the boxer world...
knowing the tricks
Probably Szma Zhongyuan is one of them
What is Taoist magic?
lt's the same as a trap
But it's very crafty
lt combines the tricks of Taoist magic...
with mechanical switchboards.
producing many forms of traps...
locking people inside
Like now for instance
lt seems as if we're close to the balcony
But no matter how hard we try
we couldn't prop the boat across
The traps under the water...
and the bamboos...
will block our way automatically
No wonder Szma Zhongyuan managed...
to lock the Bat here
Look!
The Bat without Wings
Szma Zhongyuan is really good
He's helped us to cross the water
lf anyone tried to rescue the Bat.
he'd be surely dead
What should we do?
Get to the shore first
How could we?
Taoist magic is beyond our understanding
lt seems to know everything
There's only one way to break it
And that's to go against it
We go that way if we want to go
to the balcony
Come on
There're traps everywhere
ls he the Bat without Wings?
Look at the chains. He's probably the Bat
No
He doesn't look like the one in Maple Wood
Let's take a look there
The water is toxic
Many people must have died here
Dead without permission
lt's made of iron
Guess we should climb up the bamboo
...to get there like we do before
l think it's the only way out
We're trapped again
Surely we are. because...
the traps are moving under the water again
Who are you?
Don't you know who l am?
l'm the Bat without Wings
Why did you kill my daughter?
Where's he?
l saw someone throwing darts at us
But there's no way outta here
Strange! Where did the people go?
lt's a nice house
Who owns it?
Who are you. sir?
You enter Szma Villa without informing
Do you have something important?
Szma Villa?
Yes
This is my house
Mr. Xiao and Mr. Lei
Why did you come out over there?
We tried to catch the Bat on Bamboo lsland
But he escaped through a tunnel
in a small house
We went after him...
but unexpectedly turned up here
Really?
So what. the Bat isn't dead?
Right
The Bat without Wings didn't die
The traps on the Bamboo lsland...
were set up by our master...
to imprison the Bat
For our convenience to look after
that idiot
...he made this underground tunnel
No matter what
Since you gentlemen are here
Please let me serve you with wine
Hope you'll have a good stay here
Please
Thanks
Oh!
Mr. Lei. how do you suddenly find out...
the Bat is on the island?
Mr. Leng Qiuyun told us
lf l guess right.
the Bat has already escaped...
from the island
Because l just saw it's another one there
Really?
lt may have connection to...
my father's death at the frontier
Anyway...
it's already dark now
Please stay here for a night...
and leave tomorrow
Sleep late to enjoy the moonlight
Rise early to tend to flowers
lt's late. Why don't you go to bed.
Miss Szma?
ls it because of your fondness
of the moon?
No
lt's quiet in the villa
Since my father left.
no one ever visited us
So whenever there's a full moon.
l'm always here to think about the past
Still missing Hero Linghu?
You know our relationship?
Everyone in the boxer world knows...
...you're a perfect match
Unfortunately. the Bat abducted you
Hero Linghu tried to save you...
and went to the frontier
But he's killed by that madman
Linghu Tian and my father went
to the frontier...
it wasn't because of me
Because he believed...
the Bat never hurt me
The reason l accompanied your father
was because your father told me...
the Bat kept two kungfu manuals
lf l couldn't destroy them. it'd be a...
disaster for the martial world
But there are already 7 people
Why did you have to go?
Dongcheng...
A great man should plan and worry ahead
and enjoy the fruits after the people
How can l let the other folk alone?
Promise me you must come back
l'll come back
He said he'll be back
But he didn't
He wants to look for the manuals
But l couldn't fulfill his last wish
Boxers are always looking for
fame and money
Hero Linghu is very exceptional
lt's no doubt whenever there's a full moon
you'll miss him
Well...the night is deep and the fog heavy
l speak too much
l think it's already mid-night
You'd better go to bed
Tomorrow we bid farewell
Please...
Mr. Lei...
ln the small house on Bamboo lsland
you remember
...there's a pair of stone deer?
There's a pair over at
the Tianlung Temple too
Do you think...
they look the same?
Now that you remind me
Do you mean the deer in the temple
...has the same mechanism?
''Tianlung Temple''
May l know who is coming?
Please show up
lt looks like...tonight someone
has invited us...
to come here on purpose
Look!
What a big stone statue!
This painting...
Didn't we see it in Mr. Leng's house?
Could it possibly be that...
One of these two statues is Miss Szma
Other one is the mysterious lady
Leng mentioned
Possibly
lt must be the home of the Bat
Who's the mysterious woman in yellow?
lf we can locate her.
we may find out the Bat...
and his secret
lf this is the home of the Bat.
he must bring all the girls...
back to here
Let's check the place out
We may find some clues
Right
Come and take a look
Lei-feng wore this the other day
Am l right?
Right
Her mother embroidered the edge for her
l think when she died...
she was tied up here
Look!
This was Lei-feng's handwriting
Probably she wrote it before she died
Ximen
What Ximen?
Could it be Ximen Luoye?
Ximen Luoye
Mr. Lei. how do you know?
There are 2 pretty women
in the martial world
One is Szma Dongzheng
The other one is Ximen Luoye
Ximen family is very reputed
in boxer world
They've very strict discipline
No one ever saw her
Do you know where she is now?
The aristocratic Ximen family
was withered...
and completely declined
lt has lost its glamour
l heard Miss Ximen stays in
Shiau Shiang house
somewhere in the suburbs of Hanzhou
''Shiau Shiang House''
Thank you. miss
Xi-erh
Except you. no one talks to me...
all these years
lt's not true
Who then?
Me
You?
l've not seen you for 5 years
But you're as pretty as before
What are you doing here?
l need the Bat's Blade that you kept
Why did you kill them?
To keep their mouths shut
l guessed right
You're not the Bat without Wings
Ms. Ximen is really clever
as the people say
lf you don't want to die.
hand out the Bat's Blade
But if you kill me.
you will never get the Blade. too
How can you say...
l will never get the Blade?
Master
We got the Bat Blade
Miss Ximen
Do you really think l'm here
for the Blade?
lt's just a plot...
to lure you out here
My men have already got it
l just lied
l asked my guys to do a small trick
and you fell into my trap so easily
and showed me the Blade
You...
You're really beautiful
No wonder that madman was fond of you
Stop or l'll kill myself
Are you sure?
No way
Miss Ximen...
Go
Here
How are you?
Don't touch me
l've no hope
lf you're here for the Bat Blade.
you're late
Who has come?
The Bat without Wings
He's taken the Blade away
But the Bat isn't the real one
What?
Then who is he?
What? Him?
Miss Ximen...
Xiao Qi
l never imagined you to be faster than us
C'mon. hand it over
As it is the Blade isn't here since long
We're busy. you search for yourself
Stop
Mr. Lei. don't tie up with them
Leave here immediately
Yes
Go
Chase
Big brother. please
Our plan is successful
lt's lucky that you came in time
or Xiao Qi will discover that...
l pretended dead by holding my breath
Okay. let them fight each other
and we may take the advantage
of the result
Dad. you're back?
Here's the Blade
ls it the Blade of the Ximen family?
lt's strange
Xiao Qi had gone to Ximen's house
They met Leng Qiuyun
Did Leng tell them everything?
l think...
Leng is a very mysterious person
Since he's back from the frontier.
he's been avoiding everyone
Right
Did Ximen Luoye tell Xiao...
who you are?
No
When they went there.
Ximen Luoye had killed herself
Killed herself?
Come on
Bring out the other Bat Blade
Dad. both the Blades are here now
Let's find out...
where the secret is hidden
Temple. Lung Tian
Tianlung Temple
Right
l'd already guessed their stuff...
were hidden under the Tianlung Temple
But l searched thoroughly
Still l couldn't find it
The name of the temple was carved
on the blade
lt must be inside the temple
Why don't you bring the madman
to help you?
Right. he could help
Men
Dad
lf you find the kungfu manuals.
promise me that you'll destroy it
l want to fulfill the will of
brother Linghu
Don't worry
l tried hard to find the Blades...
is because of you
Come on...
Go...
Master. here's your clothes
Where's the master?
He took the madman away from the back door
What's the matter?
Xiao Qi is here suddenly
What?
Miss Szma...
Mr. Xiao. why are you here...
at this late hour?
We're looking for someone in here
Who?
The Bat without Wings
Ask Szma Zhongyuan out
Miss Ximen told me everything...
before she died
She's the only one who knew...
who is the Bat
Szma Dongcheng
Call your dad to compensate
the death of my daughter
Szma Dongcheng
You're from a reputed boxer family
How could you do this?
l don't think...
it's the right time to discuss this
Go now
Stop
You probably know...
how powerful our trap is
You're now in the middle of the mine trap
All the bamboo around you carry dynamite
The four strings of this instrument...
is the lead linked to the trap
lf l just snap the string...
you'll be blown into pieces
Probably you regret meddling with affairs
Miss Szma. you are good and refined
Why did you help your father...
to do such an evil thing?
What evil thing you talking about?
The reason he tried hard to get
the Blades...
was to help me to...
fulfill the last will of brother Linghu;
That of destroying the manuals
What?
He needed the Bat Blade...
in order to find the manuals?
Of course
What do you think he did all this for?
Didn't you know...
the secret on the Blades is...
about the biggest treasured vault
in boxer world?
Money is all he goes after
Who told you this?
Miss Ximen told me before she died
She's talking nonsense
You've nowhere to go
You will die...
in this mine trap
lt's enough
Don't kill them
Why?
Because what they said is true
What?
lt was for riches your dad
went after the blade
ln order to refresh the memory of the Bat.
ln the Maple Wood.
he kidnapped Lei-feng...
who looks exactly as Miss Ximen
Pushing Mr. Xiao and Lei to visit
Leng Qiuyun.
he asked me to pretend as a ghost
and to carry Lei-feng's head
...to the Zhenyuan Security Bureau
They'd be at the Tianlung Temple now.
urging...
the Bat to disclose the place
of hidden treasure
Well...is it there?
No
Old folk
Think again
Those white stuff
One by one in a row like this
Those yellow and green stuff
Piece by piece
Yellow?
Green?
No
No?
Oh! Yes!
Where are they? Tell me
These two women l love most
The one in yellow is called Ximen Luoye
The one in green is Szma Dongcheng
Think about it now
or l'll ruin the two most
favorite women...
in your life
Don't ruin them...
They're the women l love most
There's a lot of money under their skirts
Don't hurt them
What did you say?
l'll let you in on a secret
Don't tell anyone else
Okay
l put all the jewelry...
in the skirts...
of my most beloved women
ln the skirts?
Under the skirts
Come on
Go up now
The belt. lnside the belt
Not the belt
ln the yellow skirt
Come down...
What a treasure!
lt's a gold vault too
All these years of hard work is worthwhile
Dad
Aren't you looking for the
Bat's kungfu manuals here?
Why are you here?
Wu Liang told me everything
l don't believe it
l thought because of the manuals
...you looked for the Bat Blades
l never thought...
Silly girl
Don't listen to the bullshit
l've found the treasured vault
Szma Villa will be the most reputed...
and wealthy family in boxer world
A pity that you stopped at nothing
to get money
Who brought you here?
lt's me
You...
l didn't believe my father to be
such a person
l want them to witness that my dad...
actually came for the manuals.
Called them to...
see you're trying get rid of
the dirt in boxer world
l wanted them to see...
my father is a real hero
Hero?
How much does a hero worth?
When a man becomes old and weak.
you'll know...
how much is a hero worth!
l tell you the truth
ln fact. 10 years ago
l let the Bat kidnap you on purpose
So l can get the Bat Blade...
to find the treasured vault
You...
But it's fine...
l finally get what l want
Don't get closer
l just stroke her acupuncture point
on the shoulder
She can't move for a couple of hours
Didn't want her to interfere
when l kill you
All of you are useless
You three aren't satisfied yet
You'll be dead too in a minute
How could you be so confident?
Because l'm holding the Bat Blade
The Blade is extremely sharp
Every one says so in the boxer world
How could this sword...?
The Pearl Sword is the lethal weapon
lt can counter the Bat Blade
The Venomous Wuxie
The Poisonous Doctor
What? You still alive?
Of course
lf l was to die.
all these years of hard work
will be wasted
You are here...
for the treasured vault too?
Correct
We've the same kind of...
reputation being righteous gentlemen
in boxer world
We will do anything...
to cheat the treasure vault...
from those so-called notorious scumbags
lt's a pity too...
our plan wasn't successful completely
We both got only a Bat Blade
l realized later...
you've plan on Ximen Luoye
So l turned your trick against you
l gave the Blade to you...
and you'd find the treasured vault for us
Now l come to get the treasured vault
You shameless bastard...
Don't say that
From now on.
both of us will be...
the most reputed gentlemen
in martial world
From now on.
consider yourself all to be dead
No one will ever know what happened here
l'll be a reputed gentlemen...
as before
Why are you so sure we're gonna
die here today?
Because the darts l threw here...
a moment ago
lt carried the most poisonous substance...
that can make people go crazy
You all draw it in your body
When the poison starts reacting
You'll be laughing non-stop
...until you are dead
Your poison?
The faster you move.
The faster the poison reacts
Your poison is really strong
Get the vault
Yes
Listen. everyone go together
Go
Stop there
You...
Me?
l'm not poisoned
When you threw the darts.
l already realized there's something wrong
l held my breath and covered my nose
When l saw you taking off your mask
l knew it's safe to breath
Otherwise as you said...
l'd be surely dead now
Give me the antidote
Don't give him...
l...
That's okay
l will...l will
You...
Where's the antidote?
Kill those mad men first
Okay
What's the matter?
You're poisoned
Now we give...
the antidote to Szma Zhongyuan
Don't come over
What do you want?
l'm giving you the antidote
Don't come over
Look at this bottle
What?
Yes. swallow it
Swallow it?
They're trying to cheat us
They want to kill us
l won't be cheated by you
Brother
Do you know who l am?
Who?
l'm the Bat without Wings
Really?
l can fly too
Can't you see l'm flying now?
l'm flying. flying. flying
Release Miss Szma's pressure point
Yes
Follow me
Hurry up
Look. l'm the Bat without Wings
l can fly...
Dad. don'tjump...
You don't believe that l can fly?
l'll show you that l can
l'm flying...
Dad...
Dad!