Dominic Toretto,
you are hereby sentenced to serve 25 years to life,
at the Lompoc Maximum Security Prison System,
without the possibility of early parole.
This is all the aftermath of a daring daylight breakout.
There were 26 high risk inmates.
Everyone on board has been accounted for
except for one - Dominic Toretto.
Police believe the identity of man
they believe had orchestrated the shocking escape has amazingly
resulted in no fatality this afternoon.
He is former federal agent Brian O'Conner.
Appears to be a manhunt underway for three fugitives tonight.
Multiple federal and local agencies have joined forces
in the search for - Dominic Toretto
and his accomplishes Brian O'Conner and Mia Toretto.
Despite every eye in the country looking for them,
where Toretto and O'Conner are now is any ones guess.
It's gonna be here, all right.
Let's get out of here.
Mia.
Buster.
Come on.
Dom here yet?
- No. - When was the last time you heard from him?
A couple of weeks ago, up in Ecuador or somewhere.
- How does it feel ? - What's that?
Beyond the other side of a wanted person.
- Nice long. - Yes.
Why Rio, Vince?
You mean after you everything screwed up in LA?
Ended up free-fall into South America,
hit every hellhole on the way down.
We kept on going if not for Rosa.
So, listen.
There is a job coming up.
I was hoping Dom was gonna be here by now, but...
This one's clean enough, we can do it without him.
It's a big gig.
Couple of high end cars, easy targets.
All that is putting together a team to swipe them.
Just need a few more willing bodies.
But, I don't know.
Look, the way the car seem is down here,
we can unload them quick and get top dollar.
It's easy money.
From where I am seeing,
it looks like you both could use a pay day.
What are you reading?
- Tour guide. - Yeah?
Tokyo.
You know what all of these places have in common.
Extradition.
Here we go.
Excuse me, boy.
Yeah, we have found them.
Yeah, second through last racer.
What, what is it?
DEA tags, this car is en-seized.
Look, who showed up.
Oh! god, I am so happy you are OK.
I thought I told you to lay low.
We were running out of fuel.
Had to make a call.
Hey, quit talking, we only got a two-minute window.
Let's go, Vince.
Ladies first.
See you baby.
Change of plans, wait for my call.
Let her go.
Where is she going?
We are being robbed, go and pull over the train.
Access card, get the access card.
Dom, there is a bridge.
First is clear.
We are going to next.
Freeze.
We had to make a call, huh.
Shitty call, O'Conner.
Shitty call.
You two started quite a bit of trouble today.
Three of my men dead.
Three DEA agents, along with.
Of course, this is business.
Sometimes things go stray.
All I care about is the car.
Tell me where it is.
And I will let you go.
Three boxes are full of shit.
I do not know how you guys do business in your part of the world.
But here in Rio...
I like all parties to know what they are up against.
That's funny, because it goes both ways.
I hear your sister is very beautiful.
Wherever she hides, I will find her.
Mia?
Hey.
- You ok? - Yeah, you all right?
Just like a Toretto.
Where's Vince?
That's a good question.
He'll be here.
Guys, we are all over the news,
they are blaming us
for killing of those DEA agents on the train.
Which means we just jump to the top of the wanted list.
The Feds will get us anywhere, their agents are off the limits.
They are gonna send their best guys,
we gotta get out of here.
One thing we know for sure
is that they wanted this car.
- Something's in it. - We find out what it is.
We know what we are up against.
Alright, listen up. The men we're after are professional runners.
They like speed and guarantee to go down the hardest possible way.
So make sure you got a lot of firearm.
We find them,
we take them as a team and we bring them back.
And above all else, we never ever let them get into cars.
Let's go hunt.
Agent Hobbs? I'm chief of police.
Sorry to hear for loss of your men.
Is all this really necessary to apprehend two men?
Let me tell you little something about these two men.
One's a former Federal officer, been in deep cover for 5 years,
knows everyway we are gonna come from.
The other one's a professional criminal, escaped prison twice,
spent half his life on run avoiding folks like you.
Well, if there's anything we can do to help...
Two things.
One I need a translator.
Alright, We have plenty...
- Elena Neves. - A patrol officer?
You heard me.
But why? We have many more experienced people.
I like her smile.
What's the second thing?
Stay the fuck out of my way!
Brian.
There is something I have to tell you.
Oh, damn.
What a mess.
Where you have been, Vin?
You better check that tone.
You better answer some goddam questions.
Stop it, both of you.
Where were you, Vince?
Guys all over the favelas are asking questions about you.
Couldn't get out of there without leading them straight to you.
Had to wait them out.
That is such a horse shit, that was your job.
Enough O'Conner!
If he said he didn't do it, he didn't do it.
Go walk it off.
Look, I would love to expand my operations in your country.
But quite frankly.
No business methods are to find.
Let me tell you a true story.
500 years ago,
Portuguese and Spanish came to here.
Each trying to get the country from their natives.
The Spanish arrived guns blazing,
determined to prove who is boss.
But, the natives killed every single spaniard.
Personally, I prefer the methods of the Portuguese.
They came bearing gifts.
Mirrors, scissors, blankets,
things that the native couldn't get on their own.
But, to continue receiving them would require will of Portuguese.
And that's why all Brazilians speaks Portuguese today.
Now, if you dominate the people with violence,
they will eventually fight back.
Because, they have nothing to lose.
And, that's the key
I go into the favelas, and give them something to lose.
Electricity, running water, school room for their kids.
And for that taste of the better life,
I own them.
Gentlemen.
Pardon me gentlemen.
I almost wish I didn't see it.
Almost.
Wait, Dom.
Mia was on that train.
I didn't...I didn't know.
I wouldn't do anything to hurt her.
You set off the deal.
I thought the job was for the cars.
I did not know. All they wanted was the chip.
Damn.
You should have come clean.
What's going on out here?
- Nothing. - Please, Dom.
Just, let me have the chip.
I can take this to them and set things right.
Get out!
What?
You never listened to me.
Not when I told you he was a cop and not now.
You never trusted me.
Now, look where it's gotten us.
Look at our family now, I can't go home.
Your sister is stuck in this life
and where is Letty, Dom?
Where's letty?
Plasma cover.
Wilkes, I want a list of every place
within 50 miles that distribute compressed gas tank.
Pass me that evidence bag.
Officer Neves, I have been waiting for you.
- You asked for me? - I did.
May I ask, why?
My smile is not that great.
Your husband was an officer, who was gunned down in favela.
Six months later you up and join the force?
You are motivated.
Plus I procure the only one that real can't be brought.
Am I right?
- Yes. - Of course I am.
We have got some bad news.
You don't like my deserve first.
I checked the rail-line like you asked,
found a couple of spots where they unloaded the cars.
One set of tracks headed west,
until it hit the main highway and then disappeared.
And the another set of tracks headed east,
170 inch wheel base, half inch track.
The GT40? That was missing from the manifest.
For the track a couple of miles, pretty easy on the scrub.
Can't move without leaving signs.
Give me the damn badges.
The ground rolls into a hard pack and we lost the track too.
Not necessarily.
That road hits through hill into the favelas.
Couple of years ago it was washed out by a storm.
So is dirt from a mile from where you were.
If you headed that way, you will pickup the tracks there.
Come prepared?
I'm motivated.
All right then, let's find ourselves a car.
What do you think?
It's definitely not just a chip.
Look at all these side menus here, for data entry.
Let's check this one.
Look at that. Same building, same order every week.
It's a delivery schedule.
What's this?
- Drugs? - No, that's a dealer pack.
See, the most major player they weigh their money,
so they don't have to cost somebody to account it.
Right there that's 49 kilos. 49 kilos is a million in twenties.
So, you are saying each one of these shipment
is worth 10 million dollars.
Yeah.
I thought so.
So, what is that? A 100 million plus in cash oasis?
That how it keeps it off the grid.
I can say this one is razor smart about this pack.
I mean its whole network right there, just laid out on its inn.
Wilkes and Tom go from the middle, rest flank north.
What about me?
Stay here.
Police! Get on the ground!
I got Torreto.
Hey! Police!
They already know who you are.
Let's go.
- You ok here? - Yeah.
Almost, thank you.
They are gonna be looking for the three of us together now.
We need to split up.
You and Mia head south, I will lead them away.
- No. - Dom's right.
We got lucky to get away, but what happens next time?
We have no choice but to split up.
I am pregnant.
I already lost my family once.
I am not gonna do that again.
- Are you kidding me? - No.
I'm not going anywhere. Ok?
Dom, promise me we stick together.
I promise.
Family just got bigger.
Something doesn't add up.
Toretto and O'Conner.
They stay when they are supposed to run.
They steal gas and then give it away?
And now they killed three Federal agents?
It doesn't make any sense.
Here's what makes sense.
All these guys names are on a list.
They come up, we take'em down.
Not a phone call more, not a bullet less.
Wilkes! We get anything?
Standard forensics, shoe prints, hair fiber.
Prints are all over the car.
Anything else?
Yeah, we track the owner off the vehicle ID.
They are couple of shell companies in between
a electricity corporation owned by a investor named Hernan Reyes.
Investor?
If there is anything illegal happening in Rio,
Reyes is involved.
Okay, then so are we.
If you can send a clothes to that guy
I want every thing on him.
Chato, be on the roof.
I want you on watch in case somebody comes back for something.
Mac give me a cross-check on Reyes, full specs.
He goes to the John, I want to know how many times he shakes it.
- You got it boss. - Let's go.
Let's put all this mess together.
Well, that's gonna take a while.
Then you better get started.
They were taking this car apart for a reason.
Let's put it back together and find out what's missing.
Hey Dom, what do you remember about your father?
My father...
He used to....
he used to have a barbeque every sunday after church.
For everybody in the neighbourhood.
If we didn't go to church we didn't get any barbeque.
Every single day he was in the shop.
And, every single night he was at the kitchen table
with Mia helping her with her homework.
Even after she went to sleep he would stay up for few more hours.
So he could learn the next chapter and help her next day.
I remember everything about my father.
Everything.
That's just it.
I don't know shit about my dad.
I don't remember him yelling, I don't remember him smiling.
To be honest with you,
I don't remember what the hell he look like.
I had all the memories...he is just never there
You ain't gonna be like that, Brian.
We can't keep running, Dom.
We got to get out.
We got to get out, now.
You're right.
This is how we are gonna do it.
We are gonna use this into one last job.
We are gonna take all the Reyes money.
Every dime of it.
And then, disappear...
forever
New passports, new life, and no more looking over our shoulder.
- And we are just gonna buy our freedom. - That's right.
You realize we are talking about
going up against most powerful guy in all over Rio.
Yes. We are.
Then we are gonna need a team.
Alright, let's go through the basics real quick.
What do we got?
First, we are gonna need a chameleon.
Someone who can blend in... anywhere.
What else?
A fast talker.
Someone who can bullshit the way out of anything.
I got that.
These guys are gonna have a lot of surveillance we are
gonna need someone who can schedule the circuits.
And with those circuits, Reyes is gonna have a "Wall".
We are gonna need the guys who can punch through those walls.
What else?
Utilities and weapons.
Someone who ain't afraid to throw down.
Someone who backup every position.
Yeah? What else we need ?
Most importantly we are gonna need two persistent drivers.
Guys who don't crack under pressure.
Guys who never lose.
You know we got that.
Ah...hell not.
I see they really stared the bottom of the beer.
I guess they did, since your ass is here.
When you are gonna give Martin Luther King his car back?
As soon as you give Rick James his jacket back.
Sexy legs baby girl.
What time do they open?
They open the same time when I pull this trigger.
Want me to open them?
Yeah anybody can talk shit in spanish
- Two fails, I am not fail...  - Two fails.
- Who are these clowns men? - Circus clowns.
I thought comply is too illegal in Brazil.
I see, you have all met.
Here he is.
You know when you called me to come to Rio,
I assumed it would be for something more exciting than this.
This is Tej, the best circuit men in the east coast.
This is my boy Roman Pearce,
we go way back from juvenile.
I pulled that job with him Miami.
I heard about you.
Nice stakes.
Yeah, the rest were sold out.
So, whats this all about, Dom?
Why you drag us half way around the world.
Because we got a job.
Alright, so target's name is Hernan Reyes.
He runs the drug scene out there.
He has never been busted
because he doesn't leave a paper trail.
No paper trails means no banks.
No banks means cash houses.
That's right.
To tell you exact,
it's spread throughout the city.
And we are gonna hit them all.
- All of them.  - All of them.
Sounds crazy. Bring us to whole another country,
so that we can rob the dude who runs it.
I thought this is business,
sounds personal to me.
Is that what this is?
I got love for you all,
but personal ain't good business.
I can't do this homie.
So, what we are talking about is a 100 million dollar.
You say what?
See, sometimes I be over-thinking,
maybe and you know I know...we just met...but,
you just kinda gotta...
A 100 million dollars.
And everything we take, we split even.
So, that's 11 million a piece,
I am down.
I am in.
11 million?
Sounds like a whole lotta vaginal activity to me.
You can't pull off all the heist
on the same mark, you just can't.
Yeah, as soon as we hit the first one they are gonna
do everything they can to protect their assets.
Exactly.
That's all of it.
You're dead men. You're all dead men.
You don't have a place to hide.
Who is hiding?
Are you crazy ? Are you crazy?
Do you know whose house this is?
Whose money are you stealing?
We ain't stealing.
You tell your boss, exactly who did this.
Tell him there is more coming.
Wallah
Turn it over.
Its running alright, checks out fine.
Keep looking.
Boss, if something was missing we would know.
Its a goddamn shame to put a bullshit like that on a classic.
Here, as well slap some on light on it.
They took the chip.
We got a hit on the police scanner.
Armed robbery in the house of golan.
Alright if that's our guys then
whatever was on that chip led them directly to that house.
It's them for sure.
How do you know that?
Because no one else in Rio is stupid enough to rob Reyes.
Number 1 is on the move, man.
Two is on the move.
Yeah, I got mine.
I got eyes on five.
I know you said they were consolidating money somewhere.
But you all ain't gonna believe this.
Well, this job has got a little harder.
If he is moving it into a police station,
he has got some serious brass in his pocket.
Hell yeah, we can't do this.
We can't or we shouldn't.
I think it doesn't change a thing.
I say we stick to the plan.
You say what?
This shit just went from mission impossible
to mission freakin' insanity.
Whatever man!
I ain't scared. I am just letting you all know.
Going in that bouty, it's just crazy.
What time is robbery?
Around 11' o clock.
Here we go.
Enhance it.
Their faces are covered. Run it through FRS.
Well, hello you son of a bitch.
Wilkes, run the photos of
known associates of Torretto and
O'Conner against custom entries in Brazil within last 2 weeks.
Check planes, trains, boats
and everything short of a goddamn space shuttle.
They can change their names but, they can't change their faces.
Something big is going down.
That's a 1970 Charger.
Let's go.
Upload these facts into the database have the computer
cross-check them with the overhead satellites at every 15 minutes.
Stand behind in two.
If these vehicles move on the streets of Rio,
I wanna know about it.
The beauty of police offices.
A blueprint.
This is where they are keeping the money.
The vault's in the evidence room.
Can I get everyone's attention right here for a second,
we are talking about breaking into a police station.
Is anyone listening to those words? Anybody? Po-Po,
Five O, one time, peaks,
people we don't like.
You know police stations are
designed actually to let people in and out.
That's why it's a stealth mission.
We move in and out before they even know we are there.
Well, we need to get eyes in there.
At least, to find out how big the model of that vault.
Who's the folk you know, do all this.
Wait...what do you mean?
Why me?
Because you got the biggest mouth.
That is for damn certain.
Hello beautiful. Look at those dimples sexy, sexy.
Love those glasses, where did you get them from?
Is it gucci frames or something?
Damn.
Who are you sir?
Special agent O'Conner. US federal bureo of investigation.
It says caucasian?
Well, its the tan...you know tan.
Look, I am working this case
and I got some evidence here to be held.
But I need to get in and check your storage facility first.
Nope.
Look man I know you are a true professional
and I respects you, I promise.
You know, it look like you workout a little bit too.
What's you benchmark? 350.
Look, I'm just trying to do my job.
My boss sent me here to just make sure everything is safe.
It will be safe.
Ok, will you let me just come in and take a quick peek.
- Nope.  - Come on, man.
Hook a brother up please.
No. And you are not my brother.
Brother from another mother?
Look, no one enters the facility but authorized evidence personnel,
now stop wasting my time.
- I am going to call the embassy.  - No, no, no.
We good, we don't need to call them. For what?
We good.
Here, I got the box.
We all good, I promise you.
Thank you so much for your time.
I swore to god, if I was on the other side of the glass
I will bust your damn face
and translate that.
You see, I think I make a better special agent than you ever did.
Well, that depends on how you define special.
Oh..man, let's see what we got. Have fun.
Alright come on.
Though, you still can't drive.
You see. Now I see why you always getting accidents.
You can't drive a damn remote control car.
Shut up right now.
- I am not gonna shut up.  - Shut up.
Strap him in his safety belt man.
Give me the remote, going left. It looks like
something right over there to the left. What is that?
Bingo.
What is this, 6 x 6?
8 x 12?
7 x 12. 18-inch thick steel. Re-Enforced wall,
with insulated copper core to protect it against thermal lance.
The class 3 electronical lock would sure fire.
And a biometric palm scanner.
Ten times the top of the line security.
Do I wanna know, how you know all that?
I had a life before you know me O'Conner.
Let's just leave it with that, alright.
She is a beauty, though.
Beauty as in good?
Beauty as in you know... start of playing hard to get.
And, no matter how much I care her, no matter how much I love her
in the end she still ain't gonna give up that ass.
I got this, relax man, relax.
Got it, we got it.
Yeah, we are looking at four cameras.
Now, that's some high end shit too. Marker optics.
They refill the view, 10 seconds oscillation.
Nah, that's a narrow window man?
Can we just stop the scanner and replace the image.
Nah. Its hooked up into a digital sync.
Ain't no way around the system.
The best we can do is peek.
We are gonna need some real fast cars to get to this.
And, not just fast,
we need a hard ride and air.
We need something agile.
You guys mark up a track.
O'Conner, lets go get some cars.
Home, sweet home.
How about that? All motors and no tuning issues?
I always wanted one of those.
Held the record on the Envadeda 3 years running.
You got a lot of bones to bring your problems here Torreto.
Not to mention a cop.
Yeah, we can keep that on the low.
Word on the street is that a lot of people are looking for you two.
But, you didn't think we would recognise you?
Well, what kind of car you own?
That little cool may run the street around here,
but that monster has never seen a set ot tail lights, ever.
Well she is about to.
Lets go, legend.
Car for a car.
Car for car?
If you want it, come and get it.
Really?
Whe...whe...where did you get that from?
Popa's mark.
Ok O'Conner, give me your best shot.
How was that one?
Camera caught you.
What?
Yeah it still caught you.
Then I will milk the hell out of that thing too.
We are gonna need a faster car.
Exactly why your ass ain't been driving.
You gotta re-blaze.
I think, I am in love.
That was a real solid work,
but I think camera 3 still caught you though.
Let's do it again.
That's your piggy bank? You kidding me yup?
Where the hell can I get one of these?
Well we had a life before you met us.
Alright, well I get to work on the electronics tunneler.
But there's still another problem,
palm scanner.
And without Reyes hand-print,
Houdini himself can not open this bitch.
How do you know it's Reyes's hand-print?
You got 100 million dollars in a safe,
you gonna put somebody else's hand-print on it?
How are we supposed to get Reyes's hand-print?
Han, you are up.
Sure, gotta make the easy stuff.
Let's go, I will drive.
That makes six bodyguards.
Seven.
Do you think that guy with a funny look is a tourist?
So, how long were you in the army?
I got out of military probably the same time you quit smoking.
The amount of chips you ate.
The way you always had to keep your hands and mouth busy.
You are a two packs a day, for sure.
Un-Filtered.
Well, this is a bust.
How you gonna get Reyes fingerprint out of here?
You need to do some more recon.
Kinda couple extra guys.
Alright, you don't send a man to do a woman's job.
We gonna figure this out, I promise you.
What's that?
I thought she was more of a thong man?
We got the prints.
Where?
Ok. That's crazy.
So, did he just like slap that ass?
Or, did he like grab and hold on to it?
This will work.
- I'm impressed.  - Got it?
Got it. But, you still didn't answer the question.
Guys! Guys!
Guys, we have a problem.
The whole team just got burned.
Now we are all wanted.
Hang on a second.
Us diplomatic security service issued the warrants.
Agent . Hold on a second.
Hey Dom.
Is that the guy you saw in the favela?
Yeah.
Hobbs is the leader of the elite task force for the DSS.
So, he is good?
When the FBI wants to find somebody that's who they call.
Because he never misses his mark.
This guy is...he is old testament.
Blood, bullets, rap the God that's his style.
And right now he is hunting us?
Dom, we are gonna move up our time line.
Yes, but how?
This thing has already been difficult.
If it ain't that.
We need more room to breathe.
Roman is right.
We need to get some fresh air.
It got a hit.
Let's move.
Move! Move! Move!
Stopped, about a block ahead.
Park it, we are going on foot.
Hey, Toretto.
You're under arrest.
Arrest?
I don't feel like I am under arrest.
How about you, Brian?
Nah...not a bit.
Not even a little bit.
I will just give a minute, it will sink in.
We didn't kill those feds.
- That's Reyes.  - I don't give a shit.
Just here to bring in two assholes whose names hit my desk.
Yeah, that sounds like a real hero.
That's funny.
From a guy who took the oath of a cop
and then went against everything he stood for?
Or, some wanna be tough guy prick
who beat a man half to death with a socket rinch.
That real tough.
You turn around and put hands behind your back.
I don't think so.
You are so mistaken to think you got a goddamn choice boy.
Your mistake ? Thinking you are in America.
You're a long way from home.
This is Brazil!
Come on boss, another day.
Come on, it's way too heat.
I will see you soon, Toretto.
I am looking forward to it.
Yep.
Tracker's on.
Got him.
I don't understand. Why come here?
Why risk it all for 20 dollar worth of silver?
Because it's worth it.
You should run,  you know!
Hobbs will find you
You have every reason to leave, why stay ?
Why do you?
My husband was a good police officer...
an honest man...
we both grew up here.
Two years ago, he was murdered in the streets
right outside out our door.
Reyes owns this place.
He gives things to people.
And, everything has a price.
People here need a new start.
They need to be free.
You didn't killed those men in the train, did you?
Now, why would you believe anything I would tell you.
Was she so special to you?
I never thought anyone could understand how much.
But you do.
Close, but not enough.
Time window is too small, man.
The only way we can beat the cameras, is with invisible cars.
And I know, just where to get them.
Let's take a ride boys.
Don't hurt yourself.
It's been a while since i have been behind the wheel of one of these.
First time I've ever been in the front seat.
Hey, Rom what took you so long.
I thought for sure, you be showing up
with some chrome spinners or something.
Ha.....hah....real funny.
I got a 100,000 that says
I can take you all in the next quarter mile.
Yeah, you broke that like you got a 100 grand.
If we pull off this job, I will.
Next two lights, a 100,000.
If we don't pull this job off, we are probably dead anyway.
Let's make it a million.
I like that.
Alright, million dollar a quarter mile.
Alright then.
We only live once, let's do it.
What do you say Dom?
Are we talking or we racing?
Just don't cheat this time.
You gotta let that go.
It makes too easy for me boys.
No.
Not this time, Dom.
Got your wanted.
Yeah, owned you....owned you.
Good race, O'Conner.
Thanks, Dom.
You don't on the way, Rich.
Hold on, you can see it.
The man right there!
He left off the throttle with a mile.
You didn't do nothing.
He let you win.
Bullshit.
Vince, what are you doing?
Quiet, you have been tracked.
It's..ok...wait.
Reyes's guys were waiting for me at the market.
And, Vince saved my life.
You hungry?
Yeah, sure
Good!
Because you are saying grace.
Thanks Vince.
Cheers...cheers...cheers.
So we in Brazil, still a good life.
Yeah.
So, you got a...you got a
little more than 10-11 million dollars coming.
What's you gonna do with your money?
- Me? - Yeah.
Actually...man, I have been thinking about
opening up a garage back home.
A place where people can bring their cars,
and they get completely ripped off, you know what I mean?
- Really? - Yeah.
So, your dream is to start a day job?
That's...that's stupid...man, why would..
Nah...that's not stupid at all. Man.
I love what I do.
You wanna know what I am gonna do with my money.
Find some cooking lesson for my man.
See, see? There you with that theory man?
You know me...money and god damn thing.
It's gonna take a little more than money
to learn how to cook...that's all.
But, I heard they were looking for a chef.
Down at this animal shelter. Where you might....wanna.
Hey Dom,
Listen, I know you have a separate job tomorrow.
If you need an extra men...
Mike, you are in.
You always have been a family.
Thank you!
Get something to eat.
Yeah.
Brian calls it a curse.
She might be right.
You really like doing that stuff, huh?
When your life is on the line,
that's when you manner by yourself.
That's a fair deal?
We are less than 24 hours
from biggest celebration of our life.
You gotta re-fill.
This is some serious stuff.
No, I am good...I am good...no...thank you!
No, she can't.
What do you mean?
She can't.
What do you mean, she can't?
Are you serious right now?
Is that the reason you let him beat you in the quarter mile?
That was a baby gift.
No, that's messed up.
But, still it's a baby gift.
No, you are not taking that from me.
Wait, wait...hold on a second.
Did he just smack that ass or, did he grab the ass?
Thanks. Thank you.
It's your boy. Why would you keep something like that away from us.
You did it again, huh.
Baby gift?
I have no idea what they are talking about?
Toast!
Money will come and go, we know that.
The most important thing in life
will always be the people in this room.
Right here, right now.
Salute, de favelia... salute...salute...
I'm all set.
Santos, all good?
Yeah, I am always good, bro.
Hobbs is on the other side of the city.
We are not gonna get a better window.
Ok guys, it's showtime.
First team in position, let's go.
Come on, let's do this.
Hey Dom, I got eyes on Mia.
Moscow, Berlin, Goa, Hong Kong.
What do they have all in common?
We are one hour away from rest of that.
Yeah.
Police!
Come on, go.
You just made a big mistake.
It took me while to find out that tracking chip.
But, not as long to flip the receiver.
You're going down Torretto.
I'm right here.
Dom!
Stand back, I got this.
Dom, please, Dom.
Stop!
Dom!
Yeah?
We are coming in now.
Tell the marshals to prepare a vehicle to home back.
Ambush!
Wilkes, suppressing fire. Set them down.
Macroy, cover me.
Watch that.
Cut us loose! Come on! Cut us loose!
Everything all right? Let's go! Let's go!
Hey Dom,
you didn't meet my son
Nico.
I will.
He is a good kid.
You know, we named him after you
Dominic.
You have my word, Vince.
You were always my brother.
See you my brother.
We need to move, we don't have that much time.
I got some flight out,
that leaves Rio de Janeiro in next 5 hours.
Not to run away....
To finish the job.
Are you crazy Dom ? We can't.
It's a suicide mission.
That's your man over there on the table.
The plan is busted, this is bullshit man.
Reyes knows we are coming.
He's right.
They tripled the detail of the police station ,
it's gonna be a wall of gunfire.
Reyes doesn't get away with this.
It's a trap man, you know that.
Dom! Listen to them.
Run, before its too late.
Leave Rio, you can be free.
I don't need freedom.
You should know that.
You know you are all free to make your own choices.
I am in.
I will ride with you, Toretto.
At least, until we kill that son of a bitch.
So, what's the plan Dom?
We can't just go sneaking around any more.
We don't sneak.
The only thing that he cares about is his money.
If we pull that, we pull him.
Are you ready?
I'm ready.
Holl it out, Mia?
You got a straight shot, two blocks.
Go right.
Got it
Wow, the plan's working.
You guys have every cop car in Rio on your tail.
You guys have to move fast.
What's the best drop?
Ok. Keep going straight another half mile at Du-luff-seeker.
And then go left.
It ain't gonna work
Spikes ahead Dom, we got spikes.
We are going right.
Nah... it's too tight... we are not gonna fit.
We have no choice. Now.
Sh...it!
Holy...shit!
Guys I am hearing all this chatter,
you just take out a bank ?
Two in-Bound.
Alright! There is an ally coming on your left.
Yeah! I got it.
You bastard.
Alright Dom, right turn right here.
Ok guys, there is a big group coming at you from south.
You have do something, now.
Let's go wide.
You all clear on the left.
Good afternoon, officer.
License and registration, please.
Yeah! This is big boy stuff.
We are clear on the right.
- Thanks guys. - Anytime.
I see you on the other side.
You guys just copped out a 10 second window, make it count.
No...there is too many of them.
We are not gonna make it.
You're right, we aren't.
- You are. - What are you talking about?
Just let the vault go. Get out of there.
You're a father now, Brian.
No, I'm not leaving you.
You stick with the plan.
It was always the plan.
Take care of Mia.
Dom, you listen to me now.
Ok, you cut loose right now.
I thought I told you to go on.
Yeah! I had to make a call.
Help me.
That's for my team you son of a bitch.
It's hell of a mess.
Yeah, it is.
You know, I can't let you two to go.
I ain't made that way.
I will see to it that you bring yourself 24 hours.
The money stays though.
If I were you, I would use the time.
Make peace with whatever things you got left.
Because come tomorrow, I will find you.
Toretto
I'll see you soon.
No, you won't.
Thanks guys.
I see you on the other side.
You guys just copped out a 10 second window
Make it count.
Come on baby, don't be mean.
Right this way, my dear
Stay right here, I will be right back.
So, this is your dream...Huh
That's enough of me man
I take you are enjoying?
Absolutely...what's up...
Boy, what's going on?
- You good. - Yes, yes.
You know what's crazy?
There is only four of those cars in the whole world.
And I got the only one in western hemisphere
I made a sheikh in Abu Dhabi an offer he could not refuse.
And, that's a nice lady you got there too.
Oh...absolutely
Well...we got to go man. Let's do this
Ok, I will drive.
In that? Come on man..No...no way
No...Not...not in this, in that!
Are you serious right now.
Oh..Man...this is crazy.
Yeah. So, I guess that means there are
two in the western hemisphere..Huh...huh
What's your smart ass gotta say now?
Well...you know what, we can always shine together baby.
Get dressed man, we got things to do.
So, where to now?
I don't know.
Never been to Madrid.
I thought you wanna go to Tokyo...
We will get there...
Eventually...
This is the happiest I have ever seen my sister.
It goes with free.
You know? I wanna another shot.
Yeah?
Yeah.
No wagers, no body-else,
just you and me, once and for all
You sure, you gonna handle the disappointment?
Are you?
Alright, O'Conner
Let's see what you got.
You need to look at that.
Berlin, 3 am this morning.
A team of drivers, hijacked a military convey.
- Toretto. - Nope
Ain't interested.
Yes, you are, keep looking.
You believe in ghosts.
Come on, go.
You just made a big mistake.