This programme contains adult
humour
Oi! You know the rules. Huh!
Ooh, careful! You might not be able
to fit into your,
I'm going to say, wedding tracksuit?
Ah, yeah, do you still want
a plus-one to the wedding?
I say this with love,
but even if there was someone
important in my life, I would walk
backwards over hot coals
to make sure they never, ever
meet your uncle Pat.
You've met my auntie Pat.
Oh, my God.
You never know, you might meet
someone special at the wedding.
Ooh, I do love an Italian stallion.
Ah, about the destination wedding,
I couldn't afford it.
So instead, I've booked this
beautiful authentic Italian
restaurant. They've got beautiful
wines, anti-pasties, the lot.
It's called...
IN ITALIAN ACCENT: ..Allbarone.
Ooh, ciao, Bella!
But I don't know her.
Oh, you'll love it, mate.
It's right opposite the station.
It's got loads of stalls.
Mitchell, that's All Bar One!
No, no, no, no, no. This is an
Allbarone... Shit!
They put all the words close
together on the website!
They shouldn't be allowed
to do that.
Please tell me
Kylie has not consented to this.
Kayleigh and, no, I booked it as a
surprise. I was going to show her
around the venue tomorrow night.
Have you still got time
to change it?
I blew the rest of the budget
on a real-life Italian singer...
IN ITALIAN ACCENT: ..Anthony Costa.
Mitchell, the wedding is next month!
What am I going to do?
Allbarone took my deposit and
Anthony Costa charged me five grand.
Oh, my God, this is a wake-up call.
I really need to grow up.
You really do.
CROWD: Fight! Fight! Fight! Fight!
Sweet! Argh!
BOTH: Fight! Fight! Fight!
ALL: Fight! Fight! Fight! Fight!
Fight! Fight! Fight! Fight!
Woo! I'm Lucci! I love it!
Roaring up to the socials, let's go!
Yeah! Yeah!
Oh, my God, it's Warren!
CROWD CHANT: Lucci! Lucci! Lucci!
Do something then, sir!
Warren, play dead.
HE GROANS
My wee little heart!
COUGHS WEAKLY, BREATHES HEAVILY
Ha! Stay down, you muppet!
Let me get a...
ALL: Oooooooooooooh!
CHEERING
You monsters! That's recycling!
Got to get your protein in after
a good tear up.
Shake-Eel is the shit! Mm!
COUGHS
Like and subscribe, bitches!
4K, all day. Peace! Woo!
Gentlemen. Right, listen here,
you... Oh! Cheers, sir. Woo!
Warren, you can stop playing
dead now.
Oh, not another one.
And scene!
WARREN GRUNTS
Thank God for that.
Urgh! Ooh! That is minging!
SCREAMS, GRUNTS
Oh, my God!
Harrison, get the first aid kit.
Oh, Warren!
You puked on my Loubs! Ow!
MUMBLES
Murder.
I didn't catch a word of that.
Oh, she said that little scrote put
superglue in her lipstick.
Warren, that is quality!
Not Warren, Lucci Bantz. Warren was
sticking up for Usma.
CLICKS FINGERS
Loubs!
Warren picked a fight with
that unit? Who is he anyway?
You should know him, he's in your
form. I don't bother with that lot.
They've got no banter.
But, bro, he's got
200,000 followers.
He broke the internet by pranking
his parents, at his own funeral.
What's uuuuuuuup?!
Lucci doesn't die!
You should know this! What's up?
Miss, look, you're being filmed!
Filmed! There's a camera there,
this is going to get millions of
views. Old sad woman.
I'm proud of you, Warren. Would have
put big money on you
going down sooner.
You put up a good fight.
Jinx, shut up a minute,
I'm thinking.
I haven't said a word all day.
This Lucci's got a shit
load of followers, yeah?
And they would all bet big on him
to winning a fight.
So, if we stuck him
in the ring with a proper waif
and then, hypothetically, there was
a massive upset,
then hypothetically,
someone would make a fortune.
Everyone's going to bet on Lucci.
Yeah, but then I'd back the
underdog.
And then when Lucci takes a fall...
You'll make money!
Pay for my wedding
and save my relationship.
Wait, man, that's not going to work.
Anyways, Lucci Bantz is going to
throw a fight?
He'll look like a tit.
How do you know what a tit
looks like?
Cos I've seen one, innit.
Your sister in the shower
don't count.
KISSES TEETH
Inchez is right, sir.
Lucci's all about image.
But I'm his form teacher
and if I don't sign his report card,
Lucci will get excluded.
So you're going to blackmail
a child into helping you embezzle
many other children?
See, Jinx, when you shut up
and you listen, you get it.
No...
Oh, your son's therapist did
call me. Well, yes, I agree,
there has been a slight
uptick in playground argy bargy.
Yes, no, two broken legs.
That is probably one too many
thinking about it,
so, look, leave it with me.
God help us if there's a third world
war. I mean, I think we are
very much in danger of sucking all
the spunk out of our young men.
Parents are blaming the epidemic
of violence on Luke Banister,
aka Lucci Bantz.
Ah, leave the handbags to me, miss.
What do you know about handbags,
Harper,
other than how to snatch them
from the back of a speeding moped?
No, the argy bargy. Look, as a
physical educator, I believe if
the kids are choosing violence, then
we've got to speak their language.
Great minds.
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
Yep. Whipping.
Boxing match. Whipping?
No, fair. No, perhaps whipping does
have some negative connotations.
But a shatterproof ruler,
a well-aimed slipper.
Yeah, I was just
thinking about a boxing match.
Less bruising through a glove,
I like it.
As long as it takes place
behind closed doors.
No, no, we've got to get a crowd
in. To...make an example of 'em.
Oh, I see! Like a public hanging.
Yes.
I mean, it is too late
for Luke Banister unfortunately,
I will have to expel him.
No, no, don't do that, love.
No, stick him on red report.
I'm his form teacher,
so if he steps out of line,
I won't sign his report card,
goodbye, Lucci Bantz.
I like it.
But don't call me love.
Fraser?
Ooh, since when did you have pets?
I wouldn't call them pets exactly,
but I'm not needlessly cruel. Soup?
Right, that is exactly why you're
not catering my wedding.
Spaghetti arabantia, ledgesana,
freshly baked ladaleines -
please, I would love to cater an
All Bar One, it's a stunning venue.
You knew that it was an All Bar One?
Yes! I can't wait to show
Anthony Costa my
Anthony Costa tattoo.
Where's Lucci?
And why is he plugging all this
shit on his socials?
Lucci's mum won't let him
drink protein shakes at home.
She's a real fun sponge.
Fraze bars?
Shake-Eel.
It's a pun,
but they're also 30% real eel.
I shot Lucci the good shit
and he made me
the Eelon Musk of the
protein community.
Simples!
Table for three?
Here he is!
Ha!
Welcome to Chez Fray.
Any allergies?
Yeah. I'm allergic to old
geezers in shit trainers.
Whoa! Shots fired!
Someone's hangry.
You meant him, right? Ahem!
Listen here, son.
You might think you're
Billy Big Bollocks now
but I can take your career
up a level. Who are you?
I am your ticket to the big time.
And I am putting on a fight that's
going to make Fury Wilder
look like Will Smith defending his
little grumpy mate at the Oscars.
The only thing is, is you've got to
go down in the fourth round.
What? Right. Little man,
I'm Lucci Bantz!
4K, biatch!
I don't lose!
Can't even spell lose.
So you'd lose a spelling bee.
LAUGHS
What?!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
SLURRED: I know you're really
disrespecting my boy asking him
to fight for nothing.
Fraser, are you having a stroke?
No, he's doing this
Sly Stallone impression.
No, actually, I do think
I am allergic to something
in the Shake-Eel.
Guessing it's the eel.
Ooh, boy! That's why they're always
so kind to me
at the London Aquarium.
Right, listen, Banister,
unfortunately for you,
I'm also your form teacher.
Now, you need me
to sign your report card, or else
you're going to get expelled.
No school, no content.
And all of this goes away.
So, are you going to go down in the
fourth round or not?
I hope you like it blue.
Lucci agreed to fight!
Abbey Grove Fight Night is on.
And I'll be taking full creative
control of this production.
Oh, do you like boxing, sir?
Uh, Cagey Joe in Bugsy, yeah.
Who? OK, fine.
We want it to feel like heavyweights
in Vegas.
Celine, Adele, Britney.
Tyson, Mayweather, Lennox Lewis.
Is that Leona's brother?
Oh, for God's sake!
Right. We need to find a challenger.
Me! Me, sir, man.
I need to sprinkle some
karma on that bitch, cos at 11.59,
messing with a girl's power plump
lip gloss, is haram.
I swear, I'm going to gouge that
prick's eye out
and use it as a Beautyblender!
Loving the energy but I'm afraid
this one is for the boys.
Ooh, ooh, oooh! I'll fight for you,
sir, and I will win,
cos this is a game of inches
and I am the king!
I'll be the lyric-spitting bad
man that will crush Lucci Bantz.
Then I'll shag his mother
while he shits his pants!
SCREAMS
Oh!
I've heard of a glass jaw but I've
never seen a glass fist before.
All you've got to do is dance round
the ring for four rounds
and then one punch, yeah?
And they say I don't teach you all
transferable skills.
He doesn't mean literally
dancing around the ring.
Bopability, passion! Use it, Warren!
Tits and teeth!
MOANS
Come on, you dosser! Let's go.
I am a fighter, but I'm also
a lover as well, you know?
Look in the mirror, what do you see?
Uh, me. No.
That right there is
your biggest enemy.
WAILS
Oh, for f... The kid's a bell-end.
Jab! Jab! Jab! Punch!
Woo! God, this horse is going to be
tender.
Yeah! Urgh!
Woo! Nice one, champ.
So, is your mum still single? Argh!
Hmm!
The photo I'm holding in my hand
is of the champion
we have selected to represent Class
K in the fight of this century,
thus saving Mr Harper's wedding.
Ooh!
Warren, my love...it's not you.
Yeah, I love Kayleigh, mate,
but I couldn't do that to ya.
Besides, the last thing
I need is another court date.
LAUGHS
I'm sorry, is this a joke to you?
I cannot believe you would come
in here with a defeatist attitude.
I'm sorry, sir,
I'm just not a fighter.
Take control of your own destiny.
No, I don't want to get
humiliated by that monster.
Stop it!
I have never in my life
yelled at a girl like this!
I was rooting for you,
we were all rooting for you!
Mm-hm, mm-hm.
Learn something from this!
Can you just tell them
who's fighting?
It's Harrison.
SCREAMS
It's him again!
Ladies and gentlemen,
tomorrow night, two giants go
head-to-head here at Abbey Grove.
ALL: Ooh!
Let's meet the fighters.
He's got a million-dollar smile
but don't let that fool you.
He's a killer.
It's Harrison "The Hurricane".
MUSIC: Believe
by Cher
Stop it! Stop!
No, I said no pictures! Get back!
Get back!
Warren.
What the hell is this music?
What? You asked for Believe.
Yeah, by Eminem.
MUSIC CHANGES
Oh, that's more like it.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
Lucci Bantz.
4K...
CROWD: ..All day!
CROWD: ..All day.
Woo! Let's go!
Right, gentlemen,
before we weigh you,
let's face off for one last time.
Wait. What's this bit?
It's like Housewives, The Reunion.
Oh, work!
Ha!
LUCCI LAUGHS
It's a pussy!
I can't fight him,
I'll get done by the RSPCA, won't I?
Harrison, say something.
Say something back to him.
Erm...
WHISPERS: Stephen.
Uh...
Yeah? Well, you're a dumb ho. Ah!
And, er, your shorts are not
giving, child.
Also, your shoulders are
overdeveloped.
I'm going to go through
you like Fraser's tuna bhuna.
ALL: Ooh!
That bad boy burns.
WHISPERS: Go on, Harrison. One more.
HE PURRS
Meow! What's he doing?
Stephen, what did you tell him?
I just said slap him.
Purr! Oh, God. He thinks he's a cat.
Meow!
Oh, no.
Oh, I think he likes you, look.
LAUGHS
SCREAMS
Oh! OK, OK, that'll do.
LAUGHTER
Get some of this inside you.
Ten inches of non-filtered eel.
I don't want the eel!
Er, Blessing, these odds
are far too short.
I can't help it, sir.
Everyone's betting on Harrison.
He made Lucci look
like a dickhead in the weigh-in.
Even if I win,
I ain't going to make any money.
And I've got my eye on this gorgeous
little Mexican spot for my wedding.
Brand-new in town,
it's called Taco Bella.
Are you trying to say
Taco Bell in a Spanish accent?
No. Don't ask stupid questions.
Right, we need to change fighters.
The only way we can change fighters
is through injury,
otherwise people are going to get
suspicious.
Sir! Sir! Oh, my God!
Harrison just headbutted a mirror!
There is blood everywhere!
Result! Problem solved.
Ha-ha! Right.
Let's change this fighter.
We need to find someone that is
utterly, utterly pathetic,
like a proper little streak of piss.
Like a little...
Warren. Warren?
You can't make him
fight Lucci Bantz, sir.
Warren has PTSD. Ah, is that the one
where you can't concentrate?
No, it's post traumatic...
Oh, look, meatballs for lunch.
Lovely. Come on, sir.
Sir, Lucci already humiliated me
in front of the whole school.
You said you weren't going to make
me fight. Warren,
if you get in that ring for me,
all of you can come
to my wedding, yeah?
It's a free bar and some
of the bridesmaids ain't picky.
Do it, Warren.
Do it for the pussy, man.
I said they weren't picky,
I didn't say they was blind.
I can't. I'm sorry.
Look, Warren, please.
If Kayleigh finds out that
I've ruined her big day, then...
Well, then she's going to leave me.
I really love her.
Come on. You know
you want to help me out.
OK. Yeah! Oh, my God, phallus!
What? Oh, my gosh! Who put that?
Right. Get out of the way,
you dossers.
I am betting 500 quid on Warren
to win by knockout Round 4.
Thank you very much.
PHONE RINGS
Wait, let me at it.
Let me see, let me see.
Hello, babe. You all right?
ON PHONE: Mitchell, where are you?
Eh? Harper! Where are you?
Just give me sec, yeah? One sec.
All right, Miss?
Look, when I agreed to this event,
I didn't expect you to
invite the parents!
Well, of course,
I invited the parents, Miss,
they're here to help the pot.
A pot...
Pot...ential of this innovative
disciplinary event.
I love your dickie bow... Sh!
Now, I know there's money
changing hands.
Let me make this nice and easy,
in words of one syllable,
I want you to get my beak wet.
Miss Hoburn, do you really think
I would pull the ladder up? Yes.
The school gets the gate, you get
the car park, how does that sound?
Deal. Hey! Yes, I drive a hard
bargain, Mr Harper.
Don't forget,
I helped the government procure
PPE during the pannie D.
Yeah, right. There you go.
Ooh! I like it. Sweet as.
PHONE BEEPS
Sorry, babe, where were we?
ON PHONE: Do you remember what
we were meant to be doing tonight?
Huh?
Oh, shit! I forgot to cancel.
Bollocks!
You ain't gone to Allbarone,
have you?
You mean All Bar One?
Mitchell?
Ah, did you drive?
That'll be the sat nav
getting confused. It done that to
me... Mitchell, if you've spent
that money, I swear to God...
No, no, no, no, no!
Babe, I will explain everything
in about four rounds' time, yeah?
Uh, Usma? Usma! Can you get Kayleigh
a seat, please? Front row.
Oh! Front row? With these clothes?
Just do it, please.
Come on, I'm really stressed out.
What is going on?
Love you.
HE CHUCKLES
W...Welcome to Fight Night
in Hertfordshire's Sin City!
Give it up!
CHEERING
I give you Lucci Bantz!
CROWD CHANT: Lucci! Lucci! Lucci!
BOOING
That's me, huh? Lucci, that's me!
And now it is my pleasure to
introduce Abbey Grove's most
sickening bitch, it's Warren!
MUSIC: If I Could Turn Back Time
by Cher
Take his eyes out, Warren!
Woo!
Warren, stop fannying about
and get in the ring.
He can't even get in the ring.
THEY LAUGH
Ow! Ah!
Sir, when I asked for
a different song,
I didn't mean another
one from the same Cher album.
Now, Warren, how do you see this
fight playing out tonight?
I see it from a bird's-eye view.
I'm...I'm floating weightless...
watching my body being
thrown around like a rag doll.
The higher I get, the less my death
seems to matter. Ah, ah, ah!
There is a golden boy inside of you,
not just a punched out trap!
As I said when I played Cagey Joe
in Bugsy...
I don't know how
that's going to help.
You're not listening!
I am a dead man walking and there's
nothing that you learned as an
understudy on a free town tour of
Bugsy Malone that can change that!
Bravo, Warren.
One minute in the spotlight and I
don't even recognise you any more.
I would like to invite you all to
stand for the national anthem.
# God save our... #
# Oh say
# Can you see
# By the dawn's early light
# Oh the... #
SLURS LYRICS
# ..By the twilight's last gleaming?
# Whose broad stripes
and bright stars
# Whoa! Whoa! #
Let's play some boxing!
All right, lads.
Right, keep it clean,
obey my commands.
And my God have mercy on your
souls. Touch gloves!
Go for it! Come on, Warren!
Go for it!
WHIMPERS
Come on! Urgh!
Ow! Urgh!
Oh, my God, it's so violent!
WARREN GROANS
Ooh!
Yeah, that's it, Warren!
Run away!
Help me! HELP!
Tie him up!
Kill him, Warren! KILL HIM!
Oh, shit, listen to Usma.
Someone woke up and chose violence.
Shame it wasn't Warren.
WARREN WHIMPERING
BELL
Someone get him some water!
Well done, Warren! Well done!
That's it. Good man.
This is it, mate. This is it.
Round 4, yeah?
Lucci is going to lower his guard
and that is your cue to land the
punch. He's going to go down.
Game over.
BELL
You've got this one, Warren!
Woo!
Lucci! Stick to the plan!
Oh!
STEPHEN SCREAMS
Warren! Warren!
One...
Come on, let's go! Huh?
..two...
Drink your Shake-Eel!
4K all day, people.
Oi! If Warren don't get up,
I'm going to exclude you.
Fill your boots. Thanks to you,
I got verified on TikTok.
The people love me!
CROWD: Lucci! Lucci! Lucci!
..seven...
..eight... Get up!
And you're out.
BELL
Sit down. God! When's the interval?!
Let's go!
Oi, Blessing! Lucci's tucked me
right up.
Take that and stick it on Lucci
to win by knockout in
the 12th round, yeah?
But what about Warren, sir?
Oh, he ain't got a chance, has he?
But you always back Class K.
Yeah? You tell that to Kayleigh.
Just do it.
Go. All right, babe?
Move your bum! Oh!
WARREN MOANS
These heels are killing me!
I'm sorry, sir.
I shouldn't have told people that
you were an understudy.
Oh, don't worry.
Nobody believed you anyway.
You just looked a bit bitter.
I know you were rooting for me.
Er, I am always rooting for you.
Oi, Warren! I heard your nan
was fit.
Fraser! What? I didn't tell him,
what can I say? The kids got eyes.
Give me my gloves.
I just want to hit him, just once.
He's strong but he's got no rhythm.
You'll get your chance
but you have to dip, duck,
and slide.
I don't know how to do any of that.
Yes, you do!
I'll say it again, I teach y'all
transferable skills!
GROWLS
Gentlemen, Round 5!
Now...listen to me,
you're going to stay on beat just
like a dance class
and take my direction, OK? Let's go.
Five, six, seven, eight.
Round 5.
BELL
Six, Pussycat Dolls! Roar! Boop!
Ha! Beyonce. Roar! Cha-cha!
And...yaas! Ha!
Ha! Westside! Roll!
Again, six, seven, eight!
Spice Girls! Seven, eight!
What are you doing? Hit me!
Are you kidding?!
Yes, fight for this now!
Fight, fight, fight!
Hit me! Come on!
Again, fight, fight, fight! Woo!
What?! Gangnam Style!
Fraser.
Hello.
Keep going, you've got this,
you've got this.
Finish!
Yes, Warren!
CHEERING
A one, a two,
a three... Oh, no, actually,
can we get a medic, please,
to stop this boy bleeding
on the canvas?
You won't believe how much it cost
to hire. Oi, Miss.
I thought they loved me.
They did. Right up until the point
where Warren slut-dropped you
into punching yourself in the face.
Fickle thing, fame.
Please don't let Miss Hoburn expel
me, sir. My mum will kill me.
I promise I'll
sign your report card,
as long as you promise to stop
being a total bell-end.
Mm-hm, OK. Yeah?
Can I have your attention, please?
It's time to announce the winner.
CHEERING
And the winner
by disqualification is...
Lucci Bantz!
What? Huh? How?
Lead. From the chemistry lab roof.
Concealed in this boy's glove.
Now, I take cheating very
seriously... Oh!
Oh, shit! Warren's a bad man!
CHEERING
Did you put lead in Warren's gloves?
No. I'm not that smart. I didn't bet
on the disqualification.
Kayleigh, look, I am so sorry.
I'm an idiot.
I blew all of our wedding
money on Anthony Costa. Who?
Who's Anthony Costa?
Fraser, not now.
Red flag.
Kayleigh, I love you so much.
I tried to fix the fight to pay
for our special day and I blew it.
You deserve so much more than me.
But I want to marry you for you,
OK? I don't care where we do it.
I ain't even bought you a ring.
Well, there's a ring right here.
Are you serious?
Yes. Why not?
It's about you and me, right?
Surrounded by people who love us,
but I do still want a proper ring.
Yeah, course.
Kayleigh, if you want to change your
mind, nobody will judge you, OK?
But if I must, you may kiss
the bride.
Come on!
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
Yes, sir!
Well, it's official. From boxing
bells to wedding bells,
this brother is punching
WAY above his weight. Facts.
Did all right, didn't I?
Yeah, you did good.
Hmm?
How did you... When did you get...
Never bet against Class K.
Oi, bless him,
Lucci's tucked me right up.
Take this and put it on Lucci to
win by knockout on Round 12, yeah?
But what about Warren?
Oh, he ain't got a chance, has he?
Put this on Lucci Bantz
by disqualification in Round 5.
Oi! You want to rile him up?
Diss his nan, she's a cougar.
I just want to hit him, just once.
Give me my gloves.
Oi, miss.
Blessing, you're a genius!
Enjoy your honeymoon, sir.
Oh, we will. We're going to do
two weeks on this
beautiful little island,
just off the coast of France
it's called the...
IN FRENCH ACCENT: Isle du Wight.
Wow! I hope you and Kayleigh have a
lovely time on the Isle of Wight.
Huh?
NEWS REPORTER: And 100
wedding guests,
some as young as 12 have been
hospitalised by a mystery virus.
The groom has blamed the catering.
Slow down, buster!
You've got the wrong guy!
Pavel! Edna!
I thought we were friends!