Some say juvenile.
I say genius!
Leave me alone!
Matt, I'm getting ready
for graduation!
Matt!
Say goodbye
to your little toy.
And say hello to Matt owning
his big sister for eternity!
Never give up
Yeah, yeah
The tide is high,
but I'm holding on
I'm gonna be
your number one
I'm not the kind of girl
Who gives up
just like that
Oh, no
It's not the things you do
that tease and hurt me bad
But it's the way you do
the things you do to me
I'm not the kind of girl
Who gives up
just like that
Oh, no
The tide is high,
but I'm holding on
I'm gonna be
your number one
The tide is high,
but I'm holding on
I'm gonna be
your number one
Ooh
Number one
Every girl wants you
to be her man
But I'll wait right here
till it's my turn
I'm not the kind of girl
Who gives up
just like that
Oh, no
The tide is high,
but I'm holding on
I'm gonna be
your number one
The tide is high,
but I'm holding on
I'm gonna be
your number one
Number one
Gotta hold on
Every time
that I get the feeling
You give me something
to believe in
Every time
that I got you near me
I know the way
that I want it to be
But you know
I'm gonna take my chance now
I'm gonna make it happen
somehow
And you know
I can take the pressure
A moment's pain
for a lifetime of pleasure
Pleasure, pleasure,
pleasure...
Every girl wants you
to be her man
But I'll wait right here
till it's my turn
I'm not the kind of girl
Who gives up
just like that
Oh, no
The tide is high,
but I'm holding on
I'm gonna be
your number one
The tide is high
But I'm holding on
I'm gonna be
your number one
Whoa!
Every time
that I get the feeling
You give me something
to believe in
Every time
that I got you near me
I know the way
that I want it to be
But you know
I'm gonna take my chance now
I'm gonna make it happen
somehow
And you know
I can take the pressure
A moment's pain
for a lifetime of pleasure
The tide is high...
I shall win the Academy Award!
Yesterday, you were in diapers,
and now you're graduating
junior high.
You're growing up, and I can't
believe you're going to Rome
for two weeks
all by yourself.
Without me.
Without me there with you.
Without me with you there.
You there without me.
Mom, that's about
all the combinations
of those words you can make.
Lizzie, this is a big day
for you, sweetheart.
He's going to quote a dead guy.
As William Shakespeare wrote,
"Be not afraid of greatness:
some are born great,
some achieve greatness,
and some have greatness
thrust upon them."
Thanks, Dad, but I'm just trying
to get through graduation.
Greatness can wait
till this nightmare's over.
Hey, Gordo.
So, do I look okay?
I'm your guy best friend.
You should talk to Miranda
about this.
But she's in Mexico City.
Yes. Your blue robe
looks way cooler
than all the other girls'.
Oh...my...God.
Only you would think
you could hide that powder- blue,
puffy-sleeved,
it's-kind-of-a-peasant-dress-
but-it-might-just-be-
a-baggy- disaster
that you wore
to the spring dance.
Lizzie McGuire, you are
an outfit repeater!
But I...
Maybe I'm an outfit repeater,
but you're
an outfit rememberer,
which is just as pathetic.
Does she not have
anything better to do
than make my life miserable?
I mean...
we used to be best friends.
But that was before
she became popular.
McGuire!
Go.
Hey, Mr. Escobar.
Nice after-shave.
Oh, thank you.
Margaret Chan either has ebola
or a very bad cold.
In any event, you're up.
U-U-Up where?
At the podium.
You are going to deliver
the class president's speech.
B-But what about
the vice president?
He's not graduating.
The secretary treasurer's
next in line.
All I did was handle petty cash.
I'm sorry, but you're not
buying your way out of this.
I want you to deliver
your speech
with as much pride
and commitment
as Margaret Chan would,
even though
you're no Margaret Chan.
You're no Margaret Chan.
Run!
Ladies and gentlemen,
uh, Lizzie McGuire.
Um...
U-Uh, Margaret Chan
couldn't make it tonight,
so I'm going - I'm going to
be filling in for her.
Not that any of us
could really do that,
but, um, anyway...
Honey, I'm losing the feeling
in my knuckles.
I think that we can all agree
that junior high
is filled with
embarrassing and awkward
and sometimes just downright
humiliating moments, right?
Uh...
Oh!
Me neither.
It is so sad.
Wow.
It's like watching one
of those animals
get killed
on the Discovery Channel.
I-I think Margaret Chan
would want me to have
some water right now.
Uhh! Oh!
Play something!
Do something!
Yes! Ha ha ha!
Come on! Mom! Dad!
I've got to get out
of the country!
I know you're still upset,
but it wasn't that bad.
Oh, really, Mom?
Was your junior-high graduation
on "Good Morning America"?
What creep would send
Diane Sawyer a video
to embarrass you like that?
Oh.
- Ugh!
What is that?
That is Miss Ungermeyer.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Hey!
She's gonna be our principal
for the next four years.
If you stay on her good side,
it's a one-way ticket
to an lvy League school.
What if you're on her bad side?
Excuse me!
I need to mop up some puke.
Well, you...
You wind up as that guy?
No. You end up working
for that guy.
Can you make sure there are
no garlic or soy products
in anything Brittany
puts near her mouth?
Miss Ungermeyer,
Luke has tennis elbow.
Could somebody
carry his luggage?
My son has asthma,
and he must have his puffer.
Brittany, she's got allergies.
Attention, parents...
shut your pie holes.
I'm on a mission here
to drag your progeny
to 31 historically significant
Roman landmarks
in two weeks.
Now, when these back-talking
miscreants return to you,
they will have dipped their
toes in a lake of culture,
before assuming their destiny
folding shirts
at the outlet mall.
Many - actually, most -
of your classmates opted
for the 36-hour bus ride
to the Water-slide Wonderland.
Whoo!
But you...
you, who are not
mouth- breathing trailer trash,
you will get to experience
the delights
of la citta eterna!
Hmm-hmm.
Rome. The eternal city.
Did no one read
the info packets?
Watch and learn.
Um, Miss Ungermeyer,
I just wanted to let you know
I'm really looking forward
to this exciting
and academically enriching trip.
What's your name?
David Gordon.
- David Gordon.
- Mm-hmm.
I think, in ltalian,
that means a sneaky brownnoser
with a hidden agenda, huh?
Uh, uh.
Yeah! Come on,
check those bags!
I want to see that junk
in the trunk
and a seat looking neat.
Okay.
Mom...
Okay, it's only
two weeks, Mom.
- Honey, she's got to go.
- Two weeks.
- Bye, sweetie.
- Bye.
- Safe trip, huh?
- Okay.
Sweetheart...
- Okay?
- Mm-hmm.
Flight 72 to Rome.
Final boarding,
Hey! We're going to the land
where they invented spaghetti!
Ah heh.
Yeah, and the best part is
Kate and all the little
teeth- whitening friends
who'd be ragging on me
for messing up graduation
went to Water-slide Wonderland.
How many Lizzies does it take
to screw in a light bulb?
I don't know, but it only takes
one to screw up a graduation.
Hey. Zip it.
Whoa!
Down each avenue or via,
street or strata
You can see 'em disappearing
two by two
On an evening in Roma
Do they take 'em
for espresso?
Yeah, I guess so
On each lover's arm,
a girl I wish I knew
On an evening in Roma
So please meet me
in the plaza near your casa
I am only one,
and that is one too few
On an evening in Roma
Don't know what
the country's coming to
But in Rome,
do as the Romans do
Will you?
- On an evening in Roma
Here we are.
Step right up.
Number one...
Number two...
Welcome to the Hotel Cambini.
Lest you think there are many
of you and less of me
and it will therefore be easy
to pull anything over on me,
think again.
In addition to being
smarter, faster,
and better-looking
than most of you,
I've also enlisted
a little help.
The assistant manager
of the hotel, Giorgio Averni,
was a commander
in the ltalian Navy
and is therefore
as up on his game as I am mine.
Giorgio, would you like
to brief my students
on the security procedures
of the hotel?
We serve at 5:00.
The cookies.
Yeah.
You heard the man.
Room assignments.
David Gordon...
you will be rooming
with Ethan Craft.
You'll be in Room 103.
Are those English
or ltalian numbers?
You got a problem with that?
Um, no, ma'am.
Any room is just -
just fine for me.
Being a spineless jellyfish
is almost as unattractive
as being a little brownnoser.
McGuire!
Seeing as how Margaret Chan
was unable to make the trip,
you will be rooming with...
Okay, I am not,
under any circumstances,
sharing a room with -
I'll be taking the bed
by the window.
You don't mind, do you?
Uh, ye-e-e-e-s!
No.
I sleep much better
with the Swiss eiderdown.
Lizzie, seeing as we're roomies
and we're gonna be spending
time together,
I wanted to let you know
I understand
you want to put all that
embarrassing stuff behind you
and just move on
and have a fresh start.
You do?
Yes. I understand
your dream.
It's a big dream.
It's a huge dream,
and you can't do it alone.
In fact, I don't think
you can do it at all.
Let it go.
Lizzie, come on.
Whoa!
Gordo, what?
Don't worry.
Where are we going?
Look.
Wow!
Pretty cool, huh?
You know what, Gordo?
I'm not gonna let
Kate Sanders get to me.
Promise me something.
Anything.
Promise that when we're here,
we'll find adventures.
All right? This is
our chance to start over.
I mean, do anything
that we want to do.
Yeah. I-I know.
You're right.
Hmm. You and me.
Adventures. Deal.
Deal.
The Trevi Fountain was designed
by Gian Lorenza Bernini
and Peitro da Cortona
in the 17th century.
And it took about 100 years
to finish this bad boy.
Throughout history, people have
come from all over the world
to make a wish and toss their
coin in the Trevi Fountain.
Those people are suckers.
You got to make your own luck
in this world.
All right, moving on, people.
Let's go.
Scusi,
Grazie.
Scusi, Grazie,
You know what?
Forget what she says.
Make a wish.
I'm in Rome
with my best friend.
I'm good.
You make one.
Okay.
Hmm.
lsabella?
Huh?
Okay, I was wishing for smooth
sailing through high school,
but this will work.
Uh, I'm sorry.
It's just you look an awful lot
like a friend of mine.
Paolo, you have to get
to your photo shoot.
We got to go.
What you little halflings
are feeling right about now
is your energy flagging.
We got four more stops today.
I want you to
at least be able to shuffle
from monument to monument.
We got one word for that,
and it's gelato.
Keep in mind
that ltalian ice cream has
about twice the sugar
of American ice cream.
Means you're gonna want about
two scoops, huh?
I know I do.
All right.
I don't mean to bother you.
I'm Paolo.
Paolo Valisari.
Oh, um, I'm Lizzie McGuire,
and this is my friend Gordo.
This is my friend Sergei.
Sergei, doesn't she look
exactly like lsabella?
- lsabella!
- Paolo!
Um...
Paolo!
lsabella! Isabella!
Paolo! Paolo!
Ciao, Paolo!
Uh, hmm...
Wow! That really
does look like me.
Except for the hair,
you could be her twin.
Isabella is my singing partner,
and you're like her sister.
Like two pods in a pea.
Lizzie, can I see you again?
Maybe tomorrow?
Please?
What's the word for "yes"
in ltalian?
- Si,
Uh...
No, I'm -
It's okay.
I can cover for you.
Head check!
I'm sorry. I'm here
with my school, so I can't.
Forgive me
if I embarrassed you.
Some people,
when they come to Rome,
they want to find adventure.
Oh, it's okay.
I got some cool cheese.
Did you just say
"cool cheese"?
Wah!
Paolo...
We must go.
Uh, Lizzie,
if you change your mind,
I will meet you tomorrow morning
at the Trevi Fountain at 9:00.
Hey, Gordon, McGuire,
did you not hear me say
"head check"?
15, 16.
Who are you?
Paolo Valisari.
Put your money
in your front pockets.
She makes me very scared.
Join the club.
Lizzie...
Ci vediamo,
What does that mean?
We will see each other.
Hey.
This Paolo and lsabella CD
isn't so bad.
I mean, if you're into
the Alanis Morissette-y,
alternative, dark,
like, brooding,
I-never-go-out-
and-my-life's-a-black-hole-
of-depression kind of thing,
you'd think they stink.
For driving-around-in-the-car-
with- the-top- down,
Ioving-life kind of thing,
they're good.
Here. Listen.
You don't have to sail
the ocean
Yeah, not bad.
You use scented soap, huh?
What?
Um, it -
N-Never - never mind.
So, Paolo wants me to meet him
at the Trevi Fountain tomorrow.
So go.
That would mean I would have to
sneak away from the group.
So?
I'm incapable of sneaking.
Weren't you the one that said
we were gonna have adventures
on this trip?
Yeah. We. We were
going to have adventures.
And we will.
It just so happens that
you have dibs on the first one.
Okay.
Just as long
as we don't do anything
that would get us tossed
on a plane home.
Uh. Unh.
Lizzie, are -
are you feeling okay?
Is this girl sick,
or isn't she?
She doesn't have a fever,
and yet she's in bed.
Ask yourself why
a beautiful young girl
on her first visit
to Rome,
probably seeking adventure,
wants to lie in bed
all day.
She's ill.
I heard she fell down
at graduation,
made a complete fool
out of herself.
I saw that on CNN.
CNN?
Often, the nervous system
collapses
after that type of humiliation.
Hmm.
Do you have
any recommendations?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
This young woman
should stay in bed.
Uh, she - she should
also eat two apricots.
Oh, for digestion or...
No, they're in season.
Very delicious.
Feel better, Signorina McGuire.
You rest up, McGuire.
Don't want you to miss
all the adventures of Rome.
Uh, doctor, I have a boil...
Sorry.
Uno, due, tre,
- Tre,
Bene,
I-I just - I had them all wish
for you to come.
Hmm...
I don't have much time.
You know my chaperon -
Wait, wait, wait.
I have to show you something.
Sometimes the world
Is a valley
of heartaches and tears
- Come on.
And in the hustle and bustle,
no sunshine appears
But you and I have a love
always there to remind us...
Wow!
You should see Rome
the way Romans do.
So you knew
that I would come.
I hoped you would.
Are you sure you know
how to drive this thing?
This is Rome.
Nobody knows how to drive.
Volare
Oh, oh
Cantare
Oh, oh, oh, oh
Let's fly
way up to the clouds
Away from
the maddening crowds
We can sing in the glow
of a star that I know of
Where lovers enjoy
peace of mind
Let us leave the confusion
and all disillusion behind
Just like birds
of a feather
And the rainbow together
we'll find
Volare
Oh, oh
Cantare
Oh, oh, oh, oh
Whoo!
Volare
Oh, oh
Cantare
Oh, oh, oh, oh
No wonder
my happy heart sings
Your love has given me
wings
No wonder
my happy heart sings
Your love has given me
wings
Wow!
I don't know what catastrophe
is going to happen in Rome,
but with Lizzie there,
something will.
What are you going to do
with that information?
Give it away, like you did
with the graduation video?
Hey! She was really
freaked out by that.
And you have what
to show for it?
The pride of a job well done?
Try buying a PS2 with
the pride of a job well done.
Oh!
Matt, Matt, Matt.
We've been over this
before. Cash up front.
Melina,
are you staying for dinner?
- I'd love to, Mrs. McGuire.
- Great.
We'll need extra energy to work
on our summer reading list.
In that case,
I'll make brownies.
Oh.
I've said it before.
You're weak. Weak!
Don't do anything
without consulting me first.
You rock.
Hey, Paolo,
can I ask you something?
Si, carina,
Um, I know that our lives
are a little different.
Actually, like, several
universes different.
But doesn't Sergei get tired
of following us around?
Actually, Sergei's my bodyguard.
So, you see,
between me and Sergei,
you'll always be safe.
Whoa!
How famous do you have to be
before you need a bodyguard?
Paolo, go! Go!
I-It's Miss Ungermeyer!
It's our bus!
- Go!
- I cannot.
Miss Ungermeyer, didn't we just
pass the Castel Sant'Angelo?
Yep. What about it?
I just noticed
it's not on our itinerary.
That is correct.
Well, s-shouldn't it be?
I-I mean,
it was a papal residence
and it does contain frescoes
from artists influenced
by the school of Raphael.
What are you up to, Gordon?
N-N-Nothing.
I-I just figure that,
while in Rome,
we should be exposed
to as much Renaissance,
Raphaelite work
typified by chiaroscuro
and Hellenic mythical imagery
as humanly possible.
Whew.
Ah, Gordon,
you are on the list,
and the list is not a place
you want to be.
What is this?
Only in Rome, huh?
You know how to move that, or
you want me to do it for you?
What are you looking at?
Want a piece of that,
a piece of the Ungermeyer?
Over there by that statue.
You see it?
Yeah.
That's where
the artist Caravaggio
had his opponent
burned at the stake.
Or was it the pope
who had Caravaggio burned
at the stake?
Either way,
this neighborhood was tough.
Paolo...
Si, carina?
Do you still love her?
Who? Isabella?
Si,
Of course I still love her.
But like a sister.
So, why did you break up?
It's, um, it's complicated.
- What?
Yes, we've been voted "best
pop duo of the year" again.
But I want to do
more serious music.
And when I told this
to lsabella,
she said flat-out "no."
I was forced to tell her,
"This is it.
This will be
our last CD together."
Did she totally freak out?
She totally freak out.
I feel awful about that,
but what about me?
I need to grow as an artist.
Yeah.
So, the other day
when I saw you,
I just - I don't know,
I had this crazy -
I just - I don't know.
W-What?
I had this crazy idea
that maybe you could help me.
Come on. How crazy could it be?
Just tell me.
No, I can't.
It's too - It's too...
- Please.
- Okay.
Isabella and I are supposed to
present an award together
at the International
Music Video Awards.
Cool!
I-I mean, cool for
regular people like me,
but for you,
I guess it's like work.
No, no, no.
It's cool for me, too.
You get all kinds
of free stuff.
But now because lsabella's
so mad at me,
she's refusing to appear.
The record company's threatening
to sue if she doesn't show up.
What about you?
For me is no problem.
I write the music.
I don't know
where it comes from.
It just comes from me.
La la la la
See?
So I can go solo.
But lsabella...
She needs the help to sing.
You mean lsabella lip-synchs?
Please, please!
Promise me you
will speak of this to no one.
Imagine what would happen
to lsabella's career.
Oh, that's so sweet.
You still care about her.
You're definitely
broken up, right?
Si,
So, when I saw you yesterday
and how people thought
you were lsabella,
I got my crazy idea
that maybe you could pretend
to be lsabella
and present the award
with me onstage.
Present an award?
O-Onstage?
In front of an audience?
I-I-I'm really not good
in front of crowds.
I could never do that.
Of course you can do it.
You are magnifico.
I don't know ltalian,
but I know what that means.
I don't know, Paolo.
I...
Don't worry, carina,
I could never ask you to do
this crazy thing.
No. You know what?
You don't have to ask.
If this is gonna help
you and lsabella, then...
...I'll do it.
Grazie!
Prego!
Head check!
Gordo. Gordo.
You, Lizzie McGuire,
are actually presenting an award
at the lMVAs with Paolo?
No. Me lsabella with Paolo.
- What?
- It's a long story.
I'm doing it because
lsabella won't.
You're gonna get up onstage
in front of all these people?
That's the great thing.
It's not gonna be me.
It's Paolo's idea
to help lsabella
because he still loves her.
But not romantically.
Like a sister.
He is so amazing.
And he's 17!
For being so famous
and used to getting everything
that you want,
he's just -
he's just so kind.
For real?
That's a lot
to say about someone
just knowing them a day.
I-I know that.
But I feel like
I've known him my whole life.
Anyway, um...
I just wanted to come by
and thank you.
I had the most magical day
of my life.
It wouldn't have happened
if it weren't for you.
It was that good, huh?
You're such a good friend.
The sting.
What sting?
You want a little mano a mano?
See, this is
one of the reasons
me and you aren't friends.
I never have any idea
what you're talking about.
Some dudes get the approach.
Others, the sting.
That ltalian dude.
He's big-time approach.
I actually feel my brain
turning into goo.
Embrace the sting.
That's what you're vibin'
from Lizzie.
Wait a minute.
Now, you actually think
that I'm jealous of Paolo?
Word.
Oh, no.
No, see, that would mean
that I like Lizzie
as more than a friend.
You and I
have trouble communicating?
You're wrong, man.
Whoa!
This girl looks freakishly
like my sister!
- Ow.
- Zoom! Zoom!
Another freakish coincidence.
I mean, she has the same
necklace as my sister's.
Huh.
Why do we even pretend
you're in charge?
- Let's see what this says.
Ow.
"lsabella goes blond.
Italian pop duo
Paolo and lsabella
wowed the crowd outside a shop
near the Trevi Fountain,
showing off lsabella's
new blond hair."
They must think that Lizzie
is this famous singer!
And if I show this to my mom,
Lizzie will be so busted!
If you show this to your mom,
it's worth nothing.
But if you show this
to the ltalian tabloids,
we will be rolling in cash,
my friend.
Interesting!
"We"?
Not up to toughing it out
on the streets with us?
I could try, Miss Ungermeyer.
No, I just hate seeing you
being denied
the cultural experience
of being in a foreign country.
You missed seven points
of historical significance
yesterday.
I know. It's really killing me
too, Miss Ungermeyer.
Which is why I thought
I'd bring you something
to help ease the pain, hmm?
Mmh, well, that's really
thoughtful of you.
Seeing as how
your teeny- tiny little body
doesn't have the strength,
we're gonna have to let
your mind do the wandering.
Ah!
"The Rise and Decline
of the Roman Empire," hmm?
I'd like one report on the rise
and one on the decline.
Ouch!
If I didn't have a headache
a minute ago, I do now.
You don't have a problem
with that, do you?
Um, no.
- What else do I have to do?
Why not
Take a crazy chance?
Do a crazy dance?
If you lose the moment
You might lose a lot
So why not?
Why not?
Why not
take a crazy chance?
Wow.
I am so grateful for your help.
You're doing a very kind thing
for lsabella.
Uh, Paolo, where are we?
Via Condotti.
One of the most expensive
shopping districts
in the world.
We must find you
the perfect outfit.
Ah!
Oh, hey, lsabella, Paolo!
Ciao!
Your hair is so blond
and, uh, innocent.
- Who did it?
- Um...
The island we were on
was really, really sunny,
so it was j-just the sun.
We must get sun, too, no?
Ciao, bella!
Ciao, Ciao, Ciao.
They are so tall!
- They all want to be you.
- They want to be lsabella.
Sit and I'll get Franca.
I will just be a moment.
Whoa! Take your time.
I'll just be sitting here
in heaven.
Hard as it is to imagine,
as we look at the ruins
of the Forum,
that this was once
the center of commerce,
religion, and politics
in ancient Rome.
All right, now,
the Forum came into being
in the sixth century B.C.,
and with it,
a new urban culture was born.
Uh, um, di-
Yeah, Craft?
Is it time for the spaghetti?
It's 9:00 in the morning.
So? You never had leftover
spaghetti for breakfast?
I don't eat carbs.
You never had
a spaghetti sandwich, either?
This cultural experience
is, like, so wasted on you.
Excuse me, where did you
buy that Prada bag?
Craft! Sanders! Separate.
We did, Miss Ungermeyer.
And thank God.
Why don't you people, uh,
do something at your, uh,
skill level here?
Take a 10-minute shopping break
while I choke down an espresso.
This dude definitely spent
too much time on his biceps
and not enough on his abs.
Totally old school.
Wha-
Nice spy, bro.
Yeah, watch and learn.
The slow curve.
Works every time.
I've got to talk to them.
That's not how the slow curve
works. They come to us.
Um, eh, ciao.
- Ciao.
Do you guys speak English?
Yes.
It is your friend we like.
Word.
Word?
Is that his name?
Yeah, sure.
Do you know who that is
on the cover?
- Oh, lsabella. Certo,
- Certo,
Do you think you guys could
translate it for me?
Um, only if
you introduce us to Word.
Can I keep the magazine, then?
Deal!
All right.
Let's go.
Ciao, Word.
Word?
Mmh?
English?
She's speaking English.
Our single is in English
and lsabella needs to practice.
What have you done?
Uh, uh, uh...
You look...
You look like a schoolgirl.
Maximus, what is wrong?
You love lsabella.
Nice Maximus.
Very odd.
There is something...
something very different
about you.
Um...
Rest.
The rest on the island
did lsabella good.
She is transformed.
Yeah.
Well, I cannot
put clothes on this.
You - fix the hair.
Fix the eyebrows.
Fix the lips.
- Oh!
- And fix the ears!
Fix the ears?
Jewelry.
That's a language
every girl understands.
You better work
Covergirl
Work it, girl
Give it a twirl
Do your thing
On the runway
Work
You better work it, girl
Wet your lips
And smile to the camera
Work
- Ah! Aah!
- Work
- Turn to the right
- Oh!
Sashay
Chante
Well, it don't matter
what you wear
They're checkin' out
your savoir faire
Ooh, ooh, ooh, yeah
And when you walked
into the room
You had everybody's eyes
on you
Supermodel
Work
Work it, girl
Do your thing
On the runway
Work,
you've got to work it, girl
Of the world
Wet your lips
And smile to the camera
Work
- Aah!
- Work
Sashay
Chante
Work
Sashay
Chante
You better work
Work
Give it up
On the ru-u-u-nway
Work
Ohhhh
Whoo
Okay. Diva - good.
Tacky - bad.
We'll have to fix that.
Okay, none of these are me.
- Why are you laughing at me?
You're not supposed to be you.
If I have to go onstage
as lsabella,
then I-I'm gonna have to
be confident,
and that's the thing
I'm worst at.
- We are all the same that way.
- Not you.
Yes, me, and lsabella, too.
It's how she works
through her fears
that makes her strong.
Isabella doesn't let
Franca di Montecatini
tell her what to wear.
Isabella tells Franca.
Okay, so you're telling me
to tell Franca
di Monteca-teca- tecatini
how I should dress?
Si,
Test your strength.
Vai! Vai, vai,
You don't like my clothes?
No. No.
I-I love your clothes.
But I don't want you
to dress me.
What?!
See, I'm not your Barbie doll.
I am lsabella Parigi,
and I dress myself.
So, choices.
I-I need choices.
Whoa.
I really like these two.
You pick.
Both.
Wow.
This is the exact color
I wore to my spring formal.
- Danny Kessler thought...
Look at all of you.
You'd think that I'm American.
I am,
how you say, um...
awesome?
The island.
You should go more often.
Mmh.
Ooh, ooh, ooh
Goodbye, Lizzie McGuire.
Hello, fabulous.
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Come on
You make me feel
like a star
Oh, baby
You say, "Stay, baby, stay
Just the way you are"
And tell me, "Girl, you're
fine and you will shine
Forever in my heart"
That's why you,
yeah, you
You make me feel
like a star
Ooh, ooh, ooh
- There you go.
- Grazie.
Grazie.
Ooh, ooh, ooh
I'm ready for my close-up.
- Whoo!
I cannot believe
that not one Roman guy
has asked me out yet.
Look.
Paolo...
We gotta go!
Where's the zoom
on this thing?
Uh, uh...
Hello? Excuse me.
Oh!
I'm sorry.
I was just...
Hup! Head check!
Let's go! On the bus,
then back to the hotel!
Come on! Come on! Go!
Andiamo! Andiamo!
- Hold on!
Okay! Hello.
Hotel Cambini.
This is Giorgio.
- Go!
- Huh? What?
Wait.
Excuse me,
can you fix this?
It will not close.
Why is it open
when there is no rain?
This umbrella is stubborn.
It's bad luck to have
an open umbrella inside.
- In Hotel Cambini, no bad luck.
- Hey, thanks.
GlORGlO:
Ah!
One at a time.
No running.
Ha ha ha!
Ha! Ha ha!
Age before beauty, huh?
You look strangely large
and familiar.
Which floor?
Oh. Thank you. First.
Okay.
Little hint for you -
you want to push the button,
elevator moves.
Elevator is not safe.
You an employee here?
- No.
Who are you to tell me
whether the elevator's safe?
I am Sergei.
Sergei.
You're gonna have to
stand down immediately.
Just because you are one hunk
of Slavic muscle
does not mean you're not
gonna make it on my list!
Elevator is safe now.
Hey! Your umbrella!
Feeling any better?
Mom?
Still a little warm.
Miss Sanders,
would you be so kind
as to look after her for me?
As in do stuff for her?
Why should I be punished?
I'm not the one who's sick.
Next year, I'm joining
the mouth breathers
at Water-slide Wonderland.
You are so busted.
You've been out
of this hotel room.
What?
How do you know?
Please.
Your eyebrows finally match,
your hair has highlights,
fresh manicure.
I smelled acetone the second
I walked in the lobby.
Okay, but you didn't rat me out
to Miss Ungermeyer.
Yet.
Not until I figure out
what's in it for me.
Now spill, Dorkerella.
You'll never make me talk!
I-I know that this
sounds insane,
but I think Paolo
really does like me.
How could this happen?
How did you get my trip?
How is Lizzie McGuire
living this fantasy
and I can't even get
an ltalian boy
to buy me a plate of spaghetti?
Um, Kate,
you don't eat spaghetti.
I'd eat carbs if an ltalian boy
bought them for me.
So, I suppose you want me
to keep quiet about this?
Yeah.
I'd appreciate that.
Well, I'll keep it quiet
if you keep it quiet
about me keeping it quiet.
And when we get back home,
I'm the cool one again,
and you turn
back into a pumpkin.
Oh, my God. It's her.
What are you doing?
Uh, it's a long story.
What do you want?
We're closed.
I-I just wanted
to talk to Lizzie.
So talk.
I was kind of thinking
maybe, you know,
outside in the courtyard.
If this is about
that parallel-universe,
Italian-rock-star,
Lizzie's- suddenly-a- diva thing,
I know all about it.
She figured it out.
Evil and smart.
Embrace it. Fear it.
You might want
to take a look at this.
I'm on the front cover
of a tabloid!
I wish to thank everyone
who's always believed in me
for this great honor.
Do you know what that says?
Paolo and lsabella
are supposed to be singing
at the music awards.
Well, it's got to be a mistake.
I had some ltalian girls
translate it.
Paolo didn't tell you?
Mmh, no.
Don't you think it's weird
he tried to hide this?
Can you believe it?
Maybe it's a last-minute thing.
Aren't these things planned
months in advance?
When did you become an expert
on ltalian award-show thingies?
It's called common sense,
which I have a lot of
to make up for my lack
of the slow curve.
Slow curve?
Forget it.
If you want to believe
some ltalian kid
you think you know
after two days
because he's
an international superstar,
is really rich and has
nice hair, be my guest.
Gordo.
Oh, my God! He's early!
Lizzie.
Oh, my God,
I gotta get dressed.
I'll cover for you in case
Miss Ungermeyer does one of her
middle-of-the-night,
head-check things.
Thanks. I owe you.
Duh!
Mom, Dad, I found something
on the Internet
I think you both should see.
What is it?
Since Lizzie's in Europe,
I thought I'd do
a little E- search on ltaly.
That's nice, son.
But what I found out,
it's not so E-assuring.
In fact, it may shock you.
What are we looking at?
Maybe nothing, and, uh,
maybe something.
You see, when polled,
74% of ltalian teenage boys
said they would most like
to date American girls.
Where'd you get these numbers?
They're available for anyone
who has a computer.
You don't have to worry
about your sister.
She's well-chaperoned.
Miss Ungermeyer's there.
Yeah, what is she,
5'1", 5'2" max?
Oh, please.
Matt, as interesting
as this is,
where are you taking it?
All right, you caught me.
I always do.
I don't know why I even try.
I'll deny
I ever said this, but...
...I miss my sister.
There. I said it.
Now you know.
I know I rag on her
all the time,
but now that she's gone,
I-I -
Oh, honey, we miss her, too.
So, so much.
I feel so alone!
Oh! Listen to me.
You don't have to
make fake pie charts.
You just come to us
with the truth, okay?
I know that now, Mom.
It's just so hard.
I miss her so much!
Oh!
I can't believe
I let you talk me into
Ietting her go
on that trip!
I'll go get the passports.
Oh, honey.
- Shh.
Hmm, hmm, hmm.
Ah, hmm, ah.
Hmm.
Uh...
Hmm, hmm, hmm, hmm, hmmmm.
Hmm?
Hmm.
Hmm!
- Paolo.
- Si,
What is this?
Uh, a car.
Look, are we supposed to sing?
Scusa?
Don't speak to me in ltalian.
It's too adorable.
Are Paolo and lsabella
supposed to sing at the awards?
Si,
Si?! Well,
why didn't you tell me?
I wanted to, but you told me
not to telephone the hotel.
Get in. I'll explain
everything on the way.
I want to show you the
Tivoli Gardens before sunset.
Come on.
We have to get you back
by 10:00.
Okay.
So, where is Sergei?
You're not the only one
who sneaks off at night.
lsabella and I
were going to sing,
but after lsabella
would not speak to me,
I told the producers
we refuse to perform.
I said lsabella
had throat problems.
So, what happened?
I mean, what changed?
Isabella did.
The real lsabella
or me lsabella?
You. A reporter
heard her speaking,
and he reported
lsabella's voice was fine.
He said her English
was very good.
The record company called,
and they're going to sue
if we don't sing.
What?
So, they're
gonna make you sing?
I-I mean, us sing?
Don't worry, carina,
I'll make this work.
Look.
Ah!
Look, Paolo, I-I don't think
this is going to work.
I cannot sing
in front of an audience.
I won't even let my mom
hear me sing in the shower.
I will teach you
all you need to know.
Okay.
So, what is lsabella gonna do
when she sees me being her?
She won't. She's off on some
island trying to get over this.
Come on.
Here's my vow to you.
I, Paolo Valisari,
will never let you,
Lizzie McGuire, be embarrassed.
If I fail,
I have to spend seven days
with that scary
head-check woman.
Her name's Miss Ungermeyer.
Carina, hasn't everything
I've promised you come to be?
Everyone believes
you are lsabella.
You're having
the time of your life.
You even told
Franca di Montecatini
to buzz off!
Don't you trust that we can
do the singing together?
I guess.
Well, you shouldn't.
Hmmm-mmmm
Ohhh
Ye-e-e-ah
You've been searching the
world to find true love
Looking in all
the wrong places
When all of the time,
you've been blind to love
It's plain as the nose
on your face is
It's here
It's now
Open your eyes and see it
Right here
Right now
Ohh
This is so beautiful.
Yes, you are.
Ohhhh
Love has been
right by your side
Oh, so close,
that you couldn't see
If love could speak,
it would shout to the sky
"I've always been here,
I always will be"
Wow!
I'm here
I'm now
Open your eyes and see
Right here
Right now
Open your eyes to love
Open your heart
To love
Hey.
What do you got there,
little man?
- Uh, nothing.
- What's this?
Uh, that's not Lizzie!
No!
- Yes, it is.
- No, it isn't.
I know my daughter.
I gave her that necklace.
All right, tell me
what you know that I don't.
It's only
a 14-hour flight, Dad.
Swallow those biscotti.
We got a big day.
The Pantheon, the Colosseum.
Oh.
Uh, halt!
Got to get these apricots
to McGuire.
She looked sick as a dog
this morning.
Mr. Gordon,
you having a problem?
N-No, I just...
I'm starting to agree
with Ethan.
- We need to eat more spaghetti.
- You da man!
Sorry.
Is there a reason you
don't want me to go upstairs?
No, I-I just really think
we should get going.
Uh, so much Roma,
so little time-a.
Well, when I get upstairs -
and I will get upstairs -
I expect to find Miss McGuire
in her bed.
She may be in the bathroom
or - or something.
I'm beginning
to get the feeling
she was never sick
to begin with.
No, no, no!
She - She was!
I bet this whole thing
was just a clever ruse
to sneak out of this hotel,
wasn't it?
Yeah, it - it was.
It was?
Well, Lizzie and I were
talking about adventures,
and I don't know.
Ah, spit it out, Gordon.
Lizzie's upstairs.
It - It's me.
I'm the one
who's been sneaking out.
- You?
- But - But -
Feels good
to get it off my chest.
You realize
what this means?
I shouldn't look to you
for a college recommendation?
You should look
for your suitcase, Gordon.
You're goin' home.
Oh, I pegged you
right from the start.
David Gordon.
Sneaky little brownnoser
with a hidden agenda.
Well, you're busted.
Love lifts us up
where we belong.
Wow.
This place is so cool.
Si,
Are you sure it's okay
we're here?
Si,
And here is where, exactly?
It's the rehearsal hall.
But the Colosseum
will look more like this.
Sergei!
If you want to convince
the world you're lsabella,
you must take the stage.
You must dance...
...and sing.
Have you ever seen
such a beautiful night?
Just move your mouth
with the words.
Oh. So you want me
to lip-synch.
- Si,
Just like lsabella.
You know the song, right?
Uh, well, yeah.
I mean, I have your CD, but...
So try it.
I'm not gonna try it.
- Okay.
Have you ever seen
such a beautiful night?
I could almost kiss the stars
for shining so bright
Was it awful?
- Uh, yes.
But it helps to sing.
Really - really sing?
It looks more real
when you're lip-synching.
- You weren't singing.
- But I won't be lip-synching.
No one's going to hear you.
The microphone will be off.
You must try.
Please?
Okay.
Have you ever seen
such a beautiful night?
I could almost kiss the stars
for shining so bright
When I see you smiling
I go, "Oh, oh, oh"
I would never want
to miss this
'Cause in my heart
I know what this is
This is what dreams
are made of
This is what
Dreams are made of
I've got
Somewhere I belong
Somebody to love
This is what
Dreams
Are made of
Brava.
And now we dance!
Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
I'm glad you're up.
I had the most amazing night.
I'm gonna grab Gordo
so I can tell you together.
You won't find him.
What?
Why? Where'd he go?
Probably getting on a plane
right now.
Why?
He totally covered for you
and got himself
kicked off the trip.
I-I don't believe it.
W-Why would he do that?
You're seriously asking
that question?
Call the airline and see
if Gordo's plane has left!
- Do you know what flight?
- Si, si,
I will call.
I cannot believe Gordo
would do this for me.
Maybe he's not
on the plane yet.
Maybe I could go
to the airport and...
And what?
I don't know.
I am now on hold.
This is the final call
for Lufthansa Flight 6240,
departing for Los Angeles.
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Mm-hmm.
Thank you very nice.
The plane is gone.
Who is this girl?
I have been on the island,
trying to forget
about this whole situation.
Can somebody tell me
what is going on?
I can. That's my friend
Lizzie McGuire.
Let him go.
I demand you tell me
everything you know
about Lizzie McGuire.
I demand you tell me everything
about Paolo Valisari.
I left him and all thoughts
about him on the island.
You may have left him
on the island,
but Lizzie is out there
pretending to be you
so you don't get sued.
We need to talk in private.
Gordo's life is ruined
because of me.
Selfish me!
What are you gonna do now?
It's over.
I'm going to turn myself in
to Miss Ungermeyer.
Lizzie, you'll get sent home,
and you won't be able
to help Paolo.
I'm never going to be able
to get through this
the way I feel now.
Okay. Fine. Quit.
But then everything Gordo did
will be for nothing.
Now, you know things are bad
when Kate starts making sense.
I know one thing's for sure.
What?
I'm not gonna have to
act sick today.
Mr. Craft, you are in
the most historic
and beautiful city
in the world.
Has it had no effect on you?
Well, actually, it has.
The cobblestones
are shredding my wheels.
Switched to a pair
of birdhouse pterodactyls.
Have you even made a dent
in your reading list?
I finished it.
You read 11 books?
I mean I read the list.
Shh.
McGuire.
Lizzie McGuire.
Si, si, we are in
the travel guides.
No. No.
No.
We're the parents of Lizzie.
Ah! Si!
I'll call a cab.
It's very far.
Anybody else want to step up
to the plate?
Who's asking for McGuire?
I had left you
four messages already,
but she's been under
my watchful eye all the while.
Where'd Sanders go?
Lizzie? Sweetheart?
Honey?
Cool!
Where is Lizzie?
Do you have
any embarrassing photos
or videos of her
while she's been here?
Ow.
Uh...
Tell us where Lizzie is,
or this deck's gonna catch air.
It's possible she's at the
International Music Video Awards
doubling for pop star lsabella,
who's totally her twin.
Why does everyone
always look at me like that?
When you wish upon a star
Your dreams will take you
very far
Once you see your light
so clear
In the sky so very dear
You're a shining star
No matter who you are
Shining bright to see
What you can truly be
Prince William?
Tell him he'll have to hold.
Ooh!
- Oh.
Shine its watchful light
on you
Hey, Paolo!
Words of wisdom,
yes, I can
You're a shining star
No matter who you are
Shining bright to see
What you can truly be
Si,
What?
He said for you to enter
from here, stage right,
and I must enter
from stage left.
What about my dress?
I have to get dressed.
It's in your dressing room.
Lizzie, you have time.
Calm down.
You can do it.
Of course I can do it.
This is moi
we're talking about.
I don't think I can do it.
Lizzie, you must.
We've rehearsed this.
You know the steps, the words.
You will be great.
I know.
How do you know?
Because.
Because you shine
like the light from the sun.
Paolo. Paolo.
31 minutes till showtime.
Lizzie.
Gordo!
What are you doing here?!
Lizzie, that's
not important right now.
You need to listen to me.
I feel so bad. I cannot believe
you would do that for me.
- Why aren't you gone?
- Long story.
I want to hear it, but
I've got to get my dress on.
Listen to me.
Paolo is setting you up.
What are you talking about?
Actually, he is setting me up.
Freaky, huh?
Way freaky.
Way, way freaky.
That whole story
about Paolo doing his own music
and going solo.
That's lsabella.
She's the one that sings live.
Paolo is the one
that lip-synchs, not me.
Isabella wants to quit the act.
Paolo is just a liar.
This has all been some scheme
to set you up
and embarrass you onstage
so it looks
like lsabella can't sing.
Si, si, It's true.
Paolo wants to destroy
lsabella's career.
But Paolo would never
do that to me.
I don't believe you.
Isabella...
Lizzie, who are you
going to believe,
this boy you are knowing
your whole life
or this boy you are
just meeting who says,
"You shine with the light
from the sun"?
Okay. Well, then, you're here
now, so go and sing.
But I am not blond.
Paolo will know that it's me,
and he'll make an excuse
to leave.
But if we want to
get back at him
in front of the whole world
on live TV,
we must make him sing.
And really sing, not lip-synch.
How? What am I
supposed to do?
- I can't sing live!
Change! Change!
Change your clothes
and go up there and do
what you rehearsed.
Everything will be fine,
I-I promise.
- I have a plan.
- What plan?
28 minutes till showtime.
So, what's the plan?
I don't know.
No, see, it doesn't matter
about the tickets,
because my daughter
is back there
impersonating
a famous pop star,
so I got to get in!
That's what everyone says.
Enough of this!
- Uhh!
Let's go!
Did Paolo bring
the voice track for me?
No. No, he did not.
There is no track.
Paolo says you're gonna sing
live, like you always do.
Paolo and lsabella!
Sandro, turn down
lsabella's mike.
- What's that?
- Turn down the mike!
Have you ever seen
such a beautiful night?
I could almost kiss the stars
for shining so bright
When I see you smiling,
I go
"Oh, oh, oh"
I would never want
to miss this
'Cause in my heart
I know what this is
This is what dreams
are made of
Sing to me, Paolo.
This is
what dreams are made of
Okay.
Say buonasera to my new American
friend, Lizzie McGuire!
Paolo tried to use her
to fool all of you
into thinking I could not sing.
Lizzie McGuire is nice girl.
You try to hurt her.
Let me go, Sergei.
You work for me.
Not anymore, Paolo.
I quit.
Paolo!
Paolo cannot sing music.
Now he must face music.
- Was it all a lie?
- No, it's just...
- Do you want to hear us sing?
Have you ever seen
such a beautiful night?
I could almost kiss the stars
for shining so bright
When I see you smiling,
I go
"Oh, oh, oh"
I would never want
to miss this
'Cause in my heart
I know what this is
Hey, now
This is what dreams
are made of
Hey, now
This is what dreams
are made of
I've got
somewhere I belong
somebody to love
This is what dre-e-e-ams
Are made of
Wait! Isabella!
Go! Si!
Lizzie!
Ru-u-u-u-n!
Hey, hey, hey!
Have you ever wondered
what life is about?
You could search the world
and never figure it out
You don't have to sail
the oceans
No, no, no
Happiness is no mystery
It's here and now
It's you and me, yeah
Hey, now, hey, now
This is what dreams
are made of
Hey, now, hey, now
This is what dreams
are made of
I've got somewhere I belong
I've got somebody to love
This is what dre-e-e-ams
Are made of
Hey, now
This is what dreams
are made of
Hey, hey, hey, hey
Hey, now
This is what dreams
are made of
Open your eyes
This is what dreams
are made of
Shout to the skies
This is what dreams
are made of
Hey, hey, hey, hey
Then I see you smile
And I go, "Oh, oh, oh"
Yesterday
my life was duller
Now everything
is technicolor
Hey, now, hey, now
This is what dreams
are made of
Hey, now, hey, now
This is what dreams
are made of
I've got somewhere I belong
I've got somebody to love
This is what dre-e-e-ams
Dre-e-e-ams
Are made of
Hey, now, hey, now
Hey, hey, hey, hey
Hey!
Lizzie got everything
you're supposed to get
when you go to Europe.
Adventure, romance,
total confidence.
Yeah?
Well, if all that can happen
to Lizzie McGuire,
the only thing I know now is
I don't know anything.
That's hot.
What?
Girls who think they know
everything are just a turnoff.
Really?
Oh, totally.
What about you
not ratting out Lizzie?
I mean,
that was just so...
not you.
That's good.
Si,
Aaaaaaah!
Mom, Dad, I'm so glad
that you guys made it.
You would have never
believed me.
That is for sure.
I thought after you found out
all I did, I would be grounded.
You're grounded for the rest
of the summer, sweetheart,
but we're really proud of you.
Lying, even for a good reason,
is beneath you, Gordon.
Yeah. I know. I know.
I'm a lying, spineless,
brownnosing jellyfish
with a hidden agenda.
I got it.
That may be true,
but I'll tell you something.
Little Miss Diva
told me everything.
The way I see it, you're
a pretty loyal friend, Gordon.
And loyalty goes a long way
with the Ungermeyer.
- Hmm?
- Thanks.
Hey, just think about it.
We got 4 years of high school
to look forward to together.
Ooh. Sammies.
Sergei is hungry.
So is Miss Ungermeyer.
You are strong woman.
You protect cubs like lioness.
Sergei is impressed.
Hmm. You're still on my list.
As long as I am at the top.
Hey, there!
I bet you're wondering,
who is this Lizzie McGuire,
where did she come from,
and what are her
most embarrassing moments?
Well, I can give you
total access to all of that
for a very competitive price.
Hmm. When in Rome...
Yeah, yeah.
Do as the Romans do, right?
No.
We do not blackmail
our sisters.
As a former commander
in the ltalian Navy,
I am ordering you
to leave the country.
No!
Hey.
So, one last sneak-away
for old times' sake?
Yeah. Sounds good.
Okay.
Aha.
No!
So, are you gonna miss it here?
I don't know.
Kate says I should stay
and have my stuff shipped over,
because when I leave,
it'll never be the same.
She's wrong, as usual.
You didn't have to be in Rome
for all this to happen.
You think?
Trust me.
You had it in you
the whole time.
Gordo?
What?
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Yeah.
So, um, want to get back
to that party
so we don't get
in any more trouble?
Yeah. I can't afford
any more trouble.
Yeah.
Why not?
Think you're goin' nowhere
When you're walkin'
down the street
Acting like
you just don't care
When life can be so sweet
But why you want to be
like that
As if there's nothing new?
You're not foolin' no one
You're not even foolin' you
So walk a little slower
and open up your eyes
Sometimes it's so hard to see
the good things passin' by
And there may never be a
sign, no flashing neon light
Telling you to make your move
when the time is right
Why not
Take a crazy chance?
Do a crazy dance?
If you lose the moment,
you might lose a lot
So why not?
Why not?
Oh, I could be
the one for you
Oh, yeah,
maybe yes, maybe no
Oh, it could be
the thing to do
What I'm sayin' is you got to
let me know, oh, oh
Ah, ah, yeah
Ah, ah, ah
Yeah, yeah
Ah, ah, ah, yeah
Ah, yeah
Ah, yeah, yeah
You'll never get to heaven
or even to L,A,
If you don't believe
there's a way
Why not
Take a star from the sky?
Spread your wings and fly?
It might take a little,
and it might take a lot
But why not?
Why not?
Why not
Take a crazy chance?
Do a crazy dance?
If you lose the moment,
you might lose a lot
So why not?
Why not?
Hmmmmmm, mmmm, mmmm
Ohhhhh, yeah
You've been searching
the world
To find true love
Looking in all
the wrong places
When all of the time,
you've been blind to love
It's plain as the nose
on your face is
It's here, it's now
Open your eyes and see it
Right here, right now
Open your eyes to love
You've been down on yourself,
thinking something's wrong
Wondering why love
has never found you
Don't you know it's been
right here all along
If only you'd look
around you?
It's here
It's now
Open your eyes and see it
Right here
Right now
Open your eyes to love
Love has been
right by your side
Oh, so close
that you couldn't see
If love could speak,
it would shout to the sky
"I've always been here
I always will be"
I'm here
I'm now
Open your eyes and see me
Right here
Right now
Open your eyes to love
Open your mind to love
Open your heart to love
Ooh, ooh, ooh