♪ Fixed & Synced by
bozxphd.Enjoy The Flick ♪
There are places in my
neighborhood no one ever thinks about.
You see them every day and every
day you forget about them.
These are the places where
ah the things happen
that people are not
allowed to see.
You see, in Brooklyn, money
changes hands all night long.
It's just no! the kind you
can deposit in a bank.
All that money needs
in end up somewhere.
They call it a drop ban.
A bar the bosses choose
randomly each night...
to be the safe for
an entire city.
You never know up from when
your bar becomes the drop bar.
You just take all the
city's dirtiest money...
and bag men come and go
from all over town...
and nobody ever sees it coming;.
Nobody ever sees it going.
And then they could tell you
to be the drop bar next week.
Or maybe even next year.
The point is, you never know.
In the meantime...
“me...
.. . I just tend bar.
And wait.
Bobby, you want to sprinkle
the infield with The General?
This is fucking awesome.
We spend $80 million...
to drag a bunch of
Jersey geriatrics
across the river to
wet-shit their Depends.
The old guard.
They're not that old.
You see Stackhouse
block LeBron with his walker?
Gentlemen, these
are on the house.
When he speaks,
he says nice things.
Rardy, can you clean that up?
Okay, if it's for Richie.
You got new pants, Sully?
Yeah, I'll send them
to the dry cleaners.
- Rardy, we're not thanking you.
- Fuck you.
Fucking sphinx, that guy.
Cousin Marv, thanks
for the drink.
Thanks, Marv.
Shall we say
something for the kid?
Sully, go ahead. Yeah,
Sully, do it up.
Uh...
Richie "Glory Days“ Whelan.
Fort Hamilton, class of
'92 and a funny prick.
May he rest in peace.
Glory Days.
PAUL; Fucking A.
Let me guess.
You bought them the round.
Yeah. They're only...
They're celebrating the anniversary
of a very close friend, Marv.
The kid's been dead, what...
10 years now?
Mmm.
Ought to be a point
where you move on.
Stop scoring free
drinks off a corpse.
Speaking of which,
stop letting her ride
a stool all night and
not pay for her drinks.
Who, Millie? Yeah, Millie.
She doesn't drink that much.
When's the last time
you charged her?
It's
Millie, you know.
After midnight, you let her smoke
in here even though it's illegal.
You think I didn't know that?
If she can't pay
her tab tonight,
she don't come back in
here till she does.
Her bar tab is, like, 120 bucks.
It's about $140.
But she can't afford
it, you know?
Yeah, I'm gonna start crying now.
Okay?
And get all the candy canes
and Christmas shit down.
It's December 27th. Come on.
Gentlemen.
Why don't you go
fuck yourselves?
hallowed be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day
our daily bread.
Forgive us our trespasses as we forgive
those who trespass against us.
Lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
Peace be with you.
Body of Christ.
The Body of Christ.
Oh. Oh.
Oh. That's not good.
What are
you doing in there?
All right. All right, now.
Aw.
Hey. What are
you doing in my trash?
You have a dog in
your trash can.
It's a boxer.
Oh.
Jesus.
You have a dog here
in your trash.
Ooh.
Oh.
This one's bleeding.
What's your name?
Bob Saginowski.
Let me see your license.
My license? My wallet
is in my pocket
You'll have to take it out.
I just sent that picture to four people.
We clear?
Oh, he's freezing.
Yeah, well, it's cold.
Let's bring him inside.
I'm Nadia' by the way.
Is it bad?
It's not that deep, but, man.
Someone beat the shit out of this dog.
See these knots?
That's not skull,
that's contusions.
Are you a vet?
No, I'm a waitress at
the Ashmont Grill.
But I worked at Animal
Rescue one summer as a tech.
Careful.
They're so hard, this breed.
To find them a home.
Boxers?
This isn't a boxer.
It's a pit bull.
That's a dangerous dog.
It's not the dog's fault
his owner is a dick.
This guy...
look at him.
He's nothing but sweet.
You'll need a crate... makes them
feel safe. I have one you can borrow.
And food and chew
toys and stuff.
But I was, I was just passing
a garbage can. I can't...
I'll just take him back.
To who? The guy who beat him?
I'll take him to the
proper authorities.
That would be the shelter.
Right.
After they give the owner
seven days to reclaim him,
if he decides not to...
this dog will be put
up for adoption.
But who knows what kind
of person will take him?
I don't know.
You can take him. You take him.
I work nights. I work a lot.
We'll have to send him
to Animal Rescue.
Okay, look, can you, can you...
give me a couple days to
think about it? Please?
I have to think about this.
It's a big responsibility.
I don't know anything about...
Please, just a couple days.
I'll come back.
Please, a couple days.
Hold him till the weekend.
Just the weekend. It's a couple days.
Please. Please.
Saturday morning.
Thank you.
All right. Thank you.
Saturday.
Bob?
The dog needs a name.
Mmm, right.
Oh, my God.
You're going to be okay.
Do you know a Nadia Dunn?
Nadia Dunn?
You don't?
No.
That's the girl who's
holding the dog.
The dog again.
You know, I was thinking
that training a dog...
housebreaking, and
all that, that's...
l mean, that is a huge
responsibility, right?
Well, it's a dog.
It's not like some
long-lost retarded
relative shows up
in a wheelchair...
a colostomy bag hanging
out of his ass.
Says, "I'm yours now.
Take care of me."
It's not that.
It's a dog.
Yeah.
What?
No.
It's a fucking bad idea.
We should hit it for
everything or not at all.
Little brother, listen.
My guy says we got
to show him...
that we can handle our shit.
Says we do it in steps. See
how the owners respond.
They could respond pretty
fucking bad, you nut.
So that's what we'll see.
Your guy. Your fucking guy
talks a whole hell of a lot.
It's a fucking drop bar.
Not tonight it isn't.
Okay?
Okay.
Don't think about
it, just fill it.
Okay, we won't
cause any trouble.
You're making trouble!
Do you know what the
fuck you're doing?
Marv.
Do you know whose money this is?
Fucking fill the bag!
All right.
Just take it easy.
There you go.
Go ahead.
You fucking talk too much.
Oh.
Where's Rardy?
Rardy?
What the fuck?
You all right?
Oh, God, I'm gonna be sick.
I'm okay.
Look at his head.
Split open. We got to
call an ambulance.
That's bad. Rardy, don't move.
Just stay where you are.
How bad do I look?
Don't move. It's not good.
I'm putting something
on your head.
Hold that
There's one for your face.
The 8 o'clock at St. Dom's.
Every morning we see each
other and we've never met.
Detective Evandro Torres.
Hi. I'm Bob Saginowski.
A shame about St. Dom's.
What do you mean?
I just found out they're
folding it into St. Mary's.
Can you believe that?
I did not know that.
You're the bartender? Yeah.
The guys with the guns...
Want to take a walk?
They sound like anyone who
ever came in here before?
Nah. The guy closest to me,
I could see that his
watch had stopped.
Officer Bernardo says you said
they were covered head to toe'?
Handles, masks'?
Yeah, but I could see his
wrist as it was turning.
The face of the watch was
in front of me, like that.
And it was stopped?
Yeah. It said 6:15.
How much they take you for?
Well, whatever was
in the register.
So, if I was to ask around,
I wouldn't hear
anything about...
anyone making book here, or
someone moving money around?
Excuse me?
I wouldn't hear that? Nah.
Do you have insurance, Rardy?
What do you think?
No, we don't
have insurance.
The whole thing's a travesty.
Yeah, he took a pretty bad hit.
Nah, I meant St. Dom's.
Yeah. Yeah.
Beautiful church.
They did Mass right.
No group hugs after the Our Father.
No folk singers.
By the time the seculars get
done persecuting the Church...
all we'll have left is a bunch of
condos with stained glass windows.
What's up with the
surveillance cameras in there?
They don't record.
They're just a
deterrent for crime.
Why don't you take Communion?
Excuse me?
I've seen you at Mass for years.
You haven't taken
Communion once.
Well, you know,
that's my business.
You think so, huh?
Yeah, I think so.
Jesus. I fucking know so.
So was he gonna let you
wear his letter jacket...
or did he have to twist your
nipples a few times first?
Why the fuck would you tell
that cop about the watch?
I don't know.
You don't know.
It just came out.
Well, next time, why don't you nip
that impulse in the bud, huh'?
What the fuck is wrong with you?
It was very unlike me, Marv.
They took us for five
thou and some change.
Five thousand?
Thank God they picked
up the envelope,
so we're not on the
hook for that.
So we're all right. We're okay.
No, they took us for five
large and some change.
It's their bar,
it's their money.
They're going to want it back.
So we're not so fucking okay.
Bob?
You all right? Yeah.
Kind of early for the eight.
Yeah. I figured I could wait.
Well, come on in.
It's just a bowl and some food.
Oh. Thank you. Thank you.
Good luck.
Thank you.
You know, I've never
owned a dog before...
so' you know...
I have no idea what I'm doing.
At all.
You'll need bowls.
A leash.
Uh, poop bags.
And from now on, keep
your shoes up on a shelf.
Let me see if I can
find the bed section.
Oh. What do you want?
This is the best book I know.
You should read it.
Everything is in here.
What are you naming him?
Well, I was thinking about maybe Rocco.
I like the name Rocco.
But then I thought Mike.
Mike?
You don't like Mike?
No. Mike is not a
great name for a dog.
Rocco is better.
Okay -
So did they name you
Nadia after the gymnast?
Yeah. So you're a gymnast?
No.
Oh. Here you go. See?
"Rocco". Hey, he likes it.
Yeah, I like Mike.
You have him? Yeah.
Be patient.
Bye, thank you.
"Make sure the bottoms of the two
side panels rest inside the bottom."
Hey, Rocco?
I made you a safe place.
Bob?
Cold one, huh?
Who needs snow blower
when you have Bob?
Maybe you come to
my house later.
Sure.
I'm kidding.
This guy.
You on the welfare?
Excuse me?
Bob does all the work.
You watch.
No, I was shoveling.
You're shoveling, all right.
He was.
Come.
You know this guy?
No.
But I know this guy.
Moment I know him, I know him.
Somebody robbed my bar.
Yes. That's right. I'm sorry, Mr.
Umarov.
Call my father Mr.
Bob...
call me Chovka, eh?
That's right, I'm sorry, Mr.
Chovka, somebody did rob your bar.
Who robbed our bar?
We don't know. They wore masks.
That's right. So
we couldn't see.
Police report says one
wore a broken watch.
You tell them this?
Yeah, I did. I wasn't thinking.
It just came out.
So what are you doing to get
my father's money back?
Well, we put the word out.
In the neighborhood.
That's right.
They got the word
out in the neighborhood.
So the word is out there, huh?
The word. That's right.
With my money.
Find my fucking money.
"Find my money."
If we knew where
their money was,
it would mean we
knew who robbed us.
Which would mean
we were in on it,
which means they'd
shoot us in the face.
Fucking Chechnyans.
Chechens, Marv.
They're from Chechnya, but
you call them Chechens.
Yeah, Chechnya.
I said that. You
don't call people
from Ireland
Irelandians, do you?
What the fuck are
you talking about?
Yo, yo. What's the sunset
nightcap this evening?
You bring your own cup?
What, I just got
out of the womb?
Salud.
So what up, Evandro?
You remember Marvin Stipler?
Cousin Marv?
He got pushed off his own book,
nine, ten years ago,
by the Chechens.
His bar got held up.
It's owned by one of Papa
Umarov's shell companies.
What kind of dumb-ass
holds up one of his bars?
You got me.
Major Crimes up on the Umarovs?
We barely survived the
last budget cuts.
We're not sticking our
heads up to go after
some Russian John Q
barely knows exists.
Chechen.
You want him, he's all yours.
Hey, baby brother, you
ready to eat'? Huh?
What?
Are you ready to eat?
No.
I ate already.
When did you eat?
I ate.
Oh, no. Hey, hey, no.
Rocco, stay there. Stay.
Don't do it.
Don't do it. Don’t jump.
Oh, crikey Jesus.
That was close.
Aw, you gave me a heart attack.
Where the fuck you been?
Getting here.
You got the money? No.
What do you mean, no?
I mean no 'cause
fucking Bri has it.
Bri has it.
Did you tell your
brother about me?
No.
Why the fuck you
hit Rardy so hard?
I had to. You had to.
And I had to call an ambulance.
So there's an
ambulance and cops.
What's with his watch?
People noticed it's broke.
Tell him to get a new one
and get rid of that one.
Today.
What's the next step? When
do we hit a real drop bar?
Let's just assume I'm not some
asshole without a plan, okay?
When an airplane goes down, what's the
safest airline to fly the next day?
The one that had the crash.
Right. There you go.
So we just wait.
I don't understand a fucking
word you're saying.
It's like you're
speaking Brazilian.
Just let me take
care of it, okay?
Keep your head down.
It's not Brazilian.
Brazilians speak Portuguese.
Where you going?
I'm leaving.
Stay here. We can't be
seen together, genius.
Fuck you. How long?
I don't know. Ten minutes!
Sit.
Sit. No, that's standing.
Come here.
Go, go. Oh, man.
How you doing?
Good.
Oh, shit. Rocco, come on!
Come. Good boy.
You didn't read the
book, did you?
Uh, some of it, yeah.
No.
Not a lot.
I was thinking-mow
the holidays over...
l lost a shift at
the restaurant.
I'm sorry.
So maybe you could
hire me, you know?
Pay me to babysit Rocco
when you're working?
Hey, well, that's not
such a bad idea.
I work a lot at the bar.
That would be very kind of you.
You have a number I can call'?
Maybe call. You want to
arrange this properly?
Just put it there.
Have you got a pen? No.
I think I have a pen.
Where's that pen
when you need it?
Does it work?
Yeah.
Here you go.
Great. That's a great idea.
And I need a key.
Well, like' maybe I could... if you
call me, I'll either have it...
and drop it around yours, or I
could leave it at the bar for you.
Call me.
Yeah, I'll call you... on this
number you gave me right now.
Happy New Year, by the way!
Happy New Year!
We should
join that show.
You can't fucking sing.
Not that one, the other
one, where the people...
go around the world picking
up clues and stuff.
It'd be cool. Let's do it.
We could see things.
What things?
I don't know. Other countries.
Other ways.
You see the old man today?
Yeah, was by.
They want
their money, Marv.
Who?
The home.
They'll get it.
It's the collection
agency now, not the home.
Medicaid cutbacks. Me retiring.
They're going to ship him out.
To where?
To a lesser place.
Maybe it's time.
Yeah.
Just kill him.
Our father. Because
it's inconvenient.
He's dead, Marv.
So what are all those beeps
coming out of the machines...
he's hooked up to, and the waves
on the screen of the thing?
That's life.
That's electricity,
is what that is.
The other day, I picked up his
hand and put it on my cheek.
And I could hear his blood.
So you want to unplug him?
Go ahead, your decision.
Take it easy.
No, make the decision.
I'll be all right with it.
Mmm-hmm.
That's! be a first.
Never mind. It's okay.
I'll get to Europe
in another life.
Rocco. Come to heel.
Come to heel. Come to heel.
And sit.
You see that?
Yeah, I saw it.
He almost gave me the paw.
When I watch TV, he
sleeps on my leg.
Really? Out.
Come.
I'll be right back.
Crazy. Come on.
That's a nice dog.
Thank you. I appreciate it.
Yeah, that's a nice-looking dog.
Don't forget to feed it.
Tell me where the hospital is?
Bang a U-ey, go down
to the end here.
Take a right. There'll be signs.
Thanks.
I promise, tomorrow we'll go to the park.
But I'm in a mad rush today.
I will be back very soon.
Hey, man, how you doing?
Mind if I step in? It's
kind of cold outside.
Thanks a lot.
Jesus.
Can I help you?
Yeah. Where are you keeping him?
What are you talking about?
The dog. You keep him in the kitchen?
The cellar?
I remember you.
You came up to me in the park and
told me I had a nice-looking dog.
Yeah, well, he's not your dog.
Yeah, he's my dog.
Oh, yeah'? You register him?
City says you have to license it.
How about a chip?
Excuse me? A security chip.
Implanted in the dog.
Pooch goes missing,
shows up at a vet.
Vet scans the dog.
Up pops a barcode with
the owner's info.
The owner, meanwhile, walks
around with a slip of paper.
It has the security chip
account number on it.
Check it out.
You got my dog.
No, it's my dog.
You beat him.
I'll tell the cops you did.
What do you want?
It's kind of sunny, right?
Hmm.
But you never know, I guess.
You never ask about it.
You're the only
person I ever met
who didn't ask about it in
the first five minutes.
It's your business, not mine.
You'll tell me when you
tell me, or you won't.
I did it to myself.
I was pretty high.
You did that?
With one of those...
like, a peeler.
Peeler?
You know, a potato peeler?
Oh, God, yeah, I know
what that is, right.
I was a different person then.
I didn't really like myself.
Do you like yourself now?
Sir, you cannot
have a dog in here.
Dog goes, YOU guys go, okay?
I'm telling you...
l got guys following me.
You don't.
I do. I told you about
the guy in the car.
He was asking you
for directions.
It was the way he asked. The
way he was looking at me.
I'm not a fucking idiot.
What about you? The guy
with the umbrella.
Oh, he's just
interested in the dog.
The dog. Mmm.
How do you know? Maybe he's
just telling you that.
It's too
much for them to...
put them back where
they found them,
because that would
require courtesy.
You should just get
a dumpster, Marv.
"Just get a dumpster, Marv.
Get a dumpster."
Sure.
You remember I don't own
the bar anymore, right?
Huh?
Yeah.
Oh, yeah, but it's not
your bar Chovka took.
That was 10 years ago.
No, it was eight-and-a-half
years ago.
All right.
Eight-and-a-half years.
Dottie thinks we
should visit Europe.
That's what I've become... a guy
that goes to Europe with his sister.
Hops in a, a tour bus...
with a fucking camera around my
neck like a fucking jerk off.
What?
Uh...
You need to see this, Marv.
No, I don't.
I don't need to do anything.
I'm just going to
stand right here.
I'm going to stand
right the fuck here.
No.
You really should
take a look at this.
I don't need to see Europe.
I don't need to see Dottie.
And I don't need to see
what's in that bag.
Aw, what the fuck?
We need to do something with it.
What, the money or the...
thing?
I bet what's in here adds up
to what we lost that night.
Why'd they give it back to us?
So we give it back to them.
That's clearly what they expect.
Like you're wrapping
a piece of meat.
Like you've done it
a thousand times.
Do you wonder if you hadn't
mentioned the watch...
No, I don't.
Well, I do.
Hi, guys. You got any Zima?
No, we're closed.
Well, your door was
unlocked, so...
I'm sorry about that, but
we're closed now, so...
Yeah. Yeah.
You got to go.
Hey, Bob.
How you doing? Nice to see you.
All right, come on.
Say hi to Nadia.
Don't forget to stitch her up
when she stabs herself, okay?
Tossing the missing piece of the
One-Armed Man around like a ham...
and the front door's open!
He didn't see anything.
But he could've.
But he didn't
You know that guy?
Yeah. That's the guy I
told you about with Rocco.
Who claims the dog is his?
You know who else he is?
No.
He's the guy who says
he killed Richie Whelan.
That guy? Yeah.
That's Eric Deeds?
Yeah, that's Eric Deeds.
And he's fucked in the
squash, that guy.
Been in the joint
a couple times.
He did a 30-day in the
cuckoo house, if I recall.
So you watch that fucking kid.
Some fucking day, Marv.
Yeah, some fucking day.
Will you pass me the sports bag
by the wasp-and-ants spray?
Yeah, sure, I'd love to.
Thank you.
I'm going for a walk now.
Okay.
Fucking Christ.
Don't look at that.
Don't look at it.
Hey, hey, what's this?
Go get it. Go on.
Yeah, play with it.
My big red bone.
Go get it. Go get that!
Get the bone!
Aw, shit.
Mr. Saginowski.
How you doing?
I'm good.
We haven't caught them yet.
Yeah, well, you
know, I assumed...
That we didn't do our job?
No, I just heard it was hard to
make an arrest on robbery cases.
What's up with the bag?
This is...
It's my poop bag and sometimes
I keep leashes and balls...
and stuff in my bag.
Kind of empty.
Yeah, well, I used my last
poop bag and I lost the ball.
Richie Whelan.
Uh-huh.
What about him? You know him?
Sure. His friends were in the bar the
other day, toasting his anniversary.
What anniversary?
Of the last time
anybody saw him.
Which was at your bar.
That's right. Yeah, he left.
He took his car and they
found it someplace.
Astoria. Torched.
That's a good-looking dog.
Oh, thank you.
You know an Eric Deeds?
Uh...
Tall guy? Beard? He's,
like, a broader'?
Um, maybe.
I mean, you working in that bar.
Come on.
You know people, Mr. Saginowski.
I got a picture.
Nah. You think maybe
he robbed the bar?
No.
I'm hearing here and
there that this guy...
has something to do with
the Whelan disappearance.
Really?
That's a really
good-looking dog.
I came by to give
him his afternoon walk.
Great.
I freaked. Is your cell on?
Yeah, but it's on vibrate.
I couldn't feel it.
I called a bunch of times.
I know, I could see that.
I'm sorry.
I thought you were
working today.
I am. It's just I had this...
You know what? It's a
really long story.
I'm sorry. I should have called you.
I apologize.
It's okay. Hey.
So you know Eric Deeds, huh?
No. l don’t "know
him“ know him...
you know? I know
him from around.
So you don't know him?
Not really, no.
That's funny, because the way
he said it, I figured...
Figured what?
I don't know. You know, maybe...
I don't know.
Why are you on my ass about it?
I was just asking a question.
No' you were insinuating.
No, I wasn't.
Now you're arguing
just to argue with me.
No.
See? I'm not.
I don't need this shit, okay?
Wait. What happened here?
Did I say something wrong?
You think you can
push me around?
No. Wait.
Don't you fucking touch me.
I don't understand.
I asked her one question.
A question. Simple. And then
it all came out sideways.
You don't get it.
They get in a mood...
you could give them
the Hope Diamond
and they'd complain
about the weight.
Am I right?
Bob, you ain't actually talking
about a girl, are you?
Bobby's got himself a girl?
Guy gets a dog, becomes
a pussy magnet.
They're flinging
it at my man now.
I'm gonna go play some pool.
How are you?
Chovka, let me
get you a drink.
Marv'? Stella-Andre,
he drinks Stella.
Oh.
There you go.
Here it is.
I put it in a Ziploc. But it's all there.
You can count it.
Ziploc?
Well, it was a little wet.
I was going to dry it, but
we don't have a dryer.
So I figured I'd put it in a Ziploc.
If you spread it out...
on a table, it should be
good come the morning.
I have no idea what you're
talking about, Bob.
This isn't what you
gave me last time.
That? No, that's not
the Bowmore 18.
You didn't like it. You
said it smelled like feet.
I figured that you would
prefer this a lot more.
This is very special.
It's Irish.
We die.
All of us...
Andre.
But before you do, you have to
try this fucking whiskey, man.
Yeah, get him one.
Come on. Here.
You handle the drop.
All right. Which night?
Super Bowl.
Okay -
ls good.
Detective
Evandro Torres.
Jimmy Sullivan.
Thanks for seeing me.
So you got nothing else about
the night Glory Days vanished?
The only thing I remember was that
he left the bar to score weed.
And the guys he got it from
were a couple of shitheads.
A nut job named Deeds and his
junkie buddy... what was his name?
Tim Brennan. He was in
the original statement.
Theta me guy.
He was going to see them both'?
Or only one?
I don't remember.
But Bob Saginowski
and Cousin Marv?
You trying to tie them to this?
Nah, I just-
You got me out here in front
of the guys l work with,
looking like a snitch.
Thanks for that. But
Cousin Marv's place?
That's my bar. All right?
Don't fuck with my bar.
You know, I'm...
I'm sorry.
I don't care
if you know him.
It's just that...
the way that he
said hi, you know,
it sounded like it
meant something.
I was just asking.
What else did he say?
He said that Rocco was his.
That he has a chip in
his neck to prove it.
He used to be my boyfriend.
In the beginning,
he was charming.
He was really nice.
I know a lot of people said things
about him, but I don’t judge people.
I don't want to prejudge people.
Sure.
It just became too much.
I haven't seen him in a while.
I thought he was gone.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
You don't have to explain.
Everybody has a past.
And if this guy put Rocco in your
trash, that's not your fault.
And as for Rocco, he won't blame you.
You know?
He don't know no better.
He's not just going to go away.
Eric? No.
He doesn't strike me as the
type that wants to do that.
He's not.
He killed a kid
named Glory Days.
Yeah. I heard that
I heard that.
Richie Whelan.
Hmm.
Why?
I don't know.
He's not a big fan of "why".
Eric.
Hmm.
It's broken.
Yeah, it is.
Do you want me to fix it?
You want to fix it?
Yeah.
Sure.
You want another beer?
Yeah.
Sol heard that Cousin
Marv doesn't own the bar?
That some hard guys do.
But you're not a hard guy.
So why do you work there?
You know me and Cousin
Marv go way back, right?
Yeah, Marv is
actually my cousin.
Yeah?
Marv and his sister, Dottie...
his father and my mother,
they're all sisters.
Really?
Did they share makeup?
Why would they do that?
You said they were sisters.
Oh, you're right. Yeah.
You know what I mean.
Why are you jumping
on me like that?
It's fun. Fun.
Fun.
Yeah, Marv thought
he was a tough guy.
Mmm. We had a crew once.
Back in the day, when we was
young, we made a little money...
but it was never, you know...
So a mean crew rolls into
town, and, you know...
we flinched. That's it.
End of the crew.
But you're still in the life.
Me? No.
No. No, no, no.
I just tend the bar.
What are you doing? Get in.
You fucking come out here.
Are you nuts? It's freezing!
Get in.
I'm not getting in the car!
You think the trunk's
lined with plastic?
How should I know?
Here, go look then. Go ahead.
Don't you fuck with me.
Don't you fucking dare!
Nobody’s fucking with you.
You hear?
All right? Yeah.
Want to call your mommy
and tell her you're okay?
Dam "yoke.
Last time anybody saw my brother
alive, he got in a car with a guy.
All right.
You're right. I'm sorry.
Take it easy.
What we got here is a
risk-versus-reward kind of thing.
We took the risk. And up to now,
it's not been working
out so well, I know.
Yeah, but?
But I know where the Super
Bowl drop off will be.
So if you want to hit
them back for Bri,
you hit them back for a million.
It's suicide. Fucking suicide.
I got news for you, Fitzy.
We're dead already, we're
just walking around.
The only way to get
out is to leave.
I'm not doing another one, man.
You're not. I'm not.
You sure about that?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Okay, I'll square
it with you then.
I'm buying something with it.
First, you don't tell anybody
what we just discussed.
You don't tell anybody.
Second, I need a place to
hole up for a couple days.
What, you're on the street?
You didn't close the trunk.
I closed it.
Not very well.
I closed that fucking thing.
Forget about the trunk. No,
I'm not on the street.
Everybody knows where I live.
Nobody knows where you live.
So can I shack up
with you tonight
or maybe tomorrow night?
Not with me, but I know a place.
All right?
Got cable?
Motherfucker, what?
You know, cable.
Fuck you.
You have to get behind it!
Slam it with two hands!
Here you are.
Good night.
I got that.
Bob?
Thanks.
For what?
Good night.
Sorry I was so long.
I didn't take you with me.
You want a chewie?
Here.
There you go. For you.
Oh.
Mind if I sit down?
No, have a seat.
What's up?
I was wondering why you
don't like my cousin.
He took my dog.
He didn't take your dog.
You beat the crap out of it
and put it in a trash can.
I felt bad about it.
That count?
Yeah.
Okay, good.
And now you want it back.
What kind of question is that?
I don't know what I want.
I don't know.
But I don't want him walking
around thinking he's the shit.
He needs to learn.
Learn what?
That he shouldn't
have fucked with me.
Are you fucking with me?
Me'? No, no.
I'm too old for that shit.
I come in peace.
Why is that? Is there a war?
Not that I know of.
Good.
In the bar the other night,
you made my cousin nervous.
You don't see that often.
I think there's a way you
and I can sort that out...
and both be happy.
Look at you.
You're looking good.
Eric Deeds' psych file.
You got three
minutes to read it.
There better be no
grease on those fingers.
Well, I'll be damned.
Like you fucking
weren't already?
What? Not what you
were expecting?
My file?
Yeah.
You know what you're gonna do?
You got to give me 10.
Ten grand. By tomorrow morning.
Who's got $10,000?
Come on.
Listen. You want the dog,
you give me 10. Simple.
Listen here, pal.
You can't walk into people's
lives and expect them to-
Listen, listen. Take it easy.
Listen to me.
That is life. That's what it is.
People like me coming along
when you're not looking.
Just get my money, 10:00
a.m., your place, okay?
And if you don't get it, I'll go
to the cops and get my dog back.
Simple. And then I'll forget
to feed it for a while.
And then when the dog gets
all yappy about it...
l'll beat his fucking
head with a rock.
All right? You picture that.
Yeah.
Remember what I did
to Richie Whelan.
Yep.
And I had a partner back then.
I still have him.
Mmm-hmm.
You okay? Mmm-hmm.
Okay. It was good to see you.
Bobby, how's it going?
Good. You?
Good.
What's happening? I thought
you took early retirement.
What can you do? I'll
do another year or two.
Hope the phlebitis don't get too bad.
See how I feel. Marv?
I'm heading out to work.
Good day, Dot.
You, too!
Are you going to eat something?
Yeah.
Okay
Biggest day in the
world tomorrow,
I can't get you on the phone.
Oh, yeah. I forgot to tell
you, I don't feel good...
so I'm not coming in.
Call the BarTemps.
I did already.
Super Bowl. We always use them.
So what do you need me for?
I don't.
But."
you're blowing off the
biggest tip day of the year.
What, I work for tips now?
You ever go to the
front of the bar.“
and look at the sign on the bar?
Whose name is on it?
That's my name.
'Cause I used to own it once.
Yeah, you been playing that
flute a long time now.
And you've been awfully
fresh since...
you got that dog that
you mistake for a kid.
Marv, you can't redo it.
All right? They
pressed, you blinked.
It's done. It's over.
It's been over for a while now.
Well, I'm not the guy who wasted his
entire life waiting for it to start.
I did that? Mmm-hmm.
At least I had something once.
I was respected. I was feared.
When I walked into a
place, people sat up.
They sat up straight.
They noticed.
What's! you ever have'?
And the fucking bar stool
you put that old biddy at.
You don't think I don't know
that you did it on purpose?
That was my stool and
nobody sat on that stool
because it was
Cousin Marv's stool.
And that meant something.
That meant something!
But it didn't
Ever.
It was just a stool.
Are you doing
something desperate?
Again?
Marv?
Are you doing something that maybe
we can't clean up this time?
I told you, I don't feel good.
So why don't you get
the fuck out of here?
Really.
Good-bye, Marv.
I hope you feel better soon.
Don't forget to eat something.
The
Body of Christ.
The Body of Christ.
Should we go?
Let's move out.
Rocco, I'll have to
lock you down in a sec.
We have a long day.
Hey, BM, how you doing'!?
I got to... l got
to talk to you.
I want to take you
someplace tonight.
It's a lot of fun.
Then we're out of here.
Hi. How you doing?
What do you want?
I don't want you here.
Please leave.
No, listen to me. Sit clown
and listen to me, okay?
I want you to go.
This is my home.
I'm not your girl anymore.
I want you to leave.
Come on, take a seat. Come on.
Don't play that shit. Sit down.
You look good, by the way.
We're going somewhere tonight.
It's gonna be a lot of fun.
And after that,
we're out of here.
I want you to go. Please.
You're going to go.
And make yourself
pretty, all right?
Good to see you, man.
Where you been?
I came back to see you, Jimmy.
He said, I'm coming
right back for you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please rise and
remove your hats.“...
.. . as we honor America with the
singing of our national anthem.
Two Dos
Equis, three Amstel,
two shots of Jack and a
Dewar's on the rocks.
You hear that, Rardy?
Coming up.
Hey, Bob?
Bob?
Bob!
Can I get two more
Heineken on 1-3?
Rardy? Two more Heineken.
White wine, right? Yeah.
Can you get me a Sm“ rocks
and a house Chard for the lady?
I didn't see you this morning.
Yeah, so what?
So you don't want the money?
You bring it? What?
Did you bring the money?
You strike me as the
type who would bring it.
Two Stella and an Amstel.
Sure.
Rardy, two Amstels and a Stella.
Why is she here?
She's my girl.
Hmm.
Give me that piece of paper
and you get the money.
What paper?
The microchip and the
license, like we agreed.
Why would I do that?
Because that's why I'm paying
you the money. That's the deal.
That's a deal. Hold on a second.
You can keep the change.
Keep the change.
Two Stellas
and one Amstel.
What's up? Wait a minute.
I can't talk right now.
Wait a second.
Here you go.
What's that noise?
Where are you?
I'm at the place. Your place.
The bar?
Why the fuck you
show up so early?
This was simple. You show
up at {he designated time,
do the thing and lea ve.
I know what he seems like, but I
shit you not, do not fuck with him.
Stay away from him.
He already thinks
you want to kill him
over some fucking dog.
Just stay in the back.
Yeah, I got it.
And you're in a bar.
Don't drink too much.
I'll see you at 2:00,
you fucking idiot.
What an amazing game!
Twenty-seven to 23,
your final score!
Are you with him? No.
So why are you here?
What were you talking about?
I told you, nothing.
Bob.
Oh, yeah, we do.
This is not good.
This is so not good.
I don't want to be here.
I didn't want to come here.
He was waiting in my
house when I got home.
I'm sorry, Bob.
He has a gun.
I'm going to the ladies'.
What were you talking about?
Football.
Give me another shot, will you?
What was the name
of your partner?
Wouldn't be much of a threat if you
knew who he was, would he, Bob?
Yeah, but...
he helped you kill
Richie Whelan, right?
That's the rumor, Bob.
More than a rumor.
It's what you said.
Then it's more than a rumor, Bob.
What time is it?
You know, you don't have to keep
calling me Bob all the time.
I'll see what I can do, Bob.
What is that?
The 10 grand you wanted.
This is 10 grand?
Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
You know what I think?
I'm going to look in
the safe at 2:00.
Time lock goes off at 2:00 a.m.
You got 90 seconds
to close it...
or it triggers two
silent alarms.
We should look in
the safe at 2:00.
Now you listen.
I'm happy to pay you
10 grand for the dog.
Yeah. Ten grand for the dog.
But that's it.
And how much for her?
How about that? How much
should he pay for you?
Eric, please. Please
don't do this.
Where's Marv? Marv?
You need him for something?
I don't want anything.
I just don't want him creeping
up my back all of a sudden.
Yeah, my sweet cousin Marv.
You know he's had some
trouble, Marv. Yeah.
Like, about 10 years
ago, man, he had...
a problem with the cards.
I didn't know that, Bob.
But he was more of a
loan shark back then.
And I remember this kid.“
he was into him for a
shitload of money.
Hopeless case when it came
to the dogs and B-ball.
Just degenerate, really.
Kind of kid who'd never be
able to pay back what he owed.
It's 1:57, all right?
And then the kid goes to A.C.
and he...
hits up a slot machine
for 22 grand.
Bam.
Who'd have thunk it?
It was, like,
a fraction move than
what he owed Marv.
So he didn't pay up and
you roughed him up.
No, no. That's not
what happened.
He paid back Marv, every cent.
He was a good guy.
It's 1:58, all right?
What he didn't account for was
Marv skimming off his own stash.
Because of his habits
and his gambling debts.
And this kid coming out of the
blue with 22 grand was a...
what'd he say?
"A viable business opportunity."
That's my cousin Marv.
So long as nobody knew that he'd
paid Marv back off, you know?
You see where this is going?
Yeah, kid had to be ripped off.
No. Kid had 1:0 be killed.
So nobody'd know he'd
paid Marv back off.
So that's what we did.
Oh, so you...
killed him. Yeah, I did.
I shot him in the face, twice.
Then I wrapped his
head in a towel
and stabbed him in the heart...
so he would bleed out,
put him in my bathtub
and watched him drain.
Then I put him in an oil tank...
with laundry
detergent and lye...
and sealed it back up.
Want to know what his name was?
It's 2:00, Bob.
It's 2:00.
His name.
I would not know, Bob.
Yes, you do. This is
something you know.
I wouldn't knew that, Bob.
Guess.
I know it's 2:00, and you
got to open the safe!
Listen to me.
His name...
was Richie Whelan.
Everybody called him Glory Days?
I killed Richie Whelan, okay?
Sure you did.
Fucking punk.
Go out to dinner dressed like
you're still in your living room.
You wear those...
big hippity-hoppity clown shoes.
You speak to women terribly.
You treat them despicably.
You hurt harmless dogs that
can't defend themselves.
I'm tired of you, man.
I'm tired of you.
You embarrass me.
You know, he would
have kept coming back.
People like this, you let them
take something from you...
and they keep coming back.
You still owe them and
they never, never change.
You can never change their mind.
You just...
I mean, you just
fucking shot him.
Yes, I did. Absolutely. He
was going to hurt our dog.
Bob? Mmm.
Can l... can I go now?
Yeah, of course. You can.
So you... you'll let me go?
Sure, sure.
Why not?
And, and nobody will ever
hurt you again. Okay?
This is done. Okay?
You got your stuff?
Go on now.
But now... now you'll
think I'll talk.
I won't talk, Bob.
I know you won't
I promise. l won’t.
Nadia, you can't. Not with these people.
They won't...
Your people, Bob.
No, they're not my...
I'm not them.
And I'm not this.
You've seen better days, huh?
Andre?
He just came in.
Yeah, that's right. When
I opened up the door.
I was just letting
Millie out, and...
Put a gun in your face, but
you said, "Not tonight," huh?
I didn't say anything.
You ever see him before?
Yeah.
Yeah, he was in here.
Over there, watching the game.
Caught my attention
'cause he was on his own.
Maybe he wasn't
No, he was, though.
Or maybe he wasn't.
I'm sorry, I don't follow you.
Sure you do. You say he
was on his own, alone.
I say he wasn't.
What's to follow?
You.
You're alone.
Sometimes it's good to be alone.
Say it.
I'm alone.
No way, my man.
You have friends.
Speaking of friends,
your cousin Marv?
He told me he's retiring. He want
you to be the boss of the bar.
I said, "Oi course,
It's your bar."
"But it's not your money.“
"So why you always trying
to take my money?"
So I made him a deal.
“You and your druggy friends
leave my money alone...
and I'll pay you a ticket
to a nice, quiet place."
So what do you think?
Hmm?
Take down his name, put up yours.
"Bob's Bar."
Has a nice ring to it, huh?
"Bob's Big Bad Bar."
I'm kidding, my friend.
Lighten up.
Sure.
Did he fit?
Yeah. Had to break his
legs, but he fit fine.
Smile. Don't mind,
everything's gonna be okay.
Get some rest.
Good night.
There are some sins you commit
that you can come back from...
no matter how hard you try.
You just can't, you know? It's like the
devil is waiting for your body to quit.
Because he knows...
he knows that“...
he already owns your soul.
And then I think, maybe, you
know, there is no devil.
"Nah."!
"Nah, you can come in."
"You have to leave now."
"You have to leave and go away
and you have to be alone."
"You have to be alone forever."
I'm sorry to hear
about Cousin Marv.
It was a carjacking
gone bad is what they said.
Carjacking? Right.
That was an execution.
A block and a half
from this bar.
Anyway, it fucking sucks
and I'm really sorry.
Thank you.
Are you going to the
church closing tomorrow?
Yeah, of course.
I don't know yet. I got a shift.
They sold it. To Milligan Development.
What'd I tell you?
Condos with stained
glass windows.
Eric Deeds.
I mentioned him to you once.
Yeah, I remember.
You didn't then.
I remember you mentioning him.
He was in this bar Super Bowl Sunday.
You see him'?
No. There was a lot
of people in here
on Super Bowl Sunday, so...
Yeah, that's true.
It's just this was the last place
he was ever seen and then...
Just like Richie Whelan.
Mmm.
Ironic, 'cause Deeds
supposedly killed Whelan.
Bodies getting clipped or vanishing
all over the place, but...
come on, man, you
don't see anything?
Nah. You know, that's
this neighborhood, right?
But he could turn up.
People do all the time.
That's true. If he does, it'll
probably be in a psych ward.
Which is where he was the
night Whelan disappeared.
I'm not lying. It's true.
Deeds always took credit for the Whelan
hit 'cause nobody else wanted to.
He thought it would
help his street cred...
but he didn't kill Whelan.
He didn't?
Yeah.
No one ever sees you
coming, do they' Bob?
Rocco. Something
we got to do.
When you left the bar, I
know that meant stay away.
I know that meant stay away,
but you didn't say it.
So if you say it, then...
l will just go. Believe me,
Nadia, I will leave right now.
But you have to say it.
Let me go get my jacket.
Yeah?
Sure, great. Great.
♪ Hope it helped -> bozxphd ♪