Follow me.
How is he feeling?
...cruel violence is spreading
throughout the German occupied Europe.
The crime of Hitler... the crimes cannot be
tolerated by our beloved country.
May I borrow your newspaper?
I left mine on the bus.
There are informants everywhere.
We just want to keep our families safe.
What can we do?
Jean will meet you tonight
to print two thousand copies.
I’ll take care of it.
Distribute these amongst the workers.
May we speak?
I’m not interested.
Yes?
We identified an illegal radio signal
from your home.
I don’t have a radio.
Please, come in.
- I know he is here
- May I offer you something to eat?
Don’t believe this propaganda madam.
The Germans are the enemy... not the Jews.
I’m a new patient.
For Dr. Chevain?
No Dr. Benoit.
Father Robert Alesch.
Your sermons are legendary.
We can’t stand by with our arms folded.
Indeed.
I’m looking for Brigitte?
Do you have a message for her?
I need to see her.
I’m sorry, Father, but...
I apologize for the inconvenience.
Perhaps you can return another time?
I can’t promise,
but I’ve heard Brigitte might be in town.
There is a double agent in Bordeaux.
All my contacts have been arrested.
Who knows if any of them have talked.
I need protection,
a disguise and money to rebuild a network.
I’ve heard about Brigitte.
If you see her, please--
I’ll pass along the message.
It’s urgent.
I understand.
It look’s beautiful, doesn’t it?
Boarding
Train for Paris!
Search everything.
Everybody off the train!
Everybody off, bring your luggage!
We found her!
Everybody back on the train!
I won’t be long.
8, rue des Archers
This will be helpful.
In the center, right?
We’ve finally caught you.
You must go!
It’s too dangerous here!
What, a woman with a wooden leg?
She will slow us down.
I’m telling you she cannot do it.
It’s not going to work.
Stop!
It’s the police!
I said stop!
What do you have there?
Good. Let’s play.
It’s for the prisoner, sir.
They can have it when we’re done.
Put it down here.
Let’s pack it up for tonight.
But I’ll be back tomorrow for a rematch.
Bring her to the prisoners.
To pass the time tonight.
That’s nice of you.
Lights out!
Thank God!
Let’s go.
What is going on here?
Is there a problem, sir?
What are you all doing past curfew hour?
We don’t want to cause trouble.
Get on your knees, all of you. Now!
Sir, there’s a misunderstanding.
Your accent... it’s not from around here.
I thought it was you!
Oh my God! How are you?
What are you doing here?
It’s complicated.
You look like you could
really use a cup of tea.
Yes, that would be lovely.
I’m so happy to see you.
You can’t even imagine.
I’ve been sleeping in alleys for days.
I have nowhere to go.
Can you help me?
I have a family, Noor.
If anyone finds out...
Giselle, thousands of Jews are disappearing.
Now innocent French children
are being marked with yellow stars.
Aren’t you afraid?
Please... for France?
A few days.
That’s all I can offer you.
Roosevelt’s decision,
committing U.S. troops to aid the British
in the seizure of French North Africa has
culminated in a major defeat to the Axis.
Having lost control of the Mediterranean,
Hitler’s forces are gathering on the frontiers of
Southern France to occupy the rest of France.
Klaus Barbie has arrived!
I’d do anything to get my hands
on that limping bitch’s throat.
Distribute these fliers. All over France.
Tone it down on those sermons.
This is new for me.
I wanted to be convincing, Herr Barbie...
Do not disparage the Führer’s name!
...so no one suspects anything. My apologies.
Your bonus.
I paid for both of your whores in Paris, as well.
Find me this woman.
This is the punishment for anyone...
who is caught aiding spies
and betraying the Führer.
Where is she?
You are asking me questions
and I do not know the answers.
Why would she have told me anything?
I am a doctor.
I am healing people, that’s it.
Where is she?
I don’t know.
This is what we do with spies.
What have you done?
I did this for you.
For you to eat.
Move it you dirty whore! Keep moving.
Loyalty. It’s overrated.
Start transmitting as Madeline.
She’s heading South... Pyrenees.
She’s tried to escape twice.
We can’t get anything out of her.
Put her on the next van.
You did it!